<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Rediscovering the Small Web</title>
<link>https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;header readability=&quot;12.586363636364&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;Most websites today are built like commercial products by professionals and marketers, optimised to draw the largest audience, generate engagement and 'convert'. But there is also a smaller, less-visible web designed by regular people to simply to share their interests and hobbies with the world. A web that is unpolished, often quirky but often also fun, creative and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;info&quot;&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/index.html&quot;&gt;Parimal Satyal&lt;/a&gt;, 25 May 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every website redesign begins with inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this one, there were two: Anders' &lt;a href=&quot;https://anders.unix.se&quot;&gt;clean, readable website&lt;/a&gt;, which inspired the homepage, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://marijnflorence.neocities.org/index.html&quot;&gt;Marijn's site&lt;/a&gt;, which reminded me just how &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; the web can be. The colours, graphics, &lt;a href=&quot;https://marijnflorence.neocities.org/music/&quot;&gt;creative navigation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holocene_calendar&quot;&gt;interesting ideas&lt;/a&gt;... the simple fact of clicking through the pages of someone's personal website in 2020 made me nostalgic of the web of the late 90s and early 2000s that I grew up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of you might have read my previous article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/against-a-user-hostile-web/&quot;&gt;Against an Increasingly User Hostile Web&lt;/a&gt;. In it, I argue that we are replacing an open web that connects and empowers with one that restricts and commoditises people. I talk about how the modern web of surveillance, bloat and walled gardens is at odds with the open web that I love. I was pleasantly surprised by how much the sentiment seemed to be shared by so many other people who emailed me, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eduardomorais.com/stream/id/3519&quot;&gt;wrote responses on their own blog&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15611122&quot;&gt;discussed it&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://lobste.rs/s/5bi46y/against_increasingly_user_hostile_web&quot;&gt;online forums&lt;/a&gt;. Despite being two and a half years old, that article rather disappointingly still reflects the state of the web today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But stumbling upon Marijn’s site gave me hope. It led me down a rabbit hole of many other small websites made by people with all kinds of interests: movies, aviation, music, art, computers. It reminded me that the creative, personal, fun web I grew up with is not a thing of the past. It’s still here in 2020. You just have to know where to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My aim is not to convince you that everything was better in the past; it wasn't. You had trojans, malware, endless pop-ups, terrible security practices, browser incompatibility, slow Java applets. No, technically, the modern web is more secure and more usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This essay is my attempt to show you what the small and independent web can look like, why it’s different from the the sites that dominate web traffic today, why it's worth exploring and how easy it is for anyone to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This essay is somewhat long; you might find this table of contents handy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/#retro-redesign&quot;&gt;Retro Redesign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/#first-webpages&quot;&gt;The First Webpages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/#masters-navigators&quot;&gt;Masters and Navigators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/#modern-gatekeepers&quot;&gt;Modern Gatekeepers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/#commercial-web-of-marketing&quot;&gt;The Commercial Web (of Marketing)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/#product-oriented-website&quot;&gt;The Product-Oriented Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/#web-as-creative-space&quot;&gt;The Web as a Creative Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/#highlights-from-the-past&quot;&gt;Highlights: From the Past&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/#highlights-from-the-present&quot;&gt;Highlights: From the Present&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/#your-own-corner&quot;&gt;Your Own Corner of the Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;retro-redesign&quot;&gt;Retro Redesign&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;, I mention that this website is “a tribute to the creative web of the 90s”. This is not simply because this website has animated gifs and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://users2.smartgb.com/g/g.php?a=s&amp;amp;i=g26-37520-60&quot;&gt;guestbook&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; I built it is also inspired by how I built my earliest websites: everything is written in &lt;strong&gt;plain HTML&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No content management systems, no generators, no templates, no themes, no plugins. Just plain markup and styling, the most basic of the basic building blocks of the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t originally plan to do it like this. I previously &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/crafting-a-simple-blog-with-metalsmith&quot;&gt;used a static site generator&lt;/a&gt; to output plain HTML and was simply working on a new design template for that. But my three-year-old node.js setup was now spewing error messages, telling me some dependencies had to be updated and that a plugin was no longer compatible. Because I'm lazy and didn't want to fix any of that, I wondered if I couldn’t just do it all manually instead and save myself the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did. I decided to hand-code everything in plain HTML and CSS, manually link all the pages and even hand-write the RSS feed. And to be honest, I haven’t had this much fun making a website since when I first started playing around with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webdesignmuseum.org/old-software/html-editors/microsoft-frontpage-97&quot;&gt;Microsoft Frontpage&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webdesignmuseum.org/old-software/graphic-software/adobe-photoshop-4-0&quot;&gt;Adobe Photoshop 4.0&lt;/a&gt; in the late 90s and early 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach wouldn't work for a bigger website. But for a small one like mine with about 10 total pages, it has many obvious benefits: next to no dependencies, easy to maintain, reasonably future proof, easily portable and most important of all, terribly fun to work on. I stayed up till six in the morning for two straight days working on the redesign, not because I couldn’t sleep but because I didn’t want to stop. Admittedly, about 30% of that time was spent scouring &lt;a href=&quot;https://gifcities.org/&quot;&gt;GifCities.org&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/web/&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt; for animated GIFs and backgrounds. (You might notice that each page of the website has a different background, including some with &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/china-one-nation-how-many-languages/&quot;&gt;original art&lt;/a&gt; by my friend).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redesigning my website this way inspired me to scour archives of old websites for interesting relics from the early web. This in turned led me to the fun, creative websites that are actively maintained even today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand what these small websites represent and why I think they are important, we need to start in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-webpages&quot;&gt;The First Webpages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web was still in its infancy in the early 90s. You probably know the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had only just been &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/science/computing/birth-web/short-history-web&quot;&gt;invented by Sir Tim Berners-Lee&lt;/a&gt; in 1991 and released into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/science/computing/birth-web/licensing-web&quot;&gt;public domain&lt;/a&gt; in 1993, making it available for free to anyone in the world to use and build on. In its very early days, it was really only accessible to the more technical crowd, much like &lt;em&gt;Gopher&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;FTP&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Usenet&lt;/em&gt; and other internet protocols at the time. It wasn't until the first easy-to-use graphical browser &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncsa.illinois.edu/enabling/mosaic&quot;&gt;Mosaic&lt;/a&gt; was released for free in 1993 that regular computer users would discover the web for the first time. Others like myself discovered it later still when the Mosaic-spinoff &lt;a href=&quot;http://sillydog.org/netscape/&quot;&gt;Netscape Navigator&lt;/a&gt; (the foundation of today's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/new/&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;) and Internet Explorer became commonplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was all terribly exciting. Unlike traditional media, you could now speak back and participate. It was the first interplanetary communication system where anyone, anywhere in the world, could make a page and share their thoughts and ideas with the world. Netscape would later even include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ccsf.edu/Pub/Fac/composer.html&quot;&gt;an editor&lt;/a&gt; that let users make webpages visually, the same as using a word-processor (&quot;WYSIWYG&quot;, as it was called back then: &lt;em&gt;what you see is what you get&lt;/em&gt;). The goal was to enable anyone, even those without the technical skills, to put a page up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you wanted your web page to be &quot;on the web&quot;, where would you put it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You needed a web host of some sort to store the pages and share a public address so other people could visit. It would ideally also be free so you could try things for fun without having to think about it too much. That's where &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19980704165228/http://www20.geocities.com/join/freehp.html&quot;&gt;Geocities&lt;/a&gt; came in, along with other free web hosts like &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20000815052634/http://www.tripod.lycos.com/&quot;&gt;Tripod&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20000229235048/http://www.fortunecity.com/build/index.html&quot;&gt;Fortunecity&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20000815053429/http://www.freeservers.com/&quot;&gt;Freeservers&lt;/a&gt;. They were perhaps the biggest catalysts to democratising the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/Geocities-1998.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Geocities introduction page from February 1998&quot;/&gt; Geocities introduction page from February 1998, accessed via &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19980213154923/http://www13.geocities.com:80/main/info/&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was so simple, anyone who wanted to could create a free account and build a website to share their hobbies and ideas. And share they did! People made websites about virtually everything: music, philosophy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20011004132631/http://www.geocities.com/~intransit1/home/home_frm.html&quot;&gt;art projects&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20010424064639/http://www.geocities.com/spunk1111/&quot;&gt;ASCII art&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20000815075236/http://www.pezcentral.com/pezmenu.html&quot;&gt;candy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://geocities.restorativland.org/Athens/Olympus/1406/main.html&quot;&gt;about their lives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key detail was that most people who made these websites were neither professionals nor companies; they were simply people who wanted to share their interests. Like I did back in 2001 with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20020103123131/http://www.geocities.com:80/gammarayfan&quot;&gt;unofficial fansite for German metal band Gamma Ray&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/gammarayfansite-2001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Geocities-hosted Gamma Ray fansite from January 2001&quot;/&gt; My Geocities-hosted Gamma Ray fansite from January 2001, accessed via &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20020103123131/http://www.geocities.com:80/gammarayfan/&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how would someone go about finding these pages? We didn't have Google in the early days. Other search engines like &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19980214192548/http://www.lycos.com/&quot;&gt;Lycos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19970630113649/http://www06.excite.com/&quot;&gt;Excite&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19980206192654/http://www.northernlight.com/&quot;&gt;Northern Lights&lt;/a&gt; did exist but were nowhere near as efficient as modern search engines. Finding something you were interested in was not as simple as typing a few words and getting to that information in one click.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, the web was much more of an adventure. It was a &lt;em&gt;place&lt;/em&gt; that you wandered to discover new areas, like exploring the vast open seas. A new virtual space that lead to all kinds of strange, interesting, exciting places. This is what the web was like, at least, in our collective imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;masters-navigators&quot;&gt;Masters and Navigators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web was a different kind of place in those early years, and we had different words to talk about it. In an article titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://rhizome.org/editorial/2015/nov/30/oldweb-today/&quot;&gt;Cyberspace, the old-fashioned way&lt;/a&gt;, authors at the Rhizome project make a very important point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today's web browsers want to be invisible, merging with the visual environment of the desktop in an effort to convince users to treat &quot;the cloud&quot; as just an extension of their hard drive. &lt;strong&gt;In the 1990s, browser design took nearly the opposite approach, using iconography associated with travel to convey the feeling of going on a journey.&lt;/strong&gt; Netscape Navigator, which used a ship's helm as its logo, made a very direct link with the nautical origins of the prefix cyber-, while Internet Explorer’s logo promised to take the user around the whole globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/navigator-explorer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Old logos of Netscape Navigator and Internet Explorer&quot;/&gt; Old logos of Netscape Navigator and Internet Explorer
&lt;p&gt;Navigation. Exploration. Browsing. Surfing. The web was akin to a virtual manifestation of physical space. We even had a word for it: &lt;em&gt;webspace&lt;/em&gt;. In Geocities, this was expressed with the notion of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19980704165140/http://www20.geocities.com/neighborhoods/&quot;&gt;neighborhoods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, creatively-named categories like &lt;em&gt;Area51&lt;/em&gt; for sci-fi, &lt;em&gt;Heartland&lt;/em&gt; for families and pets, &lt;em&gt;RainForest&lt;/em&gt; for the environment, &lt;em&gt;Vienna&lt;/em&gt; for classical music, &lt;em&gt;CapeCanaveral&lt;/em&gt; for science and mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/geocities-neighbourhoods-1998.png&quot; alt=&quot;A partial list of neighborhoods avialable on Geocities in 1998&quot;/&gt; Neighborhoods avialable on Geocities in 1998, accessed via &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19980703151237/http://www11.geocities.com/neighborhoods/&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another word that was very common back in the Geocities days that has since died out is the word &quot;webmaster&quot; (mostly gender-neutral, although sometimes declined to the feminine &quot;webmistress&quot;). The idea was that you created a &lt;em&gt;space&lt;/em&gt; on the web, of which you were the &lt;em&gt;master&lt;/em&gt;. You welcomed visitors (sometimes with a splash screen), guided them around by explaining what the site was about and the different spaces available to them (usually on the home page) and reminded them to leave a word on the guestbook on their way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the semantics of the web of yore made sense in the context of how you &lt;em&gt;practically&lt;/em&gt; interacted with it. You very rarely just came in for one specific thing and then immediately left like you might; you usually &lt;em&gt;entered&lt;/em&gt; a website and looked around. You browsed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which takes us back to the original question of how other &lt;em&gt;internautes&lt;/em&gt; found your website in the first place. You were lucky if your small site showed up in pre-Google search engines, but even if it did, it would mean that somebody was actively looking for it. But not everybody who visited your website &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; looking for anything specific. They might simply have wanted to find other websites about a topic they were interested it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way of doing so was by browsing directories, like the Geocities neighbourhoods: lists of websites often arranged by categories and sub-categories. In fact, most search engines were also directories, or &lt;em&gt;portals&lt;/em&gt; as some were called back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/excite-channels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In 1997, Excite was both a search engine and a directory, organised into channels.&quot;/&gt; In 1997, Excite was both a search engine and a directory, organised into channels, accessed via &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19970601223506/http://www10.excite.com/&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest ones was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20010206123038/http://www.dmoz.org/about.html&quot;&gt;DMOZ open-directory project&lt;/a&gt;, based on the original Mozilla directories, whose goal it was to &lt;em&gt;&quot;produce the most comprehensive directory of the web, by relying on a vast army of volunteer editors&quot;&lt;/em&gt;. You can still browse &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20010224172816/http://www.dmoz.org/&quot;&gt;a 2001 archive of the old directory&lt;/a&gt; to get a sense of how it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/dmoz-2000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;About DMOZ page from 2001&quot;/&gt; About DMOZ page from 2000, accessed via &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20000408141943/http://dmoz.org/about.html&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other way to discover new websites relied on a key feature of the web: hyperlinks. You would go to one website and find your way to many others, much like if you go to my &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/retro-stuff&quot;&gt;Retro Stuff&lt;/a&gt;&quot; page and follow one of the links to something interesting elsewhere on the web. This idea of linking to things &lt;em&gt;elsewhere&lt;/em&gt; was particularly common; most websites had a &quot;links&quot; page with their own personal collection of interesting webpages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cross-linking was the main way I personally discovered my favourite websites, which I would then add to my bookmarks to be able to find them again later. In fact, the practice of cross-linking had an intersting cultural element: &lt;em&gt;webrings&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/example-webring.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An example of a webring, about European History&quot;/&gt; An example of a webring (about European History) from &lt;a href=&quot;http://brisray.com/web/webrings.htm&quot;&gt;Ray's Miscellany&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brisray.com/web/webrings.htm&quot;&gt;Webrings&lt;/a&gt; were &quot;circular&quot; collections of websites, often around a topic or a theme. The idea was that you could go from one website to another by clicking on the &quot;next&quot; or &quot;previous&quot; buttons usually placed on the bottom of each member's homepage. These have also largely disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;modern-gatekeepers&quot;&gt;Modern Gatekeepers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, most of the time spent on the web is either &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; a small number of very dominant platforms like Facebook and LinkedIn, or mediated &lt;em&gt;through&lt;/em&gt; them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is so much &quot;content&quot; that is constantly pushed at you as a user that very few of us actually venture out to browse and explore anymore. We simply don't need to. But these platforms thrive on &quot;user engagement&quot;—likes, comments, clicks and shares—and their algorithms are more likely to give visibility to content that generates this behavior. Instead of browsing, the web is for many an endless and often overwhelming stream of content and commentary picked out by algorithms based on what they think you already like and will &lt;em&gt;engage&lt;/em&gt; with. It's the opposite of exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you're not &lt;em&gt;receiving&lt;/em&gt; information passively and instead actually actively looking for something, you most likely have the same singular point of entry as about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/216573/worldwide-market-share-of-search-engines/&quot;&gt;87% of all web users&lt;/a&gt;: Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has become the de facto gatekeeper of the web, an arbiter of what is useful and what should get visibility. Except, most websites that appear on the first page, the links that you are most likely to click on—&lt;a href=&quot;https://backlinko.com/google-ctr-stats&quot;&gt;less than 1% of searchers click on something in the second page&lt;/a&gt;—are designed to be there by optimising for Google's algorithms. One consequence of this is that most of the websites that people get to &quot;organically&quot; are created by professionals and marketers who &quot;position&quot; themselves on those keywords. This means that the smaller, amateur web gets hidden in the shadows of web professionals who design around specific keywords and audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/google-bartending-recipes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Google's results for 'bartending recipes' won't take you to the small web&quot;/&gt; Google's results for &quot;bartending recipes&quot; won't take you to the small web
&lt;p&gt;Not only is Google largely a monopoly in search— other search engines like Bing, DuckDuckGo and Qwant are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/216573/worldwide-market-share-of-search-engines/&quot;&gt;still far behind in adoption&lt;/a&gt;—it is also the biggest ad selling platform. Last year, it represented &quot;31,1% of worldwide ad spending, or $103,73 billion&quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emarketer.com/content/global-digital-ad-spending-2019&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). The power that comes from being in such a position, along with being present in almost all major websites (through their widely-used analytics platform, despite the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emerald.com/insight/content/doi/10.1108/OIR-02-2018-0056/full/pdf?title=protecting-privacy-on-the-web-a-study-of-https-and-google-analytics-implementation-in-academic-library-websites&quot;&gt;numerous privacy concerns&lt;/a&gt;) means it can actively push its own vision of the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this web is quite different from the kind of &quot;small web&quot; crafted by webmasters of the 90s and early 2000s. Google's web has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20190214003848/https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/analytics/&quot;&gt;different set of values and vocabulary&lt;/a&gt; that come with it: personalisation, insights, engagement, conversion, performance, optimisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;commercial-web-of-marketing&quot;&gt;The Commercial Web (of Marketing)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has always been a place for commerce and marketing on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webdesignmuseum.org/web-design-history/amazon-com-1995&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; was already selling books online back in 1995, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webdesignmuseum.org/web-design-history/ebay-1997&quot;&gt;eBay&lt;/a&gt; was launched in 1997 and &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19970605120422/http://www.dell.com/&quot;&gt;Dell&lt;/a&gt; sold over a million dollars worth of equipment by the end of the same year. By the 2000s, despite the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.ted.com/an-eye-opening-look-at-the-dot-com-bubble-of-2000-and-how-it-shapes-our-lives-today/&quot;&gt;dot com bust&lt;/a&gt;, online commerce was growing. This development was natural; the web enabled sellers to reach more distant clients without having to rely on phone orders, fax or the postal system. The commercial web co-existed and grew with the personal, amateur one. The open nature of the web meant that all kinds of websites could thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But today's web is &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; commercial. The smaller web of individuals has neither the resources nor the will to compete for visibility and audience the way the commercial web does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies and marketers understood that the web presented new opportunities to sell more and &lt;em&gt;target&lt;/em&gt; users based on their online activity. They started pouring money into digital ad strategies, analysing how people used the web, what they talk about, what they search for and what they click on. Marketing companies convinced brands that you had to be online and produce content to be more relevant because that's where their customers already were. They invented words like &quot;native advertising&quot; and &quot;sponsored content&quot; (content made to look like a regular articles but are really paid advertising). Companies started pouring money into their digital strategies to understand and alter influence the behavior of internet users to their advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantcast.com/products/measure-audience-insights/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/quantcast.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Companies like Quantcast offer detailed behavioral/psychographic data on us web users, including our actions across different websites, to marketers to track and influence us&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Companies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantcast.com/products/measure-audience-insights/&quot;&gt;Quantcast&lt;/a&gt; offer detailed behavioral/&lt;em&gt;psychographic&lt;/em&gt; data on us web users, including our actions across different websites, to marketers to track and influence us.
&lt;p&gt;With its content startegy, analytics (the surveillance infrastructure that I &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/against-a-user-hostile-web&quot;&gt;spoke about in my previous article&lt;/a&gt;) and search engine optimisation, the commercial web brought a completely different set of priorities: to &lt;em&gt;engage&lt;/em&gt; their &quot;audience&quot;, &lt;em&gt;convert&lt;/em&gt; them and &lt;em&gt;retain&lt;/em&gt; them for as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For them, the web was just another marketing channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to the small web, this commercial web is tactical and predatory. It can dynamically generate hundreds of pages around common search queries. It can follow web users across different websites, analyse their interactions, and use that information to target them more precisely. It also has serious resources. Just last year, companies spent over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emarketer.com/content/global-digital-ad-spending-2019&quot;&gt;over 300 billion euros&lt;/a&gt; in online digital advertising, most of this money going to the same platforms and gatekeepers—Google and Facebook—that sell their ability to better target you based on the information you give them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What this means is that web users end up interacting and spending most of their time on the visible, predatory commercial web, while the very long tail of smaller, amateur websites remains hidden in the noise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;product-oriented-website&quot;&gt;The Product-oriented Website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design of the modern commercial web is also &quot;sanitised&quot;: it is polished, follows conventions and is optimised for efficiency. This is one of the reasons so many websites you go to today look and feel the same. The codes of the commercial web have become so dominant that we have forgotten that the small web still exists and has a completely different priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern web design principles are very rarely directed at regular people looking to make a website on something they are interested in. Instead, the focus is on creating websites that perform well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don't use too many colours. Write short, catchy headlines. Don't let content be too long. Optimise for SEO. Produce video content, attention span is decreasing. Have a an obvious call to action. Push your newsletter. Keep important information above the fold. Don't make users think. Follow conventions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/neil-patel-design.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An SEO person's idea of good design for better conversions&quot;/&gt; An SEO person's idea of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neilpatel.com/blog/web-design-conversions/&quot;&gt;Universal Web Design Principles That Improve Usability And Conversion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern websites are designed to direct user behavior towards certain goals: a purchase, a click, a share or a sign-up. The words, the colours, the message are tailored to these goals, much like packaging on products in the super market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2008 article called by Smashing Magazine called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2008/01/10-principles-of-effective-web-design/&quot;&gt;10 Principles Of Good Website Design&lt;/a&gt; was the top result when I searched for &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://startpage.com/do/metasearch.pl?query=good%20web%20design&quot;&gt;good web design&lt;/a&gt;&quot; whilst writing this essay. There are many others, some more recent, but they all pretty much say the same thing. The author of this one even clearly begins by stating that &lt;em&gt;&quot;[...] user-centric design has established as a standard approach for successful and profit-oriented web design&lt;/em&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the web is not always &quot;profit-oriented&quot; and it certainly does not need be &quot;user-centric&quot; (and I say this as a UX consultant). If it were, there would be very little creativity and self-expression left. The rich diversity of the web would be reduced to the online equivalent of a massive, orderly, clinical shopping mall meant to drive sales. No, the web can just as well be &quot;author-centered&quot;, hobby-centered or even be &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.geocities.institute/archives/6551&quot;&gt;dog-centered&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth remembering a website does not have to be a product; it can also be art. &lt;strong&gt;The web is also a creative and cultural space that need not confine itself to the conventions defined by commercial product design and marketing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-as-creative-space&quot;&gt;The Web as a Creative Space&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the dominance of the commercial web and the normalisation of its code and techniques, it is easy for most people to think that the web is a complex machine. Most websites today are built with sophisticated content management systems, SEO and social media strategies, multiple plugins, detailed analytics and audience tracking, optimized for different breakpoints and served via a global CDN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the web is really a lot simpler than that. You really only need two things: a web host and HTML (and basic CSS for formatting). And you don't need to make it &quot;user-centered&quot;; much like the early webmasters on Geocities carving out their own corner of the web, you can express yourself any way you want. It’s the difference between product and art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A painter wouldn’t add more red to her painting or change the composition because market data showed that people liked it better. It’s her creative vision; some people might like it, others might not. But it is her creation, with her own rules. The question of &quot;performance&quot; is simply irrelevant. It's the same thing with the small web.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the commercial web is &quot;industrial&quot;, you could say that the small web is &quot;artisanal&quot;. One is not better than the other. They serve different needs and both can co-exist in an open web. It would nevertheless be a shame if we only spent time on the commercial web and never got the opportunity to experience the creativity, passion and quirkiness of the small web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To show you what the it can look like and how different it can be from modern websites, I have collected a few examples that I think illustrate the richness of the small web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;highlights-from-the-past&quot;&gt;Highlights: From the Past&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will first look at small websites from the past and then move on to ones that are up and running today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be able to dig up these websites and give you access to them, I am grateful to the wonderful and important archival work done by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/web/&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;, which, thanks to the 439 billion web pages saved since the mid 90s, lets you travel back in time and see how a website looked in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://restorativland.org/&quot;&gt;Restorativland&lt;/a&gt;, a &quot;restored visual gallery of the archived Geocities sites, sorted by neighborhood&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;On to the examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Laurel &amp;amp; Hardy Fansite&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fan-made site from 1998 about comedy duo Stan Laurel and Oliver Norville Hardy. The author has this to say about the website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this website you will find: over one hundred pictures, a small collection of sound files, the complete movie list - from the silent eara to the talkies. Ever wondered what they were singing? Go to the lyrics page and read the text. Laurel &amp;amp; Hardy were the stars but they couldn't have done it without the help of others. You can see who they were on the Supporting Cast page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://geocities.restorativland.org/Hollywood/Studio/5352/siteinfo.html&quot;&gt;siteinfo&lt;/a&gt; page, you’ll notice that the “why” of the website is simply “why not!!”. Why not indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://geocities.restorativland.org/Hollywood/Studio/5352/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/laurel-hardy-fansite.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the home page of A Laurel and Hardy Fansite&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of the home page of &lt;em&gt;A Laurel and Hardy Fansite&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link&quot; src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/link.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://geocities.restorativland.org/Hollywood/Studio/5352/index.html&quot;&gt;Visit A Laurel &amp;amp; Hardy Fansite&lt;/a&gt; on Restorativland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fractal Explorer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A complete website about fractals by Fabio Cesari, (then) a 24 year old student of computer engineering at the University of Bologna, Italy. Includes very clear explanations, image galleries and step-by-step guided tours:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people have probably been fascinated by the infinite complexity and beauty of fractals. I wrote this brief tutorial to explain, in simple terms, how the Mandelbrot set and Julia sets are generated. This document provides an informal introduction to these subjects, and is only intended to be a starting point to learn more about fractals and fractal geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20020223163039fw_/http://www.geocities.com/fabioc/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/fractal-explorer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the homepage of On to Mars!&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of the guided tour of a Mandelbrot set in &lt;em&gt;Fractal Explorer&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link&quot; src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/link.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20020223163039fw_/http://www.geocities.com/fabioc/&quot;&gt;Visit Fractal Explorer&lt;/a&gt; on Internet Archive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The National Coca-Cola Bottle Clearing House&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is almsot certainly a definitive list of every single commemorative Coca-Cola bottle since the 70s. There are some surprising entries. For example, did you know there was an 8oz (~240ml) &lt;em&gt;Dominos Pizza International Expo 1991&lt;/em&gt; edition, or that such an expo existed at all? Or a 10oz (~300ml) &lt;em&gt;English Royal Wedding&lt;/em&gt; one in 1982?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://geocities.restorativland.org/Heartland/2983/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/coca-cola-clearinghouse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the homepage of The National Coca Cola Bottle Clearing House&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of the homepage of &lt;em&gt;The National Coca Cola Bottle Clearing House&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link&quot; src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/link.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://geocities.restorativland.org/Heartland/2983/&quot;&gt;Visit The National Coca-Cola Bottle Clearing House&lt;/a&gt; on Restorativland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NetHistory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the Internet existed, BITNET was “&lt;em&gt;an early world leader in network communications for the research and education communities, and helped lay the groundwork for the subsequent introduction of the internet, especially outside the US&lt;/em&gt;&quot;. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livinginternet.com/u/ui_bitnet.htm&quot;&gt;LivingInternet.com&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is an “informal history of BITNET and the Internet”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're looking for a dry, formal history of the Internet, look elsewhere. The purpose of NetHistory is to give you a feeling for what it was like in the pioneering days of BITNET and the Internet. Hopefully, you will gain some perspective and come to understand the early Internet experience (although one could argue that the experience in question is a lot like sitting in front of a mainframe terminal in the middle of the night with a Twinkie-and-Jolt buzz). At worst, you should find it entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NetHistory has extensive archives of early network publications (VM/COM, NetMonth, FSFNet, DargonZine, Nutworks, The Gilding Byte among others) and “personal insights of the people who were there while BITNET and Internet history was being made”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20010516205238/http://nethistory.dumbentia.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/nethistory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of NetHistory's Archive page&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of &lt;em&gt;NetHistory&lt;/em&gt;'s Archive page
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link&quot; src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/link.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20010516205238/http://nethistory.dumbentia.com/&quot;&gt;Visit NetHistory&lt;/a&gt; on Internet Archive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;joan stark's ASCII Art Gallery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think text art is dull? This artist has something to tell you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might not think so after visiting this website. There is much more to these low bandwidth graphics than smileys and emoticons. ASCII Art has progressed beyond being a simple computer graphics technique and has become a popular art form. You'll be amazed at what can be created by only using ASCII (American Standard Code of Information Interchange) characters. Some of the text graphics at this site are html-colorized, some are JavaScript-animated, others are simply text. All are unique, created by hand, and certainly not the same ol' boring text art that you might be expecting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20010420182629/http://www.geocities.com/spunk1111/indexjava.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/joanstark-ascii.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of joan stark's ASCII Art Gallery&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of &lt;em&gt;joan stark's ASCII Art Gallery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link&quot; src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/link.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20010420182629/http://www.geocities.com/spunk1111/indexjava.htm&quot;&gt;Visit joan stark's ASCII Art Gallery&lt;/a&gt;on Internet Archive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;highlights-from-the-present&quot;&gt;Highlights: From the Present&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As excited as I was to find these wonderful relics, I was even more excited to learn that the small web exists today just as it did back when I was a kid. It's just less visible. Among the projects contributing to keeping the small web alive, three are particularly exciting to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiby.me&quot;&gt;Wiby.me&lt;/a&gt; is a search engine for old-school, interesting and informative webpages, with a useful &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiby.me/surprise/&quot;&gt;surprise me&lt;/a&gt;&quot; button that takes you to a random result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neocities.org&quot;&gt;Neocities.org&lt;/a&gt; is a modern web host that lets anyone to create a basic website for free and be a part of a community where you can follow other webmasters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://curlie.org/&quot;&gt;Curlie&lt;/a&gt; is &quot;&lt;em&gt;the largest human-edited directory of the Web. It is constructed and maintained by a passionate, global community of volunteer editors&lt;/em&gt;&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Ottaviana's Kitchen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website from 1996 is still up today and features a family's Italian recipes passed down from generation to generation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Grandparents were immigrants from Italy. They came to Ellis Island, in search of the great American dream. This was where my mother was born in Newark, NJ. The recipes were passed to her from her mother, and then passed to me from mine. Since I have no children of my own, what better way to pass on these recipes but on my we page so everyone can enjoy them, and maybe start their own tradition with them. So for now, Buon Appetito.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ottavianaskitchen.com/menu.htm&quot;&gt;entire menu&lt;/a&gt; and find authentic recipes to &lt;a href=&quot;http://ottavianaskitchen.com/sauces.htm&quot;&gt;sauces&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ottavianaskitchen.com/soups.htm&quot;&gt;soups&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ottavianaskitchen.com/risotto.htm&quot;&gt;risotti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ottavianaskitchen.com/cookies.htm&quot;&gt;cookies and dessert&lt;/a&gt;, and much much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://ottavianaskitchen.com/sauces.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/ottavianas-kitchen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of a recipe page from Ottaviana's Kitchen&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of a recipe page from &lt;em&gt;Ottaviana's Kitchen&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link&quot; src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/link.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ottavianaskitchen.com/intro.htm&quot;&gt;Visit Ottaviana's Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Europäische Schmetterlinge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a German website about European butterflies created in 1998 and maintained until 2005 by Mario Maier. But it isn't just &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; old website about butterflies; this one is a near-exhaustive collection of almost all butterflies in Europe organised by genus/species, each with a description, an indication of its &quot;flight time&quot; and the corresponding caterpillar's plants of choice, along with photos (most taken by the author himself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.butterflies.de/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/europaeische-schmetterlinge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the page on Melitae didyma butterflies on Europäische Schmetterlinge&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of the page on &lt;em&gt;Melitae didyma&lt;/em&gt; butterflies on &lt;em&gt;Europäische Schmetterlinge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the pages like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.butterflies.de/Deutsch/ainsae.htm&quot;&gt;this one on &lt;em&gt;Agrodiaetus ainsae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; seem to have more information than currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyommatus_fulgens&quot;&gt;available on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;! I originally found the &lt;a href=&quot;https://geocities.restorativland.org/Paris/Cafe/1508/&quot;&gt;Geocities version&lt;/a&gt; on Restorativland and then found this version that is currently up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link&quot; src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/link.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.butterflies.de/&quot;&gt;Visit Europäische Schmetterlinge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;update&quot;&gt;It looks like the same author had a larger website for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; butterflies on Earth that was up until 2018. You can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20180421072253/http://www.butterflycorner.net/Schmetterlinge-aus-aller-Welt.1.0.html&quot;&gt;an archived copy of Butterfly Corner&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Marseillaise.org&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything you wanted to know about the French national anthem &lt;em&gt;La Marseillaise&lt;/em&gt;, from Ian Patterson’s website that’s been up “in one form or another since 1996”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome. No doubt you've come here to see what all the fuss is about on the 14th of July. I think you'll find all you want to know here. La Marseillaise is the national anthem of France, believed by many to be the most stirring of all anthems. Here you will find a transcription of its score, complete sound clips in various formats and a translation into English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marseillaise.org/english/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/marseillaise-org.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of Marsaillaise.org&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of &lt;em&gt;Marsaillaise.org&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link&quot; src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/link.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marseillaise.org/english/&quot;&gt;Visit Marseillaise.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Webtender&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in mixing your own drinks? The Webtender, which has been online since 1995, features over 6000 recipes, a handbook with information on bar glassware, tools, measurements and ingredients, a forum, a wiki and even lets you search for recipes based on what you have in your in your bar!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webtender.com/info/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/webtender.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the home page of Webtender&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of the home page of Webtender
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got the idea to this database when I saw a program called Bartender for the Amiga. I wanted to create a useful web-service, and decided to make something similar for the World Wide Web. Remember that this was just at the same time as the Web (I prefer to call it that) became popular with not only students and people connected to the Internet at work, but also to people at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, during spring 1995 I started to collect drink recipes from various Internet sources, including the mentioned program. One of the main sources was The (Un)Official Internet Bartender's Guide and postings to the newsgroup &lt;code&gt;rec.food.drink&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I decided to let my visitors help building the database. A lot of people make their own drinks, or have their own favourite, so why not let them add it to the database? I created a simple web form that visitors could use to add their drinks. It bacame a success!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, about 1500 of the drinks have been added by me, and the rest have been contributed by visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link&quot; src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/link.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webtender.com/info/&quot;&gt;Visit The Webtender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Distant Skies - A Crystalis Fansite&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fan-made website about an action-RPG game called Crystalis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Crystalis' is an Action-RPG for the Nintendo Entertainment System. It was released in Japan in April of 1990 and in the United States the following July. It was praised by critics at the time for its graphics and gameplay and it inspired a devout, if somewhat small, fan following. In Japan the game was called ゴッド・スレイヤー はるか天空のソナタ or God Slayer: Sonata of the Distant Sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built in the visual style of the game itself, the site provides detailed information about the story, characters, game world, spells and items in the game. Even though I don’t know the game, it’s fun to browse around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://distantskies.neocities.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/distant-skies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the home page of Distant Skies&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of the home page of &lt;em&gt;Distant Skies&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;external-link&quot; src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/link.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://distantskies.neocities.org/&quot;&gt;Visit Distant Skies - A Crystalis Fansite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-own-corner&quot;&gt;Your Own Corner of the Web&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the small web still exists, and is still giving us all kinds of websites to browse through and discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As fun as it is to explore what's out there, the best part is really to join in and make your own website. Not on closed platforms or on social media mediated by ad companies, but simply in your own little corner of the web. It's the best way to see how simple and open the web really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could easily put up those drawings you've been making, share your thoughts and ideas, or reviews of your favourite whiskys. Make a website to share your writing tips or your best recipes. Or a list of your favourite addresses in your city for travelers who might be visiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you would need is to learn basic markup (HTML) and styling (CSS), set up a site on a free host like &lt;a href=&quot;https://neocities.org&quot;&gt;Neocities.org&lt;/a&gt; and start playing. As you can imagine, Neocities is a Geocities-like free web host (minus the ads) whose mission it is to &quot;&lt;em&gt;make the web fun again by giving you back control of how you express yourself online&lt;/em&gt;&quot;. Discovering and joining Neocities was one of the reasons I got so excited about the small web. You can spend hours and hours &lt;a href=&quot;https://neocities.org/browse?sort_by=last_updated&quot;&gt;browsing through&lt;/a&gt; the many sites hosted there, or just get a free account to play with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://neocities.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/neocities-home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the home page of Neocities&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A screenshot of the home page of Neocities
&lt;p&gt;If you don't know how to make websites, HTMLDog has excellent tutorials to learn &lt;a href=&quot;https://htmldog.com/guides/html/beginner/&quot;&gt;basic HTML&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://htmldog.com/guides/css/beginner/&quot;&gt;basic CSS&lt;/a&gt;. If you prefer video, Khan Academy has an excellent free course for beginners called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khanacademy.org/computing/computer-programming/html-css&quot;&gt;Making Webpages&lt;/a&gt;&quot; that looks very complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have no prior experience, it might take you a while to get a hang of how to change text sizes and colours, add images and link between pages, but I think that’s part of the fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could of course always just get a pre-made template or a theme and use that, but it's a different exercise. It’s the difference between buying art and learning how to paint or sculpt. The end result might be the same but the exercise is very different. It might be more practical but is nothing like creating an HTML page from scratch and putting it up on the web for the world to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great thing about the web is that you can always view the source of any public website to take inspiration and learn. Make sure you pick simple, basic ones; the modern web is full of bloated websites that make HTML unreadable. This website, for example, only uses basic HTML and CSS and I invite you to play with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/parimalsatyal/neu/blob/master/essays/the-small-web/index.html&quot;&gt;the code&lt;/a&gt; to your heart’s content. It’s all in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/license.tt&quot;&gt;public domain&lt;/a&gt;, so you can even copy all of it and modify it (and you don’t have to credit me or even link back, it’s all free).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do end up making a website after reading this, I’d love to see it (and perhaps even add it on here): send me an email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:webmaster@neustadt.fr&quot;&gt;webmaster@neustadt.fr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;thoughts-and-feedback&quot;&gt;Thoughts and Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small web still exists and has a lot to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might not be as polished as the commercial web we're used to, but I hope I have, at the very least, piqued your curiosity and made you want to explore it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to hear from you if you have thoughts and comments about the essay, or if you have other interesting examples, or corrections. You can email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:webmaster@neustadt.fr&quot;&gt;webmaster@neustadt.fr&lt;/a&gt;. This essay along with everything else on this website is also on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/parimalsatyal/neu/blob/master/essays/the-small-web/index.html&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;; if you find errors or have suggestions for an edit, you can simply send me a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed your stay on my website. Feel free to browse around; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/retro-stuff&quot;&gt;Retro Stuff&lt;/a&gt; has other relics from the 90s and the 2000s that you might enjoy. And of course, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://users2.smartgb.com/g/g.php?a=s&amp;amp;i=g26-37520-60&quot;&gt;sign my guestbook&lt;/a&gt; on your way out if you'd like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;update&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elsewhere:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23326329&quot;&gt;discussion on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; around this essay has plenty of other interesting links and ideas that you might also enjoy. &lt;em&gt;(Updated 28 May).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;update&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merci:&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks to Mario Sanchez for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/parimalsatyal/neu/pull/1&quot;&gt;pointing out and fixing&lt;/a&gt; some typos.&lt;/p&gt;
— &lt;span class=&quot;return&quot;&gt;← &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/&quot;&gt;back home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/license.txt&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/img/publicdomain.png&quot; alt=&quot;CC0 Public Domain Logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/&quot;&gt;Rediscovering the Small Web&lt;/a&gt;, written by Parimal Satyal on 25 May 2020 and published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr&quot;&gt;Neustadt.fr&lt;/a&gt;. This text is in the public domain with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/license.txt&quot;&gt;CC0 1.0 Universal license&lt;/a&gt;; you are free to do whatever you want with it (obviously doesn't apply to the websites and resources I've linked to, or the logos and graphics in the background). A link back is nice but not required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 17:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>livatlantis</dc:creator>
<og:image>neustadt-small-web-thumbnail.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bash IRC Quote Database</title>
<link>http://bash.org</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://bash.org</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome!&lt;/strong&gt; Browse away to your amusement, and feel free to add some quotes yourself.
&lt;p&gt;If you like or dislike a quote, vote with the + and - links. If you feel that the quote doesn't deserve to be in the database at all, click its [X] link next to it; while the quote will not be removed from the database immediately, it will be resubmitted for review, and it is possible that it will be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions? Comments?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:qdb@bash.org&quot;&gt;qdb@bash.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017-02-28&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Queue now at zero. Fixed PHP encoding issues that caused some quotes to not be displayed. Changed voting button behavior to popup instead of browsing away. Blocking the popups will not affect your ability to vote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017-02-21&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

So, this time we &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; fixed modding. We also changed the behavior of the &quot;latest quotes&quot; function to display the most recently approved quotes, irrespective of the order it was submitted.&lt;p&gt;Managers: &lt;a href=&quot;http://bash.org/?search=Ninety&quot;&gt;Ninety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Moderators: &lt;a href=&quot;http://bash.org/?search=Amanda&quot;&gt;Amanda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bash.org/?search=vx0&quot;&gt;vx0&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bash.org/?search=kastein&quot;&gt;kastein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 16:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adnanh</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://bash.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Guerrilla Public Service Redux (2017)</title>
<link>https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/guerrilla-public-service/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/guerrilla-public-service/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At some point in your life you’ve probably encountered a problem in the built world where the fix was obvious to you. Maybe a door that opened the wrong way, or poorly painted marker on the road. Mostly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/magic-roundabout-circumnavigating-worlds-complex-intersection/&quot;&gt;when we see these things&lt;/a&gt;, we grumble on the inside, and then do nothing. But not Richard Ankrom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.19.51-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5172 size-thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.19.51-PM-300x223.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 12.19.51 PM&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;223&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.19.51-PM-300x223.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.19.51-PM.png 537w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early morning of August 5, 2001, artist Richard Ankrom and a group of friends assembled on the 4th Street bridge over the 110 freeway in Los Angeles. They had gathered to commit a crime — one Ankrom had plotted for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty years earlier, Ankron, then living in Orange County, was driving north on the 110 freeway. As he passed through downtown Los Angeles, he was going to merge onto another freeway, the I-5 North. But he missed the exit and got lost. And for some reason, this stuck with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.18.02-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5167 size-thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.18.02-PM-300x197.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 12.18.02 PM&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;197&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.18.02-PM-300x197.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.18.02-PM-600x394.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.18.02-PM.png 719w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years later, when Ankrom moved to downtown Los Angeles, he was driving on the same stretch of freeway where he’d gotten lost before. He looked up at the big green rectangular sign suspended above and realized why he missed the exit all those years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sign was not adequately marked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.19.18-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5166 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.19.18-PM-600x389.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 12.19.18 PM&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;389&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.19.18-PM-600x389.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.19.18-PM-300x195.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.19.18-PM.png 717w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The I-5 exit wasn’t indicated on the green overhead sign. It was clear to Ankrom that, the California Department of Transportation (known as Caltrans) &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/episode-68-built-for-speed/&quot;&gt;had made a mistake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ankrom, an artist and sign painter, decided to make the Interstate 5 North shield himself. He also decided that he would take it upon himself to install it above the 110 freeway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He  would call it an act of “guerrilla public service.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.21.13-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5179 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.21.13-PM-600x368.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 12.21.13 PM&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;368&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.21.13-PM-600x368.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.21.13-PM-300x184.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.21.13-PM.png 666w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ankrom started by studying L.A. Freeways signs and holding up pantone swatches to perfectly match the paint color. He dangled over bridges to measure the exact dimensions of other signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.11.10-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5176 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.11.10-PM-600x398.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 1.11.10 PM&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;398&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.11.10-PM-600x398.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.11.10-PM-300x199.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.11.10-PM.png 701w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, Ankrom consulted the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/FR-2009-12-16/pdf/E9-28322.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;MUTCD&lt;/a&gt;,  The Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices, which provides “uniform standards and specifications for all official traffic control devices in California.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.28.08-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5168 size-thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.28.08-PM-300x203.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 12.28.08 PM&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;203&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.28.08-PM-300x203.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.28.08-PM-600x406.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.28.08-PM.png 672w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ankrom wanted his sign to be built to the exact specifications of Caltrans, which were designed to be read by motorists traveling at high speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He copied the height and thickness of existing interstate shields, copied their exact typeface, and even sprayed his sign with a thin glaze of overspray of gray house paint so that it wouldn’t look too new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If he was successful, no one would know that the signs weren’t put up by Caltrans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.13.37-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5183 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.13.37-PM-600x389.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 1.13.37 PM&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;389&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.13.37-PM-600x389.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.13.37-PM-300x194.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.13.37-PM.png 707w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a finishing touch, Ankrom signed his name on the back with a black marker, like a painter signing a canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came the next phase of the project: the installation. Ankrom planned it with the precision of a bank heist. He cut his hair, bought some work clothes and a hardhat and an orange vest. He even made a Caltrans contractor-esque decal for his pick-up truck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/2015-02-09-10.19.38-am.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5195 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/2015-02-09-10.19.38-am-600x363.png&quot; alt=&quot;2015-02-09 10.19.38 am&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;363&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/2015-02-09-10.19.38-am-600x363.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/2015-02-09-10.19.38-am-300x182.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/2015-02-09-10.19.38-am-728x441.png 728w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He feared he could get arrested, or worse — drop the sign or one of his tools on the cars driving underneath. But he felt it was too late to turn back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.15.28-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5169 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.15.28-PM-600x391.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 1.15.28 PM&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;391&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.15.28-PM-600x391.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.15.28-PM-300x196.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.15.28-PM.png 698w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 5, 2001, Ankrom parked his truck and went to work. He positioned his ladder over the razor wire and made his way up to the catwalk under the sign, nearly 30 feet above the highway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.16.19-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5185 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.16.19-PM-600x390.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 1.16.19 PM&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.16.19-PM-600x390.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.16.19-PM-300x195.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.16.19-PM.png 695w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole installation took less than 30 minutes. As soon as the sign was up, Ankrom packed up his ladder, rushed back to his truck, and blended back into the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For about nine months, only a small group of people knew that the Interstate 5 shield hanging above the 110 freeway was a forgery. Then one of Ankrom’s friend leaked the story to a local paper. And that’s how Caltrans found out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.17.31-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5186 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.17.31-PM-600x401.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 1.17.31 PM&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.17.31-PM-600x401.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.17.31-PM-300x201.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.17.31-PM.png 695w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ankrom had hoped he could get his sign back from Caltrans after they took it down; he figured he would hang it in an art gallery. But Caltrans didn’t take the sign down. His guerrilla sign had passed the Caltrans inspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.18.08-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5178 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.18.08-PM-600x393.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-02-06 at 1.18.08 PM&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.18.08-PM-600x393.png 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.18.08-PM-300x197.png 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-1.18.08-PM.png 682w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankrom.org/freeway_signs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Richard Ankrom&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than eight years after Ankrom’s sign went up, he got call from a friend who noticed some workers taking it down. His sign was being replaced with as part of routine maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;Guerrilla Public Service 2011&quot; width=&quot;267&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Clgl63CWOkM?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the new sign went up, however, Caltrans had added the I-5 North shield not only to it, but also to two additional signs up the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another guerrilla public service project in New York City by group called the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.core77.com/blog/urbanism/the_efficient_passenger_project_vs_the_mta_is_good_signage_a_bad_idea_26433.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Efficient Passenger Project&lt;/a&gt;. The EPP has been hanging signs in subway stations informing  people where they should board the train to make the most efficient transfers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/0epp.jpg&quot; class=&quot;media-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5190 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/0epp-600x773.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0epp&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;773&quot; srcset=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/0epp-600x773.jpg 600w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/0epp-300x386.jpg 300w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/0epp-728x937.jpg 728w, https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/0epp.jpg 880w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eppnyc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;EPP NYC&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the EPP’s signage has the look and feel of those from the MTA, they are completely unaffiliated. The MTA considers these signs vandalism, and is taking down the signs as fast as they go up — they have also done the same with other &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/guerrilla-signs-3d-maps-clever-wayfinding-nyc-subway-system/&quot;&gt;guerrilla subway signage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Point being, if you decide to undertake an act of “guerrilla public service,” just know that it may not be received as such, so proceed with caution and avoid getting caught.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coda: Guerrilla Urbanism &amp;amp; Gardening&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of other fascinating urban interventions out there as well. Some raise awareness, even if they are only temporary, but others (like the L.A. sign project) have had more permanent effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In San Francisco, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/guerrilla-bike-lanes-san-francisco-makes-illicit-infrastructure-permanent/&quot;&gt;guerrilla bike lane&lt;/a&gt; installed by activists was later made official by the city. A nearby &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/guerrilla-public-seating-sf-bench-project-makes-free-seats-city-sidewalks/&quot;&gt;public bench project&lt;/a&gt; has been putting up free benches in SF for decades as well. The Bay Area has also been home to a number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/guerrilla-drive-ins-mobile-urban-movie-theaters-animate-disused-spaces/&quot;&gt;guerrilla movie theater&lt;/a&gt; initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/unpleasant-design-hostile-urban-architecture/&quot;&gt;Guerrilla urbanism&lt;/a&gt; is not just limited to streets and sidewalks, either — &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/guerrilla-garden-eden-death-life-urban-microtopia/&quot;&gt;guerrilla gardening&lt;/a&gt; efforts, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/eco-warfare-seed-bullets-bombs-guerrilla-gardeners-green-arsenal/&quot;&gt;seed bombs and ammunition&lt;/a&gt;, have helped spread greenery around cities. Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;https://weburbanist.com/2015/10/22/guerrilla-grafting-public-trees-spliced-to-bear-edible-fruit/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;guerrilla grafters&lt;/a&gt; have done creative work that questions whether ornamental street trees could also be used to &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/fruit-walls-before-greenhouses-walled-gardens-created-urban-micro-climates/&quot;&gt;grow fruit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/agricultural-futures-vertical-urban-farms-home-aeroponics/&quot;&gt;feed hungry citizens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Also be sure to check out similar &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/&quot;&gt;99% Invisible&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/episodes/&quot;&gt;episodes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/articles/&quot;&gt;articles&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/category/cities/&quot;&gt;cities&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/category/infrastructure/&quot;&gt;infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;  including &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/episode-68-built-for-speed/&quot;&gt;Built for Speed&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/magic-roundabout-circumnavigating-worlds-complex-intersection/&quot;&gt;The Magic Roundabout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 16:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DerWOK</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Guerrilla Public Service Redux - 99% Invisible</og:title>
<og:description>At some point in your life you’ve probably encountered a problem in the built world where the fix was obvious to you. Maybe a door that opened the wrong way, or poorly painted marker on the road. Mostly, when we see these things, we grumble on the inside, and then do nothing. But not Richard Ankrom. In the</og:description>
<og:url>https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/guerrilla-public-service/</og:url>
<og:image>https://99percentinvisible.org/app/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-06-at-12.19.51-PM-300x223.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/guerrilla-public-service/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Maximator: European signals intelligence cooperation</title>
<link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Maximator cooperation involved both signals analysis and cryptanalysis. The signals analysis part focused on coordinating interception mechanisms and efforts and on exchanging intercepted (encrypted) messages. Signals analysis was discussed in multilateral meetings, involving the entire Maximator alliance (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#F0001&quot;&gt;Figure 1&lt;/a&gt;). Cryptanalysis, on the other hand, was discussed only bilaterally.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0012&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Each participating country was supposed to perform its own decryptions. This is common practice in the intelligence community in order to prevent being fed cooked-up information. The communication channels between the partners in 1990 are described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#F0002&quot;&gt;Figure 2&lt;/a&gt;. Dedicated crypto systems were used for each of the bilateral connections. The cryptanalytical part of the cooperation involved exchanges of algorithms used in various (deliberately weakened) cryptographic devices used by target countries. It was then left up to the Maximator participants themselves to find out how to exploit weaknesses in the algorithms of these devices. Such exploitations are also called ‘solutions’. A common approach was to use so-called correlation attacks on shift registers. This technique became public in the late 1980s&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0013&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; but was at that time already quite common in the intelligence community&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0014&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; – now chagrined by the publication. In principle, (implementations of) solution methods were not exchanged within Maximator. Occasionally, (long term) cryptographic keys were shared, as outcomes of such solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The focus within Maximator was on interception (and decryption) of diplomatic traffic going through the ether (HF and SHF). In the early days of Maximator, encrypted connections were almost exclusively used for diplomatic and military communication. In the 1980s and 1990s commercial companies slowly started using encryption on their main communication lines. It was only from the late 1990s onwards that encryption became a commodity, for ordinary users, in order to protect their online communications and transactions. This completely changed the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early days of Maximator, encryption was still hardware-based. The transition from rotors to shift registers had mostly happened.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0015&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Cryptographic algorithms were ‘baked into’ dedicated chips, and were not yet software-based. There were only a few companies that offered (hardware) encryption devices on the world market. Those companies were mostly controlled by western intelligence organisations, so that many countries outside a small circle received deliberately weakened versions, whose cipher texts could be decrypted by &lt;em&gt;cognoscienti&lt;/em&gt; with relative ease. The Swiss company Crypto AG is the main example; it supplied its cryptographic devices to around 70-80% of the (non-communist) market, while being secretly owned by the CIA and the BND, as was disclosed in early 2020 by the German ZDF television programme &lt;em&gt;Frontal 21&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0016&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, based on leaked CIA and BND documents.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0017&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;17&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the right context in mind, one can already recognise the Maximator alliance in these BND documents. The alliance is never mentioned there, especially not by name, but one byline says: &lt;em&gt;Diese Fähigkeiten blieben nicht auf USA und Deutschland beschränkt; im Laufe der Jahre wurden Staaten wie Dänemark, Frankreich, Großbritannien, Israel, Niederlande, Schweden u.a. in den Kreis der&lt;/em&gt; ‘&lt;em&gt;cognoscenti&lt;/em&gt;’ &lt;em&gt;aufgenommen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0018&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; For those who already knew about a five-country alliance in continental Europe it is clear from this quote which those five countries are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an aside, Aldrich has already mentioned continental European SIGINT cooperation and that ‘ … the Europeans had recently set up their own mini-UKUSA alliance called “The Ring of Five”, consisting of the SIGINT agencies of Germany, the Netherlands, France, Belgium and Denmark … ’&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0019&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;19&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; However, this Ring of Five is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the Maximator alliance: as mentioned, Belgium is not in Maximator but Sweden is (see the Rheinhausen page in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#F0001&quot;&gt;Figure 1&lt;/a&gt;). Besides Maximator, whose focus is on diplomatic communications, there seems to be (or, has been) a parallel alliance for intercepting (metadata of) military communications.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0020&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; It contains the five countries listed By Aldrich in his book &lt;em&gt;GCHQ&lt;/em&gt;. The two alliances – Maximator and the one mentioned by Aldrich – are different but are easily confused.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0021&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;21&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;S0003&quot; readability=&quot;90.717055326932&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;_i7&quot; class=&quot;section-heading-2&quot;&gt;3. TIVC, the Dutch leg of Maximator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wiebes provides a short, first history of the Dutch SIGINT organisation TIVC.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0022&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;22&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Here we extend this account with three new perspectives, namely (1) that TIVC formed the Dutch part of the Maximator alliance, (2) that TIVC obtained via Maximator partner the BND information about the algorithms in Crypto AG devices – to which the BND had access via its hidden ownership of the company, and (3) that cryptographic equipment of the Dutch manufacturer Philips was also weakened, with Dutch (partly TIVC) involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned by Wiebes, TIVC was embedded within the Royal Dutch Navy and operated from the navy barracks at Kattenburg in the centre of Amsterdam. It had separate departments for signals analysis and for cryptanalysis (including linguists). After 2010 these departments became part of the Joint SIGINT Cyber Unit (JSCU) which is jointly operated by the two intelligence and security services (AIVD and MIVD) in the Netherlands. Signals interception for TIVC came mainly from the HF-antennas at Eemnes and satellite (SHF) dishes at Burum and Zoutkamp in the north of the Netherlands. From 1963 the Netherlands also had an interception station in the Caribbean, at Curaçao, with Venezuela&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0023&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;23&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and Cuba as main targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As described above, TIVC was an early partner in Maximator. It was a relatively small, but effective SIGINT organisation that claims to have deciphered (mostly diplomatic) communications from almost 75 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;S0003-S2001&quot; class=&quot;NLM_sec NLM_sec_level_2&quot; readability=&quot;45.861236802413&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading-3&quot; id=&quot;_i8&quot;&gt;3.1. The Falklands war&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Maximator alliance and its member TIVC played a special role in the Falklands war (1982). At the time, the Argentinian navy and diplomatic service used Crypto AG equipment to secure their communications. In particular, they used the devices HC550 and HC570, which belong to the same family and use the same cryptographic algorithm.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0024&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; This algorithm was rigged, jointly by the BND and the CIA, via their ownership of Crypto AG. The details of this algorithm were shared by the BND within Maximator with TIVC. This enabled the Dutch to read Argentinian naval and diplomatic communications before the war started. As reported by Aldrich and Wiebes, the British SIGINT organisation GCHQ had neglected Argentina.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0025&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;25&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; It was not able to read communications secured by Crypto AG devices. When the war started, it asked, under pressure, countries on the European continent for help. A directly involved Dutch source states that at that stage a specialist from TIVC travelled to GCHQ and explained how the HC500 Crypto AG devices for Argentinian naval and diplomatic communications worked; subsequent solution of the ciphers was left to GCHQ itself.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0026&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Looking back, the CIA history says that in 1982 the ability to read Argentine communications became critical to Great Britain’s successful prosecution of the Falklands war.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0027&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; A stronger statement occurs in the BND history: ‘&lt;em&gt;Da die Briten als ständige Trittbrettfahrer dieser Operation angesehen werden mussten (…) darf behauptet werden, dass der Ausgang des Falkland-Krieges 1982 ganz wesentlich von der hier beschriebenen Operation beeinflusst, wenn nicht sogar entschieden wurde&lt;/em&gt;’ – that the outcome of the war was influenced in an essential way, if not decided, by the Rubicon operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that GCHQ knew how to break the Argentinian codes is well-known. As Aldrich writes: ‘How was GCHQ reading the Argentinean communications with such ease? The answer was quite simple. Some of Argentina’s high-grade military and diplomatic communications systems made use of expensive but thoroughly compromised European cypher machines … ’&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0028&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;28&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; A small piece of the puzzle that is added here is the nature of these cypher machines and the route through which GCHQ actually learned about how to break them, namely via the BND, Maximator and TIVC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some stage during the war the Argentinians found out that their coded messages were being read. They could not quickly change all equipment, so they decided to change their cryptographic key management – which makes sense. They started refreshing their keys every hour, instead of every three days. This made code breaking much more difficult, since a short period of one hour may not contain enough cipher text to carry out a successful cryptanalytical attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different stories about how the Argentinians learned about the compromise of their encipherments. The most common explanation is that they found out via member of Parliament Ted Rowlands who revealed in the House of Commons on 3 April 1982, that GCHQ was reading Argentine diplomatic communications. However, another account that circulates in Dutch intelligence circles is that a British pilot shot down by the Argentinians carried information that could only have been obtained via compromised communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;S0003-S2002&quot; class=&quot;NLM_sec NLM_sec_level_2&quot; readability=&quot;54.824234354194&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading-3&quot; id=&quot;_i9&quot;&gt;3.2. Aroflex, Philips and Turkey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aroflex is the name for a successful electronic encryption device developed by Philips in the Netherlands in the late 1970s. It was approved for use within NATO, by the relevant evaluation agency SECAN. NATO allowed several countries to use the Aroflex also for their internal communications, but it did not allow commercial sale of the device. For further usage, two modified – rigged, if you like – versions of the Aroflex were developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a commercial version of the Aroflex device, with an adapted crypto algorithm, was developed under the official name T1000CA, but with the unofficial name Beroflex. TIVC collaborated with Philips in the design of the crypto algorithm for this Beroflex. Both sides came up with their own proposal for modification of the Aroflex. After delibration, TIVC’s proposal was selected because it involved the least modification of the existing Aroflex. Still, breaking encipherments involved solving many systems of binary linear equations. This was beyond what general purpose computers could do at the time. TIVC turned to Philips’ research department (known as Natlab) which designed a dedicated chip that could solve the equations in about 40 minutes.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0029&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;29&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; This chip was built into a special purpose decryption device that was sold to the U.S. and to Maximator partners. The CIA history contains a single line about Beroflex and about this special device to break it: ‘ … the cryptologic could not be exploited without a Dutch special purpose device which both NSA and the ZfCh were forced to procure’.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0030&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;30&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Thus, the Dutch were not only active (too) in deliberately weakening crypto equipment, in good public-private partnership, but even in developing and selling dedicated devices to break it. This story has recently appeared, via independent sources, in the Dutch press.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0031&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;31&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aroflex was modified in a second way, especially for Turkey. This country had bought (secure) Aroflex devices for communication with its NATO partners. For its internal communications Turkey had been using equipment of the French manufacturer Sagem.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0032&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;32&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; These French devices used the one-time-pad (OTP) technology, which is perfect, in principle, as long as one does not re-use any keystream material. However, this is precisely what Turkey did: its keystream tapes were endlessly re-used in a circular manner, where, once a full round had been made, the tape continued a number of steps beyond the previous start position. This elementary mistake turned out to be fatal and made Turkish internal communications readable by many non-intended recipients (including TIVC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Turkey turned to Crypto AG to buy new equipment, a heated discussion erupted between the U.S. and Germany about whether this NATO partner should receive rigged devices or not – with Germany protecting Turkey’s interests. The two (secret) owners of Crypto AG could not resolve the matter between them. The U.S. then gave up and opted for a different route: via the Dutch COMSEC authority NBV it approached Philips with the request to develop a special rigged version of Aroflex for Turkey.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0033&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;33&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Philips complied, as recently explained publicly by the Philips cryptographer involved.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0034&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;34&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; This U.S.-instigated rigging happened via the Dutch COMSEC authority NBV, which is a separate organisation within the intelligence community, that kept the whole operation secret for several years from the Dutch code breakers at TIVC. As a result, critical questions were asked within Maximator about TIVC’s role in the sudden appearance of unknown ciphertext emerging out of Turkey. TIVC was (also) clueless at first, but when it eventually found out about NBV’s secret involvement together with the U.S., it was not amused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;S0003-S2003&quot; class=&quot;NLM_sec NLM_sec_level_2&quot; readability=&quot;37.872376154492&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading-3&quot; id=&quot;_i10&quot;&gt;3.3. Attacks in Paris and Berlin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CIA and BND histories have been written by people who were not so closely involved in the cryptological aspects of the operation.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0035&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;35&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; This might explain some inaccuracies and over-attributions in their accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, in 1991 an Iranian hit team assassinated the last prime minister under the Shah, Shapour Bakhtiar, at the time living in exile in Paris. The familiar story that the U.S. immediately provided France with proof of Iran’s involvement from intercepted messages about the assassination, is repeated in ‘Gedächtnisprotokoll’, the internal BND document dated 11 December 2009, with the addition: ‘&lt;em&gt;Diese waren mit Geräten verschlüsselt, die von Bühlers Firma gekauft worden waren&lt;/em&gt;’, freely translated as: these message were enciphered with devices that had been bought from Bühler’s enterprise, that is, from Crypto AG. This is then further discussed as grounds for Iran’s growing distrust of Crypto AG and as proof of the irresponsible behaviour of the U.S. However, a closely involved source in Dutch intelligence reports that the controversial Iranian messages were not at all encrypted with Crypto AG devices, but with a non-trivial manual cipher. Resulting cipher texts were intercepted and broken by TIVC, and apparently by many other SIGINT organisations as well. The fact that the Iranians learned that their (manually encrypted) communication had been compromised should not have surprised them at all and is not necessarily the reason for them to distrust Crypto AG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reaction to the La Belle discothèque bombing in West Berlin in 1986, ‘Reagan appears to have jeopardized the Crypto operation after Libya was implicated’ according to Greg Miller (based on the leaked CIA and BND reports).&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0036&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;36&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; However, Dutch intelligence sources from TIVC say that they never saw any encrypted communications coming out of Libya based on Crypto AG devices.&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0037&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;37&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; They suggest that the attack may have been carried out by a Libyan hit squad that used its own cipher – possibly a manual cipher too. However, TIVC never intercepted the ‘La Belle’ evidence itself, so it cannot fully exclude the possibility that Crypto AG technology was used in that affair. According to Faligot, the French did read the evidence,&lt;span class=&quot;ref-lnk fn-ref-lnk lazy-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-rid=&quot;EN0038&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#&quot; data-reflink=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;38&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; so they (or the Americans) may be able to clarify the cryptographic nature of the communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;199.36889897843&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. See, for example, Aid and Wiebes, eds., &lt;em&gt;Secrets of Signals Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Internal CIA ‘MINERVA: A History’ document and internal BND documents listed in the references.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. It extends the coverage provided in Wiebes, “Dutch SIGINT during the Cold War.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. On this, see Faligot, “France, SIGINT and the Cold war,” and Gehlen, &lt;em&gt;The Service&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. Produced by the Augustiner Brewery, the oldest independent brewery in Munich. See their website; &lt;a class=&quot;ext-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.augustiner-braeu.de/en/home.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.augustiner-braeu.de/en/home.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6. To be historically precise, there were temporary names ‘Ostsee’ until 1977 and ‘Alpenjäger’ until 1979.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7. Norway stopped its (diplomatic) cryptanalytical efforts in 1965. See Jacobsen, “Scandinavia, SIGINT and the Cold War,” 227–28.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. As a result, Belgium was not ‘protected’ by the Maximator members and bought (weakened) Crypto AG equipment, as also reported in the leaked BND and CIA documents, so that its (Crypto AG based) communication was readable by both western five-member SIGINT alliances (Five-eyes and Maximator). Belgium used the Aroflex both for NATO and for internal communication, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#S0003-S2002&quot;&gt;Section 3.2&lt;/a&gt;. Belgium’s cryptographic behaviour and discipline were problematic. For instance, at least once it compromised its own communications via a basic mistake in key management; also, it voluntarily replaced the (secure) Aroflex with the (insecure) Beroflex for its diplomatic communication, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#S0003-S2002&quot;&gt;Section 3.2&lt;/a&gt; again. There is a stark contrast with Belgium’s academic crypto community (esp. at KU Leuven) which operates at the highest international levels, producing global encryption and hashing standards AES and SHA-3 (adopted by the U.S. National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) in 2001 and in 2015).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9. Schmidt-Eenboom, “The Bundesnachrichtendienst, the Bundeswehr and SIGINT in the Cold War and After.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10. Wiebes, “Dutch SIGINT During the Cold War.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11. Faligot, “France, SIGINT and the Cold War.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12. This restriction of cryptanalytical discussions to bilateral meetings existed in the first few decades of Maximator’s existence, but seems to have been relaxed later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13. Meier and Staffelbach, “Fast Correlation Attacks on Stream Ciphers”; “Fast Correlation Attacks on Certain Stream Ciphers”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14. van Tuyll, “Design and Strength of a Feasible Electronic Ciphermachine from the 1970s.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15. See, for example, de Leeuw and Bergstra, eds., &lt;em&gt;The History of Information Security&lt;/em&gt; for more historical information, and van Tuyll, “Design and Strength”; and Meier and Staffelbach, “Fast Correlation Attacks on Stream Ciphers”; “Fast Correlation Attacks on Certain Stream Ciphers”, for technical specifics about attacking shift registers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16. See YouTube, broadcast on 11 February 2020. &lt;a class=&quot;ext-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q_9dfEX4SfU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q_9dfEX4SfU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17. Miller, “The intelligence coup of the century” and the documents cited at footnote 2, above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18. Author’s translation: ‘These capabilities were not restricted to the U.S. and Germany; over the years countries like Denmark, France, Great Britain, Israel, the Netherlands, Sweden among others were included in those in the know.’ A footnote in ‘Einführung: Die Operation THESAURUS/RUBICON’, Internal BND document, Nov. 2012, adds that those countries learned about the cryptographic details of the various devices, but not about the operation as such, that is, about the joint German-U.S. ownership and running of Crypto AG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19. Aldrich, &lt;em&gt;GCHQ&lt;/em&gt;, 442.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20. Speculatively: it may have been called &lt;em&gt;Fünfgruppe&lt;/em&gt;, German for ‘group of five’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21. Also because the Maximator communications network (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538#F0002&quot;&gt;Figure 2&lt;/a&gt;), was (partly) used by this second alliance too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22. It was called &lt;em&gt;Wiskundig Centrum&lt;/em&gt; (WKC) at first, but we shall use the later name TIVC that is also used in Wiebes, “Dutch SIGINT During the Cold War.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23. Venezuela used for a long time the CX52 M machine from Crypto AG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24. For this reason these devices are often jointly called HC500. A similar device was the HC520, with the same encryption algorithm, which was not used by Argentina; its cryptographic keys were slightly different from HC550 and HC570 and were recognisable. For more information about these devices, see the online Crypto Museum; &lt;a class=&quot;ext-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cryptomuseum.com/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://cryptomuseum.com/index.htm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25. Aldrich, &lt;em&gt;GCHQ&lt;/em&gt;, 389 &amp;amp; 402. See also, Wiebes, “Dutch SIGINT During the Cold War,” 275.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;26. It is unclear why the U.K. turned to the Europeans since its close American UKUSA partner knew in detail about the rigged Crypto AG algorithms. The reason might be that in the first few weeks of the war the Americans hesitated about choosing sides in the conflict. Greg Miller in the &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; writes: ‘In 1982, the Reagan administration took advantage of Argentina’s reliance on Crypto equipment, funneling intelligence to Britain during the two countries brief war over the Falkland Islands, according to the CIA history, which doesn’t provide any detail on what kind of information was passed to London.’ Miller, “The intelligence coup of the century”. This suggests that the U.K. received decrypted intelligence products from the US, but not the method to decrypt itself. However, the BND author of ‘Gedächtnisprotokoll’, the internal BND document dated 11 December 2009, has no doubt that the U.K. got the decryption method from the U.S.: ‘&lt;em&gt;Die Briten hatten die Entzifferungs-Lösungen natürlich von den Amerikanern&lt;/em&gt;’. A logical explanation might be that GCHQ asked &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; the Americans and the Europeans – that is, it asked both five-party sigint alliances – and that the Dutch were simply the first to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;27. MINERVA, a history. Internal CIA document, 2004.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28. Aldrich, &lt;em&gt;GCHQ&lt;/em&gt;, 399.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;29. Some of the mathematical details: solving the Beroflex involved finding a solution for one of &lt;span class=&quot;NLM_disp-formula-image inline-formula&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/na101/home/literatum/publisher/tandf/journals/content/fint20/0/fint20.ahead-of-print/02684527.2020.1743538/20200412/images/fint_a_1743538_ilm0001.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://:0/&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;mml-formula&quot; data-formula-source=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;image&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;src&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;/na101/home/literatum/publisher/tandf/journals/content/fint20/0/fint20.ahead-of-print/02684527.2020.1743538/20200412/images/fint_a_1743538_ilm0001.gif&amp;quot;}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;NLM_disp-formula inline-formula&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://:0/&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-formula-source=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;mathjax&amp;quot;}&quot;/&gt;k=q⋅lA⋅Δh&lt;/span&gt; systems of 150 binary linear equation with about 110 variables each. The well-known mathematical technique for finding such a solution is called Gaussian elimination. Each system of equations involved a matrix with 150 rows and 110 columns, which could be reduced via Gaussian elimination to a diagonal matrix of size 110 × 110. The specially developed chip could handle a 14 × 14 matrix. A sufficiently sized diagonal matrix of size 112 requires 36 = 8 + 7 + … + 1 of such chips. This set-up could solve a linear system in 150 clock cycles. With the chip’s working speed of 1 Mhz the Beroflex could be solved in at most 150 * 2&lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;/10&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;/60 ~ 42 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30. MINERVA, a history. Internal CIA document, 2004.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;31. In newspaper &lt;em&gt;De Volkskrant&lt;/em&gt;, 20 February 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;32. Specifically, the CPP-ME model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;33. This route had been tried before in the Netherlands, for the pocket encryptor PX1000 that originally contained the strong encryption algorithm DES. The NSA paid Philips handsomely – tens of millions of dollars – to buy the rights and remaining stock of PX1000 devices from the manufacturer Text Lite and to start selling a new version of PX1000 with a more ‘government friendly’ algorithm provide by the NSA. This story has attracted quite some press attention in the Netherlands, for instance from the radio programme &lt;em&gt;Argos&lt;/em&gt; (20 April 2019) and weekly magazine &lt;em&gt;De Groene&lt;/em&gt; (7 August 2019). See also the Crypto Musuem website and Brücker, &lt;em&gt;Government intervention on consumer crypto hardware&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;34. Prof. dr. Cees Jansen in a Radio Interview, &lt;em&gt;Argos&lt;/em&gt;, 15 February 2020; see also his own website &lt;a class=&quot;ext-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ceesjansen.nl/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.ceesjansen.nl/en/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;35. With the possible exception of ‘Einführung: Die Operation THESAURUS/RUBICON’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;36. Miller, “The intelligence coup of the century.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;37. Recall that (HF and SHF) intercepts were shared within Maximator, so had any of the partners seen Crypto AG based ciphertext from Libya, the Dutch could have seen it too. What did get intercepted was traffic out of Libya encrypted via devices of the manufacturer Gretag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;38. Faligot, “France, SIGINT and the Cold War,” 195.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 15:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tormeh</dc:creator>
<og:title>Maximator: European signals intelligence cooperation, from a Dutch perspective</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/cover-img/10.1080/fint20.ahead-of-print</og:image>
<og:description>(2020). Maximator: European signals intelligence cooperation, from a Dutch perspective. Intelligence and National Security. Ahead of Print.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02684527.2020.1743538</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hong Kong’s security law is going to devastate its economy</title>
<link>https://asia.nikkei.com/Opinion/Hong-Kong-security-law-is-going-to-devastate-its-economy</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://asia.nikkei.com/Opinion/Hong-Kong-security-law-is-going-to-devastate-its-economy</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;William Pesek is an award-winning Tokyo-based journalist and author of &quot;Japanization: What the World Can Learn from Japan's Lost Decades.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China's announcement last week that it plans to impose national security legislation on Hong Kong raised grave concerns about the city's democracy. But the economic toll could be sizable, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very least, Hong Kong can kiss goodbye its status as the world's second-freest economy, a halo bestowed by the Heritage Foundation. The Washington-based think tank has long fetishized Hong Kong's negligible tax rates, duty-free ports, ease of doing business, unfettered capital flows and transparent rule of law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worse, last year the U.S. passed the Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act, which mandates an annual review of the city's autonomy; if it finds that China has taken more control, as this move certainly suggests, the U.S. can remove economic and trade privileges Hong Kong enjoys. This would remove its attraction as a gateway to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this comes as Hong Kong's economy reels from last year's massive protests -- which may now return -- the U.S.-China trade war and the fallout from the coronavirus outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong's gross domestic product fell 5.3% in the first quarter of this year; President Xi Jinping's new move is only going to ensure more economic trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;align-center ez-embed-type-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--lightbox article__image--inline&quot; data-trackable=&quot;image-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;img full=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-ap-northeast-1.amazonaws.com%2Fpsh-ex-ftnikkei-3937bb4%2Fimages%2F7%2F3%2F8%2F6%2F27226837-6-eng-GB%2FCropped-1590138090G20200522%20empty%20shopping%20district%20Hong%20Kong.jpg?source=nar-cms&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid js-lightbox-magnify lightbox__magnify&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-ap-northeast-1.amazonaws.com%2Fpsh-ex-ftnikkei-3937bb4%2Fimages%2F_aliases%2Farticleimage%2F7%2F3%2F8%2F6%2F27226837-6-eng-GB%2FCropped-1590138090G20200522%20empty%20shopping%20district%20Hong%20Kong.jpg?source=nar-cms&quot; onerror=&quot;this.src = '/bundles/app/images/placeholder.jpg?f445'; this.alt = '(placeholder image)'&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article__caption&quot;&gt;An empty street on the shopping district of Hong Kong covered by teargas, pictured in November 2019: Xi's new move is only going to ensure more economic trouble.   © &lt;span class=&quot;ezstring-field&quot;&gt;LightRocket/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2012, the most powerful Chinese leader in generations has steadily chipped away at many of the reasons multinational companies are headquartered in Hong Kong. His government has cowed Hong Kong-based media into self-censorship; worked to muddy business ownership reporting to make it harder to find out who owns companies; and imposed &quot;patriotic&quot; education on students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During last year's protests, Beijing strong-armed companies like Cathay Pacific to punish employees supporting Hong Kong's pro-democracy movement and ousted Cathay's chairman and CEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xi is &quot;completely destroying Hong Kong,&quot; Dennis Kwok, a pro-democracy politician, told fellow lawmakers. Xi's latest maneuver, he says, &quot;is the end of 'one country, two systems,'&quot; the concept that enabled Hong Kong to run a world-leading financial system without meddling from Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of direct ways the new national security law could backfire on economic freedom in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, it criminalizes &quot;foreign interference&quot; without specifying who the measure targets or where the boundaries lie. Might a Goldman Sachs report out of Hong Kong questioning China's gross domestic product data put its business charter at risk? What about &lt;a href=&quot;https://asia.nikkei.com/Companies/Nomura-Holdings-Inc&quot;&gt;Nomura Holdings&lt;/a&gt; downgrading a key China Inc. company?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International news organizations might feel paranoid about reporting on fraud at Hong Hong-listed companies or China corralling more than 1 million ethnic minority residents in Xinjiang province into &quot;indoctrination camps.&quot; It is hard to see how short sellers like Muddy Waters Research maintain Hong Kong offices when they spotlight alleged fraud at mainland companies, most recently Nasdaq-listed Luckin Coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extradition bill that helped fuel the 2019 protests, which allowed people to be moved from Hong Kong to the mainland, could return, perhaps imposed by fiat from Beijing. What multinational corporate board or startup team eying an IPO wants to have that worry in the backs of their minds? Or the specter of the Chinese Communist Party remaking Hong Kong's judiciary and banking system in its image?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more Xi damages China's liberal financial zone, the more the foreign companies generating millions of jobs in Hong Kong will question why they should stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all before we consider that last year's protest might imminently return, COVID-19 social-distancing be damned. &quot;The reaction in Hong Kong could be intense, and violent,&quot; says Bill Bishop, author of the widely read Sinocism newsletter, wrote to readers on May 21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protests lasted six months and drove Hong Kong into its first recession in a decade. They devastated retail sales in a city that derives 65% of GDP from private consumption. And they ravaged tourism sharply and slammed property markets: average home prices fell 29% in 2019 and have continued to drop since. The declines are likely to continue as Xi methodically morphs Hong Kong into just another mainland city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Chief Executive Carrie Lam and Financial Secretary Paul Chan still have jobs in a month, their roles may be little more than delivering bad news from Beijing -- not just on GDP, but how the Hong Kong that libertarians loved is dying a little more each day.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 15:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>partingshots</dc:creator>
<og:title>Hong Kong security law is going to devastate its economy</og:title>
<og:description>Companies will reject Beijing control and US can withdraw trade privileges</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-ap-northeast-1.amazonaws.com%2Fpsh-ex-ftnikkei-3937bb4%2Fimages%2F3%2F1%2F9%2F5%2F27225913-5-eng-GB%2FCropped-1590136653R20200522%20Victoria%20harbour%20Chinese%20national%20flag.JPG?source=nar-cms&amp;width=1024&amp;height=512&amp;fit=cover&amp;gravity=faces</og:image>
<og:url>https://asia.nikkei.com/Opinion/Hong-Kong-security-law-is-going-to-devastate-its-economy</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://asia.nikkei.com/Opinion/Hong-Kong-security-law-is-going-to-devastate-its-economy</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Boeing cutting more than 12,000 U.S. jobs with thousands more planned</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-boeing-jobs/boeing-laying-off-6700-u-s-workers-with-thousands-more-planned-idUSKBN2332EP</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-boeing-jobs/boeing-laying-off-6700-u-s-workers-with-thousands-more-planned-idUSKBN2332EP</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Boeing Co (&lt;span id=&quot;”symbol_BA.N_0”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/companies/BA.N&quot;&gt;BA.N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) said on Wednesday it was eliminating more than 12,000 U.S. jobs, including 6,770 involuntary layoffs, as the largest American planemaker restructures in the face of the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PrimaryAsset_container&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20200527&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1520068755&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPEG4Q1GZ&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: A Boeing logo is seen at the company's facility in Everett, Washington, U.S. January 21, 2020. REUTERS/Lindsey Wasson&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: A Boeing logo is seen at the company's facility in Everett, Washington, U.S. January 21, 2020. REUTERS/Lindsey Wasson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing also disclosed it plans “several thousand remaining layoffs” in coming months but did not say where those would take place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing is slashing costs as a sharp drop in airplane demand during the pandemic worsened a crisis for the company whose 737 MAX jet was grounded last year after a second fatal crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing said it restarted 737 MAX production at a “low rate” at its Renton, Washington factory. Reuters reported in April that regulatory approval for the MAX was not expected until at least August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing shares closed up 3.3% at $149.52, then rose another 4.6% to $155.84 after hours on news of the MAX production restart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company announced in April it would cut 10% of its worldwide workforce of 160,000 by the end of 2020. Boeing said Wednesday 5,520 U.S. employees will take voluntary layoffs, and also disclosed it was notifying 6,770 workers of involuntary layoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Dave Calhoun told employees in an email the “pandemic’s devastating impact on the airline industry means a deep cut in the number of commercial jets and services our customers will need over the next few years, which in turn means fewer jobs on our lines and in our offices. ... I wish there were some other way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CFRA analyst Colin Scarola upgraded Boeing to buy and raised his price target to $174 from $112 saying Boeing “can weather its current crises and grow over the long term.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April, Boeing recorded zero orders for the second time this year and customers canceled another 108 orders for the 737 MAX, compounding its worst start to a year since 1962.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, Boeing raised $25 billion in a bond offering that allowed it to avoid taking government aid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The job cuts include more than 9,800 employees in Washington State. Boeing said the “several thousand remaining layoffs will come in additional tranches over the next few months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing said it expects to resume 737 MAX deliveries in the third quarter following regulatory approvals before gradually increasing to 31 per month during 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aerospace sector has been hard hit including many Boeing suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Electric Co (&lt;span id=&quot;”symbol_GE.N_1”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/companies/GE.N&quot;&gt;GE.N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) said this month it planned to cut its aviation unit’s global workforce this year by as much as 25%, or up to 13,000 jobs. SpiritAero Systems Holdings (&lt;span id=&quot;”symbol_SPR.N_2”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/companies/SPR.N&quot;&gt;SPR.N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) announced it is cutting another 1,450 jobs in Kansas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by David Shepardson; Editing by Chizu Nomiyama, Will Dunham and David Gregorio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 15:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hhs</dc:creator>
<og:title>Boeing cutting more than 12,000 U.S. jobs, thousands more planned</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-boeing-jobs-idUSKBN2332EP</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Boeing Co said on Wednesday it was eliminating more than 12,000 U.S. jobs, including 6,770 involuntary layoffs, as the largest American planemaker restructures in the face of the coronavirus pandemic.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20200527&amp;t=2&amp;i=1520068755&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEG4Q1GZ</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-boeing-jobs/boeing-laying-off-6700-u-s-workers-with-thousands-more-planned-idUSKBN2332EP</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube actively deletes anti CCP comments</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/palmerluckey/status/1265077232176775168</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/palmerluckey/status/1265077232176775168</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This appears to be a new global policy on YouTube, not directed at me specifically. Try saying anything negative about the 五毛, or even mentioning them at all. Your comment will last about 30 seconds and get deleted without warning or notice, CCP-censor style. To what end?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 15:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>podnami</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/PalmerLuckey/status/1265077232176775168</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Obsidian – A knowledge base that works on local Markdown files</title>
<link>https://obsidian.md/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://obsidian.md/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;feature-explanation&quot;&gt;In our age when cloud services can &lt;a class=&quot;u-muted&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2013/07/31/evernote-competitor-catch-com-shuts-down-its-note-taking-apps-company-heading-in-different-direction/&quot;&gt;shut&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;u-muted&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2014/5/22/5741602/one-time-evernote-pinterest-rival-springpad-to-close-its-doors&quot;&gt;down&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;u-muted&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gadgets.ndtv.com/apps/news/microsoft-to-do-new-features-wunderlist-shuts-down-2224833&quot;&gt;get&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;u-muted&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2012/3/12/2865638/twitter-acquires-posterous-blogging-platform&quot;&gt;bought&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&quot;u-muted&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/14/evernotes-new-privacy-policy-allows-employees-to-read-your-notes/&quot;&gt;change privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; any day, the last thing you want is proprietary formats and data lock-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-explanation&quot;&gt;With Obsidian, &lt;span class=&quot;u-pop&quot;&gt;your data sits in a local folder&lt;/span&gt;. Never leave your life's work held hostage in the cloud again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-explanation&quot;&gt;Plain text Markdown also gives you the unparalleled interoperability to use any kind of sync, encryption, or data processing that works with plain text files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 15:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ericax</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://obsidian.md/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Roman mosaic floor found under Italian vineyard</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-52818746</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-52818746</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;The mosaic floor found under a vineyard in northern Italy&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/2852/production/_112522301_photo-2020-05-24-22-28-02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Comune di Negrar di Valpolicella&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Local officials said scholars first found evidence of a villa at the site more than a century ago
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;A Roman mosaic floor has been discovered under a vineyard in northern Italy after decades of searching. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surveyors in the commune of Negrar di Valpolicella north of Verona published images of the well-preserved tiles buried under metres of earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to officials, scholars first found evidence of a Roman villa there more than a century ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technicians are still gently excavating the site to see the full extent of the ancient building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Images posted online show the pristine mosaic as well as foundations of the villa. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.comunenegrar.it/c023052/po/mostra_news.php?id=1404&amp;amp;area=H&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;A note on the commune website&lt;/a&gt; said diggers finally made the discovery &quot;after decades of failed attempts&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surveyors will liaise with the owners of the vineyard and the municipality &quot;to identify the most appropriate ways to make this archaeological treasure hidden under our feet available and accessible&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technicians will need &quot;significant resources&quot; to finish the job. But local authorities have pledged to give &quot;all necessary help&quot; to continue with the excavation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-46252520&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;'Indiana Jones of art' finds stolen mosaic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-wiltshire-36062538&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Roman villa discovered 'by chance'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pompeii - the Roman city buried after the eruption of Mount Vesuvius - officially reopened to the public on Tuesday after months of closures due to the coronavirus pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greece's famous Acropolis reopened to visitors earlier this month. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p07py85f.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;The guerrilla mosaic artist brightening his city&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 15:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>willvarfar</dc:creator>
<og:title>Roman mosaic floor found under Italian vineyard</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Authorities north of Verona in Italy found the well-preserved tile floor after decades of searching.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-52818746</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/2852/production/_112522301_photo-2020-05-24-22-28-02.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-52818746</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SpaceX&amp;#039;s historic Demo-2 astronaut launch live on Wednesday</title>
<link>https://www.spacex.com/launches/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.spacex.com/launches/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in orbit, the crew and SpaceX mission control will verify the spacecraft is performing as intended by testing the environmental control and life support systems, the maneuvering thrusters, and thermal control systems, among other things. Crew Dragon will perform a series of phasing maneuvers to position itself for rendezvous and docking with the International Space Station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spacecraft is designed to do this autonomously but astronauts onboard the spacecraft and the Space Station will be diligently monitoring approach and docking and can take control of the spacecraft if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 15:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mauliknshah</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>SpaceX</og:title>
<og:description>SpaceX designs, manufactures and launches advanced rockets and spacecraft.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.spacex.com/static/images/share.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://www.spacex.com</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.spacex.com/launches/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>