<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>If you see the cops, start recording</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/5/21281264/protests-police-violence-record-phone-video-right-legal</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/5/21281264/protests-police-violence-record-phone-video-right-legal</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;u02WBi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/31/21276044/police-violence-protest-george-floyd&quot;&gt;Police violence&lt;/a&gt; against people peacefully assembling in the United States is being documented across the country thanks to the combined efforts of professional journalists and anybody with a smartphone. As protests grow in all 50 states, more and more videos are surfacing of police violently and lawlessly attacking people in public places who are protesting peacefully or not even protesting at all. And while video of police brutality &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/06/03/1002587/sousveillance-george-floyd-police-body-cams/&quot;&gt;has largely done nothing to stop it&lt;/a&gt; — and, in fact, may further traumatize the communities being brutalized by police — the current historical moment demands a complete record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fAkgjy&quot;&gt;Justice is not guaranteed by taking video, but we are seeing some results as the volume of police violence increases. On June 4th, two Buffalo, New York police officers were filmed assaulting a 75-year-old man who appeared to simply be speaking to them. The officers pushed the man, who then stumbled backward and fell, hitting his head on the pavement. Blood could be seen spilling from the man’s ear as several officers could be seen walking past his body on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Xx6Adh&quot;&gt;The video was captured by Mike Desmond of WBFO, Buffalo’s NPR affiliate station. (Warning: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wbfo/status/1268712530358292484&quot;&gt;the video is graphic&lt;/a&gt;.) It quickly spread on Twitter, sparking outrage from onlookers. Buffalo Mayor Byron Brown subsequently announced an investigation into the incident and said that two officers had been suspended without pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;v923e5&quot;&gt;“I was deeply disturbed by the video,” the mayor said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wQah9Q&quot;&gt;But before action was taken by city leaders, Buffalo police lied about the incident. In an initial statement, the department said that a person was arrested “during a skirmish with other protesters,” and that “during that skirmish involving protesters, one person was injured when he tripped and fell.” The video clearly refutes the statement, showing that there was no skirmish around the elderly man, and that the officers pushed him to the ground for no justifiable reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a9BdcN&quot;&gt;Again: recording the police does not guarantee justice. And the swift action in this case could be explained by the fact that a white, elderly man both posed no conceivable threat to police and presented a more sympathetic case to the public. On the same day of the attack in Buffalo, New York Governor Andrew Cuomo &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2020/06/cuomo-de-blasio-claim-not-to-have-seen-viral-police-violence-videos.html&quot;&gt;denied that the NYPD was assaulting protesters&lt;/a&gt; with batons, calling the question about it from a reporter a “hyperpartisan attack,” and claiming that “[the police] don’t do that.” (The NYPD &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; do that, and they have been seen doing that across the city in the past week because of people recording the attacks from their cellphones.) But Cuomo swiftly responded to the video of the elderly man’s assault in Buffalo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;kdXb8w&quot; readability=&quot;7.1783536585366&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;8.4451219512195&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This incident is wholly unjustified and utterly disgraceful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've spoken with Buffalo &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MayorByronBrown?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@MayorByronBrown&lt;/a&gt; and we agree that the officers involved should be immediately suspended pending a formal investigation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police Officers must enforce — NOT ABUSE — the law. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/EYIbTlXnPt&quot;&gt;https://t.co/EYIbTlXnPt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Andrew Cuomo (@NYGovCuomo) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NYGovCuomo/status/1268739684504604673?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 5, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fPD7tD&quot;&gt;Black and brown people who are victims of police violence, even when it is captured on video, are rarely delivered justice. But without the evidence, police have the upper hand. Their lies can go unchallenged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;7D4r7s&quot;&gt;You have a right to record the police&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;DMjc5Q&quot;&gt;Everyone in the United States — citizen or resident — has a constitutional right to record police who are performing their public duties. The police don’t have the right to stop you as long as you’re not disrupting their business, and they aren’t allowed to confiscate your phone or camera just because you were recording them. This is the consistent opinion of federal courts and the Supreme Court, which affirmed in 2014 (in a 9-0 decision) that cops need a warrant if they want to seize and search your cellphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;XQ0fNa&quot;&gt;Of course, the nationwide protests are about the police &lt;em&gt;ignoring civil rights&lt;/em&gt;. Indeed, the videos we’ve seen in the past week show widespread police lawlessness, with officers arbitrarily violating the rights of peaceful demonstrators in lawful assemblies. So there’s no &lt;em&gt;guarantee&lt;/em&gt; that the police will respect your right to record. This canyon — between the law as it is written and the law as it is realized — is one of the reasons Americans are protesting in all 50 states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5ukkR2&quot;&gt;If you are worried about retaliation for posting your video, ask a friend who can do it safely, or contact a journalist who may be able to distribute it while protecting your identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;SHw9pw&quot;&gt;Additionally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/21276979/phone-protest-demonstration-activism-digital-how-to-security-privacy&quot;&gt;take precautions&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;GWcuLe&quot;&gt;If you know you will be in public for a long period of time, bring a spare charger or get an external battery case for your phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;Ll8WtF&quot;&gt;If you have a spare phone or device, consider using it to record instead of your primary device. This can help ensure that the phone you use as a lifeline is not compromised.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;FezTWV&quot;&gt;Make sure your phone is locked so that it cannot be accessed if it is confiscated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;06gbZ1&quot;&gt;If you want to learn more, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclupa.org/en/know-your-rights/know-your-rights-when-taking-photos-and-making-video-and-audio-recordings&quot;&gt;check out this helpful guide&lt;/a&gt; from the ACLU on your right to take videos and photographs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3WMkBo&quot;&gt;White people have the greatest responsibility to record&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;s5IL2I&quot;&gt;Recording the police is an equal right for everyone, but it is not an equal responsibility. Marginalized people are more at risk for recording the police than whites; the man who filmed the killing of Eric Garner, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/13/18253848/eric-garner-footage-ramsey-orta-police-brutality-killing-safety&quot;&gt;was persecuted by New York City Police&lt;/a&gt; who took revenge with targeted harassment and imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ksWJZ6&quot;&gt;If you feel safe recording the police, press the button. What you capture could make the difference between a cover-up and the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 19:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tomte</dc:creator>
<og:description>Buffalo police lied about attacking an elderly man. The video exposed them.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/651qcEn90lDgGZJwr3jsLS5kMfA=/0x39:1900x1034/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20020175/buffalo.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>If you see the cops, start recording</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/5/21281264/protests-police-violence-record-phone-video-right-legal</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/5/21281264/protests-police-violence-record-phone-video-right-legal</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>U.S. states lean toward breaking up Google&amp;#039;s ad tech business</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/05/states-lean-toward-pushing-to-break-up-googles-ad-tech-business.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/05/states-lean-toward-pushing-to-break-up-googles-ad-tech-business.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;InlineImage-imageEmbed hasBkg&quot; id=&quot;ArticleBody-InlineImage-105951028&quot; data-test=&quot;InlineImage&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineImage-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visitors pass by the logo of Google at the high profile startups and high tech leaders gathering, Viva Tech, in Paris, France May 16, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Platiau | Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; readability=&quot;118.94634146341&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state attorneys general investigating Google for potential antitrust violations are leaning toward pushing for a breakup of its ad technology business as part of an expected suit, people familiar with the situation told CNBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifty attorneys general have been probing Google's business practices for months, alongside a similar probe being led by the U.S. Department of Justice. Both the states and the DOJ are looking to file a suit against the internet giant as soon as within the next few months, the people told CNBC.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The states and the Justice Department have not yet officially decided whether to combine their expected suits, the people said, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2020/02/07/google-antitrust-probe-expands-as-states-beef-up-staff.html&quot;&gt;though they have been collaborating closely&lt;/a&gt;. Both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/14/states-google-antitrust-probe-to-expand-into-search-android-businesses.html&quot;&gt;have been investigating Google's search, ad technology and android business&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attorneys general investigating Google, which is owned by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=GOOGL&quot;&gt;Alphabet&lt;/a&gt;, haven't yet definitively ruled out pushing for alternatives for its ad technology business, like imposing restrictions on how it runs its business, one of the sources said. A suit may also include a push for both that option and breaking up the ad tech business. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should the attorneys general aggressively pursue a break up of Google's ad technology business, it would be notable. While regulatory enforcement agencies have recently favored &quot;structural remedies&quot; − breakups and divestitures − regulators have less onerous solutions available, like barring certain behaviors through a consent decree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the attorneys general file their expected lawsuit, they have a number of tools at their disposal to signal their intent to push for a breakup of Google's ad technology business. That includes what they allege, the evidence they introduce, pre-trial briefings and news conferences.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Google's case, pushing for a breakup of its ad technology business may be difficult, some lawyers say, because it does not exist as a stand-alone unit easily hived off. And its two main deals, DoubleClick in 2007 and AdMob in 2009, were years ago. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Courts are very concerned that by ripping a company apart, it hurts consumers and make it worse for people that don't have the expertise to do that,&quot; said Stephen Houck, one of the government lawyers in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=MSFT&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; antitrust case two decades ago. Houck is now an adviser to Google. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Google generates the majority of its roughly $161 billion in revenue from ad sales, the revenue it gets from the software and technology that serve as the backbone of that business is far smaller. Its Network Members business, which includes AdMob, AdSense and Google Ad Manager, generated about $22 billion in sales the last fiscal year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://adage.com/article/digital/google-waves-goodbye-doubleclick-ad-business-evolves/314046&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google retired&lt;/a&gt; the DoubleClick name in 2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/displayvideo/answer/9059464?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;putting&lt;/a&gt; its DoubleClick products for advertisers together with Google Analytics 360 to become the &quot;Google Marketing Platform.&quot; Then it put its DoubleClick products for publishers and the DoubleClick ad exchange into the &quot;Google Ad Manager.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the government has successfully fought for a breakup of corporate giants in the past, including Standard Oil in 1911 and AT&amp;amp;T in the 1980s, more recent cases have imposed weaker remedies. Both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=IBM&quot;&gt;IBM&lt;/a&gt; in the 1980s and Microsoft in 2000 concluded antitrust suits without breaking up the respective companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, political winds have more recently seemingly turned against big technology companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/donald-trump/&quot;&gt;President Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt; has alleged, along with other Republicans, that companies like Google censor conservative content, a claim Google has denied. He earlier this month &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2020/05/28/trump-social-media-executive-order-could-affect-2020-election.html&quot;&gt;signed an executive order&lt;/a&gt; vowing to crack down on the liability protections for internet companies like Google through Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending the signing of that executive order was Attorney General William Barr, whose deputy recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2020/02/04/doj-antitrust-chief-recuses-himself-from-the-google-probe.html&quot;&gt;took leadership of the Justice Departments' antitrust investigation into Google&lt;/a&gt;, after the country's top antitrust official, Makan Delrahim, recused himself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presidential candidate Joe Biden served as vice president for Barack Obama, who has been criticized for allowing tech companies to become too powerful on his watch. Biden has said that, as president, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/12/06/biden-trump-is-ripping-the-soul-out-of-america-and-recession-is-likely.html&quot;&gt;he would set up a new department within the Justice Department&lt;/a&gt; to go back and look at the megamergers that have occurred and those that are being proposed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for Google told CNBC in a statement, &quot;We continue to engage with the ongoing investigations led by the Department of Justice and Attorney General Paxton, and we don't have any updates or comments on speculation.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The facts are clear,&quot; she added, &quot;our digital advertising products compete across a crowded industry with hundreds of rivals and technologies, and have helped lower costs for advertisers and consumers.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton, who is leading the ad tech part of the probe, declined to comment. A spokesperson for the DOJ did not respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;ArticleBody-subtitle&quot;&gt;What's at stake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; readability=&quot;62.470711297071&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-tech-antitrust-google-explainer/explainer-advertising-execs-point-to-five-ways-google-stifles-business-idUSKCN1VW2L9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Critics have said&lt;/a&gt; that Google bundles its ad tools so that rivals can't afford to match its offerings and that its operation of search results, YouTube, Gmail and other services hinder ad competition. They also say that Google owns all sides of the &quot;auction exchange&quot; through which ads are sold and bought, giving it an unfair advantage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has argued it competes with many vertically integrated players including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=T&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=CMCSA&quot;&gt;Comcast&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=VZ&quot;&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt;. Data from the St. Louis Federal Reserve, meantime, show that the price of digital advertising &lt;a href=&quot;https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=ph5G__;!!PIZeeW5wscynRQ!4h5PZq3cvBOqmQAOjADAHvNn53kJjgeHN3FKEvQYoylYxqPhAjn9p7Xa_Bo5oL9oqQ$&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has fallen&lt;/a&gt; by more than 40% since 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it remains unclear in what fashion the attorneys general might push to break up Google's ad tech business, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2007/04/13/google-agrees-to-buy-doubleclick-for-31-billion-in-cash.html&quot;&gt;Google's $3.1 billion acquisition of DoubleClick&lt;/a&gt; provided it the crucial foothold into advertising technology. The Federal Trade Commission decided in a 4-1 vote it would not seek to block the deal, ruling that it was not anti-competitive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dissenting vote, Pamela Jones, argued at the time that she worried the deal would give Google too much power by way of the data that DoubleClick provides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;By purchasing DoubleClick, Google will acquire data that will contribute to, and exacerbate, network effects,&quot; she wrote. &quot;As a result, the Google/DoubleClick combination is likely to 'tip' both the search and display markets in Google's favor, and make it more difficult for any other company to challenge the combined firm.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jones added that the combined Google and DoubleClick could get access to &quot;unparalleled data sources&quot; that would allow it to match up buyers and sellers of ads in a way its competitors could not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lawyer for Google said in a Texas court earlier this year that the attorneys general probe was seeking &quot;very detailed information&quot; on the names of Google's ad tech customers and details pertaining to product pricing, according to a court transcript obtained by CNBC. Inquiries focused on Google's DoubleClick and AdMob businesses, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For its part, Google argued in a blog post last year that the ad technology industry is &quot;famously crowded,&quot; citing competitors like Telaria, Rubicon Project and The Trade Desk. It also said publishers use its technology &quot;to access demand from hundreds of partners,&quot; while advertisers use its technology to buy ad space &quot;on more than 80 exchanges.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: Comcast is the owner of NBCUniversal, parent company of CNBC.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 18:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>TangerineDream</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>States are leaning toward a push to break up Google's ad tech business</og:title>
<og:description>Critics have said that Google bundles its ad tools so that rivals can't afford to match its offerings and that its operation of search results, YouTube, Gmail and other services hinder ad competition. Google has argued it has a slew of ad-tech competitors.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/05/states-lean-toward-pushing-to-break-up-googles-ad-tech-business.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/105951028-1559760769619rts2hzoq.jpg?v=1580150072</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/05/states-lean-toward-pushing-to-break-up-googles-ad-tech-business.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reddit Founder Alexis Ohanian Resigns from the Board of Reddit</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/alexisohanian/status/1268943033137053698</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/alexisohanian/status/1268943033137053698</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;That’s such an excellent idea! I’ve always wanted to get into coding. I wish I knew about this last year when I was 30. 😔 Just missed the cutoff at 31. But PLEASE keep up the great work, we need more resources like this in the black LGBTQIA+ community. ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 16:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dootah</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/alexisohanian/status/1268943033137053698</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fitful nightly sleep linked to chronic inflammation, hardened arteries</title>
<link>https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/06/04/fitful-nightly-sleep-linked-to-chronic-inflammation-hardened-arteries/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/06/04/fitful-nightly-sleep-linked-to-chronic-inflammation-hardened-arteries/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_80373&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Atherosclerosis750.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-80373&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-80373&quot; src=&quot;https://news.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Atherosclerosis750.jpg&quot; alt=&quot; 3-D illustration of blood vessels with plaque buildup.&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; srcset=&quot;https://news.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Atherosclerosis750.jpg 750w, https://news.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Atherosclerosis750-410x273.jpg 410w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-80373&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;3-D illustration of blood vessels with plaque buildup. (iStockphoto)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disrupted nightly sleep and clogged arteries tend to sneak up on us as we age. And while both disorders may seem unrelated, a new UC Berkeley study helps explain why they are, in fact, pathologically intertwined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UC Berkeley sleep scientists have begun to reveal what it is about fragmented nightly sleep that leads to the fatty arterial plaque buildup known as atherosclerosis that can result in fatal heart disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’ve discovered that fragmented sleep is associated with a unique pathway — chronic circulating inflammation throughout the blood stream — which, in turn, is linked to higher amounts of plaques in coronary arteries,” said study senior author Matthew Walker, a UC Berkeley professor of psychology and neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings, published today, June 4, in the journal &lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology,&lt;/em&gt; adds poor sleep as a key risk factor for cardiovascular disease, which ranks as the top killer of Americans, with some 12,000 deaths each week — although COVID-19, which has killed, on average, 1,000 a day during the pandemic in the U.S., comes close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To the best of our knowledge, these data are the first to associate sleep fragmentation, inflammation and atherosclerosis in humans,” said study lead author Raphael Vallat, a postdoctoral researcher in Walker’s Center for Human Sleep Science at UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Established risk factors for cardiovascular disease in humans include poor diet, lack of exercise, obesity, high blood pressure and smoking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using statistical modeling, the researchers analyzed the diagnostic data of more than 1,600 middle-aged and older adults using a national dataset known as the Multi-Ethnic Study of Atherosclerosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To isolate the effect of sleep quality on heart health, the study controlled for age, ethnicity, gender, body mass index, sleep disorders, blood pressure and high-risk behaviors such as smoking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers then tracked the results of the study participants, analyzing their blood tests, their calcium scores that can gauge plaque buildup, as well as several different measures of sleep, including wristwatch-assessed sleep across a week and a night in a sleep laboratory that measured electrical brainwave signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final outcome clearly linked disrupted sleep patterns to higher concentrations of circulating inflammatory factors and, specifically, of white blood cells known as monocytes and neutrophils, which are key players in atherosclerosis, researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In revealing this link with chronic inflammation, the findings suggest a missing middleman that is brokering the bad deal between fragmented sleep and the hardening of blood vessels,” Walker said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Indeed, these associational results in humans mirror recent data in which experimentally manipulated sleep disruption in mice led to higher levels of circulating inflammation that caused atherosclerotic lesions in the rodents,” added Vallat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings linking poor sleep to atherosclerosis via chronic inflammation have major public health implications, researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, atherosclerosis often begins in early adulthood. “Unfortunately, this process goes largely unnoticed until the plaque buildup, in middle or old age, suddenly blocks arterial blood flow to the heart, lungs, brain and/or other organs, hence its moniker, ‘silent killer,’” said Vallat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The insidious nature of the disease requires that we pay extra attention to our sleep hygiene, even starting in early to midlife,” said study co-lead author Vyoma Shah, a doctoral student in Walker’s lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To more accurately gauge one’s sleep quality, the researchers recommend the use of clinical grade sleep trackers, because the study found that people’s subjective assessments of their sleep were not reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you track your sleep patterns using objective measures, the same way you track your weight, blood pressure or cholesterol, you can make modifications to your sleep habits, which could make a tangible difference to later life health outcomes,” said Shah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With chronic inflammation shaping up to be a bridge connecting poor sleep to cardiovascular disease, it’s worth exploring its role in a plethora of other diseases where inflammation is known to be a possible factor, the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This link between fragmented sleep and chronic inflammation may not be limited to heart disease, but could include mental health and neurological disorders, such as major depression and Alzheimer’s disease,” Walker said. “These are new avenues we must now explore.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to Walker, Vallat and Shah, co-authors of the study are Susan Redline at Harvard Medical School and Peter Attia, founder of Attia Medical, a medical practice focused on the science of longevity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tips to improve sleep quality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maintain a regular sleep routine, going to bed and waking up at the same time each day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As part of a nightly wind-down routine, avoid viewing computer, smartphone and TV screens in the last hour before bedtime, and keep phones and other digital devices out of the bedroom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage in some form of physical exercise during the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get exposure to natural daylight, especially in the first half of the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid stimulants, like caffeine, and sedatives, like alcohol, later in the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can’t sleep, get out of bed and do a relaxing activity away from the bedroom, such as reading in dim light. Only return to bed when you’re sleepy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get screened for sleep apnea if you are known to be a heavy snorer and/or feel excessively tired during the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consult your doctor if you are experiencing insomnia, and inquire about cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia (CBTI).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 16:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ClarendonDrive</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Fitful nightly sleep linked to chronic inflammation, hardened arteries</og:title>
<og:url>https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/06/04/fitful-nightly-sleep-linked-to-chronic-inflammation-hardened-arteries/</og:url>
<og:description>Scientists tie disrupted slumber to deadly plaque buildup known as atherosclerosis</og:description>
<og:image>https://news.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Atherosclerosis750.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/06/04/fitful-nightly-sleep-linked-to-chronic-inflammation-hardened-arteries/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>CMU’s ‘Penrose’ Turns Complex Math Notations into Illustrative Diagrams</title>
<link>https://syncedreview.com/2020/06/05/cmus-penrose-turns-complex-math-notations-into-illustrative-diagrams/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://syncedreview.com/2020/06/05/cmus-penrose-turns-complex-math-notations-into-illustrative-diagrams/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A team of researchers from CMU and Technion recently introduced a new system, Penrose, that can turn complex mathematical notations into various styles of simple diagrams. The novel system rapidly attracted attention on social media as a promising visualization tool for effectively communicating complex mathematical ideas and concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;22346&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://syncedreview.com/2020/06/05/cmus-penrose-turns-complex-math-notations-into-illustrative-diagrams/e524e78fcb7b055be033b3829e9cd59d/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/e524e78fcb7b055be033b3829e9cd59d.gif?fit=756%2C426&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;756,426&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;e524e78fcb7b055be033b3829e9cd59d&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/e524e78fcb7b055be033b3829e9cd59d.gif?fit=300%2C169&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/e524e78fcb7b055be033b3829e9cd59d.gif?fit=756%2C426&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/e524e78fcb7b055be033b3829e9cd59d.gif?w=950&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-22346&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;22334&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://syncedreview.com/2020/06/05/cmus-penrose-turns-complex-math-notations-into-illustrative-diagrams/image-14-38/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-14.png?fit=1331%2C473&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1331,473&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;image-14&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-14.png?fit=300%2C107&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-14.png?fit=950%2C338&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-14.png?fit=950%2C338&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;image.png&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-22334&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-14.png?w=1331&amp;amp;ssl=1 1331w, https://i2.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-14.png?resize=300%2C107&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-14.png?resize=1024%2C364&amp;amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-14.png?resize=768%2C273&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-14.png?resize=600%2C213&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 950px) 100vw, 950px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers noted that it is relatively rare to find diagrams in mathematical writings, which mostly contain formal and technical language. While high-quality visuals can be useful for effectively conveying mathematical ideas, the graphic tools required to produce such diagrams are not always available or user-friendly, and this has limited their usage in mathematical writing. “There are a ton of great tools for making diagrams, but we found ourselves always either spending a long time drawing them in a graphical interface, or meticulously tweaking coordinates in code,” first author on the Penrose paper and fourth-year CMU PhD student Katherine Ye &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hypotext/status/1268218084453744699&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other popular professional typesetting systems such as LaTex convert mathematical input into a visual representation through algorithmic codifying. The CMU team similarly designed Penrose to codify the best practices of mathematical illustrators in a way that is reusable and widely accessible. Ye says Penrose enables users to create diagrams by simply typing in mathematical expressions that describe relationships, whereupon “the tool automatically takes care of laying everything out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-embed__wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;As a simple example, let's make a Venn diagram. In Penrose, we can just write some code like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set A, B&lt;br/&gt;Intersecting(A, B)&lt;br/&gt;Set C := Intersection(A, B)&lt;br/&gt;Label A $text{Circles}$&lt;br/&gt;Label B $text{Diagrams}$&lt;br/&gt;Label C $text{Venn Diagrams}$&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hit go, and we get this picture. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/y5eGYp9TcS&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/y5eGYp9TcS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Katherine Ye (@hypotext) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hypotext/status/1268218087989444609?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 3, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But unlike other visualization tools that generate diagrams through direct manipulation or low-level graphics programming, Penrose offers more than just illustrations.&lt;/strong&gt; With a visual representation that is user-defined in a constraint-based specification language, Penrose’s capability to separate abstract mathematical objects and their visual representations can also provide insights on the inspection and debugging of user-defined data structures. The mappings from mathematical objects to visual icons make Penrose a flexible and scalable system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the system enables even novice users to create diagrams by simply typing mathematical statements in familiar notations, users are expected to have the necessary knowledge to confirm whether the diagrams correctly communicate the intended mathematical meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;22343&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://syncedreview.com/2020/06/05/cmus-penrose-turns-complex-math-notations-into-illustrative-diagrams/image-18-28/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-18.png?fit=1468%2C708&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1468,708&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;image-18&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-18.png?fit=300%2C145&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-18.png?fit=950%2C458&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-18.png?fit=950%2C458&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-22343&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-18.png?w=1468&amp;amp;ssl=1 1468w, https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-18.png?resize=300%2C145&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-18.png?resize=1024%2C494&amp;amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-18.png?resize=768%2C370&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image-18.png?resize=600%2C289&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 950px) 100vw, 950px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team named the system after renowned mathematician and physicist Roger Penrose, whose eponymous Penrose Diagram is a two-dimensional illustration of the causal relations between different points in spacetime. The team hopes Penrose can be developed into a broader platform for automatic illustration that could, for example, automatically illustrate math textbooks or webpages. They will present the work at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://s2020.siggraph.org/conference/&quot;&gt;SIGGRAPH 2020 Conference on Computer Graphics and Interactive Techniques&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The paper &lt;em&gt;Penrose: From Mathematical Notation to Beautiful Diagrams&lt;/em&gt; and the associated code can be found on the project &lt;a href=&quot;https://penrose.ink/siggraph20.html&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journalist&lt;/strong&gt;: Fangyu Cai | &lt;strong&gt;Editor&lt;/strong&gt;: Michael Sarazen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-120977279-22331-5edaeab79106c&quot; data-src=&quot;https://widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=120977279&amp;amp;post_id=22331&amp;amp;origin=syncedreview.com&amp;amp;obj_id=120977279-22331-5edaeab79106c&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-120977279-22331-5edaeab79106c&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 16:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Yuqing7</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>CMU’s 'Penrose' Turns Complex Math Notations Into Illustrative Diagrams - Synced</og:title>
<og:description>CMU and Technion Researchers recently introduced a new system, Penrose, that can turn complex mathematical notations into various styles of simple diagrams.</og:description>
<og:url>https://syncedreview.com/2020/06/05/cmus-penrose-turns-complex-math-notations-into-illustrative-diagrams/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i1.wp.com/syncedreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/BeFunky-collage-8.png?fit=3264%2C1828&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://syncedreview.com/2020/06/05/cmus-penrose-turns-complex-math-notations-into-illustrative-diagrams/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Slack Removed a Blog Post Showing How Police Use Its Tech</title>
<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/jgxma3/slack-blog-post-worked-with-police</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/jgxma3/slack-blog-post-worked-with-police</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Slack recently deleted one of the company's own blog posts that explained how a local police department used the chat platform to share intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move came after some Black Slack employees flagged the blog post years ago, one employee suggested on Twitter. Slack removed the post in the past few days in the wake of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/y3zvwj/military-fbi-flying-surveillance-planes-george-floyd-protesters&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;widespread protests about police brutality&lt;/a&gt; after a white police officer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/pkybn8/police-radio-scanner-apps-george-floyd-protests&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;killed unarmed Black man George Floyd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;These days, the Hartford Police Department’s intelligence sharing is primarily coordinated over Slack with more than 450 investigators and officers from all over the state,&quot; the blog post read, referring to Hartford, Connecticut, according to archived and cached versions viewed by Motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post explained how the police department used Slack to post updates in a #department-wide channel, and use other channels such as #narcotics, #crimes, and #BOLO (be on the lookout). Sometimes the officers used Slack to track specific crimes, such as ATM robberies, the post added. The Slack team hosted over 450 members across 75 agencies and states, according to the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__blockquote&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you work at Slack or did you used to? Do you know more about how Slack works with the police? We'd love to hear from you. Using a non-work phone or computer, you can contact Joseph Cox securely on Signal on +44 20 8133 5190, Wickr on josephcox, OTR chat on jfcox@jabber.ccc.de, or email joseph.cox@vice.com.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SlackHQ/status/1267825650397671424&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Slack tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;We are horrified and sickened not only by George Floyd’s murder and the larger context of police brutality against Black people, but also by the pattern of violent response to largely peaceful protests. We stand in solidarity with our Black employees, customers, and community.&quot; The &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SlackHQ/status/1267825653769842690&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;company added&lt;/a&gt; that its CEO, Stewart Butterfield, initially distributed a message internally about the issue, before the company published it publicly.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;We commit to following up publicly with the actions we will be taking. And in the meantime, we hope you all stay safe, that the current violence ends quickly, and that this crisis can be the start of structural change, finally, after hundreds of years. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackLivesMatter?src=hashtag_click&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#BlackLivesMatter&lt;/a&gt;,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SlackHQ/status/1267825655548243968&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the company Twitter account added&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/megsa_/status/1267913722204323840&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Megan Anctil, a former Slack employee, tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;is one of those actions going to include taking down the blog post about working with the police that I and other black employees diplomatically asked to have removed three years ago that’s still up?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stewart/status/1267919523350364161&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Butterfield responded&lt;/a&gt; it was, and said Anna Niess, product design at the company, had also raised it internally that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In emails to Motherboard, a Slack spokesperson repeatedly declined to say whether Slack still has a relationship with the Hartford Police Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Hartford Police still uses Slack. It is an important role in information sharing within our agency, as well as some of our neighboring partners,&quot; a Lt. Paul C. Cicero, major crimes division and media relations, told Motherboard in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack has contracts with the Executive Office of the President, the State Department, the Department of the Air Force, and other government agencies, according to public procurement records.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: This piece has been updated to include comment from the Hartford Police Department.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscribe to our cybersecurity podcast, &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/podcast/cyber/id1441708044?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CYBER&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 15:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jmsflknr</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Slack Removed a Blog Post Showing How Police Use its Tech</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/test-uploads/articles/5eda656da2b9e10096464d0c/lede/1591371208426-slack-logo.png?crop=1xw:0.9973404255319149xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/jgxma3/slack-blog-post-worked-with-police</og:url>
<og:description>Slack declined to say whether it is still working with the police department.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/jgxma3/slack-blog-post-worked-with-police</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Unmarked Federal Agents Occupying Washington, D.C</title>
<link>https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2020/06/05/protests-washington-dc-federal-agents-law-enforcement-302551</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2020/06/05/protests-washington-dc-federal-agents-law-enforcement-302551</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;Nearly all of these agencies are headquartered in and around the capital, making it easy for Attorney General William Barr to enlist them as part of his vast effort to “flood the zone” in D.C. this week with what amounts to a federal army of occupation, overseen from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/william-barr-george-floyd-protests-fbi-atf-us-marshals/2020/06/02/6d093d0a-a515-11ea-b473-04905b1af82b_story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FBI Washington area command post&lt;/a&gt; in Chinatown. Battalions of agents were mustered in the lobby of Customs and Border Protection’s D.C. headquarters—what in normal times is the path to a food court for federal workers. The Drug Enforcement Administration has been given &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/jasonleopold/george-floyd-police-brutality-protests-government&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;special powers&lt;/a&gt; to enable it to surveil protesters. It is the heaviest show of force in the nation’s capital since the protests and riots of the Vietnam War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;As large as the public show of force on D.C.’s streets has turned out to be—Bloomberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-06-05/federal-plan-to-control-d-c-protests-has-7-600-personnel-tapped?srnd=premium&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; Thursday that the force includes nearly 3,000 law enforcement—it still represents only a tiny sliver of the government’s armed agents and officers. The government counts up its law enforcement personnel only every eight years, and all told, at last count in 2016, the federal government employed over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ojp.gov/sites/g/files/xyckuh241/files/media/document/fedlawenforceoff2016.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;132,000 civilian law enforcement officers&lt;/a&gt;—only about half of which come from the major “brand name” agencies like the FBI, ATF, Secret Service, DEA and CBP. The Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, which serves as the general academy for federal agencies who don’t have their own specialized training facilities, lists around &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fletc.gov/current-partners&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;80 different agencies&lt;/a&gt; whose trainees pass through its doors in Georgia, from the IRS’ criminal investigators and the Transportation Security Administration's air marshals to the Offices of the Inspector General for the Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. and the Railroad Retirement Board. Don’t forget the armed federal officers at the Environmental Protection Agency or the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration’s Office of Law Enforcement, whose 150 agents investigate conservation crime like the Tunas Convention Act of 1975 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/16/971&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;16 USC § 971-971k&lt;/a&gt;) and the Northern Pacific Halibut Act of 1982 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/16/chapter-10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;16 USC § 773-773k&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;story-enhancement has-video&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;In and around D.C., there are more than a score of agency-specific federal police forces, particularly downtown where protests have played out over the past week, nearly every block brings you in contact with a different police force. A morning run around the National Mall and Capitol Hill might see you cross through the jurisdictions of the federal U.S. Capitol Police, the Park Police, the National Gallery of Art police, the Smithsonian Office of Protective Services, the Postal police, Amtrak police, the Bureau of Engraving and Printing police, the Supreme Court police, the Uniformed Division of the Secret Service, the Government Publishing Office police, and the Department of Homeland Security’s Federal Protective Service. (Only recently did the Library of Congress police merge with the Capitol Police across the street into one unit.) Run a bit farther and you might encounter the FBI Police or the U.S. Mint police. And that’s not even counting the multistate Metro Transit police and the local D.C. Metropolitan Police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;The public has little understanding or appreciation for the size of some of these agencies, each of which has its own protocols, training, hiring guidelines and responsibilities. On the lighter side, few tourists know, for instance, that the National Gallery of Art—home to some of the world’s most famous artwork—has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtoncitypaper.com/news/article/13024443/the-shooting-gallery&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shooting range&lt;/a&gt; for its police tucked away above its soaring central rotunda. On the darker side, the roughly 20,000 federal prison guards known formally as the Bureau of Prisons—whose riot units make up a sizable chunk of the officers imported to D.C. and who represent the single largest component of federal officers in the Justice Department—are concerning to see on the streets in part because they’re largely untrained in civilian law enforcement; they normally &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DebGoldenDC/status/1268308485160214528&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;operate&lt;/a&gt; in a controlled environment behind bars with sharply limited civil liberties and use-of-force policies that would never fly in a civilian environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;There are more gun-carrying agents employed across the federal government by inspectors general—the quasi-independent watchdogs responsible for rooting out fraud and abuse of taxpayer dollars—than there are ATF agents nationwide; the roughly 4,000 inspector general agents nationwide, in fact, is roughly equivalent to the entire size of the DEA. The Department of Veterans Affairs’ police department, who guard the nation’s veteran hospitals, facilities and cemeteries, is larger than the entire U.S. Marshals Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;Beyond those 132,000 federal civilian law enforcement, the U.S. has tens of thousands of military law enforcement officers, including military police units and investigators like the 2,000 agents of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations, the 1,200 agents of the Naval Criminal Investigative Service or the 900 agents of the Army’s Criminal Investigation Division. Plus, the 40,000 armed personnel of the U.S. Coast Guard, which has broad law enforcement powers on the nation’s rivers, lakes and oceans, but is counted as part of the military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;Then there are the officers who can be spotted across Northern Virginia in white marked patrol vehicles labeled only as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/b5/CIA_Security_Protective_Service_Police_Ford_Taurus_PI.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;United States Police&lt;/a&gt;,” the purposefully vague public name given to what is formally known as the CIA’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/careers/search-jobs/support-professional/security-protective-officer.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Security Protective Services&lt;/a&gt;, who provide security to the CIA and the Office of Director of National Intelligence. They carry weapons, but have limited law enforcement authority. (As one agent told me, only half-joking, “We can’t arrest you, but we can kill you.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;The list of crimes these agents and officers collectively enforce is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.ca/How-Become-Federal-Criminal-Illustrated/dp/1982112514&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;endless&lt;/a&gt;, so much that a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CrimeADay?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tongue-in-cheek Twitter feed&lt;/a&gt; daily shares the most obscure federal criminal penalties. One of this week’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CrimeADay/status/1268337109896749059&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;: “21 USC §331, 333, 343 &amp;amp; 21 CFR §150.160(b)(2) make it a federal crime to sell jam made from a combination of more than five fruits.” It’s hard to even say who might even be in charge of enforcing that one—perhaps the agents of the Food and Drug Administration Office of Criminal Investigations? (You should check out its “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fda.gov/inspections-compliance-enforcement-and-criminal-investigations/office-criminal-investigations-most-wanted-fugitives/office-criminal-investigations-oci-most-wanted-fugitives#jumaine&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Most Wanted&lt;/a&gt;” page, in case you happen to have seen Cellou Jumaine, wanted for importing 990,000 counterfeit tubes of Colgate toothpaste.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;The Justice Department can’t even come up with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052702304319804576389601079728920&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reliable count&lt;/a&gt; of the number of federal crimes on the books to enforce; it’s somewhere north of 3,000 but federal law is so voluminous and convoluted that no one has really tried to count it since 1982. When I was writing a history of the FBI, the bureau couldn’t even tell me the total number of criminal provisions it was specifically responsible for enforcing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;Many federal agencies have broad law enforcement powers—and can end up enforcing laws that wouldn’t on the surface appear to have much to do with their stated &lt;em&gt;raison d’etre&lt;/em&gt;. Fun fact: The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2009/04/25/AR2009042503121.html?hpid=topnews&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vast majority&lt;/a&gt; of the total arrests made by the Pentagon police, formally known as the Pentagon Force Protection Agency, are for drunk driving. Roughly every two or three days, an intoxicated driver gets lost in the maze of interstate roads around the Defense Department headquarters and takes a wrong turn into one of its parking lots. Such incidents account for as many as four out of five arrests the PFPA make annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;The rise of so many specialized federal forces—and so many federal law enforcement officers overall—is a relatively recent phenomenon; the FBI was unarmed until the mid-1930s and modern incarnations of the DEA and ATF, for example, were only founded in the 1970s, as part of President Richard Nixon’s law and order push. Historically, it’s not altogether surprising that many of the personnel on D.C.’s streets this week have come from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CBPMarkMorgan/status/1267958057457377280&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Border Patrol&lt;/a&gt; and the Bureau of Prisons, which have long served as the nation’s “surge” national police force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;What is surprising is that those two agencies now facing down Black Lives Matter and crowds protesting systemic racism historically have been enlisted by the federal government to &lt;em&gt;protect&lt;/em&gt; blacks against white protesters. Attorney General Robert F. Kennedy, for instance, deputized officers from the Border Patrol and the Bureau of Prisons to work as U.S. marshals and secure the University of Mississippi in 1962 to protect James Meredith as he enrolled at the school after desegregation. Similarly, the Border Patrol once watched over the Freedom Riders in Alabama and Mississippi in the 1960s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;The biggest—and most troubling—shift in the makeup of federal law enforcement has come in the decades after 9/11, as the number of armed personnel has surged, law enforcement agencies have proliferated and oversight reins have loosened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;Whereas for years, the Department of Justice—which typically has strict oversight regimes and whose leadership is made up primarily of lawyers and prosecutors—accounted for the bulk of federal officers and agents, the post-9/11 growth of DHS has meant that it alone now accounts for nearly half of all sworn federal law enforcement officers. (There’s even a special &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fema.gov/media-library-data/1401457809387-a5f389c7b9be8163c27cfad0ee241e00/MWEOC+Fact+Sheet.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;80-person police force&lt;/a&gt; within the Federal Emergency Management Agency, a component of DHS, that guards the president’s doomsday bunker at Mount Weather in Berryville, Virginia.) That shift means agencies like Immigration and Customs Enforcement, which after 9/11 replaced the Justice Department’s Immigration and Naturalization Service, are now instead led by a department &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2019/04/17/dont-count-on-dhs-to-resist-trumps-worst-impulses-226659&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;less grounded in the Constitution&lt;/a&gt; and whose leadership is more political appointees than career prosecutors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;More broadly, though, many federal agencies exist with little sustained oversight and continue to struggle with training, recruiting and use of force incidents. The Department of the Interior’s Park Police, one of the agencies that has served as the front ranks of the riot security in Lafayette Park, has long been one of the capital region’s most troubled law enforcement entities, with complaints and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/crime-law/2020/02/07/park-police-changed-their-policies-use-force-pursuits-after-officers-chased-killed-motorist-bijan-ghaisar/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;questions&lt;/a&gt; about its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/public-safety/us-park-police-officers-will-not-face-charges-in-shooting-of-bijan-ghaisar/2019/11/14/1497a788-f1ab-11e9-89eb-ec56cd414732_story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;use of force&lt;/a&gt; and even a five-year-long lawsuit over the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courthousenews.com/d-c-circuit-rules-for-fired-park-police-chief/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;firing&lt;/a&gt; of its police chief after she complained about inadequate staffing. (This week, D.C. Mayor Muriel Bowser, who thanks to the District’s odd nonstate status finds herself in the odd position of not controlling the police forces patrolling her own city, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcwashington.com/news/local/mpd-mayor-distinguish-dc-officers-actions-from-federal-police/2320804/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blasted&lt;/a&gt; the U.S. Park Police and officers from the Secret Service—normally tasked with guarding the White House and foreign embassies in D.C.—for clearing Lafayette Park Monday night to allow Trump to walk across the street for a photo op at St. John’s church.) The Federal Protective Service, which oversees security at 9,000 federal buildings across the country, has been reorganized and reshuffled numerous times since 9/11, rarely spending more than a few years in the same box on DHS org charts. And after a hiring surge caused it to lower recruiting standards, CBP has struggled with a decade of rampant crime and corruption in its own ranks—so much so that for most of the past decade, a CBP officer or agent was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/07/2016-donald-trump-mexico-us-border-patrol-immigration-undocumented-illegal-customs-texas-rio-grande-214060&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;arrested&lt;/a&gt; on average every single day—and its use of force has been widely criticized, even by professional policing organizations. (For a period of time during the Obama administration, the FBI actually declared CBP’s corruption was the nation’s biggest threat at the border.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;The Bureau of Prisons has been dogged for years with questions about its management, training and tactics. Amid the protests in Minneapolis after the killing of George Floyd, a federal inmate also with the last name Floyd (no relation) died this week in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2020/06/04/us/jamel-floyd-brooklyn-prison-death-pepper-spray/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;encounter&lt;/a&gt; with guards in New York City after being pepper-sprayed in his cell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;Similarly, watchdogs have complained for years about the odd status of the U.S. Marshals Service, a federal agency with roots in the frontier and Wild West that today is in charge of protecting courts and judges, securing federal prisoners and hunting fugitives. The national service is still led across the country by 94 local politically appointed marshals whose posts are handed out as favors, not because of their law enforcement acumen. (The &lt;em&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/em&gt; once famously surveilled for 10 days the U.S. marshal in Massachusetts, appointed after a stint on the security detail of the state’s governor, and found he worked an average of only &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.boston.com/news/local/articles/2004/10/26/us_marshal_gets_full_time_pay_for_a_few_hours_work?pg=full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;four hours a day&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;Under the Trump administration, Cabinet officials have come under scrutiny for using the government’s law enforcement agents as a sort of Praetorian Guard: EPA Administrator Scott Pruitt resigned amid scandals that included his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/9/5/17819548/epa-scott-pruitt-inspector-security-detail&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;unprecedented&lt;/a&gt; 20-agent round-the-clock security detail, who picked up his dry cleaning and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/energy-environment/wp/2018/06/07/pruitt-enlisted-security-detail-in-picking-up-dry-cleaning-moisturizing-lotion/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;moisturizing lotion&lt;/a&gt;; Education Secretary Betsy Devos is protected by a detail of U.S. marshals at a cost of roughly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2019/10/01/betsy-devos-security-detail-cost-015986&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$500,000 a month&lt;/a&gt;, and Secretary of State Mike Pompeo is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/07/01/politics/pompeo-democrats-whistleblower-claims/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;under investigation&lt;/a&gt; after a whistleblower complained he was using his Diplomatic Security Service agents to pick up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/07/01/politics/pompeo-democrats-whistleblower-claims/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chinese food&lt;/a&gt; or look after his dog. Even obscure Cabinet secretaries who could pass all-but unnoticed on any street in the country now warrant security: Want to be the special-agent-in-charge of guarding the Agriculture secretary? &lt;a href=&quot;https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:h0tv3_F-Zi8J:https://aghires.com/jobs/supervisory-administrative-management-specialist-in-washington-d-c-washington-d-c-us/+&amp;amp;cd=6&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ct=clnk&amp;amp;gl=us&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Executive Protective Operations Division of the USDA’s Office of Safety, Security and Protection is hiring&lt;/a&gt; right now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;Concerningly, under the Trump administration, many of these agencies have been rudderless—overseen by rotating series of acting officials. More than half of all federal civilian law enforcement right now is being led by temporary acting officials, everything from ICE and CBP to DEA. (That calculation doesn’t even count the thousands of special agents in inspectors general offices that have recently seen an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2020/05/19/trumps-firing-inspector-general-investigating-mike-pompeo-grows-even-more-suspicious/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;administrationwide purge&lt;/a&gt; of the government’s watchdogs.) The Bureau of Prisons was being overseen by an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/story/2019/08/19/prisons-chief-removed-jeffrey-epstein-death-1468530#:~:text=Hurwitz%20is%20a%20longtime%20bureaucrat,General%20Jeff%20Sessions%20in%202018.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;acting director&lt;/a&gt; last summer when Jeffrey Epstein managed to commit suicide while supposedly under strict monitoring. The DEA, with its special temporary powers for the protests, is currently led by an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dea.gov/press-releases/2020/05/19/attorney-general-barr-announces-timothy-j-shea-new-acting-administrator&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;acting administrator&lt;/a&gt; who has been on the job for just days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;Such leadership voids are not solely a recent problem of the Trump administration: Thanks to pressure from the National Rifle Association on Republican lawmakers about the agency’s firearms investigations, the ATF has had a Senate-confirmed director for a total of only two years since 2003. Last month, the Trump administration &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vermontgmg/status/1263466201629495297&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;withdrew&lt;/a&gt; its most recent nominee to be ATF director, Chuck Canterbury, a former police union leader who had been deemed by Republican senators as too liberal on guns. (Yes, you read that right: The former head of the Fraternal Order of Police was considered too liberal for the GOP.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;The proliferation of federal officers across government—and the proliferation of watchdogs watching those government agencies—means that you might one day be woken up by a SWAT team-style raid by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heritage.org/crime-and-justice/commentary/beware-the-us-education-department-swat-team&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Department of Education&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_ca/article/xd5q9k/even-the-epa-is-using-swat-teams-now&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;EPA&lt;/a&gt;. And the number keeps growing: Congress was surprised when the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction—known as SIGAR—began procuring its own ammunition, flashing lights and body armor for its special agents. Just like its laws, there are too many federal agents for the government to keep track of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; story-text__paragraph&quot;&gt;The Covid-19 pandemic has even spawned what will apparently be the nation’s newest federal investigator: The Senate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/brian-miller-confirmed-as-pandemic-special-inspector-general-in-partisan-vote/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;confirmed on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/05/us/politics/inspector-general-coronavirus-stimulus.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;special inspector general&lt;/a&gt; to oversee the $500 billion pandemic recovery spending. He, presumably, will be recruiting his own agents and equipment soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 13:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Kapura</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Story Behind Bill Barr’s Unmarked Federal Agents</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2020/06/05/protests-washington-dc-federal-agents-law-enforcement-302551</og:url>
<og:description>The motley assortment of police currently occupying Washington, D.C., is a window into the vast, complicated, obscure world of federal law enforcement.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.politico.com/54/7e/73ff5a54470da06b44a540dea273/200604-policie-gty-773.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2020/06/05/protests-washington-dc-federal-agents-law-enforcement-302551</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>There Are No Bugs, Just TODOs</title>
<link>https://almad.blog/essays/no-bugs-just-todos/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://almad.blog/essays/no-bugs-just-todos/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;One of my life’s traumas is the bug trackers, the issue trackers, the project management tools. The toolset that completes the version control log to form the development equivalent of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Double-entry_bookkeeping&quot;&gt;double-entry bookkeeping&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with its accounting equivalent, those tools are actually useful indeed. While we collectively learned to avoid the CEO MBAs that run a company only based on its accounting books and disregard the underlying business. I think we haven’t learned to avoid managers who only run software development through tickets and disregard the underlying software delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issue tracking became an industry, its software gained consciousness and started becoming a social network, apparently optimizing engagement and time spent in a product as opposed to helping you get things done. This is often coupled with people whose job security is tied to making sure projects are complicated enough to require a project manager&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;/&gt; to run them and the amount of resulting paperwork is mind-boggling. The wide-spread acceptance of this state is what brought Jira creators public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t disprove the existence of reasonably-configured and fast Jira, but I am yet to experience it—and I’ve been trying hard. In one of my jobs, we pushed Trello&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;/&gt; to the limits and in response, the corporate veterans were pushing for Jira hard. I’ve been ensured the product is now a completely different thing I remember. Well, few months (and some well-paid, fine-tuned configurations) later, I saw the same turn-based accounting strategy that I remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to blame any particular product, but rather what people ask from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-minimal-skeleton&quot;&gt;The Minimal Skeleton&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there are relatively few properties that are needed in an issue and relatively few rules to make the handling efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ownership&quot;&gt;Ownership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critically, the issue needs to find its way to someone who can get it done. This is usually done by putting it to the correct board, but can be tricky in larger companies and often needs a reliable triage by someone from within engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a “component” attribute that I passionately dislike. If “components” are created by engineers, they are often arbitrary, they don’t survive refactoring and can lead to dilution of responsibilities over time. If they are created by product owners, they correspond to customer perception and not necessarily to the internal structure, and the translation layer is needed. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assign to a single person&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;/&gt;. If you don’t know who that is, there should be no owner and there should be a clearly assigned person (we used current oncall agent) to process them and assign accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;position-in-a-queue&quot;&gt;Position In a Queue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the single most important thing for a project organization. &lt;strong&gt;Every team must have a single ordered queue of tasks&lt;/strong&gt;. A lot of project management chaos arises when an engineer has multiple queues to pick from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happens often and in opaque form. Of course noone intentionally scatters tasks around. But in practice, there is planning that assigns tickets in priority buckets (like high, medium, low) with unclear sorting inside them. Then a high-priority customer ticket comes in. Then there is an incident. And then we have the internal bug tracker, but also a list of Github issues, and we decided to do both at once. Also, I just got an email from our marketing guy about a typo on our page. Does this paragraph feel confusing? Exactly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a way to put all of those into a single place and make sure &lt;em&gt;every single one of them is prioritized relatively&lt;/em&gt;. When sitting down to computer and achieving flow, there should be one top item just looking at them to pick up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the flow is more complicated, there should be an algorithm that everybody should agree on. An example may be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If there is downtime, it’s the top priority of everyone affected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is an incident, it’s the top priority for an on-call agent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My deployed issue waiting for my verification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewed pull request waiting for deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My pull request with completed code review that requested changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outstanding pull request waiting for code review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer escalation received through email. For valid ones, create incident and delegate to on-call. For invalid ones, reply, apologize and provide customer support link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top issue in the sprint backlogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any issue in the “when engineers have time” backlog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;state&quot;&gt;State&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where things go ugly. The possible ticket states are often designed by architects and not by people who are actually going to use the thing. I’ve seen a map of issue state transitions that definitely looked Turing-complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I advise to start with the “Todo”, “Doing” and “Done” triad and only add more if absolutely required. Moving issues from one state to another needs to be associated with an explicit action. If you add more, make sure that you have an explicit agreement with everyone that the &lt;em&gt;latest-stage ticket has the highest priority&lt;/em&gt; unless you are going to get all tickets stuck in the most boring stage, such as “verification”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;task-breakdown&quot;&gt;Task Breakdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every ticket with a state should correspond to a single deployment (which is not large in the continuous delivery environment). If it’s larger, it should be broken down into a sub ticket and the relationship between those two should be recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-anti-patterns&quot;&gt;The Anti-Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it. If you really scale, you may need a few more…but fewer than you think. While the following attributes are common, they most definitely shouldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;priority&quot;&gt;Priority&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no absolute priority of an issue, only a relative priority to other issues&lt;/strong&gt;. Once you start assigning priorities from a list, anything else than “Highest” is a passive-aggressive&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;/&gt; way of saying “No”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If priority is just an attributed with a list of values, it becomes the most abused field very quickly. Sooner or later, you will also start adding additional “really highest highest immediate” priorities, also known as “CEO called”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resist the temptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ticket-type&quot;&gt;Ticket Type&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The type is usually a list that contains values like “Enhancement”, “Bug”, “Task” and “Documentation”. My question would be: why do you want to have this information and what is it going to be used for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “Type” field led to one of the most unproductive discussions of my life. The “it’s not a bug, it’s a feature” saying means I am probably not alone. &lt;strong&gt;We collectively shouldn’t care&lt;/strong&gt;. When people scream “this is a bug”, it is irrelevant what it is caused by. It is a scream of a significant expectation mismatch. The team should work on resolving it, regardless of whether it was caused by a developer diverging from the designed intent or because of the original intent going wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant pushes for this field I have experienced from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfectionists who like to procrastinate by sorting things While I support everyone in having hobbies, it is unfortunate if the team suffers because of it. Find a way to agree on the usefulness and help the perfectionists manage the imperfections. I recommend buying them a portable zen garden to compensate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top-level managers who like pie charts. This is often to compare the quality of the teams by comparing the number of defects they create. The only thing that remains is to tie your bonuses to it and you can make “this is a feature, not a bug” saying your official company anthem&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;/&gt;. In a less dysfunctional and more valid case, it is to estimate “how much effort we are burning for upkeep versus developing new things”, which I find valid in certain circumstances—but then “upkeep” and “new” should be the ticket types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers. “Bug” is used to mean either “high priority” or “your fault, fix it and don’t even try to bill us”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whenever the push comes, pay attention and dig out the actual root cause for the request which is better resolved by other means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;software-version&quot;&gt;Software Version&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking the version makes sense for shipped libraries and on-premise packages. It makes no sense for continuously delivered SaaS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For assessing whether the bugreport still makes sense, the reporting date is usually enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;severity&quot;&gt;Severity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severity begs to be perceived as equal to a priority. But severity is very different for different roles and its priority is always a decision on relative priorities that take laboriousness into account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider a typo in a text on a page. How do you handle it when it’s in the middle of the page? When it’s in the main call to action on a landing page? When it’s fixed trivially and when does it require five-person approval and an access to a 3^rd^ party system?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is usually duplicate to priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-ticket-swamp&quot;&gt;The Ticket Swamp&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most challenging thing is to have an issue hygiene. Saying “no” is hard, but without it, the issue system becomes an unmanageable mess. &lt;strong&gt;The system should be designed to encourage closing issues aggressively and easily&lt;/strong&gt;. This is ultimately the appeal of Kanban boards: the goal to have is the lowest time possible for an issue to be open and to provide an incentive to prune the queue aggressively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise the amount of tickets becomes unmanageable and starts to resemble a swamp. You carefully walk in only to be sucked, never to resurface again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to recover is to automatically close tickets after a certain period of time. This may be a subtle way of saying “no”, but I think it has its place, especially if we are talking about public trackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one good argument in its favor: the software continuously changes and hence old issues may be invalid. In order to put them into a sprint, they need to be checked—in some cases, that’s actually more work than the issue itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving up is a reasonable response in order to keep having &lt;em&gt;a tracker&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;a database&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-separation-of-internal-support&quot;&gt;The Separation of Internal Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for this to work, there needs to be a separate system for handling questions for the development team from the rest of the company&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;/&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is crucial for communication culture. What I’ve seen as an alternative is to write a message to a random engineer or their team lead, which leads to abuse. It’s important to make that channel more responsive and reliable than any other individual inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other alternative is to open badly-specified development tickets. This road leads to a swamp. It’s easy to overpower the team’s ability to triage all tickets, at which point the whole queue is going to be ignored and you have Ticket Swamp on steroids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Steven Mizell for editing and feedback.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 13:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Almad</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://almad.blog/essays/no-bugs-just-todos/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: How do I reach making $1-1.5k/mo in 13 months?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23427689</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23427689</guid>
<description>I'm a dev with almost no experience in a 3rd world country. Considering the COVID situation, In the worst case scenario I'll be without a job for a while. I have finances to manage for (probably) a year and a month or two.
&lt;p&gt;I want to ask what are the ways with good probability of making ~ $1-1.5/mo (enough to live and still have considerable remaining in my situation)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm asking for ideas because the popular ideas are out of question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Domsetic Freelancing/Consulting does not have much scope, SMB don't seem to be doing well so site-dev work for them also isn't viable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Making software for companies and govt. here isn't much of an option either, there's corruption and they don't particularly care about having a $99/mo solution when there are people willing to work for that rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- More of a opinion, but overseas freelancing opportunities aren't gonna hire a newbie and fiverr is a race to bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd appreciate any advice on how to proceed, any problem you think is a opporutnity to have a solution for or just your experience from another economic depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meta: Started coding 3.5 years ago and probably have enough under my belt to try multiple projects over this duration. Made a new account as I don't want to link this to my real identity. I'm not looking for job offers out of sympathy. This is just considering the worst case scenario, and I want to have something to fall back to if it turns out to be the case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 12:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>noddly</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23427689</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WeChat permanently closes account after user sets offensive password</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/BethanyAllenEbr/status/1268611608672194560</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/BethanyAllenEbr/status/1268611608672194560</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Now for me, losing my WeChat account is slightly annoying, but that's all. But what if I used it the way many Chinese people do now? As THE single platform through which I talk to my family and my boss, pay my bills, pay at restaurants, apply for small loans (I think?), etc&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 12:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>drevil-v2</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/BethanyAllenEbr/status/1268611608672194560</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>