<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Cow Game Extracted Facebook Data</title>
<link>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/03/my-cow-game-extracted-your-facebook-data/556214/?single_page=true</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/03/my-cow-game-extracted-your-facebook-data/556214/?single_page=true</guid>
<description>&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a spell during 2010 and 2011, I was a virtual rancher of clickable cattle on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like a long time ago. Obama was serving his first term as president. Google+ hadn’t arrived, let alone vanished again. Steve Jobs was still alive, as was Kim Jong Il. Facebook’s IPO hadn’t yet taken place, and its service was still fun to use—although it was littered with requests and demands from social games, like FarmVille and Pet Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d had enough of it—the click-farming games, for one, but also Facebook itself. Already in 2010, it felt like a malicious attention market where people treated friends as latent resources to be optimized. Compulsion rather than choice devoured people’s time. Apps like FarmVille sold relief for the artificial inconveniences they themselves had imposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, I made a satirical social game called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cowclicker.com&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'0',r'556214'&quot;&gt;Cow Clicker&lt;/a&gt;. Players clicked a cute cow, which mooed and scored a “click.” Six hours later, they could do so again. They could also invite friends’ cows to their pasture, buy virtual cows with real money, compete for status, click to send a real cow to the developing world from Oxfam, outsource clicks to their toddlers with a mobile app, and much more. It became strangely popular, until eventually, I shut the whole thing down in a bovine rapture—the “cowpocalypse.” It’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2011/12/ff_cowclicker/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'1',r'556214'&quot;&gt;kind of a complicated story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But one worth revisiting today, in the context of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/03/the-cambridge-analytica-scandal-in-three-paragraphs/556046/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'2',r'556214'&quot;&gt;scandal&lt;/a&gt; over Facebook’s sanctioning of user-data exfiltration via its application platform. It’s not just that abusing the Facebook platform for deliberately nefarious ends was easy to do (it was). But worse, in those days, it was hard to avoid extracting private data, for years even, without even trying. I did it with a silly cow game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cow Clicker is not an impressive work of software. After all, it was a game whose sole activity was clicking on cows. I wrote the principal code in three days, much of it hunched on a friend’s couch in Greenpoint, Brooklyn. I had no idea anyone would play it, although over 180,000 people did, eventually. I made a little money from the whole affair, but I never optimized it for revenue generation. I certainly never pondered using the app as a lure for a data-extraction con. I was just a strange man making a strange game on a lark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, if you played Cow Clicker, even just once, I got enough of your personal data that, for years, I could have assembled a reasonably sophisticated profile of your interests and behavior. I might still be able to; all the data is still there, stored on my private server, where Cow Clicker is still running, allowing players to keep clicking where a cow once stood, before my caprice raptured them into the digital void.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/posts/2018/03/candycrysgh/37dc9f68d.png&quot; class=&quot;lazyload&quot;/&gt;The authorization dialog for the game &lt;em&gt;Candy Crush. (King / Facebook)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand why withdrawing data was the default behavior in Facebook apps, you have to know something about how apps get made and published on Facebook. In 2007, the company turned its social-network service into an application platform. The idea was that Facebook could grow its number of users and the time they spent engaged by allowing people and organizations to build services overtop of it. And those people and organizations would benefit by plugging into a large network of users, whose network of friends could easily be made a part of the service, both for social interaction and viral spread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you access an app on Facebook’s website, be it a personality-quiz, a game, a horoscope, or a sports community, the service presents you with an authorization dialog, where the specific data an app says it needs is displayed for the user’s consideration. That could be anything from your name, friend list, and email address, to your photos, likes, direct messages and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/graph-api/reference/user/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'3',r'556214'&quot;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information shared with an app by default has changed over time, and even a savvy user might never have known what comprised it. When I launched Cow Clicker in 2010, it was easier to acquire both “basic” information (name, gender, networks, and profile picture) and “extended” user information (location, relationship status, likes, posts, and more). In 2014, Facebook began an &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/facebook-login/review/what-is-login-review&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'4',r'556214'&quot;&gt;app review process&lt;/a&gt; for information beyond that which a user shared publicly, but for years before that, the decision was left to the user alone. This is consistent with Facebook’s longstanding, official policy on privacy, which revolves around &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2018/01/control-privacy-principles/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'5',r'556214'&quot;&gt;user control&lt;/a&gt; rather than procedural verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;c-section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;App authorizations are not exceptionally clear. For one thing, the user must accept the app’s request to share data with it as soon as they open it for the first time, even before knowing what the app does or why. For another, the authorization is presented by Facebook, not by the third party, making it seem official, safe, and even endorsed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/posts/2018/03/image/772a9b4d6.png&quot; class=&quot;lazyload&quot;/&gt;Cow Clicker on Facebook, 2010. The game appears to live natively inside the Facebook interface, but it runs—and stores its data—on a separate server. (Cow Clicker / Ian Bogost / The Atlantic)
&lt;p&gt;The part of the Facebook website where apps appear, under the blue top navigation (as seen above), introduces further confusion. To the average web user, especially a decade ago, it looked like the game or app was just a part of Facebook itself. The page is seamless, with no boundary between the site’s navigational chrome and the third-party app. If you look at the browser address bar while using a Facebook app on the website, the URL begins with “apps.facebook.com,” further cementing the impression that the user was safely ensconced in the comforting, blue cradle of Facebook’s care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-4&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s not what really takes place. When a user loads an app, Facebook’s servers pass those requests to a remote computer, where the individual or company that made the app hosts their services. The app sends its responses to Facebook, which formats and presents them to the user, as if they were inside of Facebook itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authorization process happens once, the first time the app is accessed for a specific user. After that, every time the user loads the app, Facebook sends it a payload of basic user data to facilitate the app’s operation (additional data can be requested separately when needed). For years, these transmissions were even conducted unencrypted, until Facebook required apps to communicate with its service over a secure connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond its own terms of service for applications, which many developers probably didn’t read or feel compelled to heed, Facebook “secured” user data shared with third-parties by requiring every app to publish a privacy policy. Because data sharing was seen as a form of user-control, not corporate policy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/policy&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'6',r'556214'&quot;&gt;Facebook doesn’t appear to review&lt;/a&gt; platform-developer privacy policies. As far as I can tell, all the platform did was to insure that accessing the URL for an app’s privacy policy didn’t result in a page-not-found error. Facebook was checking that privacy policies existed as reachable web pages, not that they existed as privacy policies, let alone policies that provided any specific protections. And besides, users probably never read the policies, which were linked unassumingly from the application-permissions interface. They might easily, and reasonably, have assumed that Facebook was simply reiterating its own privacy policy when presenting new access to an app. They would have been wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-5&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In essence, Facebook was presenting apps as quasi-endorsed extensions of its core service to users who couldn’t have been expected to know better. That might explain why so many people feel violated by Facebook this week—they might never have realized that they were even using foreign, non-Facebook applications in the first place, let alone ones that were siphoning off and selling their data. The website always just looked like Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;c-section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the case of Cow Clicker, which only ever aimed to let people click on pictures of cows, I was able to access two potentially sensitive pieces of data without even trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is a player’s Facebook ID. This is a numeric, unique identifier attached to every Facebook account. Once I have your Facebook ID, I can look up your profile programmatically, or I can just load it in the public website by appending it to “facebook.com”—Mark Zuckerberg’s is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/4&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'7',r'556214'&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, Facebook generates a unique, app-specific ID for each user, in order to prevent an app from connecting someone directly to Facebook profiles. But back in Cow Clicker’s heyday of 2010, Facebook didn’t do this, and every app got your actual ID. Those data could be correlated against other information—data collected from Facebook, fashioned by the app, or acquired elsewhere. Because I collected and stored my users’ true Facebook IDs to be able to count their clicks and build their pastures and the like, I still have them, and, in theory, I could use them nefariously. A 2014 terms-of-service update prohibits some of that activity, but not everyone cares about violating the Facebook terms of service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-6&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second type of information is a piece of profile data Cow Clicker received without asking for it. Back in 2010, Facebook still allowed users to join “networks”—affiliations like schools, workplaces, and organizations. In some cases, those affiliations required authorization, for example having an email address at a domain that corresponds with a university. Over time, verification became less important to Facebook, and now users can affiliate with schools or workplaces arbitrarily. The less friction, the more data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, on my friend’s couch in Brooklyn, I noticed that Facebook was shipping user affiliation data over the wire to me, so I decided to store it. Facebook allowed apps to store data for which user permission was granted, but urged developers not to request or store more than it needed to operate. Putting affiliation data in the Cow Clicker database allowed me to provide leaderboard rankings by network, allowing my players to compete for clicks with their work colleagues or classmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s neither a terribly interesting feature nor a particularly wicked one. But because I stored the numerical identifiers for user affiliations, I still have them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/reference/fql/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'8',r'556214'&quot;&gt;Until 2016&lt;/a&gt;, I could use a database-query tool called FQL, Facebook Query Language, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/13163573/with-facebook-deprecating-its-rest-api-what-happens-to-affiliations&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'9',r'556214'&quot;&gt;retrieve&lt;/a&gt; the details of those networks, and correlate them back to my users. Had I wanted to, I could have recombined that information with other data and used it for retargeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-7&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cow Clicker’s example is so modest, it might not even seem like a problem. What does it matter if a simple diversion has your Facebook ID, education, and work affiliations? Especially since its solo creator (that’s me) was too dumb or too lazy to exploit that data toward pernicious ends. But even if I hadn’t thought about it at the time, I could have done so years later, long after the cows vanished, and once Cow Clicker players forgot that they’d ever installed my app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also why Zuckerberg’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/03/zuckerberg-facebook-cambridge-analytica-statement/556187/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'10',r'556214'&quot;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt; to the present controversy feels so toothless. Facebook has vowed to audit companies that have collected, shared, or sold large volumes of data in violation of its policy, but the company cannot close the Pandora’s box it opened a decade ago, when it first allowed external apps to collect Facebook user data. That information is now in the hands of thousands, maybe millions of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;c-section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I’m not even sure I know what the Facebook platform’s terms of service dictated that I do with user data acquired from Facebook. Technically, users could revoke certain app permissions later, and apps were supposed to remove any impacted data that they had stored. I doubt most apps did that, and I suspect users never knew—and still don’t know—that revoking access to an app they used eight years ago doesn’t do anything to reverse transmissions that took place years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Jason Koebler &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/59jpa8/its-too-late-to-protect-your-facebook-data-cambridge-analytica&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'11',r'556214'&quot;&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;, it’s too late. “If your data has already been taken, Facebook has no mechanism and no power to make people delete it. If your data was taken, it has very likely been sold, laundered, and put back into Facebook.” Indeed, all the publicity around Facebook’s Cambridge Analytica crisis might be sending lots of old app developers, like me, back to old code and dusty databases, wondering what they’ve even got stored and what it might yet be worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r' ',d,r'related',#data-omni-index,@data-article-id&quot;&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Related Story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/03/zuckerberg-facebook-cambridge-analytica-statement/556187/&quot; data-omni-index=&quot;0&quot; data-article-id=&quot;926882&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;242&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2018/03/AP_16176695540889/thumb_wide_medium.jpg?1521672329&quot; alt=&quot;Mark Zuckerberg looking off into the distance &quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/03/zuckerberg-facebook-cambridge-analytica-statement/556187/&quot; data-omni-index=&quot;0&quot; data-article-id=&quot;926882&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;Zuckerberg Offers the Bare Minimum on the Cambridge Analytica Mess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s &lt;em&gt;laissez-faire&lt;/em&gt; openness surely contributed to the data-extraction free-for-all that’s playing itself out now via the example of Cambridge Analytica. But so did its move-fast-and-break-things attitude toward software development. The Facebook platform was &lt;a href=&quot;http://bogost.com/writing/blog/oauth_of_fealty/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'12',r'556214'&quot;&gt;truly a nightmare&lt;/a&gt; to use and to maintain. It was built like no other software system then extant, and it changed constantly—regular updates rolled out weekly. Old code broke, seemingly for no good reason. Some Facebook app developers were dishonest from the start, and others couldn’t help themselves once they saw the enormous volume of data they could slurp from millions or tens of millions of Facebook users. But many more were just struggling to eke out a part of their living in an ecosystem where people might discover them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adweek.com/digital/facebook-platform-supports-more-than-42-million-pages-and-9-million-apps/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'13',r'556214'&quot;&gt;Millions of apps&lt;/a&gt; had been created by 2012, when I hung up my cowboy hat. Not only apps apparently designed with duplicity in mind, like Aleksandr Kogan’s personality-quiz, which extracted data that was then sold to Cambridge Analytica. But hundreds of thousands of creators of dumb toys, quizzes, games, and communities that might never have intended to dupe or violate users surely did so anyway, because Facebook rammed their data down our throats. On the whole, none of us asked for your data. But we have it anyway, and forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 18:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jameshart</dc:creator>
<og:title>My Cow Game Extracted Your Facebook Data</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/03/my-cow-game-extracted-your-facebook-data/556214/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2018/03/cow-3/facebook.png?1521737685</og:image>
<og:description>The Cambridge Analytica scandal is drawing attention to malicious data thieves and brokers. But every Facebook app—even the dumb, innocent ones—collected users’ personal data without even trying.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/03/my-cow-game-extracted-your-facebook-data/556214/?single_page=true</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: How do you find freelance work?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16651077</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16651077</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.709826589595&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.1398843930636&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16651077&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16651077&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: How do you find freelance work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16651077&quot;&gt;235 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=i_am_nobody&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;i_am_nobody&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16651077&quot;&gt;5 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16651077&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16651077&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16651077&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20do%20you%20find%20freelance%20work%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20do%20you%20find%20freelance%20work%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16651077&amp;amp;auth=6bac67804b7b4cf57c857f4ceda6210138d0c9ff&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16651077&quot;&gt;103 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;19.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;I'm a software engineer with a full-time job, but I have lots of spare time in my off hours. I'd like to monetize this time, but finding freelance work has been extremely daunting.
&lt;p&gt;I don't have a ton of networking skills, so I don't have a network I can tap for opportunities. I don't really know how to find opportunities otherwise. I have the approvals I need from my full-time job to do this, but it's still not something where I want to splash my name all over the place. I also don't have a lot of public code, so no big portfolio I can point people to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not looking for massive pay, just something to occupy my time and some side money. But I want to leverage my skills, not do mechanical turk work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you find freelance work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Summer 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 18:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>i_am_nobody</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16651077</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circular Shock Acoustic Waves in Ionosphere Triggered by Launch of Formosat‐5</title>
<link>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1002/2017SW001738</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1002/2017SW001738</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The launch of SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket delivered Taiwan's FORMOSAT‐5 satellite to orbit from Vandenberg Air Force Base in California at 18:51:00 UT on 24 August 2017. To facilitate the delivery of FORMOSAT‐5 to its mission orbit altitude of ~720 km, the Falcon 9 made a steep initial ascent. During the launch, the supersonic rocket induced gigantic circular shock acoustic waves (SAWs) in total electron content (TEC) over the western United States beginning approximately 5 min after the liftoff. The circular SAWs emanated outward with ~20 min duration, horizontal phase velocities of ~629–726 m/s, horizontal wavelengths of ~390–450 km, and period of ~10.28 ± 1 min. This is the largest rocket‐induced circular SAWs on record, extending approximately 114–128°W in longitude and 26–39°N in latitude (~1,500 km in diameter), and was due to the unique, nearly vertical attitude of the rocket during orbit insertion. The rocket‐exhaust plume subsequently created a large‐scale ionospheric plasma hole (~900 km in diameter) with 10–70% TEC depletions in comparison with the reference days. While the circular SAWs, with a relatively small amplitude of TEC fluctuations, likely did not introduce range errors into the Global Navigation Satellite Systems navigation and positioning system, the subsequent ionospheric plasma hole, on the other hand, could have caused spatial gradients in the ionospheric plasma potentially leading to a range error of ~1 m.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 16:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zdw</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1002/2017SW001738</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GitLab 10.6 released with CI/CD for GitHub</title>
<link>https://about.gitlab.com/2018/03/22/gitlab-10-6-released/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://about.gitlab.com/2018/03/22/gitlab-10-6-released/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;115.38321720691&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;18.637305699482&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sast-security-report-on-pipelines-view&quot;&gt; SAST security report on pipelines view&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few releases ago, we shipped &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/topics/autodevops/#auto-sast&quot;&gt;Static Application Security Testing (SAST)&lt;/a&gt;, which automatically finds vulnerabilities in any new code changes in a merge request. This allows you to fix them before merging, ensuring these security problems are not introduced nto master and not released to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this release, this same information is available in a complete SAST security report in the &lt;strong&gt;CI/CD &amp;gt; Pipelines&lt;/strong&gt; page. This allows developers, production/systems engineers, and any other security stakeholders to have even more visibility into any security risks as your code progresses through CI/CD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;SAST security report on pipelines view&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/10_6/sast_report.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/merge_requests/sast.html#security-report-under-pipelines&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on SAST security reports in the pipeline view&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;13.853249475891&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;external-authorization-control&quot;&gt; External Authorization Control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some regulated environments, project classification systems are used to control access to projects, and can now be used with GitLab. When enabled, admins can set the classification of each project. In addition to GitLab access controls, access to projects will also require approval from the external authorization service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/admin_area/settings/external_authorization.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on External Authorization Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;16.498516320475&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;authentication-support-for-dast&quot;&gt; Authentication support for DAST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few releases ago, we shipped &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/examples/dast.html&quot;&gt;Dynamic Application Security Testing (DAST)&lt;/a&gt;, allowing you to check for security vulnerabilities dynamically and automatically in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/review_apps/index.html&quot;&gt;Review App&lt;/a&gt; version of your work-in-progress code, before it is merged into master and released to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, this feature was limited to public pages. With this release, you can now specify credentials that DAST will use to authenticate into your web app and to simulate an attacker that is able to access sections protected with a login process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Authentication support for DAST&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/10_6/dast_auth.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/examples/dast.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Authentication support for DAST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;18.781278962002&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;external-cicd-configuration-in-starter-and-bronze&quot;&gt; External CI/CD configuration in Starter and Bronze&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GitLab 10.5 we added the ability to &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/2018/02/22/gitlab-10-5-released/#include-external-files-in-cicd-pipeline-definition&quot;&gt;include external CI/CD configuration files&lt;/a&gt; into the main &lt;code&gt;.gitlab-ci.yml&lt;/code&gt; for your project. This feature was available only to Premium users on self-hosted Gitlab and Silver users on GitLab.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We received a lot of feedback from customers asking us to move this to to a lower tier and we are excited to bring this feature to even more users in this release by making it now availabe to Starter users on self-hosted Gitlab and Bronze users on GitLab.com. The ability to have a centralized control over the pipeline configuration and to reuse the same definition in multiple projects is something that is valuable for enterprises and smaller businesses as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that as part of our commitment to open source, public projects on Free GitLab.com have features equivalent to a Gold level subscription. So those public projects will continue to have this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/yaml/#include&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on including external CI/CD configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;11.683698296837&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;branches-overview&quot;&gt; Branches overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As projects and teams grow, so do the number of branches. The new branches overview and filtered branches lists make it easy to quickly find the branch you’re looking for. Branches with a commit added in the last three months are shown as active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/tnir&quot;&gt;Takuya Noguchi&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/merge_requests/15402&quot;&gt;contribution&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Branches overview&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/10_6/branches_overview.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/repository/branches/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Branches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;25.35652173913&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;navigate-to-external-issue-tracker&quot;&gt; Navigate to external issue tracker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some teams use GitLab integrated with an external issue tracker. For example, Jira issues integrated with GitLab merge requests is a popular workflow for many teams. In this scenario, GitLab issues still function as normal, and teams are free to use them, for example, in separate one-off scenarios where a team wants everything just in GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To streamline this integration, we’ve added a new link to the project navigation. If you have configured any external issue tracker (Redmine, Jira, Bugzilla, or the Custom Issue Tracker), there will be a separate link in the project navigation that allows you to quickly navigate to that external system. The GitLab issues link remains so that there’s no confusion and also allows you to use both issue trackers if you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Navigate to external issue tracker&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/10_6/external-tracker-nav.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/integration/external-issue-tracker.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on External Issue Tracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;20.378561736771&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-importexport-api&quot;&gt; Project import/export API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects are extremely important in GitLab, since they contain all the valuable work (including the Git repo) and organization (including issues and merge requests) of your team. Using the existing project export and import features of GitLab, projects can easily be transferred within and between instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to now, this was a manual process. With this release, project exports and imports are now part of the GitLab API, allowing you even more automated and flexible workflows when you need move your projects within or between GitLab instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/travismiller&quot;&gt;Travis Miller&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/merge_requests/15860&quot;&gt;contribution&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/project_import_export.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Project Import/Export API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;16.075313807531&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;labels-in-epics&quot;&gt; Labels in Epics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab issues and merge requests support labels to enable flexible and highly customizable management of these objects. It’s an effective design that we’ve also brought to Epics in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now assign group labels to epics from the sidebar of an epic, exactly the same as with issues and merge requests. And you can filter by labels on the epics list page in a group, again like issues and merge requests. Users of GitLab will thus find this feature immediately recognizable. This allows you easily mix and match epics into different categories based on the powerful search and filter bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Labels in Epics&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/10_6/epics-labels.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/group/epics/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Epics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;23.630136986301&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;gitlab-chatops-alpha&quot;&gt; GitLab ChatOps (alpha)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many organizations, much of their communication, including their operations and troubleshooting discussions, is moving to chat. There is also typically an “operations toolbox,” containing frequently used commands to check on the health of an environment or to perform routine actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With GitLab 10.6 we wanted to make it easy to both automate these routine actions, as well as bring them into Slack itself. Getting started is as easy as adding a job to your GitLab CI YML, and enabling Slack slash commands integration. Users will then be able to interact with it by typing in the slash command, the CI job name, and then passing any relevant arguments. The job will be executed on a runner, with the output being sent right back to Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/chatops/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on GitLab ChatOps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;13.579881656805&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;epics-api&quot;&gt; Epics API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the labels support mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/2018/03/22/gitlab-10-6-released/#labels-in-epics&quot;&gt;above&lt;/a&gt;, we have maintained parity with API support for Epics. You can get a list of epics based on the same search and filter parameters of the search and filter bar in the web UI of the epics page. This includes searching by the epic title and description, filtering by the author and labels, and ordering by “created at” and “updated at” timestamps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/epics.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Epics API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;18.291316526611&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;merge-request-approvals-api&quot;&gt; Merge Request Approvals API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this release, the Merge Request Approvals API was limited to approving and unapproving a merge request only. With this release, you can now fully configure approvals at the project level and at the merge request level, giving users feature parity with the GitLab web UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Approvals API, teams can now create more elaborate code review and approval workflows that are specific to their needs. You can use as much or as little of the API as needed to customize which parts of your workflow happen inside the GitLab web UI, and which parts happen outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/merge_request_approvals.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Merge Request Approvals API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;16.55303030303&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;discussions-api&quot;&gt; Discussions API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this release, we have brought API support to discussions in issues, snippets, and epics. This means that all comments and discussions (for issues) are now accessible via the API. Teams can leverage this API for flexible, customized, and specific workflows that are not necessarily in the main GitLab web UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;API support for comments and discussions in merge requests will also come &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/20901&quot;&gt;in a future release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/discussions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Discussions API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;27.140019860973&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;business-and-other-custom-metrics&quot;&gt; Business and other custom metrics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/2017/03/22/gitlab-9-0-released/#environment-monitoring-ce-ees-eep&quot;&gt;GitLab 9.0&lt;/a&gt;, developers have been able to monitor critical system and response metrics of their deployed apps, like throughput, latency, and CPU/memory utilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This provided a great baseline understanding of both the user experience your customers were receiving as well as resource utilization, directly in the tool they use every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With GitLab 10.6 we have added the ability to add your own metrics, allowing deeper introspection of your application and business. For example metrics from a credit card processing module can be added, tracking not just success rates but also revenue and order size. This can help surface failures that may not result in HTTP errors, as well as the ultimate impact on business performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, simply provide the Prometheus &lt;a href=&quot;https://prometheus.io/docs/prometheus/latest/querying/basics/&quot;&gt;PromQL query&lt;/a&gt; and it will begin to display in the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Business and other custom metrics&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/10_6/custom_metrics.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/integrations/prometheus.html#adding-additional-metrics&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on adding business and other custom metrics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;16.688333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;filipino-indonesian-and-turkish-language-support&quot;&gt; Filipino, Indonesian, and Turkish language support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of our ongoing effort to internationalize GitLab, we have now added support for Filipino, Indonesian and Turkish translations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also externalised strings on the Repository Locked Files (Premium and above) list page allowing our translation community to add more languages and strings to GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in contributing to GitLab’s internationalization efforts, we welcome you to join our &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/development/i18n/index.html&quot;&gt;translation community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/development/i18n/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on translating GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;19.126315789474&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud-native-gitlab-helm-chart-alpha&quot;&gt; Cloud native GitLab Helm chart (alpha)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that the cloud native GitLab &lt;a href=&quot;https://helm.sh&quot;&gt;Helm&lt;/a&gt; chart is now in alpha, and available for testing. This chart features a more cloud native architecture, with a container for each component of GitLab and no requirement for shared storage. These changes result in increased resilience, scalability, and performance of GitLab on Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the chart and containers are still in active development, contain &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/charts/helm.gitlab.io/blob/master/doc/architecture/alpha.md#known-issues-and-limitations&quot;&gt;known issues and limitations&lt;/a&gt;, and should not be used for production. For this release &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/pricing/self-hosted/feature-comparison/&quot;&gt;GitLab Premium&lt;/a&gt; is required, while we work to bring &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/40781&quot;&gt;Object Storage support to Libre&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/charts/helm.gitlab.io/blob/master/README.md&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on GitLab Helm chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;5.4016620498615&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;gitlab-runner-106&quot;&gt; GitLab Runner 10.6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also releasing GitLab Runner 10.6 today! GitLab Runner is the open source project that is used to run your CI/CD jobs and send the results back to GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;most-interesting-changes&quot;&gt;Most interesting changes:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List of all changes can be found in GitLab Runner’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-runner/blob/v10.6.0/CHANGELOG.md&quot;&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/runner/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on GitLab Runner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;6.0504347826087&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;omnibus-improvements&quot;&gt; Omnibus improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;GitLab &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.mattermost.com/releases/mattermost-4-7/&quot;&gt;Mattermost 4.7&lt;/a&gt; includes enhanced image preview and thumbnails, faster load times, upgraded desktop app, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.mattermost.com/security-updates/&quot;&gt;security updates&lt;/a&gt;. Upgrading is recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chef has been updated to 13.6.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Omnibus has been updated to 5.6.10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL has been updated to 9.6.8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python has been updated to 3.4.8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jemalloc has been updated to 5.0.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;announce-ip&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;announce-port&lt;/code&gt; are now configurable for Redis/Sentinel, to better support HA in Docker environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/omnibus/README.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Omnibus GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;64.950828729282&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;16.498516320475&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;authentication-support-for-dast&quot;&gt; Authentication support for DAST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few releases ago, we shipped &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/examples/dast.html&quot;&gt;Dynamic Application Security Testing (DAST)&lt;/a&gt;, allowing you to check for security vulnerabilities dynamically and automatically in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/review_apps/index.html&quot;&gt;Review App&lt;/a&gt; version of your work-in-progress code, before it is merged into master and released to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, this feature was limited to public pages. With this release, you can now specify credentials that DAST will use to authenticate into your web app and to simulate an attacker that is able to access sections protected with a login process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Authentication support for DAST&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/10_6/dast_auth.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/examples/dast.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Authentication support for DAST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;11.683698296837&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;branches-overview&quot;&gt; Branches overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As projects and teams grow, so do the number of branches. The new branches overview and filtered branches lists make it easy to quickly find the branch you’re looking for. Branches with a commit added in the last three months are shown as active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/tnir&quot;&gt;Takuya Noguchi&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/merge_requests/15402&quot;&gt;contribution&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Branches overview&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/10_6/branches_overview.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/repository/branches/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Branches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;20.378561736771&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-importexport-api&quot;&gt; Project import/export API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects are extremely important in GitLab, since they contain all the valuable work (including the Git repo) and organization (including issues and merge requests) of your team. Using the existing project export and import features of GitLab, projects can easily be transferred within and between instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to now, this was a manual process. With this release, project exports and imports are now part of the GitLab API, allowing you even more automated and flexible workflows when you need move your projects within or between GitLab instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/travismiller&quot;&gt;Travis Miller&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/merge_requests/15860&quot;&gt;contribution&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/project_import_export.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Project Import/Export API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;23.630136986301&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;gitlab-chatops-alpha&quot;&gt; GitLab ChatOps (alpha)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many organizations, much of their communication, including their operations and troubleshooting discussions, is moving to chat. There is also typically an “operations toolbox,” containing frequently used commands to check on the health of an environment or to perform routine actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With GitLab 10.6 we wanted to make it easy to both automate these routine actions, as well as bring them into Slack itself. Getting started is as easy as adding a job to your GitLab CI YML, and enabling Slack slash commands integration. Users will then be able to interact with it by typing in the slash command, the CI job name, and then passing any relevant arguments. The job will be executed on a runner, with the output being sent right back to Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/chatops/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on GitLab ChatOps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;18.291316526611&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;merge-request-approvals-api&quot;&gt; Merge Request Approvals API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this release, the Merge Request Approvals API was limited to approving and unapproving a merge request only. With this release, you can now fully configure approvals at the project level and at the merge request level, giving users feature parity with the GitLab web UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Approvals API, teams can now create more elaborate code review and approval workflows that are specific to their needs. You can use as much or as little of the API as needed to customize which parts of your workflow happen inside the GitLab web UI, and which parts happen outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/merge_request_approvals.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Merge Request Approvals API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;27.140019860973&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;business-and-other-custom-metrics&quot;&gt; Business and other custom metrics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/2017/03/22/gitlab-9-0-released/#environment-monitoring-ce-ees-eep&quot;&gt;GitLab 9.0&lt;/a&gt;, developers have been able to monitor critical system and response metrics of their deployed apps, like throughput, latency, and CPU/memory utilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This provided a great baseline understanding of both the user experience your customers were receiving as well as resource utilization, directly in the tool they use every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With GitLab 10.6 we have added the ability to add your own metrics, allowing deeper introspection of your application and business. For example metrics from a credit card processing module can be added, tracking not just success rates but also revenue and order size. This can help surface failures that may not result in HTTP errors, as well as the ultimate impact on business performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, simply provide the Prometheus &lt;a href=&quot;https://prometheus.io/docs/prometheus/latest/querying/basics/&quot;&gt;PromQL query&lt;/a&gt; and it will begin to display in the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Business and other custom metrics&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/10_6/custom_metrics.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/integrations/prometheus.html#adding-additional-metrics&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on adding business and other custom metrics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;19.126315789474&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud-native-gitlab-helm-chart-alpha&quot;&gt; Cloud native GitLab Helm chart (alpha)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that the cloud native GitLab &lt;a href=&quot;https://helm.sh&quot;&gt;Helm&lt;/a&gt; chart is now in alpha, and available for testing. This chart features a more cloud native architecture, with a container for each component of GitLab and no requirement for shared storage. These changes result in increased resilience, scalability, and performance of GitLab on Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the chart and containers are still in active development, contain &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/charts/helm.gitlab.io/blob/master/doc/architecture/alpha.md#known-issues-and-limitations&quot;&gt;known issues and limitations&lt;/a&gt;, and should not be used for production. For this release &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/pricing/self-hosted/feature-comparison/&quot;&gt;GitLab Premium&lt;/a&gt; is required, while we work to bring &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/40781&quot;&gt;Object Storage support to Libre&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/charts/helm.gitlab.io/blob/master/README.md&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on GitLab Helm chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;6.0504347826087&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;omnibus-improvements&quot;&gt; Omnibus improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBRE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;GitLab &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.mattermost.com/releases/mattermost-4-7/&quot;&gt;Mattermost 4.7&lt;/a&gt; includes enhanced image preview and thumbnails, faster load times, upgraded desktop app, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.mattermost.com/security-updates/&quot;&gt;security updates&lt;/a&gt;. Upgrading is recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chef has been updated to 13.6.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Omnibus has been updated to 5.6.10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL has been updated to 9.6.8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python has been updated to 3.4.8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jemalloc has been updated to 5.0.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;announce-ip&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;announce-port&lt;/code&gt; are now configurable for Redis/Sentinel, to better support HA in Docker environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/omnibus/README.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read through the documentation on Omnibus GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 15:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbanffy</dc:creator>
<og:title>GitLab 10.6 released with CI/CD for GitHub and deeper Kubernetes integration</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://about.gitlab.com/2018/03/22/gitlab-10-6-released/</og:url>
<og:image>https://about.gitlab.com/images/tweets/gitlab-10-6-released.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://about.gitlab.com/2018/03/22/gitlab-10-6-released/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Evolution Is the New Deep Learning</title>
<link>https://www.sentient.ai/blog/evolution-is-the-new-deep-learning/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sentient.ai/blog/evolution-is-the-new-deep-learning/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-9098&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/AdobeStock_93655844-s1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2150&quot; height=&quot;1290&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/AdobeStock_93655844-s1.jpg 2150w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/AdobeStock_93655844-s1-360x216.jpg 360w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/AdobeStock_93655844-s1-768x461.jpg 768w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/AdobeStock_93655844-s1-1350x810.jpg 1350w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/AdobeStock_93655844-s1-560x336.jpg 560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2150px) 100vw, 2150px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/risto-miikkulainen-ab43b9b8/&quot;&gt;Risto Miikkulainen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Vice President Research; Professor of Computer Science at the University of Texas at Austin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[If you are visiting from Hacker News, please be sure to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/&quot;&gt;papers responsible&lt;/a&gt; for the development of these apps].&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Sentient, we have an entire team dedicated to research and experimentation in AI. Over the past few years, the team has focused on developing new methods in Evolutionary Computation (EC), i.e. designing artificial neural network architectures, building commercial applications, and solving challenging computational problems using methods inspired by natural evolution. This research builds upon more than 25 years of research at UT Austin and other academic institutions, and coincides with related efforts recently at &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/evolution-strategies/&quot;&gt;OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/blog/population-based-training-neural-networks/&quot;&gt;DeepMind&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1802.01548&quot;&gt;Google Brain&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/deep-neuroevolution/&quot;&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt;. There is significant momentum building in this area; indeed, we believe evolutionary computation may well be the next big thing in AI technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Deep Learning (DL), EC was introduced decades ago, and it is currently experiencing a similar boost from the available big compute and big data. However, it addresses a distinctly different need: Whereas DL focuses on modeling what we already know, EC focuses on creating new knowledge. In that sense, it is the next step up from DL: Whereas DL makes it possible to recognize new instances of objects and speech within familiar categories, EC makes it possible to discover entirely new objects and behaviors—those that maximize a given objective. Thus, EC makes a host of new applications possible: designing more effective behaviors for robots and virtual agents; creating more effective and cheaper health interventions, growth recipes for agriculture, and mechanical and biological processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Sentient released five papers and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;web portal&lt;/a&gt; reporting significant progress in taking this step, focusing on three areas: (1) DL architectures are evolved to exceed state of the art in three standard machine learning benchmarks; (2) techniques are developed for increasing performance and reliability of evolution in real-world applications; and (3) evolutionary problem solving is demonstrated on very hard computational problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post focuses on the first of these areas, i.e. optimization of DL architectures with EC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sentient Reveals Breakthrough Research in Neuroevolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the power of deep learning comes from the size and complexity of the networks. With neuroevolution, the DL architecture (i.e. network topology, modules, and hyperparameters) can be optimized beyond human ability. The three demos that we will cover in this article are Omni Draw, Celeb Match, and the Music Maker (Language Modeling). In all three examples, Sentient successfully surpassed the state-of-the-art DL benchmark using neuroevolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/lstm-music/&quot;&gt;Music Maker (Language Modeling)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Language Modeling domain, the system is trained to predict the next word in a “language corpus”, i.e. a large collection of text such as several years of the Wall Street Journal. After the network has made its prediction, this input can be looped back into its input, and the network can generate an entire sequence of words. Interestingly, the same technique applies equally well to musical sequences, where it makes for a fun demo. The user inputs a few initial notes, and the system improvises an entire melody based on that starting point. By means of neuroevolution, Sentient optimized the design of the gated recurrent (Long Short-Term Memory or LSTM) nodes (i.e. the network’s “memory” structure) to make the model more accurate in predicting the next note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/lstm-music/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-9103 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/music-maker-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;894&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/music-maker-1.png 1200w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/music-maker-1-360x268.png 360w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/music-maker-1-768x572.png 768w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/music-maker-1-560x417.png 560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the language modeling domain (i.e. predicting the next word in a language corpus called &lt;a href=&quot;https://catalog.ldc.upenn.edu/ldc99t42&quot;&gt;Penn Tree Bank&lt;/a&gt;), the benchmark is defined by Perplexity Points, a measurement of how well a probabilistic model can predict real samples. The lower the number the better, as we want the model to be less “perplexed” when predicting the next word in a sequence. In this case, Sentient beat the standard LSTM structure by 10.8 Perplexity Points. Remarkably, although several human-designed LSTM variations have been proposed, they have not improved performance much—LSTM structure was essentially unchanged for 25 years. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/lstm/&quot;&gt;neuroevolution experiments&lt;/a&gt; showed that it can, as a matter of fact, be improved significantly by adding more complexity, i.e. memory cells and more nonlinear, parallel pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/lstm/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-9007 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/lstm-16.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/lstm-16.png 1920w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/lstm-16-360x203.png 360w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/lstm-16-768x432.png 768w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/lstm-16-1350x759.png 1350w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/lstm-16-560x315.png 560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does this breakthrough matter? Language is a powerful and complex construct of human intelligence. Language modeling, i.e. predicting the next word in a text, is a benchmark that measures how well machine learning methods can learn language structure. It is therefore a surrogate for building natural language processing systems that includes speech and language interfaces, machine translation (such as Google Translate), and even medical data such as DNA sequences and heart rate diagnosis. The better we can do in the language modeling benchmark, the better language processing systems we can build, using the same technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/omni-draw/&quot;&gt;Omni Draw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omniglot is a handwritten character recognition benchmark on recognizing characters in 50 different alphabets, including real languages like Cyrillic (written Russian), Japanese, and Hebrew, to artificial languages such as Tengwar (the written language in Lord of the Rings).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/omni-draw/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-9104 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/omni-draw-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1650&quot; height=&quot;1337&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/omni-draw-1.png 1650w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/omni-draw-1-360x292.png 360w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/omni-draw-1-768x622.png 768w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/omni-draw-1-1350x1094.png 1350w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/omni-draw-1-560x454.png 560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1650px) 100vw, 1650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This demo showcases multitask learning, in which the model learns all languages at once and exploits the relationship between characters from different languages. So, for instance, the user inputs an image and the system outputs suggestions for different character matches in different languages, saying “this would be ‘X’ in Latin, ‘Y’ in Japanese, and ‘Z’ in Tengwar, etc.”—taking advantage of its understanding of the relationships between Japanese, Tengwar, and Latin to figure out which character is the best match. This differs from a single task learning environment where the model trains on one language at a time and cannot make the same connections across language data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this Omniglot multitask character recognition task, our research team improved error of character matching from &lt;strong&gt;32% to 10%.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omniglot is an example of a dataset that has relatively little data per language—for instance, it may have only a few characters in Greek but many in Japanese. It succeeds by using its knowledge of the relationships between languages to find solutions, hence, finding a solution in the face of missing or sparse data. Why is this important? For many real world applications, labeled data is expensive or dangerous to acquire (e.g., medical applications, agriculture, and robotic rescue), hence automatically designing models that exploit the relationships to &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; or related datasets could, in a way, substitute the missing dataset and boost research capabilities. It is also an excellent demonstration of the power of neuroevolution: there are many ways in which the languages can be related, and evolution discovers the best ways to tie their learning together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/celeb-match/&quot;&gt;Celeb Match&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Celeb Match demo deals similarly with multitask learning, but this time, with a large-scale data sets. The demo is based on the CelebA dataset, which consists of around 200,000 images of celebrities, each of which is labeled with 40 binary attributes such as “Male vs. Female”, “beard vs. no beard”, “glasses vs. no glasses”, etc. Each attribute induces a “classification task” that induces the system to detect and identify each attribute. As a fun add-on, we’ve created a demo that turns this task around: The user can set the desired degree for each attribute, and the system finds the closest celebrity match, as determined by the evolved multitask learning network. For instance, if the current attribute settings result in an image of Brad Pitt, the user can increase “gray hair” to find which celebrity would be similar to Brad Pitt but with different hair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/celeb-match/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-9102 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/celeb-match-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1213&quot; height=&quot;873&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/celeb-match-1.jpg 1213w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/celeb-match-1-360x259.jpg 360w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/celeb-match-1-768x553.jpg 768w, https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/celeb-match-1-560x403.jpg 560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1213px) 100vw, 1213px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this domain, the state-of-the-art benchmark is the test error across all attributes, i.e. whether the system detected the attribute correctly (male/female, young/mature, large eyes/small eyes), etc. In the CelebA multitask face classification domain, Sentient used evolutionary computation to optimize the networks that detect these attributes, reducing error from &lt;strong&gt;8.00% to 7.94%&lt;/strong&gt; for an ensemble (an average of) three models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technology is a step forward in the ability for AI to predict diverse attributes of people, places, and things in the physical world. Unlike networks trained to find similarities based on abstract, learned features, it makes the similarities semantic and interpretable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Just the Tip of the Iceberg!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omni Draw, Celeb Match, and the Music Maker are just three examples of interactive demos that illustrate the power of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea-1/&quot;&gt;neuroevolution&lt;/a&gt;. We invite you to learn more about the technology behind them on our website and papers, as well as the two other aspects of evolution as the next deep learning: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea-2/&quot;&gt;commercialization&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea-3/&quot;&gt;solving hard problems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more on our evolution research web portal, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentient.ai/sentient-labs/ea/&quot;&gt;Evolution is the New Deep Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 15:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jonbaer</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Evolution is the New Deep Learning</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.sentient.ai/blog/evolution-is-the-new-deep-learning/</og:url>
<og:description>By Risto Miikkulainen Vice President Research; Professor of Computer Science at the University of Texas at Austin [If you are visiting from Hacker News, please be sure to check out the papers respo…</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.sentient.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/AdobeStock_93655844-s1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sentient.ai/blog/evolution-is-the-new-deep-learning/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Section 230: A Key Legal Shield for Facebook, Google Is About to Change</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2018/03/21/591622450/section-230-a-key-legal-shield-for-facebook-google-is-about-to-change</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2018/03/21/591622450/section-230-a-key-legal-shield-for-facebook-google-is-about-to-change</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res593573333&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/gettyimages-475157855-890852ec7848300ee093bd93b49383703d5034e3-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/gettyimages-475157855-890852ec7848300ee093bd93b49383703d5034e3-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1996 law sits at the heart of a major question about the modern Internet: How much responsibility should fall to online platforms for how their users act and get treated? &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Oivind Hovland/Getty Images/Ikon Images&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Oivind Hovland/Getty Images/Ikon Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/gettyimages-475157855-890852ec7848300ee093bd93b49383703d5034e3-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A 1996 law sits at the heart of a major question about the modern Internet: How much responsibility should fall to online platforms for how their users act and get treated?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Oivind Hovland/Getty Images/Ikon Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated at 5:17 p.m. ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's 1995, and Chris Cox is on a plane reading a newspaper. One article about a recent court decision catches his eye. This moment, in a way, ends up changing his life — and, to this day, it continues to change ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case that caught the congressman's attention involved some posts on a bulletin board — the early-Internet precursor to today's social media. The ruling led to a new law, co-authored by Cox and often called simply &quot;Section 230.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 1996 statute became known as &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/1/16072680/cda-230-stop-enabling-sex-traffickers-act-liability-shield-senate-backpage&quot;&gt;a core pillar of Internet freedom&lt;/a&gt;&quot; and &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2013/09/the-law-that-gave-us-the-modern-internet-and-the-campaign-to-kill-it/279588/&quot;&gt;the law that gave us modern Internet&lt;/a&gt;&quot; — a critical component of free speech online. But the journey of Section 230 runs through some of the darkest corners of the Web. Most egregiously, the law has been used to defend Backpage.com, a website featuring ads for sex with children forced into prostitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, this law still sits at the heart of a major question about the modern Internet: &lt;em&gt;How much responsibility do online platforms have for how their users behave or get treated?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first major change to Section 230 in years, Congress voted this week to make Internet companies take a little more responsibility than they have for content on their sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Library or newspaper?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court decision that started it all had to do with some online posts about a company called Stratton Oakmont. On one finance-themed bulletin board, someone had accused the investment firm of fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years later, Stratton Oakmont's crimes would be turned into a Hollywood film, &lt;em&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street.&lt;/em&gt; But in 1994, the firm called the accusations libel and wanted to sue. But because it was the Internet, the posts were anonymous. So instead, the firm sued Prodigy, the online service that hosted the bulletin board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prodigy argued it couldn't be responsible for a user's post — like a library, it could not liable for what's inside its books. Or, in now-familiar terms: It's a platform, not a publisher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court disagreed, but for an unexpected reason: Prodigy moderated posts, cleaning up foul language. And because of that, the court treated Prodigy like a newspaper liable for its articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Cox read about this ruling, he thought this was &quot;exactly the wrong result&quot;: How was this amazing new thing — the Internet — going to blossom, if companies got punished for &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;/em&gt; to keep things clean? &quot;This struck me as a way to make the Internet a cesspool,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this moment, Cox was flying from his home in California to return to Congress. Back at work, Cox, a Republican, teamed up with his friend, Oregon Democrat Ron Wyden, to rectify the court precedent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, they produced Section 230 — perhaps the only 20-year-old statute to be claimed by Internet companies and advocates as technologically prescient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res593554359&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/gettyimages-74894454-26c8d594d3874e50371ce2eabaa887b66c7db04d-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/gettyimages-74894454-26c8d594d3874e50371ce2eabaa887b66c7db04d-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Ron Wyden, D-Ore., (left) and Rep. Christopher Cox, R-Calif., speak about the Communications Decency Act in 1997. They were behind Section 230, which says that with some exceptions, online platforms can't be sued for something posted by a user. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Douglas Graham/Congressional Quarterly/Getty Images&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Douglas Graham/Congressional Quarterly/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/gettyimages-74894454-26c8d594d3874e50371ce2eabaa887b66c7db04d-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Sen. Ron Wyden, D-Ore., (left) and Rep. Christopher Cox, R-Calif., speak about the Communications Decency Act in 1997. They were behind Section 230, which says that with some exceptions, online platforms can't be sued for something posted by a user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Douglas Graham/Congressional Quarterly/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;The original purpose&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 230 lives inside the Communications Decency Act of 1996, and it gives websites broad legal immunity: With &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/47/230&quot;&gt;some exceptions&lt;/a&gt;, online platforms can't be sued for something posted by a user — and that remains true even if they act a little like publishers, by moderating posts or setting specific standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Section 230 is as important as the First Amendment to protecting free speech online, certainly here in the U.S.,&quot; says Emma Llanso, a free expression advocate at the Center for Democracy and Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res592284305&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap pullquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside aria-label=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;bucket&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No provider or user of an interactive computer service shall be treated as the publisher or speaker of any information provided by another information content provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;47 U.S. Code § 230&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The argument goes that without Section 230, we would never have platforms like YouTube, Facebook, Twitter, Yelp or Reddit — sites that allow ordinary people to post opinions or write reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's &quot;the one line of federal code that has created more economic value in this country than any other,&quot; says Michael Beckerman, who runs the Internet Association, which represents many of Silicon Valley's largest companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Section 230 is also tied to some of the worst stuff on the Internet, protecting sites when they host revenge porn, extremely gruesome videos or violent death threats. The broad leeway given to Internet companies represents &quot;power without responsibility,&quot; Georgetown University law professor Rebecca Tushnet wrote in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholarship.law.georgetown.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?referer=https://www.google.com/&amp;amp;httpsredir=1&amp;amp;article=1078&amp;amp;context=fwps_papers&quot;&gt;oft-cited paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cox says, &quot;The original purpose of this law was to help clean up the Internet, not to facilitate people doing bad things on the Internet.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;A Teflon shield&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original purpose hasn't always prevailed in court. And one specific example has prompted Congress to vote to amend Section 230 — the first cutback to websites' protections in years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's the case of Backpage.com, a site ostensibly for classifieds, but one well known for its adult-services ads. Among them — if you know what to look for — are sex ads featuring children forced into prostitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;All of those terms were indicative of an underage child — Lolita, fresh, new to town,&quot; says Mary Mazzio, a filmmaker whose documentary &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bq-PdMr7pTY&quot;&gt;I Am Jane Doe&lt;/a&gt; tells the story of several young girls sold for sex on Backpage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, victims and their families brought case after case against Backpage — and lost. The website kept convincing judges across the country that Section 230 shielded it from liability for the posts of its users. Major digital-rights groups, including the Center for Democracy and Technology, argued that holding Backpage liable could have chilling effects for social media and other websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bewildered Mazzio: &quot;How is it possibly legal that a website that makes millions and millions of dollars has no accountability for this crime?&quot; she says. &quot;Section 230 has turned into a Teflon shield, not to protect free speech but to protect business revenue.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-court-backpage/u-s-supreme-court-will-not-examine-tech-industry-legal-shield-idUSKBN14T1OR&quot;&gt;last year declined&lt;/a&gt; to hear victims' appeal in the case of Backpage and Section 230.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res593572073&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/ap_17010723014058_custom-6e6425c512da99d0e7f62a75fcda1303661c59a1-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/ap_17010723014058_custom-6e6425c512da99d0e7f62a75fcda1303661c59a1-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kubiiki P. wipes tears as she testifies at a 2017 Senate hearing about her young daughter being sold for sex on Backpage.com. The site, ostensibly for classifieds, is well-known for its adult-services ads. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Cliff Owen/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Cliff Owen/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;The judge-made law&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/114/crpt/srpt214/CRPT-114srpt214.pdf&quot;&gt;mounting evidence&lt;/a&gt; showed that Backpage was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/public-safety/backpage-has-always-claimed-it-doesnt-control-sex-related-ads-new-documents-show-otherwise/2017/07/10/b3158ef6-553c-11e7-b38e-35fd8e0c288f_story.html?utm_term=.4bc40802346a&quot;&gt;actively involved&lt;/a&gt; in the sex ads. That means the site is a publisher liable for its content. Backpage and its founders are now facing a federal grand jury in Arizona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Sen. Ron Wyden, co-author of the law, the Department of Justice missed the mark for not going after Backpage earlier, since Section 230 does not preclude federal criminal investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond Backpage, similar concerns continue to play out with sites that solicit revenge porn, publicly acknowledge potential risks to users or ignore harassment complaints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I'm afraid ... the judge-made law has drifted away from the original purpose of the statute,&quot; says Cox, who is now president of Morgan Lewis Consulting. He says he was shocked to learn how many Section 230 rulings have cited other rulings instead of the actual statute, stretching the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cox argues that websites that are &quot;involved in soliciting&quot; unlawful materials or &quot;connected to unlawful activity&quot; should not be immune under Section 230. Congress should revisit the law, he says, and &quot;make the statute longer and make it crystal clear.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res593548735&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/ap_17024824143064_custom-355f2067a7c468a0e498d6827934561cb212235e-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/ap_17024824143064_custom-355f2067a7c468a0e498d6827934561cb212235e-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backpage.com executives — CEO Carl Ferrer (from left), former owner James Larkin, Chief Operating Officer Andrew Padilla, former owner Michael Lacey — are sworn in to testify before a Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs subcommittee on investigations in January 2017. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Cliff Owen/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Cliff Owen/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cox draws this distinction of websites like Backpage — &lt;em&gt;involved&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;connected&lt;/em&gt; with their content — and sites that are &quot;pure intermediaries.&quot; He wouldn't say whether that term applied to Facebook or Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the Internet giants themselves — as well as Wyden — talk about the law as being rooted in responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The real key to Section 230,&quot; Wyden says, &quot;was making sure that companies in return for that protection — that they wouldn't be sued indiscriminately — were being responsible in terms of policing their platforms.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beckerman of the Internet Association describes Section 230 as &quot;not a blanket amnesty&quot; but a call for responsible policing of platforms. The Internet companies say that on sex trafficking, they actively help investigate cases — and that generally, without Section 230, websites would resort to more censorship or decide to know as little as possible about what happens on their platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Danielle Citron, a University of Maryland law professor who authored the book &lt;em&gt;Hate Crimes in Cyberspace&lt;/em&gt;, argues that responsibility is exactly what is missing from the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Yes, let's think about the consequences for speech,&quot; she says, pointing to the flip side of the freewheeling Internet. &quot;There are countless individuals who are chased offline as a result of cyber mobs and harassment.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res593568618&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/ap_39348704874_custom-bc950dc456c6b4533b841bd5324e9216dc45c73c-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/ap_39348704874_custom-bc950dc456c6b4533b841bd5324e9216dc45c73c-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People rally in 2014 at the Washington state Supreme Court, which heard a case filed by three victims of sex trafficking against Backpage.com, saying the website helped promote the exploitation of children. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Rachel La Corte/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Rachel La Corte/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A rift among companies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politically, the story of Section 230 has recently taken a surprising turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Backpage saga has galvanized lawmakers to act on bills amending Section 230 with the goal of stemming online sex trafficking. The legislation allows more state and civil lawsuits against websites related to online sex trafficking, for &quot;knowingly assisting, supporting or facilitating&quot; crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate passed the bill Wednesday, sending it to President Trump for his signature. The White House has supported the legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for the first time, after years of staunch defiance, the Internet Association came out in support of legislation to change Section 230, shocking smaller Internet companies and digital-rights groups by breaking ranks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry giants are narrowly threading the needle. After the bill passed the House, the Internet Association said the industry not only is &quot;committed to ending trafficking online&quot; but also &quot;will defend against attempts to weaken these crucial protections&quot; of Section 230.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We all share the same goal,&quot; the association's Beckerman told NPR, &quot;and that's to ensure that victims are able to have justice they need, but also enable our companies to stop this practice.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engine, a group advocating on behalf of smaller Internet companies, argues that Silicon Valley behemoths like Google, Facebook and Twitter can handle more lawsuits and the legal uncertainty that would smother a startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not the last challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wyden points out that these are the very same platforms facing massive scrutiny for being manipulated by Russian operatives during the 2016 election, making it a politically touchy moment for the companies to fight over sex-trafficking legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The big companies have a lot of egg on their face over the election, and nobody wants to be seen as being soft on sex trafficking,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wyden and Cox have opposed the legislation to amend Section 230, along with groups including Engine and the Center for Democracy and Technology. Opponents of the bill say it could lead to crimes moving deeper into the dark web and to websites resorting to more censorship or ignorance of what happens on their platforms to avoid liability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Rob Portman, R-Ohio, author of the Senate bill, says the tech community &quot;overreacted&quot; to amending Section 230 &quot;to the point that they weren't willing to look at the obvious problem, which is that it's been abused to sell people online.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wyden says all this should be a wake-up call for Silicon Valley:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If the technology companies do not wake up to their responsibilities — and use the power 230 gives them — to better protect the public against sex trafficking and countries that try to hack our political system, you bet that companies can expect (this legislation) will not be the last challenge for them.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPR researcher Will Chase and Business Desk intern Ian Wren contributed to this report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res592247501&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage567789605&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2017/12/01/567789605/cyntoia-brown-case-highlights-how-child-sex-trafficking-victims-are-prosecuted&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/2017\/12\/01\/567789605\/cyntoia-brown-case-highlights-how-child-sex-trafficking-victims-are-prosecuted&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/12/01/1201_cyntoia_sq-9b60e006fbd2007d2403f87043ddce771cd55fb1-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/12/01/1201_cyntoia_sq-9b60e006fbd2007d2403f87043ddce771cd55fb1-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Cyntoia Brown Case Highlights How Child Sex Trafficking Victims Are Prosecuted&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 15:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mononokay</dc:creator>
<og:title>Section 230: A Key Legal Shield For Facebook, Google Is About To Change</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2018/03/21/591622450/section-230-a-key-legal-shield-for-facebook-google-is-about-to-change</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The 1996 law is praised by the tech industry as the core pillar of Internet freedom. But its path also runs through some of the darkest corners of the Web, such as online sex trafficking of children.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/14/gettyimages-475157855_wide-8398f741be67de796a3f39b3a691b6a5acc37909.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2018/03/21/591622450/section-230-a-key-legal-shield-for-facebook-google-is-about-to-change</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cutting ‘Old Heads’ at IBM</title>
<link>http://features.propublica.org/ibm/ibm-age-discrimination-american-workers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://features.propublica.org/ibm/ibm-age-discrimination-american-workers/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;opening&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead-in&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt;or nearly a half century,&lt;/span&gt; IBM came as close as any company to bearing the torch for the American Dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the world’s dominant technology firm, payrolls at International Business Machines Corp. swelled to nearly a quarter-million U.S. white-collar workers in the 1980s. Its profits helped underwrite a broad agenda of racial equality, equal pay for women and an unbeatable offer of great wages and something close to lifetime employment, all in return for unswerving loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;promotion&quot; readability=&quot;-19.459459459459&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Email Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up to get ProPublica’s major investigations delivered to your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Do you have information about age discrimination at IBM?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/getinvolved/left-ibm-layoffs-retirements&quot;&gt;Let us know.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;But when high tech suddenly started shifting and companies went global, IBM faced the changing landscape with a distinction most of its fiercest competitors didn’t have: a large number of experienced and aging U.S. employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company reacted with a strategy that, in the words of one confidential planning document, would “correct seniority mix.” It slashed IBM’s U.S. workforce by as much as three-quarters from its 1980s peak, replacing a substantial share with younger, less-experienced and lower-paid workers and sending many positions overseas. ProPublica estimates that in the past five years alone, IBM has eliminated more than 20,000 American employees ages 40 and over, about 60 percent of its estimated total U.S. job cuts during those years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In making these cuts, IBM has flouted or outflanked U.S. laws and regulations intended to protect later-career workers from age discrimination, according to a ProPublica review of internal company documents, legal filings and public records, as well as information provided via interviews and questionnaires filled out by more than 1,000 former IBM employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among ProPublica’s findings, IBM:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Denied older workers information the law says they need in order to decide whether they’ve been victims of age bias, and required them to sign away the right to go to court or join with others to seek redress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeted people for layoffs and firings with techniques that tilted against older workers, even when the company rated them high performers. In some instances, the money saved from the departures went toward hiring young replacements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converted job cuts into retirements and took steps to boost resignations and firings. The moves reduced the number of employees counted as layoffs, where high numbers can trigger public disclosure requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encouraged employees targeted for layoff to apply for other IBM positions, while quietly advising managers not to hire them and requiring many of the workers to train their replacements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Told some older employees being laid off that their skills were out of date, but then brought them back as contract workers, often for the same work at lower pay and fewer benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;IBM declined requests for the numbers or age breakdown of its job cuts. ProPublica provided the company with a 10-page summary of its findings and the evidence on which they were based. IBM spokesman Edward Barbini said that to respond the company needed to see copies of all documents cited in the story, a request ProPublica could not fulfill without breaking faith with its sources. Instead, ProPublica provided IBM with detailed descriptions of the paperwork. Barbini declined to address the documents or answer specific questions about the firm’s policies and practices, and instead issued the following statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are proud of our company and our employees’ ability to reinvent themselves era after era, while always complying with the law. Our ability to do this is why we are the only tech company that has not only survived but thrived for more than 100 years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With nearly 400,000 people worldwide, and tens of thousands still in the U.S., IBM remains a corporate giant. How it handles the shift from its veteran baby-boom workforce to younger generations will likely influence what other employers do. And the way it treats its experienced workers will eventually affect younger IBM employees as they too age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifty years ago, Congress made it illegal with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eeoc.gov/laws/statutes/adea.cfm&quot;&gt;Age Discrimination in Employment Act&lt;/a&gt;, or ADEA, to treat older workers differently than younger ones with only a few exceptions, such as jobs that require special physical qualifications. And for years, judges and policymakers treated the law as essentially on a par with prohibitions against discrimination on the basis of race, gender, sexual orientation and other categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent decades, however, the courts have responded to corporate pleas for greater leeway to meet global competition and satisfy investor demands for rising profits by expanding the exceptions and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/americans-age-discrimination-eroding-protection-under-the-law&quot;&gt;shrinking the protections against age bias&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Age discrimination is an open secret like sexual harassment was until recently,” said Victoria Lipnic, the acting chair of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, or EEOC, the independent federal agency that administers the nation’s workplace anti-discrimination laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everybody knows it’s happening, but often these cases are difficult to prove” because courts have weakened the law, Lipnic said. “The fact remains it’s an unfair and illegal way to treat people that can be economically devastating.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many companies have sought to take advantage of the court rulings. But the story of IBM’s downsizing provides an unusually detailed portrait of how a major American corporation systematically identified employees to coax or force out of work in their 40s, 50s and 60s, a time when many are still productive and need a paycheck, but face huge hurdles finding anything like comparable jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dislocation caused by IBM’s cuts has been especially great because until recently the company encouraged its employees to think of themselves as “IBMers” and many operated under the assumption that they had career-long employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the ax suddenly fell, IBM provided almost no information about why an employee was cut or who else was departing, leaving people to piece together what had happened through websites, listservs and Facebook groups such as “Watching IBM” or “Geographically Undesirable IBM Marketers,” as well as informal support groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marjorie Madfis, at the time 57, was a New York-based digital marketing strategist and 17-year IBM employee when she and six other members of her nine-person team — all women in their 40s and 50s — were laid off in July 2013. The two who remained were younger men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since her specialty was one that IBM had said it was expanding, she asked for a written explanation of why she was let go. The company declined to provide it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/portrait-madfis-02-480*320-f3f0df.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt; Marjorie Madfis was among seven women in their 40s and 50s laid off from their IBM marketing team in White Plains, New York, in 2013. The two members who remained were younger men. “The only explanation is our age,” says Madfis. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Demetrius Freeman for ProPublica)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They got rid of a group of highly skilled, highly effective, highly respected women, including me, for a reason nobody knows,” Madfis said in an interview. “The only explanation is our age.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Paulson, also 57, a senior manager with 18 years at IBM, had been on the road for more than a year overseeing hundreds of workers across two continents as well as hitting his sales targets for new services, when he got a phone call in October 2015 telling him he was out. He said the caller, an executive who was not among his immediate managers, cited “performance” as the reason, but refused to explain what specific aspects of his work might have fallen short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took Paulson two years to land another job, even though he was equipped with an advanced degree, continuously employed at high-level technical jobs for more than three decades and ready to move anywhere from his Fairview, Texas, home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s tough when you’ve worked your whole life,” he said. “The company doesn’t tell you anything. And once you get to a certain age, you don’t hear a word from the places you apply.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Henry, a 61-year-old IBM sales and technical specialist who loved being on the road, had just returned to his Columbus home from a business trip in August 2016 when he learned he’d been let go. When he asked why, he said an executive told him to “keep your mouth shut and go quietly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry was jobless more than a year, ran through much of his savings to cover the mortgage and health insurance and applied for more than 150 jobs before he found a temporary slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you’re over 55, forget about preparing for retirement,” he said in an interview. “You have to prepare for losing your job and burning through every cent you’ve saved just to get to retirement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM’s latest actions aren’t anything like what most ex-employees with whom ProPublica talked expected from their years of service, or what today’s young workers think awaits them — or are prepared to deal with — later in their careers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In a fast-moving economy, employers are always going to be tempted to replace older workers with younger ones, more expensive workers with cheaper ones, those who’ve performed steadily with ones who seem to be up on the latest thing,” said Joseph Seiner, an employment law professor at the University of South Carolina and former appellate attorney for the EEOC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But it’s not good for society,” he added. “We have rules to try to maintain some fairness in our lives, our age-discrimination laws among them. You can’t just disregard them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/illo-wire-A-480*42-4ba30e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;old-heads-neednt-apply&quot;&gt;‘Old Heads’ Needn’t Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead-in&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt;or much of its history,&lt;/span&gt; IBM viewed its fate and that of its predominantly U.S. workforce as inseparable. By the late 1960s, the company’s grip on the mainframe computer business had grown so great the Justice Department sued it for monopolizing the industry, a case that dragged on for years before being dropped as “without merit.” Such dominance convinced executives they could deliver extraordinary workplace stability in return for loyal service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When recessions occur or there is a major product shift, some companies handle the resulting workforce imbalances by letting people go,” explained an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4415012-IBM-About-Your-Company-1984-Excerpt.html&quot;&gt;employee handbook&lt;/a&gt; of the 1980s. By contrast, IBM “retrains, reassigns and even relocates employees.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For their part, continued the handbook, employees must be “flexible, willing to change, work overtime, and adapt to new situations quickly.” The logic behind the bargain was that “people are a treasured resource.” At IBM, “they are treated like one.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But within a decade, IBM had stumbled not once but three times, in ways that would come to cost both the company and its workers. First, it failed to appreciate the “major product shift” behind a new chip technology that first entered people’s lives as the guts of pocket calculators and cheap digital watches and was making possible increasingly powerful and networked personal computers that undercut the company’s mainframe business. Second, it misjudged its employees’ reaction to switching to a kind of pension that no longer rewarded older, long-service workers. IBM workers responded with a lawsuit that forced the company to settle by paying more than $300 million and reinstating expensive traditional pensions for more than 100,000 of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And by the early years of the new century, IBM was falling behind again by failing to quickly devise innovative uses for the internet like its new rivals, Google, Facebook and Amazon. As it slipped, the company began having second thoughts about the price of unbending loyalty to its long-serving workforce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/document-gray-hairs-480*343-c196e0.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt; This excerpt from a 2006 IBM Business Consulting Services paper titled “The Maturing Workforce” refers to baby-boomer employees as “gray hairs” and “old heads.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4414883-Maturing-Workforce-feus01291-1.html&quot;&gt;Read the full report.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a little-noticed paper issued in 2006 by the London office of one of the company’s consulting arms, executives praised boomers’ experience, but described them as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4414883-Maturing-Workforce-feus01291-1.html&quot;&gt;“gray hairs” and “old heads.”&lt;/a&gt; While recognizing that older workers were important to high-tech employers such as IBM, it concluded that “successor generations … are generally much more innovative and receptive to technology than baby boomers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper was subsequently cited in an age discrimination lawsuit in U.S. District Court in Pennsylvania. Before the complaint was settled last year, the plaintiffs alleged in a filing: “IBM’s Boomer employees — being labeled by IBM’s own research as uncollaborative, skeptical of leadership, technologically unsophisticated, less innovative and generally out of touch with IBM’s brand, customers and objectives — were shown the door in droves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time IBM’s current CEO, Virginia “Ginni” Rometty, took over in 2012, the company had shifted its personnel focus to millennials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rometty launched a major overhaul that aimed to make IBM a major player in the emerging technologies of cloud services, big data analytics, mobile, security and social media, or what came to be known inside as CAMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, she sought to sharply increase hiring of people born after 1980.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“CAMS are driven by Millennial Traits,” declared a slide presentation for an invitation-only IBM event in New York in December 2014. Not only were millennials in sync with the new technologies, but they were also attuned to the collaborative, consensus-driven modes of work these technologies demanded, company researchers said they’d discovered. Millennials “are not likely to make decisions in isolation,” the presentation said, but instead “depend on analytic technologies to help them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, people 50 or over are “more dubious” of analytics, “place less stock in the advantages data offers,” and are less “motivated to consult their colleagues or get their buy in … It’s Baby Boomers who are the outliers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The message was clear. To succeed at the new technologies, the company must, in the words of the presentation, “become one with the Millennial mindset.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4415015-Executive-Summary-Myths-Exaggerations-and.html&quot;&gt;Similar language&lt;/a&gt; found its way into a variety of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4414982-Tsounos-Discovery-Demand-6-30-17.html&quot;&gt;IBM presentations&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4414981-Transforming-to-Next-Gen.html&quot;&gt;subsequent years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even before the New York conference, IBM had begun a major effort to recruit millennial employees. It launched a blog, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20150214235249/http://themillennialexperience.weebly.com:80/about.html&quot;&gt;The Millennial Experience&lt;/a&gt;,” and a hashtag on Twitter, #IBMillennial.” It began an online and print advertising campaign primarily featuring young people. It established a “Millennial Corps,” a network of more than 5,000 young IBMers whom Rometty and other top executives said they’d &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/3059849/these-millennials-have-become-the-top-decision-makers-at-ibm&quot;&gt;regularly consult&lt;/a&gt; before making business decisions. And it sharply improved benefits, like parental leave, especially important to younger employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its initiatives won IBM &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/ibm/responsibility/2014/ibmer/employee-inclusion.html&quot;&gt;plaudits&lt;/a&gt; from women’s groups; lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender organizations; human rights and disability associations; indeed advocates for just about every class of people protected under U.S. equal employment opportunity laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the entire effort was guided by something that then-IBM brand strategist Bill Grady told the 2014 conference: “What’s good for Millennials is good for everyone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;exit-strategy&quot;&gt;Exit Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead-in&quot;&gt;As IBM trained its sights&lt;/span&gt; on younger workers, it also took steps to change the way it dealt with those who’d spent many years on the job. It embraced a legal strategy that made it much easier for the company to dismiss older workers, and to do so in ways that minimized legal consequences and largely avoided public attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until 2014, IBM had provided &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4417473-2013-IBM-Layoff-Disclosure.html&quot;&gt;two lists&lt;/a&gt; to workers getting laid off. One showed the positions and ages, but not the names, of all the people laid off from their business units at the same time. The other showed the positions and ages of all those staying on. For example, Madfis, the digital marketing strategist, got a list when she was let go in July 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such lists are common in corporate layoffs, thanks to a disclosure requirement added to the ADEA in 1990. The reason for the new rule was that virtually all employers had begun making severance pay and other parting benefits contingent on a laid-off worker signing away the right to sue the company. Congress wanted to make sure that before employees signed such waivers they understood enough to make “knowing and voluntary” decisions about whether they might have been targeted because of their age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM complied with the disclosure requirement for more than two decades. As a result, even when the company stopped disclosing its U.S. employment totals — and thus its job cuts — the numbers still became known as employees collected and tallied the number of layoffs from lists provided to workers by various company units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;One Departure, Two Letters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Just a few months after receiving a layoff notice, the same employee received a congratulatory letter about retiring.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/document-ibm-layoff-notice-360*459-3af16e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/document-ibm-reitrement-letter-360*459-00c980.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So after it ran into political flak for its workforce reductions, IBM decided to stop giving out the lists. When Diane Moos, 62, of Long Beach, California, lost her job as a systems security specialist in May 2016, she had no way of knowing how many people had been laid off with her, or their ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM spokesman Doug Shelton &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.insurancejournal.com/news/national/2014/05/13/328904.htm&quot;&gt;said at the time&lt;/a&gt; the company was acting out of concern for its workers who had complained the disclosures “infringed on employee privacy” — even though the lists contained no names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did IBM get around the legal requirement for the disclosures? With a move that even critics acknowledge is ingenious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company’s pre-2014 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4417466-2013-IBM-Layoff-Separation-Agreement.html&quot;&gt;layoff documents&lt;/a&gt; required employees receiving severance to waive all bias claims based on “race, national origin, ancestry, color, creed, religion, sex, sexual orientation, pregnancy, marital status, age … disability, medical condition, or veteran status.” The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4417464-2016-IBM-Layoff-Separation-Agreement.html&quot;&gt;new documents&lt;/a&gt; deleted “age” from the waiver list. In fact, they specifically said employees were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; waiving their right when it came to age and &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; pursue age discrimination cases against the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, the new documents added, employees had to waive the right to take their age cases to court. Instead, they had to pursue them through private arbitration. What’s more, they had to keep them confidential and pursue them alone. They couldn’t join with other workers to make a case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the new documents in place, IBM was no longer asking laid-off workers to sign away their right to complain about age bias so, the company’s lawyers told the EEOC, the disclosure requirement in the 1990 amendments to the age act no longer applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics say the company’s argument is hard to square with the statute’s clear requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You have a law that says older workers being laid off need this information and employers are obligated to provide it. You have a company that’s not providing it,” said David Lopez, the former general counsel for the EEOC. “How can this not be undercutting the intent of the law?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their relationships with both workers and customers, American corporations are making increasingly heavy use of arbitration, contending the process is fair and saves all parties time and legal costs. The Supreme Court has repeatedly expanded the right of companies to require that disputes be settled by arbitrators rather than judges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to employment claims, studies have found that arbitrators overwhelmingly favor employers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1586&amp;amp;context=articles#page=39&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt; by Cornell University law and labor relations specialist Alexander Colvin found that workers &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2018&amp;amp;context=articles&quot;&gt;win only 19 percent of the time&lt;/a&gt; when their cases are arbitrated. By contrast, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?referer=https://www.google.com/&amp;amp;httpsredir=1&amp;amp;article=1586&amp;amp;context=articles&quot;&gt;they win 36 percent of the time&lt;/a&gt; when they go to federal court, and 57 percent in state courts. Average payouts when an employee wins follow a similar pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given those odds, and having signed away their rights to go to court, some laid-off IBM workers have chosen the one independent forum companies can’t deny them: the U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. That’s where Moos, the Long Beach systems security specialist, and several of her colleagues, turned for help when they were laid off. In their complaints to the agency, they said they’d suffered age discrimination because of the company’s effort to “drastically change the IBM employee age mix … to be seen as a startup.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its formal reply to the EEOC, IBM said that age couldn’t have been a factor in their dismissals. Among the reasons it cited: The managers who decided on the layoffs were in their 40s and therefore older too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/illo-typewriter-3x2-FINAL-480*320-1ae44e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;tilting-the-table&quot;&gt;Tilting the Table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead-in&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap wide&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;hether IBM is staying within&lt;/span&gt; U.S. age laws as it cuts from and adds to its workforce turns largely on how and why the company chooses individuals to be eliminated. While executives say they never target older workers, internal company documents and interviews suggest otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider, for example, a planning presentation that former IBM executives said was drafted by heads of a business unit carved out of IBM’s once-giant software group and charged with pursuing the “C,” or cloud, portion of the company’s CAMS strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation laid out plans for substantially altering the unit’s workforce. It was shown to company leaders including Diane Gherson, the senior vice president for human resources, and James Kavanaugh, recently elevated to chief financial officer. Its language was couched in the argot of “resources,” IBM’s term for employees, and “EP’s,” its shorthand for early professionals or recent college graduates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the goals: “Shift headcount mix towards greater % of Early Professional hires.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the means: “[D]rive a more aggressive performance management approach to enable us to hire and replace where needed, and fund an influx of EPs to correct seniority mix.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the expected results: “[A] significant reduction in our workforce of 2,500 resources.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A slide from a similar presentation prepared last spring for the same leaders called for “re-profiling current talent” to “create room for new talent.” Presentations for 2015 and 2016 for the 50,000-employee software group also included plans for “aggressive performance management” and emphasized the need to “maintain steady attrition to offset hiring.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM declined to answer questions about whether either presentation was turned into company policy. The description of the planned moves matches what hundreds of older ex-employees told ProPublica they believe happened to them: They were ousted because of their age. The company used their exits to hire replacements, many of them young; to ship their work overseas; or to cut its overall headcount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ed Alpern, now 65, of Austin, started his 39-year run with IBM as a Selectric typewriter repairman. He ended as a project manager in October of 2016 when, he said, his manager told him he could either leave with severance and other parting benefits or be given a bad job review — something he said he’d never previously received — and risk being fired without them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albert Poggi, now 70, was a three-decade IBM veteran and ran the company’s Palisades, New York, technical center where clients can test new products. When notified in November of 2016 he was losing his job to layoff, he asked his bosses why, given what he said was a history of high job ratings. “They told me,” he said, “they needed to fill it with someone newer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentations from the software group, as well as the stories of ex-employees like Alpern and Poggi, square with internal documents from two other major IBM business units. The documents for all three cover some or all of the years from 2013 through the beginning of 2018 and deal with job assessments, hiring, firing and layoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documents detail practices that appear at odds with how IBM says it treats its employees. In many instances, the practices in effect, if not intent, tilt against the company’s older U.S. workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, IBM spokespeople and lawyers have said the company never considers a worker’s age in making decisions about layoffs or firings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But one 2014 document reviewed by ProPublica includes dates of birth. An ex-IBM employee familiar with the process said executives from one business unit used it to decide about layoffs or other job changes for nearly a thousand workers, almost two-thirds of them over 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documents from subsequent years show that young workers are protected from cuts for at least a limited period of time. A 2016 slide presentation prepared by the company’s global technology services unit, titled “U.S. Resource Action Process” and used to guide managers in layoff procedures, includes bullets for categories considered “ineligible” for layoff. Among them: “early professional hires,” meaning recent college graduates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;picture-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/document-cams-slide-480*349-4878aa.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
This slide, from an invitation-only IBM conference in New York in December 2014, suggests that the company’s future success in marketing emerging technologies depended on how well it understood and embraced the generation born after 1980.
&lt;p&gt;In responding to age-discrimination complaints that ex-employees file with the EEOC, lawyers for IBM say that front-line managers make all decisions about who gets laid off, and that their decisions are based strictly on skills and job performance, not age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ProPublica reviewed spreadsheets that indicate front-line managers hardly acted alone in making layoff calls. Former IBM managers said the spreadsheets were prepared for upper-level executives and kept continuously updated. They list hundreds of employees together with codes like “lift and shift,” indicating that their jobs were to be lifted from them and shifted overseas, and details such as whether IBM’s clients had approved the change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An examination of several of the spreadsheets suggests that, whatever the criteria for assembling them, the resulting list of those marked for layoff was skewed toward older workers. A 2016 spreadsheet listed more than 400 full-time U.S. employees under the heading “REBAL,” which refers to “rebalancing,” the process that can lead to laying off workers and either replacing them or shifting the jobs overseas. Using the job search site LinkedIn, ProPublica was able to locate about 100 of these employees and then obtain their ages through public records. Ninety percent of those found were 40 or older. Seventy percent were over 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM frequently cites its history of encouraging diversity in its responses to EEOC complaints about age discrimination. “IBM has been a leader in taking positive actions to ensure its business opportunities are made available to individuals without regard to age, race, color, gender, sexual orientation and other categories,” a lawyer for the company wrote in a May 2017 letter. “This policy of non-discrimination is reflected in all IBM business activities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ProPublica found at least one company business unit using a point system that disadvantaged older workers. The system awarded points for attributes valued by the company. The more points a person garnered, according to the former employee, the more protected she or he was from layoff or other negative job change; the fewer points, the more vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrangement appears on its face to favor younger newcomers over older veterans. Employees were awarded points for being relatively new at a job level or in a particular role. Those who worked for IBM for fewer years got more points than those who’d been there a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ex-employee familiar with the process said a 2014 spreadsheet from that business unit, labeled “IBM Confidential,” was assembled to assess the job prospects of more than 600 high-level employees, two-thirds of them from the U.S. It included employees’ years of service with IBM, which the former employee said was used internally as a proxy for age. Also listed was an assessment by their bosses of their career trajectories as measured by the highest job level they were likely to attain if they remained at the company, as well as their point scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tilt against older workers is evident when employees’ years of service are compared with their point scores. Those with no points and therefore most vulnerable to layoff had worked at IBM an average of more than 30 years; those with a high number of points averaged half that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps even more striking is the comparison between employees’ service years and point scores on the one hand and their superiors’ assessments of their career trajectories on the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with many American employers, IBM has argued it needs to shed older workers because they’re no longer at the top of their games or lack “contemporary” skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But among those sized up in the confidential spreadsheet, fully 80 percent of older employees — those with the most years of service but no points and therefore most vulnerable to layoff — were rated by superiors as good enough to stay at their current job levels or be promoted. By contrast, only a small percentage of younger employees with a high number of points were similarly rated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No major company would use tools to conduct a layoff where a disproportionate share of those let go were African Americans or women,” said Cathy Ventrell-Monsees, senior attorney adviser with the EEOC and former director of age litigation for the senior lobbying giant AARP. “There’s no difference if the tools result in a disproportionate share being older workers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the point system that disadvantaged older workers in layoffs, other documents suggest that IBM has made increasingly aggressive use of its job-rating machinery to pave the way for straight-out firings, or what the company calls “management-initiated separations.” Internal documents suggest that older workers were especially targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like in many companies, IBM employees sit down with their managers at the start of each year and set goals for themselves. IBM graded on a scale of 1 to 4, with 1 being top-ranked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;promotion&quot; readability=&quot;-22.003184713376&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; readability=&quot;7.4904458598726&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Eroding Protection Under the Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Older Americans who face discrimination on the job can’t rely on the courts as much as earlier generations did. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/americans-age-discrimination-eroding-protection-under-the-law&quot;&gt;Read more.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those rated as 3 or 4 were given formal short-term goals known as personal improvement plans, or PIPs. Historically many managers were lenient, especially toward those with 3s whose ratings had dropped because of forces beyond their control, such as a weakness in the overall economy, ex-employees said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But within the past couple of years, IBM appears to have decided the time for leniency was over. For example, a software group planning document for 2015 said that, over and above layoffs, the unit should seek to fire about 3,000 of the unit’s 50,000-plus workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make such deep cuts, the document said, executives should strike an “aggressive performance management posture.” They needed to double the share of employees given low 3 and 4 ratings to at least 6.6 percent of the division’s workforce. And because layoffs cost the company more than outright dismissals or resignations, the document said, executives should make sure that more than 80 percent of those with low ratings get fired or forced to quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the 2015 document said the division should work “to attract the best and brightest early professionals” to replace up to two-thirds of those sent packing. A more recent planning document — the presentation to top executives Gherson and Kavanaugh for a business unit carved out of the software group — recommended using similar techniques to free up money by cutting current employees to fund an “influx” of young workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a recent interview, Poggi said he was resigned to being laid off. “Everybody at IBM has a bullet with their name on it,” he said. Alpern wasn’t nearly as accepting of being threatened with a poor job rating and then fired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpern had a particular reason for wanting to stay on at IBM, at least until the end of last year. His younger son, Justin, then a high school senior, had been named a National Merit semifinalist. Alpern wanted him to be able to apply for one of the company’s Watson scholarships. But IBM had recently narrowed eligibility so only the children of current employees could apply, not also retirees as it was until 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpern had to make it through December for his son to be eligible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in August, he said, his manager ordered him to retire. He sought to buy time by appealing to superiors. But he said the manager’s response was to threaten him with a bad job review that, he was told, would land him on a PIP, where his work would be scrutinized weekly. If he failed to hit his targets — and his managers would be the judges of that — he’d be fired and lose his benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpern couldn’t risk it; he retired on Oct. 31. His son, now a freshman on the dean’s list at Texas A&amp;amp;M University, didn’t get to apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I can think of only a couple regrets or disappointments over my 39 years at IBM,”” he said, “and that’s one of them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/illo-scissors-crop-FINAL-480*207-f2233c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;congratulations-on-your-retirement&quot;&gt;’Congratulations on Your Retirement!’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead-in&quot;&gt;Like any company in the U.S.,&lt;/span&gt; IBM faces few legal constraints to reducing the size of its workforce. And with its no-disclosure strategy, it eliminated one of the last regular sources of information about its employment practices and the changing size of its American workforce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there remained the question of whether recent cutbacks were big enough to trigger state and federal requirements for disclosure of layoffs. And internal documents, such as a slide in a 2016 presentation titled “Transforming to Next Generation Digital Talent,” suggest executives worried that “winning the talent war” for new young workers required IBM to improve the “attractiveness of (its) culture and work environment,” a tall order in the face of layoffs and firings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the company apparently has sought to put a softer face on its cutbacks by recasting many as voluntary rather than the result of decisions by the firm. One way it has done this is by converting many layoffs to retirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ex-employees told ProPublica that, faced with a layoff notice, they were just as happy to retire. Others said they felt forced to accept a retirement package and leave. Several actively objected to the company treating their ouster as a retirement. The company nevertheless processed their exits as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project manager Ed Alpern’s departure was treated in company paperwork as a voluntary retirement. He didn’t see it that way, because the alternative he said he was offered was being fired outright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorilynn King, a 55-year-old IT specialist who worked from her home in Loveland, Colorado, had been with IBM almost as long as Alpern by May 2016 when her manager called to tell her the company was conducting a layoff and her name was on the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King said the manager told her to report to a meeting in Building 1 on IBM’s Boulder campus the following day. There, she said, she found herself in a group of other older employees being told by an IBM human resources representative that they’d all be retiring. “I have NO intention of retiring,” she remembers responding. “I’m being laid off.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProPublica has collected documents from 15 ex-IBM employees who got layoff notices followed by a retirement package and has talked with many others who said they received similar paperwork. Critics say the sequence doesn’t square well with the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This country has banned mandatory retirement,” said Seiner, the University of South Carolina law professor and former EEOC appellate lawyer. “The law says taking a retirement package has to be voluntary. If you tell somebody ‘Retire or we’ll lay you off or fire you,’ that’s not voluntary.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, the company’s retirement paperwork included a letter from Rometty, the CEO, that read, in part, “I wanted to take this opportunity to wish you well on your retirement … While you may be retiring to embark on the next phase of your personal journey, you will always remain a valued and appreciated member of the IBM family.” Ex-employees said IBM stopped sending the letter last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM has also embraced another practice that leads workers, especially older ones, to quit on what appears to be a voluntary basis. It substantially reversed its pioneering support for telecommuting, telling people who’ve been working from home for years to begin reporting to certain, often distant, offices. Their other choice: Resign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Harlan had worked as an IBM marketing strategist from his home in Moscow, Idaho, for 15 years when a manager told him last year of orders to reduce the performance ratings of everybody at his pay grade. Then in February last year, when he was 50, came an internal video from IBM’s new senior vice president, Michelle Peluso, which announced plans to improve the work of marketing employees by ordering them to work “shoulder to shoulder.” Those who wanted to stay on would need to “co-locate” to offices in one of six cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early last year, Harlan received an email congratulating him on “the opportunity to join your team in Raleigh, North Carolina.” He had 30 days to decide on the 2,600-mile move. He resigned in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/portrait-harlan-06-480*582-2bfb10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt; David Harlan worked for IBM for 15 years from his home in Moscow, Idaho, where he also runs a drama company. Early last year, IBM offered him a choice: Move 2,600 miles to Raleigh-Durham to begin working at an office, or resign. He left in June. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Rajah Bose for ProPublica)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Peluso video was leaked to the press, an IBM spokeswoman told the Wall Street Journal that the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/ibm-a-pioneer-of-remote-work-calls-workers-back-to-the-office-1495108802&quot;&gt;vast majority&lt;/a&gt;” of people ordered to change locations and begin reporting to offices did so. IBM Vice President Ed Barbini said in an initial email exchange with ProPublica in July that the new policy affected only about 2,000 U.S. employees and that “most” of those had agreed to move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But employees across a wide range of company operations, from the systems and technology group to analytics, told ProPublica they’ve also been ordered to co-locate in recent years. Many IBMers with long service said that they quit rather than sell their homes, pull children from school and desert aging parents. IBM declined to say how many older employees were swept up in the co-location initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They basically knew older employees weren’t going to do it,” said Eileen Maroney, a 63-year-old IBM product manager from Aegean, South Carolina, who, like Harlan, was ordered to move to Raleigh or resign. “Older people aren’t going to move. It just doesn’t make any sense.” Like Harlan, Maroney left IBM last June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having people quit rather than being laid off may help IBM avoid disclosing how much it is shrinking its U.S. workforce and where the reductions are occurring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doleta.gov/programs/factsht/warn.htm&quot;&gt;federal WARN Act&lt;/a&gt;, adopted in the wake of huge job cuts and factory shutdowns during the 1980s, companies laying off 50 or more employees who constitute at least one-third of an employer’s workforce at a site have to give advance notice of layoffs to the workers, public agencies and local elected officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar laws in some states where IBM has a substantial presence are even stricter. California, for example, requires advanced notice for layoffs of 50 or more employees, no matter what the share of the workforce. New York requires notice for 25 employees who make up a third.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the laws were drafted to deal with abrupt job cuts at individual plants, they can miss reductions that occur over long periods among a workforce like IBM’s that was, at least until recently, widely dispersed because of the company’s work-from-home policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM’s training sessions to prepare managers for layoffs suggest the company was aware of WARN thresholds, especially in states with strict notification laws such as California. A 2016 document entitled “Employee Separation Processing” and labeled “IBM Confidential” cautions managers about the “unique steps that must be taken when processing separations for California employees.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ProPublica review of five years of WARN disclosures for a dozen states where the company had large facilities that shed workers found no disclosures in nine. In the other three, the company alerted authorities of just under 1,000 job cuts — 380 in California, 369 in New York and 200 in Minnesota. IBM’s reported figures are well below the actual number of jobs the company eliminated in these states, where in recent years it has shuttered, sold off or leveled plants that once employed vast numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, other employers in the same 12 states reported layoffs last year alone totaling 215,000 people. They ranged from giant Walmart to Ostrom’s Mushroom Farms in Washington state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether IBM operated within the rules of the WARN act, which are notoriously fungible, could not be determined because the company declined to provide ProPublica with details on its layoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-second-act-but-poorer&quot;&gt;A Second Act, But Poorer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead-in&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap wide&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;ith 35 years at IBM&lt;/span&gt; under his belt, Ed Miyoshi had plenty of experience being pushed to take buyouts, or early retirement packages, and refusing them. But he hadn’t expected to be pushed last fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miyoshi, of Hopewell Junction, New York, had some years earlier launched a pilot program to improve IBM’s technical troubleshooting. With the blessing of an IBM vice president, he was busily interviewing applicants in India and Brazil to staff teams to roll the program out to clients worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interviews may have been why IBM mistakenly assumed Miyoshi was a manager, and so emailed him to eliminate the one U.S.-based employee still left in his group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That was me,” Miyoshi realized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his sign-off email to colleagues shortly before Christmas 2016, Miyoshi, then 57, wrote: “I am too young and too poor to stop working yet, so while this is good-bye to my IBM career, I fully expect to cross paths with some of you very near in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He did, and perhaps sooner than his colleagues had expected; he started as a subcontractor to IBM about two weeks later, on Jan. 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miyoshi is an example of older workers who’ve lost their regular IBM jobs and been brought back as contractors. Some of them — not Miyoshi — became contract workers after IBM told them their skills were out of date and no longer needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employment law experts said that hiring ex-employees as contractors can be legally dicey. It raises the possibility that the layoff of the employee was not for the stated reason but perhaps because they were targeted for their age, race or gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM appears to recognize the problem. Ex-employees say the company has repeatedly told managers — most recently earlier this year — not to contract with former employees or sign on with third-party contracting firms staffed by ex-IBMers. But ProPublica turned up dozens of instances where the company did just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/portrait-miyoshi-05-480*320-b4d861.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt; Only two weeks after IBM laid him off in December 2016, Ed Miyoshi of Hopewell Junction, New York, started work as a subcontractor to the company. But he took a $20,000-a-year pay cut. “I’m not a millionaire, so that’s a lot of money to me,” he says. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Demetrius Freeman for ProPublica)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responding to a question in a confidential questionnaire from ProPublica, one 35-year company veteran from New York said he knew exactly what happened to the job he left behind when he was laid off. “I’M STILL DOING IT. I got a new gig eight days after departure, working for a third-party company under contract to IBM doing the exact same thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, of course, ex-employees are happy to have another job, even if it is connected with the company that laid them off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry, the Columbus-based sales and technical specialist who’d been with IBM’s “resiliency services” unit, discovered that he’d lost his regular IBM job because the company had purchased an Indian firm that provided the same services. But after a year out of work, he wasn’t going to turn down the offer of a temporary position as a subcontractor for IBM, relocating data centers. It got money flowing back into his household and got him back where he liked to be, on the road traveling for business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compensation most ex-IBM employees make as contractors isn’t comparable. While Henry said he collected the same dollar amount, it didn’t include health insurance, which cost him $1,325 a month. Miyoshi said his paycheck is 20 percent less than what he made as an IBM regular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I took an over $20,000 hit by becoming a contractor. I’m not a millionaire, so that’s a lot of money to me,” Miyoshi said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lower pay isn’t the only problem ex-IBM employees-now-subcontractors face. This year, Miyoshi’s payable hours have been cut by an extra 10 “furlough days.” Internal documents show that IBM repeatedly furloughs subcontractors without pay, often for two, three or more weeks a quarter. In some instances, the furloughs occur with little advance notice and at financially difficult moments. In one document, for example, it appears IBM managers, trying to cope with a cost overrun spotted in mid-November, planned to dump dozens of subcontractors through the end of the year, the middle of the holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former IBM employees now on contract said the company controls costs by notifying contractors in the midst of projects they have to take pay cuts or lose the work. Miyoshi said that he originally started working for his third-party contracting firm for 10 percent less than at IBM, but ended up with an additional 10 percent cut in the middle of 2017, when IBM notified the contractor it was slashing what it would pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many ex-employees, there are few ways out. Henry, for example, sought to improve his chances of landing a new full-time job by seeking assistance to finish a college degree through a federal program designed to retrain workers hurt by offshoring of jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when he contacted the Ohio state agency that administers the Trade Adjustment Assistance, or TAA, program, which provides assistance to workers who lose their jobs for trade-related reasons, he was told IBM hadn’t submitted necessary paperwork. State officials said Henry could apply if he could find other IBM employees who were laid off with him, information that the company doesn’t provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TAA is overseen by the Labor Department but is operated by states under individual agreements with Washington, so the rules can vary from state to state. But generally employers, unions, state agencies and groups of employers can petition for training help and cash assistance. Labor Department data compiled by the advocacy group Global Trade Watch shows that employers apply in about 40 percent of cases. Some groups of IBM workers have obtained retraining funds when they or their state have applied, but records dating back to the early 1990s show IBM itself has applied for and won taxpayer assistance only once, in 2008, for three Chicago-area workers whose jobs were being moved to India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/illo-punchcard-crop-FINAL-480*307-5466ea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;teasing-new-jobs&quot;&gt;Teasing New Jobs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead-in&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;s IBM eliminated thousands&lt;/span&gt; of jobs in 2016, David Carroll, a 52-year-old Austin software engineer, thought he was safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His job was in mobile development, the “M” in the company’s CAMS strategy. And if that didn’t protect him, he figured he was only four months shy of qualifying for a program that gives employees who leave within a year of their three-decade mark access to retiree medical coverage and other benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the layoff notice Carroll received March 2 gave him three months — not four — to come up with another job. Having been a manager, he said he knew the gantlet he’d have to run to land a new position inside IBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, he went at it hard, applying for more than 50 IBM jobs, including one for a job he’d successfully done only a few years earlier. For his effort, he got one offer — the week after he’d been forced to depart. He got severance pay but lost access to what would have been more generous benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Kishkill, then 60, of Hillsdale, New Jersey, had made a similar calculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A senior systems engineer, Kishkill recognized the danger of layoffs, but assumed he was immune because he was working in systems security, the “S” in CAMS and another hot area at the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The precaution did him no more good than it had Carroll. Kishkill received a layoff notice the same day, along with 17 of the 22 people on his systems security team, including Diane Moos. The notice said that Kishkill could look for other jobs internally. But if he hadn’t landed anything by the end of May, he was out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a daughter who was a senior in high school headed to Boston University, he scrambled to apply, but came up dry. His last day was May 31, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, the fruitless search for jobs within IBM is the last straw, a final break with the values the company still says it embraces. Combined with the company’s increasingly frequent request that departing employees train their overseas replacements, it has left many people bitter. Scores of ex-employees interviewed by ProPublica said that managers with job openings told them they weren’t allowed to hire from layoff lists without getting prior, high-level clearance, something that’s almost never given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProPublica reviewed documents that show that a substantial share of recent IBM layoffs have involved what the company calls “lift and shift,“ lifting the work of specific U.S. employees and shifting it to specific workers in countries such as India and Brazil. For example, a document summarizing U.S. employment in part of the company’s global technology services division for 2015 lists nearly a thousand people as layoff candidates, with the jobs of almost half coded for lift and shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ex-employees interviewed by ProPublica said the lift-and-shift process required their extensive involvement. For example, shortly after being notified she’d be laid off, Kishkill’s colleague, Moos, was told to help prepare a “knowledge transfer” document and begin a round of conference calls and email exchanges with two Indian IBM employees who’d be taking over her work. Moos said the interactions consumed much of her last three months at IBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-chapters&quot;&gt;Next Chapters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead-in&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap wide&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;hile IBM has managed&lt;/span&gt; to keep the scale and nature of its recent U.S. employment cuts largely under the public’s radar, the company drew some unwanted attention during the 2016 presidential campaign, when then-candidate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computerworld.com/article/3139394/it-careers/at-campaigns-end-trump-takes-a-swipe-at-ibm.html&quot;&gt;Donald Trump lambasted&lt;/a&gt; it for eliminating 500 jobs in Minnesota, where the company has had a presence for a half century, and shifting the work abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company also has caught flak — in places like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investigativepost.org/2018/02/19/taxpayers-fund-ibms-dysfunctional-call-center/&quot;&gt;Buffalo, New York&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraphherald.com/news/tri-state/html_ed60c223-cd97-55b3-b65e-a2386c0828a2.html&quot;&gt;Dubuque, Iowa&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.columbiatribune.com/b3ed78d6-f248-11e6-af28-576bcdc3ea18.html&quot;&gt;Columbia, Missouri&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theadvocate.com/baton_rouge/news/business/article_2d8f6c4a-a215-11e7-894c-b32baeed8a86.html&quot;&gt;Baton Rouge, Louisiana&lt;/a&gt; — for promising jobs in return for state and local incentives, then failing to deliver. In all, according to public officials in those and other places, IBM promised to bring on 3,400 workers in exchange for as much as $250 million in taxpayer financing but has hired only about half as many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Trump’s victory, Rometty, in a move at least partly aimed at courting the president-elect, pledged to hire 25,000 new U.S. employees by 2020. Spokesmen said the hiring would increase IBM’s U.S. employment total, although, given its continuing job cuts, the addition is unlikely to approach the promised hiring total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When The New York Times ran a story last fall saying IBM now has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/28/technology/ibm-india.html&quot;&gt;more employees in India&lt;/a&gt; than the U.S., Barbini, the corporate spokesman, rushed to declare, “The U.S. has always been and remains IBM’s center of gravity.” But his stream of accompanying &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ebarbini/status/913336040932433920&quot;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt; and graphics focused as much on the company’s record for racking up patents as hiring people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM has long been aware of the damage its job cuts can do to people. In a series of internal training documents to prepare managers for layoffs in recent years, the company has included this warning: “Loss of a job … often triggers a grief reaction similar to what occurs after a death.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most, though not all, of the ex-IBM employees with whom ProPublica spoke have weathered the loss and re-invented themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marjorie Madfis, the digital marketing strategist, couldn’t land another tech job after her 2013 layoff, so she headed in a different direction. She started a nonprofit called Yes She Can Inc. that provides job skills development for young autistic women, including her 21-year-old daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After almost two years of looking and desperate for useful work, Brian Paulson, the widely traveled IBM senior manager, applied for and landed a position as a part-time rural letter carrier in Plano, Texas. He now works as a contract project manager for a Las Vegas gaming and lottery firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ed Alpern, who started at IBM as a Selectric typewriter repairman, watched his son go on to become a National Merit Scholar at Texas A&amp;amp;M University, but not a Watson scholarship recipient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lori King, the IT specialist and 33-year IBM veteran who’s now 56, got in a parting shot. She added an addendum to the retirement papers the firm gave her that read in part: “It was never my plan to retire earlier than at least age 60 and I am not committing to retire. I have been informed that I am impacted by a resource action effective on 2016-08-22, which is my last day at IBM, but I am NOT retiring.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King has aced more than a year of government-funded coding boot camps and university computer courses, but has yet to land a new job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Harlan still lives in Moscow, Idaho, after refusing IBM’s “invitation” to move to North Carolina, and is artistic director of the Moscow Art Theatre (Too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ed Miyoshi is still a technical troubleshooter working as a subcontractor for IBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ed Kishkill, the senior systems engineer, works part time at a local tech startup, but pays his bills as an associate at a suburban New Jersey Staples store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, Paul Henry was back on the road, working as an IBM subcontractor in Detroit, about 200 miles from where he lived in Columbus. On Jan. 8, he put in a 14-hour day and said he planned to call home before turning in. He died in his sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;waypoint-section closer&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Do you have information about age discrimination at IBM?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/getinvolved/left-ibm-layoffs-retirements&quot;&gt;Let us know.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/illo-wire-A-480*42-4ba30e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot; readability=&quot;12.46783625731&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/people/peter-gosselin&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://features.propublica.org/ibm/assets/images/generated/peter-gosselin-400x400-360*360-6603bd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/people/peter-gosselin&quot;&gt;Peter Gosselin&lt;/a&gt; joined ProPublica as a contributing reporter in January 2017 to cover aging. He has covered the U.S. and global economies for, among others, the Los Angeles Times and The Boston Globe, focusing on the lived experiences of working people. He is the author of “High Wire: The Precarious Financial Lives of American Families.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;hr/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 12:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mwexler</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://features.propublica.org/ibm/ibm-age-discrimination-american-workers/</og:url>
<og:title>Cutting ‘Old Heads’ at IBM</og:title>
<og:description>As it scrambled to compete in the internet world, the once-dominant tech company cut tens of thousands of U.S. workers, hitting its most senior employees hardest and flouting rules against age bias.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.propublica.org/images/externals/20180322-ibm-1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://features.propublica.org/ibm/ibm-age-discrimination-american-workers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Number systems of the world, sorted by complexity of counting (2006)</title>
<link>http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Number Systems of the World&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; text=&quot;#000000&quot; link=&quot;#0000FF&quot; vlink=&quot;#663399&quot; alink=&quot;#FF0000&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;45.918627987594&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/index.html&quot;&gt;A Playground of Thoughts&lt;/a&gt; &amp;gt; Number Systems of the World&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number_title.gif&quot; width=&quot;306&quot; height=&quot;59&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number Systems of the World&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/numberj.html&quot;&gt;Japanese page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am collecting number systems of world languages. The languages shown below are listed according to the complexity of the way of counting numbers in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I translate words included in number words to English, and I use '+' and '×' for implicit additions and multiplications. For instance, I explain the French words &lt;em&gt;vingt et un&lt;/em&gt; (21) and &lt;em&gt;quatre-vingt-dix-neuf&lt;/em&gt; (99) as &quot;20 and 1&quot; and &quot;4 × 20 + 10 + 9&quot; respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if you find a mistake. A list of numbers in your language is welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some pages use the character set UTF-8. Latest web browsers automatically choose a proper character set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;33.402269861286&quot;&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;th&gt;Complexity&lt;br /&gt;Rank&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Language&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Language Family, Subfamily&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Native speakers&lt;br /&gt;population&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Spoken Area&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.8181818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/huli.html&quot;&gt;Huli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;(new)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Trans-New Guinea, Main Section&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;70,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Papua New Guinea&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;4.7590361445783&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/ndom.html&quot;&gt;Ndom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;(new)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Trans-New Guinea, Kolopom&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;450&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Frederik Hendrik Island&lt;br /&gt;(near New Guinea)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/nimbia.html&quot;&gt;Nimbia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Afro-Asiatic, Chadic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nigeria&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.758064516129&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/hindi.html&quot;&gt;Hindi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Indo-Iranian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;182,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Northern India&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/tzotzil.html&quot;&gt;Tzotzil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mayan, Cholan-Tzeltalan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;265,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mexico&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/ainu.html&quot;&gt;Ainu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(language isolate)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hokkaidô (Japan)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/alamblak.html&quot;&gt;Alamblak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sepik-Ramu, Sepik&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;1,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Papua New Guinea&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.65&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/nahuatl.html&quot;&gt;Nahuatl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uto-Aztecan, Southern Uto-Aztecan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;1,377,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mexico&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.625&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/malagasy.html&quot;&gt;Malagasy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Austronesian, Malayo-Polynesian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;10,156,900&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Madagascar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.7142857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/yoruba.html&quot;&gt;Yoruba&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Niger-Congo, Atlantic-Congo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;20,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nigeria, Benin&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/traditional_welsh.html&quot;&gt;Welsh (Traditional)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;(new)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Celtic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;580,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wales (U.K.)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/breton.html&quot;&gt;Breton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Celtic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;500,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brittany (France)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.7966101694915&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/manx.html&quot;&gt;Manx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Celtic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Isle of Man (U.K., extinct)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/scots_gaelic.html&quot;&gt;Scots Gaelic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Celtic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;94,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scotland (U.K.)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.5636363636364&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/georgian.html&quot;&gt;Georgian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;South Caucasian, Georgian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;4,103,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Georgia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/danish.html&quot;&gt;Danish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Germanic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;5,292,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Denmark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.6619718309859&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/javanese.html&quot;&gt;Javanese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Austronesian, Malayo-Polynesian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;75,500,800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Java (Indonesia)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/latin.html&quot;&gt;Latin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Italic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Italy (extinct)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/french.html&quot;&gt;French&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Italic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;72,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;France&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.7931034482759&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/zulu.html&quot;&gt;Zulu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Niger-Congo, Atlantic-Congo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;9,142,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;South Africa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/basque.html&quot;&gt;Basque&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Basque&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;580,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Basque (France, Spain)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.7313432835821&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/arabic.html&quot;&gt;Arabic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Afro-Asiatic, Semitic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;West Asia, North Africa (ancient)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.7169811320755&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/ganda.html&quot;&gt;Ganda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Niger-Congo, Atlantic-Congo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;3,025,440&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uganda&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/maltese.html&quot;&gt;Maltese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Afro-Asiatic, Semitic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;370,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Malta&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/assyrian.html&quot;&gt;Assyrian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Afro-Asiatic, Semitic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;217,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Iraq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.5714285714286&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/kurmanji.html&quot;&gt;Kurmanji&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Indo-Iranian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;7,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Turkey&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/dutch.html&quot;&gt;Dutch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Germanic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;20,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Netherlands&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;28&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/german.html&quot;&gt;German&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Germanic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;98,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.671875&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/swahili.html&quot;&gt;Swahili&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Niger-Congo, Atlantic-Congo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;5,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kenya, Tanzania&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/ojibwa.html&quot;&gt;Ojibwa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Algic, Algonquian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;50,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada, U.S.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/italian.html&quot;&gt;Italian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Italic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;37,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Italy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/spanish.html&quot;&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Italic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;332,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spain, Latin America&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/swiss_french.html&quot;&gt;Swiss French&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Italic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;1,272,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Switzerland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;34&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/tigrinya.html&quot;&gt;Tigrinya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Afro-Asiatic, Semitic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;6,060,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Eritrea, Ethiopia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;35&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/turkish.html&quot;&gt;Turkish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Altaic, Turkic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;59,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Turkey&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.4583333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/balkan_romani.html&quot;&gt;Balkan Romani&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Indo-Iranian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;1,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Former Yugoslavia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/hungarian.html&quot;&gt;Hungarian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uralic, Finno-Ugric&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;14,500,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hungary&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.6769230769231&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;38&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/tagalog.html&quot;&gt;Tagalog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Austronesian, Malayo-Polynesian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;17,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Philippines&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;39&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/polari.html&quot;&gt;Polari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(unclassified)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;U.K.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/scots.html&quot;&gt;Scots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Germanic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;100,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scotland (U.K.)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/english.html&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Germanic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;322,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;U.S., U.K., etc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;42&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/norwegian.html&quot;&gt;Norwegian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Germanic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;5,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Norway&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;43&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/swedish.html&quot;&gt;Swedish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Germanic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;9,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sweden&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.6785714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;44&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/sukuma.html&quot;&gt;Sukuma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Niger-Congo, Atlantic-Congo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;5,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tanzania&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.5714285714286&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/hawaiian.html&quot;&gt;Hawaiian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Austronesian, Malayo-Polynesian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;1,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hawaii&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/finnish.html&quot;&gt;Finnish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uralic, Finno-Ugric&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;6,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Finland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;47&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/estonian.html&quot;&gt;Estonian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uralic, Finno-Ugric&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;1,100,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Estonia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;48&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/romanian.html&quot;&gt;Romanian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Italic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;1,500,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Romania&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;49&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/ancient_japanese.html&quot;&gt;Ancient Japanese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japanese&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japan (ancient)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.5932203389831&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/kiribati.html&quot;&gt;Kiribati&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Austronesian, Malayo-Polynesian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;67,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kiribati&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.758064516129&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/wolof.html&quot;&gt;Wolof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Niger-Congo, Atlantic-Congo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;3,215,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Senegal, Gambia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;52&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/croatian.html&quot;&gt;Croatian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Slavic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;21,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Croatia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.625&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;53&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/seneca.html&quot;&gt;Seneca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Iroquoian, Northern Iroquoian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;U.S.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.5454545454545&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;54&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/indonesian.html&quot;&gt;Indonesian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Austronesian, Malayo-Polynesian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;17,050,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indonesia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;55&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/mandinka.html&quot;&gt;Mandinka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Niger-Congo, Mande&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;914,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Senegal, Gambia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;56&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/wu.html&quot;&gt;Wu Chinese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sino-Tibetan, Chinese&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;77,175,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shanghai (China)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;57&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/tok_pisin.html&quot;&gt;Tok Pisin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Creole, English-based&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;50,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Papua New Guinea&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.4915254237288&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/vietnamese.html&quot;&gt;Vietnamese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Austro-Asiatic, Mon-Khmer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;66,897,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Viet Nam&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.7777777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/igbo.html&quot;&gt;Igbo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Niger-Congo, Atlantic-Congo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;17,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nigeria&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/thai.html&quot;&gt;Thai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Daic, Tai&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;21,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thailand&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;61&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/modern_welsh.html&quot;&gt;Welsh (Modern)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;(new)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indo-European, Celtic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;580,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wales (U.K.)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/aymara.html&quot;&gt;Aymara&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aymaran&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;2,200,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bolivia, Peru&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/cuzco_quechua.html&quot;&gt;Cuzco Quechua&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Quechuan, Quechua II&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;1,500,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Peru&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;64&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/chinook_wawa.html&quot;&gt;Chinook Wawa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pidgin, Amerindian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada, U.S.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/mandarin.html&quot;&gt;Mandarin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sino-Tibetan, Chinese&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;885,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Northern China&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/japanese.html&quot;&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japanese, Japanese&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;125,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;67&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/cantonese.html&quot;&gt;Cantonese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sino-Tibetan, Chinese&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;66,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Guangdong (China)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;68&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/esperanto.html&quot;&gt;Esperanto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(artificial)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;France etc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2.6727272727273&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number/tongan.html&quot;&gt;Tongan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Austronesian, Malayo-Polynesian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;123,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tonga&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://euslchan.tripod.com/index.html&quot;&gt;Numeral Systems of the World's Languages&lt;/a&gt; - an excellent site of a comprehensive list of number systems&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zompist.com/numbers.shtml&quot;&gt;Numbers from 1 to 10 in Over 4000 Languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://members.tripod.com/~rjschellen/IENums.htm&quot;&gt;Numerals in Indo-European Dialects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly enough, it's proven that Chinese-speaking children are better at counting numbers than English-speaking counterparts because of their language. Bilingual children are better at counting when they think in Chinese than in English. The irregularity of the English number system makes it harder for children to count numbers properly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apa.org/monitor/apr99/english.html&quot;&gt;English words may hinder math skills development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psych.ualberta.ca/~jbisanz/Research%20Group/Projects/BCG.htm&quot;&gt;Counting Ability in Bilingual Children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nku.edu/~sheffield/cotterpbyd.html&quot;&gt;Visualization and Explicit Number Naming as a Foundation for Children's Early Work in Mathematics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathematicalbrain.com/int01.html&quot;&gt;The Mathematical Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/index.html&quot;&gt;Return to my homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;Copyright(C) T&lt;small&gt;AKASUGI&lt;/small&gt; Shinji (ts&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/at.gif&quot; width=&quot;18&quot; height=&quot;17&quot; align=&quot;bottom&quot; /&gt;sf.airnet.ne.jp)&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 11:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ColinWright</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.sf.airnet.ne.jp/ts/language/number.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Krita 4.0 – A painting app for cartoonists, illustrators, and concept artists</title>
<link>https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-0-0-released/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-0-0-released/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;main-title&quot;&gt;Krita 4.0.0 Released!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Published    3/22/2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we’re releasing Krita 4.0! A major release with major new features and improvements: improved vector tools, SVG support, a new text tool, Python scripting and much, much, much more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a-CY4hmkg_I?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new splash screen for Krita 4.0, created by Tyson Tan, shows Kiki among the plum blossoms. We had wanted to release Krita 4 last year already, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/en/item/krita-foundation-update/&quot;&gt;trials and tribulations&lt;/a&gt; caused considerable delays. But, like the plum blossoms that &lt;span class=&quot;Y0NH2b CLPzrc&quot;&gt;often bloom most vibrantly when it’s coldest, we have overcome, and Krita 4 is now ready!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kiki_4.0_sm-1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6301&quot; src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kiki_4.0_sm-1-1024x463.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;463&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kiki_4.0_sm-1.png 1024w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kiki_4.0_sm-1-300x136.png 300w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kiki_4.0_sm-1-768x347.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve again created a long, long page with all the details of everything that’s new and improved in Krita 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/en/krita-4-0-release-notes/&quot;&gt;See the full release notes with all changes!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already mentioned SVG support, a new text tool and Python scripting, so here are some other highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/colorize-mask.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-6255&quot; src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/colorize-mask.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;527&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/colorize-mask.png 800w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/colorize-mask-300x198.png 300w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/colorize-mask-768x506.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Masked brushes: add a mask to your brush tip for a more lively effect. This opens up some really cool possibilities!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/waterpaint.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-6247&quot; src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/waterpaint.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;514&quot; height=&quot;316&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New brush presets! We overhauled the entire brush set for Krita 4. Brush presets are now packaged as a bundle, too. And Krita 3’s brush set is available as well, it’s just disabled by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/bundles.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-6434&quot; src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/bundles.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;780&quot; height=&quot;686&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/bundles.png 780w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/bundles-300x264.png 300w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/bundles-768x675.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Known issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krita 4 is a huge step for the Krita project, as big as, if not bigger than the 3.0 release. There are some known issues and caveats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Krita 4 uses SVG for vector layers. This means that Krita 3 files with vector layers may not be loaded entirely correctly. Keep backups!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krita 4’s new text tool is still limited compared to what we wanted to implement. We focused on creating a reliable base and making the text tool work reliably for just one, simple use-case: creating text for comic book balloons, and we’ll continue working on improving and extending the text tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have a new binary build factory for Windows and Linux. Unfortunately, we don’t have 32 bits Windows builds at this point in time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because macOS has a very low limit on shared memory segments, G’Mic cannot work on macOS at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Reference Images Docker has been removed. It was too easy to crash it if invalid image files where present. In Krita 4.1 it will be replaced by a new reference images tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Windows&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note for Windows users: if you encounter crashes, please follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.krita.org/Dr._Mingw_debugger&quot;&gt;these instructions&lt;/a&gt; to use the debug symbols so we can figure out where Krita crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this moment, we do not have 32 bits Windows builds available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that on Windows 7 and 8 you need to install the Universal C Runtime separately to enable Python scripting. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.krita.org/Introduction_to_Python_Scripting#Technical_Details&quot;&gt;manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Linux&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, the appimage does not have working translations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(If, for some reason, Firefox thinks it needs to load this as text: to download, right-click on the link.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/%7Ekritalime/+archive/ubuntu/ppa&quot;&gt;Krita Lime PPA&lt;/a&gt; to install Krita 4.0.0 on Ubuntu and derivatives. We are working on an updated snap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;OSX&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: the gmic-qt and python plugins are not available on macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Source code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;md5sums&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all downloads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Linux appimage and the source tarball are signed. You can retrieve the public key over https here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://share.kde.org/index.php/s/fJ99V5mZvuyD0z8&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;0x58b9596c722ea3bd.asc&lt;/a&gt;. The signatures are &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.kde.org/stable/krita/4.0.0/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Support Krita&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krita is a free and open source project. Please consider supporting the project with &lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/en/support-us/donations/&quot;&gt;donations&lt;/a&gt; or by &lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/en/support-us/shop&quot;&gt;buying training videos or the artbook!&lt;/a&gt; With your support, we can keep the core team working on Krita full-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_6455&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Krita4_Alegoric_final.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6455&quot; src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Krita4_Alegoric_final-1024x507.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;507&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Krita4_Alegoric_final-1024x507.png 1024w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Krita4_Alegoric_final-300x149.png 300w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Krita4_Alegoric_final-768x380.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Artwork by Ramon Miranda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;ssba-classic-2&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssbp-wrap left ssbp--theme-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;ssba_google_share&quot; href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/share?url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-0-0-released/&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/google.png&quot; title=&quot;Google+&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Google+&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google+&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; ssba_sharecount&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;linkedin&quot; class=&quot;ssba_linkedin_share ssba_share_link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/shareArticle?mini=true&amp;amp;url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-0-0-released/&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/linkedin.png&quot; title=&quot;LinkedIn&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on LinkedIn&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linkedin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a data-site=&quot;pinterest&quot; class=&quot;ssba_pinterest_share&quot; href=&quot;javascript:void((function()%7Bvar%20e=document.createElement('script');e.setAttribute('type','text/javascript');e.setAttribute('charset','UTF-8');e.setAttribute('src','//assets.pinterest.com/js/pinmarklet.js?r='+Math.random()*99999999);document.body.appendChild(e)%7D)());&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/pinterest.png&quot; title=&quot;Pinterest&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Pin on Pinterest&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pinterest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; ssba_sharecount&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;reddit&quot; class=&quot;ssba_reddit_share&quot; href=&quot;http://reddit.com/submit?url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-0-0-released/&amp;amp;title=Krita%204.0.0%20Released!&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/reddit.png&quot; title=&quot;Reddit&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Reddit&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reddit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; ssba_sharecount&quot;&gt;120&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;ssba_facebook_share&quot; href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-0-0-released/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/facebook.png&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Facebook&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; ssba_sharecount&quot;&gt;1.1k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;tumblr&quot; class=&quot;ssba_tumblr_share&quot; href=&quot;http://www.tumblr.com/share/link?url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-0-0-released/&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/tumblr.png&quot; title=&quot;tumblr&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Tumblr&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumblr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; ssba_sharecount&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;ssba_twitter_share&quot; href=&quot;http://twitter.com/share?url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-0-0-released/&amp;amp;text=Krita%204.0.0%20Released%21%20&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/twitter.png&quot; title=&quot;Twitter&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Tweet about this on Twitter&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a data-site=&quot;vk&quot; class=&quot;ssba_vk_share ssba_share_link&quot; href=&quot;http://vkontakte.ru/share.php?url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-0-0-released/&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/vk.png&quot; title=&quot;VK&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on VK&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 10:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>reddotX</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-0-0-released/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox Product Roadmap</title>
<link>https://wiki.mozilla.org/Firefox/Roadmap</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://wiki.mozilla.org/Firefox/Roadmap</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;mf-section-0&quot; readability=&quot;46.530586766542&quot;&gt;
&lt;table readability=&quot;2.3561151079137&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/File:Firefox-med-logo.png&quot; class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Firefox-med-logo.png&quot; src=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/images/thumb/f/f2/Firefox-med-logo.png/100px-Firefox-med-logo.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;selflink&quot;&gt;Firefox Product Roadmap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Owner: &lt;strong&gt;Asa Dotzler&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Updated: &lt;strong&gt;2018-03-22&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6279069767442&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Firefox is a key expression of Mozilla's &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/mission/&quot;&gt;mission&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/about/manifesto/&quot;&gt;manifesto&lt;/a&gt;; it represents our vision of a people-centric web experience, as well as a platform and tooling that make it possible to do amazing things with the web.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;In 2018 Firefox browsers will be fast, personal, mobile, and opinionated.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No strategy can capture everything we're doing with the Firefox browsers over the next year, but this document covers the key focus areas: making Firefox browsers even faster, making them more personal, supercharging mobile, and getting opinionated on behalf of users. (All dates are estimates and subject to change.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accomplish fast, Mozilla will continue the Quantum effort, replacing Gecko internal components with those prototyped in the Servo engine and updating and re-writing other areas of Firefox for performance and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To become more personal, Mozilla will invest in making browser extensions easier to build, discover and use with more APIs, and changes to both the browser and the Mozilla add-ons service that expose add-ons to more people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the mobile front, Firefox Klar will be getting the Quantum treatment with performance optimizations and re-writes, Firefox for iOS will be tuned for iPads and gain on-by-default Tracking Protection, and Firefox for FireTV will continue to mature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, in 2018, Firefox will get more opinionated. People on the web deserve a browser that represents people first, a browser that isn't neutral when it comes to advertising, tracking and other dark patterns on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Fast&quot;&gt;Fast&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mf-section-1&quot; readability=&quot;72.99596398634&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People love fast. 2017 was all about making Firefox faster and that's why we called it Firefox Quantum. There's still more room to improve and in 2018 Mozilla will continue to focus on speed. Bringing another significant component over from our research and development engine, Servo, will improve how smooth websites render. Updates to our content painting system will allow the main thread, and thus the browser UI and focused tab, to stay responsive, and changes to our networking stack will result in faster page loads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2017/10/the-whole-web-at-maximum-fps-how-webrender-gets-rid-of-jank/&quot;&gt;WebRender&lt;/a&gt;: With WebRender, we want web apps to run at a silky smooth 60 frames per second (FPS) no matter how big the display is or how much of the page is changing from frame to frame. Initial releases will be for selected Nvidia GPUs. (Firefox 64)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://mozillagfx.wordpress.com/2018/01/09/retained-display-lists/&quot;&gt;Retained Display List&lt;/a&gt;: Gecko will retain the display list between paints, only building a new display list for the parts of the page that changed since we last painted and then merge the new list into the old to get an updated list. (Firefox 60)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1307504&quot;&gt;Race Cache with Network&lt;/a&gt;: When we detect that disk IO may be slow, we send a network request in parallel, and we use the first response that comes back. For users with slow spinning disks and a low latency network, the result would be faster loads. (Firefox 59)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1188435&quot;&gt;TCP fast open&lt;/a&gt;: a TCP extension to speed up the opening of successive TCP connections between two endpoints. (Firefox 60)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://mikeconley.ca/blog/2018/01/11/making-tab-switching-faster-in-firefox-with-tab-warming/&quot;&gt;Tab Warming&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Tab warming&quot; is what we're calling the process of pre-emptively rendering the layers for a tab, and preemptively uploading them to the compositor, when we're pretty sure you're likely to switch to that tab (61)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://mozillagfx.wordpress.com/2017/12/05/off-main-thread-painting/&quot;&gt;Off Main Thread Painting&lt;/a&gt;: With OMTP the visual state of the page is still computed on the main thread, but the potentially costly task of rasterization is passed off to a designated “rasterization thread”, and the main thread can carry on and stay responsive. (Firefox 58 on Windows, 59 on Mac)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1425602&quot;&gt;Async Blocklist Loading&lt;/a&gt;: With async blocklist loading users will see faster startup times. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1272409&quot;&gt;Resize Observer API&lt;/a&gt;: Allows websites to register for resize notifications on specific elements, speeding up web page performance. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1150081&quot;&gt;CSS Containment&lt;/a&gt;: lets web developers opt-in to stricter layout isolation leading to better page performance. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1351107&quot;&gt;UTF Parsing&lt;/a&gt;: an across-the-board load-time win for pages with lots of JS for faster page loading. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1385403&quot;&gt;OOP Extensions for Mac&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1357487&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;: We've already shipped out of process extensions for Windows leading to faster page loads and more browser responsiveness. This year we'll catch up on Mac and Linux. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1371255&quot;&gt;Replace storage.local&lt;/a&gt; implementation: For improved extension performance, we will replace the storage.local implementation with something more efficient. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1361474&quot;&gt;Interpreter ICs&lt;/a&gt;: This will improve interpreter speed increasing the performance of JavaScript on sites and apps. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1336227&quot;&gt;Faster startup first paint&lt;/a&gt;: Firefox will show a browser window as soon as possible after startup, not waiting on the full stack to load. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1401624&quot;&gt;Object-biased NaN Boxing&lt;/a&gt;: a lot of code containing small loops do not benefit from any sort of optimization strategy. With Object-based NaN boxing, we will see improved web page JavaScript performance. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Personal&quot;&gt;Personal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mf-section-2&quot; readability=&quot;62.295081967213&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox has always been the most customizable browser available. This year, we're investing to make Firefox the best option for users to tailor their web experiences to their needs. We'll provide new APIs to make extensions and themes more capable and we'll add features in the browser and at addons.mozilla.org that help people discover and use add-ons that will make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Context-aware AMO: People arrive at AMO for different reasons and with different levels of experience. We'll use the signals we receive to better assist the user with what they came for. (Q4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/data/2017/12/09/add-on-recommendations-for-firefox-users-a-prototype-recommender-system-leveraging-existing-data-sources/&quot;&gt;Telemetry-Aware Add-on Recommender (TAAR)&lt;/a&gt;: we will integrate our add-on recommender with addons.mozilla.org and within Firefox in places like Discovery Pane. (Q4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contextual Feature Recommender: CFR is a system that proactively delivers personalized Firefox feature and extension recommendations to users based on their behaviour. (Q4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1330328&quot;&gt;Expanded Theme Support, and Element Theming Support in Extensions&lt;/a&gt;: Firefox will become more themeable allowing users to customize additional browser components such as &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/showdependencytree.cgi?id=1330328&amp;amp;hide_resolved=1&quot;&gt;sidebars, popups and scroll bars&lt;/a&gt; (Q3) In addition, more APIs will be added to allow themed components to respond to different browser states such as active, inactive, focused and mouse-hover. (Q3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More Extension APIs: Firefox extensions will become more capable with additional features for tab management and organization, including a full implementation of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/WebExtensions/TabHiding&quot;&gt;Tab Hiding&lt;/a&gt; (61) and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1437098&quot;&gt;User Scripts&lt;/a&gt; (61) APIs. Two other highly requested feature areas, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1215064&quot;&gt;Toolbars&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1340930&quot;&gt;Secure Overlays&lt;/a&gt; (Q4) will land an initial set of development APIs, while other feature areas such as &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1427928&quot;&gt;Session Management&lt;/a&gt;, Bookmark Management (Q3) and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/buglist.cgi?component=WebExtensions%3A%20Android&amp;amp;component=WebExtensions%3A%20Compatibility&amp;amp;component=WebExtensions%3A%20Developer%20Tools&amp;amp;component=WebExtensions%3A%20Experiments&amp;amp;component=WebExtensions%3A%20Frontend&amp;amp;component=WebExtensions%3A%20General&amp;amp;component=WebExtensions%3A%20Request%20Handling&amp;amp;component=WebExtensions%3A%20Storage&amp;amp;component=WebExtensions%3A%20Themes&amp;amp;component=WebExtensions%3A%20Untriaged&amp;amp;product=Toolkit&amp;amp;resolution=---&amp;amp;short_desc=clipboard&amp;amp;short_desc_type=allwordssubstr&amp;amp;list_id=14066067&quot;&gt;Clipboard Interaction&lt;/a&gt; (Q2) will be rounded out with incremental APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User-created Themes: In addition to installing themes from Mozilla Add-ons website, Firefox users will be able to easily design, use, and share their own unique browser themes. (October)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide Firefox installers to non-Firefox users visiting AMO. Instead of offering an “Install” button to a non-Firefox client viewing add-ons on AMO, a stub installer may be offered that provides the user with Firefox and the add-on viewed. (May)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://mozilla-lockbox.github.io/&quot;&gt;Lockbox&lt;/a&gt; integration with Firefox: Mozilla's new password manager will integrate with Firefox and Firefox accounts allowing users to take their passwords beyond the browser. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-factor auth for Firefox Accounts: Firefox Accounts will get multi-factor auth via Time-based One-Time Passwords. (Q2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Account Recovery for Firefox Accounts: offer users a first version of our account recovery mechanism which allows users to recover their encrypted data even if they've forgotten their password. (Q3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1325870&quot;&gt;Language Switching&lt;/a&gt;: Provide an interface for users to switch languages and make language pack discovery and installation part of the Firefox UX. (63)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/Firefox/Enterprise_deployment&quot;&gt;Policy Manager&lt;/a&gt;: Firefox will allow computer administrators to customize features (e.g. proxy, default bookmarks, etc.) for their users. The policy manager supports two implementations: A policies.json file in the distribution directory or Window GPO. (Firefox 60)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Mobile&quot;&gt;Mobile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mf-section-3&quot; readability=&quot;58.645785876993&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 we focused almost totally on making desktop Firefox blazing fast with the Quantum effort. This year we expand our focus to include more mobile work, with new products like Lockbox, and targeted feature updates that will make all of our mobile apps silky smooth, more powerful, and a joy to use whether it's Firefox for Android, Firefox for iOS, Firefox for FireTV, or Firefox Focus and Klar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Mobile/GeckoView#Bugs&quot;&gt;Transition Klar to GeckoView&lt;/a&gt;: Currently, the Firefox Klar browser uses WebView to render sites. We're moving to GeckoView, which will bring WebAssembly, WebRTC, WebGL 2, WebVR, and other emerging, modern web technologies to the Klar browser (Q3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Klar Features: Klar will also gain Search and Autocomplete (May), anti-fingerprinting, an A/B testing framework, and Contextual hints (July)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stylo in Firefox for Android: Firefox for Android will be getting some “Quantum” treatment with the incorporation of the Stylo CSS engine. (60)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox for iOS will gain &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1433453&quot;&gt;Drag and Drop from other applications&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1433455&quot;&gt;Full Hardware Keyboard support&lt;/a&gt;, Tracking Protection enabled by default in an upcoming release in early April. More updates and navigational improvements, specifically for iPad will be coming up later in the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updates for Firefox Focus for Android: Firefox Focus will get Search and Autocomplete (May), Request Desktop Site, an A/B testing framework, Contextual hints (July), Find in page and more ad and tracker blocking (December).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox for FireTV matures: Firefox for FireTV will gain custom tiles (Q1), parental controls, Pocket video feed, request desktop site (Q2), and a custom keyboard with Awesomebar powers. (Q3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockbox Mobile apps: People will be able to access their saved passwords in an iOS app with an Android app to follow. (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Opinionated&quot;&gt;Opinionated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mf-section-4&quot; readability=&quot;45.49005609383&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web has grown and changed dramatically over the last two decades and not all for the better. Trackers, intrusive ads and other dark patterns threaten to drive people away from the open web and that's not good for people browsing or publishing. Over the next year or so, Firefox will take a stand against tracking, intrusive ads, and other dark patterns on the web by blocking the worst content and more clearly communicating the privacy and other protections the browser offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Filter certain types of ads by default: Firefox will offer users a simple ad filtering option. We're in the early stages still, researching types of advertisements that should be blocked by default. (Q3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block ad re-targeting: We are working on blocking cross-domain tracking. Details to follow. (Q3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Privacy Controls: We will bring all of our key privacy controls into a single location in the product making them more discoverable and putting users in control of their data privacy experience. (Q3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking Protection Improvements: We would like to make tracking protection more fine-grained allowing users to turn on or off specific types of tracker. We will also opportunistically block trackers when page load performance is adversely impacted. (Q3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1368744&quot;&gt;Global permissions management&lt;/a&gt;: Permission prompts, especially for notifications, have gotten out of control and users must deny them individually at every site that offers them. Firefox will provide users with a way to disable permission prompts globally for Location, Camera, Microphone, and Notifications. (Firefox 59)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1382574&quot;&gt;Block video auto-play&lt;/a&gt;: Firefox will provide users with a way to block video auto-play that doesn't break websites. (62)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mozilla/blurts-server&quot;&gt;Breach Alerts&lt;/a&gt;: Breach alerts will inform a user if a site they've visited has been breached and will ask if the user wants to have their account checked to determine if it was compromised. If it was compromised, some helpful information will be presented to the user. (October)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Web_Platform_and_Tooling_advancements&quot;&gt;Web Platform and Tooling advancements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mf-section-5&quot; readability=&quot;82.928649835346&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The roadmap described above focuses primarily on the Firefox consumer products. Web developers will not be left out and will see significant improvements to the Firefox web platform and our developer and designer tooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Web Components: Implementations of the new consensus-based &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Web_Components/Using_shadow_DOM&quot;&gt;Shadow DOM&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Web_Components/Using_custom_elements&quot;&gt;Custom Elements&lt;/a&gt; are expected to ship in Firefox 63&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://jakearchibald.com/2017/es-modules-in-browsers/&quot;&gt;ES6 Modules&lt;/a&gt;: Allows you to use native ECMAScript modules, for example defining modules with &amp;lt;script type=&quot;module&quot;&amp;gt;, defining fallback scripts with &amp;lt;script nomodule&amp;gt;, and importing code features that have been exported from modules. (60)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/TPE-Layout/Dashboard#CSS_Shapes&quot;&gt;CSS Shapes&lt;/a&gt;: CSS Shapes can be applied to floats. A circle shape on a float will cause inline content to wrap around the circle shape instead of the float's bounding box. (61)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1302685&quot;&gt;Variable Fonts&lt;/a&gt; (OpenType Font Variations): the technology enables a single font file to behave like multiple fonts. (61)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/mozilla.dev.platform/tsevyqfBHLE/lccldWNNBwAJ&quot;&gt;Web Authentication&lt;/a&gt;: an API enabling the creation and use of strong, attested, scoped, public key-based credentials by web applications, for the purpose of strongly authenticating users. (60)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/pointerevents/&quot;&gt;W3C Pointer Events&lt;/a&gt;: creates a single DOM event model to handle pointing input devices such as a mouse, pen/stylus or touch. (59)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1428879&quot;&gt;CSS 'overscroll-behavior'&lt;/a&gt;: allow authors to control the browser's scroll overflow behavior — what happens when the boundary of a scrolling area is reached. (59)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1433716&quot;&gt;3-Panel Inspector&lt;/a&gt;: This feature allows the Rules view to detach into its own dedicated panel. As result, developers have the ability to author and debug CSS at the same time.(61)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1242029&quot;&gt;Shapes Path Editor&lt;/a&gt;: The Shape Path Editor is a developer tool that allows modification of CSS Shapes and Clip Paths right in the browser. In Firefox 61 the platform will support the Shape Outside CSS property and we will extend the tool to go with the platform feature.(61)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1280059&quot;&gt;New Font Tooling&lt;/a&gt;: In Firefox 61, the layout team introduces support for Variable Fonts. We take this opportunity to rethink Firefox' fonts tooling and provide a new experience to developers working on both variable and non-variable fonts. (61 through 63, shipped in steps)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1409965&quot;&gt;Flexbox Inspector&lt;/a&gt;: The Flexbox Inspector will allow developers to highlight and debug the flexbox layout model. In later releases (66) we will add separate tools to analyze Alignment and Sizing of elements. (64)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=devtools-app-panel-m1&quot;&gt;Service Workers panel&lt;/a&gt;: developers need to have a solid Service Worker debugging experience that matches Chrome's experience so they can make sure their apps work in Firefox. (61)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source Maps Excellence: Source Maps are the translation layer for developers to transform and minify their original code with modern tools while keeping it debuggable. Going beyond what any browser currently provides, our tools will map variables and correctly step through original code. (61)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Framework Support: Attract back modern web app developers into our tools by matching up how devtools represent frameworks (components, state, errors, callstacks, etc) to the mental models of developers (Q3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Context-based Devtools Feature Recommendation: Recommend features and extensions based on developers' technologies to level users up into advanced features and developer extensions for a stickier experience. (Q3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onboarding for Chrome devtools users: Show users switching from Chrome around; what's cool, what's different from Chrome and what's new. (Q3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance Profiling for GeckoView: Enable the performance tooling that made Quantum Flow a success for the GeckoView project (61)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote Debugging: Support mobile push needs a solid mobile debugging experience, by replacing WebIDE with a modern and well integrated flow that doesn't get in the way. (62/63)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Firefox_Product_Roadmap_Timeline_.28click_image_to_view_the_spreadsheet.29&quot;&gt;Firefox Product Roadmap Timeline (click image to view the spreadsheet)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mf-section-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1U1IxTOlsaBcRsnJv0XAaVqQLU4otB6h2lG0NDcvWG-E/edit?usp=sharing&quot; title=&quot;Firefox Timeline&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Firefox Timeline&quot; src=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/images/thumb/b/b1/Firefox-timeline-2018-03-21.png/1000px-Firefox-timeline-2018-03-21.png&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1116&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 08:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nachtigall</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://wiki.mozilla.org/Firefox/Roadmap</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>