<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Hundreds of extreme self-citing scientists revealed in new database</title>
<link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;content position-relative cleared clear mq1200-padded&quot; data-component=&quot;article-container&quot; role=&quot;main&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;article-item__header clear cleared pull--both&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article__type&quot;&gt;NEWS FEATURE
&lt;div class=&quot;ml10 article__date&quot;&gt;&lt;time itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot;&gt;19 August 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;article-item__teaser-text serif&quot;&gt;Some highly cited academics seem to be heavy self-promoters — but researchers warn against policing self-citation.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bordered-container clear cleared pull--both&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliations&quot; class=&quot;tab-group text14&quot; role=&quot;tablist&quot; data-test=&quot;author-affiliations&quot; data-tab-group=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0&quot; class=&quot;tab-box js-box-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-head&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;view author info&quot; class=&quot;sans-serif strong tab tab-skin&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; aria-controls=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-content&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Show author information&quot;&gt;Richard Van Noorden &amp;amp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-content&quot; class=&quot;tab-content pin-right grid grid-12 last&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pa10&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-head&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clear cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;align-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;sans-serif&quot;&gt;Search for this author in:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-1&quot; class=&quot;tab-box js-box-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-1-head&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;view author info&quot; class=&quot;sans-serif strong tab tab-skin&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; aria-controls=&quot;author-affiliation-news-1-content&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Show author information&quot;&gt;Dalmeet Singh Chawla&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-1-content&quot; class=&quot;tab-content pin-right grid grid-12 last&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pa10&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;author-affiliation-news-1-head&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clear cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;align-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;sans-serif&quot;&gt;Search for this author in:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;align-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__body serif cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world’s most-cited researchers, according to newly released data, are a curiously eclectic bunch. Nobel laureates and eminent polymaths rub shoulders with less familiar names, such as Sundarapandian Vaidyanathan from Chennai in India. What leaps out about Vaidyanathan and hundreds of other researchers is that many of the citations to their work come from their own papers, or from those of their co-authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaidyanathan, a computer scientist at the Vel Tech R&amp;amp;D Institute of Technology, a privately run institute, is an extreme example: he has received 94% of his citations from himself or his co-authors up to 2017, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.3000384&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.3000384&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;a study in &lt;em&gt;PLoS Biology&lt;/em&gt; this month&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7#ref-CR1&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-action=&quot;anchor-link&quot; data-track-label=&quot;go to reference&quot; data-track-category=&quot;references&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. He is not alone. &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.mendeley.com/datasets/btchxktzyw/1#file-ad4249ac-f76f-4653-9e42-2dfebe5d9b01&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://data.mendeley.com/datasets/btchxktzyw/1#file-ad4249ac-f76f-4653-9e42-2dfebe5d9b01&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;The data set, which lists around 100,000 researchers&lt;/a&gt;, shows that at least 250 scientists have amassed more than 50% of their citations from themselves or their co-authors, while the median self-citation rate is 12.7%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;recommended pull pull--left sans-serif&quot; data-label=&quot;Related&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-017-08404-0&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;recommended article&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;recommended__image&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w400/magazine-assets/d41586-019-02479-7/d41586-019-02479-7_15941128.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study could help to flag potential extreme self-promoters, and possibly ‘citation farms’, in which clusters of scientists massively cite each other, say the researchers. “I think that self-citation farms are far more common than we believe,” says John Ioannidis, a physician at Stanford University in California who specializes in meta-science — the study of how science is done — and who led the work. “Those with greater than 25% self-citation are not necessarily engaging in unethical behaviour, but closer scrutiny may be needed,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data are by far the largest collection of self-citation metrics ever published. And they arrive at a time when funding agencies, journals and others are focusing more on the potential problems caused by excessive self-citation. In July, the Committee on Publication Ethics (COPE), a publisher-advisory body in London, &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/files/COPE_DD_A4_Citation_Manipulation_Jul19_SCREEN_AW2.pdf&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/files/COPE_DD_A4_Citation_Manipulation_Jul19_SCREEN_AW2.pdf&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;highlighted extreme self-citation&lt;/a&gt; as one of the main forms of citation manipulation. This issue fits into broader concerns about an over-reliance on citation metrics for making decisions about hiring, promotions and research funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When we link professional advancement and pay attention too strongly to citation-based metrics, we incentivize self-citation,” says psychologist Sanjay Srivastava at the University of Oregon in Eugene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although many scientists agree that excessive self-citation is a problem, there is little consensus on how much is too much or on what to do about the issue. In part this is because researchers have many legitimate reasons to cite their own work or that of colleagues. Ioannidis cautions that his study should not lead to the vilification of particular researchers for their self-citation rates, not least because these can vary between disciplines and career stages. “It just offers complete, transparent information. It should not be used for verdicts such as deciding that too high self-citation equates to a bad scientist,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data drive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ioannidis and his co-authors didn’t publish their data to focus on self-citation. That’s just one part of their study, which includes a host of standardized citation-based metrics for the most-cited 100,000 or so researchers over the past 2 decades across 176 scientific sub-fields. He compiled the data together with Richard Klavans and Kevin Boyack at analytics firm SciTech Strategies in Albuquerque, New Mexico, and Jeroen Baas, director of analytics at the Amsterdam-based publisher Elsevier; the data all come from Elsevier’s proprietary Scopus database. The team hopes that its work will make it possible to identify factors that might be driving citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most eye-catching part of the data set is the self-citation metrics. It is already possible to see how many times an author has cited their own work by looking up their citation record in subscription databases such as Scopus and Web of Science. But without a view across research fields and career stages, it’s difficult to put these figures into context and compare one researcher to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;recommended pull pull--left sans-serif&quot; data-label=&quot;Related&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/brazilian-citation-scheme-outed-1.13604&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;recommended article&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;recommended__image&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w400/magazine-assets/d41586-019-02479-7/d41586-019-02479-7_17074630.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vaidyanathan’s record stands out as one of the most extreme — and it has brought certain rewards. Last year, Indian politician Prakash Javadekar, who is currently the nation’s environment minister, but at the time was responsible for higher education, presented Vaidyanathan with a 20,000-rupee (US$280) award for being among the nation’s top researchers by measures of productivity and citation metrics. Vaidyanathan did not reply to &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;’s request for comment, but he has previously defended his citation record in reply to questions about Vel Tech posted on Quora, the online question-and-answer platform. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/How-did-Vel-Tech-University-get-such-a-high-rank-on-the-top-Asian-universities-list&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://www.quora.com/How-did-Vel-Tech-University-get-such-a-high-rank-on-the-top-Asian-universities-list&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;In 2017, he wrote that&lt;/a&gt; because research is a continuous process, “the next work cannot be carried on without referring to previous work”, and that self-citing wasn’t done with the intention of misleading others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two other researchers who have gained plaudits and cite themselves heavily are Theodore Simos, a mathematician whose website lists affiliations at King Saud University in Riyadh, Ural Federal University in Yekaterinburg, Russia, and the Democritus University of Thrace in Komotini, Greece; and Claudiu Supuran, a medicinal chemist at the University of Florence, Italy, who also lists an affiliation at King Saud University. Both Simos, who amassed around 76% of his citations from himself or his co-authors, and Supuran (62%) were &lt;a href=&quot;https://hcr.clarivate.com/#&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://hcr.clarivate.com/#&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;last year named on a list of 6,000 “world-class researchers selected for their exceptional research performance” produced by Clarivate Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, an information-services firm in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, which owns Web of Science. Neither Simos nor Supuran replied to &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;’s requests for comment; Clarivate said that it was aware of the issue of unusual self-citation patterns and that the methodology used to calculate its list might change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What to do about self-citations?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past few years, researchers have been paying closer attention to self-citation. A 2016 preprint, for instance, suggested that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/men-cite-themselves-more-than-women-do-1.20176&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/men-cite-themselves-more-than-women-do-1.20176&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;male academics cite their own papers, on average, 56% more&lt;/a&gt; than female academics do&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7#ref-CR2&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-action=&quot;anchor-link&quot; data-track-label=&quot;go to reference&quot; data-track-category=&quot;references&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, although a replication analysis last year suggested that this might be an effect of higher self-citation among productive authors of any gender, who have more past work to cite&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7#ref-CR3&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-action=&quot;anchor-link&quot; data-track-label=&quot;go to reference&quot; data-track-category=&quot;references&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In 2017, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.natureindex.com/news-blog/italian-scientists-increase-self-citations-in-response-to-promotion-policy&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://www.natureindex.com/news-blog/italian-scientists-increase-self-citations-in-response-to-promotion-policy&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;study showed that scientists in Italy began citing themselves more heavily&lt;/a&gt; after a controversial 2010 policy was introduced that required academics to meet productivity thresholds to be eligible for promotion&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7#ref-CR4&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-action=&quot;anchor-link&quot; data-track-label=&quot;go to reference&quot; data-track-category=&quot;references&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. And last year, Indonesia’s research ministry, which uses a citation-based formula to allocate funding for research and scholarship, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cen.acs.org/policy/publishing/Indonesias-scientists-voice-concerns-countrys/96/web/2018/12&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://cen.acs.org/policy/publishing/Indonesias-scientists-voice-concerns-countrys/96/web/2018/12&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;said some researchers had gamed their scores&lt;/a&gt; using unethical practices, including excessive self-citations and groups of academics citing each other. The ministry said that it had stopped funding 15 researchers and planned to exclude self-citations from its formula, although researchers tell &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; that this hasn’t yet happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the idea of publicly listing individuals’ self-citation rates, or evaluating them on the basis of metrics corrected for self-citation, is highly contentious. For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/files/COPE_DD_A4_Citation_Manipulation_Jul19_SCREEN_AW2.pdf&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/files/COPE_DD_A4_Citation_Manipulation_Jul19_SCREEN_AW2.pdf&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;in a discussion document issued last month&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7#ref-CR5&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-action=&quot;anchor-link&quot; data-track-label=&quot;go to reference&quot; data-track-category=&quot;references&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, COPE argued against excluding self-citations from metrics because, it said, this “doesn’t permit a nuanced understanding of when self-citation makes good scholarly sense”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;recommended pull pull--left sans-serif&quot; data-label=&quot;Related&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/the-top-100-papers-1.16224&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;recommended article&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;recommended__image&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w400/magazine-assets/d41586-019-02479-7/d41586-019-02479-7_15245886.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2017, Justin Flatt, a biologist then at the University of Zurich in Switzerland, called for more clarity around scientists’ self-citation records&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7#ref-CR6&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-action=&quot;anchor-link&quot; data-track-label=&quot;go to reference&quot; data-track-category=&quot;references&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Flatt, who is now at the University of Helsinki, &lt;a href=&quot;https://physicstoday.scitation.org/do/10.1063/PT.6.3.20170919a/full/&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://physicstoday.scitation.org/do/10.1063/PT.6.3.20170919a/full/&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;suggested publishing a self-citation index&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;-index, along the lines of the &lt;em&gt;h&lt;/em&gt;-index productivity indicator used by many researchers. An &lt;em&gt;h&lt;/em&gt;-index of 20 indicates that a researcher has published 20 papers with at least 20 citations; likewise, an &lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;-index of 10 would mean a researcher had published 10 papers that had each received at least 10 self-citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flatt, who has received a grant to collate data for the &lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;-index, agrees with Ioannidis that the focus of this kind of work shouldn’t be about establishing thresholds for acceptable scores, or naming and shaming high self-citers. “It’s never been about criminalizing self-citations,” he says. But as long as academics continue to promote themselves using the &lt;em&gt;h&lt;/em&gt;-index, there’s a case for including the &lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;-index for context, he argues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Context matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An unusual feature of Ioannidis’s study is its wide definition of self-citation, which includes citations by co-authors. This is intended to catch possible instances of citation farming; however, it does inflate self-citation scores, says Marco Seeber, a sociologist at Ghent University in Belgium. Particle physics and astronomy, for example, often have papers with hundreds or even thousands of co-authors, and that raises the self-citation average across the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ioannidis says that it’s possible to account for some systematic differences by comparing researchers to the average for their country, career stage and discipline. But more generally, he says, the list is drawing attention to cases that deserve a closer look. And there’s another way to spot problems, by examining the ratio of citations received to the number of papers in which those citations appear. Simos, for example, has received 10,458 citations from only 1,029 papers — meaning that on average, he gets more than 10 citations in each paper mentioning his work. Ioannidis says this metric, when combined with the self-citation metric, is a good flag for potentially excessive self-promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed intensity--high&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;figure__image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;//media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-02479-7/d41586-019-02479-7_17081338.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-02479-7/d41586-019-02479-7_17081338.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;figure__caption sans-serif&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr10&quot;&gt;Source: Jeroen Baas, unpublished analysis of Scopus database.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In unpublished work, Elsevier’s Baas says that he has applied a similar analysis to a much larger data set of 7 million scientists: that is, all authors listed in Scopus who have published more than 5 papers. In this data set, Baas says, the median self-citation rate is 15.5%, but as many as 7% of authors have self-citation rates above 40%. This proportion is much higher than among the top-cited scientists, because many of the 7 million researchers have only a few citations overall or are at the start of their careers. Early-career scientists tend to have higher self-citation rates because their papers haven’t had time to amass many citations from others (see ‘The youth effect’).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed intensity--high&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;figure__image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;//media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-02479-7/d41586-019-02479-7_17081280.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-02479-7/d41586-019-02479-7_17081280.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;figure__caption sans-serif&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr10&quot;&gt;Source: Jeroen Baas, unpublished analysis of Scopus database.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Baas’s data, Russia and Ukraine stand out as having high median self-citation rates (see ‘Country by country’). His analysis also shows that some fields stick out — such as nuclear and particle physics, and astronomy and astrophysics — owing to their many multi-authored papers (see ‘Physics envy?’). Baas says he has no plans to publish his data set, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed intensity--high&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;figure__image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;//media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-02479-7/d41586-019-02479-7_17081282.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-02479-7/d41586-019-02479-7_17081282.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;figure__caption sans-serif&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr10&quot;&gt;Source: Jeroen Baas, unpublished analysis of Scopus database.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Not good for science?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the &lt;em&gt;PLoS Biology&lt;/em&gt; study identifies some extreme self-citers and suggests ways to look for others, some researchers say they aren’t convinced that the self-citation data set will be helpful, in part because this metric varies so much by research discipline and career stage. “Self-citation is much more complex than it seems,” says Vincent Larivière, an information scientist at the University of Montreal in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Srivastava adds that the best way to tackle excessive self-citing — and other gaming of citation-based indicators — isn’t necessarily to publish ever-more-detailed standardized tables and composite metrics to compare researchers against each other. These might have their own flaws, he says, and such an approach risks sucking scientists even further into a world of evaluation by individual-level metrics, the very problem that incentivizes gaming in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We should ask editors and reviewers to look out for unjustified self-citations,” says Srivastava. “And maybe some of these rough metrics have utility as a flag of where to look more closely. But, ultimately, the solution needs to be to realign professional evaluation with expert peer judgement, not to double down on metrics.” Cassidy Sugimoto, an information scientist at Indiana University Bloomington, agrees that more metrics might not be the answer: “Ranking scientists is not good for science.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ioannidis, however, says his work is needed. “People already rely heavily on individual-level metrics anyhow. The question is how to make sure that the information is as accurate and as carefully, systematically compiled as possible,” he says. “Citation metrics cannot and should not disappear. We should make the best use of them, fully acknowledging their many limitations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;emphasis&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/d41586-019-02479-7&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;references&quot; class=&quot;references&quot; data-toggle=&quot;anchor-links-section&quot; data-label=&quot;References&quot; data-concertina=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;section aria-labelledby=&quot;Bib1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;serif article-section js-article-section cleared clear&quot; id=&quot;Bib1-section&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;js-section-title section-title strong position-relative tighten-line-height background-gray-light pt20 pb6 pl0 pr20 standard-space-below small-space-above mq640-pt10 mq640-pb10 mq640-pl20 mq640-mt0 mq640-ml-20 mq640-mr-20 extend-left&quot; id=&quot;Bib1&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pl20 mq875-pl0 js-collapsible-section&quot; id=&quot;Bib1-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-container-section=&quot;references&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;clean-list ma0 standard-space-below indented-list&quot; data-test=&quot;references-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;small-space-below border-gray-medium border-bottom-1 position-relative js-ref-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;citation&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Article&quot; data-test=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;indented-counter serif h2 tighten-line-height text-right position-absolute grade-c-hide&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tiny-space-below&quot; id=&quot;ref-CR1&quot;&gt;Ioannidis, J. P. A., Baas, J., Klavans, R. &amp;amp; Boyack, K. W. &lt;em&gt;PLoS Biol.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;, e3000384 (2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;small-space-below border-gray-medium border-bottom-1 position-relative js-ref-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;citation&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Article&quot; data-test=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;indented-counter serif h2 tighten-line-height text-right position-absolute grade-c-hide&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tiny-space-below&quot; id=&quot;ref-CR2&quot;&gt;King, M. M., Bergstrom, C. T., Correll, S. J., Jacquet, J. &amp;amp; West, J. D. &lt;em&gt;Socius&lt;/em&gt; https://doi.org/10.1177/2378023117738903 (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;small-space-below border-gray-medium border-bottom-1 position-relative js-ref-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;citation&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Article&quot; data-test=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;indented-counter serif h2 tighten-line-height text-right position-absolute grade-c-hide&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tiny-space-below&quot; id=&quot;ref-CR3&quot;&gt;Mishra, S., Fegley, B. D., Diesner, J. &amp;amp; Torvik, V. I. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt;, e0195773 (2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;small-space-below border-gray-medium border-bottom-1 position-relative js-ref-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;citation&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Article&quot; data-test=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;indented-counter serif h2 tighten-line-height text-right position-absolute grade-c-hide&quot;&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tiny-space-below&quot; id=&quot;ref-CR4&quot;&gt;Seeber, M., Cattaneo, M., Meoli, M. &amp;amp; Malighetti, P. &lt;em&gt;Res. Policy&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;48&lt;/strong&gt;, 478–491 (2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;small-space-below border-gray-medium border-bottom-1 position-relative js-ref-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;citation&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Article&quot; data-test=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;indented-counter serif h2 tighten-line-height text-right position-absolute grade-c-hide&quot;&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tiny-space-below&quot; id=&quot;ref-CR5&quot;&gt;COPE Council. &lt;em&gt;COPE Discussion Document: Citation Manipulation&lt;/em&gt; (COPE, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;small-space-below border-gray-medium border-bottom-1 position-relative js-ref-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;citation&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Article&quot; data-test=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;indented-counter serif h2 tighten-line-height text-right position-absolute grade-c-hide&quot;&gt;6.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tiny-space-below&quot; id=&quot;ref-CR6&quot;&gt;Flatt, J. W., Blasimme, A. &amp;amp; Vayena, E. &lt;em&gt;Publications&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;, 20 (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;hide-print text-right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7-references.ris&quot; class=&quot;text14 sans-serif strong&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;download citation references&quot; data-track-category=&quot;article body&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot;&gt;Download references&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;c-latest-content mt40 hide-print&quot; data-simple-tab=&quot;&quot; data-tab-group=&quot;&quot; data-component-id=&quot;latest-news&quot; data-track=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-action=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-category=&quot;latest content&quot; data-track-label=&quot;visible&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;latest-content&quot; role=&quot;tablist&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;serif strong&quot;&gt;Latest on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cleared&quot;&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;latest-content-2&quot; class=&quot;c-latest-content__container&quot; data-container=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;latest-content-2-head&quot; class=&quot;c-latest-content__category c-latest-content__switch serif&quot; data-switch=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; aria-controls=&quot;latest-content-2-content&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;latest tag (rank:2)&quot;&gt;Peer review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;nature-briefing nature-briefing-box mt0 cleared hide-print&quot; data-component-id=&quot;nature-briefing-box&quot; data-track=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-action=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-category=&quot;nature briefing&quot; data-track-label=&quot;box visible&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nature-briefing-box__header pa20&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;nature-briefing-box__standfirst mb0 sans-serif tighten-line-height&quot;&gt;An essential round-up of science news, opinion and analysis, delivered to your inbox every weekday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;article__aside align-right&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;related-content shrink--aside hide-print&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;aside__title sans-serif&quot;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-right-2&quot; class=&quot;div-gpt-ad advert medium-rectangle js-ad text-center hide-print grade-c-hide&quot; data-gpt-unitpath=&quot;/285/nature.com/article&quot; data-gpt-sizes=&quot;300x250&quot; data-gpt-targeting=&quot;pos=right;artid=/articles/d41586-019-02479-7;path=/articles/d41586-019-02479-7&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/jump?iu=/285/nature.com/article&amp;amp;sz=300x250&amp;amp;c=1248160844&amp;amp;t=pos%3Dright%26artid%3D/articles/d41586-019-02479-7&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-test=&quot;gpt-advert-fallback-img&quot; src=&quot;https://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/ad?iu=/285/nature.com/article&amp;amp;sz=300x250&amp;amp;c=1248160844&amp;amp;t=pos%3Dright%26artid%3D/articles/d41586-019-02479-7&quot; alt=&quot;Advertisement&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;250&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 19:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dmckeon</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Hundreds of extreme self-citing scientists revealed in new database</og:title>
<og:description>Some highly cited academics seem to be heavy self-promoters — but researchers warn against policing self-citation.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.nature.com/lw1024/magazine-assets/d41586-019-02479-7/d41586-019-02479-7_17081482.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02479-7</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Most startup theory is ex-post, therefore bs</title>
<link>https://shafyy.com/post/startup-theory-ex-post/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://shafyy.com/post/startup-theory-ex-post/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;People love to academize things. They love inductive reasoning. Setting up theories based on a small number of empirical observations. Generalizing them, and packaging them neatly in small little bites of advice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t only happen in the startup domain. It happens in the business world at-large. I should know, I went to business school and learned by heart case studies how General Electric did this, or how Kodak fucked up that. In the end, it’s all bull crap. There are other categories too. For example relationship advice. Career advice. What have you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me focus on startups though, that’s where I feel at home the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you run a startup, a lot of people will give you advice. A lot lot. Most people suck at giving advice, so they just give you an example. Ex-post advice. An empirical case study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say shit like “why don’t you do the Tesla strategy, start with a small but premium market, and then move to a lower but bigger market”. Or “Airbnb growth hacked Craigslist to link to their own website. And did you know that the founders lived with their users. You should do that, too!””&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growth hacking, ugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my (unsolicited advice): Think for yourself. Do you think Musk copied that strategy from the business school he never went to? Do you think Brian Chesky of Airbnb heard that strategy from a friend? Hell, do you even think that freeriding off of Craigslist was their reason for success?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most satisfying thing about being an entrepreneur is that you can do what &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think makes sense. That doesn’t mean don’t get advice. But get advice from people who know you, who you know, and most importantly, learn how to apply that advice. And that last point is probably one of the hardest things to get right as a founder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do something new, something wild. Do you want to raise VC funding? Good, learn the ins and outs, and do it. Don’t want to do it? So don’t! Want to finance your startup by working part-time at a local pub? Perfect!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, now I’m starting to sound like Shia LaBeouf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My point is - if it doesn’t work out, at least it didn’t work out on the terms you set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments or just want to tell me that I suck? Great, please post to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/canolcer/status/1163872555251490816&quot;&gt;Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 17:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>shafyy</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://shafyy.com/post/startup-theory-ex-post</og:url>
<og:title>Most startup theory is ex-post, therefore bs - shafyy's blog</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://shafyy.com/post/startup-theory-ex-post/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>IRS budget cuts cost $34.3B in lost revenue from big business</title>
<link>https://www.accountingtoday.com/news/irs-budget-cuts-mean-34-3b-in-lost-revenue-from-big-business</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.accountingtoday.com/news/irs-budget-cuts-mean-34-3b-in-lost-revenue-from-big-business</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A series of budget cuts at the Internal Revenue Service has led to an estimated $34.3 billion in lost tax revenue from large companies, according to a new study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New research from the Indiana University Kelley School of Business backs up previous statistics indicating that the IRS is auditing fewer tax returns from corporations because it has fewer people and resources available to identify potential errors and follow up on questionable tax returns. However, the researchers say this is the first study to actually quantify the amount of corporate tax revenue lost during the audit process per dollar of IRS budget cuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We're quantifying the effect of budget cuts on collections by trying to better understand how cuts impact the entire enforcement process — from audit rates to ultimate settlements between taxpayers and tax authorities,&quot; stated Casey Schwab, an associate professor of accounting at Kelley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sourcemedia.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/234f8ce/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1334+0+0/resize/840x560!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fsourcemedia.brightspotcdn.com%2Fc4%2F0d%2F7b315ebf4907bbd59b0678fef885%2Firs-building.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A man walks past the IRS headquarters in Washington, D.C.&quot; width=&quot;840&quot; height=&quot;560&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;Figure-content&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;The IRS headquarters in Washington, D.C.
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research study, &quot;&lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.aaajournals.org/doi/abs/10.2308/accr-52520?utm_source=15-kelley-research-on-irs-budget-cuts&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=How+do+IRS+resources+affect+the+corporate+audit+process?&amp;amp;utm_campaign=ag&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;How do IRS resources affect the corporate audit process?&lt;/a&gt;&quot; is slated to be published by &lt;em&gt;The Accounting Review&lt;/em&gt;, a journal from the American Accounting Association. It uses IRS audit data from 2000 through 2010 of large, public corporations. The professors estimate the IRS could have collected an extra $34.3 billion from just this subsample of companies with relatively little in extra overall resources from Congress. The $34.3 billion estimate accounts for approximately 19.3 percent of the estimated corporate tax gap from 2002 through 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, especially since the passage of the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act at the end of 2017, Congress has appropriated more funding for the IRS to implement the new tax law, as well as deal with issues such as taxpayer identity theft, taxpayer service and computer modernization. However, relatively little funding has been designated for increasing IRS tax audits, even though audits and examinations more than pay for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The scope of the audits is substantially reduced,&quot; Schwab said in a statement. &quot;The IRS has fewer resources to actually dig into the details. While the IRS appears to still target the most aggressive positions, they can't audit as many positions within the return. They just don't have the resources.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adjusted for inflation, the 2019 IRS budget of $11.3 billion is less than in 2000 and 19 percent beneath its highest level of funding in 2010, according to the Government Accountability Office. The agency now has 21 percent fewer employees than it did eight years ago. Meanwhile, the number of examiners has declined by 38 percent since 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Given the continued cuts to the IRS budget, the amount of lost tax revenue from public companies could be even higher than what we estimate,&quot; stated Bridget Stomberg, also an associate professor of accounting at Kelley. She jointly conducted the study with Schwab, along with Michelle Nessa, an assistant professor at Michigan State University, and Erin Towery, an associate professor at the University of Georgia and an academic research consultant to the IRS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers believe their study should be of interest to lawmakers when Congress weighs the amount of funding to appropriate to the IRS, particularly as the IRS faces further resource constraints as a result of the new responsibilities of implementing not only the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act, but also the more recent Taxpayer First Act, which promises to reform many of the practices of the IRS, including the appeals process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;By eliminating the role of the IRS, you're effectively reducing corporate tax burdens. On the one hand, this could be used to spur economic growth,&quot; Schwab stated. &quot;On the other hand, there's a notion that everyone should pay their fair share. The IRS is fundamental in preventing businesses from engaging in transactions that aggressively reduce their tax liability.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 17:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mars4rp</dc:creator>
<og:title>IRS budget cuts cost $34.3B in lost revenue from big business</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.accountingtoday.com/news/irs-budget-cuts-mean-34-3b-in-lost-revenue-from-big-business</og:url>
<og:image>https://sourcemedia.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/333ef3d/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1050+0+0/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fsourcemedia.brightspotcdn.com%2Fc4%2F0d%2F7b315ebf4907bbd59b0678fef885%2Firs-building.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The federal government is collecting billions of dollars less than it could because of resource shortages at the tax agency, according to a new study.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.accountingtoday.com/news/irs-budget-cuts-mean-34-3b-in-lost-revenue-from-big-business</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>IBM Open-Sources Power Chip Instruction Set</title>
<link>https://www.nextplatform.com/2019/08/20/big-blue-open-sources-power-chip-instruction-set/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nextplatform.com/2019/08/20/big-blue-open-sources-power-chip-instruction-set/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/ibm-power9-chip-logo-2-bw-678x381.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;ibm-power9-chip-logo-2-bw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been a long time coming, and it might have been better if this had been done a decade ago. But with a big injection of open source spirit from its acquisition of Red Hat, IBM is finally taking the next step and open sourcing the instruction set architecture of its Power family of processors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big Blue is also moving the OpenPower Foundation, which it formed with Google, Mellanox Technologies, Nvidia, and Tyan &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2013/08/06/ibm_opens_up_power_chips_armstyle_to_take_on_chipzilla/&quot;&gt;to help create an ecosystem around the Power architecture six years ago this month&lt;/a&gt;, under the administrative control of the Linux Foundation. (Considering how many open source projects are under the control of the Linux Foundation, perhaps it is time for that organization to consider a name change. The Open Foundation is probably appropriate, and probably already owned by someone else.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any event, if you have ever wanted to create your own Power processor and was lamenting how expensive it might be to license the technology from IBM, now is your chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM’s long journey to opening up the Power architecture began a long time ago, starting with the creation of the PowerPC Alliance between Apple, IBM, and Motorola back in 1991, just as Big Blue was starting to get serious about the Power architecture for RS/6000 Unix systems – Unix was all the rage then, and Sun Microsystems and Hewlett Packard were circling IBM’s proprietary mainframes and minicomputers like starving wolves, with a very lean and hungry Oracle snarling nearby. Behind the scenes, IBM was preparing to move its proprietary AS/400 enterprise systems to a common hardware platform with the RS/6000, a credible Windows Servers was years away (and would very briefly run on Power iron), and a young Linus Torvalds had just created the first Linux kernel (which would eventually be the key to keeping Power iron alive in HPC centers in particular and in some enterprise datacenters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history is long and complex, but suffice it to say that Motorola and IBM both had their challenges bringing server-class processors to market and the move to 64-bits was particularly difficult. Interestingly, it was IBM’s AS/400 processor team in Rochester, Minnesota which saved the day by creating a very good 64-bit PowerPC chip that also had a double-pumped vector processor embedded in it, and it is this processor, not the ones designed by the AIX people down in Austin, that is the very kernel of all Power chips and systems that have followed since. Eventually Sun Microsystems went up on the rocks with its UltraSparc-III systems, and Hewlett Packard and Intel created Itanium, which had its own litany of woes, and this left the door wide open for IBM to be a spoiler in the early 2000s. And it was just then, back in 2001, when IBM got its first dual-core chip and its first processor to clock above 1 GHz out the door – that would be the Power4 “GigaProcessor” – and IBM brought the hammer down in Unix, delivering twice the bang for the buck as Sun and HP did in Unix, eating market share like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time all of this was going on, the Motorola 68000 series of chips, which were at the heart of Apple PCs as well as myriad kinds and untold millions of embedded controllers. Arm may rule in controllers today, but back then its was Motorola 68Ks, and the kind of unified processor architecture spanning from embedded devices to datacenter gear was first done – and actually realized – with the PowerPC architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, since then, the Unix market has been largely replaced by X86 systems running Linux and Windows Server, and Sparc from Sun and PA-RISC from HP, and Itanium from Intel are all dead. Motorola has ceded the embedded controller market to Arm, and IBM has been trying to breathe some life into Power, first through the Power.org in 2004 and the OpenPower Foundation in 2013. With each move, IBM has opened up its technology a little more and broadened its appeal. It is a question as to whether this will be enough, with an ascending AMD providing an alternative to Intel processors and the Arm collective fielding many good processors, all using Arm licenses and many adding their own special tweaks to the Arm designs while not violating the Arm architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one is saying that the OpenPower Foundation will have an easy time growing its ecosystem, despite the many architectural advantages that Power holds over other ISAs, but it now has an easier time than a more closed architecture has. It doesn’t hurt that the Power ISA is being given away royalty free, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We started OpenPower six years ago because the industry was seeing the decline of Moore’s Law, and we were seeing the need for more powerful systems to support HPC, artificial intelligence, and data analytics,” Ken King, general manager of OpenPower at IBM, tells &lt;em&gt;The Next Platform&lt;/em&gt;. “We needed to find other ways to drive system performance, and with limitations on the processor, the ability to integrate and innovate up and down the stack was becoming more critical. This led to things like NVLink with Nvidia, a close relationship with Mellanox on interconnects, and OpenCAPI for other devices, and we have seen some progress here. But we are also seeing a shift in the industry, with companies moving to more open hardware. IBM opening up Power to the point where we would license the CPU RTL to others so they could design their own processors was limited in its effect because there were not that many people who wanted to spend many hundreds of millions of dollars – not for license fees, but for full development – to create their own high-end CPU. We did make some progress in opening up our reference designs, and there are over 20 vendors who are now making Power-based systems. We are seeing interesting developments with the nascent RISC-V architecture, and hyperscalers are hiring their own chip designers and building their own CPUs and interconnects. They are getting into the hardware space, even if they are not going to be hardware vendors, to drive that performance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that environment, now is as good time as any to get the Power ISA opened up and see what kind of uptake it might have against RISC-V and Arm and a closed X86 architecture from AMD and Intel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be precise about what IBM is doing, it is opening up the Power ISA and giving it to the OpenPower Foundation royalty free with patent rights, and that means companies can implement a chip using the Power ISA without having to pay IBM or OpenPower a dime, and they have patent rights to what they develop. Companies have to maintain compatibility with the instruction set, King explains, and there are a whole set of compatibility requirements, which we presume are precisely as stringent as Arm and are needed to maintain runtime compatibility should many Power chips be developed, as IBM hopes will happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OpenPower Foundation, working under the Linux Foundation umbrella, will have an open governance model, with IBM having precisely the same one vote as other OpenPower Foundation members as to what changes can be made to the Power ISA in the future. IBM will have retain the right to make whatever changes that it wants to the architecture to suit its own needs, but all other changes will require a majority vote of the members to ensure compatibility. “Everything has to stay in the compliance guidelines because we do not want a bunch of fragmentation,” says King. This presumably also applies to Big Blue. If companies want to make a non-compliant change, it takes a unanimous vote of the members to do so. For instance, this may be for some specific set of instructions for a very precise workload set. Anyone can do a custom chip, too, but they will fall out of compliance with the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to all of this, IBM is providing a softcore model of the Power ISA that has been implemented on FPGAs – presumably from Xilinx, not Intel’s Altera devices – that people can play around with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, IBM is also taking its OpenCAPI accelerator interface and its OpenCAPI Memory Interface variant, which is a key feature of the Power9’ (that’s a &lt;em&gt;prime&lt;/em&gt; symbol, not a typo) processor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/2019/08/06/talking-high-bandwidth-with-ibms-power10-architect/&quot;&gt;that is coming out sometime this year&lt;/a&gt;, and it is actually contributing the RTL for these reference designs to the OpenCAPI Consortium, which is independent from OpenPower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some work needs to be done to reduce the number of communication methods and protocols that are being employed to link CPUs to each other, to accelerators, and to storage. Gen-Z, CCIX, CXL, OpenCAPI, NVLink, Infinity Fabric – the list keeps getting longer and the differences between them all are disruptive in a bad way. We need one or two standards, maybe. Perhaps this last bit is a step in getting us there. IBM just wants for companies to make OMI memory, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/2018/08/28/ibm-power-chips-blur-the-lines-to-memory-and-accelerators/&quot;&gt;which we have talked about before&lt;/a&gt; and which we will be detailing shortly based on a presentation that IBM made this week at Hot Chips. OpenCAPI memory may be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/2019/08/06/talking-high-bandwidth-with-ibms-power10-architect/&quot;&gt;the best way to get most of the bandwidth benefits of HBM memory without having to resort to stacking up and packing it up&lt;/a&gt;, but keeping it in DIMM form factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, right here right now, King is extending the olive branch out to Intel, much as it did back in the late 1990s when InfiniBand was created largely by Intel and IBM as a replacement for the PCI-Express bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“OpenCAPI and OMI are architecture agnostic, and the goal is to enable others to create their own coherent accelerator and memory interfaces in an open standards environment,” says King. “We are hoping over time – and we have been having these discussions – that with OpenCAPI we are able to work with Intel and converge OpenCAPI and CXL to converge them into one, common standard. And there is a lot of interest in that, without getting into the specifics.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We suspect that Google, Facebook, and maybe a few others have some good ideas about how this might get done, and that this time around, they will have a big say on how these standards will converge. One thing is for sure: They won’t tolerate six standards when one or two will do.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 16:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Katydid</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Big Blue Open Sources Power Chip Instruction Set</og:title>
<og:description>It has been a long time coming, and it might have been better if this had been done a decade ago. But with a big injection of open source spirit from its</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.nextplatform.com/2019/08/20/big-blue-open-sources-power-chip-instruction-set/</og:url>
<og:image>https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/ibm-power9-chip-logo-2-bw.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nextplatform.com/2019/08/20/big-blue-open-sources-power-chip-instruction-set/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google&amp;#039;s software mistreats or harms the user</title>
<link>https://www.gnu.org/proprietary/malware-google.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gnu.org/proprietary/malware-google.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;M201809140&quot; readability=&quot;1.2916666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/platform/amp/2018/9/14/17861150/google-battery-saver-android-9-pie-remote-settings-change&quot;&gt;back door for remotely changing “user” settings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article suggests it might be a universal back door, but this isn't clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201202280&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChromeOS has a universal back door. At least, Google says it does—in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/intl/en/chromebook/termsofservice.html&quot;&gt;section 4 of the EULA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201103070&quot; readability=&quot;12.455172413793&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Android, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computerworld.com/article/2506557/google-throws--kill-switch--on-android-phones.html&quot;&gt;Google has a back door to remotely delete apps&lt;/a&gt;. (It was in a program called GTalkService, which seems since then to have been merged into Google Play.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://jon.oberheide.org/blog/2010/06/25/remote-kill-and-install-on-google-android/&quot;&gt;forcibly and remotely install apps&lt;/a&gt; through GTalkService. This is not equivalent to a universal back door, but permits various dirty tricks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Google's &lt;em&gt;exercise&lt;/em&gt; of this power has not been malicious so far, the point is that nobody should have such power, which could also be used maliciously. You might well decide to let a security service remotely &lt;em&gt;deactivate&lt;/em&gt; programs that it considers malicious. But there is no excuse for allowing it to &lt;em&gt;delete&lt;/em&gt; the programs, and you should have the right to decide who (if anyone) to trust in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;M201703160&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csmonitor.com/Technology/2017/0316/Google-Family-Link-gives-parents-a-way-to-monitor-preteens-accounts&quot;&gt;offers censorship software&lt;/a&gt;, ostensibly for parents to put into their children's computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201701180&quot; readability=&quot;3.830985915493&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows and MacOS, Chrome &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/a/chromium.org/dev/developers/extensions-deployment-faq&quot;&gt;disables extensions&lt;/a&gt; that are not hosted in the Chrome Web Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, an extension was &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170120094917/https://consumerist.com/2017/01/18/why-is-google-blocking-this-ad-blocker-on-chrome/&quot;&gt;banned from the Chrome Web Store, and permanently disabled&lt;/a&gt; on more than 40,000 computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201602030&quot; readability=&quot;10.873646209386&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/media/2016/feb/03/google-pulls-ad-blocking-app-for-samsung-phones&quot;&gt;Google censored installation of Samsung's ad-blocker&lt;/a&gt; on Android phones, saying that blocking ads is “interference” with the sites that advertise (and surveil users through ads).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ad-blocker is proprietary software, just like the program (Google Play) that Google used to deny access to install it. Using a nonfree program gives the owner power over you, and Google has exercised that power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google's censorship, unlike that of Apple, is not total: Android allows users to install apps in other ways. You can install free programs from f-droid.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These bugs are/were not intentional, so unlike the rest of the file they do not count as malware. We mention them to refute the supposition that prestigious proprietary software doesn't have grave bugs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section gives examples of Google software harassing or annoying the user, or causing trouble for the user. These actions are like sabotage but the word “sabotage” is too strong for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The wrongs in this section are not precisely malware, since they do not involve making the program that runs in a way that hurts the user. But they are a lot like malware, since they are technical Google actions that harm the users of specific Google software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;M201605150&quot; readability=&quot;13.017543859649&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revolv is an IoT device which managed “smart home” operations: switching the lights, operate motion sensors, regulating temperature, etc. On May 15th, 2016, Google said it would shut down the service linked to the device, making it unusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although you may own the device, its functioning depended on the server that never belonged to you. So you never really had control of it. This unjust design is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/network-services-arent-free-or-nonfree.html&quot;&gt;Service as a Software Substitute (SaaSS)&lt;/a&gt;. That is what gave the company the power to convert it into a $300 out-of-warranty brick, for your “dumb home”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201604050&quot; readability=&quot;1.9586776859504&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google/Alphabet &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/04/nest-reminds-customers-ownership-isnt-what-it-used-be&quot;&gt;intentionally broke Revolv home automatic control products that depended on a server&lt;/a&gt; to function, by shutting down the server. The lesson is, reject all such products. Insist on self-contained computers that run free software!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201511244&quot; readability=&quot;1.4352941176471&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has long had &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/nov/24/google-can-unlock-android-devices-remotely-if-phone-unencrypted&quot;&gt;a back door to remotely unlock an Android device&lt;/a&gt;, unless its disk is encrypted (possible since Android 5.0 Lollipop, but still not quite the default).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;M201907210&quot; readability=&quot;10.241379310345&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google “Assistant” records users' conversations &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/07/google-defends-listening-to-ok-google-queries-after-voice-recordings-leak/&quot;&gt;even when it is not supposed to listen&lt;/a&gt;. Thus, when one of Google's subcontractors discloses a thousand confidential voice recordings, users were easily identified from these recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Google “Assistant” uses proprietary software, there is no way to see or control what it records or sends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than trying to better control the use of recordings, Google should not record or listen to the person's voice. It should only get commands that the user wants to send to some Google service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201906220&quot; readability=&quot;9.3713163064833&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Chrome is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercurynews.com/2019/06/21/google-chrome-has-become-surveillance-software-its-time-to-switch/&quot;&gt;instrument of surveillance&lt;/a&gt;. It lets thousands of trackers invade users' computers and report the sites they visit to advertising and data companies, first of all to Google. Moreover, if users have a Gmail account, Chrome automatically logs them in to the browser for more convenient profiling. On Android, Chrome also reports their location to Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to escape surveillance is to switch to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/icecat/&quot;&gt;IceCat&lt;/a&gt;, a modified version of Firefox with several changes to protect users' privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201904130&quot; readability=&quot;2.6587677725118&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google tracks the movements of Android phones and iPhones running Goggle apps, and sometimes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/04/13/us/google-location-tracking-police.html&quot;&gt;saves the data for years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonfree software in the phone has to be responsible for sending the location data to Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201902040&quot; readability=&quot;6.5725190839695&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google invites people to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commondreams.org/views/2019/02/04/google-screenwise-unwise-trade-all-your-privacy-cash?cd-origin=rss&quot;&gt;let Google monitor their phone use, and all internet use in their homes, for an extravagant payment of $20&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a malicious functionality of a program with some other purpose; this is the software's sole purpose, and Google says so. But Google says it in a way that encourages most people to ignore the details. That, we believe, makes it fitting to list here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201811230&quot; readability=&quot;1.5238095238095&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Android phone was observed to track location even while in airplane mode. It didn't send the location data while in airplane mode. Instead, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesun.co.uk/tech/7811918/google-is-tracking-you-even-with-airplane-mode-turned-on/&quot;&gt;it saved up the data, and sent them all later&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201808030&quot; readability=&quot;2.7241379310345&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Google apps on Android &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/aug/13/google-location-tracking-android-iphone-mobile&quot;&gt;record the user's location even when users disable “location tracking”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other ways to turn off the other kinds of location tracking, but most users will be tricked by the misleading control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201711210&quot; readability=&quot;0.29752066115702&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android tracks location for Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20171121/09030238658/investigation-finds-google-collected-location-data-even-with-location-services-turned-off.shtml&quot;&gt;even when “location services” are turned off, even when the phone has no SIM card&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201704131&quot; readability=&quot;16.075801749271&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low-priced Chromebooks for schools are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/wp/school-issued-devices-and-student-privacy&quot;&gt;collecting far more data on students than is necessary, and store it indefinitely&lt;/a&gt;. Parents and students complain about the lack of transparency on the part of both the educational services and the schools, the difficulty of opting out of these services, and the lack of proper privacy policies, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But complaining is not sufficient. Parents, students and teachers should realize that the software Google uses to spy on students is nonfree, so they can't verify what it really does. The only remedy is to persuade school officials to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/education/edu-schools.html&quot;&gt;exclusively use free software&lt;/a&gt; for both education and school administration. If the school is run locally, parents and teachers can mandate their representatives at the School Board to refuse the budget unless the school initiates a switch to free software. If education is run nation-wide, they need to persuade legislators (e.g., through free software organizations, political parties, etc.) to migrate the public schools to free software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201609210&quot; readability=&quot;-0.60714285714286&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google's new voice messaging app &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2016/9/21/12994362/allo-privacy-message-logs-google&quot;&gt;logs all conversations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201609140&quot; readability=&quot;5.206106870229&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Play (a component of Android) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.extremetech.com/mobile/235594-yes-google-play-is-tracking-you-and-thats-just-the-tip-of-a-very-large-iceberg&quot;&gt;tracks the users' movements without their permission&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you disable Google Maps and location tracking, you must disable Google Play itself to completely stop the tracking. This is yet another example of nonfree software pretending to obey the user, when it's actually doing something else. Such a thing would be almost unthinkable with free software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201507280&quot; readability=&quot;0.67256637168142&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Chrome makes it easy for an extension to do &lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/2015/07/28/how-i-disabled-your-chrome-security-extensions/&quot;&gt;total snooping on the user's browsing&lt;/a&gt;, and many of them do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201506180&quot; readability=&quot;-0.40425531914894&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Chrome includes a module that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/2015/06/google-chrome-listening-in-to-your-room-shows-the-importance-of-privacy-defense-in-depth/&quot;&gt;activates microphones and transmits audio to its servers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201407170&quot; readability=&quot;-0.46153846153846&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;nest-thermometers&quot;&gt;Nest thermometers send &lt;a href=&quot;http://bgr.com/2014/07/17/google-nest-jailbreak-hack&quot;&gt;a lot of data about the user&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201308040&quot; readability=&quot;0.5421686746988&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Chrome &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brad-x.com/2013/08/04/google-chrome-is-spyware/&quot;&gt;spies on browser history, affiliations&lt;/a&gt;, and other installed software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201308010&quot; readability=&quot;0.66788321167883&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spyware in Android phones (and Windows? laptops): The Wall Street Journal (in an article blocked from us by a paywall) reports that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2013/8/1/4580718/fbi-can-remotely-activate-android-and-laptop-microphones-reports-wsj&quot;&gt;the FBI can remotely activate the GPS and microphone in Android phones and laptops&lt;/a&gt;. (I suspect this means Windows laptops.) Here is &lt;a href=&quot;http://cryptome.org/2013/08/fbi-hackers.htm&quot;&gt;more info&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201307280&quot; readability=&quot;2.535&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spyware is present in some Android devices when they are sold. Some Motorola phones, made when this company was owned by Google, use a modified version of Android that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beneaththewaves.net/Projects/Motorola_Is_Listening.html&quot;&gt;sends personal data to Motorola&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201307250&quot; readability=&quot;-0.375&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Motorola phone &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170629175629/http://www.itproportal.com/2013/07/25/motorolas-new-x8-arm-chip-underpinning-the-always-on-future-of-android/&quot;&gt;listens for voice all the time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201302150&quot; readability=&quot;10.070945945946&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Play intentionally sends app developers &lt;a href=&quot;http://gadgets.ndtv.com/apps/news/google-play-store-policy-raises-privacy-concerns-331116&quot;&gt;the personal details of users that install the app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merely asking the “consent” of users is not enough to legitimize actions like this. At this point, most users have stopped reading the “Terms and Conditions” that spell out what they are “consenting” to. Google should clearly and honestly identify the information it collects on users, instead of hiding it in an obscurely worded EULA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, to truly protect people's privacy, we must prevent Google and other companies from getting this personal information in the first place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M201208210&quot; readability=&quot;0.62987012987013&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many web sites report all their visitors to Google by using the Google Analytics service, which &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcworld.idg.com.au/article/434164/google_analytics_breaks_norwegian_privacy_laws_local_agency_said/&quot;&gt;tells Google the IP address and the page that was visited&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;M200809060&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Chrome contains a key logger that &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20190126075111/http://www.favbrowser.com/google-chrome-spyware-confirmed/&quot;&gt;sends Google every URL typed in&lt;/a&gt;, one key at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;M201304080&quot; readability=&quot;2.4655172413793&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motorola, then owned by Google, made &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.azimuthsecurity.com/2013/04/unlocking-motorola-bootloader.html&quot;&gt;Android phones that are tyrants&lt;/a&gt; (though someone found a way to crack the restriction). Fortunately, most Android devices are not tyrants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 16:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>eddyg</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gnu.org/proprietary/malware-google.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A World Without Power (2013)</title>
<link>https://jacquesmattheij.com/a-world-without-power/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jacquesmattheij.com/a-world-without-power/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The 14th of August, 2003 was an interesting day in many ways. I’d just taken the family down to Toronto to spend a day there and pick up our newly minted passports at the Dutch embassy. We had some fun in the city seeing the sights, visited Niagara Falls and were on the way back on a sunny August thursday afternoon. What could possibly go wrong? We pulled into a gas station just outside of Barrie. We parked behind the person gassing up and waited our turn. The guy took his time, walked into the store to pay, got into his car and drove off. We moved up the line to the pump, I got out and put the nozzle into the fuel port but nothing happened. This normally means that the pump hasn’t been ‘cleared’, usually that takes 10 seconds or so (an annoying little bell starts ringing in the office over the blinking light indicating the pump that needs to be cleared). After a minute of waiting I went into the office. “Sorry bud, the power is out”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bummer! The car we were driving was our family car, one of those ford minivan affairs and it wasn’t exactly a paragon of fuel economy. 3.8 liter engine, still slow as could be and it drank like a fish. So when we pulled into the gas station the needle was at ‘empty’ and the fuel warning light was on. We were stuck for the duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at Barrie from the highway down and noticed that there were lots of people in the streets, many more than you’d normally see in a place like that. Traffic lights were out. Billboards were dark. Little by little it dawned on me that this was more than just a trivial outage. I tried my cellphone, it still had a signal and called to the Island where we lived. We had a business there (a gas station, coincidentially) and I asked them if they had power. No, they didn’t. Oh oh. But the generator was up and running and as far as they were concerned it was business as usual. Maybe a bit more busy because some traffic from the highway pulled in on the island to gas up. I asked them to call the supplier (Wardlaw fuels in Sault Ste Marie, an awesome company to work with) to make sure they were going to be provisioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An hour and a half into the blackout a truck from OPG pulled into the station. The guy in it took all the ice his truck would carry, paid cash and drove off again. Now I was getting really worried. OPG is the “Ontario Power Generating Company”, they are the company that runs all the grid infrastructure, and more importantly they run the nuclear generators. If a guy with that much knowledge buys ice he must know something that the general public doesn’t know yet: that this outage is going to take a very long time, long enough that food will spoil. Nuclear power is funny in that it is excellent baseline power, but when you shut down a nuke it’s going to be down for a while. They go down quite quickly but they take forever to get back online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw one guy walk around to the spot where the air hose for refilling tires was. A few minutes later the same guy walks by with the length of air hose coiled up and on his shoulder like it was the most normal thing in the world. Presumably he was going to use it to siphon fuel from one car into another. Let’s hope they were at least both his cars. Another guy made off with the fire extinguisher. I’ve heard it say that the veneer over our society is very thin and that it won’t take much to bring out the ugliness underneath but I had not expected to see that illustrated so clearly so quickly. Suddenly I didn’t feel safe and I did not want to wait for who knows how long next to an unfamiliar town in a vulnerable position like this with my wife and kid with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mobile still worked, so I called the gas station on the Island again. The mood around us continued to detoriorate from resigned to menacing, people were getting angry with the operator of the station (just some kid that was clearly not the cause of the trouble). I asked the people at our gas station on the Island to please go to our house, get our other car (a honda civic hybrid, capable of doing 1200 km on a single tank if you were careful), load it up with fuel cannisters and drive down to where we were. They said they’d get on it, and that the station was being mobbed by people that wanted gas, some coming all the way from DesBarats and Sault Ste. Marie (a good 50 Km or 30 Miles away). They’d already gone through one full drop (50,000 liters) and another one was on the way. Our trusty diesel was doing just fine running the pumps and half of the freezers, they’d sold the food in so they could be switched off, the other half at a discount rather than to let it go bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to some of the people stranded around us. One group was a bunch of motorcycle enthusiasts, guys that not only drive but &lt;em&gt;build&lt;/em&gt; their own bikes. Lots of nice metalworking there so we talked for a bit about that. One girl that was stranded came from Toronto and was on the way to Muskoka, a popular place to spend the holidays. We waited… One of the bike guys went into town and scored a pizza. One of the pizza bakers had set up in the street and was selling pizzas for $5 as long as he had ingredients. We munched our pizza, talked some more and waited some more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barrie is about 500 km from the Island, and around 10 pm I saw our saviors roll into the station. Two kids with huge grins on their faces and music blaring loud from the open windows. I don’t think I was ever so glad to see my own car. The honda was a veritable bomb, it was filled with cannisters as many as they could cram in. We gassed up, then gassed the bikes of the bike guys (we swapped addresses, they invited us for a pig roast which we attended and they came to visit us on the island). The girl got enough gas to get back to Toronto, and we parcelled out the remaining fuel in the same way, just enough to get as many people home as possible. No charge, obviously (people were on the whole expecting to pay the gas station with a credit card or debit card). We made a lot of friends that day :), and quite a few enemies too (all those that we couldn’t help).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, finally done we drove back to the island. It was the weirdest ride on Highway 17 North ever. Normally even at night there is light traffic there, this time not a single car. Just lots of wildlife, deer, moose and the occasional bear that had already taken over the highway so we went pretty slow. In none of the little villages on the road were there any lights. When we got back to the island it was 5:30 am or so, the gas station was &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; open, the pumps were still manned and going pretty much continuously. For 75 miles around there was no gas. The distribution point had huge tanks (millions of liters) that did a gravity dump into the delivery trucks, and then the truck would do a gravity dump into the underground storage tanks at the station. So none of that required power. And then the generator driven pumps would pull the fuel out of the underground tanks and deliver it to the customers just like normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outage lasted 2 days and a bit. We went trough our monthly amount of fuel in that time and we made the Sault Star (the local newspaper) after the power was restored. (Good thing too, their presses were down just like everything else, we wouldn’t have been able to cope with the demand if there had been any publicity during the outage, word of mouth we could deal with, barely).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we bought the station one of the first things I did was install that generator. I felt that what with the station being critical infrastructure for many of the islanders that we could not be dependent on Ontarios power grid. The island was fed by cables to a step-down transformer, and after that there was a ‘low voltage’ (not really that low, but low compared to long distance lines) distribution net on the island and every house had its own drop transformer. Outages were frequent, once every couple of months, and more frequently in the winter months. Whenever lightning struck it was &lt;sup&gt;50&lt;/sup&gt;⁄&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; that the power would go out. I imagined a situation where the power was out for just a bit longer than normal and decided that we could not run that risk. My software background makes me abhor single points of failure and to run an infrastructure business without a back-up in place seemed unwise and ran against my nature (even if the partners in the bussines thought that it was a bit over the top they still helped installing the genny).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have any idea that there would be such a massive power outage (there had not been one like that in decades). I also didn’t know that I was going to be one the main beneficiaries of having a back-up. I definitely didn’t plan to get our business in the newspaper this way and did not realize how many people would end up relying on our silly little out-of-the-way gas station with it’s puny 2x50K liter reservoirs for a critical resource (a typical highway station has a &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;⁄&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; of a million liters). But being prepared for the occasion sure didn’t hurt. What is really scary is that apparently none of the other (much larger) stations than ours had thought this scenario through. Critical infrastructure being down is annoying enough, but the knock-on effects are devastating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our house didn’t have any issues at all, we were ‘off the grid’ by that time so our business worked uninterrupted. One thing that I was very impressed with was how well the cellphone network dealt with the outage, for at least 24 hours all the base stations worked, after that point they slowly dropped out one by one as their batteries ran dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infrastructure is invisible, as long as it works. And only when it fails do you realize just how much we are all dependent on it and how badly we are able to cope with such infrastructure being unavailable for any length of time. No power translates quickly into: no fuel, no water, no food and so on. If this had happened during the winter instead of a nice summer day the results would have been much more severe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no moral to this story, but I’d like to add one: if you’re in the infrastructure business design as if lives depend on it. One day they may, even if you can’t foresee how that is possible. Even if you’re just running a lousy gas station on some barely accessible island.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 13:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>acdanger</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jacquesmattheij.com/a-world-without-power/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The WeWork IPO</title>
<link>https://stratechery.com/2019/the-wework-ipo/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stratechery.com/2019/the-wework-ipo/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There is a reason — beyond the fact it is August — that WeWork’s upcoming IPO has driven so much discussion: it is a document defined by audaciousness, both in terms of the company’s vision and also the flagrant disregard for corporate governance norms by its leadership. And, of course, massive losses despite massive amounts of capital raised. I suspect all of these things are related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The AWS Example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine it is 2006, and you go to investors with a bold new business plan: computer hardware! Never mind that IBM just sold its PC business to Lenovo a year previously, and that servers appeared on the same path to commoditization, particularly with the emergence of x86 solutions from companies like Dell in place of specialized architectures from traditional suppliers like Sun. It doesn’t sound particularly promising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet 2006 was the year that Amazon launched Amazon Web Services, a computer hardware business that leveraged the commoditization of hardware into a business with operating margins of around 30%. It turned out having one company manage that commodity hardware for everyone else had several important advantages that more than justified those margins:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New companies had instant access to an entire server stack for basically free, because payments tracked usage (which for new companies is zero).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growing companies did not need to obtain funding for or spend the time on extensive build-outs months or years ahead of future growth, instead they could pay for new capabilities as they needed them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Established companies no longer needed to have a competency in managing server installations, and could instead focus on their core competencies while outsourcing to cloud providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In all three cases the fundamental shift was from servers as capital investment to variable costs; the benefits were less about saving dollars and cents and more about increasing flexibility and optionality. At least, that is, to start: today AWS has offerings that extend far beyond basic compute and storage to capabilities like server-less (which, paradoxically, requires owning an huge number of always-available servers) that are uniquely possible because of AWS’ scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The WeWork Bull Case&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWS, broadly speaking, is the WeWork bull case. Consider the phrase, “fixed cost”. There is nothing more fixed than real estate, yet WeWork’s offering transforms real estate into a variable cost for all kinds of companies, with benefits that roughly mirror public clouds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New companies can have instant access to a well-appointed office space and pay for only a desk or two, and then grow as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growing companies do not need to spend time on extensive build-outs months or years ahead of future growth, and instead pay for more space as they need it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Established companies no longer need to have a real estate competency all over the world, and can in fact expand to new territories with far less risk than previously required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that, just like the public cloud, price is not necessarily the primary driver for WeWork space. Still, there is no doubt that AWS, for example, pays far less for AWS’ underlying infrastructure than any of their customers would pay on their own. For one, AWS can spread the cost of data centers around the world over a huge number of customers; for another AWS can bargain with hardware suppliers or simply design and make its own components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WeWork can achieve similar gains, to an extent. Within a single location, common space, by virtue of being shared by all WeWork members, can be built out much more than any one member could build out on their own. Similarly, WeWork’s network of locations around the world provide options that accrue to all members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WeWork has also developed an expertise in utilizing office space efficiently, and while some of this is simply a willingness to cram more people into less space, opening triple-digit locations a year means that the company is by definition learning and iterating on what works for office space far faster than anyone else, and that is before the promised application of sensors and machine learning to the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there is the question as to whether WeWork is, or can become, more than a real estate play at scale: what might be the equivalent of “server-less” when it comes to office space — a unique capability that is uniquely unlocked by one company providing all of the real estate needs for, well, everyone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;WeWork’s Losses and Ambition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this vision, WeWork’s massive losses are, at least in theory, justifiable. The implication of creating a company that absorbs all of the fixed costs in order to offer a variable cost service to other companies is massive amounts of up-front investment. Just as Amazon needed to first build out data centers and buy servers before it could sell storage and compute, WeWork needs to build out offices spaces before it can sell desktops or conference rooms. In other words, it would be strange if WeWork were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; losing lots of money, particularly given its expansion rate; from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1533523/000119312519220499/d781982ds1.htm&quot;&gt;S-1&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.57.46-PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.57.46-PM-1024x715.png&quot; alt=&quot;WeWork's Aggressive Growth&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;447&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4331&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.57.46-PM-1024x715.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.57.46-PM-300x209.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.57.46-PM-768x536.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.57.46-PM-903x630.png 903w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company also includes this graphic, which on its own isn’t particularly helpful given the missing Y-axis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.58.51-PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.58.51-PM-1024x346.png&quot; alt=&quot;A WeWork property's path to profitability&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;216&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4330&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.58.51-PM-1024x346.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.58.51-PM-300x101.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.58.51-PM-768x259.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-6.58.51-PM-1200x405.png 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is useful is considering these two graphics together: over 300 locations — more than half — are in the money-losing part of the second graph, which helps explain why WeWork’s expenses are nearly double its revenue; should the company stop opening locations, it seems reasonable to expect that gap to close rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, it is doubtful that WeWork will slow the rate with which is opens locations given the company’s view of its total addressable market. From the S-1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 111 cities in which we had locations as of June 1, 2019, we estimate that there are approximately 149 million potential members. For U.S. cities, we define potential members by the estimated number of desk jobs based on data from the Statistics of U.S. Businesses survey by the U.S. Census Bureau. For non-U.S. cities, we consider anyone in select occupations defined by the International Labor Organization — including managers, professionals, technicians and associate professionals and clerical support workers — to be potential members, because we assume that these individuals need workspace in which they have access to a desk and other services. We view this as our addressable market because of the broad variety of professions and industries among our members, the breadth of our solutions available to individuals and organizations of different types and our track record of developing new solutions in response to our members’ needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect to expand aggressively in our existing cities as well as launch in up to 169 additional cities. We evaluate expansion in new cities based on multiple criteria, primarily our assessment of the potential member demand as well as the strategic value of having that city as part of our location portfolio. Based on data from Demographia and the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, we have identified our market opportunity to be 280 target cities with an estimated potential member population of approximately 255 million people in aggregate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When applying our average revenue per WeWork membership for the six months ended June 30, 2019 to our potential member population of 149 million people in our existing 111 cities, we estimate an addressable market opportunity of $945 billion. Among our total potential member population of approximately 255 million people across our 280 target cities globally, we estimate an addressable market opportunity of $1.6 trillion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you catch that? WeWork is claiming nearly every desk job around the globe as its market, a move that by definition means moving beyond being a real estate company. From the S-1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our membership offerings are designed to accommodate our members’ distinct space needs. We provide standard, configured and on-demand memberships within our spaces. We also offer Powered by We, a premium solution configured to an organization’s needs and deployed at the organization’s location. Powered by We leverages our analysis, design and delivery capabilities to beautify and optimize an existing workplace, while also offering an organization increased efficiencies and an option to invigorate its spaces through our community offerings. The technology we deploy includes software and hardware solutions that deliver improved insights and an easier-to-use workplace experience for employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-7.16.37-PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-7.16.37-PM-1024x327.png&quot; alt=&quot;WeWork's breadth of offerings&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;204&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4329&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-7.16.37-PM-1024x327.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-7.16.37-PM-300x96.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-7.16.37-PM-768x245.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-7.16.37-PM-1200x383.png 1200w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-7.16.37-PM.png 1586w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheer scale of this ambition again calls back to AWS. It was in 2013 that Amazon’s management &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2013/11/13/jeff-bezos-believes-aws-could-be-amazons-biggest-business/&quot;&gt;first stated&lt;/a&gt; that AWS could end up being the company’s biggest business; at that time AWS provided a mere 4% of Amazon’s revenue (but 33% of the profit). In 2018, though, AWS had grown by over 1000% and was up to 11% of Amazon’s revenue (and 59% of the profit), and that share is very much expected to grow, even as AWS faces a competitor in Microsoft Azure that is growing even faster, in large part because existing enterprises are moving to the cloud, not just startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WeWork, meanwhile, using its expansive definition of its addressable market, claims that it has realized only 0.2% of their total opportunity globally, and 0.6% of their opportunity in their ten largest cities. To be fair, one may be skeptical that existing enterprises in particular will be hesitant to turn over management of their existing offices to WeWork, which would dramatically curtail the opportunity; on the other hand, large enterprises now make up 40% of WeWork’s revenue (and rising), and more importantly, WeWork doesn’t have any significant competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;WeWork’s (Lack of) Competition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point around competition is an important one, and one of the more compelling reasons to be bullish on WeWork’s opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious competitor is a company called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iwgplc.com&quot;&gt;IWG&lt;/a&gt;, with 3,306 locations and 445k workstations at the end of 2018. WeWork, in comparison, had 528 locations and 604k workstations as of June 30, 2019. Note the date mismatch — this isn’t a perfect comparison — but that only makes the point that these are two very different companies: WeWork had only 466k workstations at the end of 2018; a year earlier, when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/wework-a-20-billion-startup-fueled-by-silicon-valley-pixie-dust-1508424483&quot;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; pointed out that WeWork’s then-valuation was 5x IWG’s (it is now 13x), WeWork had a mere 150k, while IWG had 414k.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, WeWork is massively more concentrated than IWG (i.e. fewer locations with more workstations), and growing exponentially faster; unsurprisingly, and relatedly, IWG is making money (£154 million last year). That, though, further makes the point: IWG, for better or worse, is constrained by the revenue it makes; WeWork, on the other hand, is perhaps best understood as a clear beneficiary of a world of seemingly unlimited capital. It is difficult to see IWG competing in the long run, or, frankly, anyone else: who is going to fund a WeWork competitor, instead of simply pouring more money into WeWork itself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Capital and Recessions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question of capital is perhaps the biggest one facing WeWork: from the company’s inception on critics have (fairly) wondered what will happen in a recession. It is one thing to sign long leases at low rates and rent out office space at higher rates when the economy is growing; what happens when the economy is shrinking and those long-term leases are not going anywhere, while WeWork customers very well may be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a fair concern and almost certainly the largest reason to be skeptical of WeWork in the short run, but the company does have counter-arguments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;First, WeWork argues that in a downturn increased flexibility and lower costs (relative to traditional office space) may in fact attract new customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, WeWork claims its growing enterprise customer base has nearly doubled lease commitments to 15 months with a committed revenue backlog of $4.0 billion; this is still far shorter than WeWork’s mostly 15-year leases, but perhaps long enough to stabilize the company through a recession.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third, WeWork notes that a recession — provided the company has sufficient capital — would actually allow it to accelerate its buildout as lease and construction costs come down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company also has another, rather unsavory, advantage in a recession: its opaque corporate structure. While there are many downsides to the fact that the “We Company” is a collection of entities, one of the big advantages is that landlords will have a difficult time enforcing any leases that WeWork abandons. From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/83decf7a-c04d-11e9-b350-db00d509634e&quot;&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are limits to what landlords can do to enforce rental commitments. The company, like others in the shared office sector, creates special purpose vehicles for its leases, meaning landlords do not have direct recourse to the parent company if it fails to pay rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, companies in the sector have changed the terms of their leases when downturns hit. Regus, now IWG, renegotiated leases in 2002 when the end of the tech boom cut into its customer base. More recently, an IWG subsidiary that leased a site near Heathrow airport applied for voluntary liquidation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To counter such concerns, WeWork has guaranteed a portion of its rental payments, though a small fraction of the overall obligation. About $4.5bn of rent payments are backed by corporate guarantees and $1.1bn by bank guarantees, according to the group’s pre-IPO filing. It has paid more than $268.3m in cash deposits to landlords and used another $183.9m of surety bonds, a form of insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those guarantees are only $1.6 billion more than WeWork’s committed revenue backlog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;WeWork’s Corporate Governance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly, there is a lot to like about the WeWork opportunity. Yes, a $47 billion valuation seems way too high, particularly given the fact the company is on pace to make only about $440 million in gross profit this year (i.e. excluding all buildout and corporate costs), and given the huge recession risk. At the same time, this is a real business that provides real benefits to companies of all sizes, and those benefits are only growing as the nature of work changes to favor more office work generally and more remote work specifically. And, critically, there is no real competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that the “unsavoriness” I referred to above is hardly limited to the fact that WeWork can stiff its landlords in an emergency. The tech industry generally speaking is hardly a model for good corporate governance, but WeWork takes the absurdity an entirely different level. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;WeWork paid &lt;em&gt;its own CEO&lt;/em&gt;, Adam Neumann, $5.9 million for the “We” trademark when the company reorganized itself earlier this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That reorganization &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/c7fc1f42-b890-11e9-96bd-8e884d3ea203&quot;&gt;created a limited liability company to hold the assets&lt;/a&gt;; investors, however, will buy into a corporation that holds a share of the LLC, while other LLC partners hold the rest, reducing their tax burden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WeWork previously &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-14/wework-gave-founder-loans-as-it-paid-him-rent-ipo-filing-shows&quot;&gt;gave Neumann loans&lt;/a&gt; to buy properties that WeWork then rented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WeWork has hired several of Neumann’s relatives, and Neumann’s wife would be one of three members of a committee tasked to replace Neumann if he were to die or become permanently disabled over the next decade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neumann has three different types of shares that guarantee him majority voting power; those shares retain their rights if sold or given away, instead of converting to common shares.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@byrnehobart/what-is-we-understanding-the-wework-ipo-b74f0f1f1b46&quot;&gt;Byrne Hobart has made the case&lt;/a&gt; that some of the real estate transactions with Neumann are justifiable, but given how bad everything else in this list is, not assuming the worst is a generous interpretation; meanwhile, Neumann has already reportedly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/wework-co-founder-has-cashed-out-at-least-700-million-from-the-company-11563481395&quot;&gt;cashed out $700 million of his holdings via sales and loans&lt;/a&gt;. Everything taken together hints at a completely unaccountable executive looting a company that is running as quickly as it can from massive losses that may very well be fatal whenever the next recession hits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Capital Glut&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I would argue that the WeWork bull case and bear case have more in common than it seems: both are the logical conclusion of effectively unlimited capital. The bull case is that WeWork has seized the opportunity presented by that capital to make a credible play to be the office of choice for companies all over the world, effectively intermediating and commoditizing traditional landlords. It is utterly audacious, and for that reason free of competition. The bear case, meanwhile, is that unlimited capital has resulted in a complete lack of accountability and a predictable litany of abuses, both in terms of corporate risk-taking and personal rent-seeking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the real question, then, is what has driven the capital glut that has both helped WeWork’s business and harmed WeWork’s corporate governance? Is it merely the current economic cycle, which means a recession will not only pressure WeWork’s finances but also turn off the spigot of cash? Or has there been a fundamental shift in the global economy, as the increased impact of technology, with its capital-intensive business model that throws off huge amounts of cash, drives more and more global output?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, there is a case that WeWork is both a symptom of software-eating-the-world, as well as an enabler and driver of the same, which would mean the company would still have access to the capital it needs even in a recession. Investors would just have to accept the fact they will have absolutely no impact on how it is used, and that, beyond the sky-high valuation and the real concerns about a duration mismatch in a recession, is a very good reason to stay away.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 13:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>denzil_correa</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The WeWork IPO</og:title>
<og:url>https://stratechery.com/2019/the-wework-ipo/</og:url>
<og:description>The WeWork IPO is defined by audaciousness and excess, all of which is driven by unlimited access to capital.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Screen-Shot-2019-08-20-at-7.16.37-PM-1024x327.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stratechery.com/2019/the-wework-ipo/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘They Get Fired All the Time. And They Have No Idea Why’</title>
<link>https://www.institutionalinvestor.com/article/b1gq9tqwk8z108/They-Get-Fired-All-the-Time-And-They-Have-No-Idea-Why</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.institutionalinvestor.com/article/b1gq9tqwk8z108/They-Get-Fired-All-the-Time-And-They-Have-No-Idea-Why</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Three weeks after I enrolled my youngest child in a neighborhood nursery school in Brooklyn, I got the call. An administrator and my child’s lead teacher urgently wanted to meet with my husband and me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our daughter, it turned out, was wandering out of the classroom. She wasn’t making eye contact. She didn’t respond to her name. She couldn’t carry on a conversation with her teachers or classmates. She had poor fine motor skills. She didn’t play with toys like others did. Most alarmingly, she wasn’t socializing well — or at all — with other children. In short, it was impossible to teach her in a regular classroom setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were baffled. Those observations didn’t square with the ebullient, extremely verbal child whose pediatrician had never raised any red flags about her social or emotional development. But at the school’s urging, we had her evaluated through New York City’s Department of Education. Looking for a diagnosis — something the DOE doesn’t give for preschoolers — we also sought the advice of a developmental pediatrician, who confirmed what no one else would tell us: Our daughter was on the autism spectrum. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how, in the winter of 2019, I was thrust headlong into the world of autism and all that it entailed: figuring out what the diagnosis meant, learning how to navigate the overwhelming bureaucracy of parenting a special-needs child, wondering anxiously what her future might be like. Statistics I uncovered were deeply disturbing — fewer than 16 percent of adults diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder were employed full-time, for example.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at about the same time, something extraordinary happened. In February 2019, Bill Gross, christened the Bond King for his phenomenal multidecade winning streak as a co-founder and portfolio manager at PIMCO, revealed in an interview with Bloomberg Television that he had recently been diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disclosure prompted a discussion in the &lt;em&gt;Institutional Investor&lt;/em&gt; newsroom about how many other people in finance might also fall on the spectrum, whether diagnosed or undiagnosed. The idea for a feature was born. With my personal and professional worlds converging to a degree they never had in my nearly 20-year career covering finance, I jumped at the chance to write it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-698df097386c422d8ac88e03f621a0ac&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slot698df097386c422d8ac88e03f621a0ac&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through weeks of intensive research, a singular truth emerged. People with Asperger’s syndrome, the term still commonly used for one of the most well-known forms of autism spectrum disorder, bring serious advantages to the financial markets: extreme focus, a facility with numbers, a willingness to consider unpopular opinions, a strong sense of logic, and an intense belief in fairness and justice. But, like other autistic employees, they often feel alienated from their managers, colleagues, and clients. Sometimes they simply get fired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is hope. An emerging group of self-styled neurodiversity activists, many of whom proudly identify as autistic, are demanding to be accepted exactly as they are and are working toward a world that doesn’t just accommodate but embraces autistic people. And in an increasingly tight labor market, some companies, like JPMorgan Chase, are seeking to take advantage of the strengths that autistic workers bring to the table — and they’re seeing real financial benefits from doing so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, overall employment numbers for autistic people remain bleak, and stereotypes about them persist in spite of research breakthroughs and increased awareness over the past few years.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the reporting of this story, numerous analysts, money managers, traders, and institutional investors bravely shared their experiences with me: the frustrations, the benefits, and the challenges of working in one of the world’s most competitive industries as an autistic person. Here are some of their stories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Greg — not his real name — works at a quantitative&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; investment firm on the West Coast. Like all quants, he’s good at math, but one of his particular specialties is recognizing patterns and details. He’s so good at it, in fact, that one December he picked up on an odd trading pattern and realized his firm should make changes to its models. The move saved his firm 3,000 basis points, or 30 percent, which translated to savings of literally millions of dollars for its clients.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg is smart, to be sure. But he credits his pattern recognition ability — and the attendant windfall — to Asperger’s syndrome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-dc2da4d6a0e74bbfbbe2237ac65a783b&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slotdc2da4d6a0e74bbfbbe2237ac65a783b&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Finance is mostly details, and just having the ability to systematize and categorize and focus on details can be a huge advantage,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people on the autism spectrum, including Greg, the condition also has its downsides. For those who struggle socially, just getting past the interview stage can be an extraordinary trial, to say nothing of the challenges of navigating the customs of corporate culture once they actually do get jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the condition isn’t rare. If anything, it’s become a kind of glib shorthand for describing a certain subtype of finance professional as being “on the spectrum”: brilliant, solitary math whizzes who struggle with social interactions, obsess over things, and can be a little too blunt, but who mint money thanks to their dazzling insights. (It’s even turned up in pop culture. Novelist Gary Shteyngart’s &lt;em&gt;Lake Success&lt;/em&gt; chronicles the midlife crisis of Barry Cohen, who flees his failing firm and abandons his autistic son, only to realize after a period of solitude and self-examination that his own struggles with socializing, gift for math, and singular obsession with watches point to the origin of his son’s condition.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The archetype holds a kernel of truth — and real-life examples abound on the trading floors of bulge-bracket banks and in the halls of hallowed quant firms. One institutional investor — who is on the spectrum — speculated that, based on the number of due diligence meetings his firm has, the rate of autism spectrum disorder is almost certainly higher in finance professionals than in the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, the most famous person in finance to self-identify as autistic was Michael Burry, one of the heroes of Michael Lewis’s book &lt;em&gt;The Big Short&lt;/em&gt;. Burry made hundreds of millions on his view — extremely contrarian at the time — that the housing market was about to go bust. He was one of the first not only to spot the problems in the market, but to create a way to short it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The savvy bet cost him a few investors in the short run, but it ultimately made him very rich — and shone a bright light on Asperger’s syndrome when Burry revealed to Lewis that he had realized he had the condition shortly after his young son was diagnosed with it. The revelation spurred numerous other people to seek out their own diagnoses. One of those people turned out to be Gross, the Bond King, who said that in reading about Burry, he recognized himself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-f1f16b667e584bd58d78db70a0d30c74&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slotf1f16b667e584bd58d78db70a0d30c74&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today autism spectrum disorder is broadly described as a developmental disorder that affects communication and behavior. One form of the condition used to be called Asperger’s syndrome, named for Hans Asperger, the clinician who is now widely credited with discovering autism, as we understand it today, in the early 20th century. But that changed with the 2013 revision of the &lt;em&gt;Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders&lt;/em&gt;, which grouped autistic disorder, Asperger’s, and another condition not previously classified as autism into a new, single diagnosis called “autism spectrum disorder.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the term “Asperger’s syndrome” is still used in other countries, and many people in the U.S. continue to use it to identify themselves. The cluster of traits commonly associated with Asperger’s includes an obsession with fairness, the ability to focus intensely on repetitive tasks, social awkwardness, a pathological inability to lie, a tendency to be extremely literal, and a facility for thinking logically and discounting extraneous information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several of those traits can come in handy when it comes to careers in investing and money management, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you worry about looking good or fitting in, then you’re going to keep your unpopular opinions to yourself,” notes Jonathan Tepper, who worked as a trader at SAC Capital and as a proprietary trader at Bank of America before founding Variant Perception, which provides research and investment strategies to hedge funds and other asset managers. “When Variant started, I wrote a report saying the Spanish banking system was insolvent and unemployment would go up to 25 percent — and it was described as a ‘catastrophist’ report. We were attacked, but it turned out to be correct. Most people at the time were not writing about that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Brown, who manages a $135 million multistrategy fund called Aristides Capital — and who, like Gross, discovered his condition after reading &lt;em&gt;The Big Short&lt;/em&gt; — agrees. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m utterly unable to get caught up in manias,” says Brown, an Air Force veteran and MD who refers to himself as an “aspie” in his Twitter bio. “Just being able to recognize when the herd is acting silly and not being caught up in it is definitely a big advantage. There is a certain normal human emotional response that people get very excited about a chart that’s going up and to the right, and I don’t have that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-530e2f16599840f4bd2f767a8eba0acb&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slot530e2f16599840f4bd2f767a8eba0acb&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;But as Greg and other finance professionals diagnosed with ASD explain, there are drawbacks. Some, deemed virtually unemployable because of their poor social skills, simply start their own firms, content to manage small amounts of capital or outsource the money-raising functions to more socially adept professionals. Burry, who initially trained to be a physician but balked at treating patients, opened his own shop, generating buzz and attracting capital based entirely on his phenomenal performance as a stock picker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Burry, who did not respond to a request for comment, the discovery that he was autistic was initially distressing. It also made sense. As Lewis writes, “It explained an awful lot about what he did for a living, and how he did it: his obsessive acquisition of hard facts, his insistence on logic, his ability to plow through reams of tedious financial statements.” As Burry told Lewis, “Only someone who has Asperger’s would read a subprime-mortgage-bond prospectus.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gross felt similar shock waves of recognition upon his diagnosis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m sort of proud of it, because it explains a lot about me,” he said in the Bloomberg Television interview. “All Asperger’s are not geniuses; the intelligence thing is not necessarily a big part of it. But my personal behavior, my ability to relate to people, my singular hobbies — stamp collecting, this, and this, and this — I said, hey, so maybe I do. So I did go to a psychiatrist. And at the end of the meeting I said, ‘Do you think I have Asperger’s?’ And she said, &lt;em&gt;‘Oh, yeah’&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gross was a larger-than-life figure in the then-moribund world of bond trading, becoming almost as well known for his unusually vivid investment letters, nasty divorce, and spats with colleagues as for his investment prowess. Of course, rainmakers like Gross can be as eccentric as they want, at least up to a point — he was eventually forced out of his job at PIMCO in a messy exit that was finally settled in 2017. He told the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; earlier this year that his condition makes him a “singular, dominating, angry, quiet, introverted person,” which alienated colleagues and ultimately led to his ouster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But relatively few autistic people manage to have such brilliant careers — or to have careers at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-149daddca76746eb83545a1f6d8d0952&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slot149daddca76746eb83545a1f6d8d0952&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s in spite of the fact that more than a third of people diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder are college-educated, studies show. Given that an estimated one in 59 children have been diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder — making it one of the largest minority groups in America — this could potentially become a social problem of crisis proportions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for those people already working on Wall Street who either fit the definition but don’t have a diagnosis or who do but don’t want their employers to know — the workplace can be especially fraught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.institutionalinvestor.com/media/AMG/II/articles/2019/8/14/Wall_Street_spot.jpg&quot; class=&quot;summernote-placed-asset&quot; data-uniqueidentifier=&quot;37763&quot; data-profile=&quot;Image&quot; data-timestamp=&quot;1565809662802&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“If you’ve met one person with autism, you’ve met one person with autism”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is an often-heard quotation in neurodiversity activist circles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The range of human behavior described by the autism spectrum is exceptionally broad,” says Steve Silberman, the author of &lt;em&gt;NeuroTribes: The Legacy of Autism and the Future of Neurodiversity&lt;/em&gt;. “You have super-chatty people who go on and on about their favorite TV shows or whatever, and then you have people who cannot talk at all, and don’t seem to want to talk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silberman’s interest in autism began around the turn of the century. As a journalist in Silicon Valley, he noticed a strange coincidence: Two of the brilliant computer scientists and Valley tech pioneers he was profiling had autistic children. When he made this observation to a friend in a local café, a teacher overheard him and told him she thought there was an “epidemic” of autism in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-bb5bd30b55a740f8b57c15762fde9b98&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slotbb5bd30b55a740f8b57c15762fde9b98&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;“At that point everyone, including clinicians and researchers, thought that autism was extremely rare,” says Silberman. “I can’t overstate how pervasive the belief that autism was rare was. And so I thought to myself, ‘Why am I running into two families in Silicon Valley where there are kids in the families that have this exceptionally rare condition?’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That led to a 2001 article for &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt; magazine, “The Geek Syndrome,” in which Silberman raised the question of whether genetics was the reason that autism seemed to be surging in Silicon Valley. The story generated an enormous response from readers who saw themselves or their children in its portrayals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While researching the article, Silberman made another striking discovery: The research of Leo Kanner (pronounced “konner”) — an Austrian psychiatrist who emigrated to the U.S. in the early 1920s and who was widely considered to be the world’s leading authority on autism from the middle of the century through the 1980s or so — conflicted dramatically with the much-less-well-known work of fellow Austrian Hans Asperger. Kanner insisted that autism was very rare, “inevitably devastating,” and caused by a lack of warmth from parents, Silberman writes in &lt;em&gt;NeuroTribes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asperger, a pediatrician, offered an alternative view of autism — one that Silberman argues is progressive even by contemporary standards. As Silberman explained in a recent TED talk, Asperger viewed the condition as a continuum, with affected individuals displaying “an astonishing diversity of gifts and disabilities.” As Asperger explained to his colleagues in the 1930s, “Once you learn to recognize the distinctive traits of autism, you see them everywhere.” Asperger argued that autism is a lifelong — and a very common — condition that requires support from teachers, parents, and the community, and that it’s primarily genetically transmitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why did Kanner’s model prevail for so long? Silberman contends in &lt;em&gt;NeuroTribes&lt;/em&gt; that Kanner deliberately suppressed Asperger’s work in the U.S. — and in so doing set back the diagnosis and treatment of autism for most of the 20th century. Thanks to the efforts of a British psychiatrist named Lorna Wing and her colleagues to get Asperger’s groundbreaking work translated into English and disseminated on a wide scale, clinicians — and most important, government health agencies — finally began to accept Asperger’s model of autism in the 1990s, Silberman writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s about the time that autism began to gain a foothold in the national consciousness. The 1988 film &lt;em&gt;Rain Man&lt;/em&gt;, starring Dustin Hoffman, centered around an autistic-savant character who was strictly wedded to his routines and couldn’t live on his own but had an uncanny ability to count cards in Las Vegas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-c3af11de97b747268fdd53578df9ad78&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slotc3af11de97b747268fdd53578df9ad78&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Silberman explains, few people knew what autism looked like before the release of the film. The movie, along with the change in criteria for autism diagnoses as well as the introduction of new diagnostic tests, created what he has called “a perfect storm of autism awareness.” The number of diagnoses increased dramatically, as Wing and her colleagues had hoped they would, because the prevalence of autism as described by Asperger was much greater than Kanner had theorized. The change also revealed that autism looks very different from one person to the next.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s true even of the financial professionals on the spectrum who were interviewed for this story. Variant’s Tepper, who was diagnosed as an adult, jokes that when he revealed to his friends — already convinced he was on the spectrum — that a psychologist had confirmed he had the condition, they said, “And you paid him for that?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in spite of his somewhat obsessive interests, tendency to memorize numbers as a child, and penchant for logic and facts, Tepper says the condition hasn’t impeded his daily functioning in the slightest. He maintains a thriving social life in London, where he lives, and argues that his ASD helps more than hinders him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you look at people who score highly for all the traits that are measured, you find lots of entrepreneurs, investment managers, and others,” says Tepper, who wonders if autism spectrum disorders are overdiagnosed. “It doesn’t change how I behave or who I am, just [brings] more awareness into how I relate to others.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others have struggled more, particularly in childhood, but eventually figured out coping mechanisms that enabled them to work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was the sort of kid who, if I was into something, I’d just go on about it,” says Aristides Capital’s Brown, who taught himself the rudiments of how to have a conversation with someone else — focusing on actively paying attention to what the other person is saying so that what he says next is in response to what was just said. “Even one weird habit I have sometimes is, on the phone, if I’m actively listening to someone, I don’t intuitively make any noise. My way of listening is to be dead silent, so I’ve had to learn to say ‘uh-huh,’ that kind of thing.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-2283fecaa26e42e2bd71e75d345fecf5&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slot2283fecaa26e42e2bd71e75d345fecf5&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That self-training, which autistic people refer to as “masking,” extended to body language, Brown adds: “The way I know to make eye contact is thinking about making eye contact. Just thinking about carrying my body in a way that’s not slouchy, it takes a lot of thought and being ‘on.’ Meeting with people is very much performance.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And one that he doesn’t particularly relish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve had people say, ‘With your performance record you should be managing a billion dollars by now,’” says Brown. He attributes his smaller portfolio partly to Aristides’ focus on an illiquid corner of the microcap space, which limits his fund’s capacity. “And part of it is that I’m just a shitty marketer. I have poor interpersonal skills; I am not good at creating FOMO,” he explains, laughing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brown, like others in his position, hired an adept No. 2 who runs day-to-day operations and has enlisted the help of third-party marketers for capital raising. This allows him to focus on the portfolio, where he’s most comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think a big reason you see a lot of ASD people working in quantitative investing is personally because you just don’t have to talk to people very much,” muses Greg, the West Coast quant. “But the type of mind-set you need to succeed in quantitative investing — in a normal person it might be perceived as paranoia, but for an ASD person it’s thinking, ‘Everybody knows exactly what I know.’ If you think that everybody knows exactly what you know, that manifests itself as pushing and pushing to get better and constantly re-creating your edge, and that is absolutely what is necessary in quant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For others, however, that mind-set can manifest as low self-esteem and sometimes crippling self-doubt. Bart — whose last name is being withheld — is a passionate devotee of the markets and possesses a keen intelligence. He bought his first stock in 1987 and has followed the markets ever since. But his difficulty with socializing has made it hard for him to function in society. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-17fb76a709c24db5abe2590652ad1a0b&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slot17fb76a709c24db5abe2590652ad1a0b&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like others interviewed for this story, Bart had a hard time remembering the names of his classmates as a young student. He got into in trouble at school and then drifted from one menial job to another, starting as a night watchman in a cheese factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bart ultimately got a job that suited him, working as a logistics manager, again on the night shift — which served the dual purpose of limiting his contact with others and allowing him to follow global markets during quiet periods. But after a few years, he burned out and quit, falling into a paralyzing funk that he struggled for years to come out of. Roughly ten years ago a psychiatrist finally diagnosed him with ASD. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then Bart has carved out a peaceful existence as a day trader working from home, in a suburb of Amsterdam. He severed the few social contacts he had left, preferring to let his wife handle the socializing, which he finds excruciating.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Life has been a bit easier, a bit more relaxing,” he says. “I was always interested in finance, especially in the stock market. It was always a hobby, but from that point on it became a bit of an obsession. But now in the last couple of years, I’m more a swing trader — if I don’t trade one day, I don’t feel unhappy; I’m okay with it. I think that comes with age.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Bart says the self-doubt that has plagued him all his life still affects his trading decisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s more a handicap than a help for me,” he explains, “because my first thought is 95 percent that I’m right. After that I start doubting. You go over the pros and the cons, and that’s difficult for me.” But his lack of emotional attachment to his positions works well on the flip side. “When I have a losing position, I have no problems with closing it. I don’t care.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-9dc9f76438a8442796e0ecd4a5f774f3&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slot9dc9f76438a8442796e0ecd4a5f774f3&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For people like Bart who are diagnosed as adults, there is initially a sense of relief — at last there’s a name and an explanation for what has made them different their whole lives. But this is quickly followed by the sobering realization that autism spectrum disorder is a lifelong condition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People don’t really want to feel like they’re different,” says Greg. “If I have high blood pressure, I can go get a Lipitor prescription. If you’re diagnosed with Asperger’s, there’s not a pill or a patch or a cream. It’s mostly thinking about a set of strategies to approach different situations, and it’s a little bit of a cloud over your head.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;For all the progress in diagnosing and treating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; autism spectrum disorder in the past couple of decades, some of the hallmark traits of the condition make it extremely difficult even for those who are verbal and highly intelligent — in other words, most likely to pass as neurotypical — to succeed at work. A big part of the problem is in the way firms recruit and interview employees. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you look at job descriptions, people tend to put core skills in that won’t always be there” for autistic people, according to Richmal Maybank, an employer engagement manager at the National Autistic Society. “Things like ‘Must be a great team player, must have amazing communication skills’ — some of these generic must-haves that are put into job descriptions often unintentionally leave [autistic] people out and make people think, ‘Oh, maybe this isn’t right for me.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NeuroTribes&lt;/em&gt; author Silberman recalls a conversation he once had with Jose Velasco, who heads up software giant SAP’s Autism at Work program to recruit and train autistic workers. “‘The list of stuff that you’re supposed to do in every job interview is like a list of stuff that’s really hard for most autistic people to do.’” [Have] a firm handshake, good eye contact, sell yourself . . . it’s the opposite of autism, almost.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg, the West Coast quant, recalls a particularly terrifying job interview with a large public pension plan. He arrived at the interview room and got settled on one side of the table. Then a large group of executives came and sat down across from him. “If it’s one person, I can devote a quarter of my brain RPMs to trying to decipher their body language or interest, but if it’s a dozen people, it’s basically having an audience watching you squirm. It’s really painful.” Even worse: After that grueling first round, the executives left — and another large group followed them in to repeat the process. “I almost said, ‘I can just go back to the airport for my flight; it’s not that important,’” Greg recalls, laughing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-24742db7eecd4db99f7893238e72a1c7&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slot24742db7eecd4db99f7893238e72a1c7&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those who make it through this arduous process, keeping their jobs is another matter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Socially, we look for certain styles of communication and certain behaviors that aren’t always present with people on the spectrum,” explains James Mahoney, head of JPMorgan Chase’s Autism at Work program. “We are really good at hiring the gregarious extrovert. We want that strong communicator.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That focus on the extroverted people person comes at an immense cost, Mahoney argues. “I’m absolutely confident, without any scientific metrics, that we walk away from brilliance every day because of differences in that communication style.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcia Scheiner, the founder of Integrate Autism Employment Advisors, which helps companies fill jobs with young adults on the autism spectrum, and the parent of an adult son with Asperger’s syndrome, gives an example: A person on the spectrum may be sitting in a meeting, “and somebody says something and someone on the spectrum will say, ‘Well, that’s the stupidest thing I’ve ever heard.’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrate’s clients are companies that are specifically looking to hire autistic workers, namely young adults who are transitioning into the workforce. She recalls one candidate she placed in an actuary role at a large accounting firm. One day the young man’s manager called her in a panic. The manager had asked him if he would like to complete a task that needed doing, and the young man simply said, “No.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, when asked why, the young man said he’d been working on another project on a deadline and didn’t think he should take on extra work. Scheiner explained to the manager that he needed to be more specific and directly tell the employee that he wanted him to set aside what he was currently working on and start on the new task. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-f19399096d184751af46d33a0f57f988&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slotf19399096d184751af46d33a0f57f988&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In this case, the person was disclosed [as being on the spectrum] and they were working with us, so there was the ability to deal with those issues,” she says. “But for people who go in and don’t disclose and then start doing those kinds of things that make perfect sense to them, they get fired all the time. And they have no idea why.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Some employers are arriving at the conclusion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that the payoff from hiring autistic workers exceeds any cultural training or accommodations that need to be made and have started to specifically seek out autistic workers. The trend is catching on in an exceptionally tight labor market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mahoney says JPMorgan Chase started its Autism at Work program as a pilot four years ago. The firm’s initial hires were in the software quality assurance department, which has a high volume of work and very clear rules about when things pass and fail — another area where autistic people, who often have a strong sense of fairness and justice, excel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We found the people on the spectrum with no experience had the same level of quality —and were much faster — after six months than the [neurotypical] people with five or ten years of experience,” Mahoney says. On the back of that initial success, the bank expanded hiring to another job family: workers who receive requests from a system queue. Those workers ramped up even faster than the first group. “By the third month they were at between 90 and 140 percent higher productivity and higher quality” than other employees, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program switched out of pilot mode 18 months after it started. Today the bank employs 146 individuals on the autism spectrum, with 90 percent hired through the program and the rest who already worked at the bank and disclosed their diagnoses, in some cases because of the program. (Mahoney estimates that the number of autistic people the bank employs is much higher in total.) The program has hired people for 40-plus different roles, from intern to bank teller to fraud analyst to senior manager. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mahoney urges employers who are thinking about implementing such programs to take the leap — provided they will be hiring workers to fill slots that already exist, rather than creating jobs to fill a quota that could later be eliminated in a restructuring. He emphasizes that the program has been a runaway success for the bank, but that he and other executives had to rethink and redo how they recruited, interviewed, and hired workers through the program. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-3d984253be114075ad7673b87bdfab41&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slot3d984253be114075ad7673b87bdfab41&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That started with the job interview process. As Maybank of the National Autistic Society notes, small measures such as furnishing questions in advance, offering more processing time, and using skills-based assessments can be effective for these candidates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mahoney also urges interviewers to be more literal and ask questions such as “What did you do at your previous job?” rather than “What would you do in this situation?” The latter calls for conjecture, and some people on the spectrum might not be able to answer in the abstract, he says.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many workers on the autism spectrum, other conditions may be present, including anxiety. Mahoney recalls a candidate who had a stutter that became more pronounced with anxiety. The candidate explained this at the outset of an interview; the hiring manager opted to try the traditional route but also came up with a solution in case it didn’t work — asking questions via instant messenger. The candidate struggled, Mahoney says, until the conversation moved to internet chat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Once the candidate started using the chat mechanism,” Mahoney continues, “their answers were so crisp, on point, showed strong depth of thinking, visualization, and solving problems — and the manager afterward was quite emotional, conveying that if we hadn’t done this type of accommodation, we would have walked away from someone who was clearly well versed, clearly positioned to do the job well, and the manager couldn’t believe we could have missed out on that.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silberman takes pains to point out that companies can benefit from hiring people across the spectrum, including people who present as far more disabled than the typical Asperger’s case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is one of the things that is becoming apparent with the success of programs like SAP’s Autism at Work,” he says. “What they found was that even people who were more profoundly autistic could do lots of jobs. It’s possible to develop work environments that enable even more visibly disabled people to work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-3494c6004dbc48469fd6fb2095ca3f02&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slot3494c6004dbc48469fd6fb2095ca3f02&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those who work in more typical portfolio management or analyst functions, another potential stumbling block is what happens when employees hit the mid-career stage — which is around the time they are generally asked to do more things, such as manage people or interact with clients. Some people interviewed for this story expressed concern that career advancement can be fraught for autistic people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A lot of organizations need to look at their practices and their culture — how can people progress without having to go through traditional routes? It’s not particularly fair if you’re only able to progress within the organization if you’re going out to after-work drinks every night and building connections,” says Maybank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those cultural shifts are already underway in the autism community. The neurodiversity movement boasts a growing number of autistic activists, many of whom tweet under the hashtag #actuallyautistic and are striving to ensure that the voices of autistic adults are included in conversations about policy and discrimination. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Younger people were diagnosed when they were children, so they’ve grown up with it and are comfortable with it,” says Scheiner. “I think their peers are comfortable with it. The stigma among their peer group just doesn’t exist the way it exists for people in their late 30s and 40s and 50s.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These activists are striving to make the world more inclusive of people like my daughter — who, I’m happy to say, is now thriving at a special-needs preschool for children with autism and other conditions. Until the movement gains widespread acceptance and more people identify publicly as autistic, however, the onus is on companies to seek out and retain autistic employees, making sure they have the tools they need to thrive in the workplace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The thing is to allow them to pursue their interests with vigor, and without being discouraged by being too single-minded or obsessive,” says Silberman. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-3caed445b42d49e68eb0f0634a967c0a&quot; data-is-lazy=&quot;0&quot; data-is-responsive=&quot;1&quot; data-slot-variable-name=&quot;slot3caed445b42d49e68eb0f0634a967c0a&quot; data-is-out-of-page-slot=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The costs of not doing so could be high — and not just from a social perspective. Investors could miss out, too.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The movement toward more quantitatively rigorous and more well-defined portfolio management practices, more quantitative investing, is definitely a huge trend,” says Greg, the West Coast quant. “It’s definitely more of a benefit toward people that are on the autism spectrum than not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One anonymous commenter on Wall Street Oasis, an online community for finance pros, puts it this way: “The world has enough smart and pedigreed people, but what it lacks is courage to act on your beliefs when different. I truly do think my autism is a superpower in many ways.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 13:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>laurex</dc:creator>
<og:title>‘They Get Fired All the Time. And They Have No Idea Why.’</og:title>
<og:description>Pop culture lionizes the dazzling brilliance of money managers on the autism spectrum. Reality rarely measures up.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.institutionalinvestor.com/article/b1gq9tqwk8z108/They-Get-Fired-All-the-Time-And-They-Have-No-Idea-Why</og:url>
<og:image>https://institutionalinvestor.euromoneycdn.com/media/AMG/II/articles/2019/8/14/Wall_Street_final.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.institutionalinvestor.com/article/b1gq9tqwk8z108/They-Get-Fired-All-the-Time-And-They-Have-No-Idea-Why</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Yubico launches its dual USB-C and Lightning two-factor security key</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/20/yubikey-dual-usb-c-lightning/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/20/yubikey-dual-usb-c-lightning/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Almost two months after it was first announced, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/yubico&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;yubico&quot;&gt;Yubico&lt;/a&gt; has launched the YubiKey 5Ci, a security key with dual support for iPhones, Macs and other USB-C compatible devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yubico’s newest YubiKey is the latest iteration of its security key built to support a newer range of devices, including Apple’s iPhone, iPad and MacBooks, in a single device. Announced in June, the company said the security keys would cater to cross-platform users — particularly Apple device owners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These security keys are small enough to sit on a keyring. When you want to log in to an online account, you plug in the key to your device and it authenticates you. Your Gmail, Twitter and Facebook account all support these plug-in devices as a second-factor of authentication after your username and password — a far stronger mechanism than the simple code sent to your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security keys offer &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/20/google-data-two-factor-security/&quot;&gt;almost unbeatable security&lt;/a&gt; and can protect against a variety of threats, including nation-state attackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerrod Chong, Yubico’s chief solutions officer, said the new key would fill a “critical gap in the mobile authentication ecosystem,” particularly given how users are increasingly spending their time across a multitude of mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new key works with a range of apps, including password managers like 1Password and LastPass, and web browsers like Brave, which support security key authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 12:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jeromegv</dc:creator>
<og:title>This new YubiKey will offer dual security for Apple users – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>Almost two months after it was first announced, Yubico has launched the YubiKey 5Ci, a security key with dual support for iPhones, Macs and other USB-C compatible devices. Yubico’s newest YubiKey is the latest iteration of its security key built to support a newer range of devices, including …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/yubikey.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/08/20/yubikey-dual-usb-c-lightning/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/20/yubikey-dual-usb-c-lightning/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>People love working remotely</title>
<link>https://usefyi.com/remote-work-report/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://usefyi.com/remote-work-report/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Remote work isn’t just here to stay, it’s becoming the new norm. A way of working that people love and strive for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just the people who work 100% remotely today either. We’re all exposed to remote work on a weekly - if not daily - basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s a meeting where someone joins from home or another office. Collaborating with a vendor who works in another location. Or working from home or a co-working space part of the week. We’re all increasingly exposed to forms of remote work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the tools are here to help. Productivity tools have caught up to the remote trend. Remote integrates seamlessly into our work lives. Thanks to the likes of &lt;a href=&quot;http://usefyi.com/slack-history&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://zoom.us/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gsuite.google.com/products/meet/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Hangouts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://usefyi.com/g-suite&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;G Suite&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://usefyi.com/what-is-office-365/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Office 365&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://usefyi.com/evernote&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;, our partner on the survey &lt;a href=&quot;https://miro.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Miro&lt;/a&gt;, and the slew of other ever-expanding and new cloud collaboration tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the tools aren’t enough to make remote work. There are behavioral changes that organizations and people need to make in order for remote work to be successful. We’ll cover tips from remote workers on how to best work remotely, plus all the other juicy insights we learned about remote work and meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Remote work is on the rise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote work isn’t a new thing. It’s been on the rise for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;63% of US companies now have remote workers, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/upwork/2018-future-workforce-report-hiring-manager-insights-on-flexible-and-remote-work-trends/1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2018 Upwork Study&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gallup’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gallup.com/workplace/238085/state-american-workplace-report-2017.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;State of the American Workplace Report&lt;/a&gt; found that 43% of employees work remotely at least some of the time. And among those who work remotely at least part of the time, the percent of employees who work remotely 100% of the time is now 20%, up from 15% four years prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are increasingly attracted to remote jobs, with 37% saying they would switch to a job that gave them the ability to work off-site at least part of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;wwr-logo&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The largest remote work community in the world and remote job board &lt;a href=&quot;https://weworkremotely.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;We Work Remotely&lt;/a&gt; shared insights with us about the remote work trends they’ve seen since 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WWR is the top destination for posting remote jobs. And they’ve seen a huge increase in the number of jobs posted on their site over the last 6 years - from just over 300 in 2013, to nearly 2400 in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Number of jobs posted on &lt;span class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;WWR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren’t just more remote roles out there. Companies are increasingly going fully remote themselves. In 2014, only 2% of roles posted on WWR were from fully remote companies with no headquarters. In 2018, 16% of posted roles belonged to fully remote companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Percentage of &lt;span class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;WWR&lt;/span&gt; roles at remote companies (no HQ)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;al-logo&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/remote&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AngelList&lt;/a&gt;, a site for startups, investors, and job-seekers looking to work with startups, has also seen a surge in remote jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29%&lt;/strong&gt; of all the startups with roles posted on AngelList live in August 2019 were hiring remote roles. That’s over 7600 startups hiring remote roles, more than 1500 of which are mostly or fully remote companies themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it’s likely we’re about to see even more remote roles in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to AngelList, younger startups are more likely to hire remote than more established companies. In August 2019, 31% of companies younger than 2 years old had at least one open remote role, compared to 26% of companies older than 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The younger startups of today are much more likely to be remote friendly as they grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Companies with one or more open remote role on &lt;span class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;AngelList&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AngelList has even hired someone to lead their efforts on remote work, pointing to a focus on the growing category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And millennials are leading the charge when it comes to remote.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/themes/fyi/dist/images/remote/p-1.jpg&quot;/&gt; Millennials prefer working for companies that provide flexibility
&lt;p&gt;Fifty percent of millennials consider flexibility of hours and the location where they work to be very important when choosing whether or not to work for an organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also expect to stay at jobs with more flexibility for longer, according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.deloitte.com/content/dam/Deloitte/global/Documents/About-Deloitte/gx-2018-millennial-survey-report.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2018 Millennial Survey Report&lt;/a&gt; by Deloitte.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 11:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>galfarragem</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Remote Work Report</og:title>
<og:description>91% of remote workers said working remotely is a good fit for them. Find out why in this report based on an in-depth survey of 486 people.</og:description>
<og:url>https://usefyi.com/remote-work-report/</og:url>
<og:image>https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Aug8_RemoteReport_SocialImage_8_@2x-1024x512.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://usefyi.com/remote-work-report/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>