<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Jack Dorsey gives $1B to fund global Covid-19 relief</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/jack/status/1247616214769086465</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/jack/status/1247616214769086465</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Why the transparency? It’s important to show my work so I and others can learn. I’ve discovered and funded ($40mm) many orgs with proven impact and efficiency in the past, mostly anonymously. Going forward, all grants will be public. Suggestions welcome. Drop your cash app ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 20:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dsr12</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/jack/status/1247616214769086465</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Data Science: Reality Doesn&amp;#039;t Meet Expectations</title>
<link>https://dfrieds.com/articles/data-science-reality-vs-expectations.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://dfrieds.com/articles/data-science-reality-vs-expectations.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I use the term Data Scientist throughout this post; however, popular titles such as Machine Learning Engineer, Data Analyst, Data Engineers, BI analysts share similar responsibilities and could be used interchangeably here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had high hopes about the potential impact of being a Data Scientist. I felt every company should be a “data company”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My expectations did not meet reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where did my expectations come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended a 12-week data science bootcamp in mid-2016. 11 of the 12 weeks’ focus were on machine learning (ML) and artificial intelligence (AI). At this time, ML &amp;amp; AI news mentions had hit an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.gartner.com/smarterwithgartner/top-trends-on-the-gartner-hype-cycle-for-artificial-intelligence-2019/&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1586278559727000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNG9wXSpgrRxikBtkGMJhDQVkhk3CA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;all-time high&lt;/a&gt;. Tesla was paving the way in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/autopilot&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;self-driving cars&lt;/a&gt;, and even older behemoths like General Motors (GM) invested over a &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2016/03/11/gm-buying-self-driving-tech-startup-for-more-than-1-billion/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;billion dollars&lt;/a&gt; in an AI company to stay at the frontier of automotive tech. At the consumer level, headphones emerged that used AI to automatically translate your words to someone else as you speak, and an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/13/18309459/openai-five-dota-2-finals-ai-bot-competition-og-e-sports-the-international-champion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AI beat the world’s best esports team&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured I’d spend most of my time buried in code and data to find hidden patterns, implement machine learning models in production and optimize them. Executives would likely rely on me to help inform the product roadmap based on insights in data, and I would be highly valued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, practically none of that happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I’ve worked as a Data Scientist, a Data Engineer, and as an industry consultant. I’ve also learned from the stories of dozens of data scientists and similar professions, actively read articles on data science and followed data science thought leaders on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across these diverse data experiences, I have noticed common themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are seven most common (and at times flagrant) ways that data science has failed to meet expectations in industry. Throughout each section, I’ll propose solutions to these shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;People don’t know what “data science” does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data science leadership is sorely lacking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data science can’t always be built to specs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re likely the only “data person.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your impact is tough to measure — data doesn’t always translate to value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data &amp;amp; infrastructure have serious quality problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data work can be profoundly unethical. Moral courage required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;1. People don’t know what “data science” does.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people think “data science” is all ML, AI and/or custom algorithms. Others think it’s simply analytics. Many data scientists may spend a significant portion of their time on Extract-Transform-Load (ETL). The truth is - all of these things are possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to this lack of clarity, in interviews, you can be asked about any of these topics and more! In 50+ interviews for data related jobs, I’ve been asked about AB testing, SQL analytics questions, optimizing SQL queries, how to code a game in Python, Logistic Regression, Gradient Boosted Trees, data structures and/or algorithms programming problems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s daunting to study a wide breadth of concepts and still have depth. Keep your chin up! Expect interviews to be confusing and frustrating, as there’s no de facto set of problems and questions. Ask your hiring managers for specific details on the interview process, technologies you’ll be asked to use and why those will be asked. The more context you have, the better you can prepare to ace it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the job, you may be asked to solve a hard problem and have minimal to no direction on how to reach the solution. Because people don’t know what data science does, you may have to support yourself with work in devops, software engineering, data engineering, etc. If you end up as the only “data person” on the team, you may want to start building out a cohort of external mentors before you arrive on the job who can advise you as you proceed into uncharted waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Data science leadership is sorely lacking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most executives in charge of data science decision-making are neither educated nor trained in actual data science theory and techniques. Instead, they have relied upon non-data-driven, plug-and-play features that can be launched in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few teams have a Head of Data, Data Science Manager or other relevant role. As a Data Scientist, you may report to someone specialized in just product, engineering or even another discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These non-data proficient executives and managers are usually the ones to make important product decisions. In tech, top-down decision-making is still very prevalent. You may not have a “seat at the table” or be respected enough to be included in these decisions and your research may not be valued. Where does that leave you as a Data Scientist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one experience, a fellow researcher spent over a month researching a particular value among our customers through qualitative and quantitative data. She presented a well-written and evidence-backed report. Yet, a few days later, a key head of product outlined a vision for the team and supported it with a claim that was antithetical to the researcher’s findings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if a data science project you advocate for is greenlighted, you may be on your own as the rare knowledgeable person to plan and execute it. It’s unlikely leadership will be hands-on to help you research and plan out the project. This could be a very difficult road ahead - especially for someone junior in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Data science can’t always be built to specs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You and peers may have expectations on the potential of data science projects. Two common types of projects are in exploratory analyses and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an exploratory analysis, someone or yourself may have questions on the data and you simply want to answer those. Common questions are: How many users click this button; what % of users that visit a screen click this button; how many users have signed up by region or account type? However, the data needed to answer those questions may not exist! If the data does exists, it’s likely “dirty” - undocumented, tough to find or could be factually inaccurate. It’ll be tough to work with! You could spend hours or days attempting to answer a single question only to discover that you can’t sufficiently answer it for a stakeholder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In machine learning, you may be asked to optimize some process or experience for consumers. However, there’s uncertainty with how much, if at all, the experience can be improved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Machine learning XKCD comic&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/7nPWUrS.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one engagement, the product had a newsfeed with posts from a large network of people - content often irrelevant for users. You may have noticed your Facebook or Twitter newsfeed content is ordered in a way to show posts most relevant to you near the top - optimized to consume the content and click through on what’s relevant. Similarly, the team I worked with was asked to optimize the feed. However, they didn’t know exactly how much the feed could be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team evaluated the optimization of the feed by an evaluation metric called uCTR - unique click through rate. This is essentially the probability the user would click on the post to like it or comment on it in a session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Executives had expectations that the experience would be drastically improved. The machine learning team did improve the metric by over 50% - but only for a small group of users who were very engaged because there was more signal in the data to improve that group’s experience. The majority of users still had a bad viewing experience even after the ML model was implemented!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;50% seems significant but may be rather insignificant too. It’s high on a relative change but still can be a small absolute change. Picture this: you have 10 dollars in cash and you increase it by 50% in a day. You now have 15 dollars in cash. Yet that’s still a small number on an absolute scale. You can only buy 1 or 2 meals out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since many ML projects may not be built to the expectations of teams, most projects likey &lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2019/07/19/why-do-87-of-data-science-projects-never-make-it-into-production/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;don’t make it into production&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. You’re likely the only “data person”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly every team in a business will want to know their progress through quantitative measures. All teams, whether sales, customer support, engineering, or marketing, want metrics and data-driven dashboards to measure their efficacy and progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most companies with &amp;lt;100 employees have few employees who are proficient in SQL, databases, data analysis and data visualizations. These are skills necessary to analyze data and produce these dashboard outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the resident Data Scientist, you may become easily inundated with requests from multiple teams at once. Be prepared to ask these teams to qualify and defend their requests, and be prepared to say “no” if their needs fall outside the scope of your actual priority queue. I’d recommend utilizing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intercom.com/blog/rice-simple-prioritization-for-product-managers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RICE prioritization technique&lt;/a&gt; for projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, you may quickly realize much of this work is repetitive and while time-consuming, is “easy”. In fact, most analyses involve a great deal of time to understand the data, clean it and organize it. You may spend a minimal amount of time doing the “fun” parts that data scientists think of: complex statistics, machine learning and experimentation with tangible results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Your impact is tough to measure — data doesn’t always translate to value&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two ways to interpret this section’s header come to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one, Data Scientists are often in “support” roles. Most organizations make the majority of their decisions on intuition that stems from past readings and personal experiences - not from a Data Scientist’s analyses. I’d be shocked if you could find a small to medium size organization that acted otherwise. Generally, you want to err on the side of being decisive rather than being overly cautious in order to succeed in business. (Though, this can backfire on you.) As a Data Scientist in the org, are you essential to the business? Probably not. The business could go on for a while and survive without you. Sales will still be made, features will still get built, customer support will handle customer concerns, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started, I thought I’d be incredibly valued as the gatekeeper for helping justify business decisions. However, that was rarely the case. DJ Patil, the former Chief Data Scientist at the White House, once stated in a podcast episode that you as a Data Scientist should try to find a situation to be incredibly valuable on the job! It’s tough to find that from the outskirts of applying to jobs, but internally, you can make inroads supporting stakeholders with evidence for their decisions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another challenge being usually a “support” role in a company is quantifying your impact. A common data science task is to help a Product Manager answer a question about some recent activity in the data. You can also issue a product recommendation based on your insights. So what? How do you measure whether this work of yours was impactful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s tough to do. Most people don’t put a price or value on analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you save the company 10 million dollars through your analysis for the sales team that led them to avoiding a huge and costly new workflow, or did the sales team save the 10 million dollars? Truthfully, will anyone even value the 10 million dollars if it was simply “saved” and never spent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the job, I’d recommend you document your work well and calculate the monetary value of your analyses based on factors like employee salary, capital investments, opportunity cost, etc. These analyses will come in handy for a promotion/review packet later too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize the actual analysis is challenging to do and I’ve only heard of one data science manager who executed on this well with his team! Seek help from others on how to best craft these analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;6. Data &amp;amp; infrastructure have serious quality problems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In data science books, online classes, online tutorials, and Kaggle competitions, the problems faced are radically different from what exists in industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In those online resources, you’ll have “clean” data that’s easily available, well-documented, and structured in an outline that allows you to apply data science techniques to answer the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to quality of data on the job, I’d often compare it to a garbage bag that ripped, had its content spewed all over the ground and your partner has asked you to find a beautiful earring that was accidentally inside. Essentially, the data will be tough to find and poorly documented — or not documented at all. Data can also be presented in unstructured formats such as complicated JSON, submitted text responses with punctuation, emojis, and minimal context. Moreover, data that seems helpful can prove to be a red herring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Futurama can't trust this data meme&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/zlBFq4G.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the famous saying, “garbage in, garbage out”. If you don’t have quality data, you likely won’t produce a quality output to meet your stakeholders’ expectation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleaning data may likely become the majority of your work. In 2016, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://visit.figure-eight.com/rs/416-ZBE-142/images/CrowdFlower_DataScienceReport_2016.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt; distributed to experienced Data Scientists by the popular ML-focused company Crowdflower claimed “3 out of every 5 data scientists we surveyed actually spend the most time cleaning and organizing data”. The Data Scientist, in many cases, should be called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_janitor&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Data Janitor&lt;/a&gt;. ¯_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note, if you spend most of your time on data cleaning, that’s very little time left for coding, studying ML, and conducting analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;9.375&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Have been extremely curious about this for a while now, so I decided to create a poll.&lt;br/&gt;&quot;As someone titled 'data scientist' in 2019, I spend most of (60%+) my time:&quot;&lt;br/&gt;(&quot;Other&quot;) also welcome, add it in the replies.&lt;/p&gt;
— Vicki Boykis (@vboykis) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vboykis/status/1089920316644704256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 28, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to “dirty data”, another major challenge is handling data with poor infrastructure. Imagine a busy highway with lots of potholes, toll booths, and traffic. Your job is to somehow navigate these treacherous conditions to supply data insights at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lots of data prep and little time for analysis image&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/6lbm6cr.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://insightextractor.com/2013/04/22/business-analytics-projects-are-like-an-iceberg/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Insight Extractor - Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be faced with a database that isn’t optimized for your queries or unable to identify the source of truth in the data through its data lineage. You may wait days or weeks to get access to a database or be stuck with poor infrastructure because people are afraid to change it for fear of breaking everything! There may be no centralized data store, multiple dashboard tools used making it difficult to find information, and no repository for past data science work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I worked at Target HQ in 2012, employees would arrive to work early - often around 7am - in order to query the database at a time when few others were doing so. They hoped they’d get database results quicker. Yet, they’d still often wait several hours just to get results. The traffic jam was real!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even my friends at big tech startups have complained about the same problems with data infrastructure and technical debt. One friend had to come to work on Saturdays just to be able to query the data without extreme wait times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine wanting to investigate a hunch in the data and having to wait hours for it! Then, imagine you made a mistake in the SQL query, had to re-implement it and wait hours again! That’s practically waiting a whole day without even getting the data!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the job, if you notice poor infrastructure, speak up to your manager early on. Clearly document the problem, and try to incorporate a data engineering, infrastructure, or devops team to help resolve the issue! I'd also encourage you to learn these skills too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7. Data work can be profoundly unethical. Moral courage required&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the scariest of concerns for me. I have seen and heard of shady practices of collecting and analyzing private user data, from their private messages to their every interaction on the app. As a Data Scientist, you likely won’t have ethics training or a say in product decisions made regarding them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber is infamous for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/mar/03/uber-secret-program-greyball-resignation-ed-baker&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;secret internal tool called Greyball&lt;/a&gt; built to evade law enforcement. The tool could help identify law enforcement officials in their respective cities and provide them a “fake” Uber experience to show riders but no one would pick them up. What if you were the Data Scientist tasked with predicting who’s a law enforcement official or modifying the core driver routing algorithm to evade these individuals? Would you do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommendations of an ML model can also be unethical. I once worked on an engagement in which ML predictions were provided to consumers. These predictions were created based on flawed practices in ML model training and there was very little signal in the data. Later, the paying customers complained about how poor the recommendations were, yet the company never publicly apologized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may come a time when an ecommerce company asks you as a Data Scientist: “If we wanted to figure out if a customer is pregnant, even if she didn’t want us to know, can you do that?” These were the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/19/magazine/shopping-habits.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;exact words&lt;/a&gt; spoken to one only a few years ago at Target! But what are the ethical implications of figuring this out? Would you as a consumer want you and your family to be marketed this way? What if the significant other doesn’t know if their partner is pregnant? What if they’re considering an abortion? At companies, especially smaller ones, these ethical concerns may not be taken into consideration!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion: Where Does This Leave Us?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to discourage people from applying to data science jobs. They can be incredibly impactful towards the company’s mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather, try to ask about these concerns in interview questions to help you evaluate your next role. If you’re on the job and already facing these issues, work with your manager or coworkers to try and resolve them asap to improve your job experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you have any questions or feedback on this post: dan [@] dfrieds.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional and somewhat similar articles to this are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.naveed.dev/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Naveed Nadjmabadi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dateworking.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Steve Dean&lt;/a&gt;, Andrew Ju, Julia Xu, &lt;a href=&quot;http://emilydegrandpre.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Em deGrandpré&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://canzhiye.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Canzhi Ye&lt;/a&gt; for their advice on drafts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 19:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danielfriedman</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>Sevem common ways a data science role may not meet your expectations through tens of data scientist interviews and anecdotes from popular median</og:description>
<og:title>Data Science: Reality Doesn't Meet Expectations</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://dfrieds.com/articles/data-science-reality-vs-expectations.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Faceshield</title>
<link>https://support.apple.com/faceshield</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://support.apple.com/faceshield</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;steps&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Remove thin protective films from the face shield and forehead band by peeling from either edge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either side of the face shield can act as the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://support.apple.com/library/content/dam/edam/applecare/images/en_US/faceshield/faceshield-kit-of-parts.png&quot; width=&quot;780&quot; alt=&quot;Forehead Band, Face Shield, and Silicone Strap&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;steps&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Align your preferred slots on the face shield and forehead band&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://support.apple.com/library/content/dam/edam/applecare/images/en_US/faceshield/face-shield-align-for-fit-animations.gif&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;Regular Fit and Extra Space&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;steps&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thread the strap through the slots and pull to adjust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://support.apple.com/library/content/dam/edam/applecare/images/en_US/faceshield/face-shield-threading-animation.gif&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Thread the strap through the slots&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;steps&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Repeat on other side&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;steps&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adjust your face shield&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://support.apple.com/library/content/dam/edam/applecare/images/en_US/faceshield/face-shield-adjust-to-tighten-loosen-animation.gif&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Adjust your face shield&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;steps&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wear the face shield in addition to other personal protective equipment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Clean and reuse your face shield&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using your face shield:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Avoid exposure to high heat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handle gently to prevent drops and scratches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can sterilize and reuse your face shield. It has been evaluated to be compatible with the following chemicals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;70% Ethanol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;70% Isopropyl Alcohol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6% Bleach*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3% Hydrogen Peroxide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;*May leave a residue on the face shield.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;Disclaimer: Please use with appropriate personal protective equipment per your institution’s standards. This device has not been tested or qualified to prevent or reduce infection, and does not provide particulate filtration. Not intended for use in surgical settings. These devices have not been disinfected or cleaned. Non-sterile.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 18:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT211028</og:url>
<og:title>Assemble and adjust your Face Shield</og:title>
<og:description>To assemble your face shield, follow these steps.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://support.apple.com/library/content/dam/edam/applecare/images/en_US/social/open_graph_logo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT211028</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Landlord service Naborly makes blacklist of tenants who missed 4/1 rent (YC &amp;#039;18)</title>
<link>https://www.qpbriefing.com/2020/04/06/unconscionable-landlord-service-naborly-draws-criticism-for-creating-blacklist-of-tenants-who-missed-april-1-rent/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.qpbriefing.com/2020/04/06/unconscionable-landlord-service-naborly-draws-criticism-for-creating-blacklist-of-tenants-who-missed-april-1-rent/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As the COVID-19 pandemic ravages bank accounts worldwide, one Ontario-based company is looking to create what one housing lawyer called a &quot;blacklist&quot; of renters who missed payments on April 1, raising concerns among privacy experts and tenant advocates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naborly is a service that uses artificial intelligence to screen prospective tenants — including a credit check, criminal background check, social media scan and more — and assigns them &lt;a href=&quot;https://naborly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Naborly-Sample-Report-2019.pdf?__s=cigzi6p9i66ghy0zbd5g&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;scores&lt;/a&gt; based on how likely it believes them to meet risk factors like causing property damage or requiring eviction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company also lets landlords submit &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.naborly.com/hc/en-us/articles/360039132532-How-do-I-report-a-tenant-?&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;reviews of tenants&lt;/a&gt; they've rented to, including the tenant's full name, address, a star rating out of five and what kind of conflict the landlord may have had with the tenant. It is encouraging its users to use that service to help create a &quot;database&quot; of tenants who missed rent on April 1, to be made &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.naborly.com/hc/en-us/articles/360039132532-How-do-I-report-a-tenant-?&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt; for all our landlord users in the future.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The more data we have on what happens over the next few days is going to really accelerate our ability to retrain our AI systems and then help all of you accurately understand tenant risk moving forward into this new world,&quot; Naborly CEO &lt;strong&gt;Dylan Lenz&lt;/strong&gt; said in a YouTube &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YrK8mKRsvN4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; on April 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This database helps other landlords know in the future if a tenant has been delinquent in the past, while also helping Naborly continue to deliver the most accurate and up-to-date tenant screening service in the market,&quot; reads one email sent from the company to landlords on April 2. &quot;Please note that we keep reporting fully confidential and DO NOT notify your tenant that you have reported to our system.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former Ontario Information and Privacy Commissioner (IPC) &lt;strong&gt;Ann Cavoukian&lt;/strong&gt; called the practice &quot;unconscionable.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If I were still the commissioner, I would be all over this,&quot; said Cavoukian, who has raised &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ctvnews.ca/sci-tech/get-ready-to-give-up-your-online-privacy-to-score-the-perfect-rental-1.3192709&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;concerns&lt;/a&gt; in the past about Naborly's extensive screening process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I'm just very concerned that during these very troublesome times, that people's failure to pay rent is going to be communicated widely. I think that's just outrageous,&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cavoukian, who now leads Ryerson University's Privacy by Design Centre of Excellence, said Naborly may be in violation of the province's &lt;em&gt;Health and Information Protection Act&lt;/em&gt; since future landlords may draw inferences that a tenant was sick with COVID-19 and thus unable to pay their rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ontario Privacy Commissioner &lt;strong&gt;Brian Beamish &lt;/strong&gt;said in a statement that that was unlikely, as any such inference &quot;would be highly speculative.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Housing lawyer &lt;strong&gt;Benjamin Ries&lt;/strong&gt;, with the University of Toronto's Downtown Legal Services, said his organization has sent a letter to Naborly seeking clarification of the company's intentions, because it seems like it's building an illegal &quot;blacklist.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ries said Naborly seems to be acting as a consumer reporting agency, of which there are currently two licensed in Ontario: Equifax and TransUnion. The industry is tightly regulated due to the personal information involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Ontario's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ontario.ca/laws/statute/90c33&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Consumer Reporting Act&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, consumer reports include &quot;credit information or personal information&quot; that is used to make decisions about, in part, &quot;entering into or renewal of a tenancy agreement.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;So if the whole purpose of the five-star review is for future landlords to look up a prospective tenant and include that in their decision as to whether or not they should rent to that tenant, then it sure seems like&quot; Naborly is producing credit reports, Ries said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also noted that Canada's &lt;em&gt;Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act&lt;/em&gt; (PIPEDA) contains strict rules about personal information that can be collected by businesses — including the requirement to allow people to see what information has been collected about them, and provide the opportunity for them to challenge it if they feel it's incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Naborly &quot;seems to offer something like the opposite, right? It seems to say, 'Don't worry landlord, we won't tell your tenant that you've reported this personal information about them.' I mean, that's squarely opposite from what I understand to be the basic privacy regime that all businesses in Canada are subject to,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It seems like this is a blacklist that Naborly is hoping that landlords will help create by just informing on every single tenant, whether they've paid or not,&quot; he added. &quot;It does not seem legal.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Ries isn't satisfied with Naborly's explanation, or if they don't respond to his letter, he said he will escalate the matter to the federal privacy commissioner and Consumer Protection Ontario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process has also raised concerns from the Canadian Civil Liberties Association (CCLA), which noted that property managers in Canada are not allowed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/opc-actions-and-decisions/investigations/investigations-into-businesses/2016/pipeda-2016-002/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;publish &quot;bad tenants&quot; lists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I fear that Naborly is trying to split hairs and exploit loopholes in order to do obtusely what they cannot do directly under privacy laws,&quot; CCLA Executive Director &lt;strong&gt;Michael Bryant&lt;/strong&gt; said, noting that while the company claims it's not a property manager, &quot;my view is that it does conduct many of its functions.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ries said the idea to create &quot;bad tenant&quot; lists is a common one in Ontario, but &quot;I've never seen anything quite so brazen and out in the open as this business appears to be.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bryant also brought up the issue of consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Are the tenants consenting to giving up all their privacy rights informed or are they being tricked? Does Naborly truly have tenants’ consent to defame them?&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bryant called for an investigation of Naborly, which operates in Canada and the U.S., by the federal privacy commissioner. The CCLA will be involved somehow, he said, though they're currently &quot;at capacity&quot; dealing with governmental responses to COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for the federal commissioner said the office isn't in a position to comment on this specific case, but also pointed to the OPC's 2016 &quot;bad tenant list&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/opc-actions-and-decisions/investigations/investigations-into-businesses/2016/pipeda-2016-002/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;case&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landlords can sometimes collect personal information to verify someone's ability to pay rent, &lt;strong&gt;Vito Pilieci &lt;/strong&gt;said. But the tenants in that case had not given &quot;meaningful consent&quot; to that information being collected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, allowing landlords access to tenants' past paying habits meant the company in question was &quot;acting as a credit reporting agency, without a requisite licence,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geordie Dent&lt;/strong&gt;, the head of the Federation of Metro Tenants' Associations, said the practice is a &quot;disaster&quot; for tenants, who may be discriminated against by future landlords for missing one month's payment due to a global crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Would you, or any of your readers, want their personal information like that in a database that somebody else could check?&quot; he said, calling it &quot;scary.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Naborly gained some &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/terralynnpobuda/status/1246143376757579777&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;negative attention&lt;/a&gt; online, Lenz sent out another email apologizing for the way the request came across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Upon reflection, I recognize that the email was poorly worded and did not provide sufficient context. I am deeply sorry if it suggested that Naborly or myself were trying to do anything other than help,&quot; he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naborly did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The province has ordered a temporary &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qpbriefing.com/2020/03/17/covid-19-watch-opposition-support-evictions-paused-malls-open/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;halt on evictions&lt;/a&gt; during the pandemic. Premier &lt;strong&gt;Doug Ford &lt;/strong&gt;has said if renters have to make a choice between paying for rent and putting food on the table, they should choose food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ontario's Ministry of Housing did not comment on the collection of personal information, but called on landlords &quot;to be as flexible as possible when it comes to collecting rent, starting with April, at a time when many people are struggling.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spokesperson &lt;strong&gt;Conrad Spezowka&lt;/strong&gt; noted that tenants who have been locked out of their units or are facing threat of illegal eviction can contact the ministry's Rental Housing Enforcement Unit at 1-888-772-9277 or mho.rheu.info@ontario.ca.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 17:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Apocryphon</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.qpbriefing.com/2020/04/06/unconscionable-landlord-service-naborly-draws-criticism-for-creating-blacklist-of-tenants-who-missed-april-1-rent/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://placehold.it/745x450&amp;text=NO IMAGE</og:image>
<og:title>'Unconscionable': Landlord service Naborly draws criticism for creating 'blacklist' of tenants who missed April 1 rent - QP Briefing</og:title>
<og:description>&quot;If I were still the commissioner, I would be all over this,&quot; said former Ontario Privacy Commissioner Ann Cavoukian.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.qpbriefing.com/2020/04/06/unconscionable-landlord-service-naborly-draws-criticism-for-creating-blacklist-of-tenants-who-missed-april-1-rent/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We abused Slack&amp;#039;s TURN servers to gain access to internal services</title>
<link>https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;Publish date:&lt;/strong&gt; Apr 6, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;nav class=&quot;toc&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;toc-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;toc-heading&quot;&gt;Table of contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/#executive-summary-tldr&quot;&gt;Executive summary (TLDR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/#a-very-brief-introduction-to-the-turn-protocol&quot;&gt;A very brief introduction to the TURN protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/#introduction-to-turn-in-the-webrtc-infrastructure-context&quot;&gt;Introduction to TURN in the WebRTC infrastructure context&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/#how-slack-uses-turn&quot;&gt;How Slack uses TURN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/#what-we-found-when-testing-slacks-turn-servers&quot;&gt;What we found when testing Slack’s TURN servers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/#our-methodology-for-testing-for-open-turn-relay-abuse&quot;&gt;Our methodology for testing for open TURN relay abuse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/#how-to-fix-an-open-turn-relay-to-address-this-vulnerability&quot;&gt;How to fix an open TURN relay to address this vulnerability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/#our-timeline&quot;&gt;Our timeline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/#thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/#faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;executive-summary-tldr&quot;&gt;Executive summary (TLDR)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack’s TURN server allowed relaying of TCP connections and UDP packets to internal Slack network and meta-data services on AWS. And we were awarded $3,500 for &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackerone.com/reports/333419&quot;&gt;our bug-bounty report on HackerOne&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-very-brief-introduction-to-the-turn-protocol&quot;&gt;A very brief introduction to the TURN protocol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Traversal_Using_Relays_around_NAT&quot;&gt;Wikipedia page&lt;/a&gt; for this protocol is somewhat handy because it explains that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traversal Using Relays around NAT (TURN) is a protocol that assists in traversal of network address translators (NAT) or firewalls for multimedia applications. It may be used with the Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) and User Datagram Protocol (UDP). It is most useful for clients on networks masqueraded by symmetric NAT devices. TURN does not aid in running servers on well known ports in the private network through a NAT; it supports the connection of a user behind a NAT to only a single peer, as in telephony, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;4.8923076923077&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TURN is specified by &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5766&quot;&gt;RFC 5766&lt;/a&gt;. An update to TURN for IPv6 is specified in &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6156&quot;&gt;RFC 6156&lt;/a&gt;. The TURN URI scheme is documented in &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7065&quot;&gt;RFC 7065&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be also useful to note that TURN is actually an extension to the STUN (Session Traversal Utilities for NAT) protocol rather than a network protocol that stands on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TURN servers can get peers behind NAT connected by acting as a relay, as it is called in the RFCs, or a proxy from the perspective of a pentester. In the case of TCP relaying, TURN servers make use of a connect message &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6062#section-4.3&quot;&gt;method 0x000A in RFC 6062&lt;/a&gt; while with UDP, a send indication message &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5766#section-10&quot;&gt;method 0x006 in RFC 5766&lt;/a&gt; is used. For UDP, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5766#section-11&quot;&gt;the channel method&lt;/a&gt; can also be used and has a similar function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, one might ask, how is this related to WebRTC?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction-to-turn-in-the-webrtc-infrastructure-context&quot;&gt;Introduction to TURN in the WebRTC infrastructure context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With WebRTC, as well as VoIP in general, one of the more painful complications has been getting the media stream (i.e. RTP packets carrying audio and video) of two or more parties to reach each other. This tends to be a problem because of NAT, which is widely known to have inflicted a great deal of pain on human nature (at least that subculture which develops real-time communications software). The problem has to do with finding the IP and port tuple of each media stream which, when either or both hosts are behind NAT, tends to be less obvious. In many cases, this has been solved with STUN and when that fails, the TURN extension which tends to be the last resort before failing to get the media stream working. Here we should mention that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactive_Connectivity_Establishment&quot;&gt;ICE&lt;/a&gt; protocol (Interactive Connectivity Establishment) is what ties in STUN and TURN. In fact, TURN has been designed to work with ICE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, for many WebRTC systems, one key element is to have a TURN server to relay messages between peers when direct media traffic between peers is not allowed by a firewall or NAT device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-slack-uses-turn&quot;&gt;How Slack uses TURN&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we tested Slack, we noticed that TURN was always used for establishing the media which is passed over SRTP. This has been described extensively by the webrtcHacks blog in an article called &lt;a href=&quot;https://webrtchacks.com/slack-webrtc-slacking/&quot;&gt;Is Slack’s WebRTC Really Slacking? (Yoshimasa Iwase)&lt;/a&gt; way back in 2016, and so we will not repeat the same explanation over here. But one thing that we should highlight is that the way that Slack uses its TURN server puts it in a critical position within its infrastructure, rather than it being a measure of last resort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-found-when-testing-slacks-turn-servers&quot;&gt;What we found when testing Slack’s TURN servers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our tests showed that Slack’s TURN servers can be abused to relay TCP and UDP traffic to the TURN server itself and also internal addresses on Slack’s AWS infrastructure. For the webapp-sort of penetration testers out there, this sounds familiar because that is how SSRF (server-side request forgery) vulnerabilities are usually abused. However, there is an important difference in that abuse of this vulnerability is not limited to just HTTP-based protocols (or targets that somehow respond to HTTP requests). Instead, we see it as closer to abusing an open proxy (e.g. a socks proxy or a web proxy with the &lt;code&gt;CONNECT&lt;/code&gt; method).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What could one do by abusing Slack’s TURN servers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Connect to the AWS meta-data services at &lt;code&gt;http://169.254.169.254&lt;/code&gt; and obtain IAM temporary credentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect to open ports on &lt;em&gt;localhost&lt;/em&gt; that are usually not exposed to the Internet (e.g. node exporter): 22, 25, 53, 443, 515, 5666, 8500, 8888, 9090 and 9100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port-scan the Slack AWS infrastructure on &lt;code&gt;10.41.0.0/16&lt;/code&gt; and find server management applications; possibly abuse such “trusted” services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-meta-data-credentials.png&quot; alt=&quot;Obtaining IAM temporary credentials from AWS meta-data service&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-methodology-for-testing-for-open-turn-relay-abuse&quot;&gt;Our methodology for testing for open TURN relay abuse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, one might get the wrong impression that TURN servers do not have any authentication or authorization but the truth is that they do make use of authentication. In fact, each time there is a WebRTC session, new temporary TURN credentials are generated and returned by the system. An attacker must therefore retrieve these credentials. We used the following steps to do so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;configure our web browser to use Burp proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the &lt;em&gt;Proxy &amp;gt; HTTP history&lt;/em&gt; tab, filter for the keyword &lt;em&gt;screenhero&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start a call by pressing the call button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;observe the TURN details returned in the call to &lt;code&gt;/api/screenhero.rooms.create&lt;/code&gt; which include the temporary username and password, TURN hostname and ports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;these details are then passed to our tool stunner that was written to abuse this vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-turn-credentials.png&quot; alt=&quot;How we generated TURN credentials&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stunner is an internal tool that we developed to test STUN, and by extension, TURN for various protocol vulnerabilities. The first subcommand of interest here is &lt;code&gt;turn peer scanner&lt;/code&gt;, which runs a port scan through a TURN relay targeting a particular peer address. In the video demonstration we show the &lt;code&gt;turn peer httpproxy&lt;/code&gt; subcommand that implemented an HTTP proxy so that web browsers could be configured to pass through stunner, which then proxies HTTP requests and responses to the TURN server speaking its protocol. Finally, the TURN server relays this HTTP traffic back and forth to stunner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the rest, as they say, is a historic video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Oc8aprXLKLU&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;YouTube Video&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video shows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;How to obtain the TURN credentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing relaying to the Internet through the TURN server by checking our IP address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connecting to internal network and meta-data services on Slacks AWS infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-fix-an-open-turn-relay-to-address-this-vulnerability&quot;&gt;How to fix an open TURN relay to address this vulnerability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this issue, we recommend placing access control rules on the TURN server itself to block non-public addresses from being specified as the &lt;code&gt;XOR-PEER-ADDRESS&lt;/code&gt; in the TURN messages. In practical terms, most systems, including Slack’s, make use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coturn/coturn&quot;&gt;Coturn&lt;/a&gt;. Our recommendation is to make use of the following options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;no-multicast-peers
denied-peer-ip=0.0.0.0-0.255.255.255
denied-peer-ip=10.0.0.0-10.255.255.255
denied-peer-ip=100.64.0.0-100.127.255.255
denied-peer-ip=127.0.0.0-127.255.255.255
denied-peer-ip=169.254.0.0-169.254.255.255
denied-peer-ip=127.0.0.0-127.255.255.255
denied-peer-ip=172.16.0.0-172.31.255.255
denied-peer-ip=192.0.0.0-192.0.0.255
denied-peer-ip=192.0.2.0-192.0.2.255
denied-peer-ip=192.88.99.0-192.88.99.255
denied-peer-ip=192.168.0.0-192.168.255.255
denied-peer-ip=198.18.0.0-198.19.255.255
denied-peer-ip=198.51.100.0-198.51.100.255
denied-peer-ip=203.0.113.0-203.0.113.255
denied-peer-ip=240.0.0.0-255.255.255.255
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our recommendation here is to make use of the latest coturn which by default, no longer allows peering with &lt;code&gt;127.0.0.1&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;::1&lt;/code&gt;. In some older versions, you might also want to use the &lt;code&gt;no-loopback-peers&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside aria-label=&quot;warning&quot; class=&quot;note warning&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even when attackers can no longer abuse TURN servers to relay to internal addresses, in some cases, one might be concerned about TURN servers being used for anything other than their intended use. We can imagine attacks abusing TURN servers in the same way that they abuse open socks and HTTP proxies. But of course, this is a feature and not a bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-timeline&quot;&gt;Our timeline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;November 2017: added TURN abuse to our stunner toolset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 2017: discovered and reported TURN vulnerability in private customer of Enable Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;February 2018: briefly tested Slack and discovered the vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;April 2018: submitted our report to Slack, helped them reproduce and address the issue through various rounds of testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 2018: Slack pushed patch to live servers which was retested by Enable Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January 2020: asked to publish report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;February 2020: disclosure delayed by HackerOne/Slack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;March 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackerone.com/reports/333419&quot;&gt;report published&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to extend our gratitude to the Slack security team who handled our report and provided us with test systems to check their security fixes. And many thanks to Alfred Farrugia for his work on stunner and reproducing this vulnerability reliably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-first-discovered-the-turn-open-relay-abuse-vulnerability&quot;&gt;Who first discovered the TURN open relay abuse vulnerability?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From public records, it looks like that would be Cisco, who released an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/docs/csa/cisco-sa-20170913-cmsturn.html&quot;&gt;advisory&lt;/a&gt; for Cisco Meeting Server back in 2017 September 13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We properly identified this issue separately, apparently in late 2016, by reading the TURN RFC and eventually proving the actual vulnerability by adding features within our internal toolset, stunner, to abuse this vulnerability. Since then, we have discovered various instances of the same vulnerability during our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enablesecurity.com/security-assessment/webrtc-pentest/&quot;&gt;WebRTC Penetration Test&lt;/a&gt; engagements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-stunner-available&quot;&gt;Is stunner available?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use this during &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enablesecurity.com/#penetration-testing&quot;&gt;our penetration test services&lt;/a&gt; but unfortunately at this stage we cannot make it available outside of Enable Security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer role=&quot;contentinfo&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;themer&quot;&gt;dark theme: &lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;themer&quot; class=&quot;vh&quot;/&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Copyright 2020, Enable Security GmbH | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enablesecurity.com/about/#impressum&quot;&gt;Impressum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 15:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>reader_1000</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.rtcsec.com/2020/04/01-slack-webrtc-turn-compromise/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox 75: Ambitions for April</title>
<link>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/04/firefox-75-ambitions-for-april/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/04/firefox-75-ambitions-for-april/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Even in these times of isolation, our engineering teams have adapted, kept focused, and worked hard to bring you another exciting new edition of Firefox. On the developer tools side, you’ll find instant evaluation in the console, event breakpoints for WebSockets, and many other things besides. On the web platform side, new additions include HTML lazy loading for images, the CSS &lt;code&gt;min()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;max()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;clamp()&lt;/code&gt; functions, public static class fields, and additions to Web Animations API support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As always, read on for the highlights, or find the full list of additions in the following articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Developer tools additions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by reviewing the most interesting Developer Tools additions for 75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Instant evaluation for console expressions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2020/04/web-console.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-45997&quot; src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2020/04/web-console.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot shows the web console with instant evaluation of console expressions&quot; width=&quot;1302&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/04/web-console.png 1302w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/04/web-console-250x106.png 250w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/04/web-console-500x211.png 500w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/04/web-console-768x324.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1302px) 100vw, 1302px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evaluating expressions in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Tools/Web_Console&quot;&gt;Console&lt;/a&gt; is a rapid way to explore your application state, query the DOM, or just try out JavaScript APIs. It’s now easier to prototype longer code with &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Tools/Web_Console/The_command_line_interpreter#Multi-line_mode&quot;&gt;Firefox’s multi-line Console mode&lt;/a&gt;, which becomes ever friendlier and more IDE-like to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;em&gt;Instant evaluation&lt;/em&gt; previews the results of the current expression as you type, similar to editors like &lt;a href=&quot;https://quokkajs.com/&quot;&gt;Quokka.js&lt;/a&gt;. As long as expressions typed into the Web Console are side-effect free, their results will be previewed while you type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of polish went into making the preview as seamless as possible. Elements for DOM nodes in results are highlighted. The in-code autocomplete recommends methods and properties based on the result type. Also, you can preview errors to help you fix expressions faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Better inspection &amp;amp; measuring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Area measuring is now resizable&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2020/04/area-measurement.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-45992&quot; src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2020/04/area-measurement.png&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot showing the area measurement  tool in DevTools, that lets you quickly draw rectangles over your page to measure the height, width, and diagonal length of specific areas.&quot; width=&quot;1248&quot; height=&quot;702&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/04/area-measurement.png 1248w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/04/area-measurement-250x141.png 250w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/04/area-measurement-500x281.png 500w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/04/area-measurement-220x125.png 220w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/04/area-measurement-768x432.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1248px) 100vw, 1248px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the optional &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Tools/Measure_a_portion_of_the_page&quot;&gt;area measurement tool&lt;/a&gt; in DevTools you can quickly draw rectangles over your page to measure the height, width, and diagonal length of specific areas. You can enable the tool in the settings, under “Available Toolbox Buttons”. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SebastianZ&quot;&gt;Sebastian Zartner [:sebo]&lt;/a&gt;, these rectangles now have resize-handles, so you can adjust them precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Use XPath to find DOM elements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/XPath&quot;&gt;XPath queries&lt;/a&gt; are commonly used in automation tools to tell software which elements to look for and interact with. Thanks again to sebo, you can now use XPath in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Tools/Page_Inspector/How_to/Examine_and_edit_HTML#XPath_search&quot;&gt;Inspector’s HTML search&lt;/a&gt; for DOM elements. This makes it easier to test expressions and fine-tune queries on real sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Event breakpoints for WebSockets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2019/10/firefoxs-new-websocket-inspector/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;WebSocket inspection&lt;/a&gt; features have improved in every recent DevTools release. This time there’s a nice addition to debugging, thanks to a contribution from the talented &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/user_profile?user_id=632471&quot;&gt;Chujun Lu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You now have the option to either pause or log when WebSocket event handlers are executed. Use the newly-added &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Tools/Debugger/Set_event_listener_breakpoints&quot;&gt;Event Listener Breakpoints&lt;/a&gt; in the Debugger. When you select the Log option, event data and the handler that’s been executed will be logged, but execution will not pause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other WebSocket Inspector news, the message filter now supports regular expressions, thanks to long-time contributor &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/user_profile?user_id=603026&quot;&gt;Outvi V&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Network additions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of quality and performance work went into the Network panel for Firefox 75. This release marks major improvements for how fast simultaneous quick-firing requests are rendered without taxing your CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the interface side, contributor &lt;a href=&quot;https://fvsch.com/&quot;&gt;Florens Verschelde&lt;/a&gt; drove the proposal and design for adding borders between columns to aid readability. Note how the design is more consistent with the overall look of the DevTools. Filter buttons are also more legible, with improved contrast between states, thanks to contributor &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/user_profile?user_id=657068&quot;&gt;Vitalii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Request Blocking panel helps you test how resilient your site is when matched requests fail. It now allows wildcard patterns with “*”. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/user_profile?user_id=472694&quot;&gt;Duncan Dean&lt;/a&gt; for that contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Early-access DevTools features in Developer Edition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/developer/&quot;&gt;Developer Edition&lt;/a&gt; is Firefox’s pre-release channel. It provides early access to tooling and platform features. Its settings also enable more functionality for developers by default. We like to bring new features quickly to Developer Edition to gather your feedback, including the following highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Async Stack Traces for Debugger &amp;amp; Console&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern JavaScript code depends heavily upon stacking &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Statements/async_function&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;async/await&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on top of other &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Learn/JavaScript/Asynchronous&quot;&gt;async operations&lt;/a&gt; like events, promises, and timeouts. Thanks to better integration with the JavaScript engine, async execution is now captured to provide a more complete picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Async call stacks in the Debugger let you step through events, timeouts, and promise-based function calls that are executed over time. In the Console, async stacks make it easier to find the root causes of errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Web platform updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore what Firefox 75 provides in terms of web platform updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;HTML lazy loading for images&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/Performance/Lazy_loading&quot;&gt;Lazy loading&lt;/a&gt; is a common strategy to improve performance by identifying resources as non-blocking (non-critical) and loading them only when needed, rather than loading them all immediately. Images are one of the most common assets to be lazy-loaded in web apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make lazy loading images easier, we have introduced support for the load attribute on the HTML &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/HTML/Element/img&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; element. Setting the value to &lt;em&gt;lazy&lt;/em&gt; will instruct the browser to defer loading of images that are off-screen until the user scrolls near them. The only other possible value is &lt;em&gt;eager&lt;/em&gt;, which is the default value as you’d expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;image.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;...&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can determine if a given image has finished loading by examining the value of its boolean &lt;code&gt;complete&lt;/code&gt; property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: The &lt;code&gt;load&lt;/code&gt; event fires when the eagerly-loaded content has all been loaded. At that time, it’s possible (or even likely) that there may be lazily-loaded images within the visual viewport that have yet to load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Chrome has also implemented experimental support for lazy loading of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/HTML/Element/iframe&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; content, but this is not in a standard yet; we are waiting until it has been standardized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CSS &lt;code&gt;min()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;max()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;clamp()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some exciting new CSS additions this month! We have added support for three very useful CSS functions which are closely-related to each other but have different purposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/CSS/min&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;min()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — accepts one or more possible values or calculations to choose from, and ensures that the value used in all situations will be the smallest of the possibilities. In effect, this provides a range of values for responsive designs, along with a maximum allowed value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/CSS/max&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;max()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — accepts one or more possible values or calculations to choose from, and ensures that the value used in all situations will be the largest of the possibilities. In effect, this provides a range of values for responsive designs, along with a minimum allowed value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/CSS/clamp&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;clamp()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — accepts three values or calculations: a minimum, preferred, and a maximum. The minimum or maximum will be used if the computed value falls below the minimum or above the maximum. The preferred value will be used if the computed value falls between the two. This allows the property value to adapt to changes in the element or page it is assigned to, while remaining between the minimum and maximum values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These functions are very useful for responsive design, and can save a lot of time and code doing things that you might previously have done using a combination of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/CSS/min-width&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;min-width&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/CSS/width&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;width&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/CSS/max-width&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;max-width&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, multiple &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/CSS/Media_Queries&quot;&gt;media queries&lt;/a&gt;, or even &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/javascript&quot;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;CSS &lt;code&gt;min()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;max()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;clamp()&lt;/code&gt; in action&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s study the following example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;html {
  font-family: sans-serif;
}

body {
  margin: 0 auto;
  width: min(1000px, calc(70% + 100px));
}

h1 {
  letter-spacing: 2px;
  font-size: clamp(1.8rem, 2.5vw, 2.8rem)
}

p {
  line-height: 1.5;
  font-size: max(1.2rem, 1.2vw);
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we’ve got the body width set to &lt;code&gt;min(1000px, calc(70% + 100px))&lt;/code&gt;, which means that in wider viewports the body content will be &lt;code&gt;1000px&lt;/code&gt; wide. In narrower viewports the body content will be &lt;code&gt;70%&lt;/code&gt; of the viewport width plus &lt;code&gt;100px&lt;/code&gt; (up until this calculation’s result becomes &lt;code&gt;1000px&lt;/code&gt; or more)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top level heading’s font-size is set to &lt;code&gt;clamp(1.8rem, 2.5vw, 2.8rem)&lt;/code&gt;. This means it will be a minimum of &lt;code&gt;1.8rem&lt;/code&gt;, and a maximum of &lt;code&gt;2.8rem&lt;/code&gt;. In between those values, the ideal value of &lt;code&gt;2.5vw&lt;/code&gt; will kick in, so you will see the header text grow and shrink at viewport widths where &lt;code&gt;2.5vw&lt;/code&gt; is computed as larger than &lt;code&gt;1.8rem&lt;/code&gt; but smaller than &lt;code&gt;2.8rem&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paragraph font-size is set to &lt;code&gt;max(1.2rem, 1.2vw)&lt;/code&gt;, meaning that it will be a minimum of &lt;code&gt;1.2rem&lt;/code&gt;, but will start to grow at the point that &lt;code&gt;1.2vw&lt;/code&gt;’s computed value is larger than &lt;code&gt;1.2rem&lt;/code&gt;s’ computed value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see this in action in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://mdn.github.io/css-examples/min-max-clamp/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;min()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;max()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;clamp()&lt;/code&gt; simple example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;JavaScript language features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been a few interesting JavaScript additions in 75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, we’ve now got &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Classes/Class_fields#Public_static_fields&quot;&gt;public static class fields&lt;/a&gt;. These are useful when you want a field to exist only once per class, not on every class instance you create. This is particularly relevant for cache, fixed-configuration, or any other data you don’t need to be replicated across instances. The basic syntax looks like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code lang=&quot;js&quot;&gt;class ClassWithStaticField {
  static staticField = 'static field'
}

console.log(ClassWithStaticField.staticField)
// expected output: &quot;static field&quot;​&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up, we’ve got another boost to i18n functionality with the addition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Locale&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Intl.Locale&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a standard built-in constructor that represents a Unicode locale identifier. For example, you could create a Korean locale object like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code lang=&quot;js&quot;&gt;const korean = new Intl.Locale('ko', {
  script: 'Kore', region: 'KR', hourCycle: 'h24', calendar: 'gregory'
});&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then return properties of the object as you’d expect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code lang=&quot;js&quot;&gt;console.log(korean.hourCycle, japanese.hourCycle);
// expected output: &quot;h24&quot; &quot;h12&quot;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Form additions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a couple of useful form-specific API additions in Firefox 75:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/HTMLFormElement&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTMLFormElement&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; interface has a new method, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/HTMLFormElement/requestSubmit&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;requestSubmit()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike the old (and still available) &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/HTMLFormElement/submit&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;submit()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; method, &lt;code&gt;requestSubmit()&lt;/code&gt; acts as if a specified submit button has been clicked, rather than just sending the form data to the recipient. Thus the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/HTMLFormElement/submit_event&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;submit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; event is delivered and the form is checked for validity prior to the data being submitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/HTMLFormElement/submit_event&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;submit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; event is now represented by an object of type &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/SubmitEvent&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;SubmitEvent&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; rather than a simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/Event&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Event&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;code&gt;SubmitEvent&lt;/code&gt; includes a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/SubmitEvent/submitter&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;submitter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; property, which returns the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/Element&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Element&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that was invoked to trigger the form submission. With this event, you can have a single handler for submit events that can discern which of multiple submit buttons or links was used to submit the form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Web Animations API enhancements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 75, a number of new Web Animations API features have been added, making this spec even more interesting and useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Implicit to/from keyframes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From now on, you are able to set a beginning or end state for an animation only (i.e. a single keyframe), and the browser will infer the other end of the animation if it is able to. For example, consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://mdn.github.io/dom-examples/web-animations-api/implicit-keyframes.html&quot;&gt;this simple animation&lt;/a&gt; — the keyframe object looks like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code lang=&quot;js&quot;&gt;let rotate360 = [
  { transform: 'rotate(360deg)' }
];&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have only specified the end state of the animation, and the beginning state is implied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Automatically removing filling animations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to trigger a large number of animations on the same element. If they are indefinite (i.e. forwards-filling), this can result in a huge animations list, which could create a memory leak. For this reason, we’ve implemented the part of the Web Animations spec that automatically removes overriding forward filling animations unless the developer explicitly specifies to keep them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see this in action in our simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://mdn.github.io/dom-examples/web-animations-api/replace-indefinite-animations.html&quot;&gt;replace indefinite animations demo&lt;/a&gt;. The related JavaScript features are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;animation.commitStyles()&lt;/code&gt; — to commit the end styling state of an animation to the element being animated, even after that animation has been removed, run this method. It will cause the end styling state to be written to the element being animated, in the form of properties inside a style attribute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;animation.onremove&lt;/code&gt; — allows you to run an event handler that fires when the animation is removed (i.e. put into an active replace state).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;animation.persist()&lt;/code&gt; — when you explicitly want animations to be retained, then invoke &lt;code&gt;persist()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;animation.replaceState&lt;/code&gt; — returns the replace state of the animation. This will be &lt;code&gt;active&lt;/code&gt; if the animation has been removed, or &lt;code&gt;persisted&lt;/code&gt; if &lt;code&gt;persist()&lt;/code&gt; has been invoked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Timelines&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/Animation/timeline&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Animation.timeline&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; getter, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/Document/timeline&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Document.timeline&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/DocumentTimeline&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;DocumentTimeline&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/AnimationTimeline&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;AnimationTimeline&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; features are now enabled by default, meaning that you can now access your animation’s timeline information, which is invaluable for returning time values for synchronization purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, the animation’s timeline and the document’s timeline are the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Getting active animations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, The &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/Document/getAnimations&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Document.getAnimations()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/Element/getAnimations&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Element.getAnimations()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; methods are now enabled by default, which respectively allow you to return an array of all the active animations on an entire document, or on a specific element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ARIA annotations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox 75 (on Linux and Windows) sees the addition of support for a set of new accessibility features collectively known as ARIA annotations, which are set to be published in the upcoming WAI-ARIA version 1.3 specification. These features make it possible to create accessible annotations within web documents. Typical use cases include edit suggestions (i.e. an addition and/or deletion in an editable document), and comments (e.g. an editorial comment related to a part of a document under review).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no screenreader support available for ARIA Annoations yet, but soon we’ll be able to make use of these new roles and other attributes. For examples and more support details, read &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/Accessibility/ARIA/Annotations&quot;&gt;ARIA Annotations&lt;/a&gt; on MDN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Browser extensions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two new &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions/API/browserSettings&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;browserSettings&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have been added to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions&quot;&gt;WebExtensions API&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions/API/browserSettings/zoomFullPage&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;zoomFullPage&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to zoom the text on a page and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions/API/browserSettings/zoomSiteSpecific&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;zoomSiteSpecific&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which determines if zoom applies to only the active tab or all tabs of the same site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you have it. Firefox 75 is packed with interesting new features; check them out, and have fun playing! As always, feel free to give feedback and ask questions in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;about&quot; readability=&quot;14.944680851064&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Mills is a senior tech writer at Mozilla, where he writes docs and demos about open web apps, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, A11y, WebAssembly, and more. He loves tinkering around with web technologies, and gives occasional tech talks at conferences and universities. He used to work for Opera and W3C, and enjoys playing heavy metal drums and drinking good beer. He lives near Manchester, UK, with his good lady and three beautiful children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;url&quot; href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/author/cmillsmozilla-com/&quot;&gt;More articles by Chris Mills…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 15:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>skellertor</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/04/firefox-75-ambitions-for-april</og:url>
<og:title>Firefox 75: Ambitions for April – Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog</og:title>
<og:description>Firefox 75 is chock full of handy new dev tooling: instant evaluation in the web console, event breakpoints for WebSockets, and more. New web platform features include HTML lazy loading ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/04/area-measurement.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/04/firefox-75-ambitions-for-april/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lossless Image Compression Through Super-Resolution</title>
<link>https://github.com/caoscott/SReC</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/caoscott/SReC</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://caoscott.github.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Sheng Cao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~cywu/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chao-Yuan Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.philkr.net/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Philipp Krähenbühl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/caoscott/SReC/blob/master/figs/concept_fig.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/caoscott/SReC/raw/master/figs/concept_fig.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
@article{cao2020lossless,
  title={Lossless Image Compression through Super-Resolution},
  author={Cao, Sheng and Wu, Chao-Yuan and and Kr{\&quot;a}henb{\&quot;u}hl, Philipp},
  year={2020},
  journal={arXiv preprint arXiv:2004.02872},
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use our codebase, please consider also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fab-jul/L3C-PyTorch#citation&quot;&gt;citing L3C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the official implementation of SReC in &lt;a href=&quot;http://pytorch.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PyTorch&lt;/a&gt;. SReC frames lossless compression as a super-resolution problem and applies neural networks to compress images. SReC can achieve state-of-the-art compression rates on large datasets with practical runtimes. Training, compression, and decompression are fully supported and open-sourced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend the following steps for getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/caoscott/SReC/blob/master/INSTALL.md&quot;&gt;Install the necessary dependencies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://data.vision.ee.ethz.ch/mentzerf/validation_sets_lossless/val_oi_500_r.tar.gz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Download the Open Images validation set&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/caoscott/SReC#compressiondecompression&quot;&gt;Run compression on Open Images validation set&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/caoscott/SReC#model-weights&quot;&gt;trained model weights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/caoscott/SReC/blob/master/INSTALL.md&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for installation instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Model Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've released trained models for both &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1707.08819&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ImageNet64&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/openimages/web/index.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Open Images (PNG)&lt;/a&gt;. All compression results are measured in bits per subpixel (bpsp).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Training&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To run code, you need to be in top level directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;python3 -um src.train \
  --train-path &quot;path to directory of training images&quot; \
  --train-file &quot;list of filenames of training images, one filename per line&quot; \
  --eval-path &quot;path to directory of eval images&quot; \
  --eval-file &quot;list of filenames of eval images, one filename per line&quot; \
  --plot &quot;directory to store model output&quot; \
  --batch &quot;batch size&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training images must be organized in form of &lt;code&gt;train-path/filename&lt;/code&gt; from filename in train-file. Same thing applies to eval images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've included our training and eval files used for ImageNet64 and Open Images (PNG) in &lt;code&gt;datasets&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For ImageNet64, we use a slightly different set of hyperparameters than Open Images hyperparameters, which are the default. To train ImageNet64 based on settings from our paper, run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;python3 -um src.train \
  --train-path &quot;path to directory of training images&quot; \
  --train-file &quot;list of filenames of training images, one filename per line&quot; \
  --eval-path &quot;path to directory of eval images&quot; \
  --eval-file &quot;list of filenames of eval images, one filename per line&quot; \
  --plot &quot;directory to store model output&quot; \
  --batch &quot;batch size&quot; \
  --epochs 10 \
  --lr-epochs 1 \
  --crop 64
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;python3 -um src.train --help&lt;/code&gt; for a list of tunable hyperparameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given a model checkpoint, this evaluates theoretical bits/subpixel (bpsp) based on log-likelihood. The log-likelihood bpsp lower-bounds the actual compression bpsp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;python3 -um src.eval \
  --path &quot;path to directory of images&quot; \
  --file &quot;list of filenames of images, one filename per line&quot; \
  --load &quot;path to model weights&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Compression/Decompression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With torchac installed, you can run compression/decompression to convert any image into .srec files. The following compresses a directory of images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;python3 -um src.encode \
  --path &quot;path to directory of images&quot; \ 
  --file &quot;list of filenames of images, one filename per line&quot; \
  --save-path &quot;directory to save new .srec files&quot; \
  --load &quot;path to model weights&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want an accurate runtime, we recommend running python with &lt;code&gt;-O&lt;/code&gt; flag to disable asserts. We also include an optional &lt;code&gt;--decode&lt;/code&gt; flag so that you can check if decompressing the .srec file gives the original image, as well as provide runtime for decoding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To convert .srec files into PNG, you can run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;python3 -um src.decode \
  --path &quot;path to directory of .srec images&quot; \ 
  --file &quot;list of filenames of .srec images, one filename per line&quot; \
  --save-path &quot;directory to save png files&quot; \
  --load &quot;path to model weights&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Downloading ImageNet64&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download ImageNet64 training and validation sets &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.image-net.org/small/download.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preparing Open Images Dataset (PNG)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the same set of training and validation images of Open Images as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fab-jul/L3C-PyTorch&quot;&gt;L3C&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;validation images&lt;/strong&gt;, you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.vision.ee.ethz.ch/mentzerf/validation_sets_lossless/val_oi_500_r.tar.gz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;download them here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;training images&lt;/strong&gt;, please clone the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fab-jul/L3C-PyTorch/&quot;&gt;L3C repo&lt;/a&gt; and run &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fab-jul/L3C-PyTorch#prepare-open-images-for-training&quot;&gt;script from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fab-jul/L3C-PyTorch/issues/14&quot;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; for differences between Open Images JPEG and Open Images PNG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fab-jul/L3C-PyTorch&quot;&gt;L3C&lt;/a&gt; for implementations of EDSR, logistic mixtures, and arithmetic coding. Special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fab-jul&quot;&gt;Fabian Mentzer&lt;/a&gt; for letting us know about issues with the preprocessing script for Open Images JPEG and resolving them quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 13:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>beagle3</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/22038081?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>caoscott/SReC</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/caoscott/SReC</og:url>
<og:description>PyTorch Implementation of &quot;Lossless Image Compression through Super-Resolution&quot; - caoscott/SReC</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/caoscott/SReC</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Docker Compose Specification</title>
<link>https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-the-compose-specification/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-the-compose-specification/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;/header&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;25961&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-the-compose-specification/compose_github_repo_card/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/compose_github_repo_card.png?fit=1280%2C640&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1280,640&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;compose_github_repo_card&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/compose_github_repo_card.png?fit=600%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/compose_github_repo_card.png?fit=1110%2C555&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/compose_github_repo_card.png?fit=1110%2C555&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-25961&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/compose_github_repo_card.png?w=1280&amp;amp;ssl=1 1280w, https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/compose_github_repo_card.png?resize=600%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/compose_github_repo_card.png?resize=1110%2C555&amp;amp;ssl=1 1110w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Docker is pleased to announce that we have created a new open community to develop the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/compose-spec&quot;&gt;Compose Specification&lt;/a&gt;. This new community will be run with open governance with input from all interested parties allowing us together to create a new standard for defining multi-container apps that can be run from the desktop to the cloud. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Docker is working with Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft and others in the open source community to extend the Compose Specification to more flexibly support cloud-native platforms like Kubernetes and Amazon Elastic Container Service (Amazon ECS) in addition to the existing Compose platforms. Opening the specification will allow innovation to flourish and deliver more choices to developers, accelerating how development teams build and ship applications.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently used by millions of developers and with over 650,000 Compose files on GitHub, Compose has been widely embraced by developers because it is a simple cloud and platform-agnostic way of defining multi-container based applications. Compose dramatically simplifies the code to cloud process and toolchain for developers by allowing them to define a complex stack in a single file and run it with a single command. This eliminates the need to build and start every container manually, saving development teams valuable time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;25952&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-the-compose-specification/screen-shot-2020-04-06-at-3-15-06-pm/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-06-at-3.15.06-PM.png?fit=1700%2C1066&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1700,1066&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screen-Shot-2020-04-06-at-3.15.06-PM&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-06-at-3.15.06-PM.png?fit=478%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-06-at-3.15.06-PM.png?fit=1110%2C696&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-06-at-3.15.06-PM.png?fit=1110%2C696&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-25952&quot; width=&quot;514&quot; height=&quot;321&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-06-at-3.15.06-PM.png?w=1700&amp;amp;ssl=1 1700w, https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-06-at-3.15.06-PM.png?resize=478%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 478w, https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-06-at-3.15.06-PM.png?resize=1110%2C696&amp;amp;ssl=1 1110w, https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-06-at-3.15.06-PM.png?resize=1536%2C963&amp;amp;ssl=1 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously Compose did not have a published specification, and was tied to the implementation, and to specifics of the platforms it shipped on. Open governance will benefit the wider community of new and existing users with transparency and the ability to have input into the future direction of the specification and Compose based tools. With greater community support and engagement, Docker intends to submit the Compose Specification to an open source foundation to further enhance the level playing field and openness.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get started using Docker Compose today to try the existing features you can download Docker Desktop with Docker Compose &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-desktop&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Or if you are looking for some examples or ideas to get started with Compose why not check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/docker/awesome-compose&quot;&gt;Awesome Compose Repo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;The draft specification is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.compose-spec.io/&quot;&gt;compose-spec.io&lt;/a&gt;; we are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/compose-spec/compose-spec/issues/57&quot;&gt;looking for contributors to the Compose Specification&lt;/a&gt; along with people who are interested in building tools around the specification. Docker will continue to contribute to the specification and be an active member of the community around it going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;mt-5 border-top pt-3&quot;&gt;

&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 13:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alexellisuk</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Announcing the Compose Specification - Docker Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Docker is pleased to announce that we have created a new open community to develop the Compose Specification.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-the-compose-specification/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i2.wp.com/www.docker.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/compose_github_repo_card.png?fit=1110%2C555&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-the-compose-specification/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A new form of brain stimulation relieved severe depression in a small study</title>
<link>http://med.stanford.edu/news/all-news/2020/04/stanford-researchers-devise-treatment-that-relieved-depression-i.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://med.stanford.edu/news/all-news/2020/04/stanford-researchers-devise-treatment-that-relieved-depression-i.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;social-icons social_share parbase&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;social-share&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;facebook-share-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;facebook-share share send parbase&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;twitter-share-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;twitter-share twittershare parbase&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;news-excerpt&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Stanford Medicine researchers used high doses of magnetic stimulation, delivered on an accelerated timeline and targeted to individual neurocircuitry, to treat patients with severe depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; class=&quot;publication-date&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;publication-day&quot;&gt;Apr 6&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;publication-year&quot;&gt;2020&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;main parsys&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image adaptiveimage parbase section&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull-right image-full-width&quot; data-fullscreen-modal=&quot;&quot;&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;sm-image background-color-8C1515 caption bottom&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot; data-picture=&quot;&quot; data-alt=&quot;Deirdre Lehman and Nolan Williams&quot; data-group=&quot;&quot;&gt;
























&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://med.stanford.edu/news/all-news/2020/04/stanford-researchers-devise-treatment-that-relieved-depression-i/_jcr_content/main/image.img.620.high.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Deirdre Lehman and Nolan Williams&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deirdre Lehman, who suffered from depression, with Nolan Williams, who oversaw a clinical trial of a potential treatment that uses transcranial magnetic stimulation. In this photo, Williams and Lehman demonstrate how a patient is positioned and the equipment is used during the treatment.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steve Fisch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text parbase section&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;main_content&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new form of magnetic brain stimulation rapidly relieved symptoms of severe depression in 90% of participants in a small study conducted by researchers at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/&quot;&gt;Stanford University School of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers are conducting a larger, double-blinded trial in which half the participants are receiving fake treatment. The researchers are optimistic the second trial will prove to be similarly effective in treating people whose condition hasn’t improved with medication, talk therapy or other forms of electromagnetic stimulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The treatment is called Stanford Accelerated Intelligent Neuromodulation Therapy, or SAINT. It is a form of transcranial magnetic stimulation, which is approved by the Food and Drug Administration for treatment of depression. The researchers reported that the therapy improves on current FDA-approved protocols by increasing the number of magnetic pulses, speeding up the pace of the treatment and targeting the pulses according to each individual’s neurocircuitry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before undergoing the therapy, all 21 study participants were severely depressed, according to several diagnostic tests for depression. Afterward, 19 of them scored within the nondepressed range. Although all of the participants had suicidal thoughts before the therapy, none of them reported having suicidal thoughts after treatment. All 21 participants had previously not experienced improvements with medications, FDA-approved transcranial magnetic stimulation or electroconvulsive therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only side effects of the new therapy were fatigue and some discomfort during treatment, the study reported. The results was published online April 6 in the &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There’s never been a therapy for treatment-resistant depression that’s broken 55% remission rates in open-label testing,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/nolan-williams&quot;&gt;Nolan Williams&lt;/a&gt;, MD, assistant professor of psychiatry and behavioral sciences and a senior author of the study. “Electroconvulsive therapy is thought to be the gold standard, but it has only an average 48% remission rate in treatment-resistant depression. No one expected these kinds of results.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Calming the brain chatter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Deirdre Lehman, 60, woke up the morning of June 30, 2018, she said she was hit by “a tsunami of darkness.” Lehman had struggled with bipolar disorder all her adult life, but with medications and psychotherapy her mood had been stable for 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image adaptiveimage parbase section&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull-left image-half-width&quot; data-fullscreen-modal=&quot;&quot;&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;sm-image background-color-666666 caption bottom&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot; data-picture=&quot;&quot; data-alt=&quot;Deirde Lehman&quot; data-group=&quot;&quot;&gt;
























&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://med.stanford.edu/news/all-news/2020/04/stanford-researchers-devise-treatment-that-relieved-depression-i/_jcr_content/main/image_893421470.img.620.high.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Deirde Lehman&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After undergoing the experimental treatment, Lehman's depression dissipated. She has since completed a bachelor’s degree at the University of California-Santa Barbara, where she had dropped out as a young woman when her bipolar symptoms overwhelmed her studies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steve Fisch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text parbase section&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;main_text&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There was a constant chattering in my brain: It was my own voice talking about depression, agony, hopelessness,” she said. “I told my husband, ‘I’m going down and I’m heading toward suicide.’ There seemed to be no other option.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lehman’s psychiatrist had heard of the SAINT study and referred her to Stanford. After researchers pinpointed the spot in her brain that would benefit from stimulation, Lehman underwent the therapy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“By the third round, the chatter started to ease,” she said. “By lunch, I could look my husband in the eye. With each session, the chatter got less and less until it was completely quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That was the most peace there’s been in my brain since I was 16 and started down the path to bipolar disorder.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In transcranial magnetic stimulation, electric currents from a magnetic coil placed on the scalp excite a region of the brain implicated in depression. The treatment, as approved by the FDA, requires six weeks of once-daily sessions. Only about half of patients who undergo this treatment improve, and only about a third experience remission from depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford researchers hypothesized that some modifications to transcranial magnetic stimulation could improve its effectiveness. Studies had suggested that a stronger dose, of 1,800 pulses per session instead of 600, would be more effective. The researchers were cautiously optimistic of the safety of the treatment, as that dose of stimulation had been used without harm in other forms of brain stimulation for neurological disorders, such as Parkinson’s disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other studies suggested that accelerating the treatment would help relieve patients’ depression more rapidly. With SAINT, study participants underwent 10 sessions per day of 10-minute treatments, with 50-minute breaks in between. After a day of therapy, Lehman’s mood score indicated she was no longer depressed; it took up to five days for other participants. On average, three days of the therapy were enough for participants to have relief from depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The less treatment-resistant participants are, the longer the treatment lasts,” said postdoctoral scholar &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/eleanor-cole&quot;&gt;Eleanor Cole&lt;/a&gt;, PhD, a lead author of the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Strengthening a weak connection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also conjectured that targeting the stimulation more precisely would improve the treatment’s effectiveness. In transcranial magnetic stimulation, the treatment is aimed at the location where most people’s dorsolateral prefrontal cortex lies. This region regulates executive functions, such as selecting appropriate memories and inhibiting inappropriate responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For SAINT, the researchers used magnetic-resonance imaging of brain activity to locate not only the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex, but a particular subregion within it. They pinpointed the subregion in each participant that has a relationship with the subgenual cingulate, a part of brain that is overactive in people experiencing depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In people who are depressed, the connection between the two regions is weak, and the subgenual cingulate becomes overactive, said &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/keith-sudheimer&quot;&gt;Keith Sudheimer&lt;/a&gt;, PhD, clinical assistant professor of psychiatry and a senior author of the study. Stimulating the subregion of the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex reduces activity in the subgenual cingulate, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test safety, the researchers evaluated the participants’ cognitive function before and after treatment. They found no negative side effects; in fact, they discovered that the participants’ ability to switch between mental tasks and to solve problems had improved — a typical outcome for people who are no longer depressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month after the therapy, 60% of participants were still in remission from depression. Follow-up studies are underway to determine the duration of the antidepressant effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers plan to study the effectiveness of SAINT on other conditions, such as obsessive-compulsive disorder, addiction and autism spectrum disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;‘Resilient and stable’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The depression Lehman woke up to almost two years ago was the worst episode she had ever experienced. Today, she said, she is happy and calm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since undergoing SAINT treatment, she has completed a bachelor’s degree at the University of California-Santa Barbara; she had dropped out as a young woman when her bipolar symptoms overwhelmed her studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I used to cry over the slightest thing,” she said. “But when bad things happen now, I’m just resilient and stable. I’m in a much more peaceful state of mind, able to enjoy the positive things in life with the energy to get things done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graduate student Katy Stimpson and &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/brandon-bentzley&quot;&gt;Brandon Bentzley&lt;/a&gt;, MD, PhD, a medical fellow in psychiatry and behavioral sciences, are also lead authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other Stanford co-authors are former lab manager Merve Gulser; graduate students Kirsten Cherian, Elizabeth Choi, Haley Aaron and Austin Guerra; &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/flint-espil&quot;&gt;Flint Espil&lt;/a&gt;, PhD, clinical assistant professor of psychiatry and behavioral sciences; research coordinators Claudia Tischler, Romina Nejad and Heather Pankow; medical student Jaspreet Pannu; postdoctoral scholars Xiaoqian Xiao, PhD, &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/james-bishop&quot;&gt;James Bishop&lt;/a&gt;, PhD, &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/208701&quot;&gt;John Coetzee&lt;/a&gt;, PhD, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/angela-phillips&quot;&gt;Angela Phillips&lt;/a&gt;, PhD; &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/hugh-solvason&quot;&gt;Hugh Solvason&lt;/a&gt;, MD, PhD, clinical professor of psychiatry and behavioral sciences; research manager Jessica Hawkins; &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/booil-jo&quot;&gt;Booil Jo&lt;/a&gt;, PhD, associate professor of psychiatry and behavioral sciences; &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/kristin-raj&quot;&gt;Kristin Raj&lt;/a&gt;, MD, clinical assistant professor of psychiatry and behavioral sciences; &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/charles-debattista&quot;&gt;Charles DeBattista&lt;/a&gt;, MD, professor of psychiatry and behavioral sciences; &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/jennifer-keller&quot;&gt;Jennifer Keller&lt;/a&gt;, PhD, clinical associate professor of psychiatry and behavioral sciences; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/profiles/alan-schatzberg&quot;&gt;Alan Schatzberg&lt;/a&gt;, MD, professor of psychiatry and behavioral sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research was supported by Charles R. Schwab, the Marshall and Dee Ann Payne Fund, the Lehman Family Neuromodulation Research Fund, the Still Charitable Fund, the Avy L. and Robert L. Miller Foundation, a Stanford Psychiatry Chairman’s Small Grant, the Stanford CNI Innovation Award, the National Institutes of Health (grants T32035165 and UL1TR001085), the Stanford Medical Scholars Research Scholarship, the NARSAD Young Investigator Award and the Gordie Brookstone Fund. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;media h-card&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;media-body&quot;&gt;By &lt;span class=&quot;name p-name&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Mandy Erickson&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;p-note&quot;&gt;Mandy Erickson is a science writer in the Office of Communications. Email her at merickso@stanford.edu.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stanford Medicine integrates research, medical education and health care at its three institutions - &lt;a href=&quot;http://med.stanford.edu/school.html&quot;&gt;Stanford University School of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://stanfordhealthcare.org&quot;&gt;Stanford Health Care (formerly Stanford Hospital &amp;amp; Clinics)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://stanfordchildrens.org&quot;&gt;Lucile Packard Children's Hospital Stanford&lt;/a&gt;. For more information, please visit the Office of Communication &amp;amp; Public Affairs site at &lt;a href=&quot;http://mednews.stanford.edu&quot;&gt;http://mednews.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 12:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stanford researchers devise treatment that relieved depression in 90% of participants in small study</og:title>
<og:image>http://med.stanford.edu/content/dam/sm-news/images/2020/04/saint-williams.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Stanford Medicine researchers used high doses of magnetic stimulation, delivered on an accelerated timeline and targeted to individual neurocircuitry, to treat patients with severe depression.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://med.stanford.edu/news/all-news/2020/04/stanford-researchers-devise-treatment-that-relieved-depression-i.html</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://med.stanford.edu/news/all-news/2020/04/stanford-researchers-devise-treatment-that-relieved-depression-i.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft buys corp.com so bad guys can’t</title>
<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/microsoft-buys-corp-com-so-bad-guys-cant/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/microsoft-buys-corp-com-so-bad-guys-cant/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In February, KrebsOnSecurity told the story of a private citizen &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/02/dangerous-domain-corp-com-goes-up-for-sale/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;auctioning off the dangerous domain &lt;strong&gt;corp.com&lt;/strong&gt; for the starting price of $1.7 million&lt;/a&gt;. Domain experts called corp.com dangerous because years of testing showed whoever wields it would have access to an unending stream of passwords, email and other sensitive data from hundreds of thousands of &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Windows&lt;/strong&gt; PCs at major companies around the globe. This week, &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Corp.&lt;/strong&gt; agreed to buy the domain in a bid to keep it out of the hands of those who might abuse its awesome power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-50460&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/corpcomtoxic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;159&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wisconsin native &lt;strong&gt;Mike O’Connor&lt;/strong&gt;, who bought corp.com 26 years ago but has done very little with it since, said he hoped Microsoft would buy it because hundreds of thousands of confused Windows PCs are constantly trying to share sensitive data with corp.com. Also, early versions of Windows actually encouraged the adoption of insecure settings that made it more likely Windows computers might try to share sensitive data with corp.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From February’s piece:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;52.901694915254&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At issue is a problem known as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computerworld.com/article/3480799/icann-seeks-to-tackle-dns-namespace-collision-risks.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;namespace collision&lt;/a&gt;,” a situation where domain names intended to be used exclusively on an internal company network end up overlapping with domains that can resolve normally on the open Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows computers on an internal corporate network validate other things on that network using a Microsoft innovation called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Active_Directory&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Active Directory&lt;/a&gt;, which is the umbrella term for a broad range of identity-related services in Windows environments. A core part of the way these things find each other involves a Windows feature called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itprotoday.com/security/whats-dns-name-devolution&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;DNS name devolution&lt;/a&gt;,” which is a kind of network shorthand that makes it easier to find other computers or servers without having to specify a full, legitimate domain name for those resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if a company runs an internal network with the name internalnetwork.example.com, and an employee on that network wishes to access a shared drive called “drive1,” there’s no need to type “drive1.internalnetwork.example.com” into Windows Explorer; typing “\\drive1\” alone will suffice, and Windows takes care of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But things can get far trickier with an internal Windows domain that does not map back to a second-level domain the organization actually owns and controls. And unfortunately, in early versions of Windows that supported Active Directory — Windows 2000 Server, for example — the default or example Active Directory path was given as “corp,” and many companies apparently adopted this setting without modifying it to include a domain they controlled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compounding things further, some companies then went on to build (and/or assimilate) vast networks of networks on top of this erroneous setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, none of this was much of a security concern back in the day when it was impractical for employees to lug their bulky desktop computers and monitors outside of the corporate network. But what happens when an employee working at a company with an Active Directory network path called “corp” takes a company laptop to the local Starbucks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chances are good that at least some resources on the employee’s laptop will still try to access that internal “corp” domain. And because of the way DNS name devolution works on Windows, that company laptop online via the Starbucks wireless connection is likely to then seek those same resources at “corp.com.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practical terms, this means that whoever controls corp.com can passively intercept private communications from hundreds of thousands of computers that end up being taken outside of a corporate environment which uses this “corp” designation for its Active Directory domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story went on to describe how years of testing — some of which was subsidized by grants from the &lt;strong&gt;U.S. Department of Homeland Security&lt;/strong&gt; — showed hundreds of thousands of Windows computers were constantly trying to send this domain information it had no business receiving, including attempts to log in to internal corporate networks and access specific file shares on those networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Connor told me he was selling the domain after doing basically nothing with it for 26 years because he was getting on in years and didn’t want his kids to inherit this mess. When he put the domain up for sale, I asked if he’d agree to let me know if and when he sold it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday evening, he wrote to say that Microsoft had agreed to purchase it. O’Connor said he could  not discuss the terms of the deal, nor could he offer further comment beyond acknowledging the sale of corp.com to Microsoft.&lt;span id=&quot;more-51195&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a written statement, Microsoft said it acquired the domain to protect its customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To help in keeping systems protected we encourage customers to practice safe security habits when planning for internal domain and network names,” the statement reads. “We released a security advisory in June of 2009 and a security update that helps keep customers safe. In our ongoing commitment to customer security, we also acquired the Corp.com domain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, Microsoft has shipped &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.security-database.com/detail.php?alert=KB971888&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://msrc-blog.microsoft.com/2015/02/10/ms15-011-ms15-014-hardening-group-policy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;software updates&lt;/a&gt; to help decrease the likelihood of namespace collisions that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jasadvisors.com/jasbug-improper-use-of-the-dns-for-authentication-and-over-the-internet-exploitation-scenarios/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;could create a security problem&lt;/a&gt; for companies that still rely on Active Directory domains that do not map to a domain they control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, experts say hardly any vulnerable organizations have deployed these fixes for two reasons. First, doing so requires the organization to take down its entire Active Directory network simultaneously for some period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, according to Microsoft applying the patch(es) will likely break or at least slow down a number of applications that the affected organization relies upon for day-to-day operations. Faced with either or both of these scenarios, most affected companies probably decided the actual risk of not applying these updates was comparatively low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that while Microsoft’s purchase of corp.com will safeguard companies that built Active Directory infrastructures on top of “corp” or “corp.com,” any company that has tied their internal Active Directory network to a domain they do not control is opening itself to a similar potential security nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/en/system/files/files/name-collision-mitigation-study-06jun14-en.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Mitigating the Risk of DNS Namespace Collisions&lt;/a&gt; (PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZPbyDSvGasw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;DEFCON 21 – DNS May Be Hazardous to your Health (Robert Stucke)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.verisign.com/assets/labs/MitM-Attack-by-Name-Collision-Cause-Analysis-and-WPAD-Vulnerability-Assessment-in-the-New-gTLD-Era.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Mitigating the Risk of Name Collision-Based Man-in-the-Middle Attacks&lt;/a&gt; (PDF)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mid-banner&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.akamai.com/us/en/resources/our-thinking/state-of-the-internet-report/global-state-of-the-internet-security-ddos-attack-reports.jsp?utm_source=krebsonsecurity&amp;amp;utm_medium=display&amp;amp;utm_id=F-MC-49586&amp;amp;utm_campaign=security_digital_publication_2020&amp;amp;utm_content=SOTI&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/b-akamai/33.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/active-directory/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Active Directory&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/corp-com/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;corp.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/microsoft/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/mike-oconnor/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Mike O'Connor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Tuesday, April 7th, 2020 at 8:34 am and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/sunshine/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;A Little Sunshine&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any comments to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/microsoft-buys-corp-com-so-bad-guys-cant/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. You can skip to the end and leave a comment. Pinging is currently not allowed.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 12:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DyslexicAtheist</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/microsoft-buys-corp-com-so-bad-guys-cant/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>