<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Falling in love with Rust</title>
<link>http://dtrace.org/blogs/bmc/2018/09/18/falling-in-love-with-rust/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://dtrace.org/blogs/bmc/2018/09/18/falling-in-love-with-rust/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Let me preface this with an apology: this is a technology love story, and as such, it’s long, rambling, sentimental and personal. Also befitting a love story, it has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_Harry_Met_Sally...&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;When Harry Met Sally&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feel to it, in that its origins are inauspicious…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First encounters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over a decade ago, I worked on a technology to which a competitor paid the highest possible compliment: they tried to implement their own knockoff. Because this was done in the open (and because it is uniquely mesmerizing to watch one’s own work mimicked), I spent way too much time following their mailing list and tracking their progress (and yes, taking an especially shameful delight in their occasional feuds). On their team, there was one technologist who was clearly exceptionally capable — and I confess to being relieved when he chose to leave the team relatively early in the project’s life. This was all in 2005; for years for me, Rust was “that thing that Graydon disappeared to go work on.” From the description as I read it at the time, Graydon’s new project seemed outrageously ambitious — and I assumed that little would ever come of it, though certainly not for lack of ability or effort…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward eight years to 2013 or so. Impressively, Graydon’s Rust was not only still alive, but it had gathered a community and was getting quite a bit of attention — enough to merit a serious look. There seemed to be some very intriguing ideas, but any budding interest that I might have had frankly withered when I learned that Rust had adopted &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thread_(computing)#Models&quot;&gt;the M:N threading model&lt;/a&gt; — including its more baroque consequences like segmented stacks. In my experience, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dtrace.org/blogs/bmc/2008/11/03/concurrencys-shysters/&quot;&gt;every system that has adopted the M:N model has lived to regret it&lt;/a&gt; — and it was unfortunate to have a promising new system appear to be ignorant of the scarred shoulders that it could otherwise stand upon. For me, the implications were larger than this single decision: I was concerned that it may be indicative of a deeper malaise that would make Rust a poor fit for the infrastructure software that I like to write. So while impressed that Rust’s ambitious vision was coming to any sort of fruition at all, I decided that Rust wasn’t for me personally — and I didn’t think much more about it…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time later, a truly amazing thing happened: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.mozilla.org/pipermail/rust-dev/2013-December/007565.html&quot;&gt;Rust ripped it out&lt;/a&gt;. Rust’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.mozilla.org/pipermail/rust-dev/2013-November/006314.html&quot;&gt;reasoning for removing segmented stacks&lt;/a&gt; is a concise but thorough damnation; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/blob/0806be4f282144cfcd55b1d20284b43f87cbe1c6/text/0230-remove-runtime.md&quot;&gt;their rationale for removing M:N&lt;/a&gt; is clear-eyed, thoughtful and reflective — but also unequivocal in its resolve. Suddenly, Rust became very interesting: all systems make mistakes, but few muster the courage to rectify them; on that basis alone, Rust became a project worthy of close attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So several years later, in 2015, it was with great interest that I learned that &lt;a href=&quot;http://dtrace.org/blogs/ahl/2015/06/22/first-rust-program-pain/&quot;&gt;Adam started experimenting with Rust&lt;/a&gt;. On first read of Adam’s blog entry, I assumed he would end what appeared to be excruciating pain by deleting the Rust compiler from his computer (if not by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Soul_of_a_New_Machine&quot;&gt;moving to a commune in Vermont&lt;/a&gt;) — but Adam surprised me when he ended up being very positive about Rust, despite his rough experiences. In particular, Adam hailed the important new ideas like the ownership model — and explicitly hoped that his experience would serve as a warning to others to approach the language in a different way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years since, Rust continued to mature and my curiosity (and I daresay, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/postwait/status/1040608681841369089&quot;&gt;that of many software engineers&lt;/a&gt;) has steadily intensified: the more I have discovered, the more intrigued I have become. This interest has coincided with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LjFM8vw3pbU&quot;&gt;my personal quest&lt;/a&gt; to find a programming language for the back half of my career: as I mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/230142234&quot;&gt;my Node Summit 2017 talk on platform as a reflection of values&lt;/a&gt;, I have been searching for a language that reflects my personal engineering values around robustness and performance. These values reflect a deeper sense within me: that software can be &lt;strong&gt;permanent&lt;/strong&gt; — that software’s unique duality as both information and machine afford a &lt;a href=&quot;http://dtrace.org/blogs/bmc/2007/11/11/on-dreaming-in-code/&quot;&gt;timeless perfection&lt;/a&gt; and utility that stand apart from other human endeavor. In this regard, I have believed (and continue to believe) that we are living in a Golden Age of software, one that will produce artifacts that will endure for generations. Of course, it can be hard to hold such heady thoughts when we seem to be up to our armpits in vendored flotsam, flooded by sloppy abstractions hastily implemented. Among current languages, only Rust seems to share this aspiration for permanence, with a perspective that is decidedly larger than itself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taking the plunge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have been actively looking for an opportunity to dive into Rust in earnest, and earlier this year, one presented itself: for a while, I have been working on a new mechanism for system visualization that I dubbed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x3rmg33j7RA&quot;&gt;statemaps&lt;/a&gt;. The software for rendering statemaps needs to inhale a data stream, coalesce it down to a reasonable size, and render it as a dynamic image that can be manipulated by the user. This originally started off as being written in node.js, but performance became a problem (especially for larger data sets) and I did what we at Joyent have done in such situations: I rewrote the hot loop in C, and then dropped that into a node.js add-on (allowing the SVG-rendering code to remain in JavaScript). This was fine, but painful: the C was straightforward, but the glue code to bridge into node.js was every bit as capricious, tedious, and error-prone as it has always been. Given the performance constraint, the desire for the power of a higher level language, and the experimental nature of the software, statemaps made for an excellent candidate to reimplement in Rust; my intensifying curiosity could finally be sated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I set out, I had the advantage of having watched (if from afar) many others have their first encounters with Rust. And if those years of being a Rust looky-loo taught me anything, it’s that the early days can be like the first days of snowboarding or windsurfing: lots of painful falling down! So I took deliberate approach with Rust: rather than do what one is wont to do when learning a new language and tinker a program into existence, I really sat down to &lt;em&gt;learn&lt;/em&gt; Rust. This is frankly my bias anyway (I always look for the first principles of a creation, as explained by its creators), but with Rust, I went further: not only did I buy the canonical reference (&lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/&quot;&gt;The Rust Programming Language&lt;/a&gt; by Steve Klabnik, Carol Nichols and community contributors), I also bought an O’Reilly book with a bit more narrative (&lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920040385.do&quot;&gt;Programming Rust&lt;/a&gt; by Jim Blandy and Jason Orendorff). And with this latter book, I did something that I haven’t done since cribbing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BASIC&quot;&gt;BASIC&lt;/a&gt; programs from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enter_(magazine)&quot;&gt;Enter magazine&lt;/a&gt; back in the day: I typed in the example program in the introductory chapters. I found this to be very valuable: it got the fingers and the brain warmed up while still absorbing Rust’s new ideas — and debugging my inevitable transcription errors allowed me to get some understanding of what it was that I was typing. At the end was something that actually did something, and (importantly), by working with a program that was already correct, I was able to painlessly feel some of the tremendous promise of Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encouraged by these early (if gentle) experiences, I dove into my statemap rewrite. It took a little while (and yes, I had some altercations with the borrow checker!), but I’m almost shocked about how happy I am with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joyent/statemap/tree/rust&quot;&gt;the rewrite of statemaps in Rust&lt;/a&gt;. Because I know that many are in the shoes I occupied just a short while ago (namely, intensely wondering about Rust, but also wary of its learning curve — and concerned about the investment of time and energy that climbing it will necessitate), I would like to expand on some of the things that I love about Rust &lt;em&gt;other than&lt;/em&gt; the ownership model. This isn’t because I don’t love the ownership model (I absolutely do) or that the ownership model isn’t core to Rust (it is rightfully thought of as Rust’s epicenter), but because I think its sheer magnitude sometimes dwarfs other attributes of Rust — attributes that I find very compelling! In a way, I am writing this for my past self — because if I have one regret about Rust, it’s that I didn’t see beyond the ownership model to learn it earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will discuss these attributes in roughly the order I discovered them with the (obvious?) caveat that this shouldn’t be considered authoritative; I’m still very much new to Rust, and my apologies in advance for any technical details that I get wrong!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Rust’s error handling is beautiful&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that really struck me about Rust was its beautiful error handling — but to appreciate why it so resonated with me requires some additional context. Despite its obvious importance, error handling is something we haven’t really gotten right in systems software. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joyent.com/node-js/production/design/errors&quot;&gt;as Dave Pacheo observed with respect to node.js&lt;/a&gt;, we often conflate different kinds of errors — namely, programmatic errors (i.e., my program is broken because of a logic error) with operational errors (i.e., an error condition external to my program has occurred and it affects my operation). In C, this conflation is unusual, but you see it with the infamous SIGSEGV signal handler that has been known to sneak into more than one undergraduate project moments before a deadline to deal with an otherwise undebuggable condition. In the Java world, this is slightly more common with the (frowned upon) behavior of catching &lt;tt&gt;java.lang.NullPointerException&lt;/tt&gt; or otherwise trying to drive on in light of clearly broken logic. And in the JavaScript world, this conflation is commonplace — and underlies one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nodejs/node/pull/12442#issuecomment-294546588&quot;&gt;the most serious objections to promises&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the ontological confusion, error handling suffers from an infamous mechanical problem: for a function that may return a value but may also fail, how is the caller to delineate the two conditions? (This is known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semipredicate_problem&quot;&gt;semipredicate problem&lt;/a&gt; after a Lisp construct that suffers from it.) C handles this as it handles so many things: by leaving it to the programmer to figure out their own (bad) convention. Some use sentinel values (e.g., Linux system calls cleave the return space in two and use negative values to denote the error condition); some return defined values on success and failure and then set an orthogonal error code; and of course, some just silently eat errors entirely (or &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/14199689/how-can-i-handle-exit-calls-in-3rd-party-library-code&quot;&gt;even worse&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C++ and Java (and many other languages before them) tried to solve this with the notion of exceptions. I do not like exceptions: for reasons not dissimilar to Dijkstra’s in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://homepages.cwi.nl/~storm/teaching/reader/Dijkstra68.pdf&quot;&gt;famous admonition against “goto”&lt;/a&gt;, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lighterra.com/papers/exceptionsharmful/&quot;&gt;consider exceptions harmful&lt;/a&gt;. While they are perhaps convenient from a function signature perspective, exceptions allow errors to wait in ambush, deep in the tall grass of implicit dependencies. When the error strikes, higher-level software may well not know what hit it, let alone from whom — and suddenly an operational error has become a programmatic one. (Java tries to mitigate this sneak attack with checked exceptions, but while well-intentioned, they have &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.philipphauer.de/checked-exceptions-are-evil/&quot;&gt;serious flaws in practice&lt;/a&gt;.) In this regard, exceptions are a concrete example of trading the speed of developing software with its long-term operability. One of our deepest, most fundamental problems as a craft is that we have enshrined “velocity” above all else, willfully blinding ourselves to the long-term consequences of gimcrack software. Exceptions optimize for the developer by allowing them to pretend that errors are someone else’s problem — or perhaps that they just won’t happen at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, exceptions aren’t the only way to solve this, and other languages take other approaches. Closure-heavy languages like JavaScript afford environments like node.js the luxury of passing an error as an argument — but this argument can be ignored or otherwise abused (and it’s untyped regardless), making this solution far from perfect. And Go uses its support for multiple return values to (by convention) &lt;a href=&quot;https://dave.cheney.net/2012/01/18/why-go-gets-exceptions-right&quot;&gt;return both a result and an error value&lt;/a&gt;. While this approach is certainly an improvement over C, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bluxte.net/musings/2018/04/10/go-good-bad-ugly/#noisy-error-management&quot;&gt;it is also noisy, repetitive and error-prone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, Rust takes an approach that is unique among systems-oriented languages: leveraging first &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algebraic_data_type&quot;&gt;algebraic data types&lt;/a&gt; — whereby a thing can be exactly one of an enumerated list of types and the programmer is required to be explicit about its type to manipulate it — and then combining it with its support for parameterized types. Together, this allows functions to return &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; thing that’s one of &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; types: one type that denotes success and one that denotes failure. The caller can then &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/second-edition/ch18-00-patterns.html&quot;&gt;pattern match&lt;/a&gt; on the type of what has been returned: if it’s of the success type, it can get at the underlying thing (by unwrapping it), and if it’s of the error type, it can get at the underlying error and either handle it, propagate it, or improve upon it (by adding additional context) and propagating it. What it &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; do (or at least, cannot do implicitly) is simply ignore it: it has to deal with it explicitly, one way or the other. (For all of the details, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/second-edition/ch09-02-recoverable-errors-with-result.html&quot;&gt;Recoverable Errors with Result&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this concrete, in Rust you end up with code that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
fn do_it(filename: &amp;amp;str) -&amp;gt; Result {
    let stat = match fs::metadata(filename) {
        Ok(result) =&amp;gt; { result },
        Err(err) =&amp;gt; { return Err(err); }
    };                  

    let file = match File::open(filename) {
        Ok(result) =&amp;gt; { result },
        Err(err) =&amp;gt; { return Err(err); }
    };

    /* ... */

    Ok(())
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already, this is pretty good: it’s cleaner and more robust than multiple return values, return sentinels and exceptions — in part because the type system helps you get this correct. But it’s also verbose, so Rust takes it one step further by introducing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/second-edition/ch09-02-recoverable-errors-with-result.html#a-shortcut-for-propagating-errors-the--operator&quot;&gt;propagation operator&lt;/a&gt;: if your function returns a &lt;tt&gt;Result&lt;/tt&gt;, when you call a function that itself returns a &lt;tt&gt;Result&lt;/tt&gt;, you can append a question mark on the call to the function denoting that upon &lt;tt&gt;Ok&lt;/tt&gt;, the result should be unwrapped and the expression becomes the unwrapped thing — and upon &lt;tt&gt;Err&lt;/tt&gt; the error should be returned (and therefore propagated). This is easier seen than explained! Using the propagation operator turns our above example into this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
fn do_it_better(filename: &amp;amp;str) -&amp;gt; Result {
    let stat = fs::metadata(filename)?;
    let file = File::open(filename)?;

    /* ... */

    Ok(())
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, to me, is beautiful: it is robust; it is readable; it is not magic. And it is safe in that the compiler helps us arrive at this and then prevents us from straying from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/230142234&quot;&gt;Platforms reflect their values&lt;/a&gt;, and I daresay the propagation operator is an embodiment of Rust’s: balancing elegance and expressiveness with robustness and performance. This balance is reflected in a mantra that one hears frequently in the Rust community: &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrustacean.com/show_notes/bonus/_4/&quot;&gt;“we can have nice things.”&lt;/a&gt; Which is to say: while historically some of these values were in tension (i.e., making software more expressive might implicitly be making it less robust or more poorly performing), through innovation Rust is finding solutions that don’t compromise one of these values for the sake of the other.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. The macros are incredible&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was first learning C, I was (rightly) warned against using the C preprocessor. But like many of the things that we are cautioned about in our youth, this warning was one that the wise give to the enthusiastic to prevent injury; the truth is far more subtle. And indeed, as I came of age as a C programmer, I not only came to use the preprocessor, but to rely upon it. Yes, it needed to be used carefully — but in the right hands it could generate cleaner, better code. (Indeed, the preprocessor is very core to the way we implement &lt;a href=&quot;http://dtrace.org/blogs/ahl/2006/05/08/user-land-tracing-gets-better-and-better/&quot;&gt;DTrace’s statically defined tracing&lt;/a&gt;.) So if anything, my problems with the preprocessor were not its dangers so much as its many limitations: because it is, in fact, a &lt;strong&gt;pre&lt;/strong&gt;processor and not built into the language, there were all sorts of things that it would never be able to do — like access the abstract syntax tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Rust, I have been delighted by its &lt;a href=&quot;https://danielkeep.github.io/quick-intro-to-macros.html#being-hygienic&quot;&gt;support for hygienic macros&lt;/a&gt;. This not only solves the many safety problems with preprocessor-based macros, it allows them to be outrageously powerful: with access to the AST, macros are afforded an almost limitless expansion of the syntax — but invoked with an indicator (a trailing bang) that makes it clear to the programmer when they are using a macro. For example, one of the fully worked examples in &lt;em&gt;Programming Rust&lt;/em&gt; is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ProgrammingRust/examples/blob/master/json-macro/src/macros.rs&quot;&gt;json!&lt;/a&gt; macro that allows for JSON to be easy declared in Rust. This gets to the &lt;em&gt;ergonomics&lt;/em&gt; of Rust, and there are many macros (e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/macro.format.html&quot;&gt;format!&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/macro.vec.html&quot;&gt;vec!&lt;/a&gt;, etc.) that make Rust more pleasant to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of macros: they are so flexible and powerful that they allow for effective experimentation. For example, the propagation operator that I love so much actually started life as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/macro.try.html&quot;&gt;try! macro&lt;/a&gt;; that this macro was being used ubiquitously (and successfully) allowed a language-based solution to be considered. Languages can be (and have been!) ruined by too much experimentation happening &lt;em&gt;in the language&lt;/em&gt; rather than in &lt;em&gt;how it’s used&lt;/em&gt;; through its rich macros, it seems that Rust can enable the core of the language to remain smaller — and to make sure that when it expands, it is for the right reasons and in the right way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. &lt;tt&gt;format!&lt;/tt&gt; is a pleasure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, this is a small one but it’s (another) one of those little pleasantries that has made Rust really enjoyable. Many (most? all?) languages have an approximation or equivalent of the venerable &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Printf_format_string&quot;&gt;sprintf&lt;/a&gt;, whereby variable input is formatted according to a format string. Rust’s variant of this is the &lt;tt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/macro.format.html&quot;&gt;format!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; macro (which is in turn invoked by &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/macro.println.html&quot;&gt;println!&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/macro.panic.html&quot;&gt;panic!&lt;/a&gt;, etc.), and (in keeping with one of the broader themes of Rust) it feels like it has learned from much that came before it. It is type-safe (of course) but it is also clean in that the &lt;tt&gt;{}&lt;/tt&gt; format specifier can be used on any type that implements the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/fmt/trait.Display.html&quot;&gt;Display trait&lt;/a&gt;. I also love that the &lt;tt&gt;{:?}&lt;/tt&gt; format specifier denotes that the argument’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/fmt/trait.Debug.html&quot;&gt;Debug&lt;/a&gt; trait implementation should be invoked to print debug output. More generally, all of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/fmt/index.html#formatting-traits&quot;&gt;format specifiers map to particular traits&lt;/a&gt;, allowing for an elegant approach to an historically grotty problem. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/fmt/index.html&quot;&gt;a bunch of other niceties&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s all a concrete example of how Rust uses macros to deliver nice things without sullying syntax or otherwise special-casing. None of the formatting capabilities are unique to Rust, but that’s the point: in this (small) domain (as in many) Rust feels like a distillation of the best work that came before it. As anyone who has had to endure &lt;a href=&quot;http://dtrace.org/blogs/bmc/2018/02/03/talks/&quot;&gt;one of my talks&lt;/a&gt; can attest, I believe that appreciating history is essential both to understand our present and to map our future. Rust seems to have that perspective in the best ways: it is reverential of the past without being incarcerated by it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. &lt;tt&gt;include_str!&lt;/tt&gt; is a godsend&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the filthy aspects of the statemap code is that it is effectively encapsulating another program — a JavaScript program that lives in the SVG to allow for the interactivity of the statemap. This code lives in its own file, which the statemap code should pass through to the generated SVG. In the node.js/C hybrid, I am forced to locate the file in the filesystem — which is annoying because it has to be delivered along with the binary and located, etc. Now Rust — like many languages (including ES6) — has support for raw-string literals. As an aside, it’s interesting to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/9411&quot;&gt;the discussion leading up to its addition&lt;/a&gt;, and in particular, how a group of people really looked at every language that does this to see what should be mimicked versus what could be improved upon. I really like the syntax that Rust converged on: &lt;tt&gt;r&lt;/tt&gt; followed by one or more octothorpes followed by a quote to begin a raw string literal, and a quote followed by a matching number of octothorpes followed to end a literal, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
    let str = r##&quot;&quot;What a curious feeling!&quot; said Alice&quot;##;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This alone would have allowed me to do what I want, but still a tad gross in that it’s a bunch of JavaScript living inside a raw literal in a .rs file. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/macro.include_str.html&quot;&gt;include_str!&lt;/a&gt;, which allows me to tell the compiler to find the specified file in the filesystem during compilation, and statically drop it into a string variable that I can manipulate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
        ...
        /*
         * Now drop in our in-SVG code.
         */
        let lib = include_str!(&quot;statemap-svg.js&quot;);
        ...
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So nice! Over the years I have wanted this many times over for my C, and it’s another one of those little (but significant!) things that make Rust so refreshing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Serde is stunningly good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://serde.rs/&quot;&gt;Serde&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/second-edition/ch14-00-more-about-cargo.html&quot;&gt;Rust crate&lt;/a&gt; that allows for serialization and deserialization, and it’s just exceptionally good. It uses macros (and, in particular, Rust’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/second-edition/appendix-04-macros.html#procedural-macros-for-custom-derive&quot;&gt;procedural macros&lt;/a&gt;) to generate structure-specific routines for serialization and deserialization. As a result, Serde requires remarkably little programmer lift to use and performs eye-wateringly well — a concrete embodiment of Rust’s repeated defiance of the conventional wisdom that programmers must choose between abstractions and performance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the statemap implementation, the input is concatenated JSON that begins with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joyent/statemap#metadata&quot;&gt;a metadata payload&lt;/a&gt;. To read this payload in Rust, I define the structure, and denote that I wish to derive the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.serde.rs/serde/trait.Deserialize.html&quot;&gt;Deserialize trait&lt;/a&gt; as implemented by Serde:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
#[derive(Deserialize, Debug)]
#[allow(non_snake_case)]
struct StatemapInputMetadata {
    start: Vec&amp;lt;u64&amp;gt;,
    title: String,
    host: Option&amp;lt;String&amp;gt;,
    entityKind: Option&amp;lt;String&amp;gt;,
    states: HashMap&amp;lt;String, StatemapInputState&amp;gt;,
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, to actually parse it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
     let metadata: StatemapInputMetadata = serde_json::from_str(payload)?;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s… it. Thanks to the magic of the propagation operator, the errors are properly handled and propagated — and it has handled tedious, error-prone things for me like the optionality of certain members (itself beautifully expressed via Rust’s ubiquitous &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/option/index.html&quot;&gt;Option type&lt;/a&gt;). With this one line of code, I now (robustly) have a &lt;tt&gt;StatemapInputMetadata&lt;/tt&gt; instance that I can use and operate upon — &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; this performs incredibly well on top of it all. In this regard, Serde represents the best of software: it is a sophisticated, intricate implementation making available elegant, robust, high-performing abstractions; as legendary White Sox play-by-play announcer &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ken_Harrelson&quot;&gt;Hawk Harrelson&lt;/a&gt; might say, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Aj-EQrSAUs&quot;&gt;MERCY!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;6. I love tuples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my C, I have been known to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/illumos/illumos-gate/blob/7928f4baf4ab3230557eb6289be68aa7a3003f38/usr/src/lib/libdtrace/common/dt_error.c#L194-L223&quot;&gt;declare anonymous structures in functions&lt;/a&gt;. More generally, in any strongly typed language, there are plenty of times when you don’t want to have to fill out paperwork to be able to structure your data: you just want a tad more structure for a small job. For this, Rust borrows an age-old construct from ML in &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/primitive.tuple.html&quot;&gt;tuples&lt;/a&gt;. Tuples are expressed as a parenthetical list, and they basically work as you expect them to work in that they are static in size and type, and you can index into any member. For example, in some test code that needs to make sure that names for colors are correctly interpreted, I have this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
        let colors = vec![
            (&quot;aliceblue&quot;, (240, 248, 255)),
            (&quot;antiquewhite&quot;, (250, 235, 215)),
            (&quot;aqua&quot;, (0, 255, 255)),
            (&quot;aquamarine&quot;, (127, 255, 212)),
            (&quot;azure&quot;, (240, 255, 255)),
            /* ... */
        ];
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;tt&gt;colors[2].0&lt;/tt&gt; (say) which will be the string “aqua”; &lt;tt&gt;(colors[1].1).2&lt;/tt&gt; will be the integer 215. Don’t let the absence of a type declaration in the above deceive you: tuples are strongly typed, it’s just that Rust is inferring the type for me. So if I accidentally try to (say) add an element to the above vector that contains a tuple of mismatched signature (e.g., the tuple “&lt;tt&gt;((188, 143, 143), (&quot;rosybrown&quot;))&lt;/tt&gt;“, which has the order reversed), Rust will give me a compile-time error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full integration of tuples makes them a joy to use. For example, if a function returns a tuple, you can easily assign its constituent parts to disjoint variables, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
fn get_coord() -&amp;gt; (u32, u32) {
   (1, 2)
}

fn do_some_work() {
    let (x, y) = get_coord();
    /* x has the value 1, y has the value 2 */
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7. The integrated testing is terrific&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my regrets on DTrace is that we didn’t start on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/illumos/illumos-gate/tree/master/usr/src/cmd/dtrace/test&quot;&gt;the DTrace test suite&lt;/a&gt; at the same time we started the project. And even after we starting building it (too late, but blessedly before we shipped it), it still lived away from the source for several years. And even now, it’s a bit of a pain to run — you really need to know it’s there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This represents everything that’s wrong with testing in C: because it requires bespoke machinery, too many people don’t bother — even when they know better! Viz.: in the original statemap implementation, there is zero testing code — and not because I don’t believe in it, but just because it was too much work for something relatively small. Yes, there are plenty of testing frameworks for C and C++, but in my experience, the integrated frameworks are too constrictive — and again, not worth it for a smaller project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of test-driven development, many languages have taken a more integrated approach to testing. For example, Go has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bluxte.net/musings/2018/04/10/go-good-bad-ugly/#standardized-test-framework&quot;&gt;rightfully lauded testing framework&lt;/a&gt;, Python has &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/unittest.html&quot;&gt;unittest&lt;/a&gt;, etc. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/2018-edition/ch11-00-testing.html&quot;&gt;Rust takes a highly integrated approach&lt;/a&gt; that combines the best of all worlds: test code lives alongside the code that it’s testing — but without having to make the code bend to a heavyweight framework. The workhorses here are conditional compilation and Cargo, which together make it so easy to write tests and run them that I found myself doing &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; test-driven development with statemaps — namely writing the tests as I develop the code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8. The community is amazing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, the best communities are ones that are inclusive in their membership but resolute in their shared values. When communities aren’t inclusive, they stagnate, or rot (or worse); when communities don’t share values, they feud and fracture. This can be a very tricky balance, especially when so many open source projects start out as the work of a single individual: it’s very hard for a community not to reflect the idiosyncrasies of its founder. This is important because in the open source era, community is critical: one is selecting a community as much as one is selecting a technology, as each informs the future of the other. One factor that I value a bit less is strictly size: some of my favorite communities are small ones — and some of my least favorite are huge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For purposes of a community, Rust has a luxury of clearly articulated, broadly shared values that are featured prominently and reiterated frequently. If you head to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org&quot;&gt;the Rust website&lt;/a&gt; this is the first sentence you’ll read:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust is a systems programming language that runs blazingly fast, prevents segfaults, and guarantees thread safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That gets right to it: it says that as a community, we value performance and robustness — and we believe that we shouldn’t have to choose between these two. (And we have seen that this isn’t mere rhetoric, as so many Rust decisions show that these values are truly the lodestar of the project.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with respect to inclusiveness, it is revealing that you will likely read that statement of values in your native tongue, as the Rust web page has been translated into thirteen languages. Just the fact that it has been translated into so many languages makes Rust nearly unique among its peers. But perhaps more interesting is where this globally inclusive view likely finds its roots: among the sites of its peers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruby-lang.org&quot;&gt;only Ruby is similarly localized&lt;/a&gt;. Given that several prominent Rustaceans like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/steveklabnik&quot;&gt;Steve Klabnik&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/carols10cents&quot;&gt;Carol Nichols&lt;/a&gt; came from the Ruby community, it would not be unreasonable to guess that they brought this globally inclusive view with them. This kind of inclusion is one that one sees again and again in the Rust community: different perspectives from different languages and different backgrounds. Those who come to Rust bring with them their experiences — good and bad — from the old country, and the result is a melting pot of ideas. This is an inclusiveness that runs deep: by welcoming such disparate perspectives into a community and then uniting them with shared values and a common purpose, Rust achieves a rich and productive heterogeneity of thought. That is, because the community agrees about the big things (namely, its fundamental values), it has room to constructively disagree (that is, achieve consensus) on the smaller ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which isn’t to say this is easy! Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J9OFQm8Qf1I&quot;&gt;Ashley Williams in the opening keynote from RustConf 2018&lt;/a&gt; for how exhausting it can be to hash through these smaller differences in practice. Rust has taken a harder path than the “traditional” BDFL model, but it’s a qualitatively better one — and I believe that many of the things that I love about Rust are a reflection of (and a tribute to) its robust community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;9. The performance rips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we come to the last thing I discovered in my Rust odyssey — but in many ways, the most important one. As I described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aWbGPMxs0AM&quot;&gt;an internal presentation&lt;/a&gt;, I had experienced some frustrations trying to implement in Rust the same structure I had had in C. So I mentally gave up on performance, resolving to just get something working first, and then optimize it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did get it working, and was able to benchmark it, but to give some some context for the numbers, here is the time to generate a statemap in the old (slow) pure node.js implementation for &lt;a href=&quot;https://us-east.manta.joyent.com/bcantrill/public/statemap/pg-zfs.out.gz&quot;&gt;a modest trace&lt;/a&gt; (229M, ~3.9M state transitions) on my 2.9 GHz Core i7 laptop:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
% time ./statemap-js/bin/statemap ./pg-zfs.out &amp;gt; js.svg

real    1m23.092s
user    1m21.106s
sys     0m1.871s
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is bad — and larger input will cause it to just run out of memory. And here’s the version as reimplemented as a C/node.js hybrid:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
% time ./statemap-c/bin/statemap ./pg-zfs.out &amp;gt; c.svg

real    0m11.800s
user    0m11.414s
sys     0m0.330s
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was (as designed) a 10X improvement in performance, and represents speed-of-light numbers in that this seems to be an optimal implementation. Because I had written my Rust naively (and my C carefully), my hope was that the Rust would be no more than 20% slower — but I was braced for pretty much anything. Or at least, I thought I was; I was actually genuinely taken aback by the results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ time ./statemap.rs/target/release/statemap ./pg-zfs.out &amp;gt; rs.svg
3943472 records processed, 24999 rectangles

real    0m8.072s
user    0m7.828s
sys     0m0.186s
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you read that correctly: &lt;strong&gt;my naive Rust was ~32% faster than my carefully implemented C&lt;/strong&gt;. This blew me away, and in the time since, I have spent some time on a real lab machine running SmartOS (where I have reproduced these results and been able to study them a bit). My findings are going to have to wait for another blog entry, but suffice it to say that despite executing a shockingly similar number of instructions, the Rust implementation has a different load/store mix (it is much more store-heavy than C) — and is much better behaved with respect to the cache. Given the degree that Rust passes by value, this makes some sense, but much more study is merited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth mentioning that there are some easy wins that will make the Rust implementation even faster: after I had publicized the fact that I had a Rust implementation of statemaps working, I was delighted when &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dtolnay&quot;&gt;David Tolnay&lt;/a&gt;, one of the authors of Serde, took the time to make some &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joyent/statemap/pull/40#issuecomment-418230756&quot;&gt;excellent suggestions for improvement&lt;/a&gt;. For a newcomer like me, it’s a great feeling to have someone with such deep expertise as David’s take an interest in helping me make my software perform even better — and it is revealing as to the core values of the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust’s shockingly good performance — and the community’s desire to make it even better — fundamentally changed my disposition towards it: instead of seeing Rust as a language to &lt;em&gt;augment&lt;/em&gt; C and replace dynamic languages, I’m looking at it as a language to &lt;em&gt;replace&lt;/em&gt; both C and dynamic languages in all but the very lowest layers of the stack. C — like assembly — will continue to have a very important place for me, but it’s hard to not see that place as getting much smaller relative to the barnstorming performance of Rust!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Beyond the first impressions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t want to imply that this is an exhaustive list of everything that I have fallen in love with about Rust. That list is much longer would include at least the ownership model; the trait system; Cargo; the type inference system. And I feel like I have just scratched the surface; I haven’t waded into known strengths of Rust like the FFI and the concurrency model! (Despite having &lt;a href=&quot;https://queue.acm.org/detail.cfm?id=1454462&quot;&gt;written plenty of multithreaded code in my life&lt;/a&gt;, I haven’t so much as created a thread in Rust!)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building a future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can say with confidence that my future is in Rust. As I have spent my career doing OS kernel development, a natural question would be: do I intend to rewrite the OS kernel in Rust? In a word, no. To understand my reluctance, take some of my most recent experience: this blog entry was delayed because I needed to debug (and fix) &lt;a href=&quot;https://smartos.org/bugview/OS-7121&quot;&gt;a nasty problem with our implementation of the Linux ABI&lt;/a&gt;. As it turns out, Linux and SmartOS make slightly different guarantees with respect to the interaction of vfork and signals, and our code was fatally failing on a condition that should be impossible. Any old Unix hand (or quick study!) will tell you that vfork and signal disposition are each semantic superfund sites in their own right — and that their horrific (and ill-defined) confluence can only be unimaginably toxic. But the real problem is that actual software implicitly depends on these semantics — and any operating system that is going to want to run existing software will itself have to mimic them. You don’t want to write this code, because no one wants to write this code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, one option (which I honor!) is to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redox-os.org/&quot;&gt;rewrite the OS from scratch&lt;/a&gt;, as if legacy applications essentially didn’t exist. While there is a tremendous amount of good that can come out of this (and it can find many use cases), it’s not a fit for me personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while I may not want to rewrite the OS kernel in Rust, I &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; think that Rust is an excellent fit for much of the broader system. For example, at the recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://open-zfs.org/wiki/OpenZFS_Developer_Summit&quot;&gt;OpenZFS Developers Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Matt Ahrens and I were noodling the notion of user-level components for ZFS in Rust. Specifically: &lt;a href=&quot;https://illumos.org/man/1m/zdb&quot;&gt;zdb&lt;/a&gt; is badly in need of a rewrite — and Rust would make an excellent candidate for it. There are many such examples spread throughout ZFS and the broader the system, including a few in kernel. Might we want to have a device driver model that allows for Rust drivers? Maybe! (And certainly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johalun/status/983645780509712384&quot;&gt;it’s technically possible&lt;/a&gt;.) In any case, you can count on a lot more Rust from me and into the indefinite future — whether in the OS, near the OS, or above the OS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taking your own plunge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote all of this up in part to not only explain why I took the plunge, but to encourage others to take their own. If you were as I was and are contemplating diving into Rust, a couple of pieces of advice, for whatever they’re worth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I would recommend getting both &lt;em&gt;The Rust Programming Language&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Programming Rust&lt;/em&gt;. They are each excellent in their own right, and different enough to merit owning both. I also found it very valuable to have two different sources on subjects that were particularly thorny.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand ownership before you start to write code. The more you understand ownership in the abstract, the less you’ll have to learn at the merciless hands of compiler error messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get in the habit of running &lt;tt&gt;rustc&lt;/tt&gt; on short programs. Cargo is terrific, but I personally have found it very valuable to write short Rust programs to understand a particular idea — especially when you want to understand optional or new features of the compiler. (Roll on, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-roadmap-2017/issues/16&quot;&gt;non-lexical lifetimes&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be careful about porting something to Rust as a first project — or otherwise implementing something you’ve implemented before. Now, obviously, this is exactly what I did, and it can certainly be incredibly valuable to be able to compare an implementation in Rust to an implementation in another language — but it can also cut against you: the fact that I had implemented statemaps in C sent me down some paths that were right for C but wrong for Rust; I made much better progress when I rethought the implementation of my problem the way Rust wanted me to think about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrustacean.com/&quot;&gt;New Rustacean podcast&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chriskrycho&quot;&gt;Chris Krycho&lt;/a&gt;. I have really enjoyed Chris’s podcasts, and have been working my way through them when commuting or doing household chores. I particularly enjoyed his &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrustacean.com/show_notes/interview/_1/index.html&quot;&gt;interview with Sean Griffen&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrustacean.com/show_notes/interview/_3/index.html&quot;&gt;interview with Carol Nichols&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rustlings/rustlings&quot;&gt;rustlings&lt;/a&gt;. I learned about this a little too late for me; I wish I had known about it earlier! I did work through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/crazymykl/rust-koans&quot;&gt;Rust koans&lt;/a&gt;, which I enjoyed and would recommend for the first few hours with Rust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m sure that there’s a bunch of stuff that I missed; if there’s a particular resource that you found useful when learning Rust, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/messages/compose?recipient_id=173630577&quot;&gt;message me&lt;/a&gt; or leave a comment here and I’ll add it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me close by offering a sincere thanks to those in the Rust community who have been working so long to develop such a terrific piece of software — and especially those who have worked so patiently to explain their work to us newcomers. You should be proud of what you’ve accomplished, both in terms of a revolutionary technology and a welcoming community — thank you for inspiring so many of us about what infrastructure software can become, and I look forward to many years of implementing in Rust!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 22:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>irfansharif</dc:creator>
<og:image>http://dtrace.org/blogs/ahl/files/2011/10/icon.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://dtrace.org/blogs/bmc/2018/09/18/falling-in-love-with-rust/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Woman Rides Bicycle to 183.9 MPH, a New World Record</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/2018/09/18/649221471/woman-rides-bicycle-to-183-9-mph-a-new-world-record</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/2018/09/18/649221471/woman-rides-bicycle-to-183-9-mph-a-new-world-record</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res649232465&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/09/18/gettyimages-1034525506_slide-b711a655e3bc9a1de0f473f177a46641ce6ebea2-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/09/18/gettyimages-1034525506_slide-b711a655e3bc9a1de0f473f177a46641ce6ebea2-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denise Mueller-Korenek rode a custom bike at an average of 183.932 miles per hour – shattering a world record that had stood since 1995. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Matt Ben Stone/Action Plus via Getty Images&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Matt Ben Stone/Action Plus via Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/09/18/gettyimages-1034525506_slide-b711a655e3bc9a1de0f473f177a46641ce6ebea2-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Denise Mueller-Korenek rode a custom bike at an average of 183.932 miles per hour – shattering a world record that had stood since 1995.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Matt Ben Stone/Action Plus via Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fastest human to ride a bicycle over open ground is named Denise Mueller-Korenek, who rode a custom bike at an average of 183.932 miles per hour – shattering a world record that had stood since 1995.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mueller-Korenek, 45, set the new record for fastest speed riding in a slipstream, teaming up with Shea Holbrook, a professional race car driver who piloted a dragster that led the cyclist across the Bonneville Salt Flats in Utah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Good job, Mom,&quot; Mueller-Korenek's son, Daniel, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/FireCycle/videos/262786141039440/UzpfSTI5OTIxODU0MzYyMDgyNDo5MzM1NzU3ODY4NTE3NjA/&quot;&gt;said in a video he recorded&lt;/a&gt; as he joined his mother in the finish area on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;That was rough,&quot; she said. In addition to getting bounced around at speeds only supercars can aspire to, Mueller-Korenek said the salt dust had entirely coated her throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dragster has fairing on the back that essentially looks like a closet, to protect the cyclist from the wind. Behind it, Mueller-Korenek sat on a bike with gearing so steep that she needed to be towed to around 100 mph before taking over under her own power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tow rope was released some 1.5 miles into the run, Mueller-Korenek said on Facebook, &quot;leaving 3.5 miles in the draft to achieve an average speed for the last mile of 183.9mph (between mile 4 &amp;amp; 5)!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once they finished that phase of the run, the danger of a calamitous fall wasn't over: Holbrook and Mueller-Korenek had to work in tandem to slow down some 70 mph over a final mile, to reach an exit speed of 110 mph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res649235585&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage177468359&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2013/04/16/177468359/one-gear-one-mission-bike-is-good-to-100-mph-builder-says&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/thetwo-way\/2013\/04\/16\/177468359\/one-gear-one-mission-bike-is-good-to-100-mph-builder-says&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2013/04/16/donhou_sq-645c6af753d87207e9d855f83af7d24bd3a87f04-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2013/04/16/donhou_sq-645c6af753d87207e9d855f83af7d24bd3a87f04-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;One Gear, One Goal: Bike Is 'Good To 100 MPH,' Builder Says&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feat may cause &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/world-records/fastest-bicycle-speed-(in-slipstream)&quot;&gt;Guinness World Records&lt;/a&gt; to changes its categories, which currently separate bicycle speed records by gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mueller-Korenek had previously set the women's speed record on a bike, with a mark of 147.74 mph in 2016. For that effort, Holbrook was at the wheel of a highly modified Range Rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From her teenage years, Mueller-Korenek was a champion cyclist. She had top-three finishes more than a dozen times at the national and world levels. But she retired early from that career, leaving competitive racing to run a home security business and start a family. She set her sights on speed records a few years ago, after reuniting with John Howard, her former coach who had himself gone from being a decorated cyclist to racing behind dragsters, some 30 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they targeted the overall record, their team revamped the same dragster that was used to set the men's record. Dutch cyclist Fred Rompelberg, the now-previous record holder, had gone 167 mph behind the car in 1995.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mueller-Korenek and Holbrook obliterated that record this weekend, with a gripping ride during the World of Speed event held at the Salt Flats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The ride of her life and the drive of mine,&quot; Holbrook said in an Instagram post about the feat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrating the successful record attempt, Holbrook shouted, &quot;Where's our margarita? We have the salt.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moments after the run, the news that she had obliterated the land speed record for a paced cyclist drew a stunned response from Mueller-Korenek — who also noted that it was a higher speed than they were supposed to aim for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Oh shoot,&quot; she said in her son's video. &quot;We weren't supposed to go more than 175. Well, we aren't going to be let back out, probably.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I think we broke the limit of what we were supposed to do,&quot; she told Holbrook later, laughing as she hugged family members, friends and support staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As she and Holbrook embraced, Mueller-Korenek added, &quot;You had to go for it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moments later, Holbrook yelled out into the open air of the Salt Flats, &quot;Beat that, Fred!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 22:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coryfklein</dc:creator>
<og:title>Woman Rides Bicycle To 183.9 MPH — A New World Record</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/2018/09/18/649221471/woman-rides-bicycle-to-183-9-mph-a-new-world-record</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Denise Mueller-Korenek, 45, has become the fastest human ever to ride a bicycle over open ground, racing in the draft provided by a dragster.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/09/18/gettyimages-1034525506_wide-91aa9ed43ecc7ed3da167f5bc5c7d1036209e90b.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/2018/09/18/649221471/woman-rides-bicycle-to-183-9-mph-a-new-world-record</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Evernote just slashed 54 jobs, or 15 percent of its workforce</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/18/evernote-just-slashed-54-jobs-or-15-percent-of-its-workforce/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/18/evernote-just-slashed-54-jobs-or-15-percent-of-its-workforce/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that &lt;a href=&quot;https://evernote.com/&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;, the productivity app that lets people take notes and organize other files from their working and non-work life, has been trying to regain its former footing as one of the most popular apps in the U.S., and that doing so has been an ongoing struggle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just two weeks ago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/04/evernote-lost-its-cto-cfo-cpo-and-hr-head-in-the-last-month-as-it-eyes-another-fundraise/&quot;&gt;we reported&lt;/a&gt; that Evernote had lost several of its most senior executives, including its CTO Anirban Kundu, CFO Vincent Toolan, CPO Erik Wrobel and head of HR Michelle Wagner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Chris O’Neill — who took over as CEO of &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/evernote&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;evernote&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; in 2015 after running the business operations at the Google X research unit — is sharing more demoralizing news with employees. To wit, he’s firing dozens of them. At an an all-hands meeting earlier today, he told gathered staffers that Evernote has no choice but to lay off 54 people —  roughly 15 percent of the company’s workforce — and to focus its efforts instead around specific functions, including product development and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve reached out to the company for more information about what the move means for Evernote. [Update below.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, this newest development certainly doesn’t &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; encouraging. In fact, a person who tipped TechCrunch off to the executive departures two weeks ago characterized Evernote as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/04/evernote-lost-its-cto-cfo-cpo-and-hr-head-in-the-last-month-as-it-eyes-another-fundraise/&quot;&gt;in a death spiral&lt;/a&gt;,” saying that user growth and active users have been flat for the last six years and that the company’s enterprise product offering hasn’t caught on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that in addition to shoring up its ranks, Evernote may soon be facing a funding shortage, if these layoffs were’t prompted by one. The company has raised nearly $300 million over the years, including from Sequoia Capital, New Enterprise Associates, and T. Rowe Price, but the last round it raised, according to Pitchbook, was a $6 million mezzanine round that closed in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about what happened today via a note that O’Neill just sent to staffers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;50&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who missed our All Hands today, I have some difficult news to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of an ongoing evaluation of our business, we’ve decided to make a tough, but necessary decision to set Evernote up for future success. We’ll be saying goodbye to 54 talented and dedicated people, each of whom has contributed to Evernote’s mission. This was an extremely difficult decision and one that we did not take lightly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you’ve heard me say during the past few months, I set incredibly aggressive goals for the year. We’ve grown significantly this year, but at the same time we invested too far ahead of that growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must adjust quickly when part of our strategy is not meeting our expectations. Going forward, we’re streamlining certain functions and will continue to make investments to speed up and scale others, like product development and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand that today’s news may cause concern. We need to remember our amazing community of people who rely on our products and believe in our mission. Together, we have built a product that serves over 225 million people around the world who trust us with more than 9 billion notes containing their most important thoughts, ideas, and inspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I discussed in All-Hands, Evernote grew over 20% in the first half this year and we are in a stable financial position. Our Q3 revenue numbers remain strong and we expect to end the quarter north of $27 million. We have over $30 million in cash on our balance sheet and will exit 2018 generating more cash than we spend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though today is hard, this is the right decision for the business and the best way for us to invest in our future. For those friends and colleagues impacted today, we’ll be providing severance and other benefits to support them in their transition. We’ll have a series of AMAs to answer your questions that were not addressed today. As always, feel free to contact me with your questions. Tomorrow, I will publicly address our customers, partners and community on our blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: We’ve just been in touch with Evernote. It pointed us to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://evernote.com/blog/2018-09-18-message-from-ceo/&quot;&gt;newly posted piece&lt;/a&gt; by O’Neill in which he outlines the company’s strategy going forward, which includes to “operate with a more focused leadership team,” to “operate more efficiently,” and to “double down on product development —  both quality and velocity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for its funding situation, an Evernote representative insists that things are far from dire. The company is not fundraising, says this person; further, we’re told Evernote has $30 million on its balance sheet and will exit the year without burning cash.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 21:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Oystersaremyfav</dc:creator>
<og:title>Evernote just slashed 54 jobs, or 15 percent of its workforce</og:title>
<og:description>It’s no secret that Evernote, the productivity app that lets people take notes and organize other files from their working and non-work life, has been trying to regain its former footing as one of the most popular apps in the U.S., and that doing so has been an ongoing struggle. Just two week…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/evernote.jpg?w=617</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/09/18/evernote-just-slashed-54-jobs-or-15-percent-of-its-workforce/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/18/evernote-just-slashed-54-jobs-or-15-percent-of-its-workforce/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iOS 12, reviewed</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/09/ios-12-thoroughly-reviewed/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/09/ios-12-thoroughly-reviewed/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-header-800x450.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iOS 12 on an iPhone X.&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-header.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; iOS 12 on an iPhone X.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a aria-describedby=&quot;112 posters participating, including story author.&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/09/ios-12-thoroughly-reviewed/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;173&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple's iOS 12 software update is available today for supported iPhone, iPad, and iPod touch devices, and on the surface, it looks like one of the smallest new iOS releases Apple has pushed out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't a surprise; Apple said earlier this year that iOS 12 would be more about performance and stability than adding new features. Some major additions that were originally planned—like an overhauled home screen—were reportedly delayed to a later release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it's also not a bad thing. Frankly, iOS 11 had some problems. Apple released several small updates in late 2017 and throughout 2018 to fix those problems, all while battling some frustrated customers' perceptions that the company was deliberately making older devices obsolete to encourage new sales as overall smartphone sales slowed their growth industry-wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;And while Apple is pushing some fairly radical and unproven new ideas on the hardware side, first with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/11/iphone-x-review-early-adopting-the-future/&quot;&gt;iPhone X&lt;/a&gt; and now the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/09/hands-on-with-the-iphone-xs-iphone-xs-max-and-iphone-xr/&quot;&gt;iPhone XS, XS Max, and XR&lt;/a&gt;, it makes sense to take a breather and focus on addressing those complaints from users and pundits in iOS 12. That's what a lot of iOS 12 is about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there's more to iOS 12 than the average user will notice. It adds or expands upon a few ways for third-party developers to make different kinds of apps or to tap into the work Apple has done on Siri, machine learning, or augmented reality to bring new capabilities to those apps. iOS 12 also adds new features to Apple's own apps—and many of those features are driven by the company's machine-learning efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple is a changing company, and its priorities in iOS tell us a lot about what it's angling for in the near (and not-so-near) future. There's more value to this exercise than just navel-gazing: examining iOS 12 can help reveal whether the iPhone and iPad will be there for you not just now, but in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let's see what we can learn from several weeks with the iOS 12 beta and the final golden master release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-no-jump=&quot;&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Compatibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At WWDC 2018, Apple tried to position this as an update that's as much for older devices as for new ones. And it's true—almost everything iOS 12 adds works on the iPhone 5S in addition to the iPhone 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is also to improve slow performance on older devices—something for which Apple has often been criticized. When users confirmed that Apple was throttling performance on older devices to preserve battery life and stop unwanted shutdowns, detractors were quick to argue that it showed Apple deliberately limiting the shelf life of iPhones to get consumers to buy new devices. Apple denied this, and offered &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/02/apple-was-right-to-throttle-iphones-but-some-things-still-need-to-change/&quot;&gt;compelling arguments behind its throttling decision&lt;/a&gt;. (The company also offered a discounted &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/01/your-old-iphone-battery-can-be-replaced-even-if-it-passes-genius-bar-test/&quot;&gt;battery replacement program&lt;/a&gt; to address the issue on affected iPhones.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, iOS 12 seeks to improve performance even on older devices with healthy batteries. In our tests, we found that Apple succeeded on that front—but that the performance gains vary depending on the specific device. We'll explore that more shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, here are the models of iPhone, iPad, and iPod touch supported by iOS 12, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ios/ios-12-preview/&quot;&gt;according to Apple&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Supported iPhone models&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;iPhone X&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone 8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone 8 Plus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone 7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone 7 Plus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone 6S&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone 6S Plus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone 6 Plus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone SE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone 5S&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Supported iPad models&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;12.9-inch iPad Pro 2nd generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12.9-inch iPad Pro 1st generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10.5-inch iPad Pro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9.7-inch iPad Pro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad 6th generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad 5th generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad Air 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad Air&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad mini 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad mini 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad mini 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Supported iPod models&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;iPod touch 6th generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Basically, iOS 12 supports every device that iOS 11 supported. Now let's start exploring the new features in iOS 12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might notice the changes to notifications first. They're all about presentation; there haven't been any changes to how notifications work at a basic level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple notifications from one app can now be grouped together in both the lock screen and the notification center. Tapping on one of these groups will expand them out so you can access them individually. When you do this, there's a button you can tap to collapse back up to the grouping again (&quot;show less&quot;) and another button to dismiss all the notifications in the group at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three configurations for this feature in the notifications section of the iOS 12 Settings app: automatic, by app, and off. It defaults to automatic. In this case, notifications from one app will generally be grouped together, but, for not entirely transparent reasons, iOS might intelligently decide not to in some cases. By app makes sure that every single notification you get from an app is grouped together no matter what. Off obviously disables the feature and returns notifications to their pre-iOS 12 behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, some of us have a lot of apps that send a lot of notifications, so this feature is very welcome. I would have liked to have been able to customize it a bit more, though. The automatic setting is too opaque; developers can make their apps break out notifications into two or more groups instead of one, but the user won't always know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-1-lock-screen-a-150x150.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-1-lock-screen-a.jpg&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-1-lock-screen-a-980x2122.jpg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-1-lock-screen-a.jpg 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376285&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Multiple notifications from the same app can now be grouped together on the home screen.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-2-center-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-2-center.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-2-center-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-2-center.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376279&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;You'll see the same in the notification center.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-3-expanded-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-3-expanded.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-3-expanded-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-3-expanded.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376277&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Tapping on a grouping will expand to the individual notifications. You can tap &quot;show less&quot; to collapse again or tap the X to dismiss all the notifications from that group at once.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-manage-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-manage.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-manage-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-manage.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376275&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Holding down on a notification and then tapping a &quot;...&quot; icon will bring up these settings. You can tweak your notifications settings from here without going into the Settings app. You can also reach these options by swiping on a notification and tapping &quot;manage.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-5-tapback-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-5-tapback.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-5-tapback-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Notifications-5-tapback.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376291&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;You can use Tapback quick replies on notifications without opening the Messages app now, too.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also now hold down on a notification, then tap a settings button to bring up some new options for managing your notification settings right from the lock screen or notification center. That means that you either turn off notifications from certain apps, or you can configure them to &quot;deliver quietly.&quot; The latter makes it so they appear in the notification center, but they don't appear in the lock screen, present a banner, play a sound, or add a notification badge to the app. Apple calls this feature &quot;Instant Tuning.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few other small notifications improvements, too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can now use Messages Tapback quick replies from the lock screen or notification center, although this is not very intuitive. Previously you could only do this in the Messages app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App developers can now add their own similar custom user interactions to notifications directly in the lock screen or notifications center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps can now send notifications quietly to the notification center on a provisional basis without the user opting in. In this case, a notification would not appear in the lock screen or make a sound but it would quietly sit in the notification center. When the user sees it, they are given the opportunity to approve or deny future notifications like it on the spot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iOS uses machine learning to study how you manage your notifications and recommends how to deliver notifications in the future based on that. For example, it might recommend that you disable notifications from a certain app if you're never engaging with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now opt in to &quot;critical alerts,&quot; which ignore all restrictions like Do Not Disturb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Siri and Shortcuts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple dedicated a lot of its resources to making Siri more powerful in iOS 12. Most of this work is related to a new feature called Shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortcuts allow for custom types of Siri interactions, either as part of third-party apps or in a new app called Shortcuts that lets you create your own and add them to Siri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most users, the most relevant thing will be the developer angle. Developers have not had this kind of access to Siri in the past. Now you can access any number of common app actions from anywhere in the OS to a degree that was not previously possible, and Siri will recommend them to you at opportune moments by sending you notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combined with notifications' support for custom interactions for third-party apps, this adds up to a lot of potential. You're going to start seeing apps asking you to add Shortcuts to Siri that work off those apps' features. Developers can also prompt users to record Siri phrases to map to Shortcuts right inside their apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this is more about Siri as a smart suggester of things in notifications than it is about voice commands, but you can manually map voice commands to Shortcuts to your heart's content. In one example, a third-party music app like Spotify could use Shortcuts to enable playing music in that app with Siri—something users have long complained was not possible. Spotify developers would have to write new code and release an update to support it, but it is possible. It would still be more limited than the Apple Music Siri integration, though, and would require users to create their own custom phrases for specific content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortcuts is just the latest in a series of efforts by Apple to make third-party support about more than the user going into standalone apps. We saw that with Messages and Stickers, and Shortcuts works in a similar way. It's also the first of many features we'll examine in iOS 12 that are meant mainly to encourage movement in the developer community. Apple knows that the App Store is iOS' best asset, and adding ways for developers to create new experiences is one of the main strategies behind this year's update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So like a lot of features in iOS 12, Shortcuts depend on outside developer support to become fully useful for most users. But in the interim, you can create your own Shortcuts until that support comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Shortcuts app&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That brings us to the app, which isn't installed by default. Once you install it, you'll see a lot of DNA from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://workflow.is&quot;&gt;Workflow&lt;/a&gt; app, which Apple &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/03/apple-snaps-up-workflow-an-ios-automation-app-for-power-users/&quot;&gt;acquired last year&lt;/a&gt;, in Shortcuts. Like Workflow, it allows you to define a series of steps across multiple apps and iOS services. You can map those steps to a Siri voice command, and you can also share Shortcuts with contacts or add a Shortcut to the home screen, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shortcuts app basically allows you to automate complex tasks with a library of actions that relate not just to Apple services and apps, but to third-party apps as well (provided developers of those apps support it). You can then pepper access to that automation throughout the OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shortcuts app has a gallery of pre-made Shortcuts that you can activate. Those Shortcuts can be examined as models for how best to use the application, or you can modify them directly for your own unique use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating your own Shortcuts, you can work with data from the Health app, the motion sensors, location services, GPS, the clock, and so much more. And that's just at launch, with most of the options coming from Apple's own apps and services. It's kind of boggling to imagine what you could do if most popular apps in the App Store eventually supported this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-1-Library-empty-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-1-Library-empty.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-1-Library-empty-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-1-Library-empty.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376619&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;When you first open Shortcuts, you're greeted with an empty list of your created Shortcuts and the option to either create one or navigate to the gallery to discover pre-made ones.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-2-Gallery-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-2-Gallery.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-2-Gallery-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-2-Gallery.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376617&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This is the gallery. It looks a bit like the App Store.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-3-Gallery-category-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-3-Gallery-category.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-3-Gallery-category-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-3-Gallery-category.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376615&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;You can drill down further for recommended Shortcuts on certain aspects of using your phone. Here: Music.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-4-blank-shortcut-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-4-blank-shortcut.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-4-blank-shortcut-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-4-blank-shortcut.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376613&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Going back to the first screen, we can start creating a Shortcut. We're offered &quot;Help,&quot; or we can just start searching for actions and behaviors to add.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-5-list-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-5-list.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-5-list-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-5-list.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376607&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This is just a small slice of the very long list of things you can add to your Shortcut.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-4-create-Shortcut-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-4-create-Shortcut.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-4-create-Shortcut-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-4-create-Shortcut.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376609&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Here's a Shortcut in progress. The goal is to make my phone play &quot;Hollywood&quot; by Madonna when I'm driving on Hollywood Blvd. It's not finished yet; it will take some doing and trial and error for first-time users.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-6-Settings-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-6-Settings.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-6-Settings-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-6-Settings.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376603&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This is the settings panel for your Shortcut, where you can name it, add it to Siri, and more.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-7-glyph-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-7-glyph.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-7-glyph-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-7-glyph.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376611&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;You can customize the icon for the Shortcut.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-8-sharing-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-8-sharing.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-8-sharing-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Shortcuts-8-sharing.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376605&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;You can also share the Shortcut by various means.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could spend an entire article going over the various things you can do with Shortcuts. It's a powerful app with vast possibilities. The downside is that it's complicated enough that most people will likely decline to make their own Shortcuts. But expect many future Google searches turning up various articles and forum posts with step-by-step guides to Shortcut magic so that even those who don't want to completely learn it will eventually get some benefit if they're willing to dig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Siri Suggestions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siri Suggestions have been around in one form or another for a couple of years, but they are greatly expanded in iOS 12. Previously you might get recommendations like &quot;Siri Suggested Websites&quot; when typing in search queries, but now they are more powerful, and you'll find them in new places. This is most promising when you think about how it might work with third-party apps, and much of what's new here is thus tied to Shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you always order food in the GrubHub app on the way home from work every day, and if the app developers behind GrubHub choose to put in the work to add support for this, you might start seeing notifications around 5:30pm asking if you want to order your usual from GrubHub. In another example, your calendar app of choice could have a record that a meeting starts in five minutes, but you're obviously not going to make it in time. Siri might then suggest sending a pre-canned message about how you're going to be late to the meeting organizer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users of the iOS 12 beta have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/i/web/status/1005126718900797440&quot;&gt;noticing and sharing&lt;/a&gt; expressions of this feature for months. For instance, in some cases Siri reads your Messages and notices if you're talking about having lunch with someone. Even if you don't create a calendar event, Siri might remember that you planned a lunch and remind you to turn on Do Not Disturb before the lunch starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this could be useful, but it could also get annoying very quickly. You'll have to put in some time managing which suggestions and Shortcuts you want and which ones you don't. But I have a feeling most people won't want to put in the time, so they'll either leave everything on and thus experience a barrage throughout the day of recommendations that range from very helpful to senselessly irritating... or, they'll just turn them off completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Shortcuts, this is a power-user feature. If you really understand it and want to invest time and energy into managing permissions and creating custom actions, I can see it being quite useful. If you don't, it's not that attractive—though I think it could be a big deal for accessibility for those with certain disabilities. And it becomes all the more powerful when you factor in Shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, a lot of this draws on similar features Google has been including in Android for a while now. But, to harp on a running theme you'll find in this iOS 12 review, Apple is trying to communicate to users that this is different because of how it handles your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple says that all the processing is done locally on your device and that it's encrypted, so you're not sharing tons of data about your habits and activities with Apple. As in almost all cases with iOS involving machine learning, Apple's approach is arguably more attractive for privacy hawks, but the effectiveness of the feature isn't always going to be as strong as what you might see on competing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Siri changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few more minor changes that relate to Siri, too, like the ability to say &quot;Hey Siri&quot; in low power mode. There are two new accents (South African and Irish), you can ask Siri to show you your passwords in the password manager, turn on the flashlight, find your other Apple devices, translate phrases between new language pairs, and search Memories in Photos. Siri can also answer more questions about celebrities and food or about topics like motorsports, which wasn't previously supported at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-1-translation-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-1-translation.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-1-translation-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-1-translation.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376583&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;You can now translate into several new languages from English, including Japanese, Russian, Arabic, and Portuguese. There are other new non-English pairings, too. (This translation is wrong, by the way.)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-2-Flashlight-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-2-Flashlight.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-2-Flashlight-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-2-Flashlight.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376589&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;You can activate or deactivate the flashlight.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-3-food-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-3-food.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-3-food-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-3-food.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376587&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;You can ask questions about food, like nutrition information.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-Siri-Misc-3a-celebrity-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-Siri-Misc-3a-celebrity.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-Siri-Misc-3a-celebrity-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-Siri-Misc-3a-celebrity.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376581&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Or you can learn more about your favorite celebrities.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-4-motorsports-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-4-motorsports.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-4-motorsports-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-4-motorsports.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376591&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Motorsports have been added to the supported sports for questions, though I had very mixed results with this one.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-5-find-my-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-5-find-my.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-5-find-my-980x2122.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-Siri-Misc-5-find-my.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1376585&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;You can also search for your supported Apple devices.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Samuel Axon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 19:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tomduncalf</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/09/ios-12-thoroughly-reviewed/</og:url>
<og:title>iOS 12, thoroughly reviewed</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/iOS-12-header-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Apple's OS focuses on performance and laying the groundwork for future apps.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/09/ios-12-thoroughly-reviewed/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Puerto Rico Became a Tax Haven for the Super Rich</title>
<link>https://www.gq.com/story/how-puerto-rico-became-tax-haven-for-super-rich</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gq.com/story/how-puerto-rico-became-tax-haven-for-super-rich</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-heading&quot; data-reactid=&quot;97&quot; readability=&quot;35.382653061224&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;component-responsive-image photo-essay-hero&quot; data-component=&quot;ResponsiveImage&quot; data-reactid=&quot;99&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A illustration of a bunch of rich people partying in Puerto Rico.&quot; class=&quot;component-responsive-image-img&quot; src=&quot;https://media.gq.com/photos/5ba0227a8ce6d805ca628b95/16:9/w_1600/Puerto-Rico-Very-The-Newest-Haven-For-The-Super-Rich-GQ-Oct-101118-01.jpg&quot; data-reactid=&quot;106&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; data-reactid=&quot;108&quot;&gt;Illustration by Kagan Mcleod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;component-rubric rubric-link&quot; data-reactid=&quot;110&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best of GQ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;byline-container&quot; data-reactid=&quot;123&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;component-byline byline display-name&quot; data-reactid=&quot;129&quot;&gt;

&lt;time class=&quot;publish-date&quot; data-reactid=&quot;135&quot;&gt;23 hours ago&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;dek&quot; data-reactid=&quot;136&quot;&gt;A year after the tragedy of Hurricane Maria, the 51st state has become the favorite playground for extremely wealthy Americans looking to keep their money from the taxman. The only catch? They have to cut all ties to the mainland (wink, wink).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;137&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The party known as Cocktails and Compliance&lt;/strong&gt;—so called for mixing alcohol with tax advice—was thrown on a Friday evening in May, in a warehouse turned art gallery in Old San Juan. The host had kept his guest list confidential: It contained the names of hundreds of ultra-wealthy mainland Americans who'd moved to Puerto Rico to avoid paying taxes, most of whom were reluctant to advertise that fact. More than 1,500 mainlanders have established residency here since 2012, when the island rebranded itself as a tax haven, and the annual Cocktails is at the center of their social calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;138&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a high table, polishing off a bourbon on the rocks, sat a compact man in his 60s wearing a black T-shirt and black suede loafers, no socks. This was Mark Gold, the Florida-born kingpin of traffic-ticket contesting. Gold has attended Cocktails and Compliance every year since moving to Puerto Rico in 2016. “I was looking at different tax havens,” he said, “Andorra, Lichtenstein, Monaco. But the problem is, you have to give up your U.S. passport. When I heard about this, it was too good to be true. But it's real. I live in paradise. I live at the Ritz-Carlton. I drive my golf cart to the beach club for breakfast. Then I go to my sunset yoga class on the beach.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;139&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A waiter offered to replace his drink. “Why not?” said Gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;140&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only seven months had passed since Hurricane Maria laid waste to the island's power grid, and one month remained until hurricane season returned. A reliable estimate placed the death toll at 4,600; 11,000 still reportedly lacked electricity. Residents were showering with pots and plastic cups. In Manhattan, a federal judge was trying to mediate between the various hedge funds that held billions of dollars of the island's debt. Every so often the MIT-educated governor went on television to extol the virtues of austerity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;141&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In San Juan, the recovery had been notably uneven. Brand-new shopping centers abutted hotels that looked arsonized; traffic lights stared dead-eyed into the street; FEMA was shuttling relief supplies from the waterfront to staging areas. Inside Cocktails and Compliance, however, the atmosphere resembled the aftermath not of a natural disaster but of a corporate convention, with people who usually saw one another in the daytime gradually succumbing to alcohol and dim lighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;142&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the valet station, guests had entered a red-carpeted freight elevator, where bartenders poured them sangria. There were reasons to raise a toast. In 2012, Puerto Rico had passed two laws intended to make the island a “global investment destination.” Act 20 allows corporations that export services from the island to pay only 4 percent tax. Act 22 goes much further: It makes Puerto Rico the only place on U.S. soil where personal income, capital gains, interest, and dividends are untaxed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;143&quot; readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to qualify for Act 22, individuals must prove to the IRS that they have become bona fide residents of Puerto Rico, without “close contacts” on the mainland. (Most native Puerto Ricans are not eligible for the exemption.) At the party, I heard about a man who had lost his tax-free status because the IRS smoked out a wife back in Dallas. I asked Gold, 63, whether his wife had moved along with him. “Now, this is where the colorful-character shit comes in,” he said. “My third wife, she's 25. She was in college. I told her, ‘Babe, you gotta go to college in Puerto Rico, I'm really sorry. We have this opportunity that I &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; pass up. You can stay if you want, but if you stay, we gotta get divorced.’ ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;144&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the law requires him to spend at least 183 days a year on the island, Gold claimed he spends closer to 250. &lt;em&gt;“Soy boricua,”&lt;/em&gt; he said proudly—I am Puerto Rican.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;146&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The mainlanders who have relocated&lt;/strong&gt; are not quite &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt;-list billionaires, who have access to more complex tax strategies than leaving town; they belong to the middle class of the ultra-rich. They are new-money people who might not have their congressman's cell-phone number back home but who wield influence here in Puerto Rico. “Back in the States, I'm just one of 300 million voters,” James Slazas, a hedge-fund quant, told me at the party. “Here I've already met a lot of the key players.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;147&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seated nearby was Harry Dent, the best-selling finance writer, who established residency in Puerto Rico two years ago. Dent's latest book, &lt;em&gt;Zero Hour,&lt;/em&gt; foresees an imminent “economic winter season” that will eclipse the Great Recession, due in part to the shortage of consumers occasioned by the bottoming out of the birth rate in 1973. (The happy prospect of the boomer generation hurtling toward decrepitude makes him bullish on the health care sector, however.) Puerto Rico appealed to him because it was cheaper than Miami and offered excellent small airports. He also got to keep his American citizenship, though he had to give up his right to vote for president. This last bit didn't worry Dent in the slightest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;148&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I could give a flying fuck,” he said. “We've got a civil war going on. Red versus blue. We've got 4 percent unemployment, and I feel safer being here than in Miami or New York. The world's going to shit, and that doesn't mean Puerto Rico won't go down further. But they are already way down. Our bubble hasn't even burst yet.” Behind him waiters circulated silver trays of golden phyllo florets. A giant artwork on the wall showed a slave on a tobacco plantation, emerging from a background of gold leaf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;149&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little after eight o'clock, a tax consultant named David Marshall Nissman strode to the front of the room, where a lectern had been set up. Nissman used to be the U.S. attorney for the Virgin Islands. Today, he helps wealthy clients parry audits, which tax exiles regard with abject terror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;151&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To comply with Act 22, Nissman said, it all came down to what everyone called “making days.” If you spent fewer than 183 days a year on the island, the feds could recoup all the taxes you hadn't been paying. The good news was that there were a lot of ways to obey the letter, if not the spirit, of the law. There was the “one minute” rule: A single minute on the island counts as a full day, as far as the IRS is concerned. You can touch down your Learjet, get a receipt at the airport Starbucks, then continue on to the Virgin Islands for dinner. The local government could be accommodating as well: In 2017 all Puerto Rican tax exiles got a 117-day “award” due to Maria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;152&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Puerto Rican–born lawyer specializing in Act 22 compliance, who asked for anonymity to speak about his work, told me that he no longer represents clients seeking to relocate because “people were taking advantage.” He described a prospective Act 22 recipient saying, “ ‘I'll take my private jet and fly down; then I'll take my boat and go somewhere else. They won't know.’ ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;153&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Nissman warned against exactly such behavior, a slim man in a black blazer and jeans sat nearby with his hands folded in his lap. Robb Rill was the host of Cocktails and Compliance and the glue at the center of the tax-exile community. During the party, he observed his guests like an anxious football coach hoping a rowdy busful of athletes will refrain from mooning the highway. And that was at the &lt;em&gt;beginning,&lt;/em&gt; while people were mostly sober.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;154&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open bar kept serving during dinner and through the lectures. Neckties loosened. In the middle of my interview with Mark Gold, Rill stopped by our table to caution him, “Once it's in print, it's in print.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;155&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This warning, of course, made it inevitable that Gold would demonstrate its wisdom. During a presentation on the Trump tax plan, Gold shot up his hand: “Is it true that we can now write off the purchase of a jet in one year?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;156&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No, no,” said Rill, almost inaudibly. But it was futile. All the pent-up energy in the room, stifled by the minutiae of the SALT deduction and the income-sourcing rule, unwound itself into cheering and applause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;157&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That is exactly the image,” said Rill, “that we are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; trying to portray.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;159&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robb Rill grew up in Florida&lt;/strong&gt; and made his money in private equity. In 2011 he and his wife, then a securities trader, went looking for tax havens. At first they settled on the Virgin Islands, selecting a house on the edge of a cliff. The house turned out to be a metaphor: Immediately after they found it, a dispute with a local official blew up their plan. A Google search led them to Puerto Rico and Act 22, and by 2013 they were here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;160&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rill invited me to his office for a “healthy yet delicious meal,” and I parked on a bright afternoon at an office building behind a Starbucks. Rill is 47 but looks younger, with his hair pulled back in a bun and a goatee framing a pale, tapered face. “I was one of the first ten people to actually move under Act 22,” he said, taking his seat in a red-walled conference room. “There was literally nobody here.” His accountant, Jorge Kuilan, sat to his left, wearing a paisley shirt and a cryptic smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;161&quot; readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rill wanted to convince me that the acts were an economic boon to the island. The “tax hacks”—as he called them—created jobs for Puerto Ricans, like Kuilan. (The acts together have created 12,000 new jobs, according to the government, out of a total workforce of 1.1 million.) Rill's 20/22 Act Society, the organization that hosts Cocktails and Compliance, also funded relief work after Maria. On weekends, he rescued street dogs; he had opened a shelter for them, on an old farm several miles outside the city. “We're trying to break the stereotype,” he said, of “a bunch of rich guys flying in on their private planes, helicoptering into their private walled resort.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout&quot; data-reactid=&quot;162&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout-embed-component inline-pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote-content&quot;&gt;During a presentation on the Trump tax plan, one audience member shot up his hand: “Is it true that we can now write off the purchase of a jet?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;163&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he spoke, his personal chef entered the conference room. She was carrying plates of branzino, lentils, zucchini, and mushrooms, prepared—Rill explained—according to the principles espoused in a dietary manual called &lt;em&gt;How Not to Die.&lt;/em&gt; Page 135 counsels the reader to drink hibiscus tea; Rill sipped a crimsony liquid from his thermos. “This may all be ridiculous,” he said, “but if it's true, I'll be healthy forever. It's an asymmetric trade, the kind of trade I like.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;164&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a rule, tax hackers in Puerto Rico live in one of two neighborhoods. Single people favor the beachfront in Condado, which has easy access to hotel bars and nightclubs. Married people like the Rills prefer Dorado Beach, where the Ritz-Carlton runs a hotel and residential enclave. In Dorado, the couple bought two units and combined them. “I'm told I have the largest condo on the island,” Rill said. “I'm in 8,000 square feet.” (The acts used to require that mainlanders buy property, but like most of their requirements—including a stipulation to employ five local residents—it was erased by subsequent revisions meant to entice more wealthy people to relocate.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;165&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rill was emphasizing his footprint because it demonstrated his investment in the island; no “close contacts” on the mainland for him. “Some people I know have tried to play fun and games,” he said. “We don't want the schemers here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;166&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rill assured me that I would find more people like him. I did find a few. Lauren Cascio, 30, moved to the island six years ago. There were incentives here she didn't have elsewhere, like a tax credit for manufacturing and the ability to hire from an incubator for Puerto Rican–born engineers. She's raised her two children here while starting a company, Abartys Health, which sells data-management software and employs ten local engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;167&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everyone I employ is Puerto Rican,” she said. “I live a Puerto Rican life. I'm not ‘making days.’ ” I asked whether she believed everyone should have to hire locals in order to get the exemption. “People here will hate me for saying this,” she said, “but they shouldn't have reduced the job requirement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;168&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also spoke with María del Mar Ortiz, a Puerto Rican native who left the island for college and eventually took a job in finance. A few years ago, she opened We Got This, a concierge-and-lifestyle business that caters to tax hackers. “It's a big opportunity for me,” she said. Her employees drive men like Rill and Gold, cook their meals, clean their bathrooms, help them furnish a new house. I asked how much of her business was attributable to the acts. One hundred percent, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;169&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Rill, Cascio, and Ortiz could speak convincingly about the positive effects of the tax policies, they were not the most ardent believers in Act 22. That distinction went to an independent stock trader I met named Lobo Tiggre. A slim man in middle age wearing silver bracelets and a black beard, he met me for a beer on the terrace at the Condado Vanderbilt Hotel. He and his wife had arrived as residents four minutes before midnight on December 31, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;170&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I believe it is my moral duty to minimize my taxes,” Tiggre said, and Act 22 was a legal way to pay the absolute least. Tiggre thought, indeed, that the privilege he enjoyed should be extended to everyone. Some things that taxes pay for, like the police and the military, he said could be supported through voluntary contributions. “If people are too stupid to voluntarily agree to band together and defend themselves,” he said, “then maybe they deserve to be conquered by Attila the Hun.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;173&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Serafina Beach Hotel in Condado&lt;/strong&gt; hosts a pool party every weekend that is popular with the younger tax hackers. Here the proprietor is Vittorio Assaf, the parodically charismatic restaurateur who made his name and fortune in New York City, opening Café Candiotti, with original paintings by Andy Warhol inside, in the '80s and establishing Serafina in 1995. He had been lured to Puerto Rico by John Paulson, a hedge-fund manager who'd bought up much of the real estate in Condado. “When John invited me, you know, he was trying to invent Puerto Rico,” Assaf said. (Paulson still lives in New York.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;174&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked if Act 22 had delivered on its promise of lifting the island's economic fortunes. “They come all the time, they spend money,” he said of tax hackers. “They buy apartments, they do investment on the island. I mean, I guess it's fantastic. If they didn't have these guys coming down, then there would be really big trouble.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;175&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were bottles of pink champagne in dewy silver buckets, a DJ, an infinity pool. Shimmy McHugh, a nightlife impresario from New York, was at a prime table, chatting with a friend, the Puerto Rican–born president of a water-filtration company. They surveyed the scene. “We lost, I have to say, 80 percent of our good-looking women in the last two years,” McHugh said. “Bad economy, and Maria was the icing on the cake.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;176&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For McHugh, Act 22 was essential, an unmitigated good. “See that guy right there?” he said. “Black shirt and khaki pants? Five million a year in the Internet affiliate-marketing space. This guy has no problem dropping four grand a night.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;177&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McHugh's friend agreed: “For a club owner or a promoter like Shimmy, it's good. You have this guy at a table, and he's spending that money, and you have other guys at another table. They start competing with each other.” I excused myself to go find a pack of cigarettes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;178&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the liquor store across the street, George Rivera, 29, was working his shift. He knew about the tax hackers but never saw them; they didn't do their own shopping, as far as he could tell. Rivera earned $7.25 an hour. “I pay 11.5 percent in taxes” plus a 30 percent markup on imports, he said. Yet the island was a mess. The power grid lay shattered, and hurricane season was on its way. “We need taxes from the &lt;em&gt;rich.&lt;/em&gt;” Rivera shook his head. It's like the rest of the U.S., he concluded: “It's the same shit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;181&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In San Juan,&lt;/strong&gt; I often heard some version of the following aphorism: “A few percent of something is better than 39 percent of nothing.” Meaning: “The few dollars we contribute in sales and property tax is better than the zero dollars we'd contribute if the incentives hadn't drawn us down here.” Peter Schiff, a libertarian podcast personality who moved to Puerto Rico after Act 22, put it bluntly: “Who would come to a bankrupt island to pay high income taxes?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;182&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Act 22 was only the latest tax incentive cooked up by the government. The economy here used to run on sugar, and when the price of sugar sank in the 1930s, the island began offering tax breaks to corporations that opened factories here. In the short term, the policy ignited a boom. Workers sewed clothing; StarKist canned tuna; factories churned out paper, cement, and glass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;183&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When manufacturing collapsed in the '70s, the federal government engineered a second boom by enticing pharmaceutical companies to relocate to the island. In 1989, Pfizer got $156,400 in tax breaks &lt;em&gt;per employee.&lt;/em&gt; By 2004, they were reportedly manufacturing 100 million Viagra pills a year in Barceloneta. But the tax break that supported those jobs was sunsetted by Congress in 2006, just in time for the Great Recession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout&quot; data-reactid=&quot;184&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout-embed-component inline-pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote-content&quot;&gt;She asked, “Are we on record?” When I said we were, she smiled, touched her sunglasses, and stared silently out the window.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;185&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sell Act 22, the secretary of economic development met privately with financiers in cities across the United States, and the government hosted investment summits in San Juan. At one event, in 2015, Rudy Giuliani gave the keynote address. Bloggers predicted the next Singapore, the next Dubai, the next Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;186&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manuel Laboy Rivera, the official currently in charge of the policy, told me, “The rationale is these individuals will never consider Puerto Rico in the first place, never consider bringing their capital and wealth on the island.” He stressed the importance of “bringing diversity,” people with “all kinds of backgrounds: investment bankers, consultants.” He has never turned down an application under Act 22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;187&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rafael Bernabe, a professor of literature at the University of Puerto Rico and two-time candidate for governor on the Working People's Party ticket, doubted the new laws would be any more durable than those that had come before: “They can't think of anything besides new versions of the same policy. ‘Let's try and invite wealthy people.’ That's a drop in the bucket. They will hire a few gardeners, create jobs for a few more waiters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;188&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabe suggested that the government has kept the initiatives hidden in gated communities and hotel conference rooms entirely by intention. “Having a little island of affluence in the midst of this crisis? The more hidden it is, the better. When people find out, they will say, ‘Motherfucker, why can't the government find some programs to help &lt;em&gt;me?&lt;/em&gt;’ ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;189&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well,” I said, “they claim a few percent of something is better than 39 percent of nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;190&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If I am a beggar in the street,” Bernabe shot back, “and they give me ‘something,’ I will say thank you. But it would be better if I wasn't a beggar.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;193&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was gray and spitting rain&lt;/strong&gt; when Mark Gold took me out in his golf cart in Dorado Beach, a lush and quiet development of 500 homes, some of which are managed by the Ritz-Carlton, invisible from the main road. Once a coconut and grapefruit plantation, Dorado Beach is now flooded with tax hackers; home prices doubled overnight after the passage of the acts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;194&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The guy I bought my house from paid one point three million,” Gold said. “I paid two point six. My property tax is $4,000 a year. They haven't re-assessed it since 1957.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;195&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;196&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mm-hmm. Go ahead and print that. Maybe they'll figure it out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;197&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We passed a trio of luxury-apartment towers. “This is called Plantation One, Two, and Three,” said Gold. “That's where Robb lives. He's got 8,000 square feet. I guess he needs that for him, his wife, and his dog.” We passed a water park where children were playing in the sunlight. “We've got two slides,” said Gold. “The slides are sick, man.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;198&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the drive back toward Gold's house, we skirted a wide green field where a helicopter was parked—the quickest way to the airport. A woman supervised her toddler, who was playing on the gleaming black machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;199&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked Gold, who was not on the island during Maria, how the hurricane had affected the area. “Half the island closed and didn't reopen,” he said. “Unfortunately the Ritz spa is closed. It was phenomenal. Part of our nature trail, too. It was like a tropical forest. It was hammered.” Even the Ritz hotel itself—where, for $999 a night, the rooms include dedicated butlers—remained closed, though in the aftermath of the storm, when much of the island wanted for fuel and emergency services, a private security force with firearms protected the Dorado Beach grounds, so nothing befell them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;202&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On one of my last afternoons in San Juan,&lt;/strong&gt; I met Brian Tenenbaum, a real estate developer. Tenenbaum moved here in 2014, looking for distressed buildings to buy and renovate. Starting from the Vanderbilt hotel, we took my rental car for a tour of his properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;203&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So you see,” Tenenbaum said as we bounced on spotty roads, through glitching streetlights. “Bombed out, bombed out, bombed out, bombed out, bombed out, bombed out, abandoned, abandoned. Here, we're fixing this up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;204&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across from the fenced-off waterfront, we saw several blocks of concrete skeletons. These, said Tenenbaum, were a new development project, located where a thousand public-housing units had previously been demolished. The new buildings would hold 200 or 300 larger apartments, some market-rate and some subsidized. “It's the new model of how you do affordable housing,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;205&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stopped at a white stucco building with rounded colonial edges, azure trim, and a terra-cotta roof. Tenenbaum's firm bought it out of foreclosure—the Puerto Rican owner lost the property during the crisis to a bank, which sold it to Tenenbaum's firm at a discount. Tenenbaum would lease the studios there for $1,800. He then took me to Santurce, a central neighborhood built around a wide tree-lined boulevard, to look at his potential pool of tenants. “See how it's getting lusher and green? This is where my office is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;206&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenenbaum's lunch date was a scout from a hedge fund who was here to meet with the Puerto Rican authorities about the government's bond debt. Most of the people who spoke with me for this article seemed unsure of how to talk to a reporter, and it was not uncommon to spend a relaxed afternoon with a person and receive several urgent messages the next day. Marc Bejarano, who works at a local start-up incubator, spoke to me on the phone for an hour, then texted to ask if we could “collaborate” on this article because, he explained, “it'll be hard to write a piece with this subject matter in such a way as to not lead the reader to draw certain conclusions.” This scout belonged to a different stratum of financial player. No sooner had the car door closed than she asked, “Are we on record?” When I said we were, she smiled, touched her sunglasses, and stared silently out the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;207&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to imagine the city through the eyes of this scout and her hedge-fund clients. As soon as I did, Robb Rill and Mark Gold and even the acts themselves began to seem like a sideshow to what was really happening in Puerto Rico. There were forces operating here that had no interest in the property taxes at the Ritz or which pool you swam in on Saturdays. The real money talked directly to the government about the power grid and the outstanding debt, issues that could make or break the entire economy. The acts only reflected reality: Government is a business, and its most important customers are the rich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;208&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At some point soon, we're going to have 10,000 individuals,” José Pérez-Riera, the government secretary who first conceived of the acts, told me. “Just imagine the amount of development. This is the beginning of the story, if you will.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;209&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was driving Tenenbaum through the center of San Juan, I saw something in the middle of the road, green and fluorescing in the afternoon sunlight. I realized it was an iguana just before I drove over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;210&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Did I hit him?” I said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;211&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Don't worry,” said Tenenbaum. “Here they encourage you to eat them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;212&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was right. Green iguanas are an invasive species in Puerto Rico, and the government was encouraging consumption as a form of population control. Introduced as pets, the animals were initially quite rare. Indeed, no one noticed iguanas in the early years: Puerto Rico contains a highly diverse biosphere, in which a thousand new animals could exist for a brief period without anyone paying any mind. But the climate of the island agreed with them, and soon their numbers grew exponentially, until suddenly iguanas were turning up everywhere—burrowing under roads, swarming airport runways, consuming all the crops. The farmers realized they should kill them, but by now it was too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;213&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jesse Barron&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;is a journalist based in Los Angeles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;214&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A version of this story originally appeared in the October 2018 issue with the title &quot;Puerto (Very) Rico: The Newest Haven for the Super Rich.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 17:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>evo_9</dc:creator>
<og:title>How Puerto Rico Became the Newest Tax Haven for the Super Rich</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.gq.com/story/how-puerto-rico-became-tax-haven-for-super-rich</og:url>
<og:description>Welcome to a paradise for the personal-jet set among the ruins of Hurricane Maria.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.gq.com/photos/5ba0227a8ce6d805ca628b95/16:9/pass/puerto-rico-very-the-newest-haven-for-the-super-rich-gq-oct-101118-01.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gq.com/story/how-puerto-rico-became-tax-haven-for-super-rich</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GnuPG can now be used to perform notarial acts in the State of Washington</title>
<link>https://lists.gnupg.org/pipermail/gnupg-users/2018-September/060987.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lists.gnupg.org/pipermail/gnupg-users/2018-September/060987.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;Washington State Electronic Notary Public endorsements&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Index&quot; href=&quot;index.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;made&quot; href=&quot;mailto:gnupg-users%40gnupg.org?Subject=Re%3A%20Washington%20State%20Electronic%20Notary%20Public%20endorsements&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3CCAJj0OutJvyGfWNpWkAF9otM%3DdBfX6_rCN2Gm%3DEUxFdYjwaqnHQ%40mail.gmail.com%3E&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;index,nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Previous&quot; href=&quot;060986.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Next&quot; href=&quot;060990.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;37.392328767123&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C.J. Collier&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:gnupg-users%40gnupg.org?Subject=Re%3A%20Washington%20State%20Electronic%20Notary%20Public%20endorsements&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3CCAJj0OutJvyGfWNpWkAF9otM%3DdBfX6_rCN2Gm%3DEUxFdYjwaqnHQ%40mail.gmail.com%3E&quot; title=&quot;Washington State Electronic Notary Public endorsements&quot;&gt;cjac at colliertech.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mon Sep 17 20:53:02 CEST 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
Hello folks!

I thought I'd write you to let you know about my recent conversation with
the Washington State Department of Licensing (DoL).  In July, I submitted
my application for renewal of my Notary commission.  This year, the WA
Notary laws changed to allow notaries to request an endorsement with
renewal or initial application &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dol.wa.gov/forms/659007.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.dol.wa.gov/forms/659007.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;.
Since I have a bit of experience
&amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.colliertech.org/state/19.34_RCW/&quot;&gt;http://www.colliertech.org/state/19.34_RCW/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt; with non-repudiation online,
I checked the box indicating a request for Electronic Notary Public
endorsement, listed &quot;Collier Technologies LLC / GnuPG&quot; as my software of
choice, and sent in the extra $15.  My application was processed and my
third commission as notary was approved on August 17th.

I received in the mail a letter dated September 6th 2018, however, which
informed me that the software I indicated &quot;does not meet the requirements
&amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.leg.wa.gov/wac/default.aspx?cite=308-30-130&quot;&gt;http://apps.leg.wa.gov/wac/default.aspx?cite=308-30-130&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt; of the enclosed
laws and rules.&quot;

The requirements indicated were:

Requirements for technologies and technology providers.
A tamper-evident technology shall comply with these rules:
(1) A technology provider shall enroll only notaries public who have been
issued an electronic records notary public endorsement pursuant to WAC
308-30-030 &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.leg.wa.gov/wac/default.aspx?cite=308-30-030&quot;&gt;http://apps.leg.wa.gov/wac/default.aspx?cite=308-30-030&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;.
(2) A technology provider shall take reasonable steps to ensure that a
notary public who has enrolled to use the technology has the knowledge to
use it to perform electronic notarial acts in compliance with these rules.
(3) A tamper-evident technology shall require access to the system by a
password or other secure means of authentication.
(4) A tamper-evident technology shall enable a notary public to affix the
notary's electronic signature and seal or stamp in a manner that attributes
such signature and seal or stamp to the notary.
(5) A technology provider shall provide prorated fees to align the usage
and cost of the tamper-evident technology with the term limit of the notary
public electronic records notary public endorsement.
(6) A technology provider shall suspend the use of any tamper-evident
technology for any notary public whose endorsement has been revoked,
suspended, or canceled by the state of Washington or the notary public.

This all seemed to me to be something that GnuPG is designed to do and does
quite well.  So I sent an email on Friday night to the sender of the letter
requesting specific issues that my provider did not comply with.  This
morning I received a call from the DoL, and was able to successfully argue
for GnuPG's qualification as an electronic records notary public technology
provider for the State of Washington.

In short, GnuPG can now be used to perform notarial acts
&amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://app.leg.wa.gov/RCW/default.aspx?cite=42.45.140&quot;&gt;http://app.leg.wa.gov/RCW/default.aspx?cite=42.45.140&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt; in the State of
Washington!

Cheers,

C.J.
-------------- next part --------------
An HTML attachment was scrubbed...
URL: &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.gnupg.org/pipermail/gnupg-users/attachments/20180917/92100b6d/attachment-0001.html&quot;&gt;https://lists.gnupg.org/pipermail/gnupg-users/attachments/20180917/92100b6d/attachment-0001.html&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.gnupg.org/mailman/listinfo/gnupg-users&quot;&gt;More information about the Gnupg-users mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 17:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Boulth</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lists.gnupg.org/pipermail/gnupg-users/2018-September/060987.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla Faces U.S. Criminal Probe Over Musk Statements</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-09-18/tesla-faces-u-s-criminal-probe-over-musk-statements</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-09-18/tesla-faces-u-s-criminal-probe-over-musk-statements</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;Terms of Service Violation&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;9.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/assets/img/BB-Logo-2line.svg&quot; width=&quot;310&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your usage has been flagged as a violation of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/tos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;terms of service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For inquiries related to this message please &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/feedback&quot;&gt;contact support&lt;/a&gt;. For sales inquiries, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&quot;&gt;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you believe this to be in error, please confirm below that you are not a robot by clicking &quot;I'm not a robot&quot; below.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Please make sure your browser supports JavaScript and cookies and that you are not blocking them from loading. For more information you can review the Terms of Service and Cookie Policy.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;block_uuid&quot;&gt;Block reference ID:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>whatok</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=3c3290f0-bbe2-11e8-a2e5-1b245676cf66&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOC0wOS0xOC90ZXNsYS1mYWNlcy11LXMtY3JpbWluYWwtcHJvYmUtb3Zlci1tdXNrLXN0YXRlbWVudHM=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A $1, Linux-Capable, Hand-Solderable Processor</title>
<link>https://hackaday.com/2018/09/17/a-1-linux-capable-hand-solderable-processor/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hackaday.com/2018/09/17/a-1-linux-capable-hand-solderable-processor/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Over on the EEVblog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eevblog.com/forum/chat/the-$1-linux-capable-arm-processor-in-tqfp/?topicseen&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;someone noticed an interesting chip&lt;/a&gt; that’s been apparently flying under our radar for a while. This is an ARM processor capable of running Linux. It’s hand-solderable in a TQFP package, has a built-in Mali GPU, support for a touch panel, and has support for 512MB of DDR3. If you do it right, this will get you into the territory of a BeagleBone or a Raspberry Pi Zero, on a board that’s whatever form factor you can imagine. Here’s the best part: you can get this part for $1 USD in large-ish quantities. A cursory glance at the usual online retailers tells me you can get this part in quantity one for under $3. This is interesting, to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chip in question, the Allwinner A13, is a 1GHz ARM Cortex-A8 processor. While it’s not much, it is a chip that can run Linux in a hand-solderable package. There is no HDMI support, you’ll need to add some more chips (that are probably in a BGA package), but, hey, it’s only a dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to prototype with this chip, the best options right now are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.olimex.com/Products/OLinuXino/A13/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a few boards from Olimex&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.olimex.com/Products/SOM/A13/A13-SOM-512/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a System on Module&lt;/a&gt; from the same company. That SoM is an interesting bit of kit, allowing anyone to connect a power supply, load an SD card, and get this chip doing something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, there aren’t really any good solutions for a cheap Linux system you can build at home, with hand-solderable chips. Yes, you could &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2012/03/28/building-the-worst-linux-pc-ever/&quot;&gt;put Linux on an ATMega&lt;/a&gt;, but that’s the worst PC ever. A better option is &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2017/04/15/an-even-smaller-beaglebone/&quot;&gt;the Octavo OSD335x&lt;/a&gt; SoC, better known as ‘the BeagleBone on a Chip’. This is a BGA chip, but the layout isn’t &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; bad, and it can be assembled using a $12 toaster oven. The problem with this chip is the price; at quantity 1000, it’s a $25 chip. At quantity one, it’s a $40 chip. NXP’s i.MX6 chips have great software support, but they’re $30 chips, and you’ll need some DDR to make it do something useful, and that doesn’t even touch the fiddlyness of a 600-ball package&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Allwinner A13 beats all the other options on price and solderability, it should be noted that like all of these random Linux-capable SoCs, the software is a mess. There is a reason those ‘Raspberry Pi killers’ haven’t yet killed the Raspberry Pi, and it’s because the Allwinner chips don’t have documentation and let’s repeat that for emphasis: the software is a mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, if you’re looking for a cheap chip you can solder at home, this one seems to be the only game in town. We’re really looking forward to seeing what you make with it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 12:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>johncole</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>A $1, Linux-Capable, Hand-Solderable Processor</og:title>
<og:url>https://hackaday.com/2018/09/17/a-1-linux-capable-hand-solderable-processor/</og:url>
<og:description>Over on the EEVblog, someone noticed an interesting chip that’s been apparently flying under our radar for a while. This is an ARM processor capable of running Linux. It’s hand-solderab…</og:description>
<og:image>https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/lqfp-176.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackaday.com/2018/09/17/a-1-linux-capable-hand-solderable-processor/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Papers of Srinivasa Ramanujan (1887-1920), mathematician</title>
<link>https://www.trin.cam.ac.uk/library/wren-digital-library/modern-manuscripts/ramanujan/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.trin.cam.ac.uk/library/wren-digital-library/modern-manuscripts/ramanujan/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;container-fluid&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Papers of Srinivasa Ramanujan (1887-1920), mathematician&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-6724 alignleft&quot; src=&quot;https://www.trin.cam.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/RS73253_Add.Ms_.a.94_7002-300x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rs73253_add-ms-a-94_7002&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.trin.cam.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/RS73253_Add.Ms_.a.94_7002-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.trin.cam.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/RS73253_Add.Ms_.a.94_7002-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.trin.cam.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/RS73253_Add.Ms_.a.94_7002-1200x1200.jpg 1200w, https://www.trin.cam.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/RS73253_Add.Ms_.a.94_7002-360x360.jpg 360w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;The papers of Srinivasa Ramanujan, Add.Ms.c.94, are available to view through &lt;a href=&quot;https://janus.lib.cam.ac.uk/db/node.xsp?id=EAD%2FGBR%2F0016%2FAdd.Ms.a%2F94&quot;&gt;Janus&lt;/a&gt;. The page gives a list of the papers along with links to view the digitised manuscripts.
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Srinivasa Aiyanger Ramanujan was born in Erode, India in 1887. He showed early mathematical ability which developed rapidly during his teenage years. He published his first paper in 1911 and encouraged by correspondence with G. H. Hardy at Trinity College, he obtained a research scholarship at the University of Madras. He came to England in 1914 to begin a productive collaboration with Hardy. Ramanujan was particularly prolific in the field of number theory. In 1918 he became a fellow of the Royal Society and was subsequently offered a fellowship at Trinity College. He was, however, beset by ill-health and returned to India in 1919. He died in 1920.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;table id=&quot;tablepress-43&quot; class=&quot;tablepress tablepress-id-43&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody class=&quot;row-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-1 odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;Contact:&lt;br/&gt;Phone&lt;br/&gt;(01223) 338488&lt;p&gt;Email&lt;br/&gt;college.library@trin.cam.ac.uk&lt;br/&gt;wren.library@trin.cam.ac.uk&lt;br/&gt;archives@trin.cam.ac.uk&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 11:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mgdo</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.trin.cam.ac.uk/library/wren-digital-library/modern-manuscripts/ramanujan/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Life in the Spanish city that banned cars</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2018/sep/18/paradise-life-spanish-city-banned-cars-pontevedra</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2018/sep/18/paradise-life-spanish-city-banned-cars-pontevedra</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;P&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;eople don’t shout in Pontevedra – or they shout less. With all but the most essential traffic banished, there are no revving engines or honking horns, no metallic snarl of motorbikes or the roar of people trying make themselves heard above the din – none of the usual soundtrack of a Spanish city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you hear in the street instead are the tweeting of birds in the camellias, the tinkle of coffee spoons and the sound of human voices. Teachers herd crocodiles of small children across town without the constant fear that one of them will stray into traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;How can it be that private property – the car – occupies the public space?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;pullquote-cite&quot;&gt;César Mosquera&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Listen,” says the mayor, opening the windows of his office. From the street below rises the sound of human voices. “Before I became mayor 14,000 cars passed along this street every day. More cars passed through the city in a day than there are people living here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miguel Anxo Fernández Lores has been mayor of the Galician city since 1999. His philosophy is simple: owning a car doesn’t give you the right to occupy the public space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How can it be that the elderly or children aren’t able to use the street because of cars?” asks César Mosquera, the city’s head of infrastructures. “How can it be that private property – the car – occupies the public space?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;cd2a2ac1-d25a-40d3-a87a-1006468846b1&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;qanda&quot; class=&quot;atom atom--snippet atom--snippet--qanda&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;atom--snippet__label&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;atom--snippet__headline&quot;&gt;What is Walking the City week?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;atom__button atom__button--large atom__button--rounded atom--snippet__handle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;is-on&quot;&gt; Show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;is-off&quot;&gt; Hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__body&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;atom--snippet__image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/3dffe5f441b5b8a7f424d56f3b83779685f8de4d/992_2543_1528_1528/140.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot; https://media.guim.co.uk/3dffe5f441b5b8a7f424d56f3b83779685f8de4d/992_2543_1528_1528/140.jpg 140w , https://media.guim.co.uk/3dffe5f441b5b8a7f424d56f3b83779685f8de4d/992_2543_1528_1528/500.jpg 500w , https://media.guim.co.uk/3dffe5f441b5b8a7f424d56f3b83779685f8de4d/992_2543_1528_1528/1000.jpg 1000w , https://media.guim.co.uk/3dffe5f441b5b8a7f424d56f3b83779685f8de4d/992_2543_1528_1528/1528.jpg 1528w&quot; sizes=&quot;100px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As cities around the world close central streets to cars to mark &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldcarfree.net/wcfd/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;World Car-Free Day&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Guardian Cities&lt;/strong&gt; is looking at the joys and trials of urban walking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US humourist and writer &lt;strong&gt;David Sedaris&lt;/strong&gt; tells us about walking in cities from Raleigh to Reykjavik. &lt;strong&gt;Will Self&lt;/strong&gt; explains what he learns from perambulations in London, there’s &lt;strong&gt;Fran Lebowitz&lt;/strong&gt; in New York, &lt;strong&gt;Helen Garner&lt;/strong&gt; in Melbourne, “natural navigator” &lt;strong&gt;Tristan Gooley&lt;/strong&gt; in Portsmouth, and writers on Delhi and Newcastle, Cairo and Wellington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laura Laker&lt;/strong&gt; casts a critical eye on the performance of Vision Zero, the global city scheme to eliminate traffic deaths. London has signed up – will it enjoy the success of New York, or the delays of LA? The recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2018/jul/04/oxford-street-at-risk-if-pedestrianisation-blocked-london-sadiq-khan&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;blocking of Sadiq Khan’s plans to pedestrianise Oxford Street&lt;/a&gt; does not bode well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correspondent &lt;strong&gt;Stephen Burgen&lt;/strong&gt; samples the newfound silence in the Spanish car-free city of Pontevedra, and &lt;strong&gt;Matthew Keegan&lt;/strong&gt; discovers what prompted Hong Kong to reopen a popular pedestrian street to vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renate van der Zee&lt;/strong&gt; looks at the rise, fall and rebirth of the Lijnbaan in Rotterdam – Europe’s first pedestrianised street – while &lt;strong&gt;Rachel Aldred&lt;/strong&gt; at the University of Westminster crunches the numbers to identify the most dangerous London boroughs for people on foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oliver Wainwright&lt;/strong&gt; explores the City of London’s forgotten Pedways – and asks whether these 1960s walkways can make a comeback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We consider the phenomenon of “desire lines”, examine the art of following a stranger in the hope of seeing a city in a new light, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/profile/nickmead&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Nick Van Mead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__credit&quot;&gt;Photograph: Dorota and Mariusz Jarymowiczowie/Dorling Kindersley&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;atom--snippet__footer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was this helpful?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__ack&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;Thank you for your feedback.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lores became mayor after 12 years in opposition, and within a month had pedestrianised all 300,000 sq m of the medieval centre, paving the streets with granite flagstones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The historical centre was dead,” he says. “There were a lot of drugs, it was full of cars – it was a marginal zone. It was a city in decline, polluted, and there were a lot of traffic accidents. It was stagnant. Most people who had a chance to leave did so. At first we thought of improving traffic conditions but couldn’t come up with a workable plan. Instead we decided to take back the public space for the residents and to do this we decided to get rid of cars.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Novísimo metro map, Pontevedra, Spain&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/0670edd1bea01f8a8d670e315207700d293a81cf/0_0_2196_2147/master/2196.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=4ff76b045e519973e117efdb8c89637c&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

A metro-style map of Pontevedra shows typical walking times
&lt;p&gt;They stopped cars crossing the city and got rid of street parking, as people looking for a place to park is what causes the most congestion. They closed all surface car parks in the city centre and opened underground ones and others on the periphery, with 1,686 free places. They got rid of traffic lights in favour of roundabouts, extended the car-free zone from the old city to the 18th-century area, and used traffic calming in the outer zones to bring the speed limit down to 30km/h.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits are numerous. On the same streets where 30 people died in traffic accidents from 1996 to 2006, only three died in the subsequent 10 years, and none since 2009. CO2 emissions are down 70%, nearly three-quarters of what were car journeys are now made on foot or by bicycle, and, while other towns in the region are shrinking, central Pontevedra has gained 12,000 new inhabitants. Also, withholding planning permission for big shopping centres has meant that small businesses – which elsewhere have been unable to withstand Spain’s prolonged economic crisis – have managed to stay afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
 The Cityscape: get the best of Guardian Cities delivered to you every week, with just-released data, features and on-the-ground reports from all over the world
&lt;p&gt;Lores, a member of the leftwing Galician Nationalist Bloc, is a rarity in the solidly conservative northwestern region. Pontevedra, population 80,000, is the birthplace of Mariano Rajoy, the former Spanish prime minister and leader of the rightwing People’s party. However, the mayor says Rajoy has never shown any interest in an urban scheme that has earned his native city numerous awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, it hasn’t all gone off without a hitch. People don’t like being told they can’t drive wherever they want, but Lores says that while people claim it as a right, in fact what they want are privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If someone wants to get married in the car-free zone, the bride and groom can come in a car, but everyone else walks,” he says. “Same with funerals.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Pontevedra after the changes.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/14ad21b097ad24cb7e963f6f2c235bbe89e72409/0_55_1700_1122/master/1700.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=6619542791d2c732008045443328c15e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Central Pontevedra after the changes. Photograph: Luis Pereiro Gomez
&lt;p&gt;The main grumble is that the scheme has led to congestion on the periphery of the zone and that there aren’t enough parking spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The city is the perfect size for pedestrianisation,” says local architect Rogelio Carballo Soler. “You can cross the entire city in 25 minutes. There are things you could criticise, but there’s nothing that would make you reject this model.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, at a children’s birthday party, a group of parents discuss the pros and cons of the car-free city. “The problem is first thing in the morning in the few streets where cars are permitted there are traffic jams,” says Ramiro Armesto. “There’s no public transport from the peripheral car parks into the centre. On the other hand, I’ve lived in Valencia and Toledo but I’ve never lived in a city as easy to live in as this one.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raquel García says: “I’ve lived in Madrid and many other places and for me this is paradise. Even if it’s raining, I walk everywhere. And the same shopkeepers who complain are the ones who have survived in spite of the crisis. It’s also a great place to have kids.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s needed is more areas where you can park for five minutes so that you can take the kids to school when it’s raining,” says Víctor Prieto. “Here, if it’s raining – and it rains a lot – people get in their car to buy bread. They do it less now. I hardly use my car at all now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The works were all financed locally and received no aid from regional or central government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In effect, these are everyday public works that have been carried out in the context of a global project, but they cost the same or even less,” says Lores. “We’ve haven’t undertaken grand projects. We’ve done what was within our grasp.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’re eager to hear your thoughts and experiences of walking in cities. Please share your reflections with us using &lt;a href=&quot;https://guardiannewsandmedia.formstack.com/forms/walkingthecity&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt;, or on social media with the hashtag #GuardianWalking. Follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/guardiancities&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/guardiancities&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/guardiancities/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 11:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>antr</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/cities/2018/sep/18/paradise-life-spanish-city-banned-cars-pontevedra</og:url>
<og:description>In Pontevedra, the usual soundtrack of a Spanish city has been replaced by the tweeting of birds and the chatter of humans</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/393b486f64b82fd07eea6e067f6a6bcd42bf3253/462_0_1143_686/master/1143.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly9hc3NldHMuZ3VpbS5jby51ay9pbWFnZXMvb3ZlcmxheXMvZDM1ODZhNWVmNTc4MTc1NmQyMWEzYjYzNWU1MTcxNDEvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;s=5c8608aa29f6abdf35bf037d22d4e1e4</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>'For me, this is paradise': life in the Spanish city that banned cars</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2018/sep/18/paradise-life-spanish-city-banned-cars-pontevedra</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>