<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Don&amp;#039;t Do This in Production</title>
<link>https://stephenmann.io/post/dont-do-this-in-production/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stephenmann.io/post/dont-do-this-in-production/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Around March of 2017, I received a call asking for a code review on a product about to be launched. This company had issues with memory leaks, spontaneous crashing, slow loading, CPU spiking, and had to release in a couple of weeks. You might have heard this story before, just not from me, and not about this company. It’s surprisingly common.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We got together on the weekend and started looking through the code together. It took about half a day to discover the source of the known problems, and another half day to write-up a document for their engineering team to fix them. The launch succeeded, but it made me wonder how the product ever got to that place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I chatted with the developers, they seemed like intelligent people. The only clear issue was lack of experience, which they could really only solve by continuing to build and grow. I’ve run into that before. It’s common, and I think it’s healthy – well, most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, however, it had a nefarious twist: &lt;strong&gt;all of these developers lacked experience&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The department that built the product had recently come into existence, and they hired a team of developers without having a technical person on staff to vet them. It’s difficult enough for a technical person to vet a developer – I can’t even imagine vetting a candidate without having a technical background. They hired the first developer, and he vetted the second developer, and so on until they had a development team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re lucky enough for your first developer to have significant experience and a desire to mentor, then you’re golden. If you’re unlucky, however – and it’s very easy to be unlucky at something like this – then you may end up with a very fast moving team that builds very fragile software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Move fast and break things,” they said. It turns out that’s a pretty bad idea when your business relies on a small number of large customers. Broken products tend to scare them off, which in turn tanks your business. There’s a lot to be said for building things that work, but “move slowly and steadily towards a goal” just doesn’t have the same ring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, there’s a balance between moving fast and and moving slow. It’s difficult to communicate that balance because every type of product demands a different balance. I suppose that intuition comes from experience, which is a terrible answer for someone trying to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s a new developer to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural tendency seems to be asking the internet. It turns out that this is &lt;strong&gt;incredibly effective&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also &lt;strong&gt;incredibly dangerous&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This company continued to work with me after that product launch. I reviewed a significant amount of code, helped mentor their developers, and built new projects for them. Everything went swimmingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, I ran into a section of code that triggered my spidey sense. I could have sworn that I had seen it before. Sure enough, after pasting a line into a search engine, I found the exact section of code in a blog post. Naturally I read the whole thing, right up to the line that said, “&lt;strong&gt;Don’t do this in production.&lt;/strong&gt;“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet here it was, tipping its hat at me from the front lines of a production codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take long to find many sections of code from similar blog posts. Almost all of the blog posts either wrote a disclaimer or should have written one. They all solved one small piece of a problem, but took many liberties in their solution to make it simpler to read. It’s understandable. Most readers appreciate brevity when learning a concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code from these blog posts had spread through the codebase like a disease, scattering issues here and there without any rhyme or reason. And there wasn’t any obvious cure other than to read everything manually and fix issues as I went along. Without unit tests or automated deployments, this took &lt;em&gt;almost a year&lt;/em&gt;. I’m almost certain the cost of fixing the code exceeded the margin on revenue due to writing it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what other option did these developers have? They had to deliver something, and they had never released a production application before. So they did what any sensible person would try to do, and they learned on the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production systems can fail in an incredible number of ways. Without having experienced or read about these failures, it’s difficult to have an intuition about how to prevent them or how to solve them. It’s a tall order to ask a new development team to do this, especially without any guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going any further, I want to mention that every person involved in this mess had good intentions. The developers who wrote the code wanted to build a good product and improve themselves. The managers who hired them wanted the same thing. The blog post writers wanted to share useful solutions. Everyone did their best to help one another out, and it’s important to remember that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This wasn’t a problem with people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an overwhelming empathy for developers in this position. They have more information than they will ever need, but it’s completely disorganized. It’s like trying to build a ten piece puzzle, except you have to find the ten pieces within a pile of 10,000,000,000 pieces, all of which are square, and you don’t know what it’s supposed to look like at the end. Good luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read this far hoping for an answer, then I’m sorry: I don’t have a simple one. This is a difficult problem to solve. The solution is too large for a single blog post, changes every day, and differs subtly for every project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This problem motivated me to start blogging. I’ve been blessed to have learned for almost two decades from incredibly talented mentors, writers, and coworkers. Without the advice from these people, I would still be writing &lt;code&gt;GOTO&lt;/code&gt; statements in QBasic (shudder). It’s time for me to take the ball and run with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll summarize with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is about building production ready applications. It will do this from every aspect: from infrastructure automation, to testing, to design, to debugging, to documentation, to development process, to security. Every post will stand on its own feet, ready to use in the real world – &lt;strong&gt;ready to use in production.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! Please leave a comment if you have one, or a request for a post topic, or any suggestions for how to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 14:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pattrn</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stephenmann.io/post/dont-do-this-in-production/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The un-celebrity president: Jimmy Carter shuns riches, lives modestly</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp/2018/08/17/feature/the-un-celebrity-president-jimmy-carter-shuns-riches-lives-modestly-in-his-georgia-hometown/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp/2018/08/17/feature/the-un-celebrity-president-jimmy-carter-shuns-riches-lives-modestly-in-his-georgia-hometown/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Jimmy Carter finishes his Saturday night dinner, salmon and broccoli casserole on a paper plate, flashes his famous toothy grin and calls playfully to his wife of 72 years, Rosalynn: “C’mon, kid.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She laughs and takes his hand, and they walk carefully through a neighbor’s kitchen filled with 1976 campaign buttons, photos of world leaders and a couple of unopened cans of Billy Beer, then out the back door, where three Secret Service agents wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-mobile-header-caption&quot;&gt;Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter walk home with Secret Service agents along West Church Street after having dinner at a friend’s house in Plains, Ga. The former first couple, who were born in Plains, returned to the town after leaving the White House.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They do this just about every weekend in this tiny town where they were born — he almost 94 years ago, she almost 91. Dinner at their friend Jill Stuckey’s house, with plastic Solo cups of ice water and one glass each of bargain-brand chardonnay, then the half-mile walk home to the ranch house they built in 1961.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this south Georgia summer evening, still close to 90 degrees, they dab their faces with a little plastic bottle of No Natz to repel the swirling clouds of tiny bugs. Then they catch each other’s hands again and start walking, the former president in jeans and clunky black shoes, the former first lady using a walking stick for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 39th president of the United States lives modestly, a sharp contrast to his successors, who have left the White House to embrace power of another kind: wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even those who didn’t start out rich, including Bill Clinton and Barack Obama, have made tens of millions of dollars on the private-sector opportunities that flow so easily to ex-presidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid ent-photo-grid-3-hero&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder ent-photo-grid-hero&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter010.jpg&amp;amp;w=1484&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter010.jpg&amp;amp;w=480&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter010.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter010.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid-small-caption&quot;&gt;The Carters have dinner at their friend Jill Stuckey’s house, where they drank ice water out of plastic Solo cups and each had a glass of bargain-brand chardonnay.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter037.jpg&amp;amp;w=1484&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter037.jpg&amp;amp;w=480&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter037.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter037.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid-small-caption&quot;&gt;Carter enjoys his Saturday night dinner at Stuckey’s house on a paper plate.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter012.jpg&amp;amp;w=1484&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter012.jpg&amp;amp;w=480&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter012.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter012.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid-small-caption&quot;&gt;The Carters hold hands as they walk home. The couple — he, almost 94, and she, almost 91 — have been married 72 years.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid-big-caption&quot;&gt;TOP: The Carters have dinner at their friend Jill Stuckey’s house, where they drank ice water out of plastic Solo cups and each had a glass of bargain-brand chardonnay. LEFT: Carter enjoys his Saturday night dinner at Stuckey’s house on a paper plate. RIGHT: The Carters hold hands as they walk home. The couple — he, almost 94, and she, almost 91 — have been married 72 years.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Carter left the White House after one tumultuous term, trounced by Ronald Reagan in the 1980 election, he returned to Plains, a speck of peanut and cotton farmland that to this day has a nearly 40 percent poverty rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Democratic former president decided not to join corporate boards or give speeches for big money because, he says, he didn’t want to “capitalize financially on being in the White House.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presidential historian Michael Beschloss said that Gerald Ford, Carter’s predecessor and close friend, was the first to fully take advantage of those high-paid post-presidential opportunities, but that “Carter did the opposite.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Ford, other former presidents, and sometimes their spouses, routinely earn hundreds of thousands of dollars per speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t see anything wrong with it; I don’t blame other people for doing it,” Carter says over dinner. “It just never had been my ambition to be rich.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid ent-photo-grid-2&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter033.jpg&amp;amp;w=1484&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter033.jpg&amp;amp;w=480&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter033.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter033.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid-small-caption&quot;&gt;Carter’s handprints mark a sidewalk on the grounds of the Jimmy Carter Boyhood Farm in Plains.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter003.jpg&amp;amp;w=1484&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter003.jpg&amp;amp;w=480&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter003.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter003.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid-small-caption&quot;&gt;The former president arrives at Stuckey’s house for dinner wearing a casual shirt, jeans and a belt buckle with “JC” on it.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid-big-caption&quot;&gt;LEFT: Carter’s handprints mark a sidewalk on the grounds of the Jimmy Carter Boyhood Farm in Plains. RIGHT: The former president arrives at Stuckey’s house for dinner wearing a casual shirt, jeans and a belt buckle with “JC” on it.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;‘He doesn’t like big shots’&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter was 56 when he returned to Plains from Washington. He says his peanut business, held in a blind trust during his presidency, was $1 million in debt, and he was forced to sell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We thought we were going to lose everything,” says Rosalynn, sitting beside him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter decided that his income would come from writing, and he has written 33 books, about his life and career, his faith, Middle East peace, women’s rights, aging, fishing, woodworking, even a children’s book written with his daughter, Amy Carter, called “The Little Baby Snoogle-Fleejer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With book income and the $210,700 annual pension all former presidents receive, the Carters live comfortably. But his books have never fetched the massive sums commanded by more recent presidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter has been an ex-president for 37 years, longer than anyone else in history. His simple lifestyle is increasingly rare in this era of President Trump, a billionaire with gold-plated sinks in his private jet, Manhattan penthouse and Mar-a-Lago estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter is the only president in the modern era to return full-time to the house he lived in before he entered politics — a two-bedroom rancher assessed at $167,000, less than the value of the armored Secret Service vehicles parked outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ex-presidents often fly on private jets, sometimes lent by wealthy friends, but the Carters fly commercial. Stuckey says that on a recent flight from Atlanta to Los Angeles, Carter walked up and down the aisle greeting other passengers and taking selfies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo ent-photo-fullwidth&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter036.jpg&amp;amp;w=988&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter036.jpg&amp;amp;w=800&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter036.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter036.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ent-photo-caption&quot;&gt;Carter is pictured at his house after teaching his 800th Sunday school lesson at Maranatha Baptist Church since leaving the White House. Every other Sunday morning, he teaches at Maranatha, on the edge of town, and people line up the night before to get a seat. The painting at right was done by Carter.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He doesn’t like big shots, and he doesn’t think he’s a big shot,” said Gerald Rafshoon, who was Carter’s White House communications director.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter costs U.S. taxpayers less than any other ex-president, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsa.gov/cdnstatic/GSA%20FY%202019%20CJ.pdf&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;www.gsa.gov&quot;&gt;according to the General Services Administration&lt;/a&gt;, with a total bill for him in the current fiscal year of $456,000, covering pensions, an office, staff and other expenses. That’s less than half the $952,000 budgeted for George H.W. Bush; the three other living ex-presidents — Clinton, George W. Bush and Obama — cost taxpayers more than $1 million each per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter doesn’t even have federal retirement health benefits because he worked for the government for four years — less than the five years needed to qualify, according to the GSA. He says he receives health benefits through Emory University, where he has taught for 36 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter022.jpg&amp;amp;w=640&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter022.jpg&amp;amp;w=500&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter022.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter022.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ent-photo-caption&quot;&gt;The Plains general store, once owned by Carter’s Uncle Buddy, sells Carter memorabilia and scoops of peanut butter ice cream in honor of Carter, who was a peanut farmer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The federal government pays for an office for each ex-president. Carter’s, in the Carter Center in Atlanta, is the least expensive, at $115,000 this year. The Carters could have built a more elaborate office with living quarters, but for years they slept on a pullout couch for a week each month. Recently, they had a Murphy bed installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter’s office costs a fraction of Obama’s, which is $536,000 a year. Clinton’s costs $518,000, George W. Bush’s is $497,000 and George H.W. Bush’s is $286,000, according to the GSA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am a great admirer of Harry Truman. He’s my favorite president, and I really try to emulate him,” says Carter, who writes his books in a converted garage in his house. “He set an example I thought was admirable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But although Truman retired to his hometown of Independence, Mo., Beschloss said that even he took up residence in an elegant house previously owned by his prosperous in-laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Carter spreads a thick layer of butter on a slice of white bread, he is asked whether he thinks, especially with a man who boasts of being a billionaire in the White House, any future ex-president will ever live the way Carter does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I hope so,” he says. “But I don’t know.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo ent-photo-fullwidth&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter035.jpg&amp;amp;w=988&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter035.jpg&amp;amp;w=800&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter035.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter035.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ent-photo-caption&quot;&gt;A customer leaves the Plains Mtd convenience store in Plains. About 700 people live in the town, 150 miles south of Atlanta, in a place that is a living museum to Carter.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;‘A good ’ol Southern gentleman’&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plains is a tiny circle of Georgia farmland, a mile in diameter, with its center at the train depot that served as Carter’s 1976 campaign headquarters. About 700 people live here, 150 miles due south of Atlanta, in a place that is a living museum to Carter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general store, once owned by Carter’s Uncle Buddy, sells Carter memorabilia and scoops of peanut butter ice cream. Carter’s boyhood farm is preserved as it was in the 1930s, with no electricity or running water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jimmy Carter National Historic Site is essentially the entire town, drawing nearly 70,000 visitors a year and $4 million into the county’s economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter has used his post-presidency to support human rights, global health programs and fair elections worldwide through his Carter Center, based in Atlanta. He has helped renovate 4,300 homes in 14 countries for Habitat for Humanity, and with his own hammer and tool belt, he will be working on homes for low-income people in Indiana later this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is Plains that defines him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dinner, the Carters step out of Stuckey’s driveway, with two Secret Service agents walking close behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter’s gait is a little unsteady these days, three years after a diagnosis of melanoma on his liver and brain. At a 2015 news conference to announce his illness, he seemed to be bidding a stoic farewell, saying he was “perfectly at ease with whatever comes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now, after radiation and chemotherapy, Carter says he is cancer-free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October, he will become the second president ever to reach 94; George H.W. Bush turned 94 in June. These days, Carter is sharp, funny and reflective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Carters walk every day — often down Church Street, the main drag through Plains, where they have been walking since the 1920s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid ent-photo-grid-2&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter023.jpg&amp;amp;w=1484&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter023.jpg&amp;amp;w=480&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter023.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter023.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid-small-caption&quot;&gt;Gene Mattson, who owns Plains Mtd, feeds cats outside the convenience store.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter027.jpg&amp;amp;w=1484&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter027.jpg&amp;amp;w=480&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter027.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter027.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid-small-caption&quot;&gt;Veterinarian Frank Pierce sits outside his clinic in Plains.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo-grid-big-caption&quot;&gt;LEFT: Gene Mattson, who owns Plains Mtd, feeds cats outside the convenience store. RIGHT: Veterinarian Frank Pierce sits outside his clinic in Plains.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they cross Walters Street, Carter sees a couple of teenagers on the sidewalk across the street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hello,” says the former president, with the same big smile that adorns peanut Christmas ornaments in the general store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hey,” says a girl in a jean skirt, greeting him with a cheerful wave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two 15-year-olds say people in Plains think of the Carters as neighbors and friends, just like anybody else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I grew up in church with him,” says Maya Wynn. “He’s a nice guy, just like a regular person.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He’s a good ’ol Southern gentleman,” says David Lane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carter says this place formed him, seeding his beliefs about racial equality. His farmhouse youth during the Great Depression made him unpretentious and frugal. His friends, maybe only half-joking, describe Carter as “tight as a tick.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That no-frills sensibility, endearing since he left Washington, didn’t work as well in the White House. Many people thought Carter scrubbed some of the luster off the presidency by carrying his own suitcases onto Air Force One and refusing to have “Hail to the Chief” played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuart E. Eizenstat, a Carter aide and biographer, said Carter’s edict eliminating drivers for top staff members backfired. It meant that top officials were driving instead of reading and working for an hour or two every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He didn’t feel suited to the grandeur,” Eizenstat said. “Plains is really part of his DNA. He carried it into the White House, and he carried it out of the White House.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter’s presidency — from 1977 to 1981 — is often remembered for long lines at gas stations and the Iran hostage crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I may have overemphasized the plight of the hostages when I was in my final year,” he says. “But I was so obsessed with them personally, and with their families, that I wanted to do anything to get them home safely, which I did.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo ent-photo-fullwidth&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter029.jpg&amp;amp;w=988&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter029.jpg&amp;amp;w=800&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter029.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter029.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ent-photo-caption&quot;&gt;Visitors watch a video about Carter’s life in the theater at Plains High School. Carter attended the school, which served first through 11th grades. Today, the school is home to the Jimmy Carter National Historic Site.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said he regrets not doing more to unify the Democratic Party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Carter looks back at his presidency, he says he is most proud of “keeping the peace and supporting human rights,” the Camp David accords that brokered peace between Israel and Egypt, and his work to normalize relations with China. In 2002, he was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize for his efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I always told the truth,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter has been notably quiet about President Trump. But on this night, two years into Trump’s term, he’s not holding back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think he’s a disaster,” Carter says. “In human rights and taking care of people and treating people equal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The worst is that he is not telling the truth, and that just hurts everything,” Rosalynn says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter says his father taught him that truthfulness matters. He said that was reinforced at the U.S. Naval Academy, where he said students are expelled for telling even the smallest lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think there’s been an attitude of ignorance toward the truth by President Trump,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter says he thinks the Supreme Court’s &lt;em&gt;Citizens United&lt;/em&gt; decision has “changed our political system from a democracy to an oligarchy. Money is now preeminent. I mean, it’s just gone to hell now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says he believes that the nation’s “ethical and moral values” are still intact and that Americans eventually will “return to what’s right and what’s wrong, and what’s decent and what’s indecent, and what’s truthful and what’s lies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, he says, “I doubt if it happens in my lifetime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter028.jpg&amp;amp;w=640&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter028.jpg&amp;amp;w=500&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter028.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter028.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ent-photo-caption&quot;&gt;The Jimmy Carter National Historic Site draws nearly 70,000 visitors a year and $4 million into the county’s economy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Church Street, Carter points out the mayor’s house with his left hand while he holds Rosalynn’s with his right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My mother and father lived in that brick one,” he says, gesturing toward a small house across the street. “We use it as an office now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s Dr. Logan’s over here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every house has a story. Generations of them. Cracked birdbaths and rocking chairs on somebody’s great-grandmother’s porch. Carter knows them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mr. Oscar Williams lived here; his family was my competitor in the warehouse business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He points out the Plains United Methodist Church, where he spotted young Eleanor Rosalynn Smith one evening when he was home from the Naval Academy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He asked her out. They went to a movie, and the next morning he told his mother he was going to marry Rosalynn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t know that for years,” she says with a smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are asked if there is anything they want but don’t have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I can’t think of anything,” Carter says, turning to Rosalynn. “And you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No, I’m happy,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We feel at home here,” Carter says. “And the folks in town, when we need it, they take care of us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo ent-photo-fullwidth&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter016.jpg&amp;amp;w=988&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter016.jpg&amp;amp;w=800&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter016.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter016.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ent-photo-caption&quot;&gt;Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter pose for photographs with anyone who wants one after a morning church service at Maranatha Baptist Church.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;‘A heart of service’&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every other Sunday morning, Carter teaches Sunday school at the Maranatha Baptist Church on the edge of town, and people line up the night before to get a seat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Sunday morning happens to be his 800th lesson since he left the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He walks in wearing a blazer too big through the shoulders, a striped shirt and a turquoise bolo tie. He asks where people have come from, and from the pews they call out at least 20 states, Canada, Kenya, China and Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He tells the congregation that he’s planning a trip to Montana to go fishing with his friend Ted Turner, and that he’s going to ride in his son’s autogiro — a sort of mini-helicopter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m still fairly active,” he says, and everyone laughs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He talks about living a purposeful life, but also about finding enough time for rest and reflection. Then he and Rosalynn pose for photos with every person who wants one, including Steven and Joanna Raley, who came from Annandale, Va., with their 3-month-old son, Jackson Carter Raley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We want our children to grow up with a heart of service like President Carter,” says Steven, who works on Navy submarines, as Carter once did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One of the reasons we named our son after President Carter is how humble he is,” Joanna says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter holds the baby and beams for the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I like the name,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo ent-photo-fullwidth&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter025.jpg&amp;amp;w=988&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter025.jpg&amp;amp;w=800&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter025.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter025.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ent-photo-caption&quot;&gt;An oversized peanut with a toothy grin, made in Indiana as a tribute to Carter, a former peanut farmer, sits outside the Plains Mtd convenience store.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A modest life&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they reach their property, the Carters turn right off the sidewalk and cut across the wide lawn toward their house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter stops to point out a tall magnolia that was transplanted from a sprout taken from a tree that Andrew Jackson planted on the White House lawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They walk past a pond, which Carter helped dig and where he now works on his fly-fishing technique. They point out a willow tree at the pond’s edge, on a gentle sloping lawn, where they will be buried in graves marked by simple stones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They know their graves will draw tourists and boost the Plains economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their one-story house sits behind a government-owned fence that once surrounded Richard Nixon’s house in Key Biscayne, Fla. The Carters already have deeded the property to the National Park Service, which will one day turn it into a museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their house is dated, but homey and comfortable, with a rustic living room and a small kitchen. A cooler bearing the presidential seal sits on the floor in the kitchen — Carter says they use it for leftovers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a remodel not long ago, the couple knocked down a bedroom wall themselves. “By that time, we had worked with Habitat so much that it was just second-nature,” Rosalynn says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosalynn Carter practices tai chi and meditates in the mornings, while her husband writes in his study or swims in the pool. He also builds furniture and paints in the garage; the paint is still wet on a portrait of a cardinal that will be their Christmas card this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They watch Atlanta Braves games or “Law and Order.” Carter just finished reading “The Innovators” by Walter Isaacson. They have no chef and they cook for themselves, often together. They make their own yogurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this summer morning, Rosalynn mixes pancake batter and sprinkles in blueberries grown on their land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carter cooks them on the griddle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he does the dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ent-photo ent-photo-fullwidth&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter007.jpg&amp;amp;w=988&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter007.jpg&amp;amp;w=800&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter007.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter007.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ent-photo-caption&quot;&gt;After dinner at their friend’s house, the Carters leave, with two Secret Service agents walking close behind. The former president’s gait is a bit unsteady these days, three years after a diagnosis of melanoma on his liver and brain. After radiation and chemotherapy, Carter says he is cancer-free.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 07:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>siberianbear</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp/2018/08/17/feature/the-un-celebrity-president-jimmy-carter-shuns-riches-lives-modestly-in-his-georgia-hometown/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/pbox.php?url=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Carter010.jpg&amp;w=1484&amp;op=resize&amp;opt=1&amp;filter=antialias&amp;t=20170517</og:image>
<og:title>The un-celebrity president: Jimmy Carter shuns riches, lives modestly in his Georgia hometown</og:title>
<og:description>The un-celebrity president: Thirty-seven years after leaving office, Jimmy Carter shuns riches, lives modestly in his Georgia hometown</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/national/wp/2018/08/17/feature/the-un-celebrity-president-jimmy-carter-shuns-riches-lives-modestly-in-his-georgia-hometown/?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introduction to Go Modules</title>
<link>https://roberto.selbach.ca/intro-to-go-modules/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://roberto.selbach.ca/intro-to-go-modules/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The upcoming version 1.11 of the Go programming language will bring experimental support for &lt;em&gt;modules&lt;/em&gt;, a new dependency management system for Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://roberto.selbach.ca/playing-with-go-modules/&quot;&gt;I wrote a quick post about it&lt;/a&gt;. Since that post went live, things changed a bit and as we’re now very close to the new release, I thought it would be a good time for another post with a more hands-on approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s what we’ll do: we’ll create a new package and then we’ll make a few releases to see how that would work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creating a Module&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first things first. Let’s create our package. We’ll call it “testmod”. An important detail here: &lt;strong&gt;this directory should be &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;$GOPATH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;because by default, the modules support is disabled inside it&lt;/strong&gt;. Go modules is a first step in potentially eliminating &lt;code&gt;$GOPATH&lt;/code&gt; entirely at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ mkdir testmod
$ cd testmod
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our package is very simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;package testmod

import &quot;fmt&quot; 

// Hi returns a friendly greeting
func Hi(name string) string {
   return fmt.Sprintf(&quot;Hi, %s&quot;, name)
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The package is done but it is still not a &lt;em&gt;module&lt;/em&gt;. Let’s change that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ go mod init github.com/rselbach/testmod
go: creating new go.mod: module github.com/rselbach/testmod&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates a new file named &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; in the package directory with the following contents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;module github.com/rselbach/testmod&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a lot here, but this effectively turns our package into a &lt;em&gt;module&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now push this code to a repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ git init 
$ git add * 
$ git commit -am &quot;First commit&quot; 
$ git push -u origin master&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now, anyone willing to use this package would &lt;code&gt;go get&lt;/code&gt; it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ go get github.com/rselbach/testmod&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this would fetch the latest code in &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;. This still works, but we should probably stop doing that now that we have a Better Way™. Fetching &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; is inherently dangerous as we can never know for sure that the package authors didn’t make change that will break our usage. That’s what modules aims at fixing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quick Intro to Module Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go modules are &lt;em&gt;versioned&lt;/em&gt;, and there are some particularities with regards to certain versions. You will need to familiarize yourself with the concepts behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://semver.org&quot;&gt;semantic versioning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, Go will use repository tags when looking for versions, and some versions are different of others: e.g. versions 2 and greater should have a different import path than versions 0 and 1 (we’ll get to that.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well, by default Go will fetch the latest &lt;em&gt;tagged version&lt;/em&gt; available in a repository. This is an important gotcha as you may be used to working with the master branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you need to keep in mind for now is that to make a release of our package, we need to tag our repository with the version. So let’s do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making our first release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that our package is ready, we can release it to the world. We do this by using version tags. Let’s release our version 1.0.0:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ git tag v1.0.0
$ git push --tags&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates a tag on my Github repository marking the current commit as being the release 1.0.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go doesn’t enforce that in any way, but a good idea is to also create a new branch (“v1”) so that we can push bug fixes to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ git checkout -b v1
$ git push -u origin v1&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can work on &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; without having to worry about breaking our release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Using our module&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we’re ready to use the module. We’ll create a simple program that will use our new package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;package main

import (
        &quot;fmt&quot;

        &quot;github.com/rselbach/testmod&quot;
)

func main() {
        fmt.Println(testmod.Hi(&quot;roberto&quot;))
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now, you would do a &lt;code&gt;go get github.com/rselbach/testmod&lt;/code&gt; to download the package, but with modules, this gets more interesting. First we need to enable modules in our new program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ go mod init mod&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you’d expect from what we’ve seen above, this will have created a new &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; file with the module name in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;module mod&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things get much more interesting when we try to build our new program:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ go build
go: finding github.com/rselbach/testmod v1.0.0
go: downloading github.com/rselbach/testmod v1.0.0&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see, the &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; command automatically goes and fetches the packages imported by the program. If we check our &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; file, we see that things have changed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;module mod
require github.com/rselbach/testmod v1.0.0&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we now have a new file too, named &lt;code&gt;go.sum&lt;/code&gt;, which contains hashes of the packages, to ensure that we have the correct version and files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;github.com/rselbach/testmod v1.0.0 h1:9EdH0EArQ/rkpss9Tj8gUnwx3w5p0jkzJrd5tRAhxnA=
github.com/rselbach/testmod v1.0.0/go.mod h1:UVhi5McON9ZLc5kl5iN2bTXlL6ylcxE9VInV71RrlO8=&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making a bugfix release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s say we realized a problem with our package: the greeting is missing ponctuation! People are mad because our friendly greeting is not friendly enough. So we’ll fix it and release a new version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;// Hi returns a friendly greeting
func Hi(name string) string {
-       return fmt.Sprintf(&quot;Hi, %s&quot;, name)
+       return fmt.Sprintf(&quot;Hi, %s!&quot;, name)
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made this change in the v1 branch because it’s not relevant for what we’ll do for v2 later, but in real life, maybe you’d do it in &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; and then back-port it. Either way, we need to have the fix in our v1 branch and mark it as a new release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ git commit -m &quot;Emphasize our friendliness&quot; testmod.go
$ git tag v1.0.1
$ git push --tags origin v1&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updating modules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, Go will not update modules without being asked. This is a Good Thing™ as we want predictability in our builds. If Go modules were automatically updated every time a new version came out, we’d be back in the uncivilized age pre-Go1.11. No, we need to &lt;em&gt;tell&lt;/em&gt; Go to update a modules for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do this by using our good old friend &lt;code&gt;go get&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;run &lt;code&gt;go get -u&lt;/code&gt; to use the latest &lt;em&gt;minor or patch&lt;/em&gt; releases (i.e. it would update from 1.0.0 to, say, 1.0.1 or, if available, 1.1.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run &lt;code&gt;go get -u=patch&lt;/code&gt; to use the latest &lt;em&gt;patch&lt;/em&gt; releases (i.e., would update to 1.0.1 but &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to 1.1.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run &lt;code&gt;go get &lt;a href=&quot;https://roberto.selbach.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection&quot; class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;b4c4d5d7dfd5d3d1f4c2d1c6c7dddbda&quot;&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; to update to a specific version (say, &lt;code&gt;github.com/rselbach/&lt;a href=&quot;https://roberto.selbach.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection&quot; class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;ea9e8f999e87858eaa9cdbc4dac4db&quot;&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the list above, there doesn’t seem to be a way to update to the latest &lt;em&gt;major&lt;/em&gt; version. There’s a good reason for that, as we’ll see in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our program was using version 1.0.0 of our package and we just created version 1.0.1, &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of the following commands will update us to 1.0.1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ go get -u
$ go get -u=patch
$ go get github.com/rselbach/&lt;a href=&quot;https://roberto.selbach.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection&quot; class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;2450415750494b406452150a140a15&quot;&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After running, say, &lt;code&gt;go get -u&lt;/code&gt; our &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; is changed to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;module mod
require github.com/rselbach/testmod v1.0.1&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Major versions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to semantic version semantics, a major version is &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; than minors. Major versions can break backwards compatibility. From the point of view of Go modules, a major version is a &lt;em&gt;different package&lt;/em&gt; completely. This may sound bizarre at first, but it makes sense: two versions of a library that are not compatible with each other are two different libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s make a major change in our package, shall we? Over time, we realized our API was too simple, too limited for the use cases of our users, so we need to change the &lt;code&gt;Hi()&lt;/code&gt; function to take a new parameter for the greeting language:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;package testmod

import (
        &quot;errors&quot;
        &quot;fmt&quot; 
) 

// Hi returns a friendly greeting in language lang
func Hi(name, lang string) (string, error) {
        switch lang {
        case &quot;en&quot;:
                return fmt.Sprintf(&quot;Hi, %s!&quot;, name), nil
        case &quot;pt&quot;:
                return fmt.Sprintf(&quot;Oi, %s!&quot;, name), nil
        case &quot;es&quot;:
                return fmt.Sprintf(&quot;¡Hola, %s!&quot;, name), nil
        case &quot;fr&quot;:
                return fmt.Sprintf(&quot;Bonjour, %s!&quot;, name), nil
        default:
                return &quot;&quot;, errors.New(&quot;unknown language&quot;)
        }
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existing software using our API will break because they (a) don’t pass a language parameter and (b) don’t expect an error return. Our new API is no longer compatible with version 1.x so it’s time to bump the version to 2.0.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned before that some versions have some peculiarities, and this is the case now. &lt;strong&gt;Versions 2 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;and over&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;should change the import path.&lt;/strong&gt; They are different libraries now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do this by appending a new &lt;em&gt;version path&lt;/em&gt; to the end of our module name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;module github.com/rselbach/testmod/v2&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest is the same as before, we push it, tag it as v2.0.0 (and optionally create a v2 branch.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ git commit testmod.go -m &quot;Change Hi to allow multilang&quot;
$ git checkout -b v2 # optional but recommended
$ echo &quot;module github.com/rselbach/testmod/v2&quot; &amp;gt; go.mod
$ git commit go.mod -m &quot;Bump version to v2&quot;
$ git tag v2.0.0
$ git push --tags origin v2 # or master if we don't have a branch&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updating to a major version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though we have released a new incompatible version of our library, existing software &lt;em&gt;will not break&lt;/em&gt;, because it will continue to use the existing version 1.0.1. &lt;code&gt;go get -u&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;will not&lt;/em&gt; get version 2.0.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, however, I, as the library user, may want to upgrade to version 2.0.0 because maybe I was one of those users who needed multi-language support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do it but modifying my program accordingly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;package main

import (
        &quot;fmt&quot;
        &quot;github.com/rselbach/testmod/v2&quot; 
)

func main() {
        g, err := testmod.Hi(&quot;Roberto&quot;, &quot;pt&quot;)
        if err != nil {
                panic(err)
        }
        fmt.Println(g)
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then when I run &lt;code&gt;go build&lt;/code&gt;, it will go and fetch version 2.0.0 for me. Notice how even though the import path ends with “v2”, Go will still refer to the module by its proper name (“testmod”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, the major version is for all intents and purposes a completely different package. Go modules does not link the two at all. That means we can use two incompatible versions in the same binary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;package main
import (
        &quot;fmt&quot;
        &quot;github.com/rselbach/testmod&quot;
        testmodML &quot;github.com/rselbach/testmod/v2&quot;
)

func main() {
        fmt.Println(testmod.Hi(&quot;Roberto&quot;))
        g, err := testmodML.Hi(&quot;Roberto&quot;, &quot;pt&quot;)
        if err != nil {
                panic(err)
        }
        fmt.Println(g)
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This eliminates a common problem with dependency management: when dependencies depend on different versions of the same library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tidying it up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back to the previous version that uses only testmod 2.0.0, if we check the contents of &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; now, we’ll notice something:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;module mod
require github.com/rselbach/testmod v1.0.1
require github.com/rselbach/testmod/v2 v2.0.0&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, Go does not remove a dependency from &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; unless you ask it to. If you have dependencies that you no longer use and want to clean up, you can use the new &lt;code&gt;tidy&lt;/code&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ go mod tidy&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we’re left with only the dependencies that are really being used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vendoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go modules ignores the &lt;code&gt;vendor/&lt;/code&gt; directory by default. The idea is to do away with vendoring. But if we still want to add vendored dependencies to our version control, we can still do it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ go mod vendor&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will create a &lt;code&gt;vendor/&lt;/code&gt; directory under the root of your project containing the source code for all of your dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, &lt;code&gt;go build&lt;/code&gt; will ignore the contents of this directory by default. If you want to build dependencies from the &lt;code&gt;vendor/&lt;/code&gt; directory, you’ll need to ask for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ go build -mod vendor&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect many developers willing to use vendoring will run &lt;code&gt;go build&lt;/code&gt; normally on their development machines and use &lt;code&gt;-mod vendor&lt;/code&gt; in their CI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, Go modules is moving away from the idea of vendoring and towards using a Go module proxy for those who don’t want to depend on the upstream version control services directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are ways to guarantee that &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; will not reach the network at all (e.g. &lt;code&gt;GOPROXY=off&lt;/code&gt;) but these are the subject for a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post may seem a bit daunting, but I tried to explain a lot of things together. The reality is that now Go modules is basically transparent. We import package like always in our code and the &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; command will take care of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we build something, the dependencies will be fetched automatically. It also eliminates the need to use &lt;code&gt;$GOPATH&lt;/code&gt; which was a roadblock for new Go developers who had trouble understanding why things had to go into a specific directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vendoring is (unofficially) being deprecated in favour of using proxies. I may do a separate post about the Go module proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 02:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>robteix</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-CA</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://roberto.selbach.ca/intro-to-go-modules/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is serverless insecure? Let&amp;#039;s find out</title>
<link>http://www.lambdashell.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.lambdashell.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a simple AWS lambda function that does a straight exec. Essentially giving you a shell directly in my AWS infrastructure to just run your commands. A security teams worst nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do whatever you want. Ultimate goal: take over the account, escalate privs or find some sensitive info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configured with all default permissions and settings. This service will sit for a bit and if nothing interesting happens it will be reconfigured very insecurely to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$1,000 Bounty. Found something? Let me know at root@lambdashell.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 20:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vdmq</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.lambdashell.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook addiction linked to staking your self-worth on social acceptance</title>
<link>https://www.psypost.org/2018/08/facebook-addiction-linked-to-staking-your-self-worth-on-social-acceptance-51987</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.psypost.org/2018/08/facebook-addiction-linked-to-staking-your-self-worth-on-social-acceptance-51987</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;More than one billion people use Facebook to connect with others and maintain social relationships. But new research suggests that the social networking website can have an addictive side for some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A study published in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0747563218303339&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Computers in Human Behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; found that people who believed they needed to be socially accepted in order to have worth as a person were at higher risk of using Facebook in compulsive and maladaptive way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous research has examined the relationship between self-esteem and Facebook use. The researchers from Baruch Ivcher School of Psychology sought to expand on the prior work by examining contingencies of self-worth, meaning the contingencies which are viewed as primary sources of self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These contingencies are social acceptance, physical appearance, outdoing others in competition, academic competence, family love and support, being a virtuous or moral person, and God’s love. For those who view social acceptance as an important contingency, feelings of self-worth depend on the approval of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An initial survey of 337 participants with an active Facebook account found that social acceptance contingencies were positively related to Facebook addiction symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, people who agreed with statements such as “My self-esteem depends on the opinions others hold of me” tended to also agree with statements such as “I spend a lot of time thinking about Facebook”, “I am using Facebook in order to forget my personal problems”, and “I use Facebook so much that it has had a negative impact on my job or studies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also conducted a 3-week daily diary study with 80 undergraduate psychology students, which found that levels of Facebook addiction tended to increase on days when levels of social acceptance contingencies were higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“An individual who bases his or her self-worth on being socially accepted is likely to adopt the goal of forming and maintaining social ties and, therefore, may be more intensely affected by the threat or loss of such relationships,” the researchers explained in their study. “Because such individuals strive to boost self-esteem and to avoid others’ rejection, can sometimes lead to maladaptive self-regulation, such as obsessive or addictive Facebook use.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both studies, social acceptance contingencies predicted Facebook addiction over and above global self-esteem levels. The researchers also controlled for the potentially confounding effects of personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the study — like all research — has some limitations. It is unclear whether the relationship between social acceptance contingencies and Facebook addiction can be generalized to other social media platforms, like Instagram or Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0747563218303339&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Contingent self-worth and Facebook addiction&lt;/a&gt;“, was authored by Yaniv Kanat-Maymon, Lian Almog, Rinat Cohen, and Yair Amichai-Hamburger.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 20:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>brahmwg</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook addiction linked to staking your self-worth on social acceptance</og:title>
<og:description>More than one billion people use Facebook to connect with others and maintain social relationships. But new research suggests that the social networking ...</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.psypost.org/2018/08/facebook-addiction-linked-to-staking-your-self-worth-on-social-acceptance-51987</og:url>
<og:image>https://d2ck0sxsjau14o.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/facebook.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.psypost.org/2018/08/facebook-addiction-linked-to-staking-your-self-worth-on-social-acceptance-51987</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Researcher at center of epic fraud remains an enigma to those who exposed him</title>
<link>http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/08/researcher-center-epic-fraud-remains-enigma-those-who-exposed-him</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/08/researcher-center-epic-fraud-remains-enigma-those-who-exposed-him</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;article__header article__header--inline&quot; readability=&quot;25.1484375&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;byline byline--article&quot;&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/author/kai-kupferschmidt&quot;&gt;Kai Kupferschmidt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;time&gt;Aug. 17, 2018 , 9:15 AM&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JAPAN—&lt;/strong&gt;The first thing that went through Alison Avenell's head when she heard Yoshihiro Sato had died was that it might be a trick. It was March 2017, and in the previous years, Avenell, a clinical nutritionist at the University of Aberdeen in the United Kingdom, had spent thousands of hours combing through Sato's papers, together with three colleagues in New Zealand. They had discovered that Sato, a bone researcher at a hospital in southern Japan, had fabricated data for dozens of clinical trials published in international journals. &quot;With so much going on, so much fabrication, you just wonder if it's convenient for the person to go and hide,&quot; Avenell says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her second thought was that Sato might have killed himself. &quot;We have no indication that he committed suicide, but it concerns us,&quot; Avenell said when I met her at her office in late 2017. Three years earlier, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2014/08/senior-riken-scientist-involved-stem-cell-scandal-commits-suicide&quot;&gt;Japanese stem cell scientist Yoshiki Sasai had hanged himself&lt;/a&gt; in the stairwell of the RIKEN Center for Developmental Biology in Kobe after he was caught up in a stem cell scandal. &quot;We were aware of the culture in Japan and the dishonor something like this could bring,&quot; Avenell said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was one more mystery in a deeply unsettling case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sato's fraud was one of the biggest in scientific history. The impact of his fabricated reports—many of them on how to reduce the risk of bone fractures—rippled far and wide. Meta-analyses that included his trials came to the wrong conclusion; professional societies based medical guidelines on his papers. To follow up on studies they did not know were faked, researchers carried out new trials that enrolled thousands of real patients. Exposing Sato's lies and correcting the literature had been a bruising struggle for Avenell and her colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet they could not understand why Sato faked so many studies, or how he got away with it for so long. They puzzled over the role of his co-authors, some of whom had their names on dozens of his papers. (&quot;Do we honestly believe they knew nothing at all about what was going on?&quot; Avenell asked.) They wondered whether other doctors at his hospital read Sato's work—and whether the Japanese scientific community ever questioned how he managed to publish more than 200 papers, many of them ambitious studies that would have taken most researchers years to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tools of science that the group had used—analyzing studies, calculating statistics, writing papers—could reveal fraud. But they could not expose the personal and cultural factors that drove it, or assess its emotional toll. So I set off on a quest that would eventually lead me to the Mitate Hospital in Tagawa, a small town on the island of Kyushu, where Sato had worked in the last 13 years of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I: Suspicion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avenell's own quest began in 2006, when she was combing through dozens of papers for a review evaluating whether vitamin D reduces the risk of bone fractures. In two papers by Sato, she stumbled on a weird coincidence. They described different trials—one in stroke victims, the other in Parkinson's disease patients—but the control and study groups in both studies had the exact same mean body mass index. Looking further, she quickly found several other anomalies. She decided not to include Sato's studies in her analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wasn't the first to notice something was off. In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://n.neurology.org/content/64/5/811.long&quot;&gt;2005 &lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt; paper&lt;/a&gt;, Sato claimed that a drug named risedronate reduces the risk of hip fractures in women who have had a stroke by a stunning 86%. In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://n.neurology.org/content/65/9/1513.full&quot;&gt;polite letter to the journal&lt;/a&gt;, three researchers from the University of Cambridge in the United Kingdom noted that the study was &quot;potentially of great importance,&quot; but marveled that the authors had managed to recruit 374 patients in just 4 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the number of papers he published, he must have spent a very large amount of time on them. I don't understand what his gain was. … There must have been some reason to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;Mark Bolland, University of Auckland&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years later, a letter in what was then the &lt;em&gt;Archives of Internal Medicine&lt;/em&gt; was less polite. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/765620?resultClick=1&quot;&gt;A study of male stroke patients published by Sato&lt;/a&gt; had managed to enroll 280 patients in just 2 months; another one, of &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/765639?resultClick=1&quot;&gt;women with Alzheimer's disease&lt;/a&gt;, recruited a staggering 500 in an equally short period. Sato claimed to have diagnosed all of the Alzheimer's patients himself and done follow-up assessments of all 780 patients every 4 weeks for 18 months. Both studies had very few dropouts, and both showed risedronate, again, to be a resounding success. &quot;We are deeply concerned whether the data provided by Sato et al are valid,&quot; Jutta Halbekath of &lt;em&gt;Arznei-Telegramm&lt;/em&gt;, a Berlin-based bulletin about the drug industry, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/article-abstract/411829&quot;&gt;and her co-authors wrote&lt;/a&gt;. Sato apologized in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/article-abstract/411832?resultClick=1&quot;&gt;published response&lt;/a&gt; and claimed the study had been conducted at three hospitals, not one. &quot;The authors did not describe this fact, the reason being that these hospitals were reluctant to have their names in the article,&quot; he wrote. He didn't name the other hospitals or explain why they wanted to remain anonymous. The journal apparently accepted the explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The letter's authors also spotted a troubling pattern. In addition to the two papers in the &lt;em&gt;Archives of Internal Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, they found 11 further studies by Sato, published elsewhere, that tested whether sunlight, vitamin D, vitamin K, folate, and other drugs could reduce the risk of hip fractures. All but two reported &quot;extremely large effects with significant results,&quot; they noted. But the &lt;em&gt;Archives of Internal Medicine&lt;/em&gt; didn't want to point fingers at other journals. &quot;You may allude to your concern that other papers have similar concerns,&quot; its editors warned Halbekath, &quot;but we cannot allow you to mention those other papers by journal name.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, several researchers had raised red flags and waved them for everyone to see—and then everybody moved on. &quot;The trail just went cold,&quot; Avenell says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II: Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Bolland had never heard of Sato when Avenell first mentioned him in late 2012. She and Bolland, a clinical epidemiologist at the University of Auckland in New Zealand, have never met in person, but they joined forces to write meta-analyses on calcium supplements in 2008, together with Andrew Grey and Greg Gamble, both also at the University of Auckland. One topic the quartet discussed frequently was why meta-analyses on the same topic sometimes reach different conclusions. Avenell mentioned Sato's studies and noted that the effects they reported were so strong that they might swing meta-analyses if they were included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intrigued, Bolland looked up the papers. He, too, was stunned by the large cohorts, the low number of dropouts, and the big effects of almost any treatment tested. &quot;There is nothing that I can think of that produces a 70% to 80% reduction in hip fractures, yet Sato was able to do it consistently in all his trials,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow up on his suspicions, Bolland turned to statistics. When scientists compare a treatment and a control group, they usually report &quot;baseline characteristics&quot; for each—things like age, weight, and sex, or, in osteoporosis studies, bone density and calcium intake. From these values, scientists can calculate p-values that are a measure of the similarity of two groups for a given characteristic; the closer to one the value is, the more the groups resemble each other. Because the groups are randomly selected, the p-values should normally be &quot;equally distributed&quot;; the value for age or weight is just as likely to be between 0 and 0.1 as between 0.9 and 1.0, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Included in systematic reviews, meta-analyses, or treatment guidelines Did not change the outcome Unclear whether outcome changed Changed the outcome Used as (partial) rationale for a new trial 2002 1998 2006 2010 2014 2018 Number of citations by year Trial published Number of patients 628 84 Retracted 32 A 2006 paper on hip fractures in Parkinson’s patients was cited as evidence behind 2008 U.S. College of Physicians treatment guidelines. Other scientists cited a 2005 paper in The Journal of the American Medical Association to help justify five new trials. 0 10 20 0 10 20 0 10 20 Number of papers 0 10 20 30 Total scientific output Clinical trials 1996 2000 2004 2008 2012 Number of patients 0 100 200 300 400 500 600 700 1980 1990 2000 2010 2015 Retracted Not retracted A far-reaching fraud A team of four researchers has worked since 2012 to expose scientific misconduct by Japanese bone researcher Yoshihiro Sato, who published more than 200 papers before he died in 2016. The team has focused on Sato’s 33 clinical trials, together involving 5894 patients. Ripple effects The 12 trials Sato published in high-impact journals have been widely cited. Many were included in meta- analyses, sometimes changing the outcomes, or were translated into treatment guidelines. Other researchers used Sato’s fake data as part of the rationale for launching new clinical studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(GRAPHIC) J. YOU/&lt;em&gt;SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;; (DATA) F. STEWART, A. AVENELL, A. GREY, G. GAMBLE, AND M. BOLLAND; WEB OF SCIENCE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolland extracted the baseline characteristics from the 33 clinical trials Sato had published at the time, more than 500 variables all in all, and calculated their p-values. More than half were above 0.8, he found. &quot;That just shouldn't happen,&quot; he says. &quot;The randomized groups were incredibly similar.&quot; There was just one plausible explanation, he says: Sato had fabricated data for both groups and had made them more similar than they would ever be in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team felt it had a damning indictment. &quot;I thought: ‘This is so convincing. Everybody is going to believe this,’&quot; Avenell says. Still, &quot;It needed detailed statistical refereeing, and it needed to be published by a journal so that other affected journals would take note,&quot; she adds. So they wrote their accusation as a scientific paper. All they had to do was publish it and wait for researchers, journals, and institutions to react, investigate, and retract. Or so they thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III: Accusation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2013, the team submitted the manuscript to &lt;em&gt;The Journal of the American Medical Association&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt;), the highest profile journal &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/200453&quot;&gt;Sato had published in&lt;/a&gt;, and one it felt might have the resources for an in-depth investigation. After reviewing the evidence, &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt; Editor-in-Chief Howard Bauchner told the team the editors would ask Sato and, if necessary, his institution to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years later, in April 2015, &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt; told the researchers the hospital had not responded, and it would publish an &quot;expression of concern&quot;—a short note to flag Sato's &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt; paper as suspicious. It would not publish the whistleblowers' paper, however; if the team had concerns about other papers, it should contact the journals that had published them, Bauchner said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four researchers were shocked. &quot;To find out after waiting 2 years that in fact nothing much had really happened and, other than an expression of concern, was going to happen in &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt;, was quite frustrating,&quot; Bolland says. (Bauchner declined to answer &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;'s questions about the case.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the paper was rejected by &lt;em&gt;JAMA Internal Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, which had also published Sato's work. The &lt;em&gt;Journal of Bone and Mineral Research&lt;/em&gt;, a highly rated journal in the osteoporosis field, said it would investigate Sato's papers, but would not publish the manuscript either. The editors of &lt;em&gt;Trials&lt;/em&gt;, which had not published Sato's work, said it would not be appropriate to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolland became demoralized. The other three persuaded him not to give up. &quot;If you ever embark on something like this, make sure you have a good support team,&quot; he says now. Avenell, too, was sometimes despondent. Whereas the other three researchers at least saw each other in Auckland, she was on her own, frustrated, in the dreary, gray town of Aberdeen. Sometimes, she says, she would just sit in a corner of her open floor plan office and cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journals don’t really like going back to investigate when things go wrong. …They complain that it’s time-consuming and laborious and difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;Andrew Grey, University of Auckland&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, in June 2015, came a small success: The &lt;em&gt;Journal of Bone and Mineral Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jbmr.2725&quot;&gt;retracted one of the 33 trials&lt;/a&gt; the team had analyzed. A few other journals followed suit in the months after. But some seemed irritated by the group's persistence. &quot;It is apparent that the responses to the &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt; investigation by Dr. Sato and his institution have been either inadequate or not forthcoming,&quot; Grey wrote to Bauchner in December 2015. &quot;At what point will &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt; consider more decisive action, such as retraction?&quot; &quot;We will consider your opinion about how you think it best we should conduct the investigation,&quot; Bauchner responded. &quot;We often hear from people how they think we should perform our responsibilities as editors.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what Bolland calls &quot;really just the last throw of the dice,&quot; that same month the group submitted the paper to &lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt;, where Sato had published three papers about bone fractures in patients with neurological disease. When it was accepted 8 months later, Avenell cried again. &quot;I'm not one usually given to showing such emotion, especially when all I have is a computer screen and emails to look at,&quot; she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Journals don't really like going back to investigate when things go wrong,&quot; Grey concludes. &quot;They complain that it's time-consuming and laborious and difficult.&quot; (It is all of that, says Avenell, &quot;and no one ever thanks you for it.&quot;) The group says investigations of this scale should not be handled by journals or institutions; it has suggested a levy on journals to fund an independent investigative body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time &lt;a href=&quot;http://n.neurology.org/content/early/2016/11/09/WNL.0000000000003387&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt; published the investigation in December 2016&lt;/a&gt;, 10 of the 33 trials had been retracted, all but one by journals the team had contacted. One month later, Avenell received an email from an editor with troubling news. Sato was dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IV: Ripples&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When scientists die, their published papers live on—even if they're based on lies. Downloaded in seconds from anywhere in the world, fake results continue to steal other scientists' time, influencing their choice of which research avenues to follow and which trials to design and seek ethical approval for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, 21 of Sato's 33 trials have been retracted by the journals or Sato himself; Avenell has crossed them off a list taped next to her computer with a red marker. But now the team is following the ripples that the studies caused, focusing, for the time being, on a dozen papers published in the journals with the highest impact factors. Together, these studies reported results for 3182 participants. They have been referenced more than 1000 times, and 23 systematic reviews or meta-analyses have included one or more of the 12 trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strokejournal.org/article/S1052-3057(14)00304-8/pdf&quot;&gt;One meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt;, which found drugs called bisphosphonates to be highly effective in preventing hip fractures in elderly patients with stroke or Parkinson's, is based entirely on eight trials from Sato, as he was the only one to study the issue. A key conclusion &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hindawi.com/journals/tswj/2012/872173/&quot;&gt;in another meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; rests only on Sato's four studies on bone mineral density in Alzheimer's patients. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/410550&quot;&gt;Two other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mdpi.com/2072-6643/7/5/3322&quot;&gt;meta-analyses&lt;/a&gt; would probably come to different conclusions if Sato's trials were removed, Avenell says. One of those, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/410550&quot;&gt;review showing that vitamin K helps prevent fractures&lt;/a&gt;, was the basis of &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs11657-012-0109-9&quot;&gt;2011 Japanese guidelines&lt;/a&gt; that recommend the supplement for people at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fake trials led to further, real research. Eight trials referenced at least one of Sato's fabricated papers in explaining the rationale for the trial. Researchers in the Netherlands, for instance, launched a huge study in 2008 to determine whether B vitamins could help prevent hip fractures. Two previous studies found they didn't, but Sato had observed &quot;a large protective effect&quot; in elderly women. &quot;Given the conflicting results and low generalizability to the general older population, further investigation is needed,&quot; the Dutch researchers wrote to explain their thinking. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/ajcn/article/100/6/1578/4576655&quot;&gt;2-year study in 2919 elderly people found no effect of the vitamins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;The fraud has also drawn attention to the two co-authors whose names appear on Sato's papers most often. One is Kei Satoh, president of Hirosaki University, in a small town at the northern tip of Japan's main island, Honshu. Sato worked at Hirosaki University, where he collaborated with Satoh, until 2003; even after he left for Mitate Hospital, 1600 kilometers to the southwest, he and Satoh remained frequent co-authors, including on 13 of the 33 clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entity entity-paragraphs-item paragraphs-item-image align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure__head&quot;&gt;&lt;img sizes=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/350SecondaryIllustration_HiRes.jpg?itok=QVIYOzrq&quot; srcset=&quot;//www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/350SecondaryIllustration_HiRes.jpg?itok=QVIYOzrq 1w, //www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__699w__no_aspect/public/350SecondaryIllustration_HiRes.jpg?itok=OnDasTFN 700w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;SARA GIRONI CARNEVALE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Satoh—whose name, confusingly, is sometimes spelled Sato—did not respond to &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;'s emails. In a short letter to Grey, Hirosaki University Vice President Chizuko Kohri wrote last November that the university had asked &quot;three outside experts&quot; to investigate after the &lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt; paper was published. The committee investigated 38 papers, Kohri wrote. Of these, Sato had already retracted seven and wanted to retract another seven. The committee &quot;concluded that there was research misconduct in these 14 papers,&quot; Kohri wrote, but that Sato alone was responsible. According to Japanese press reports, Satoh maintains that he only corrected the English in the papers. As a sign of contrition, he gave up 10% of his salary for 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Sato's most important collaborator, however, was Jun Iwamoto. A board member of the Osteoporosis Society of Japan, Iwamoto was a senior lecturer at Keio University in Tokyo—one of the country's most prestigious—until 2017, when his contract wasn't renewed in the wake of the Sato affair. He and Sato collaborated for more than a decade and published more than 130 papers together, including 25 of the 33 clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;A panel at Keio University has been investigating Iwamoto's clinical trials. Iwamoto told the panel that he first contacted Sato in 1998, when Iwamoto was working at the New York University Winthrop Hospital in Mineola. In 2002 they started to put each other's name on every paper they authored. Still, Iwamoto claims he was unaware of Sato's practice. &quot;We talked to Dr. Iwamoto and in most of the papers which Dr. Sato published, which included Dr. Iwamoto's name, Dr. Iwamoto did not know that his name was included,&quot; says cancer researcher Hideyuki Saya, who heads the investigation. The panel was &quot;very shocked&quot; by this, Saya says. At the same time, he says, &quot;For Dr. Iwamoto it was an honor to put his name on Dr. Sato's [papers] even though he did not know much about the content.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Although considered highly irregular today, such &quot;gift authorships&quot; were common in the recent past, Saya argues. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/ijjs.12016&quot;&gt;2014 study in the &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Japanese Sociology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; found they are particularly common in Japan. &quot;We speculate that most natural science researchers in Japan may be either confused about or struggle with the situation where the strict global criteria conflict with specific local cultures that often condone gift and ghost authorships,&quot; the researchers wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Saya says the seven trials listing Iwamoto as the first author appear not to be fabricated. Data for the first four of those no longer exist, but Iwamoto can't be faulted for that, says Saya, because under rules at the time they were conducted, he had to save the data for only 5 years. Iwamoto did provide data for three more recent trials. &quot;That data, it seems, was really collected,&quot; Saya says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;But Avenell and her colleagues say they have uncovered many problems in trials on which Iwamoto was a first author as well. For instance, two of them, which tested a drug named alendronate, seem to include the same group of 25 patients, as indicated by their average age, height, serum calcium, and numerous other characteristics, but the two papers give different recruitment dates and inclusion criteria, and some of the outcome data differ. Saya chalks problems in the papers up to &quot;immaturity.&quot; &quot;We do not think there is fabrication,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Iwamoto now works at another hospital, Saya says. &quot;He has a very nice reputation.&quot; When I mention that I would like to talk to him, he suggests I should not. &quot;He is very exhausted,&quot; he says. &quot;Better not to contact him at this moment.&quot; Otherwise &quot;the same thing&quot; might happen that happened with Sato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&quot;What happened with Sato?&quot; I ask. &quot;People say he committed suicide over this,&quot; Saya says. But he doesn't know whether that's true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V: Enigma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Sato's fraudulent work has propelled him to No. 6 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/the-retraction-watch-leaderboard/&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch's list of researchers who have racked up the most retractions&lt;/a&gt;. At the top is Japanese anesthesiologist Yoshitaka Fujii, with 183 retractions; his frequent co-author Yuhji Saitoh, also from Japan, is at 10th place, while Japanese endocrinologist Shigeaki Kato is No. 8. Iwamoto is at No. 9. That means half of the top 10 are Japanese researchers. Yet only about 5% of published research comes from Japan. What explains the number of prolific Japanese fraudsters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Michiie Sakamoto, who is leading another investigation at Keio University, into Iwamoto's studies in animals, says it has to do with respect. &quot;In Japan, we don't usually doubt a professor,&quot; he says. &quot;We basically believe people. We think we don't need strict rules to watch them carefully.&quot; As a result, researchers faking their results may be exposed only after they have racked up many publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Outside researchers may also be less likely to question anomalous results from Japan. Several early critics of Sato's work say they thought at first that his unusual results might be due to something uniquely Japanese. One case in point: In 2003, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1738449/&quot;&gt;Sato published a study&lt;/a&gt; on data from 40 patients with a very rare affliction named neuroleptic malignant syndrome, collected over 3 years. In a letter to the journal, a U.K. neurologist said he and his colleagues &quot;could only recall two such cases in living memory&quot;—but instead of casting doubt on the study, they said it was interesting that the syndrome seemed so prevalent in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Japan, we don’t usually doubt a professor. We basically believe people. We think we don’t need strict rules to watch them carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;Michiie Sakamoto, Keio University&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But none of that explains why Sato decided to embark on his fraud—and nobody seems to be able to shed much light on that question. &quot;Given the number of papers he published, he must have spent a very large amount of time on them,&quot; Bolland says. &quot;I don't understand what his gain was. … There must have been some reason to do it.&quot; The Keio University panel is just as puzzled. &quot;We discussed this a lot in the committee,&quot; Saya says. It might have been like a hobby, he suggests. A thrill. Saya uses the word &quot;&lt;em&gt;otaku&lt;/em&gt;,&quot; a Japanese term often applied to people who read manga obsessively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I might find more clarity at the place where Sato perpetrated the fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitate Hospital is not known for its scientific excellence. Except for one 2006 paper on schizophrenia, its entire research output over the past 20 years was produced by Sato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hospital is a sprawling complex of beige buildings set against green hills. I walk up to the reception. It's quiet, no patients in sight. The receptionist does not understand me and asks me to write down what I want to say. &quot;I am a journalist,&quot; I write. &quot;I would like to talk to the director about Yoshihiro Sato.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her eyes widen as she reads the name and she calls a nurse who speaks English. The nurse calls the director. &quot;He does not want to talk to you,&quot; she says after she hangs up. We stand awkwardly next to each at the reception desk, both embarrassed. It is clear that everybody wants me to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I walk back to the bus stop I look back at the hospital. It is an unlikely place for an unlikely story. What did people here think about the research superstar in their midst? What do they remember about the man?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effects of Sato's fraud are still rippling out: citations, retractions, investigations. But the place at the epicenter of the disaster reveals nothing. Mitate Hospital squats silently in the midday sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VI: Epilogue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hours before I leave Japan, I meet Iwamoto's lawyer, Satoshi Ogawa. We sit in the lobby of my Tokyo hotel, our words echoing from the bare walls and the marble floor. Ogawa says Iwamoto agreed to our conversation because he wants me to understand his point of view. &quot;From his perspective, he is a victim.&quot; Avenell's team, says Ogawa, is now giving Iwamoto's papers a level of scrutiny that is unfair and is causing his client a great deal of distress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ogawa says Sato wrote a detailed account of his interactions with Iwamoto a year before he died. He shows me an English version of the document, signed by Sato and witnessed by Ogawa and a notary. &quot;I strongly requested Mr. Iwamoto to include my name as an author on the articles for which Mr. Iwamoto was the lead author,&quot; Sato wrote. &quot;I also started including Mr. Iwamoto's name in the articles for which I myself was the lead author.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The letter does not mention fraud, however. &quot;I couldn't force him to confess,&quot; Ogawa says. &quot;I think he had a mental illness.&quot; His emails were not logical, he says. &quot;To tell the truth, I predicted that he would commit suicide.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Suicide.&lt;/em&gt; Is he sure that's what happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I received the information from the lawyer of Mr. Sato,&quot; Ogawa says. Sato also left a note, he says, and he paraphrases it: &quot;I am very sorry for Mr. Iwamoto. I decided to commit suicide.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I call Avenell after my return from Japan and tell her what I have learned, there is stunned silence at first. &quot;That's what we were dreading,&quot; she says. &quot;That's horrible, really horrible.&quot; Exposing the misconduct was important, she says. &quot;Could we have done it without Sato committing suicide? So that he felt less guilty? I just don't know.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later she follows up with an email, still astonished at &quot;how such a small piece of data analysis a long time ago can end up with someone dying.&quot; As a clinician and a researcher, Avenell wrote, she knows her work can eventually make the difference between life and death. &quot;But seldom is the connection between a clinician and another human being's death so obvious.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 19:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>maxerickson</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/08/researcher-center-epic-fraud-remains-enigma-those-who-exposed-him</og:url>
<og:title>Researcher at the center of an epic fraud remains an enigma to those who exposed him</og:title>
<og:description>After years of detective work, it's still unclear why a Japanese doctor faked dozens of clinical trials</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/article_main_large/public/720MainIllustration_HiRes.jpg?itok=uTr6RdeD</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/08/researcher-center-epic-fraud-remains-enigma-those-who-exposed-him</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The new MacBook Pros with T2 chips do indeed kernel panic randomly</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/bdkjones/status/1030140659729133568</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/bdkjones/status/1030140659729133568</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Your tweet says &quot;MacBook Pros&quot;. Plural. I assume that means you have successfully replicated this error on other machines. Right? And I assume you did a full macOS reinstall to see if the problem went away before trumpeting to the entire world. Right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 19:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>miles</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/bdkjones/status/1030140659729133568</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>HUD Files Housing Discrimination Complaint Against Facebook</title>
<link>https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/HUD_No_18_085</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/HUD_No_18_085</guid>
<description>&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;4&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;HUD No. 18-085&lt;br/&gt;HUD Public Affairs&lt;br/&gt;(202) 708-0685&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR RELEASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Friday&lt;br/&gt;August 17, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HUD FILES HOUSING DISCRIMINATION COMPLAINT AGAINST FACEBOOK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Secretary-initiated complaint alleges platform allows advertisers to discriminate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON – The U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) announced today a formal complaint against Facebook for violating the Fair Housing Act by allowing landlords and home sellers to use its advertising platform to engage in housing discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HUD claims Facebook enables advertisers to control which users receive housing-related ads based upon the recipient's race, color, religion, sex, familial status, national origin, disability, and/or zip code. Facebook then invites advertisers to express unlawful preferences by offering discriminatory options, allowing them to effectively limit housing options for these protected classes under the guise of 'targeted advertising.' &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/PIH/documents/HUD_01-18-0323_Complaint.pdf&quot;&gt;Read HUD's complaint against Facebook.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Fair Housing Act prohibits housing discrimination including those who might limit or deny housing options with a click of a mouse,&quot; said Anna María Farías, HUD's Assistant Secretary for Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity. &quot;When Facebook uses the vast amount of personal data it collects to help advertisers to discriminate, it's the same as slamming the door in someone's face.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fair Housing Act prohibits discrimination in housing transactions including print and online advertisement on the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, sex, disability, or familial status. HUD's Secretary-initiated complaint follows the Department's investigation into Facebook's advertising platform which includes targeting tools that enable advertisers to filter prospective tenants or homebuyers based on these protected classes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, HUD's complaint alleges Facebook's platform violates the Fair Housing Act. It enables advertisers to, among other things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;display housing ads either only to men or women;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not show ads to Facebook users interested in an &quot;assistance dog,&quot; &quot;mobility scooter,&quot; &quot;accessibility&quot; or &quot;deaf culture&quot;;   &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not show ads to users whom Facebook categorizes as interested in &quot;child care&quot; or &quot;parenting,&quot; or show ads only to users with children above a specified age;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to display/not display ads to users whom Facebook categorizes as interested in a particular place of worship, religion or tenet, such as the &quot;Christian Church,&quot; &quot;Sikhism,&quot; &quot;Hinduism,&quot; or the &quot;Bible.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not show ads to users whom Facebook categorizes as interested in &quot;Latin America,&quot; &quot;Canada,&quot; &quot;Southeast Asia,&quot; &quot;China,&quot; &quot;Honduras,&quot; or &quot;Somalia.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;draw a red line around zip codes and then not display ads to Facebook users who live in specific zip codes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Facebook promotes its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/business/success/quadrant-homes&quot;&gt;advertising targeting platform for housing purposes with &quot;success stories&lt;/a&gt;&quot; for finding &quot;the perfect homeowners,&quot; &quot;reaching home buyers,&quot; &quot;attracting renters&quot; and &quot;personalizing property ads.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, today the U.S. Attorney for the Southern District of New York (SDNY) filed a statement of interest, joined in by HUD, in U.S. District Court on behalf of a number of private litigants challenging Facebook's advertising platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;HUD Secretary-Initiated Complaints&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secretary of HUD may file a fair housing complaint directly against those whom the Department believes may be in violation of the Fair Housing Act. Secretary-Initiated Complaints are appropriate in cases, among others, involving significant issues that are national in scope or when the Department is made aware of potential violations of the Act and broad public interest relief is warranted or where HUD does not know of a specific aggrieved person or injured party that is willing or able to come forward. A Fair Housing Act complaint, including a Secretary initiated complaint, is not a determination of liability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Secretary-Initiated Complaint will result in a formal fact-finding investigation. The party against whom the complaint is filed will be provided notice and an opportunity to respond. If HUD's investigation results in a determination that reasonable cause exists that there has been a violation of the Fair Housing Act, a charge of discrimination may be filed. Throughout the process, HUD will seek conciliation and voluntary resolution. Charges may be resolved through settlement, through referral to the Department of Justice, or through an administrative determination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year marks the 50th anniversary of the Fair Housing Act. In commemoration, HUD, local communities, and fair housing organizations across the country have coordinated a variety of activities to enhance fair housing awareness, highlight HUD's fair housing enforcement efforts, and end housing discrimination in the nation. For a list of activities, log onto &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hud.gov/fairhousingis50&quot;&gt;www.hud.gov/fairhousingis50&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persons who believe they have experienced discrimination may file a complaint by contacting HUD's Office of Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity at (800) 669-9777 (voice) or (800) 927-9275 (TTY).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 19:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>google_censors</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/HUD_No_18_085</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stacking concrete blocks is a surprisingly efficient way to store energy</title>
<link>https://qz.com/1355672/stacking-concrete-blocks-is-a-surprisingly-efficient-way-to-store-energy/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://qz.com/1355672/stacking-concrete-blocks-is-a-surprisingly-efficient-way-to-store-energy/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Thanks to the modern electric grid, you have access to electricity whenever you want. But the grid only works when electricity is generated in the same amounts as it is consumed. That said, it’s impossible to get the balance right all the time. So operators make grids more flexible by adding ways to store excess electricity for when production drops or consumption rises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;About 96% of the world’s energy-storage capacity comes in the form of one technology: pumped hydro. Whenever generation exceeds demand, the excess electricity is used to pump water up a dam. When demand exceeds generation, that water is allowed to fall—thanks to gravity—and the potential energy turns turbines to produce electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;But pumped-hydro storage requires particular geographies, with access to water and to reservoirs at different altitudes. It’s the reason that about three-quarters of all pumped hydro storage has been built &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1295901/why-energy-storage-is-key-to-a-global-climate-breakthrough/&quot;&gt;in only 10 countries&lt;/a&gt;. The trouble is the world needs to add a lot more energy storage, if we are to continue to add the intermittent solar and wind power necessary to cut our dependence on fossil fuels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;A startup called Energy Vault thinks it has a viable alternative to pumped-hydro: Instead of using water and dams, the startup uses concrete blocks and cranes. It has been operating in stealth mode until today (Aug. 18), when its existence will be announced at &lt;a href=&quot;https://kentpresents.org/&quot;&gt;Kent Presents&lt;/a&gt;, an ideas festival in Connecticut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;On a hot July morning, I traveled to Biasca, Switzerland, about two hours north of Milan, Italy, where Energy Vault has built a demonstration plant, about a tenth the size of a full-scale operation. The whole thing—from idea to a functional unit—took about nine months and less than $2 million to accomplish. If this sort of low-tech, low-cost innovation could help solve even just a few parts of the huge energy-storage problem, maybe the energy transition the world needs won’t be so hard after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;🌍&lt;em&gt; Quartz is running a series called The Race to Zero Emissions that explores the challenges and opportunities of energy-storage technologies. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2ioY0AA&quot;&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt; to be the first to know when stories are published.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;container _5e420 quartz&quot;&gt;Concrete plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;The science underlying Energy Vault’s technology is simple. When you lift something against gravity, you &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1302711/to-hit-climate-goals-bill-gates-and-his-billionaire-friends-are-betting-on-energy-storage/&quot;&gt;store energy in it&lt;/a&gt;. When you later let it fall, you can retrieve that energy. Because concrete is a lot denser than water, lifting a block of concrete requires—and can, therefore, store—a lot more energy than an equal-sized tank of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Bill Gross, a long-time US entrepreneur, and Andrea Pedretti, a serial Swiss inventor, developed the Energy Vault system that applies this science. Here’s how it works: A 120-meter (nearly 400-foot) tall, six-armed crane stands in the middle. In the discharged state, concrete cylinders weighing 35 metric tons each are neatly stacked around the crane far below the crane arms. When there is excess solar or wind power, a computer algorithm directs one or more crane arms to locate a concrete block, with the help of a camera attached to the crane arm’s trolley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_5fc35 quartz&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_83471&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/energy-vault-landscape_colorcorrected.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=940&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy Vault&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Simulation of a large-scale Energy Vault plant.
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Once the crane arm locates and hooks onto a concrete block, a motor starts, powered by the excess electricity on the grid, and lifts the block off the ground. Wind could cause the block to move like a pendulum, but the crane’s trolley is programmed to counter the movement. As a result, it can smoothly lift the block, and then place it on top of another stack of blocks—higher up off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;The system is “fully charged” when the crane has created a tower of concrete blocks around it. The total energy that can be stored in the tower is 20 megawatt-hours (MWh), enough to power 2,000 Swiss homes for a whole day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;When the grid is running low, the motors spring back into action—except now, instead of consuming electricity, the motor is driven in reverse by the gravitational energy, and thus generates electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;container _5e420 quartz&quot;&gt;Big up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;The innovation in Energy Vault’s plant is not the hardware. Cranes and motors have been around for decades, and companies like ABB and Siemens have optimized them for maximum efficiency. The round-trip efficiency of the system, which is the amount of energy recovered for every unit of energy used to lift the blocks, is about 85%—comparable to lithium-ion batteries which offer upto 90%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Pedretti’s main work as the chief technology officer has been figuring out how to design software to automate contextually relevant operations, like hooking and unhooking concrete blocks, and to counteract pendulum-like movements during the lifting and lowering of those blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Energy Vault keeps costs low because it uses off-the-shelf commercial hardware. Surprisingly, concrete blocks could prove to be the most expensive part of the energy tower. Concrete is much cheaper than, say, a lithium-ion battery, but Energy Vault would need a lot of concrete to build hundreds of 35-metric-ton blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;So Pedretti found another solution. He’s developed a machine that can mix substances that cities often pay to get rid off, such as gravel or building waste, along with cement to create low-cost concrete blocks. The cost saving comes from having to use only a sixth of the amount of cement that would otherwise have been needed if the concrete were used for building construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_5fc35 quartz&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_83471&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/andre-pedretti-energy-vault-rob-piconi.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=940&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akshat Rathi for Quartz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Rob Piconi (left) and Andrea Pedretti.
&lt;h2 class=&quot;container _5e420 quartz&quot;&gt;The storage challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;The demonstration plant I saw in Biasca is much smaller than the planned commercial version. It has a 20-meter-tall, single-armed crane that lifts blocks weighing 500 kg each. But it does almost all the things its full-scale cousin, which the company is actively looking to sell right now, would do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Robert Piconi has spent this summer visiting countries in Africa and Asia. The CEO of Energy Vault is excited to find customers for its plants in those parts of the world. The startup also has a sales team in the US and it now has orders to build its first commercial units in early 2019. The company won’t share details of those orders, but the unique characteristics of its energy-storage solution mean we can make a fairly educated guess at what the projects will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Energy-storage experts broadly categorize energy-storage into three groups, distinguished by the amount of energy storage needed and the cost of storing that energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;First, expensive technologies, such as lithium-ion batteries, can be used to store a few hours worth of energy—in the range of tens or hundreds of MWh. These could be charged during the day, using solar panels for example, and then discharged when the sun isn’t around. But lithium-ion batteries for the electric grid &lt;a href=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=1355672&amp;amp;action=edit&quot;&gt;currently cost&lt;/a&gt; between $280 and $350 per kWh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Cheaper technologies, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1302711/to-hit-climate-goals-bill-gates-and-his-billionaire-friends-are-betting-on-energy-storage/&quot;&gt;flow batteries&lt;/a&gt; (which use high-energy liquid chemicals to hold energy) can be used to store weeks worth of energy—in the range of hundreds or thousands of MWh. This second category of energy storage could then be used, for instance, when there’s a lull in wind supply for a week or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;The third category doesn’t exist yet. In theory, yet-to-be-invented, extra-cheap technologies could store months worth of energy—in the range of tens or hundreds of thousands of MWh—which would be used to deal with interseasonal demands. For example, Mumbai hits peak consumption in the summer when air conditioners are on full blast, whereas London peaks in winters because of household heating. Ideally, energy captured in one season could be stored for months during low-use seasons, and then deployed later in the high-use seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;container _5e420 quartz&quot;&gt;David vs Goliath&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Piconi estimates that by the time Energy Vault builds its 10th or so 35-MWh plant, it can bring costs down to about $150 per kWh. That means it can’t fill the needs of the third category of energy-storage use; to do that, costs would have to be closer to $10 per kWh. In theory, at the current capacity and price point, it could compete in the second category—if it could find a customer that wanted Energy Vault to build dozens of plants for a single grid. Realistically, Energy Vault’s best bet is to compete in the first category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;That said, some experts told Quartz that the cost of lithium-ion batteries, the current dominant battery technology, could fall to about $100 per kWh, which would make them cheaper even than Energy Vault when it comes to storing days or weeks worth of energy. And because batteries are compact, they can be transported vast distances. Most of the lithium-ion batteries in smartphones used all over the world, for example, are made in East Asia. Energy Vault’s concrete blocks will have to be built on-site, and each 35 MWh system would need a circular piece of land about 100 meters (300 feet) in diameter. Batteries need a fraction of that space to store the same amount of energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Batteries do have some limitations. The maximum life of lithium-ion batteries, for example, is 20 or so years. They also lose their capacity to store energy over time. And there aren’t yet reliable ways to recycle lithium-ion batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Energy Vault’s plant can operate for 30 years with little maintenance and almost no fade in capacity. Its concrete blocks also use waste materials. So Piconi is confident that there’s still a niche that Energy Vault can fill: Places that have abundant access to land and building material, combined with the desire to have storage technologies that last for decades without fading in capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, whether or not Energy Vault succeeds, it does make a strong case for the argument that, while everyone else is out looking for high-tech, futuristic battery innovation, there may be real value in thinking about how to apply low-tech solutions to 21st-century problems. Energy Vault built a functional test plant in just nine months, spending relative pennies. It’s a signal of sorts that some of the answers to our energy-storage problems may still be sitting hidden in plain sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was updated with information about Energy Vault’s first commercial-unit orders.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;🌍&lt;em&gt; Quartz is running a series called The Race to Zero Emissions that explores the challenges and opportunities of energy-storage technologies. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2ioY0AA&quot;&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt; to be the first to know when stories are published.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 17:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nabla9</dc:creator>
<og:description>To deal with variable solar and wind power, the startup Energy Vault is coming out of stealth mode to offer alternatives to lithium-ion batteries.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/energy-vault-landscape-x.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1400</og:image>
<og:title>Stacking concrete blocks is a surprisingly efficient way to store energy</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://qz.com/1355672/stacking-concrete-blocks-is-a-surprisingly-efficient-way-to-store-energy/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://qz.com/1355672/stacking-concrete-blocks-is-a-surprisingly-efficient-way-to-store-energy/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mastodon Is Better Than Twitter: Elevator Pitch</title>
<link>https://www.codesections.com/blog/mastodon-elevator-pitch/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.codesections.com/blog/mastodon-elevator-pitch/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Mastodon is a newcomer social media platform that is a lot like Twitter—short messages, followers, hashtags, all that. But Mastodon is much better than Twitter, and not just because being totally ad-free and keeping chronological timelines make it far more enjoyable to use (though that certainly helps!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that is nice, but the real advantage Mastodon has over Twitter is that Mastodon is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; an &lt;a href=&quot;http://shamusyoung.com/twentysidedtale/?p=41853&quot;&gt;outrage machine that's corroding our ability to view our politic opponents as real humans, deserving of sympathy and understanding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain how much better Mastodon is, I'm going to give you three examples of &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; Mastodon is better, and then I'll step back and talk about &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; Mastodon is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-retweets-to-boosts&quot;&gt;From Retweets to Boosts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most pernicious parts of Twitter is how people will retweet something dumb, offensive, or awful that an opponent said, along with a message mocking that opponent. Over time, this leads people on all sides of an issue to see only a distorted caricature of their opponents, comprised of an amalgam of all the worst features of that group. (This phenomenon of cherry-picking the worst bits of an opposing group &lt;a href=&quot;http://slatestarcodex.com/2014/05/12/weak-men-are-superweapons/&quot;&gt;exists independently of Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, but Twitter makes it much, much worse.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Mastodon solve this issue? Well, Mastodon doesn't have retweets; it has &quot;boosts&quot;. Boosts are essentially like retweets, with one key difference: there's no option to add your own commentary. You simply &lt;em&gt;can't&lt;/em&gt; post something awful with a message saying how awful it is—all you can do is boost something awful without commentary. What's more, the name itself—&quot;boost&quot;—draws attention to a fact that Twitter does its best to obscure: by boosting something you disagree with, you're ultimately giving that viewpoint &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; exposure, not less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, Mastodon users basically never boost toots to say how wrong they are, and there isn't an issue with armies of followers descending on the original author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mastodon-is-local-while-still-being-global&quot;&gt;Mastodon Is Local (while still being global)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Twitter, everyone belongs to a single, global Twitter, with a single set of moderation policies spanning every group individual on the service. If you get banned from Twitter, you're banned from &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Mastodon, you don't really join Mastodon itself. Instead, you join a particular server (called an &quot;instance&quot;). Your instance might have a few hundred people and a moderator or two—just the right scale to keep the discussion civil without degenerating into bureaucratic rules-lawyering. And, because you get a &quot;local&quot; feed of all posts on your instance in addition to posts from people you follow, your instance really can start to feel like a community. Finally, with instances, you keep control: if you find that you don't like the moderation policies or culture of a particular instance, you're always free to pick up and move to a different one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This neatly solves Twitter's huge problem with moderation—as Mastodon grows, the number of mods will inherently scale with that growth. Yet, even as their number grows, they'll stay part of (and accountable to) a relatively small community on their home instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Mastodon would be pretty useless if it only let you talk to a few hundred people, so it doesn't impose that limit at all. You can follow &lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt;, regardless of what instance they call home. The only difference is that if you have a problem with them, then you'd complain to &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; instance's moderators rather than to your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what stops people from setting up instances that allow for any sort of awful content and then pestering the rest of us? Well, they &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt;, but Mastodon lets you or your moderators decide to block entire instances. If a particular instance won't mind its own users, then it will likely find that few other instances want anything to do with it—or at least that it's limited to equally laissez-faire instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-user-interface-that-encourages-thoughtfulness&quot;&gt;A User Interface that Encourages Thoughtfulness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastodon's user interface provides the very prominent option to hide a portion of a post behind a screen that is only removed when and if the user chooses. This is a great format for hiding the punchline in jokes or concealing spoilers. More importantly, it's also commonly used to hide controversial posts—including posts about politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this comes down to is &lt;strong&gt;control&lt;/strong&gt;. This pattern of tagging politics and letting the reader decide whether they want to engage with them puts the reader back in control; they can chose to engage with politics—and many do! But if they don't want to (or don't want to right now), they also have the option not to view those posts. And that's not the only way the Mastodon UI puts the reader back in control; for example, it also has very powerful options for hiding toots based on keywords to give you a middle ground between unfollowing someone and seeing every toot they ever make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I acknowledge that some of this is just a cultural practice; having political toots hidden is dependent on Mastodon users recognizing how corrosive political discussions can be and opting to give their readers control over when and if they see those toots. But it's a cultural practice that the technology nudges people towards with good user-interface design, and it's a cultural practice that, at this point, is firmly established.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-why-twitter-is-in-the-outrage-business-mastodon-isn-t-a-business&quot;&gt;The Why: Twitter Is in the Outrage Business; Mastodon Isn't a Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter is a business that makes money (… er, &lt;em&gt;tries&lt;/em&gt; to make money) by selling ads. To maximize ad revenue, they want to keep you on Twitter for as long as they possibly can, which means making sure their content is as engaging as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But often, tweets are at their most engaging when they're at their most enraging. Any tweet that keeps people clicking and talking—even if they're talking about how awful the other side is—is a tweet that keeps people around to view ads. Outrage is good for Twitter's bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's why Twitter isn't—and will never be—as healthy a community as Mastodon is. Mastodon's innovations aren't &lt;em&gt;technologically&lt;/em&gt; that challenging (I mean, a lot of the tech is pretty cool, but it's nothing Twitter couldn't copy if they really wanted to). No, the reason that Mastodon has all these advantages is that they &lt;em&gt;aren't&lt;/em&gt; advantages from Twitter's perspective. From Twitter's perspective, anything that makes people less likely to angrily retweet a rival's obnoxious view is a loss, pure and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Twitter doesn't have any choice in the matter, either. Even if they wanted to sacrifice their ad revenues out of a desire to improve the quality of public discourse, they couldn't. Twitter is a public company, funded by investor money; they thus owe a legal duty to make as much money for their investors as they can. Twitter can't, and won't, stop prioritizing ad revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastodon, on the other hand, isn't profit motivated and never will be. At the top, Mastodon is a small, open-source project &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/mastodon&quot;&gt;funded on Patreon&lt;/a&gt;. Mastodon can afford to stay small, because it's not trying to be centralized—the vast bulk of the work is being done by thousands of small sys-admins across the globe running small instances of a few dozen or a few hundred users. And that part is sustainable too—running a small instance costs only a few dollars a month, and is a rewarding gig: it comes with a lot of control, and a privileged position to help craft a healthy community. Mastodon's entire model gets its incentives right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;joining&quot;&gt;Joining&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this sounds at all appealing to you, I encourage you to check out Mastodon. It's not perfect, and it might not fully replace Twitter if you're a heavy user—if for no other reason than that people you like to follow won't (yet) have switched. But the community is really great, and growing quickly. And I've had a blast with it since I got involved. If you'd like to join, the main website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmastodon.org/&quot;&gt;joinmastodon.org&lt;/a&gt;, is full of good info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmastodon.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.codesections.com/blog/mastodon-elevator-pitch/mastodon_homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;joinmastodon.org&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You certainly don't need to understand the details of how Mastodon works, but if you would like a bit better understanding of how Mastodon works under the hood, Mastodon user &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosstodon.org/@kev&quot;&gt;@kev&lt;/a&gt; wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/how-does-mastodon-work/&quot;&gt;an excellent guide to Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;And, when you're ready to pick an instance, there's a great tool that lets you search available instances at &lt;a href=&quot;https://instances.social/&quot;&gt;instances.social&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation is to use that tool to find a few relatively small instances with names that sound interesting to you. Then, click through and read about the culture and moderation policies of each instance and maybe scan through the public posts to get a sense of the local vibe. And then dive right in—you can always change your mind later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal note, if you happen to be interested in FOSS (Free and Open Source Software), then I can personally vouch for the community at &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosstodon.org&quot;&gt;fosstodon.org&lt;/a&gt;. And, on an even more personal note, whatever instance you join, please feel free to look me up. I'm &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosstodon.org/@codesections&quot;&gt;@codesections@fosstodon.org&lt;/a&gt; and would love for you to say hi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 11:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>codesections</dc:creator>
<og:title>Mastodon Is Better than Twitter: Elevator Pitch | CodeSections</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>www.codesections.com</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.codesections.com/codesections_logo_large.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.codesections.com/blog/mastodon-elevator-pitch/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>