<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Private by Design: How We Built Firefox Sync</title>
<link>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;What is Firefox Sync and why would you use it&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That shopping rabbit hole you started on your laptop this morning? Pick up where you left off on your phone tonight. That dinner recipe you discovered at lunchtime? Open it on your kitchen tablet, instantly. Connect your personal devices, securely. –&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/features/sync/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Firefox Sync&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox Sync lets you share your bookmarks, browsing history, passwords and other browser data between different devices, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/features/send-tabs/&quot;&gt;send tabs&lt;/a&gt; from one device to another. It’s a feature that millions of our users take advantage of to streamline their lives and how they interact with the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But on an Internet where sharing your data with a provider is the norm, we think it’s important to highlight the privacy aspects of Firefox Sync.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox Sync &lt;strong&gt;by default&lt;/strong&gt; protects all your synced data so Mozilla can’t read it. We built Sync this way because we put user privacy first. In this post, we take a closer look at some of the technical design choices we made and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building a browser and implementing a sync service, we think it’s important to look at what one might call ‘Total Cost of Ownership’.  Not just what users &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; from a feature, but what they &lt;em&gt;give up&lt;/em&gt; in exchange for ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that by making the right choices to protect your privacy, we’ve also lowered the barrier to trying out Sync. When you sign up and choose a strong passphrase, your data is protected from both attackers and from Mozilla, so you can try out Sync without worry. Give it a shot, it’s right up there in the menu bar!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-05-at-4.11.05-PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-32923 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-05-at-4.11.05-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sign in to Sync Button in the Firefox Menu&quot; width=&quot;442&quot; height=&quot;178&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-05-at-4.11.05-PM.png 442w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-05-at-4.11.05-PM-250x101.png 250w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 442px) 100vw, 442px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Firefox Sync is safe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encryption allows one to protect data so that it is entirely unreadable without the key used to encrypt it. The math behind encryption is strong, has been tested for decades, and every government in the world uses it to protect its most valuable secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard part of encryption is that key. What key do you encrypt with, where does it come from, where is it stored, and how does it move between places? Lots of cloud providers claim they encrypt your data, and they do. But they also have the key! While the encryption is not meaningless, it is a small measure, and does not protect the data against the most concerning threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The encryption key is the essential element. The service provider must &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; receive it – even temporarily – and must &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; know it. When you sign into your Firefox Account, you enter a username and passphrase, which are sent to the server. How is it that we can claim to never know your encryption key if that’s all you ever provide us?  &lt;em&gt;The difference is in how we handle your passphrase.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical login flow for an internet service is to send your username and passphrase up to the server, where they hash it, compare it to a stored hash, and if correct, the server sends you your data. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/06/hacker-lexicon-password-hashing/&quot;&gt;Hashing&lt;/a&gt; refers to the activity of converting passwords into unreadable strings of characters impossible to revert.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-32924 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost.png&quot; alt=&quot;Typical Web Provider Login Flow&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost.png 960w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost-250x188.png 250w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost-768x576.png 768w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost-500x375.png 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crux of the difference in how we designed Firefox Accounts, and Firefox Sync (our underlying syncing service), is that you never send us your passphrase. We transform your passphrase &lt;em&gt;on your computer&lt;/em&gt; into two different, unrelated values. With one value, you cannot derive the other. We send an authentication token, derived from your passphrase, to the server as the password-equivalent. And the encryption key derived from your passphrase never leaves your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-32925 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Firefox Sync Login Flow&quot; width=&quot;1152&quot; height=&quot;864&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost1.png 1152w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost1-250x188.png 250w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost1-768x576.png 768w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Sync-Blogpost1-500x375.png 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1152px) 100vw, 1152px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in the technical details?  We use 1000 rounds of PBKDF2 to derive your passphrase into the authentication token. On the server, we additionally hash this token with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrypt&quot;&gt;scrypt&lt;/a&gt; (parameters N=65536, r=8, p=1) to make sure our database of authentication tokens is even more difficult to crack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We derive your passphrase into an encryption key using the same 1000 rounds of PBKDF2. It is domain-separated from your authentication token by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5869&quot;&gt;HKDF&lt;/a&gt; with separate info values. We use this key to unwrap an encryption key (which you generated during setup and which we never see unwrapped), and &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; encryption key is used to protect your data.  We use the key to encrypt your data using AES-256 in CBC mode, protected with an HMAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cryptographic design is solid – but the constants need to be updated. One thousand rounds of PBKDF can be improved, and we intend to do so in the future (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1320222&quot;&gt;Bug 1320222&lt;/a&gt;). This token is only ever sent over a HTTPS connection (with preloaded HPKP pins) and is not stored, so when we initially developed this and needed to support low-power, low-resources devices, a trade-off was made. AES-CBC + HMAC is acceptable – it would be nice to upgrade this to an authenticated mode sometime in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other approaches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the only approach to building a browser sync feature. There are at least three other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Option 1: Share your data with the browser maker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this approach, the browser maker is able to read your data, and use it to provide services to you. For example,  when you sync your browser history in Chrome it will automatically go into your &lt;a href=&quot;https://myactivity.google.com/&quot;&gt;Web &amp;amp; App Activity&lt;/a&gt; unless you’ve changed the default settings. As Google Chrome Help explains, “Your activity may be used to personalize your experience on other Google products, like Search or ads. For example, you may see a news story recommended in your feed based on your Chrome history.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Option 2: Use a separate password for sign-in and encryption&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We developed Firefox Sync to be as easy to use as possible, so we designed it from the ground up to derive an authentication token and an encryption key – and we never see the passphrase &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; the encryption key. One cannot safely derive an encryption key from a passphrase if the passphrase is sent to the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could, however, add a second passphrase that is never sent to the server, and encrypt the data using that. Chrome provides this as a non-default option. You can sign in to sync with your Google Account credentials; but you choose a separate passphrase to encrypt your data. It’s imperative you choose a separate passphrase though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-in-all, we don’t care for the design that requires a second passphrase. This approach is confusing to users. It’s very easy to choose the same (or similar) passphrase and negate the security of the design. It’s hard to determine which is more confusing: to require a second passphrase or to make it optional! Making it optional means it will be used very rarely.  We don’t believe users should have to opt-in to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Option 3: Manual key synchronization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key (pun intended) to auditing a cryptographic design is to ask about the key: &lt;em&gt;“Where does it come from? Where does it go?”&lt;/em&gt; With the Firefox Sync design, you enter a passphrase of your choosing and it is used to derive an encryption key that never leaves your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another option for Sync is to remove user choice, and provide a passphrase &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; you (that never leaves your computer). This passphrase would be secure and unguessable – which is an advantage, but it would be near-impossible to remember – which is a disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to add a new device to sync to, you’d need your existing device nearby in order to manually read and type the passphrase into the new device. (You could also scan a QR code if your new device has a camera).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Browsers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Sync works the way it does because we feel it’s the best design choice. Options 1 and 2 don’t provide thorough user privacy protections by default. Option 3 results in lower user adoption and thus reduces the number of people we can help (more on this below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted above, Chrome implements Option 1 by default, which means &lt;em&gt;unless you change the settings before you enable sync&lt;/em&gt;, Google will see all of your browsing history and other data, and use it to market services to you. Chrome also implements Option 2 as an opt-in feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Opera and Vivaldi follow Chrome’s lead, implementing Option 1 by default and Option 2 as an opt-in feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brave, also a privacy-focused browser, has implemented Option 3. And, in fact, Firefox &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; implemented a form of Option 3 in its original Sync Protocol, but we changed our design in April 2014 (Firefox 29) in response to user feedback. For example, our original design (and Brave’s current design) makes it much harder to regain access to your data if you lose your device or it gets stolen. Passwords or passphrases make that experience substantially easier for the average user, and significantly increased Sync adoption by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brave’s sync protocol has some interesting wrinkles. One distinct minus is that you can’t change your passphrase, if it were to be stolen by malware. Another interesting wrinkle is that Brave does not keep track of how many or what types of devices you have. This is a nuanced security trade-off: having less information about the user is always desirable… The downside is that Brave can’t allow you to detect when a new device begins receiving your sync data or allow you to deauthorize it. We respect Brave’s decision. In Firefox, however, we have chosen to provide this additional security feature for users (at the cost of knowing more about their devices).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We designed Firefox Sync to protect your data – by default – so Mozilla can’t read it. We built it this way – despite trade-offs that make development and offering features more difficult – because we put user privacy first. At Mozilla, this priority is a core part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/mission/&quot;&gt;our mission&lt;/a&gt; to “ensure the Internet is a global public resource… where individuals can shape their own experience and are empowered, safe and independent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; It is possible to use one to &lt;em&gt;guess&lt;/em&gt; the other, but only if you choose a weak password. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/#back-foot-0&quot;&gt;⬑&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; You can find more details in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mozilla/fxa-auth-server/wiki/onepw-protocol&quot;&gt;full protocol specification&lt;/a&gt; or by following the code &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mozilla/fxa-js-client/blob/1d92f0ec458aceb56ef1619b5365ad8621183a1d/client/lib/credentials.js#L53&quot;&gt;starting at this point&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few details we have omitted to simplify this blog post, including the difference between kA and kB keys, and application-specific subkeys. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/#back-foot-1&quot;&gt;⬑&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Server hashing code is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mozilla/fxa-auth-server/blob/c28f227dc089eaf949494e8c3f810e31d9789dfa/lib/crypto/password.js#L20&quot;&gt;located here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/#back-foot-2&quot;&gt;⬑&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; The encryption code can be seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://searchfox.org/mozilla-central/rev/65f9687eb192f8317b4e02b0b791932eff6237cc/services/sync/modules/record.js#145&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/#back-foot-3&quot;&gt;⬑&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/165139&quot;&gt;https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/165139&lt;/a&gt; Section “Use your Chrome history to personalize Google” &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/#back-foot-4&quot;&gt;⬑&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Chrome 71 says “For added security, Google Chrome will encrypt your data” and describes these two options as “Encrypt synced passwords with your Google username and password” and “Encrypt synced data with your own &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/chrome/?p=settings_encryption&quot;&gt;sync passphrase&lt;/a&gt;”.  Despite this wording, only the sync passphrase option protects your data from Google. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/#back-foot-5&quot;&gt;⬑&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; One of the original engineers of Sync has written &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/warner/2014/04/02/pairing-problems/&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/warner/2014/05/23/the-new-sync-protocol/&quot;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; about the transition to the new sync protocol, and why we did it. If you’re interested in the usability aspects of cryptography, we highly recommend you read them to see what we learned. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/#back-foot-6&quot;&gt;⬑&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; You can read more about Brave sync &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brave/sync/wiki/Design&quot;&gt;on Brave’s Design page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/#back-foot-7&quot;&gt;⬑&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;about&quot; readability=&quot;0.065573770491803&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;url&quot; href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/author/trittermozilla-com/&quot;&gt;More articles by Tom Ritter…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:36:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>feross</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy</og:url>
<og:title>Private by Design: How we built Firefox Sync – Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog</og:title>
<og:description>Firefox Sync by default protects all your synced data so Mozilla can’t read it. We built Sync this way because we put user privacy first. How it works is...</og:description>
<og:image>https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2018/11/Sync_2018-11-13-Use-Bookmarks-Tabs-and-Passwords-Across-Devices-Firefox-.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Waymo CEO Says Alphabet Unit Plans to Launch Driverless Car Service</title>
<link>https://www.marketwatch.com/story/waymo-ceo-says-driverless-car-service-coming-soon-2018-11-13</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.marketwatch.com/story/waymo-ceo-says-driverless-car-service-coming-soon-2018-11-13</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;LAGUNA BEACH, Calif. -- The head of Alphabet Inc.'s Waymo unit said it plans to launch its first commercial self-driving car service in the next two months and expects businesses to be among its biggest customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at The Wall Street Journal's WSJ Tech D.Live conference on Tuesday, Waymo's John Krafcik said the new service will charge individual passengers for rides as well as businesses, such as Walmart Inc., who want to pay to shuttle their customers to stores. The service will initially be available to a small group of riders in the Phoenix area, but will expand to more people in the coming months, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waymo has said it plans to launch a self-driving ride service in 2018 and earlier this year announced deals to buy thousands of vehicles in coming years from Fiat Chrysler Automobiles NV and Tata Motors Inc.'s Jaguar Land Rover to expand its fleet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech unit, which began as a self-driving car project under Google, has spent years and driven millions of miles to develop the technology. Last year, Waymo began testing its self-driving vans with nonemployees in Chandler, Ariz., through its so-called Early Rider program to learn how potential customers might use and interact with the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, Mr. Krafcik said one surprising part of this pilot has been the number of businesses including Walmart, Avis Budget Group Inc. and AutoNation Inc. who are willing to pay for their customers' rides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is a whole other channel of demand we really hadn't thought deeply about that could end up being a really significant driver of business,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alphabet CFO Ruth Porat told analysts last month that Waymo began testing price models during the third quarter through the Early Rider program. &quot;We moved into very early days of commercialization,&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other tech companies and auto makers are rushing to develop similar technology and deploy robot taxis in a bet that the technology will reshape the landscape for personal transportation. General Motors Co.'s Cruise unit is testing a fleet of vehicles in San Francisco and has said it plans to launch a service somewhere next year. Meanwhile, federal, state and local regulators are grappling to oversee the fast-developing technology to ensure safety. A fatal crash earlier this year involving a test vehicle operated by Uber Technologies Inc. raised new questions about whether the technology is ready for deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Krafcik also highlighted the progress of Waymo's commercial trucking business, which has begun delivering freight in Atlanta. In commercial trucking, &quot;you could anticipate a material contribution to the world from Waymo over the next couple years,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write to Douglas MacMillan at douglas.macmillan@wsj.com and Tim Higgins at Tim.Higgins@WSJ.com&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 22:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sidhanthp</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.marketwatch.com/story/waymo-ceo-says-driverless-car-service-coming-soon-2018-11-13</og:url>
<og:title>Waymo CEO says driverless car service coming soon</og:title>
<og:image>https://mw3.wsj.net/mw5/content/logos/mw_logo_social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.marketwatch.com/story/waymo-ceo-says-driverless-car-service-coming-soon-2018-11-13</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Build a do-it-yourself home air purifier for about $25</title>
<link>https://www.uofmhealth.org/news/sinus-hepa-0630</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.uofmhealth.org/news/sinus-hepa-0630</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Many people with sinus problems have underlying allergies to dust, pollen, mold or animal dander. All of these can build up in the air inside homes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;81.212121212121&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to get rid of allergy symptoms is to avoid allergens in the first place, says Jeffrey E. Terrell, M.D., director of the University of Michigan Health System’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uofmhealth.org/medical-services/noseandsinus&quot;&gt;Michigan Sinus Center&lt;/a&gt;. To avoid indoor allergens, many doctors recommend using an air purifier with a High Efficiency Particulate Air (HEPA) filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost of these machines can run from $75 up to $800 for high-end systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who are looking for a cheaper alternative for high-use rooms such as the bedroom, Terrell offers a do-it-yourself solution at a fraction of the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a filtration system that you can put together with items from your local hardware store for $25 to $30 and use in your home to cut indoor allergens by about 90 percent,” says Terrell.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kH5APw_SLUU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;258&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
Start with a 20-inch by 20-inch box fan, which often retails for about $12. To the front of it, tape a 20-inch by 20-inch by 1-inch furnace filter.  
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that filter is a HEPA filter with a Minimum Efficiency Reporting Value (MERV) rating of at least 13. The higher the rating, the more particles will be filtered out of the air. These filters sell for about $15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be arrows marked on the filter to indicate the proper direction for airflow. Attach the filter to the front of the fan, so the air blows through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/lX4ZqI&quot;&gt;videotaped demonstration&lt;/a&gt;, Terrell used a sensitive air-quality meter to demonstrate that one high-end HEPA system brought the particulate count in a dusty room down to virtually zero. His homemade system brought the count down to about 10 percent of its former level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The homemade purifier can be placed on the floor. If it’s in a window, it will filter pollen blowing in from outside but won’t have as much of an impact on the air that’s already in home. People who have pollen allergies should keep their windows closed, Terrell notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can tell when it’s time to change the filter by its color,” Terrell says. “As dust and particulates get caught in the filter, it will turn from white to brown.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about sinus symptoms and treatments, visit:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uofmhealth.org/medical-services/noseandsinus&quot;&gt;http://www.uofmhealth.org/medical-services/noseandsinus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Michigan Sinus Center is located in Livonia. To make an appointment call 734-936-8051.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 22:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>io_io</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.uofmhealth.org/news/sinus-hepa-0630</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tensorflow 2.0: models migration and new design</title>
<link>https://pgaleone.eu/tensorflow/gan/2018/11/04/tensorflow-2-models-migration-and-new-design/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://pgaleone.eu/tensorflow/gan/2018/11/04/tensorflow-2-models-migration-and-new-design/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Tensorflow 2.0 will be a major milestone for the most popular machine learning framework: lots of changes are coming, and all with the aim of making ML accessible to everyone. These changes, however, requires for the old users to completely re-learn how to use the framework: this article describes all the (known) differences between the 1.x and 2.x version, focusing on the change of mindset required and highlighting the pros and cons of the new and implementations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article can be a good starting point also for the novice: start thinking in the Tensorflow 2.0 way right now, so you don’t have to re-learn a new framework (unless until Tensorflow 3.0 will be released).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tensorflow-20-why-and-when&quot;&gt;Tensorflow 2.0: why and when?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to make Tensorflow easier to learn and apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first glimpse on what Tensorlow 2.0 will be has been given by Martin Wicke, one of the Google Brain Engineers, in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/a/tensorflow.org/forum/#!forum/announce&quot;&gt;Announcements Mailing List&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/a/tensorflow.org/forum/#!topic/announce/qXfsxr2sF-0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In short:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eager execution will be a central feature of 2.0. It aligns users’ expectations about the programming model better with TensorFlow practice and should make TensorFlow easier to learn and apply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for more platforms and languages, and improved compatibility and parity between these components via standardization on exchange formats and alignment of APIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove deprecated APIs and reduce the amount of duplication, which has caused confusion for users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public 2.0 design process: the community can now work together with the Tensorflow developers and discuss the new features, using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/a/tensorflow.org/forum/#!forum/discuss&quot;&gt;Tensorflow Discussion Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compatibility and continuity: a compatibility module with Tensorflow 1.x will be offered, this means that Tensorflow 2.0 will have a module with all the Tensorflow 1.x API inside&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On-disk compatibility: the exported models (checkpoints and frozen models) in Tensorflow 1.x will be compatible with Tensorflow 2.0, only some variable rename could be required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.contrib&lt;/code&gt;: completely removed. Huge, maintained, modules will be moved to separate repositories; unused and unmaintained modules will be removed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In practice, if you’re new to Tensorflow, you’re lucky. If like me, you’re using Tensorflow from the 0.x release, you have to rewrite all your codebase (and differently from 0.x to 1.x transition, the changes are massive); however, Tensorflow authors claim that a conversion tool will be released to help the transition. However, conversion tools are not perfect hence manual intervention could be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, you have to change your way of thinking; this can be challenging, but everyone likes challenges, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s face this challenge and start looking at the changes in detail, starting from the first huge difference: the removal of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/get_variable&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.get_variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/variable_scope&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.variable_scope&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/layers&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.layers&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the mandatory transition to a Keras based approach, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/keras&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a note on the release date: it is not defined yet. But from the Tensorflow discussion group, we know that a preview could be released by the end of 2018 and the official release of 2.0 could be in Spring 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence is better to update all the existing codebase as soon as the RFCs are accepted in order to have a smooth transition to this new Tensorflow version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;keras-oop-vs-tensorflow-1x&quot;&gt;Keras (OOP) vs Tensorflow 1.x&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tensorflow/community/pull/11&quot;&gt;RFC: Variables in TensorFlow 2.0&lt;/a&gt; has been accepted. This RFC is probably the one with the biggest impact on the existing codebase and requires a new way of thinking for the old Tensorflow users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As described in the article &lt;a href=&quot;https://pgaleone.eu/tensorflow/go/2017/05/29/understanding-tensorflow-using-go/&quot;&gt;Understanding Tensorflow using Go&lt;/a&gt; every variable has a unique name in the computational graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an early Tensorflow user, I’m used to designing my computational graphs following this pattern:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Which operations connect my variable nodes? Define the graph as multiple sub-graphs connected. Define every sub-graph inside a separate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/variable_scope&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.variable_scope&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in order to define the variables of different graphs, inside different scopes and obtain a clear graph representation in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paolo_galeone/status/734047400910802944&quot;&gt;Tensorboard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I have to use a sub-graph more than once in the same execution step? Be sure to exploit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/variable_scope#__init__&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;reuse&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; parameter of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/variable_scope&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.variable_scope&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in order to avoid the creation of a new graph, prefixed with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_n&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The graph has been defined? Create the variable initialization op (how many times have you seen the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/initializers/global_variables&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.global_variables_initializer()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; call?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load the graph into a Session and run it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The example that better shows the reasoning steps, IMHO, is how a simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_adversarial_network&quot;&gt;GAN&lt;/a&gt; can be implemented in Tensorflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-gan-to-understand-tensorflow-1x&quot;&gt;A GAN to understand Tensorflow 1.x&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GAN discriminator  must be defined using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/variable_scope&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.variable_scope&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;reuse&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) parameter, because first we want to feed  with real samples, then we want to feed it again with fake samples and only at the end compute the gradient of  w.r.t. its parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The generator network , instead, is never used twice in the same iteration, hence there’s no need to worry about its variables reusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;16.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;generator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;generator network.
    Args:
        inputs: a (None, latent_space_size) tf.float32 tensor
    Returns:
        G: the generator output node
    &quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;variable_scope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;generator&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fc1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dense&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;units&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;activation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;elu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;fc1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fc2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dense&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fc1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;units&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;activation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;elu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;fc2&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dense&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fc1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;units&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;G&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;discriminator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reuse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;discriminator network
    Args:
        inputs: a (None, 1) tf.float32 tensor
        reuse: python boolean, if we expect to reuse (True) or declare (False) the variables
    Returns:
        D: the discriminator output node
    &quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;variable_scope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;discriminator&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reuse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reuse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fc1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dense&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;units&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;activation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;elu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;fc1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dense&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fc1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;units&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;D&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This two functions, when called, define inside the default graph 2 different sub-graphs, each one with its own scope (“generator” or “discriminator”). Please note that this function &lt;strong&gt;return the output tensor&lt;/strong&gt; of the defined sub-graph, not the graph itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to share the same  graph, we define 2 inputs (real and fake) and define the loss functions required to train  and .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Define the real input, a batch of values sampled from the real data&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;real_input&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;placeholder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;float32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Define the discriminator network and its parameters&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_real&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;discriminator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;real_input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Arbitrary size of the noise prior vector&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;latent_space_size&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Define the input noise shape and define the generator&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;input_noise&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;placeholder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;float32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;latent_space_size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;generator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;input_noise&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# now that we have defined the generator output G, we can give it in input to &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# D, this call of `discriminator` will not define a new graph, but it will&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# **reuse** the variables previously defined&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;discriminator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing to do is to just define the 2 loss functions and the 2 optimizers required to train  and  respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss_real&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reduce_mean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sigmoid_cross_entropy_with_logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ones_like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss_fake&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reduce_mean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sigmoid_cross_entropy_with_logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;zeros_like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# D_loss, when invoked it first does a forward pass using the D_loss_real&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# then another forward pass using D_loss_fake, sharing the same D parameters.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss_real&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss_fake&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_loss&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reduce_mean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sigmoid_cross_entropy_with_logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ones_like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The loss functions are easily defined. The peculiarity of the adversarial training is that first  must be trained, using the real samples and the samples generated by . Then, the adversarial, , is trained using the result of the  evaluation as the input signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adversarial training requires to run &lt;strong&gt;separately&lt;/strong&gt; this 2 training steps, but we have defined the models inside the same graph and we don’t want to update the  variables when we train  and vice-versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, since we defined &lt;strong&gt;every variable inside the default graph&lt;/strong&gt;, hence &lt;strong&gt;every variable is global&lt;/strong&gt;, we have to gather the correct variables in 2 different lists and be sure to define the optimizers in order to compute the gradients and apply the updates only to the correct sub-graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Gather D and G variables&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_vars&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trainable_variables&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;scope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;discriminator&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_vars&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trainable_variables&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;scope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;generator&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Define the optimizers and the train operations&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;train_D&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;train&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;AdamOptimizer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;1e-5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;minimize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;var_list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_vars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;train_G&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;train&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;AdamOptimizer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;1e-5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;minimize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_loss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;var_list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_vars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we go, we’re at step 3, graph defined so the last thing to do is to define the variables initialization op:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;init_op&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;global_variables_initializer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;pros--cons&quot;&gt;Pros / Cons&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph has been correctly defined and, when used inside the training loop and within a session, it works. However, from the software engineering point of view, there are certain peculiarities that are worth noting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The usage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/variable_scope&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.variable_scope&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; context manager to change the (full) name of the variables defined by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.layers&lt;/code&gt;: the same call to a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.layers.*&lt;/code&gt; method in a different variable scope defines a new set of variables under a new scope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The boolean flag &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;reuse&lt;/code&gt; can completely change the behavior of any call to a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.layers.*&lt;/code&gt; method (define or reuse)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every variable is global: the variables defined by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.layers&lt;/code&gt; calling &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/get_variable&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.get_variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (that’s used inside &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.layers&lt;/code&gt;) are accessible from everywhere: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.trainable_variables(prefix)&lt;/code&gt; used above to gather the 2 lists of variables perfectly describes this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining sub-graphs is not easy: you just can’t call &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;discriminator&lt;/code&gt; and get a new, completely independent, discriminator. Is a little bit counterintuitive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The return value of a sub-graph definition (call to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;generator&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;discriminator&lt;/code&gt;) is only its output tensor and not something with all the graph information inside (although is possible to backtrack to the input, but it’s not that easy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining the variables initialization op is just boring (but this is just been resolved using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/train/MonitoredSession&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.train.MonitoredSession&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/train/MonitoredTrainingSession&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.train.MonitoredTrainingSession&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;hint: use them&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those 6 points are probably all &lt;em&gt;cons&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We defined our GAN in the Tensorflow 1.x way: let’s start the migration to Tensorflow 2.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-gan-to-understand-tensorflow-2x&quot;&gt;A GAN to understand Tensorflow 2.x&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As stated in the previous section, in Tensorflow 2.x, the way of thinking changes. The removal of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/get_variable&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.get_variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/variable_scope&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.variable_scope&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/layers&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.layers&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the mandatory transition to a Keras based approach, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.12/api_docs/python/tf/keras&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; forces the Tensorflow developer to change its mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to define the generator  and discriminator  using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras&lt;/code&gt;: this will give us for free the variable sharing feature that we used to define , but implemented differently under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.layers&lt;/code&gt; will be &lt;strong&gt;removed&lt;/strong&gt;, hence starting to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras&lt;/code&gt; right now to define your models is mandatory in order to be ready to 2.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;12.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;generator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;input_shape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;generator network.
    Args:
        input_shape: the desired input shape (e.g.: (latent_space_size))
    Returns:
        G: The generator model
    &quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keras&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;input_shape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keras&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Dense&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;units&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;activation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;elu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;fc1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keras&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Dense&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;units&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;activation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;elu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;fc2&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keras&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Dense&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;units&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;G&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keras&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;outputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;discriminator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;input_shape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;discriminator network.
    Args:
        input_shape: the desired input shape (e.g.: (latent_space_size))
    Returns:
        D: the discriminator model
    &quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keras&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;input_shape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keras&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Dense&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;units&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;activation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;elu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;fc1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keras&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Dense&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;units&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;D&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keras&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;outputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the different approach: both &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;generator&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;discriminator&lt;/code&gt; returns a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras.Model&lt;/code&gt; and not just an output tensor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that using Keras we can instantiate our model and use &lt;strong&gt;the same model&lt;/strong&gt; in different parts of the source code and we effectively use the variables of that model, without the problem of defining a new sub-graph prefixed with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_n&lt;/code&gt;. In fact, differently from the 1.x version, we’re going to define just one  model and use it twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Define the real input, a batch of values sampled from the real data &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;real_input&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;placeholder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;float32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Define the discriminator model&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;discriminator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;real_input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:])&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Arbitrary set the shape of the noise prior vector&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;latent_space_size&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Define the input noise shape and define the generator&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;input_noise&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;placeholder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;float32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;latent_space_size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;generator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;input_noise&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again: there’s no need to define &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/code&gt; as we did above, and there’s no need to think ahead when defining the graphs and worry about the variable sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can go on and define the  and  loss functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_real&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;real_input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss_real&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reduce_mean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sigmoid_cross_entropy_with_logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ones_like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_z&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;input_noise&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss_fake&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reduce_mean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sigmoid_cross_entropy_with_logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;zeros_like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss_real&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss_fake&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_loss&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reduce_mean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sigmoid_cross_entropy_with_logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;logits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ones_like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_fake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far so good. The last thing to do is defining the 2 optimizers that will optimize  and  separately. Since we’re using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras&lt;/code&gt; there’s no need to manually create the list of the variables to update, since are the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras.Model&lt;/code&gt;s objects themselves that are carrying this attribute:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Define the optimizers and the train operations&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;train_D&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;train&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;AdamOptimizer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;1e-5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;minimize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D_loss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;var_list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trainable_variables&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;train_G&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;train&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;AdamOptimizer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;1e-5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;minimize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_loss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;var_list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trainable_variables&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re ready to go: we reached step 3 and since we’re still working using the static graph mode, we have to define the variables initialization op:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;init_op&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;global_variables_initializer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;proscons&quot;&gt;Pros/Cons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Transitioning from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.layers&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras&lt;/code&gt; it easy: all &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.layers&lt;/code&gt; methods have their own &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras.layers&lt;/code&gt; counterpart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras.Model&lt;/code&gt; completely removes to worry about variables reusing, issues on graph redefinition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.keras.Model&lt;/code&gt; is not an output tensor, but is a complete model that carries its own variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We still have to initialize all variables, but as said before &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.train.MonitoredSession&lt;/code&gt; can do it for us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GAN example, in both Tensorflow 1.x and 2.x, has been developed using the “old” paradigm of graph definition first, execution in a session next (that is and will be a good and valid paradigm to follow and - personal opinion - is the best one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, another big change in Tensorflow 2.x is to make the &lt;em&gt;eager mode&lt;/em&gt; the default execution mode. In Tensorflow 1.x we have to explicitly enable the eager execution, while in Tensorflow 1.x we’ll have to do the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eager-mode-first&quot;&gt;Eager mode first&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As stated in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/eager&quot;&gt;Eager execution guide&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TensorFlow’s eager execution is an imperative programming environment that evaluates operations immediately, without building graphs: operations return concrete values instead of constructing a computational graph to run later. This makes it easy to get started with TensorFlow and debug models, and it reduces boilerplate as well. To follow along with this guide, run the code samples below in an interactive python interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eager execution is a flexible machine learning platform for research and experimentation, providing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;An intuitive interface—Structure your code naturally and use Python data structures. Quickly iterate on small models and small data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier debugging—Call ops directly to inspect running models and test changes. Use standard Python debugging tools for immediate error reporting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natural control flow—Use Python control flow instead of graph control flow, simplifying the specification of dynamic models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short: there’s no need to define the graph first and then evaluate it inside a session. Using Tensorflow in eager mode allow to mix the definition and execution, exactly as a standard python program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no a 1:1 match with the static graph version, since things that are &lt;em&gt;natural&lt;/em&gt; in a graph are not in a imperative environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important example here is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/GradientTape&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.GradientTape&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; context manager that only exists in eager mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we have a graph, we do know how nodes are connected and when we have to compute the gradient of a certain function we can backtrack from the output to the input of the graph, compute the gradient and get the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In eager mode we can’t. The only way to compute the gradient of a function using automatic differentiation is to &lt;em&gt;build a graph&lt;/em&gt;. The graph of the operations executed within the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.GradientTape&lt;/code&gt; context manager on some &lt;em&gt;watchable&lt;/em&gt; element (like variables) is built and then we can ask the tape to compute the gradient we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/GradientTape&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.GradientTape&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; documentation page we can find an example that clearly explains how and why tapes are needed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;constant&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;3.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GradientTape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;watch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dy_dx&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gradient&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Will compute to 6.0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the control flow operations are just the python control flow operations (like for loops, if statements, …) differently from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.while_loop&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.map_fn&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.cond&lt;/code&gt; methods that we have to use in the static-graph version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a tool, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/autograph&quot;&gt;Autograph&lt;/a&gt; that helps you write complicated graph code using normal Python. Behind the scenes, AutoGraph automatically transforms your code into the equivalent TensorFlow graph code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the python code you need to write is not exactly pure python (for instance, you have to declare that a function return a list of elements with a specified Tensorflow data type, using operations that you won’t use in a standard python function) and its capabilities, at least at the time of writing are limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool has been created because the graph version has the great advantage of being “a single file” once exported, and therefore shipping trained machine learning models in a production environment is way more easier using the static-graph mode. Also, the static-graph mode is faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I don’t like eager mode that much. Probably because I’m used to the static graph version and I found the eager mode a coarse imitation of PyTorch. Also, trying to implement a GAN from a PyTorch implementation to a Tensorflow 2.x version, using both static graph and eager mode version, I wasn’t able to get the eager one working and I still don’t know why (while the static graph implementation works perfectly). I opened a bug report on GitHub (but the error could be mine of course): &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/23407&quot;&gt;Tensorflow eager version fails, while Tensorflow static graph works&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition to Tensorflow 2.x carries other changes that I tried to summarize in the next &lt;em&gt;what if&lt;/em&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-if&quot;&gt;What if?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of what I think will be the F.A.Q. about the transition to Tensorflow 2.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-if-my-project-uses-tfcontrib&quot;&gt;What if my project uses &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.contrib&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the information about the fate of the projects inside &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.contrib&lt;/code&gt; can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tensorflow/community/blob/rfc-contrib/rfcs/20180907-contrib-sunset.md&quot;&gt;Sunsetting tf.contrib&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably you just have to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip install&lt;/code&gt; a new python package or rename your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.contrib.something&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.something&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-if-a-project-working-in-tensorflow-1x-stops-working-in-2x&quot;&gt;What if a project working in Tensorflow 1.x stops working in 2.x?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shouldn’t happen: please double check that the transition has been correctly implemented and if it is, open a bug report on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-if-a-project-works-in-static-graph-mode-but-it-doesnt-in-eager-mode&quot;&gt;What if a project works in static graph mode but it doesn’t in eager mode?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a problem I’m currently facing, as I reported here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/23407&quot;&gt;Tensorflow eager version fails, while Tensorflow static graph works&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I don’t know if this is a bug from my side or there’s something wrong in the actual Tensorflow eager version. However, since I’m used to thinking in a static graph oriented way, I’ll just avoid using the eager version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-if-a-method-from-tf-disappeared-in-2x&quot;&gt;What if a method from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.&lt;/code&gt; disappeared in 2.x?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a high chance the method has only been moved. In Tensorflow 1.x there are a lot of aliases for a lot of methods, in Tensorflow 2.x instead, there’s the aim (if the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tensorflow/community/blob/25ab399ecf66f7cee8e7f8c479aefcb96f8cc96b/rfcs/20180827-api-names.md&quot;&gt;RFC: TensorFlow Namespaces&lt;/a&gt; will be accepted - as I wish) of removing a lot of these aliases and move methods to a better location, in order to increase the overall coherence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the RFC you can find the newly proposed namespaces, the list of the one that will be removed and all the other changes that (probably) will be made to increase the coherence of the framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the conversion tool that will be released will be probably able to correctly apply all these updates for you (this is just my speculation on the conversion tool, but since it’s an easy task that’s probably a feature that will be present).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article has been created with the specific aim of shed a light on the changes and the challenges that Tensorflow 2.0 will bring to us, the framework users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GAN implementation in Tensorflow 1.x and its conversion in Tensorflow 2.x should be a clear example of the mindset change required to work with the new version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I think Tensorflow 2.x will improve the quality of the framework and it will standardize and simplifies how to use it. New users that never seen a static-graph approach and are used to work with imperative languages could find the eager mode a good entry point to the Tensorflow world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are certain parts of the update that I don’t like (please not that those are just my personal opinions):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The focus on the eager execution and make it the default: it looks too much a marketing move to me. It looks like Tensorflow wants to chase PyTorch (eager by default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The missing 1:1 compatibility with static-graph and eager (and the possibility of mixing them) could create a mess in big projects IMHO: it would be hard to maintain this projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switching to a Keras based approach is a good move, but it makes the graph visualized in Tensorboard &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; ugly. In fact, the variables and the graphs are defined globally, and the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.named_scope&lt;/code&gt; (invoked every time a Keras Model is called, in order to share the variables easily) that creates a new “block” in the Tensorflow graph, is separated by the graph it uses internally and it has in the list of the input nodes all the variables of the model - this makes the graph visualization of Tensorboard pretty much useless and that’s a pity for such a good tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you liked the article feel free to share it using the buttons below and don’t hesitate to comment to let me know if there’s something wrong/that can be improved in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 19:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>formalsystem</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Tensorflow 2.0: models migration and new design</og:title>
<og:description>Let the machines learn</og:description>
<og:url>https://pgaleone.eu/tensorflow/gan/2018/11/04/tensorflow-2-models-migration-and-new-design/</og:url>
<og:image>https://pgaleone.eu/images/me.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://pgaleone.eu/tensorflow/gan/2018/11/04/tensorflow-2-models-migration-and-new-design/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Infinite procedurally-generated city with the Wave Function Collapse algorithm</title>
<link>https://marian42.itch.io/wfc</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://marian42.itch.io/wfc</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;An infinite, procedurally generated city, assembled out of blocks using the Wave Function Collapse algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, there is no gameplay, you can only walk around and look at the scenery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Controls: WASD for walking, Shift to run, Ctrl to jetpack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xbox controller: Left Stick for walking, right stick for looking around, A to jump, LB to run, RB to jetpack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight mode: Use M to toggle between flight mode and normal mode. In flight mode, you fly across the world, without any controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mxgmn/WaveFunctionCollapse&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Read more about the WFC algorithm here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source code: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/marian42/wavefunctioncollapse&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/marian42/wavefunctioncollapse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 18:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>guessmyname</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://img.itch.zone/aW1nLzE1OTQwMTIucG5n/original/JccxLG.png</og:image>
<og:description>Walk through an infinite, procedurally generated city</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://marian42.itch.io/wfc</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon’s HQ2 Spectacle Should Be Illegal</title>
<link>https://www.theatlantic.com/article/575539/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theatlantic.com/article/575539/</guid>
<description>&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-0&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Amazon HQ2 saga had all the hallmarks of the gaudiest reality TV. It was an absurd spectacle, concluding with a plot twist, which revealed a deep and dark truth about the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourteen months ago, Amazon announced a national beauty contest, in which North American cities could apply to win the honor of landing the retailer’s second headquarters. The prize: 50,000 employees and the glory of housing an international tech giant. The cost? Just several billion dollars in tax incentives and a potential face-lift to the host city. Then last week, in a classic late-episode shock, several news outlets reported that Amazon would split its second headquarters between Crystal City, a suburban neighborhood near Washington, D.C., and Long Island City, in Queens, New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rumored announcement has emboldened Amazon’s army of critics. Did the world’s smartest company really need 13 months, and applications from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jacobinmag.com/2018/02/amazon-corporate-headquarters-tax-breaks&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'0',r'None'&quot;&gt;238 cities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, to reach the striking conclusion that it should invest in New York and D.C.?  The former is America’s heart of capital, and the latter is America’s literal capital, where Jeff Bezos, chief executive of Amazon, already owns a house and a newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-0&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/11/amazon-washington-new-york-headquarters/575281/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'1',r'None'&quot;&gt;Annie Lowrey: Amazon was never going to choose Detroit.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Was this national auction nothing more than a scripted drama to raise the value of the inevitable winning bid? And did the retailer miss an opportunity to revitalize a midwestern city by choosing to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/11/amazon-washington-new-york-headquarters/575281/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'2',r'None'&quot;&gt;enrich the already-rich East Coast&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All good questions. But here’s the big one: Why the hell are U.S. cities spending tens of billions of dollars to steal jobs from one another in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;c-section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every year, American cities and states spend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/report_examining-the-local-value-of-economic-development-incentives_brookings-metro_march-2018.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'3',r'None'&quot;&gt;up to $90 billion&lt;/a&gt; in tax breaks and cash grants to urge companies to move among states. That’s more than the federal government spends on housing, education, or infrastructure. And since cities and states can’t print money or run steep deficits, these deals take scarce resources from everything local governments would otherwise pay for, such as schools, roads, police, and prisons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2014/09/15/should-we-ban-states-and-cities-from-offering-big-tax-breaks-for-jobs/?utm_term=.6346c2b91f55&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'4',r'None'&quot;&gt;past 10 years&lt;/a&gt;, Boeing, Nike, Intel, Royal Dutch Shell, Tesla, Nissan, Ford, and General Motors have each received subsidy packages worth more than $1 billion to either move their corporate headquarters within the U.S. or, quite often, to keep their headquarters right where they are. New Jersey and Maryland reportedly offered $7 billion for HQ2, which would be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-headquarters-hq2-new-jersey-economic-incentive-2017-10&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'5',r'None'&quot;&gt;the biggest corporate giveaway in American history&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might think, &lt;em&gt;Don’t blame the companies&lt;/em&gt;. These businesses have a fiduciary obligation to make money, and it’s negligent to leave cash piles on the table while their competitors are raking it in. And you might even think, &lt;em&gt;Don’t blame the local governments&lt;/em&gt;. Not bidding on an exciting new project feels akin to unilateral disarmament in a war for talent and business. Sometimes a big new firm can revitalize a downtown area and become a magnet for new firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/06/amazon-flex-workers/563444/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'6',r'None'&quot;&gt;Read: I delivered packages for Amazon and it was a nightmare.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are three major problems with America’s system of corporate giveaways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, they’re redundant. One recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemjensen.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Kansas-Working-Paper-7-23-15.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'7',r'None'&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by Nathan Jensen, then an economist at George Washington University, found that these incentives “have no discernible impact on firm expansion, measured by job creation.” Companies often decide where they want to go and then find ways to get their dream city, or hometown, to pay them to do what they were going to do anyway. For example, Amazon is a multinational company with large media and advertising divisions. The drama of the past 13 months probably wasn’t crucial to its (probable) decision to expand to New York City, the unambiguous capital of media and advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, companies don’t always hold up their end of the deal. Consider the saga of Wisconsin and the Chinese manufacturing giant Foxconn. Several years ago, Wisconsin Governor Scott Walker lured Foxconn with a subsidy plan totaling more than $3 billion. (For the same amount, you could give every household in Wisconsin &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/29/18027032/foxconn-wisconsin-plant-jobs-deal-subsidy-governor-scott-walker&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'8',r'None'&quot;&gt;about $1,700&lt;/a&gt;.) Foxconn said it would build a large manufacturing plant that would create about 13,000  jobs near Racine. Now it seems the company is building a much smaller factory with just one quarter of its initial promised investment, and much of the assembly work may be done by robots. Meanwhile, the expected value of Wisconsin’s subsidy has grown to more than $4 billion. Thus a state &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/answer-sheet/wp/2018/07/03/a-new-public-education-movement-is-emerging-in-wisconsin-a-rebuke-to-gov-walkers-war-on-labor-and-school-privatization/?utm_term=.5de93532b373&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'9',r'None'&quot;&gt;with declining wages for many public-school teachers&lt;/a&gt; could wind up paying more than $500,000 per net new Foxconn job—about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanprogressaction.org/issues/economy/reports/2017/11/15/169146/attacks-public-sector-unions-harm-states-act-10-affected-education-wisconsin/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'10',r'None'&quot;&gt;10 times the average salary&lt;/a&gt; of a Wisconsin teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, even when the incentives aren’t redundant, and even when companies do hold up their end of the bargain, it’s still ludicrous for Americans to collectively pay tens of billions of dollars for huge corporations to relocate &lt;em&gt;within the United States&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No story illuminates this absurdity more than the so-called Border War, in which the Kansas and Missouri sides of Kansas City have spent zillions of dollars dragging companies back and forth across state lines, within the same metro area. Several years ago, Kansas lured AMC Entertainment with tens of millions of dollars in incentives. Then Missouri responded by stealing Applebee’s headquarters from Kansas with another incentive package. Back and forth they went, until both states had spent half a billion dollars creating no net new jobs but changing the commutes of 10,000 Kansas City workers who got caught up in an interstate duel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;c-section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We need a national truce, both within states and between states,” said Amy Liu, the director of the Metropolitan Policy Program at the Brookings Institution. “There should be no more poaching of private companies with public funds.” But how would the United States ban states and local governments from poaching jobs from one another, or from giving tax dollars to private corporations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Congress could pass a national law banning this sort of corporate bribery. Mark Funkhouser, a former mayor of Kansas City, Missouri, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2014/09/15/should-we-ban-states-and-cities-from-offering-big-tax-breaks-for-jobs/?utm_term=.6346c2b91f55&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'11',r'None'&quot;&gt;envisions&lt;/a&gt; the law as the domestic version of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act, which makes it illegal for Americans to bribe foreign officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2017/09/sears-predicts-amazon/540888/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'12',r'None'&quot;&gt;Read: The history of Sears predicts nearly everything Amazon is doing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not entirely clear whether that would pass constitutional muster. The Supreme Court hasn’t ruled decisively on whether the Commerce Clause gives Washington the authority to ban interstate bidding wars. In the 2006 Supreme Court case &lt;em&gt;DaimlerChrysler Corp. v. Cuno&lt;/em&gt;, Ohio taxpayers sued the state after it paid the automaker DaimlerChrysler about $280 million in tax exemptions and tax credits. The Sixth Circuit Court sided with the taxpayers, striking down Ohio’s subsidy as a violation of the Commerce Clause. But the Supreme Court avoided a final judgment on the matter by finding unanimously that the plaintiffs &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oyez.org/cases/2005/04-1704&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'13',r'None'&quot;&gt;did not have standing to bring the suit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, Congress could make corporate subsidies less valuable by threatening to tax state or local incentives as a special kind of income. “Congress should institute a federal tax of 100 percent” on corporate subsidies, Jack Markell, a former governor of Delaware, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/21/opinion/incentives-businesses-corporations-giveaways.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'14',r'None'&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;. “This would not include investments in public infrastructure, work force development or other investments that can attract employers while also providing a significant long-term benefit to taxpayers.” Taxing subsidies would hopefully &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2018/07/landing-amazon-hq2-isnt-the-right-way-for-a-city-to-create-jobs-heres-what-works-instead&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'15',r'None'&quot;&gt;force cities to change their economic-development strategies, from importing other states’ companies&lt;/a&gt; to building their own—through investing in research universities, building more housing, and welcoming immigrants, since foreign-born Americans &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apnews.com/ab44ff583d194070a5eae431231c4450&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'16',r'None'&quot;&gt;have the highest rates of entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, the federal government could actively discourage the culture of corporate subsidies by yelling, screaming, and penny-pinching. As Meagan Day &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacobinmag.com/2018/02/amazon-corporate-headquarters-tax-breaks&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'17',r'None'&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Jacobin&lt;/em&gt;, “The federal government could withhold funds from governors and mayors who threaten to poach jobs from other states, or who won’t disclose their incentive packages.” Washington tends to look on quietly when cash-strapped states break the bank to welcome glitzy tech firms. But an attitude change at the top could trickle down to the local level. Donald Trump, or another president, could have made a national address after the HQ2 announcement slamming Amazon for soliciting taxpayer funds in a silent auction. He could have called a summit to encourage the nation’s mayors and governors to offer the same tax subsidy for HQ2—zero dollars and zero cents. Even a tweet could suffice: “7 BILLION FOR BEZOS?? Trillion-dollar companies in America don’t need our welfare! Bad!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no one is yelling and screaming. Instead, in a starkly divided country, corporate pandering is the last bastion of bipartisanship, an activity enjoyed by both Democrats and Republicans at every level of government. New Jersey and Maryland, both blue states, insisted that Amazon take $7 billion in tax savings just months after congressional Republicans passed a corporate income-tax cut that some analysts project will save Amazon nearly $1 billion over the next decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporate America is getting all the help it doesn’t need. You and I may not like it. But executives such as Jeff Bezos have no reason to care. They are winning by the rules of a broken game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;c-letters-cta&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;c-letters-cta__text&quot;&gt;We want to hear what you think about this article. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/contact/letters/&quot; class=&quot;c-letters-cta__link&quot;&gt;Submit a letter&lt;/a&gt; to the editor or write to letters@theatlantic.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;address id=&quot;article-writer-0&quot; class=&quot;c-article-writer lazyload&quot; data-author-id=&quot;1608&quot; data-include=&quot;css:https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/static/b/frontend/dist/theatlantic/css/components/article-writer.38f8b806e515.css&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/Person&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__image&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a class=&quot;o-media__object&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/derek-thompson/&quot; title=&quot;Derek Thompson's writer page&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-article-writer__img o-media__img&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/None/Derek_Thompson_grey/200.png?mod=1522336427&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-article-writer__img o-media__img lazyload&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/None/Derek_Thompson_grey/200.png?mod=1522336427&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__bio&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/derek-thompson/&quot; class=&quot;author-link&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;Derek Thompson&lt;/a&gt; is a staff writer at &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic,&lt;/em&gt; where he writes about economics, labor markets, and the media. He is the author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Hit-Makers-Science-Popularity-Distraction/dp/110198032X/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hit Makers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 18:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon’s HQ2 Spectacle Isn’t Just Shameful—It Should Be Illegal</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/11/amazons-hq2-spectacle-should-be-illegal/575539/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2018/11/RTX6HE2A/facebook.jpg?1541802126</og:image>
<og:description>Each year, local governments spend nearly $100 billion to move headquarters and factories between states. It’s a wasteful exercise that requires a national solution.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/11/amazons-hq2-spectacle-should-be-illegal/575539/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Redox – A Unix-Like Operating System Written in Rust</title>
<link>https://www.redox-os.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.redox-os.org/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redox-os.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.redox-os.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18442390&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18442390&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 293&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 140&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 16:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wtetzner</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.redox-os.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Keep Your Job as Your Company Grows</title>
<link>https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wEBlaMOmKV4&quot;&gt;I know a change is going to come&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re an early employee at a startup, one day you will wake up to find that what you worked on 24/7 for the last year is no longer the most important thing – you’re no longer the most important employee, and process, meetings, paperwork and managers and bosses have shown up. Most painfully, you’ll learn that &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2015/02/12/what-do-i-do-now/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;your role in the company has to change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;24877&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/mad-employee-s/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;720,509&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Mad employee s&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg?w=468&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-24877&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=106&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;106&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=106 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=212 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I’ve seen these transitions as an investor, board member and CEO. At times they are painful to watch and difficult to manage. Early in my career I lived it as an employee, and I handled it in the worst possible way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I wish I had known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had joined MIPS Computers, my second semiconductor company&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; as the VP of marketing and also took on the role of the acting VP of Sales. During the first year of the company’s life, I was a fireball – relentless in creating and pursuing opportunities – getting on an airplane at the drop of a hat to fly anywhere, anytime, to get a design win. I worked with engineering to try to find product/market fit (&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2009/11/30/customer-development-is-not-a-focus-group/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;big endian or little endian&lt;/a&gt;?) and get the chip designed into companies building engineering workstations – powerful personal computers, all while trying to refine how to find the right markets, customers, and sales process. I didn’t get much sleep, but I was having the time of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after a year there was good news. Our rent-a-CEO was being replaced by a permanent one. Our chip was nearing completion, and I had convinced early &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.alchemistaccelerator.com/lighthouse-customers-four-best-practices&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;lighthouse customers&lt;/a&gt; to design it into their computers. I had done amazing things with almost no resources and got the company on the radar of every tech publication and into deals we had no right to be in. I was feeling 10 feet tall. Everything was great… until the new CEO called me in for a chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember much about the details, but I do remember hearing him tell me how impressed he was with what I had accomplished so far, then immediately the visceral feeling of shock and surprise when his next words were that now the company needed to scale, and I wasn’t the right person to do that… Wait! What??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a minute I couldn’t breathe. I felt like I had been punched in the gut. How could that be?  What do you mean I’m not the right person??? Hadn’t he just listed all the great work I had done? He acknowledged it was a lot of progress but offered that it was a flurry of disconnected tactics without a coherent strategy. No one knew what I was doing, and I couldn’t explain why I was doing it when asked. “You’re just throwing stuff against the wall. That doesn’t scale.” I was speechless. Wasn’t that what the first year of a startup was supposed to be like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scrambling to save my job, I regained the power of speech, and asked him if I could be the person to take the company to the next level. And to his credit (which I only appreciated years later) he agreed that while he was going to start a search, I could be a candidate for the job. And to top it off he got me a coach to help me understand what taking it to the next level meant. In preparation I remember buying all the management books I could find and reading what little literature there was at the time about how small company management transitioned into a larger one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And herein lies the tale….&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I vaguely remember going to lunch with my coach, a nice white-haired “old guy” who was trying to help me learn the skills to grow into the new job. The problem was I had shut down. Even as we were meeting, I was obsessively thinking about the change in my role, my title and my status. “I don’t get it, I did all this work, and everything was great. &lt;em&gt;Why does anything have to change&lt;/em&gt;?”  But I never shared any of how I felt with my coach. To do this day I am really embarrassed to admit that I have no idea what my coach tried to teach me over multiple lunches and weeks. As we went to lunch, all I could think about was me and how I was being screwed. I literally paid zero attention. In my righteous anger I was unreachable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shouldn’t have been surprised, but yet again I was, when a month later the CEO said, that the report from the coach said, “I had a long way to go”. The company was going to hire a VP of Marketing. I was devastated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s Not About Change – It’s About Loss&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;If you had asked me a decade later what had been going on in my head and why I handled this so badly, I would have simply said, that: 1) I was resistant to change, and that 2) I had made this all about me and never once considered that our new CEO was right&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;All true – to a point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me another decade to realize if I had been really honest with myself &lt;em&gt;it wasn’t about fighting change at all&lt;/em&gt;. Heck every day something new was happening at our startup. I was agile enough to keep up with innumerable changes and I was changing lots of things myself. It was actually about something much more personal I wouldn’t admit to myself – it was that &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strategy-business.com/article/09306?gko=5df7f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;these changes made me fear what I was losing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I felt a &lt;em&gt;l&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;oss of status and identity &lt;/em&gt;– I had been judged inadequate to continue in my role and my stature and the value of my skills and abilities had dropped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt a &lt;em&gt;loss of certainty &lt;/em&gt;– I was now competing to hold a job I thought was mine forever in the company. At least that’s what I thought my business card said. Now I was adrift and didn’t know what the future held.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt a loss of &lt;em&gt;autonomy –&lt;/em&gt; Up until now I used my best judgment of what was needed and I was doing what I wanted, when I wanted it. I was fine making up a strategy on the fly from disconnected tactics. Now we were going to have plans and a strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt a &lt;em&gt;loss of community &lt;/em&gt;– we had been a small tight team who had bonded together under extreme pressure and accomplished amazing things. Now new people who knew none of that and appreciated little of it were coming in. They had little trust and empathy with us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt &lt;em&gt;the process lacked fairness –&lt;/em&gt; no one had warned/told me that the job I was doing needed to change over time, and no one told me what those new skills were.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was going on?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Researchers have found there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strategy-business.com/article/09306?gko=5df7f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;link between social connection and physical discomfort&lt;/a&gt; within the brain. “Being hungry and being ostracized activate similar neural responses because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strategy-business.com/article/09306?gko=5df7f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;being socially connected is necessary for survival&lt;/a&gt;. Although a job is often regarded as a purely economic transaction, &lt;em&gt;the brain experiences the workplace first and foremost as a social system&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back over the decades it’s clear that the new CEO was right. Even though these losses triggered something primal, I did need to learn discipline, pattern recognition, time management, separating the trivial from the important and the difference between tactics and strategy. I needed to learn to grow from being a great individual contributor to being a manager and then a leader. Instead I walked away from learning any of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably added five unneeded years to my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What should I have done?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Today it’s understood that all startups &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2015/02/12/what-do-i-do-now/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;go through a metamorphosis as they become larger companies&lt;/a&gt;. They go from organizations struggling for survival as they search for product/market fit, to building a repeatable and scalable business model, and then growing to profitability. And we are all &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunbar's_number&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;hard-wired for a set number&lt;/a&gt; of social relationships. This mental wiring defines boundaries in growing an organization – get bigger than a certain size, and you need a different management system. The skills needed from employees differ at each stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;24903&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/search-build-grow-4/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1385,310&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;search build grow&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=90&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-24903&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;90&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=90 400w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;h=180 800w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=34 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=67 300w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=172 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What I wish I knew was that if you’re an early company employee, &lt;em&gt;it’s not likely that the skills you have on day one are the skills needed as the company scales to the next level&lt;/em&gt;. This sentence is worth reading multiple times as no one – not the person who hired you, the VC’s or your peers -is going to tell you when you’re hired &lt;span&gt;that the company will likely outgrow you.&lt;/span&gt; Some (like your peers or even the founders) don’t understand it, and others (the VCs) realize it’s not in their interest to let you know. The painful reality is that products change, strategies change, people change…things have to change for your company to stay in business and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What should my CEO have done?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;When my CEO was explaining to me how the company needed to change to grow, he was explaining facts while I was processing deeply held feelings. The &lt;em&gt;changes in the organization and my role represented what I was about to lose&lt;/em&gt;. And when people feel they’re going to lose something deeply important, it triggers an emotional response because change feels like a threat. It’s not an excuse for my counterproductive behavior, but explains why I acted out like I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startup CEOs need to &lt;u&gt;think about these transitions from day one &lt;/u&gt;and consider &lt;em&gt;how to address the real sense of loss these transitions mean to early employees&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loss of status&lt;/em&gt;? It’s almost impossible to take away a title from someone, give it to someone else and still retain that employee. Think hard about whether titles need to be formal (VP of Engineering, VP of Marketing, VP of Sales, etc.) before the company finds product/market fit and/or tens of people – as you can almost guarantee that these people won’t have those roles and titles when you scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loss of Certainty?&lt;/em&gt; Startups and VC’s have historically operated on the “I’ll deal with this later” principle in letting early employees know what happens as the company scales. The common wisdom is that no one would want to work like crazy knowing that they might not be the ones to lead as the company grows. I call this the Moses-problem – you work for years to get the tribe to the promised land – but you’re not allowed to cross over. The company needs to give formal recognition for those individuals who brought the tribe to the promised land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loss of Autonomy? &lt;/em&gt;This is the time you and your employees get to have a discussion about the next steps in their career. Do they want to be an individual contributor? Manager of people and process? Special projects? These shouldn’t be random assignments but instead, offer a roadmap of possible choices and directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loss of Community?&lt;/em&gt; Your original hires embody the company culture. Unless you have them capture the unique aspects of the culture, it will become diluted and disappear among the new hires. Declare them &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mastersofscale.com/#/aneel-bhusri-the-elusive-formula-for-great-hiring/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;cultural co-founders&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Help them understand the community is growing and they’re the ambassadors. Have them formalize it as part of a now needed on-boarding process as the company grows. And most importantly, make sure that they are celebrated as the team that got the company to where it is now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loss of Fairness?&lt;/em&gt; Just telling employees “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wEBlaMOmKV4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;a change is going to come&lt;/a&gt;” it is not sufficient. What are the new skills needed when you scale from Search to Build to Grow – from tens to hundreds and then thousands of people? How can your existing employees gain those new skills?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;VC’s, Founders and CEOs now recognize that startups grow through different stages: &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2015/02/12/what-do-i-do-now/&quot;&gt;Search, Build and Grow&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;They recognize that employees need different skills at each stage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And that some of the original employees won’t grow into the next stage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But while these changes make rational sense to the CEO and the board, to early employees these changes feel like a real and tangible personal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strategy-business.com/article/09306?gko=5df7f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;loss&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Loss of Status and Identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of Community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of Autonomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of Certainty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of Fairness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CEOs need to put processes in places to acknowledge and deal with the real sense of loss
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;These will keep early employees motivated – and retained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And build a stronger company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For employees, how you handle change will affect the trajectory of your career and possibly your net worth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post appeared in &lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/blog/steve-blank-how-to-keep-your-job-as-your-startup-grows&quot;&gt;AngelList&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/blog/steve-blank-how-to-keep-your-job-as-your-startup-grows&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;24934&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/angellist-2/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1458,277&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Angellist&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=468&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-24934 size-thumbnail aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=28&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;28&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=28 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=295&amp;amp;h=56 295w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=57 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-official sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-6599589-24863-5bebd54b6e073&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20180319#blog_id=6599589&amp;amp;post_id=24863&amp;amp;origin=steveblank.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=6599589-24863-5bebd54b6e073&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-6599589-24863-5bebd54b6e073&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postinfo&quot;&gt;Filed under: &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/category/familycareerculture/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Family/Career/Culture&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/category/mips-computers/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;MIPS Computers&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 15:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Raj7k</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Steve Blank How to Keep Your Job As Your Company Grows</og:title>
<og:url>https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/</og:url>
<og:description>I know a change is going to come If you’re an early employee at a startup, one day you will wake up to find that what you worked on 24/7 for the last year is no longer the most important thing &amp;#82…</og:description>
<og:image>https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GitLab Made $10.5M in Revenue with Every Employee Working from Home</title>
<link>https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;11.720930232558&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The wall behind Sid Sijbrandij emanates a warm orange glow. Then, waves rush toward the shore at his back. The change in scenery isn't distracting, however. It's deliberate. The &lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://inc.com/profile/gitlab&quot;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt; co-founder has a green screen in his office, which is also his home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;14.571428571429&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every employee of the San Francisco-based startup, which offers tools for software developers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/margo-aaron/the-truth-about-working-from-home-5-things-no-one-tells-you.html&quot;&gt;works from home&lt;/a&gt;. Three years ago, that was nine people. Today, GitLab's 350 employees across 45 countries use video calls and Slack chats to stay constantly connected. The dramatic expansion has been enabled by outsize investment--a $100 million fund raise in September landed it a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/gitlab-raising-capital-at-1-billion-valuation-1537369355&quot;&gt;$1 billion valuation&lt;/a&gt;. It has also been propelled by revenue growth that skyrocketed to nearly $10.5 million last year, up 6,213 percent from just over $165,000 in 2014--helping it notch No. 44 on this year's &lt;a href=&quot;https://inc.com/inc5000/index.html&quot;&gt;Inc. 5000 list of the fastest-growing companies in America&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That growth is also deliberate, Sijbrandij attests. &lt;/span&gt;For each step of creating computer code, from planning and writing to releasing it to the world, a plethora of apps exist to help streamline that process. GitLab aims to integrate all of those systems into one platform. The company offers free limited access for individual developers and paid full access for enterprise companies, promising a 200 percent increase in development processing speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The message for people who don't speak tech: Doubling your team's efficiency is almost like hiring a bunch of extra software developers, without having to make room in the payroll budget. In a world where everything happens online, the faster you can push code, the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Catnip for coders.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The platform's first version was created in 2011 by Dmitriy Zaporozhets, Gitlab's other co-founder and current CTO. He was a programmer at a Ukrainian consulting firm who wanted a better code-sharing platform for his company's 200 employees. The best options were deemed too expensive by management, so he built one himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineImage__imageLeft__V4ioc&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word of the free open-source tool spread quickly, thanks to a post on Hacker News, the website owned by startup incubator Y-Combinator. Other developers started adding to its code, including Sijbrandij, a Dutch entrepreneur living in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, Sijbrandij sent Zaporozhets an email. &quot;Hey, I'm going to start a company around GitLab,&quot; he recalls writing. &quot;Thanks for making it. You're not going to get anything. Hope that's OK with you.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year later, Zaporozhets quit his job and joined Sijbrandij full-time. They toiled away in their respective countries, officially launching the company in 2014, until the company was accepted to Y-Combinator in 2015. The San Francisco stint gave them a much-needed crash course in sales, marketing, finance, and recruiting. They internalized the incubator's famous insistence on launching products right away, no matter what state they're in, and using customer feedback to polish them. GitLab publishes a new feature the 22nd of every month, whether it's ready or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past June, GitHub--one of the world's largest code-sharing platforms--sold to Microsoft for $7.5 billion. Some users bristled at the prospect of corporate control and fled to GitLab, which gained 200,000 code projects and a seven-fold increase in orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sijbrandij hopes the awareness bump is ending a common assumption that the similarly named companies do the same thing. While they may have started out with near-identical offerings, Sijbrandij says his company has expanded its services widely since 2011. &quot;[Our] scope is ten times bigger than GitHub,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Remote but not Isolated.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;While Zaporozhets was open with his code, he was initially cagey about his personal life--refusing even to turn on his webcam for meetings. Sijbrandij asked for a photo, and received one of Zaporozhets wearing gigantic, face-obscuring sunglasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's changed, thanks to the company's insistence on transparency. GitLab meetings and presentations are uploaded to YouTube. Its employee handbook--over 1,000 pages long when printed--is publicly available online as a resource, so employees can get questions answered without waking up co-workers in a different time zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineImage__imageLeft__V4ioc&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantage to an all-remote team is obvious: Your hiring pool is gigantic, and you don't need to convince top talent to move for you. GitLab's percentage of quality job applications is similar to other companies--its dramatic number of recent hires is due to how many applications it receives, 13,000 in the second quarter of 2018 alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, maintaining a culture is really difficult. &quot;To be honest, I was definitely a bit concerned,&quot; says Dave Munichiello, a general partner at Alphabet's venture capital arm, GV, which invested in GitLab in 2017. &quot;What happens when the all-hands meeting isn't a bunch of folks hanging around the water cooler listening to the CEO articulate the vision and the mission?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab's leaders constantly think about it. Sijbrandij even hired away Netflix's vice president of talent, Barbie Brewer, to serve as chief people officer. Virtual coffee breaks, where employees talk about their lives outside GitLab, are built into everyone's schedules. Senior leaders hold office hours in video chat rooms that anyone can join. When GitLab meets its monthly goals, everyone gets a free dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;What we've learned from GitLab,&quot; Munichiello says, &quot;is that when you have a leadership team that's as committed to remote-only as they are, and as communicative and transparent as they are, and as insistent on documentation as they are, it can work.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt; An earlier version of this article misstated the size of GitLab's September fund raise, which was $100 million.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 15:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>janvdberg</dc:creator>
<og:title>GitLab's Secret to Multi-Million-Dollar Success: All 350 Employees Work Remotely</og:title>
<og:description>It's a classic story: Tech company goes to Silicon Valley incubator, emerges with a plan, and grows explosively. The only exception is that few of GitLab's employees actually live in the Bay Area.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.incimages.com/uploaded_files/image/970x450/gitlab-founders_374507.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Selects New York City and Northern Virginia for New Headquarters</title>
<link>https://blog.aboutamazon.com/company-news/amazon-selects-new-york-city-and-northern-virginia-for-new-headquarters</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.aboutamazon.com/company-news/amazon-selects-new-york-city-and-northern-virginia-for-new-headquarters</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;RichTextArticleBody mood-color&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;RichTextArticleBody-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon today announced that we have selected New York City and Arlington, Virginia, as the locations for our new headquarters. Amazon will invest $5 billion and create more than 50,000 jobs across the two new headquarters locations, with more than 25,000 employees each in New York City and Arlington. The new locations will join Seattle as the company’s three headquarters in North America. In addition, Amazon announced that it has selected Nashville for a new Center of Excellence for its Operations business, which is responsible for the company’s customer fulfillment, transportation, supply chain, and other similar activities. The Operations Center of Excellence in Nashville will create more than 5,000 jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Washington, D.C. metro headquarters in Arlington will be located in National Landing, and the New York City headquarters will be located in the Long Island City neighborhood in Queens. Amazon’s investments in each new headquarters will spur the creation of tens of thousands of additional jobs in the surrounding communities. Hiring at both the new headquarters will begin in 2019. The Operations Center of Excellence will be located in downtown Nashville as part of a new development site just north of the Gulch, and hiring will also begin in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are excited to build new headquarters in New York City and Northern Virginia,” said Jeff Bezos, founder and CEO of Amazon. “These two locations will allow us to attract world-class talent that will help us to continue inventing for customers for years to come. The team did a great job selecting these sites, and we look forward to becoming an even bigger part of these communities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;cms-headings-h2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon in Long Island City in New York City&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Located just across the East River from Midtown Manhattan and the Upper East Side, Long Island City is a mixed-use community where arts and industry intersect. It is a diverse community with a unique blend of cultural institutions, arts organizations, new and converted housing, restaurants, bars, breweries, waterfront parks, hotels, academic institutions, and small and large tech sector and industrial businesses. Long Island City has some of the best transit access in New York City, with 8 subway lines, 13 bus lines, commuter rail, a bike-sharing service, and ferries serving the area, and LaGuardia and JFK airports are in close proximity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;As part of Amazon’s new headquarters, New York and Long Island City will benefit from more than 25,000 full-time high-paying jobs; approximately $2.5 billion in Amazon investment; 4 million square feet of energy-efficient office space with an opportunity to expand to 8 million square feet; and an estimated incremental tax revenue of more than $10 billion over the next 20 years as a result of Amazon’s investment and job creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Amazon will receive performance-based direct incentives of $1.525 billion based on the company creating 25,000 jobs in Long Island City. This includes a refundable tax credit through New York State’s Excelsior Program of up to $1.2 billion calculated as a percentage of the salaries Amazon expects to pay employees over the next 10 years, which equates to $48,000 per job for 25,000 jobs with an average wage of over $150,000; and a cash grant from Empire State Development of $325 million based on the square footage of buildings occupied in the next 10 years. Amazon will receive these incentives over the next decade based on the incremental jobs it creates each year and as it reaches building occupancy targets. The company will separately apply for as-of-right incentives including New York City’s Industrial &amp;amp; Commercial Abatement Program (ICAP) and New York City’s Relocation and Employment Assistance Program (REAP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The community will benefit from New York City providing funding through a Payment In Lieu Of Tax (PILOT) program based on Amazon’s property taxes on a portion of the development site to fund community infrastructure improvements developed through input from residents during the planning process. Amazon has agreed to donate space on its campus for a tech startup incubator and for use by artists and industrial businesses, and Amazon will donate a site for a new primary or intermediary public school. The company will also invest in infrastructure improvements and new green spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;“When I took office, I said we would build a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; New York State – one that is fiscally responsible and fosters a business climate that is attractive to growing companies and the industries of tomorrow. We’ve delivered on those promises and more, and today, with Amazon committing to expand its headquarters in Long Island City, New York can proudly say that we have attracted one of the largest, most competitive economic development investments in U.S. history,” said Governor Andrew M. Cuomo of New York. “With an average salary of $150,000 per year for the tens of thousands of new jobs Amazon is creating in Queens, economic opportunity and investment will flourish for the entire region. Amazon understands that New York has everything the company needs to continue its growth. The State’s more than $100 billion transportation infrastructure program – the most ambitious in our history – combined with our education initiatives like K-12 tech education and the first-in-the-nation Excelsior Scholarship program, will help ensure long-term success and an unrivaled talent pool for Amazon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a giant step on our path to building an economy in New York City that leaves no one behind. We are thrilled that Amazon has selected New York City for its new headquarters,” said Mayor Bill de Blasio of New York City. “New Yorkers will get tens of thousands of new, good-paying jobs, and Amazon will get the best talent anywhere in the world. We’re going to use this opportunity to open up good careers in tech to thousands of people looking for their foothold in the new economy, including those in City colleges and public housing. The City and State are working closely together to make sure Amazon’s expansion is planned smartly, and to ensure this fast growing neighborhood has the transportation, schools, and infrastructure it needs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;cms-headings-h2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon in National Landing in Arlington, Virginia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;National Landing is an urban community in Northern Virginia located less than 3 miles from downtown Washington, D.C. The area is served by 3 Metro stations, commuter rail access, and Reagan National Airport – all within walking distance. The community has a variety of hotels, restaurants, high-rise apartment buildings, retail, and commercial offices. National Landing has abundant parks and open space with sports and cultural events for residents of all ages throughout the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;As part of Amazon’s new headquarters, Virginia and Arlington will benefit from more than 25,000 full-time high-paying jobs; approximately $2.5 billion in Amazon investment; 4 million square feet of energy-efficient office space with the opportunity to expand to 8 million square feet; and an estimated incremental tax revenue of $3.2 billion over the next 20 years as a result of Amazon’s investment and job creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Amazon will receive performance-based direct incentives of $573 million based on the company creating 25,000 jobs with an average wage of over $150,000 in Arlington. This includes a workforce cash grant from the Commonwealth of Virginia of up to $550 million based on $22,000 for each job created over the next 12 years. Amazon will only receive this incentive if it creates the forecasted high-paying jobs. The company will also receive a cash grant from Arlington of $23 million over 15 years based on the incremental growth of the existing local Transient Occupancy Tax, a tax on hotel rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The community and Amazon employees will benefit from the Commonwealth investing $195 million in infrastructure in the neighborhood, including improvements to the Crystal City and the Potomac Yard Metro stations; a pedestrian bridge connecting National Landing and Reagan National Airport; and work to improve safety, accessibility, and the pedestrian experience crossing Route 1 over the next 10 years. Arlington will also dedicate an estimated $28 million based on 12% of future property tax revenues earned from an existing Tax Increment Financing (TIF) district for on-site infrastructure and open space in National Landing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is a big win for Virginia – I’m proud Amazon recognizes the tremendous assets the Commonwealth has to offer and plans to deepen its roots here,” said Governor Ralph Northam of Virginia. “Virginia put together a proposal for Amazon that we believe represents a new model of economic development for the 21st century, and I’m excited to say that our innovative approach was successful. The majority of Virginia’s partnership proposal consists of investments in our education and transportation infrastructure that will bolster the features that make Virginia so attractive: a strong and talented workforce, a stable and competitive business climate, and a world-class higher education system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are proud that Amazon has selected National Landing for a major new headquarters. This is, above all, a validation of our community’s commitment to sustainability, transit-oriented development, affordable housing, and diversity,” said Arlington County Board Chair Katie Cristol. “The strength of our workforce coupled with our proximity to the nation’s capital makes us an attractive business location. But Arlington’s real strength is the decades of planning that have produced one of the most vibrant, civically engaged communities in the world. Those plans have paved the way for this investment, and we look forward to engaging the Arlington community about Amazon’s plans and how we can grow together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;cms-headings-h2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon’s new Operations Center of Excellence in Nashville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Downtown Nashville, along the Cumberland River, is the heart of the city just north of the Gulch and is home to urban living, retail, restaurants, entertainment venues, hospitality, open green spaces, and offices. The area is served by commuter rail, more than a dozen bus routes, and is a 15-minute drive to Nashville International Airport.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;As part of Amazon’s investment, Tennessee, Davidson County and the city of Nashville will benefit from 5,000 full-time, high-paying jobs; over $230 million in investment; 1 million square feet of energy-efficient office space; and an estimated incremental tax revenue of more than $1 billion over the next 10 years as a result of Amazon’s investment and job creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Amazon will receive performance-based direct incentives of up to $102 million based on the company creating 5,000 jobs with an average wage of over $150,000 in Nashville. This includes a cash grant for capital expenditures from the state of Tennessee of $65 million based on the company creating 5,000 jobs over the next 7 years, which is equivalent to $13,000 per job; a cash grant from the city of Nashville of up to $15 million based on $500 for each job created over the next 7 years; and a job tax credit to offset franchise and excise taxes from the state of Tennessee of $21.7 million based on $4,500 per new job over the next 7 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We want to thank Amazon for its continued investment in the state of Tennessee and are excited about the additional 5,000 corporate jobs they will be creating in Nashville,” said Governor Bill Haslam of Tennessee. “It has never been clearer that Tennessee is a great place to do business, and we continue to attract a wide variety of global companies that provide high-paying, quality jobs for our residents.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Amazon’s decision to expand its presence in Nashville is a direct result of the talented workforce and strong community we’ve built here,” said Mayor David Briley of Nashville. “These are quality, high-paying jobs that will boost our economy, provide our workers with new opportunities, and show the rest of the world that Nashville is a premiere location for business investment. We thank Amazon for investing in Nashville, and we look forward to welcoming them to this community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more than 610,000 employees worldwide, including over 250,000 in North America, Amazon ranks #1 on American Customer Satisfaction Index, #2 on Fortune’s World’s Most Admired Companies, #1 on The Harris Poll’s Corporate Reputation survey, and #1 on LinkedIn’s U.S. Top Companies, a ranking recognizing the most desirable workplaces in the country. Amazon was also recently included in the Military Times’ Best for Vets list of companies committed to providing opportunities for military veterans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All economic impact and incentive figures are best estimates calculated by relevant entities in each of the selected communities based on current information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;cms-headings-h2&quot; id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FAQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Why did Amazon pick more than one location for its new headquarters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We can recruit more top talent by being in two locations. These are fantastic cities that attract a lot of great talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What differentiates the two new headquarters locations from the corporate offices and development centers Amazon has across the U.S. and around the world?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Amazon’s biggest office outside of Seattle in the U.S. has 3,100 employees – we are planning to grow both these new headquarters to over 25,000. These headquarters locations will have far more employees, senior leaders, and we will do more cross-company meetings and events at these headquarters, including company-wide All Hands meetings, Shareholder Meetings, Board of Directors meetings, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. How did you pick New York City and Northern Virginia as headquarters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We were looking for a location with strong local and regional talent—particularly in software development and related fields—to continue hiring and innovating on behalf of our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Where will the headquarters be located in New York City and Arlington?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Amazon in Northern Virginia is in National Landing in Arlington&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/6f2d76e/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2Fe0%2Fe5%2F06c5a387413792757b62d70786d5%2Famzn-arlington-v2.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map of the Arlington area with a pin placed to illustrate the location of a new Amazon headquarters. &quot; srcset=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/6f2d76e/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2Fe0%2Fe5%2F06c5a387413792757b62d70786d5%2Famzn-arlington-v2.2.jpg 1x,https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/18555ae/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/1624x1260!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2Fe0%2Fe5%2F06c5a387413792757b62d70786d5%2Famzn-arlington-v2.2.jpg 2x&quot; width=&quot;812&quot; height=&quot;630&quot;/&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;mood-bgcolor&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2z8rZWx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Download the map here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon in New York City is in the Long Island City neighborhood in Queens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/462e147/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F77%2Fe5%2Fd28b3fdc4cbd9ec1f1029a6558ad%2Famzn-nyc-v2.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map of the New York City area with a pin placed to illustrate the location of a new Amazon headquarters. &quot; srcset=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/462e147/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F77%2Fe5%2Fd28b3fdc4cbd9ec1f1029a6558ad%2Famzn-nyc-v2.2.jpg 1x,https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/5cb8f05/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/1624x1260!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F77%2Fe5%2Fd28b3fdc4cbd9ec1f1029a6558ad%2Famzn-nyc-v2.2.jpg 2x&quot; width=&quot;812&quot; height=&quot;630&quot;/&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;mood-bgcolor&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2QDx93D&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Download the map here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. What is the Operations Center of Excellence and where will it be located in Nashville?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Our Retail Operations division handles customer fulfillment, customer service, transportation, and supply chain, amongst others. The Operations Center of Excellence will be the Eastern U.S. regional hub for the tech and management functions of this division. It will be located in downtown Nashville just north of The Gulch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon Operations Center of Excellence is north of the Gulch in downtown Nashville&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/0d50e8a/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F4a%2F74%2F7a0760434eed825dada968c3c9e3%2Famzn-nashville-v2.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map of the Nashville area with a pin placed to illustrate the location of a new Amazon Operations Center of Excellence. &quot; srcset=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/0d50e8a/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F4a%2F74%2F7a0760434eed825dada968c3c9e3%2Famzn-nashville-v2.2.jpg 1x,https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/7f33b70/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/1624x1260!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F4a%2F74%2F7a0760434eed825dada968c3c9e3%2Famzn-nashville-v2.2.jpg 2x&quot; width=&quot;812&quot; height=&quot;630&quot;/&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;mood-bgcolor&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2Pqqhdy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Download the map here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. What role did economic incentives play in Amazon picking these locations and what incentives have been agreed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Economic incentives were one factor in our decision—but attracting top talent was the leading driver. Our agreements with each location may be downloaded:&lt;br/&gt;New York City, New York &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2TbfCBC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Arlington, Virginia &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2z9qnMg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2B46dEQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Nashville, Tennessee &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2z8sdx8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2OG8nOD&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Are you continuing to hire in the Seattle area?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Yes. We currently have more than 8,000 positions open and over 45,000 Amazonians in the Seattle area.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 15:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>appwiz</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon selects New York City and Northern Virginia for new headquarters</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.aboutamazon.com/company-news/amazon-selects-new-york-city-and-northern-virginia-for-new-headquarters</og:url>
<og:image>https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/90456df/2147483647/strip/true/crop/899x471+2+0/resize/1200x628!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F58%2Fe5%2F4501be6b4829961d701cae8ed249%2Fblog-social-final-2.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Amazon to invest $5 billion and create more than 50,000 jobs across the two new headquarters, and announces Nashville as new Operations Center of Excellence with more than 5,000 jobs.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.aboutamazon.com/company-news/amazon-selects-new-york-city-and-northern-virginia-for-new-headquarters</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>