<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: How to come up with monetizable side project ideas?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4168126094571&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8126094570928&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;18047553&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: How to come up with monetizable side project ideas?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_18047553&quot;&gt;269 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=sunilkumarc&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;sunilkumarc&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553&quot;&gt;12 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_18047553&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=18047553&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D18047553&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20to%20come%20up%20with%20monetizable%20side%20project%20ideas%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20to%20come%20up%20with%20monetizable%20side%20project%20ideas%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=18047553&amp;amp;auth=00cb1decf7af0192d52aa8f4973d74b426dfc08a&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553&quot;&gt;82 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;I love building small tools which solve problems I myself face in my day to day life. Having been worked in different companies over the last 4 years, I feel I've acquired enough knowledge to develop big applications(big enough to make money) on my own.
&lt;p&gt;I was wondering, how one can come up with side project ideas which can generate few hundred dollars per month on the side. Any inputs, resources and wisdom are appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Winter 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 19:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sunilkumarc</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chrome is a Google Service that happens to include a Browser Engine</title>
<link>https://ha.x0r.be/posts/chrome-is-a-google-service/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ha.x0r.be/posts/chrome-is-a-google-service/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;mt4 w-100&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;f6 b helvetica tracked&quot;&gt;POSTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;time class=&quot;f6 mv4 dib tracked&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-09-22T15:46:50+01:00&quot;&gt;September 22, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting with Chrome 69, logging into a Google Site is tied to logging into Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is typically the topic where things are complex enough that tweets or 500 character Mastodon toots don’t do it justice. I’d also mention that I prefer to avoid directly linking people’s posts on this, because I dislike the practice of taking discussions out of their original audience and treating them as official or semi-official communications from a given company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what changed with Chrome 69? From that version, any time someone using Chrome logs into a Google service or site, they are also logged into Chrome-as-a-browser with that user account. Any time someone logs out of a Google service, they are also logged out of the browser. Before Chrome 69, Chrome users could decline to be logged into Chrome entirely, skipping the use of Sync and other features that are tied to the login and they could use Chrome in a logged-out state while still making use of GMail for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to spell it out: this means Google logins for Chrome are now de-facto mandatory if you ever login to a Google site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone in the security community raised this, it turned out that apparently this is intended behaviour from Google’s side as confirmed by multiple googlers and they were wondering why the new behaviour might feel abusive to some people. Some folks working on Chrome pointed out that most people can’t differentiate between logging into a Google Site and logging into Chrome and this has lead to problems with shared computers, where person A logs into GMail, but person B is logged into Chrome. This prompted Chrome developers to come up with the change that erases the distinction entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this point that I should note that I don’t personally use Chrome, as I felt it was too closely corporate Google even before this change. This is also not a post arguing that “some users can tell the difference, therefor…”, I do believe software should be written with the common users in mind. Interestingly, the common user belief that strongly equates Chrome with a Google Service (and not an application or tool) is probably the more accurate view of Chrome, post release 69. It’s worth wondering from where users got that impression and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if this change is just about bringing Chrome in line with what most users believe anyway, what’s the fuss? Perhaps it’s not about what people believe, but what is right. Perhaps Google doesn’t want Chrome, currently having majority browser market share, to be a neutral platform. A lot of people, developers especially, believe that Chrome is a Google-influenced but more or less neutral tool and then this widespread belief has to be reconciled with the Chrome-as-a-service thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violating the content vs browser separation layer doesn’t just conform to what a lot of users believe, it also ties what’s happening inside the browser to Google on an unprecedented level, throwing the neutrality of Chrome as a platform into question. What’s the next thing that Google and only Google can make Chrome do? Concerned about shared computers but you’re not Google? There is no neutral API to log someone out from Chrome and prevent data from being synced if it’s about person A logging into Facebook in person B’s Chrome profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sidenote&lt;/em&gt;: Most Google services have for me this in common with Facebook: these services are too deeply integrated and impossible to use in part or isolation. It’s either the entire system or nothing, based on how the question of consent is approached. You would like to use GMail (logged in obviously) but Google search, Youtube, Chrome etc without a login? No can do. You selected strict settings in Facebook for your profile data? You’re just an API/permission redesign away from having your choices nullified. Part of me feels that this Chrome shared computer issue that Googlers mentioned is real, but it’s also just too convenient to solve this by tieing Chrome closer to Google, you know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;update&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;- Compare the basic (local) and signed-in mode in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/privacy/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome’s privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;. Silently upgrading from basic mode to signed-in mode makes quite a large difference.&lt;br/&gt;- Chromium is apparently also affected by this.&lt;br/&gt;- There is a workaround to disable this behaviour. I deliberately don’t include it here, as that relies on internal flags and the point of this post wasn’t to try to revert this change, but rather to think about Chrome’s direction in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&quot;w-30-l mt6-l&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 18:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dredmorbius</dc:creator>
<og:title>Chrome is a Google Service that happens to include a Browser Engine</og:title>
<og:description>Starting with Chrome 69, logging into a Google Site is tied to logging into Chrome.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://ha.x0r.be/posts/chrome-is-a-google-service/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ha.x0r.be/posts/chrome-is-a-google-service/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>3D engine entirely made of MS Excel formulae</title>
<link>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/CBel/20180213/308549/3D_engine_entirely_made_of_MS_Excel_formulae__Enjoy_this_Doomxls_file_.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/CBel/20180213/308549/3D_engine_entirely_made_of_MS_Excel_formulae__Enjoy_this_Doomxls_file_.php</guid>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;The following blog post, unless otherwise noted, was written by a member of Gamasutra’s community.&lt;br/&gt;The thoughts and opinions expressed are those of the writer and not Gamasutra or its parent company.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is on how I could write a 3D engine using only excel formula, including following functionalities :&lt;br/&gt;- infinite procedural generated maze map&lt;br/&gt;- real time ray tracer rendering&lt;br/&gt;- occlusion calculation&lt;br/&gt;- basic illumination rendering&lt;br/&gt;- illumination and compute shader&lt;br/&gt;- natural displacement engine&lt;br/&gt;- No macro at all used by the 3D engine,&lt;br/&gt;    * to enjoy the game using key press, some macro trigger the displacements, using just one simple copy instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reho.st/self/4811655ae53dd1ad1462e74ec790e16ebd2d1c33.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Endless series of walls, and monsters !&quot; src=&quot;https://reho.st/preview/self/4811655ae53dd1ad1462e74ec790e16ebd2d1c33.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In-game screen capture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can freely download the file and test it by yourself !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Demonstration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/iCeOEQVUWZ0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A computer science teacher once told us &quot;a given computation can be achieved with any programming language, even spreadsheet formula&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, as wise at it could have been, including Excel in the comparison sounded definitively stupid ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thereafter, while studying Turing machine, it then sounded correct, yet not very fulfilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several years of experience with Excel, we will mostly remind Excel formula only are definitively limited with the lack of input/outputs.&lt;br/&gt;But, the set of problems that can be simply solved with formula only remain impressive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this work is not just some kind of performance ... There is was a good reason for me to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spreadsheet are a powerful tool that everyone has to learn to use for almost every business jobs.&lt;br/&gt;Yet, when most people come to solve most complexes problems, they want to use VBA language, without even knowing why.&lt;br/&gt;And once they started learning it, they try to use it for any kind of problem, even simple search or rendering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, as an excel teacher, I'm trying to explain to these people why writing VBA macro for any problem while not being educated on computer programming is not only a real waste of time, but also a serious risk for their spreadsheet quality.&lt;br/&gt;In a business environment, using formula rather than macro is :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Faster to write for anyone but professional analyst programmer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier to maintain for anyone but professional analyst programmer. (while macro are mostly unusable once the initial developer is gone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A guaranteed quality, due to permanent value checking. (a forced Test Driven Development method)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More efficient in the long run, due to the &quot;think before you write&quot; process with formula design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And definitively, much better integrated in the overall spreadsheet tool, following the initial design pattern of the spreadsheet, while macro often appear like specific developments requiring extensive maintenance afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nota : these concerns mostly apply to procedure used as macro, while additional function written in VBA can increase the efficiency without lowering the quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I came to write this game : an applied demonstration, that macro was not necessary at first, even for some of the most complex problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be more precise, I found only 2 cases when VBA is required :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Adding specifics input or output (as I did here to get key events), while formula is always limited to change on the cell itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some complex problems (like optimization, try-and-check problems), those in which the computation time is too long, and/or taking too much space. But theses problems are quite rare in real business life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This said, now, I'll only focus on the rest of this article on how the spreadsheet actually works, for its different aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spreadsheet is meant to be a doom-like game, in a sort of maze environment.&lt;br/&gt;It could have been a fixed, manually-constructed map, possibly looping on borders, but it would require storage, lookup, and an initial design.&lt;br/&gt;In the meantime, using a procedural generated infinite map sounded much more worth of the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a random generated map, we need it to be self-consistent over time, so rand() function could not be used, as we do not control the random seed.&lt;br/&gt;The seeds for the random generator have to be the position (x;y) on the map, to get a different value for each position, and we cannot take the result of the previous random as seed for the next, or we would have to store all the map from the beginning.&lt;br/&gt;While providing high quality random, usual hash functions are too expensive, so I needed to find an other one.&lt;br/&gt;Trying to use fractal generator appeared to be also quite costly, and providing interesting result only for a small part of the map.&lt;br/&gt;Then I found the middle-square method, which isn't very &quot;random&quot; when consecutive seed are used, but gave me the idea of taking decimal of any other calculation.&lt;br/&gt;I found out that taking decimals of sin(x)+cos(y) finally provided nice decimals, without any visible pattern, and a computation time surprisingly short.&lt;br/&gt;To get decimals, mathematical function mod() and floor() are much more efficient compared to text function substring mid()&lt;br/&gt;Trying to get the map looking like a rat maze, I didnt made block of solid block, otherwise it would have looked like a cavern (minecraft style) rather than a maze.&lt;br/&gt;So we needed thin walls, with 2 possible walls for each square. We can then take 2 blocks of digits among the same random value.&lt;br/&gt;2 parameters controlling the density of walls.&lt;br/&gt;Given theses rules, we can either display the maze, or test any wall given it's position for raytracing.&lt;br/&gt;Note that the map is &quot;flat&quot;, without any top/down. It would be possible to add relief using relief generator (diamond-square algorithm could apply, as it is possible to write it with a non-recursive function), but the solution of cutting holes in both ceiling and floor, with an additional level value would greatly ease the whole following process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ok, we're definitively in hell&quot; src=&quot;https://reho.st/self/fd27e421d28e211d575353940119722d94c665f1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ok, we're definitively in hell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The raycaster solution imply to determine for each pixel which face the ray would touch first, and retrieve some information from it, (distance, angle with light, color ...).&lt;br/&gt;Raytracer also require additional ray to spread from this point (reflections, transparencies), with a direct massive increase on computation cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Occlusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problematic will be to find the first object in the course of each ray.&lt;br/&gt;Since the maze is actually flat, with horizontal walls, the nearest wall found will be the same for all pixels of a given column.&lt;br/&gt;The process can then be simplified as an horizontal radar, on 1 dimension.&lt;br/&gt;Then, there is no choice but testing for a wall on the first possible wall, then the second possible, until we find one.&lt;br/&gt;It's only a trigonometrical problem to determine which wall are to be tested.&lt;br/&gt;And as we have 2 kind of walls, we have to test both of kinds, and then keep only the nearer.&lt;br/&gt;One of the limit in excel is that condition loop does not exist, and the loop body can only be skipped to save time. So we should cut the maximum checking distance, assuming there is no wall at all if not found until then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Floor and Ceiling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To represent floor and ceiling, we just have to find where wall does stop.&lt;br/&gt;A dedicated sheet mesure the distance of the floor or ceiling depending of the vertical angle.&lt;br/&gt;Then, for each pixel, we decide if the wall is further or not than the ceiling of the floor, and decide the pixel color accordingly.&lt;br/&gt;The comparison is made efficiently by using only the projection of the distance of both wall and ceiling/floor on the camera axis. The final distance is then obtained using the pre-calculated distance factor in the distance shader. The fixed pre-calculated is mean to save resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Illumination&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final light is obtained from a light shader representing a torch light, in the direction of the camera (and weapon sight).&lt;br/&gt;Some reflection is also added, when a surface is exactly horizontal to the light ray.&lt;br/&gt;Only wall can be horizontal (if a pitch is added, it would only displace the screen pane up and down, not turning the camera)&lt;br/&gt;For each angle of the radar, we get the angle between the ray and the nearest found wall.&lt;br/&gt;Then, the reflection factor is a basic function of this angle.&lt;br/&gt;In the end, the light is the product of a factor function of the distance, the ceiling/floor or wall resolution, the reflection factor, and the light shader factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Display&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effective display is made from conditional formatting - gradient of color based on the value of the cell.&lt;br/&gt;Hiding the value is achieved by cell formatting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The player is not supposed to move through wall, or it would defeat the idea of a maze.&lt;br/&gt;Wall would not either stuck the player as he reach them. The movement should slip unless he reach a corner.&lt;br/&gt;In addition, a minimum distance should be kept from the player to avoid graphical issues, and make wall have some width.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appeared to be particularly tricky to manage all the possible cases of wall, and positions of the player compared to this wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2^5 possibilities were studied, and the 3 potentials outcome (for each displacement axis) where mapped to get the result within fewer possible tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While appearing one of the smaller, the displacement tab was one of the most complex to realize. (10 times more than the map, twice as much as the wall detection)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reho.st/view/self/39e896009b375a3aa97c175c2bd9f04d4039b2a3.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Oh, hi, Mr Red Ghost !&quot; src=&quot;https://reho.st/preview/self/39e896009b375a3aa97c175c2bd9f04d4039b2a3.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The bad guy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Graphical rendering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge for enemies was to obtain a shape that could be easily added before wall, easily rendered at any distance, and who would be more interesting than a simple cube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A complete tab is dedicated to calculation of the shape of spheres, considering the horizontal radius, and vertical height of the ovoid. The height/width ratio is used to animate the creature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wall and ceiling rendering only used the gradient on 1 color, while excel allow 2 successive (not merged) gradient. Then, the enemies can be displayed in an other color. The value range bellow 0 can be used for this gradient, the value 0 being black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The progressive transparency appeared to be not harder than the smooth rendering of a sphere surface. The ray is getting the thickness of the sphere, the thicker making the pixel more colored.&lt;br/&gt;On the border of the sphere, the low thickness is only keeping the default value of the wall behind, with a negative factor to turn it on the color of monster. The light color filter providing a transparency on the border of the sphere.&lt;br/&gt;Once again, calculation are made on the horizontal plane, and the maximum calculations are prepared before finalizing the 3d calculation for each pixel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enemies behavior&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid a complex and unsatisfying procedural behavior, enemies does not react to the player action. Their position is determined only by the time, on a complex trajectory designed to provide no explicit pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep the position, speed, and all acceleration continuous (so the movement is fluid), the trajectory is a sort of finite fractal of a big circle, and small circular variations added on it. Ratio factor between circle (and even x/y ratio) are random an non-natural, so the trajectory never loop on itself. A separate sheet was made to display the trajectory to achieve a good random generator of deterministic trajectories.&lt;br/&gt;Since the trajectories cannot take account of walls, the ability of monster to go through walls is forced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several trajectories are then computed at each instant. The entire maze is populated by the same 10 enemies repeated on a grid with a sufficient distance so the player cannot see 2 instances of the same enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The repetition grid can be zoom in/zoom out to decrease/increase the enemy density. This should be made while taking great care of excessive resulting displacement of the monster, and effective speed due to scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we have a limited number of enemies to manage, these being copied everywhere in the maze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enemies attacks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The animation of the enemies is made using the radius/height ratio. Since the attack of the enemy should be clearly visible, and yet, slow enough for the player to be able to react, enemies simply increase in radius wether they have the player in sight. The grow follow an exponential function to simulate an explosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light of sight is calculated for each enemy in the radar tab, considering walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, the player simply get damage if it turn to be inside the radius of an enemy. It works the same is the player goes on purpose inside the enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This make the damage effect on the player a simple effect of negative color on the entire screen.&lt;br/&gt;An other effect is to cancel the rendering of any other enemy when the player get damaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The life of the player is one of the element of its status, which managed though steps like its position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Player attacks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each enemy get a status value, defining either its remaining life and attacking phase. For some values, enemies are simply not displayed, for some other, the enemy slowly regenerate, and the last one make the enemy explode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This simplified model allow the player to prevent attack by decreasing the life of the enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase the challenge, the player will have difficulties to aim a small enemy by staying at long range, and the ammunition will require reload action after a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On kill, the enemy simply turn into a slow regeneration state of inactivity. Since there are few enemies repeated everywhere, there cannot be a definitive elimination of one of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Death and rebi.. restart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the life of the player goes bellow 0, most of its actions are frozen, and the game-over screen appear.&lt;br/&gt;This screen is rendered using an other light shader, and a negative effect is made on color to keep with the idea of damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The progressive display of the &quot;game over&quot; message is achieved with small factor, which are elevated with an exponential function. This allow future pixels to stay hidden before appearing once the exponent is big enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, the slide down is a simple displacement of the light shader, which include some other message, like high score and restart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The score have to be written using pixels, with a very low resolution font.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restart generate new starting parameter, and send the player elsewhere at an other instant to avoid the player to meet the same enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 17:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>samfisher83</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/CBel/20180213/308549/3D_engine_entirely_made_of_MS_Excel_formulae__Enjoy_this_Doomxls_file_.php</og:url>
<og:title>3D engine entirely made of MS Excel formulae : Enjoy this Doom.xls file !</og:title>
<og:description>A 3D engine on MS Excel, using only excel formula. This engine is applied on a complete - yet basic - doom-like game. Rendering is made through ray casting, pixel per pixel. The exercice intend to demonstrate what can be done with formula only.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/CBel/20180213/308549/3D_engine_entirely_made_of_MS_Excel_formulae__Enjoy_this_Doomxls_file_.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Little Typer</title>
<link>https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-typer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-typer</guid>
<description>&lt;div tabindex=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;30.889364739472&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;l-tabs--left&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;tab-content__title&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An introduction to dependent types, demonstrating the most beautiful aspects, one step at a time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A program's type describes its behavior. Dependent types are a first-class part of a language, and are much more powerful than other kinds of types; using just one language for types and programs allows program descriptions to be as powerful as the programs they describe. &lt;em&gt;The Little Typer&lt;/em&gt; explains dependent types, beginning with a very small language that looks very much like Scheme and extending it to cover both programming with dependent types and using dependent types for mathematical reasoning. Readers should be familiar with the basics of a Lisp-like programming language, as presented in the first four chapters of &lt;em&gt;The Little Schemer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first five chapters of &lt;em&gt;The Little Typer&lt;/em&gt; provide the needed tools to understand dependent types; the remaining chapters use these tools to build a bridge between mathematics and programming. Readers will learn that tools they know from programming—pairs, lists, functions, and recursion—can also capture patterns of reasoning. &lt;em&gt;The Little Typer&lt;/em&gt; does not attempt to teach either practical programming skills or a fully rigorous approach to types. Instead, it demonstrates the most beautiful aspects as simply as possible, one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;l-tabs--right&quot; readability=&quot;6.6534653465347&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;tab-content__rail-title&quot;&gt;Paperback&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span property=&quot;price&quot;&gt;$38.00 S&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;ISBN: &lt;span property=&quot;isbn&quot;&gt;9780262536431&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span property=&quot;numPages&quot;&gt;424&lt;/span&gt; pp. | 9 in x 7 in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;23 b&amp;amp;w illus.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;time property=&quot;publishDate&quot; content=&quot;2018-09-18&quot;&gt;September 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div tabindex=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;36.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;l-tabs--left&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;tab-content__title--small&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;tab-content__title&quot;&gt;Daniel P. Friedman&lt;/h4&gt;
Daniel P. Friedman is Professor of Computer Science in the School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering at Indiana University and is the author of many books published by the MIT Press, including &lt;em&gt;The Little Schemer&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Seasoned Schemer&lt;/em&gt; (with Matthias Felleisen); &lt;em&gt;The Little Prover&lt;/em&gt; (with Carl Eastlund); and &lt;em&gt;The Reasoned Schemer&lt;/em&gt; (with William E. Byrd, Oleg Kiselyov, and Jason Hemann).
&lt;h4 class=&quot;tab-content__title&quot;&gt;David Thrane Christiansen&lt;/h4&gt;
David Thrane Christiansen is a member of the technical staff at Galois, Inc., in Portland, Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tab-content__section tab-content__section__contributors&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;tab-content__title--small&quot;&gt;Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Harper and Conor McBride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 16:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kakashi19</dc:creator>
<og:type>books.book</og:type>
<og:url>https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-typer</og:url>
<og:title>The Little Typer</og:title>
<og:description>An introduction to dependent types, demonstrating the most beautiful aspects, one step at a time. A program's type describes its behavior. Dependent types are a first-class part of a language, and are much more powerful than other kinds of types; using just one language for types and programs allows program descriptions to be as powerful as the programs they describe. The Little Typer explains dependent types, beginning with a very small language that looks very much like Scheme and extending it to cover both programming with dependent types and using dependent types for mathematical reasoning. Readers should be familiar with the basics of a Lisp-like programming language, as presented in the first four chapters of The Little Schemer. The first five chapters of The Little Typer provide the needed tools to understand dependent types; the remaining chapters use these tools to build a bridge between mathematics and programming. Readers will learn that tools they know from programming—pairs, lists, functions, and recursion—can also capture patterns of reasoning. The Little Typer does not attempt to teach either practical programming skills or a fully rigorous approach to types. Instead, it demonstrates the most beautiful aspects as simply as possible, one step at a time.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-typer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hayabusa2 Now</title>
<link>http://haya2now.jp/en.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://haya2now.jp/en.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;box&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dist&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;The distance between the Earth and Hayabusa2, and Hayabusa2 and Ryugu. As the Earth approaches and leaves Hayabusa2 and Ryugu, the distance ratio will continue to change.&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RYUGU&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAYA BUSA2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EARTH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;haya2-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;haya2-svg&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;High Gain Antenna (HGA) enabling high speed communication. During use the antenna will blink.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://haya2now.jp/images/haya2.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-tooltip=&quot;Current power consumption. Hayabusa2's main electric power source is from the large solar panels.&quot;&gt;Bus power consumption:&lt;span class=&quot;bus-p&quot;&gt;-W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;box&quot; id=&quot;mga&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;col u-mt&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elevation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box&quot; id=&quot;transmitter&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XTRP1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XTRP2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transmitter power amplifier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transmission mode&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transmission bitrate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecting antenna&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box&quot; id=&quot;receiver&quot;&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th/&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;active&quot; id=&quot;re_1&quot;&gt;RX1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;re_2&quot;&gt;RX2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Receiving level&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;re_1_level&quot;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;re_2_level&quot;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bitrate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;re_1_brate&quot;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;re_2_brate&quot;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Connecting antenna&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;active&quot; id=&quot;re_1_ant&quot;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;re_2_ant&quot;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box&quot; id=&quot;thruster&quot;&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;thruster&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;TH01&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TH02&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;TH03&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TH04&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;TH05&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TH06&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;TH07&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TH08&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;TH09&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TH10&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;TH11&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TH12&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 15:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MKais</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://haya2now.jp/en.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SpaceX&amp;#039;s rise can be traced to a critical launch from a Pacific isle</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/09/inside-the-eight-desperate-weeks-that-saved-spacex-from-ruin/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/09/inside-the-eight-desperate-weeks-that-saved-spacex-from-ruin/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Falcon-1-800x532.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Article intro image&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Falcon-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;866&quot; data-width=&quot;1302&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; The Falcon 1 rocket ascends toward space on its fourth flight.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a aria-describedby=&quot;67 posters participating, including story author.&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/09/inside-the-eight-desperate-weeks-that-saved-spacex-from-ruin/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;117&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;They bunked in a double-wide trailer, cramming inside on cots and sleeping bags, as many as a dozen at a time. In the mornings, they feasted on steaming plates of scrambled eggs. At night, beneath some of the darkest skies on Earth, they grilled steaks and wondered if the heavens above were beyond their reach. Kids, most of them, existed alone on a tiny speck of an island in the middle of the Pacific Ocean. It was the middle of nowhere, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they worked. They worked desperately—tinkering, testing, and fixing—hoping that nothing would go wrong this time. Already, their small rocket had failed three times. One more launch anomaly likely meant the end of Space Exploration Technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three times, in 2006, 2007, and 2008, SpaceX tried to launch a Falcon 1 rocket from Omelek Island in the Pacific Ocean, a coral shelf perhaps a meter above sea level and the size of three soccer fields. Less than two months after the last failure, the money was running out. SpaceX had just one final rocket to launch, with only some spare components left over in its California factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We all knew that the stakes were incredibly high,” Zach Dunn recalled of that feverish period in 2008. This time, the Falcon 1 had to work. And the kids knew it. Barely a year out of graduate school and just 26, Dunn nonetheless was a senior engineer over the rocket’s first stage. “It was tense. There was a lot of pressure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, it is difficult to imagine the world of aerospace without SpaceX. United Launch Alliance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/05/ariane-chief-seems-frustrated-with-spacex-for-driving-down-launch-costs/&quot;&gt;Arianespace&lt;/a&gt;, the Russians, and the Chinese likely would still dominate the launch industry, with their prices a closely guarded secret. A decade ago, these industry titans saw in Elon Musk just another gnat to be swatted aside like so many who had come before. The idea of reusing an orbital rocket to lower the cost of access to space? Laughable. &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/science/2016/09/musks-mars-moment-audacity-madness-brilliance-or-maybe-all-three/&quot;&gt;Mars&lt;/a&gt;?!? This funny sounding guy from South Africa couldn't even put a small, single-engine rocket into orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;This, and more, lay on the line September 28, 2008, when SpaceX sought to finally become the first company to privately develop a rocket that successfully reached orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That's something that only nations had done before, because the barriers to entry were so high,” Chad Anderson, of the Space Angels investment group, said about privately developing an orbital rocket. “Going from zero to one is really, really difficult. And that’s what SpaceX did. That guy and that company have been swimming upstream, and fighting, for so long to get that ball rolling.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten years later, the industry has undergone &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/07/as-the-spacex-steamroller-surges-european-rocket-industry-vows-to-resist/&quot;&gt;a radical restructuring&lt;/a&gt;. The titans of aerospace have scrambled to remake themselves, or die, in the new world where Musk is not a pretender but the leading protagonist. Following in SpaceX’s wake, more than 100 private companies around the world are trying to accomplish the same feat with rockets of various sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no question who blazed the trail or that it began deep in the Pacific tropics. A few days before the fourth and possibly final attempt to launch the Falcon 1 rocket, Dunn left Omelek by boat, making the trip to “the Kwaj,” or Kwajalein Island. This nearby island was tiny, too, measuring about 4km long and several hundred meters across. But it was a continent compared to Omelek and home to SpaceX's launch control center.&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Zach-F1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot; data-height=&quot;2848&quot; data-width=&quot;4288&quot; alt=&quot;Zach Dunn with the Merlin engine that powered the successful fourth flight of the Falcon 1 rocket.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Zach-F1-980x651.jpg&quot; width=&quot;980&quot; height=&quot;651&quot; alt=&quot;Zach Dunn with the Merlin engine that powered the successful fourth flight of the Falcon 1 rocket.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Zach-F1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;2848&quot; data-width=&quot;4288&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; Zach Dunn with the Merlin engine that powered the successful fourth flight of the Falcon 1 rocket.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the morning of the launch, Dunn sat on console in a bunker on the Kwaj, monitoring the health of the Merlin-1 engine and the fuel tanks in the first stage. As the rocket took off, he watched, hoping it wouldn’t blow up. Cheers erupted inside the bunker about three minutes into the flight, when the second stage separated from the rocket. Then came an agonizing six minutes when the Falcon’s upper stage engine, named Kestrel, would have to burn, necessary to show potential customers the rocket could put their satellites into a proper orbit. And burn it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When Kestrel shut down, the place just exploded,” Dunn recalled of the bunker. “We went absolutely wild. We were all jumping around. Hugging each other. Screaming. It was a righteous celebration.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The party in the Pacific would last all night. The next day, SpaceX would begin anew in its efforts to conquer the aerospace world. This time, it would not fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hans Koenigsmann joined SpaceX as employee number four. He came to SpaceX in 2002 from another aerospace firm in Southern California, Microcosm. (SpaceX’s dynamic president and chief operating officer, Gwynne Shotwell, would follow him from the same company a couple of months later.) Soon, Koenigsmann began to work on an avionics system for a rocket, the brains that controlled it during flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a mandate from Musk to slash costs, Koenigsmann had to decide what to buy and what to build in-house, and he had to hire a team of engineers. In leaving an established company, the German-born Koenigsmann had taken a big risk, leaving a comfortable job for a completely untested venture whose founder was already &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/science/2016/09/musks-mars-moment-audacity-madness-brilliance-or-maybe-all-three/&quot;&gt;talking about Mars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Koenigsmann did not join SpaceX because he believed in that mission. “I just wanted to develop a rocket with a small team, and not 15,000 people like had been done in the past,” he said. “I wanted to show you could do this with 200.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, SpaceX wanted to launch from Vandenberg Air Force Base, located a couple hours' drive north of its Southern California headquarters. But the big rocket companies, Boeing and Lockheed Martin among them, used that facility for the launch of their rockets, and the military and its contractors were less than welcoming to the upstart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So eventually, SpaceX looked west. Far to the west, to an Army base 8,000km away surrounded by vast expanses of blue ocean. Here, there was no other traffic on the range. When SpaceX needed priority, it generally got it. “We weren’t in the shadows of other, bigger companies, so that helped us,” Koenigsmann said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even today, he can recall the route to Kwaj from Los Angeles. Take an afternoon or evening flight from LAX to Hawaii. Spend the night there and catch the 7am flight to the Marshall Islands from Gate 14. It made several stops along this once-a-day route, and one of them was the Kwaj.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once there, SpaceX employees mostly rode bicycles around the island, with its sand, surf, and palm trees. When not spending the night on Omelek, they stayed in Kwajalein’s hotel, called Macy’s—which had nothing to do with the department store. “It sounds a little bit like a tropical island, but it’s an Army version of a tropical island,” Koenigsmann said. “So the hotel was the Army version of a hotel. Every piece of furniture had a United States government number.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Hans-Falcon-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot; data-height=&quot;1378&quot; data-width=&quot;2172&quot; alt=&quot;Hans Koenigsmann with his family, and the Falcon 1 rocket, at Omelek.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Hans-Falcon-1-980x622.jpg&quot; width=&quot;980&quot; height=&quot;622&quot; alt=&quot;Hans Koenigsmann with his family, and the Falcon 1 rocket, at Omelek.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Hans-Falcon-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;1378&quot; data-width=&quot;2172&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; Hans Koenigsmann with his family, and the Falcon 1 rocket, at Omelek.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took an hour by boat to reach Omelek Island, where SpaceX built its own launch pad and a hangar for its Falcon 1 rocket. Typically, a rocket would arrive three or four months before its flight and require a lengthy series of processing and tests before launch day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s pretty unique, and people either liked it or hated it; no one was really neutral,” Koenigsmann said of the spare island life in the Pacific. As for the German, truly half a world away from his home, he liked it there beneath the dark Pacific skies. The island reminded him of why he had come there in the first place. “It gave me a real sense of remoteness and how big this planet really is,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it also taught him how damned hard it is to break out of Earth’s gravity well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 14:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tomte</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/09/inside-the-eight-desperate-weeks-that-saved-spacex-from-ruin/</og:url>
<og:title>Inside the eight desperate weeks that saved SpaceX from ruin</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Falcon-1-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The company's meteoric rise can be traced to a critical launch from a Pacific isle.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/09/inside-the-eight-desperate-weeks-that-saved-spacex-from-ruin/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Programming Language Underdog</title>
<link>https://totallywearingpants.com/posts/nim-underdog/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://totallywearingpants.com/posts/nim-underdog/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As devs in late 2018, we’ve got lots of programming language choices. Mainstream ones alone, there’s about a dozen or so of them. They’re all awesome. As you wander a bit further down the obscurity path, you’ll find languages like &lt;a href=&quot;https://elm-lang.org&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;elm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://elixir-lang.org&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;elixir&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purescript.org&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;purescript&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://reasonml.github.io&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;reason&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. And just past those, you’ll find &lt;a href=&quot;https://nim-lang.org&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out about &lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt; by accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vurtun/nuklear&quot;&gt;library for ui development&lt;/a&gt; and it said, “We also have bindings for &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;rust&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt; and others.” Cool… wait. What the hell is &lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt;? Out of curiosity, I gave it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of throw-away examples. A rewrite of an old project. A few new prototypes of incredibly cringey ideas. You know, mostly trying to get a sense of where the edges are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 months later, this language has still got me captivated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-a-speed-run&quot;&gt;First, A Speed Run&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://totallywearingpants.com/images/nim-underdog/underdog-shoeshine.jpg&quot; class=&quot;wrappable&quot;/&gt; We’re going to make a small CLI app so we have something to talk about for the rest of this article. So let’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://nim-lang.org/install.html&quot;&gt;install &lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and get a feel for the toolchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by &lt;code&gt;mkdir fun&lt;/code&gt;, then &lt;code&gt;cd fun&lt;/code&gt;, and create a text file called &lt;code&gt;wave.nim&lt;/code&gt; with this nonsense:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-nim&quot; data-lang=&quot;nim&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;# this is wave.nim&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; hand&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;👋&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create another file called &lt;code&gt;hello.nim&lt;/code&gt; and paste this in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-nim&quot; data-lang=&quot;nim&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;# this is hello.nim&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; wave

echo &lt;span&gt;&quot;Hello World &quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; hand&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/303&quot;&gt;compile&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-sh&quot; data-lang=&quot;sh&quot;&gt;$ nim c hello.nim&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About &lt;code&gt;175 ms&lt;/code&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://consumer.huawei.com/ca/tablets/matebook-x-pro/specs&quot;&gt;my laptop&lt;/a&gt; running &lt;a href=&quot;http://releases.ubuntu.com/18.04&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;. Let’s run it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-sh&quot; data-lang=&quot;sh&quot;&gt;$ ./hello
Hello World 👋&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a binary that is &lt;strong&gt;fast&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;code&gt;2 ms&lt;/code&gt;), &lt;strong&gt;small&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;code&gt;107 kB&lt;/code&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;dependency-free&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-crafty-and-capable-compiler&quot;&gt;A Crafty and Capable Compiler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://totallywearingpants.com/images/nim-underdog/underdog.png&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;wrappable&quot;/&gt; We fed the compiler the entry point (&lt;code&gt;hello.nim&lt;/code&gt;) and it found its dependencies (&lt;code&gt;wave.nim&lt;/code&gt;) by examining the code. If we were to drop a 3rd file in there, well, it wouldn’t have included it if we didn’t use an &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t give it a &lt;code&gt;main()&lt;/code&gt; function, and it just made an executable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that’s not the only option. Run &lt;code&gt;nim c --app:lib wave.nim&lt;/code&gt; and we just made a dynamic library. Run &lt;code&gt;nim c --app:staticLib wave.nim&lt;/code&gt; and now it’s a static library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows, macOS, Linux are supported, as are a few other platforms like Raspberry Pi and Nintendo Switch! With the right setup, cross-compilation can be a thing, but the story is nowhere near what &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; can do. Honestly, nothing I’ve seen touches &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; in the build arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-similar-c-program-is-only-8-5-kb&quot;&gt;A similar &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; program is only &lt;code&gt;8.5 kB&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt; bakes in a bunch of functions and constants including file I/O and a configurable &lt;a href=&quot;https://nim-lang.org/docs/gc.html&quot;&gt;garbage collector&lt;/a&gt; which adds overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ain’t your grandfather’s garbage collector. You can pick the algorithm (6 choices) and the time budget per activation. And it doesn’t run “whenever” like most do. You can even turn it off if you live in YOLOville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, we compiled in &lt;strong&gt;debug&lt;/strong&gt; mode, lol. In debug mode you get fancy stack traces and other things to help you, well, debug. Try compiling with &lt;code&gt;nim c -d:release hello.nim&lt;/code&gt;. Down to &lt;code&gt;89 kB&lt;/code&gt;. Better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With another compiler flag, you can optimize for size instead of speed. &lt;code&gt;nim c -d:release --opt:size hello.nim&lt;/code&gt; and now we’re &lt;code&gt;44 kB&lt;/code&gt;. Better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-the-c-compiler-is-faster&quot;&gt;But the &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; compiler is faster!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ya, that’s true because &lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;compiles to c&lt;/strong&gt;! Then it compiles to a binary by using &lt;code&gt;gcc&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;clang&lt;/code&gt; (for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember when we typed &lt;code&gt;nim c hello.nim&lt;/code&gt; to compile? The &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; stands for &lt;strong&gt;compile to c&lt;/strong&gt; and it’s the default backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It can compile to &lt;code&gt;c++&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;obj-c&lt;/code&gt; too&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we can use the tools of the backend’s ecosystem (like code coverage and debuggers). Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-good-language-interop&quot;&gt;So good language interop?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You bet. That’s one of the strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use libs like &lt;code&gt;imgui&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;SDL&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;redis&lt;/code&gt;, you name it. Use static libraries or link to dynamic ones like &lt;code&gt;openssl&lt;/code&gt;. There are language features to deal with name-mangling, namespacing, linking, and more. Hell, you can even type &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; code in a string within &lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt; and the compiler will do the right thing. There’s also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nim-lang/c2nim&quot;&gt;c2nim&lt;/a&gt; tool for helping you automate wrappers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-cross-platform-cross-language-that-s-crazy&quot;&gt;So Cross Platform / Cross Language? That’s crazy!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, that’s awesome! Crazy would be compiling to JavaScript. 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-sh&quot; data-lang=&quot;sh&quot;&gt;$ nim js -d:release hello.nim
$ node nimcache/hello.js
Hello World 👋&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh 💩, it compiles to JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://totallywearingpants.com/images/nim-underdog/underdog-villain.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;wrappable&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-haven-t-i-heard-of-nim-before&quot;&gt;Why Haven’t I Heard Of &lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt; Before?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://totallywearingpants.com/images/nim-underdog/underdog-bonk.jpg&quot; class=&quot;wrappable&quot;/&gt; Here’s one reason:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Language&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Funded By&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;rust&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mozilla&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;swift&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apple&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Google&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;typescript&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Microsoft&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;kotlin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jetbrains&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_________&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The correct answer, of course, is &lt;span&gt;🤷&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With big funding comes big reach and big communities. Although &lt;code&gt;nim&lt;/code&gt; hasn’t had that kind of sponsorship, it looks to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://nim-lang.org/sponsors.html&quot;&gt;heating up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I find amazing is that despite the grassroots nature of this project, it has features that run alongside the current mainstream leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;learn-more&quot;&gt;Learn More&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a big ol’ stack of URLs to get going. I’ve also heard Google is a pretty good world wide web site too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a fun start, but there is so much more. I’ll get to work on some more articles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 09:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dom96</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://totallywearingpants.com/posts/nim-underdog/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>John Dvorak: “Yesterday I was fired from PC Magazine”</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/THErealDVORAK/status/1043180806020116480</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/THErealDVORAK/status/1043180806020116480</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/THErealDVORAK/status/1043180806020116480&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/THErealDVORAK/status/1043180806020116480&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18044106&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18044106&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 169&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 02:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>leothekim</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/THErealDVORAK/status/1043180806020116480</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Fed stalls the creation of a bank with a novel business model</title>
<link>https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2018/09/22/the-fed-stalls-the-creation-of-a-bank-with-a-novel-business-model</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2018/09/22/the-fed-stalls-the-creation-of-a-bank-with-a-novel-business-model</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post__asideable-content blog-post__asideable-content--meta&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog-post__section&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleSection&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Print edition | Finance and economics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;blog-post__datetime&quot; itemprop=&quot;dateCreated&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-09-20T14:46:24Z&quot;&gt;Sep 20th 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blog-post__location-created&quot;&gt;| NEW YORK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div itemprop=&quot;description&quot; readability=&quot;95&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TEN years on from the financial crisis, the structure of American banking has not changed. At its core are government-guaranteed, and therefore cheap, deposits that banks put to work, primarily through lending. Deposits have become more important for bank funding in recent years; governments have become increasingly fussy about how the money is lent out. The basic set-up is so entrenched that many believe there is no alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A startup called TNB, short for The Narrow Bank, is questioning that assumption, and causing a stir as a result. On August 31st TNB filed a complaint in federal court against the New York Fed, which, it alleges, is breaking the law by refusing to grant it access to the central bank’s payment system. The Fed has made no comment, but in response to growing pressure, it has acknowledged the complaint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form newsletter-form--inline&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form__message&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get our daily newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrade your inbox and get our Daily Dispatch and Editor's Picks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__container latest-updates-panel__container--blog-post&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__body&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Are Emirates and Etihad about to merge?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-1.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Surprisingly, Congo’s election may take place in December&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Democrats turn to female candidates in 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Theresa May faces the nation after her Salzburg humiliation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;“Museo” revisits Mexico’s notorious museum robbery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;EU leaders are united on Brexit but divided on migration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case throws light on an unusual business model. Led by a former head of research at the New York Fed, TNB is based on the idea of a narrow bank, which was first suggested by professors at the University of Chicago as a response to the banking crisis of the 1930s. The proponents of the “Chicago plan” argued that deposits and lending need not be linked. A bank could have a narrow mandate, restricting itself to merely receiving deposits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court filing suggests that TNB planned to do just that, taking deposits from financial institutions (though not from consumers) and redepositing them at the Fed in order to take advantage of the Fed’s interest rate on reserves, which is 1.95%. There would be no need for branches or credit analysts. Compliance costs would be minimal: as the bank would not make loans, regulators would need only an audit to show the bank’s funds on account at the Fed covered its clients’ deposits. To keep costs lower still, TNB intends to avoid having deposit insurance, which can cost up to 0.4% of assets. As the money is invested with the central bank, it is already guaranteed by the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most American banks pay measly rates of interest of under 0.1%, according to Bankrate.com, a data provider. With its austere model, TNB could plausibly provide a competitive rate on deposits, while keeping some of the spread between the Fed rate and the interest it pays to customers. The operating model is not without risks. The Fed could cease paying interest to banks, for example, a demand that both America’s political parties have made at times. But TNB, or a similarly minded institution, could tweak the model in response and invest its deposits in government securities instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fed’s silence has drawn criticism. TNB has received a temporary banking charter from Connecticut, so the state regulator clearly deems it to be legal. The central bank may worry that narrow banks, which lend to neither companies nor individuals, could hamper the effectiveness of monetary policy. Their business model may also risk unsettling incumbent banks, which could have large economic consequences. TNB’s suit says that the Fed’s actions “have the effect of discriminating against small, innovative companies” and “privileging established, too-big-to-fail institutions”. The Fed may eventually be forced to explain why that is a virtue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 02:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>known</dc:creator>
<og:description>The Narrow Bank would take deposits but not make loans</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20180922_FND001_0.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2018/09/22/the-fed-stalls-the-creation-of-a-bank-with-a-novel-business-model</og:url>
<og:title>The Fed stalls the creation of a bank with a novel business model</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2018/09/22/the-fed-stalls-the-creation-of-a-bank-with-a-novel-business-model</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AI Company Accused of Using Humans to Fake Its AI</title>
<link>https://www.sixthtone.com/news/1002956/ai-company-accused-of-using-humans-to-fake-its-ai-</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sixthtone.com/news/1002956/ai-company-accused-of-using-humans-to-fake-its-ai-</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sixthtone.com/news/1002943/will-an-ai-revolution-help-or-hurt-chinas-labor-market%3F&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;common fear&lt;/a&gt; that artificial intelligence could steal our jobs, but in the case of one of China’s leading voice recognition companies, it might be more of a case of humans taking work from AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, iFlytek was hit with accusations that it hired humans to fake its simultaneous interpretation tools, which are supposedly powered by AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/45010541&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; posted on Quora-like Q&amp;amp;A platform Zhihu, interpreter Bell Wang claimed he was one of a team of simultaneous interpreters who helped translate the 2018 International Forum on Innovation and Emerging Industries Development on Thursday. The forum claimed to use iFlytek’s automated interpretation service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While a Japanese professor spoke in English at the conference on Thursday morning, a screen behind him showed both an English transcription of what he was saying, and what appeared to be a simultaneous translation into Chinese which was credited to iFlytek. Wang claims that the Chinese wasn’t a simultaneous translation, but was instead a transcription of an interpretation by himself and a fellow interpreter. “I was deeply disgusted,” Wang wrote in the letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the open letter, Wang pointed to two examples to support his claim. First, iFlytek’s tool appeared to struggle with the Japanese professor’s English accent, rendering “Davos Forum” as “Devil’s Forum.” Despite the transcription error, the Chinese translation came out correct — just as it had in Wang’s partner’s translation. Second, the majority of the Chinese translation was the same as what Wang and his partner had interpreted, including a tricky conjunction which Wang believes would have been translated literally had it really been translated by AI. Despite his concerns, Wang said that he didn’t confront the forum organizer or iFlytek staff at the forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://weibo.com/u/1866704484?is_hot=1#1537521662374&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a post on Friday&lt;/a&gt; on social media platform Weibo, iFlytek’s CEO Hu Yu said the tool used in the conference was a transcribing tool — not a translation tool. Earlier, financial news outlet Securities Times &lt;a href=&quot;https://tech.sina.com.cn/it/2018-09-21/doc-ihkhfqnt4674859.shtml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that in response to the letter, iFlytek had directed media to remarks that the company’s president Liu Qingfeng made on Monday, when he said: “Currently machines still cannot replace interpreters. Frankly, a combination of human and machine is where we’re headed.” When contacted by Sixth Tone on Friday, iFlytek’s public relations officer denied that Liu’s words constituted an official response and said that the company is currently investigating the accusation. Sixth Tone also reached out to the forum organizers, but received no response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://zb.ckcest.cn/PCweb/pages/IEID/IEID_Play.html?id=12&amp;amp;oid=&amp;amp;topicId=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video of the forum&lt;/a&gt;, an artificial voice read out Wang and his partner’s interpretation, according to Wang. Wang believes that iFlytek must have transcribed the interpreting they had done in the morning and used a robot to read it, just to prove their AI worked. “This is obviously a scam,” Wang wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The livestream of the event was no longer available by Friday afternoon. Wang had not responded to Sixth Tone’s interview request by time of publication. Following the open letter, other interpreters &lt;a href=&quot;https://weibo.com/1904534105/GAkFXEwOS?from=page_1005051904534105_profile&amp;amp;wvr=6&amp;amp;mod=weibotime&amp;amp;type=comment&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;came forward&lt;/a&gt;, claiming that they had been offered work interpreting on iFlytek’s behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twoeggz.com/news/2190390.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;not the first time&lt;/a&gt; iFlytek has been accused of disguising works done by flesh-and-blood interpreters as the work of their AI-powered product. Last year, another simultaneous interpreter accused iFlytek of hiding their existence from the keynote speakers while providing interpretation services that appeared to come from the AI product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Additional reporting: Liya Fan; Editor: Julia Hollingsworth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Header image: A Japanese professor gives a speech on IFLYT’s AI tech in Shanghai, Sept. 20, 2018. @bellwang fro Zhihu)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 01:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ytch</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>AI Company Accused of Using Humans to Fake Its AI</og:title>
<og:image>http://image5.sixthtone.com/image/5/13/443.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Interpreter accuses leading voice recognition company of ripping off his work and disguising it as the efforts of artificial intelligence.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.sixthtone.com/news/1002956/ai-company-accused-of-using-humans-to-fake-its-ai-</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sixthtone.com/news/1002956/ai-company-accused-of-using-humans-to-fake-its-ai-</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>