<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Modifications to Google Chromium for removing Google integration</title>
<link>https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bringing back the &quot;Don't&quot; in &quot;Don't be evil&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ungoogled-chromium is Google Chromium&lt;/strong&gt;, sans integration with Google. It also features some changes to enhance privacy, control, and transparency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Motivation and Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of features or background services communicate with Google servers despite the absence of an associated Google account or compiled-in Google API keys. Furthermore, the normal build process for Chromium involves running Google's own high-level commands that invoke many scripts and utilities, some of which download and use pre-built binaries provided by Google. Even the final build output includes some pre-built binaries. Fortunately, the source code is available for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ungoogled-chromium is a set of configuration flags, patches, and custom scripts. These components altogether strive to accomplish the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Disable or remove offending services and features that communicate with Google or weaken privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strip binaries from the source tree, and use those provided by the system or build them from source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable features that inhibit control and transparency, and add or modify features that promote them (these changes are minor and do not have significant impacts on the general user experience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ungoogled-chromium should not be considered a fork of Chromium&lt;/strong&gt;. The main reason for this is that a fork is associated with more significant deviations from the Chromium, such as branding, configuration formats, file locations, and other interface changes. ungoogled-chromium will not modify the Chromium browser outside of the project's goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these goals and requirements are not precise, unclear situations are discussed and decided on a case-by-case basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ungoogled-chromium is looking for contributors&lt;/strong&gt;. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium#contributing-reporting-contacting&quot;&gt;Contributing, Reporting, Contacting&lt;/a&gt; section for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of ungoogled-chromium's changes are subtle and evolve over time. As a result, it is best to consult the source code for complete and up-to-date information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ungoogled-chromium selectively borrows many of its features from the following (in no particular order):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the &lt;strong&gt;additional&lt;/strong&gt; features are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Replace many web domains in the source code with non-existent alternatives ending in &lt;code&gt;qjz9zk&lt;/code&gt; (known as domain substitution; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium/blob/master/docs/design.md#source-file-processors&quot;&gt;see docs/design.md&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strip binaries from the source code (known as binary pruning; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium/blob/master/docs/design.md#source-file-processors&quot;&gt;see docs/design.md&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable functionality specific to Google domains (e.g. Google Host Detector, Google URL Tracker, Google Cloud Messaging, Google Hotwording, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Omnibox search provider &quot;No Search&quot; to allow disabling of searching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable automatic formatting of URLs in Omnibox (e.g. stripping &lt;code&gt;http://&lt;/code&gt;, hiding certain parameters)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added menu item under &quot;More tools&quot; to clear the HTTP authentication cache on-demand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new command-line switches and &lt;code&gt;chrome://flags&lt;/code&gt; entries:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--disable-beforeunload&lt;/code&gt; - (Not in &lt;code&gt;chrome://flags&lt;/code&gt;) Disables JavaScript dialog boxes triggered by &lt;code&gt;beforeunload&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--disable-search-engine-collection&lt;/code&gt; - Disable automatic search engine scraping from webpages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--enable-stacked-tab-strip&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--enable-tab-adjust-layout&lt;/code&gt; - These flags adjust the tab strip behavior. &lt;code&gt;--enable-stacked-tab-strip&lt;/code&gt; is also configurable in &lt;code&gt;chrome://flags&lt;/code&gt; Please note that they are not well tested, so proceed with caution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--extension-mime-request-handling&lt;/code&gt; - Change how extension MIME types (CRX and user scripts) are handled. Acceptable values are &lt;code&gt;download-as-regular-file&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;install-always&lt;/code&gt;. Leave unset to use normal behavior. It is also configurable under &lt;code&gt;chrome://flags&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--fingerprinting-canvas-measuretext-noise&lt;/code&gt; (Added flag to Bromite feature) - Scale the output values of Canvas::measureText() with a randomly selected factor in the range -0.0003% to 0.0003%, which are recomputed on every document initialization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--fingerprinting-client-rects-noise&lt;/code&gt; (Added flag to Bromite feature) - Implements fingerprinting deception of JS APIs &lt;code&gt;getClientRects()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;getBoundingClientRect()&lt;/code&gt; by scaling their output values with a random factor in the range -0.0003% to 0.0003%, which are recomputed for every document instantiation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--fingerprinting-canvas-image-data-noise&lt;/code&gt; (Added flag to Bromite feature) - Implements fingerprinting deception for Canvas image data retrieved via JS APIs. In the data, at most 10 pixels are slightly modified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--max-connections-per-host&lt;/code&gt; (from Bromite) - Configure the maximum allowed connections per host.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--set-ipv6-probe-false&lt;/code&gt; - (Not in &lt;code&gt;chrome://flags&lt;/code&gt;) Forces the result of the browser's IPv6 probing (i.e. IPv6 connectivity test) to be unsuccessful. This causes IPv4 addresses to be prioritized over IPv6 addresses. Without this flag, the probing result is set to be successful, which causes IPv6 to be used over IPv4 when possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Force all pop-ups into tabs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Safe_Browsing&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Safe Browsing&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable intranet redirect detector (extraneous DNS requests)
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This breaks captive portal detection, but captive portals still work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add more URL schemes allowed for saving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Iridium Browser feature change) Prevent URLs with the &lt;code&gt;trk:&lt;/code&gt; scheme from connecting to the Internet
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Also prevents any URLs with the top-level domain &lt;code&gt;qjz9zk&lt;/code&gt; (as used in domain substitution) from attempting a connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Iridium and Inox feature change) Prevent pinging of IPv6 address when detecting the availability of IPv6. See the &lt;code&gt;--set-ipv6-probe-false&lt;/code&gt; flag above to adjust the behavior instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for building Linux packages for multiple distributions (work in progress)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows support
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Does not set the Zone Identifier on downloaded files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: Although it is the top priority to eliminate bugs and privacy-invading code, there will be those that slip by due to the fast-paced growth and evolution of the Chromium project.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Supported platforms and distributions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, only desktop platforms are supported. Functionality of specific desktop platforms may vary across different releases. For more details, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://ungoogled-software.github.io/ungoogled-chromium-wiki/statuses&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Statuses in the Wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other platforms are discussed and tracked in GitHub's Issue Tracker. Learn more about using the Issue Tracker under the section &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium#contributing-reporting-contacting&quot;&gt;Contributing, Reporting, Contacting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download pre-built packages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contributor binaries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT&lt;/strong&gt;: These binaries are provided by anyone who are willing to build and submit them. Because these binaries are not necessarily &lt;a href=&quot;https://reproducible-builds.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;reproducible&lt;/a&gt;, authenticity cannot be guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ungoogled-software.github.io/ungoogled-chromium-binaries/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visit the contributor binaries website for download links&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ungoogled-software/ungoogled-chromium-binaries&quot;&gt;Website source code and contribution instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The release versioning scheme follows that of the tags. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium#getting-the-source-code&quot;&gt;Getting the source code&lt;/a&gt; section for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Alternative installation methods&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arch Linux: &lt;a href=&quot;https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/ungoogled-chromium/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Available in AUR as &lt;code&gt;ungoogled-chromium&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;macOS cask: Available as &lt;code&gt;eloston-chromium&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting the source code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users are encouraged to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium/tags&quot;&gt;one of the tags&lt;/a&gt;. The latest tag may not be the applicable for all platforms. To determine the tag to use, please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ungoogled-software.github.io/ungoogled-chromium-wiki/statuses&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Status page in the Wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags are versioned in the following format: &lt;code&gt;{chromium_version}-{release_revision}&lt;/code&gt; where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;chromium_version&lt;/code&gt; is the version of Chromium used in &lt;code&gt;x.x.x.x&lt;/code&gt; format, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;release_revision&lt;/code&gt; is a number indicating the version of ungoogled-chromium for the corresponding Chromium version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all tags are stable for all platforms. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ungoogled-software.github.io/ungoogled-chromium-wiki/statuses&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Statuses in the Wiki&lt;/a&gt; to determine the tag to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ungoogled-software.github.io/ungoogled-chromium-wiki/faq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;See the frequently-asked questions (FAQ) on the Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design and implementation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium/blob/master/docs/design.md&quot;&gt;See docs/design.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium/blob/master/docs/building.md&quot;&gt;See docs/building.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributing, Reporting, Contacting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please submit feedback (i.e. problems, suggestions, and questions) to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium/issues&quot;&gt;Issue Tracker&lt;/a&gt;. The Issue Tracker is the main hub for development activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are chat room options available via &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/ungoogled-software/Lobby&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; and Matrix.org (name &lt;code&gt;ungoogled-software/lobby&lt;/code&gt;, which has bidirectional connection with Gitter). They are optional; it is only provided for those who prefer this format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsections of this section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone is free to help others in need of support in the Issue Tracker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issues marked with the &lt;code&gt;help wanted&lt;/code&gt; tag are changes that needs discussion or assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If it requires new code, please read through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium#submitting-changes&quot;&gt;Submitting changes&lt;/a&gt; section below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to work on an issue, please state your intent to do so first to let others know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If there are fixes, tweaks, or additions you want to make, continue onto the following section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Submitting changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please submit all changes via Pull Requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You are welcome to submit minor changes, such as bug fixes, documentation fixes, and tweaks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to submit a new feature, please read through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium#criteria-for-new-features&quot;&gt;Criteria for new features&lt;/a&gt; below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When in doubt about the acceptance of a change, you are welcome to ask via an issue first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Criteria for new features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New features should not detract from the default Chromium experience, unless it falls under the project's main objectives (i.e. removing Google integration and enhancing privacy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For larger features, please propose them via an issue first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New features should live behind a setting that is &lt;strong&gt;off by default&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Settings are usually added via a command-line flag and &lt;code&gt;chrome://flags&lt;/code&gt; enties. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium/blob/master/docs/developing.md#adding-command-line-flags-and-chromeflags-options&quot;&gt;the relevant section in docs/developing.md&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unless there are significant benefits, adding the setting to &lt;code&gt;chrome://settings&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;em&gt;not recommended&lt;/em&gt; due to the additional maintenance required (caused by the infrastructure that backs preferences).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: In the event that the codebase changes significantly for a non-essential patch (i.e. a patch that does not contribute to the main objectives of ungoogled-chromium), it will be removed until someone updates it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BSD-3-clause. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 21:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nailer</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/1305560?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>Eloston/ungoogled-chromium</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium</og:url>
<og:description>Modifications to Google Chromium for removing Google integration and enhancing privacy, control, and transparency - Eloston/ungoogled-chromium</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why I’m done with Chrome</title>
<link>https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is mainly reserved for cryptography, and I try to avoid filling it with random &lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;4975&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/512px-google_chrome_icon_september_2014-svg/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/512px-google_chrome_icon_september_2014-svg.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;512,512&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;512px-Google_Chrome_icon_(September_2014).svg&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/512px-google_chrome_icon_september_2014-svg.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=150&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/512px-google_chrome_icon_september_2014-svg.png?w=512&quot; class=&quot; size-thumbnail wp-image-4975 alignright&quot; src=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/512px-google_chrome_icon_september_2014-svg.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=150&quot; alt=&quot;512px-Google_Chrome_icon_(September_2014).svg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/512px-google_chrome_icon_september_2014-svg.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=150 150w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/512px-google_chrome_icon_september_2014-svg.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=300 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&quot;/&gt;“someone is wrong on the Internet” posts. After all, that’s what Twitter is for! But from time to time something bothers me enough that I have to make an exception. Today I wanted to write specifically about Google Chrome, how much I’ve loved it in the past, and why — due to Chrome’s new user-unfriendly &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17942252&quot;&gt;forced login policy&lt;/a&gt; — I won’t be using it going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A brief history of Chrome&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Google launched Chrome ten years ago, it seemed like one of those rare cases where everyone wins. In 2008, the browser market was dominated by Microsoft, a company with an ugly history of using browser dominance to crush their competitors. Worse, Microsoft was making noises about getting into the search business. This posed an existential threat to Google’s internet properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this setting, Chrome was a beautiful solution. Even if the browser never produced a scrap of revenue for Google, it served its purpose just by keeping the Internet open to Google’s other products. As a benefit, the Internet community would receive a terrific open source browser with the best development team money could buy. This might be kind of sad for Mozilla (who have paid a high price due to Chrome) but overall it would be a good thing for Internet standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years this is exactly how things played out. Sure, Google offered an optional “sign in” feature for Chrome, which presumably vacuumed up your browsing data and shipped it off to Google, but that was an &lt;em&gt;option.&lt;/em&gt; An option you could easily ignore. If you didn’t take advantage of this option, Google’s privacy policy was clear: your data &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/privacy/#browser-modes&quot;&gt;would stay on your computer where it belonged.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What changed?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago Google shipped an update to Chrome that fundamentally changes the sign-in experience. From now on, every time you log into a Google property (for example, Gmail), Chrome will automatically &lt;em&gt;sign the browser into your Google account&lt;/em&gt; for you. It’ll do this without asking, or even explicitly notifying you. (However, and this is important: Google developers claim this will &lt;span&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; actually start synchronizing your data to Google — yet. See further below.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your sole warning — in the event that you’re looking for it — is that your Google profile picture will appear in the upper-right hand corner of the browser window. I noticed mine the other day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;4967&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/foo/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/foo.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;526,158&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;foo&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/foo.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/foo.png?w=526&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-4967&quot; src=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/foo.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=90&quot; alt=&quot;foo&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;90&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/foo.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=90 300w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/foo.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=45 150w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/foo.png 526w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change hasn’t gone entirely unnoticed: it received some vigorous discussion on sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17942252&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;. But the mainstream tech press seems to have ignored it completely. This is unfortunate — and I hope it changes — because this update has huge implications for Google and the future of Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the rest of this post, I’m going to talk about why this matters. From my perspective, this comes down to basically four points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nobody on the Chrome development team can provide a clear rationale for &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; this change was necessary, and the explanations they’ve given &lt;em&gt;don’t make any sense.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This change has enormous implications for user privacy and trust, and Google seems unable to grapple with this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The change makes a hash out of &lt;em&gt;Google’s own privacy policies&lt;/em&gt; for Chrome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google needs to stop treating customer trust like it’s a renewable resource, because they’re screwing up badly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;I warn you that this will get a bit ranty. Please read on anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Google’s stated rationale makes no sense&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new feature that triggers this auto-login behavior is called “Identity consistency between browser and cookie jar” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17942723&quot;&gt;HN).&lt;/a&gt; After conversations with two separate Chrome developers on Twitter (who will remain nameless — mostly because I don’t want them to hate me), I was given the following rationale for the change:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;4968&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/img_3331/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/img_3331.jpeg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1125,680&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1537709525&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;IMG_3331&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/img_3331.jpeg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/img_3331.jpeg?w=700&quot; class=&quot; size-medium wp-image-4968 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/img_3331.jpeg?w=300&amp;amp;h=181&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3331&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;181&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/img_3331.jpeg?w=300&amp;amp;h=181 300w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/img_3331.jpeg?w=600&amp;amp;h=362 600w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/img_3331.jpeg?w=150&amp;amp;h=91 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To paraphrase this explanation: &lt;em&gt;if you’re in a situation where you’ve already signed into Chrome&lt;/em&gt; and your friend shares your computer, then you can wind up accidentally having your friend’s Google cookies get uploaded into &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; account. This seems bad, and sure, we want to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But note something critical about this scenario. In order for this problem to apply to you, &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;you already have to be signed into Chrome&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; There is absolutely nothing in this problem description that seems to affect users who &lt;em&gt;chose not to sign into the browser in the first place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if &lt;em&gt;signed-in&lt;/em&gt; users are your problem, why would you make a change that forces &lt;em&gt;unsigned&lt;/em&gt;–&lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; users to become signed-in? I could waste a lot more ink wondering about the mismatch between the stated “problem” and the “fix”, but I won’t bother: because nobody on the public-facing side of the Chrome team has been able to offer an explanation that squares this circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this matters, because “sync” or not…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The change has serious implications for privacy and trust&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chrome team has offered a single defense of the change. They point out that just because your browser is “signed in” does not mean it’s uploading your data to Google’s servers. Specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While Chrome will now log into your Google account without your consent (following a Gmail login), Chrome &lt;strong&gt;will not&lt;/strong&gt; activate the “sync” feature that sends your data to Google. That requires an additional consent step. So in theory your data should remain local.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my paraphrase. But I think it’s fair to characterize the general stance of the Chrome developers I spoke with as: without this “sync” feature, there’s nothing wrong with the change they’ve made, and everything is just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is nuts, for several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User consent &lt;em&gt;matters&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; For ten years I’ve been asked a single question by the Chrome browser: “Do you want to log in with your Google account?” And for ten years I’ve said &lt;em&gt;no thanks.&lt;/em&gt; Chrome &lt;span&gt;still&lt;/span&gt; asks me that question — it’s just that now it doesn’t honor my decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chrome developers want me to believe that this is fine, since &lt;em&gt;(phew!)&lt;/em&gt; I’m still protected by one additional consent guardrail. The problem here is obvious:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you didn’t respect my lack of consent on the biggest user-facing privacy option in Chrome (and  didn’t even notify me that you had stopped respecting it!) why should I trust any other consent option you give me? What stops you from changing your mind on that option in a few months, when we’ve all stopped paying attention?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter is that I’d never even heard of Chrome’s “sync” option — for the simple reason that up until September 2018, I had never logged into Chrome. Now I’m forced to learn these new terms, and hope that the Chrome team keeps promises to keep all of my data local as the barriers between “signed in” and “not signed in” are gradually eroded away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Chrome sync UI is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_pattern&quot;&gt;dark pattern&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Now that I’m forced to log into Chrome, I’m faced with a brand new menu I’ve never seen before. It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;4973&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/thing-2/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/thing1.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;572,1128&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Thing&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/thing1.png?w=152&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/thing1.png?w=519&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-4973&quot; src=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/thing1.png?w=152&amp;amp;h=300&quot; alt=&quot;Thing&quot; width=&quot;152&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/thing1.png?w=152&amp;amp;h=300 152w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/thing1.png?w=304&amp;amp;h=600 304w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/thing1.png?w=76&amp;amp;h=150 76w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 152px) 100vw, 152px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does that big blue button indicate that I’m &lt;span&gt;already&lt;/span&gt; synchronizing my data to Google? That’s scary! Wait, maybe it’s an &lt;em&gt;invitation&lt;/em&gt; to synchronize! If so, what happens to my data if I click it by accident? (I won’t give it the answer away, you should go find out. Just make sure you don’t accidentally upload all your data in the process. It can happen quickly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, Google has transformed the question of consenting to data upload from something &lt;em&gt;affirmative&lt;/em&gt; that I actually had to put effort into — entering my Google credentials and signing into Chrome — into something I can now do with a single accidental click. This is a dark pattern. Whether intentional or not, it has the effect of making it easy for people to activate sync without knowing it, or to think they’re already syncing and thus there’s no additional cost to increasing Google’s access to their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t take my word for it. It even gives (former) Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lcamtuf/status/1043338876297728000?s=21&quot;&gt;people the creeps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Big brother doesn’t need to actually &lt;em&gt;watch&lt;/em&gt; you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; We tell things to our web browsers that we wouldn’t tell our best friends. We do this with some vague understanding that yes, &lt;em&gt;the Internet spies on us.&lt;/em&gt; But we also believe that this spying is weak and probabilistic. It’s not like someone’s standing over our shoulder checking our driver’s license with each click.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens if you take that belief away? There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://openscholarship.wustl.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1556&amp;amp;context=law_globalstudies&quot;&gt;numerous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2265271&quot;&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; indicating that even the &lt;em&gt;perception of surveillance&lt;/em&gt; can significantly greatly magnify the degree of self-censorship users force on themselves. Will user feel comfortable browsing for information on sensitive mental health conditions — if their real name and picture are always loaded into the corner of their browser? The Chrome development team says “yes”. I think they’re wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;For all we know, the new approach has privacy implications &lt;em&gt;even if sync is off&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The Chrome developers claim that with “sync” off, a Chrome has no privacy implications. This might be true. But when pressed on the actual details, nobody seems quite sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if I have my browser logged out, then I log in and turn on “sync”, does all my past (logged-out) data get pushed to Google? What happens if I’m forced to be logged in, and then subsequently turn on “sync”? Nobody can quite tell me if the data uploaded in these conditions is the same. These differences could really matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The changes make hash of the Chrome privacy policy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chrome &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/privacy/&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; is a remarkably simple document. Unlike most privacy policies, it was clearly written as a promise to Chrome’s users — rather than as the usual lawyer CYA. Functionally, it describes two browsing modes: “Basic browser mode” and “signed-in mode”. These modes have very different properties. Read for yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;4969&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/untitled-2/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-2.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1172,476&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Untitled 2&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-2.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-2.png?w=700&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-4969&quot; src=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-2.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=122&quot; alt=&quot;Untitled 2&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;122&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-2.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=122 300w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-2.png?w=600&amp;amp;h=244 600w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-2.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=61 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;4970&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/untitled-3/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-3.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1796,600&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Untitled 3&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-3.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-3.png?w=700&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-4970&quot; src=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-3.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=100&quot; alt=&quot;Untitled 3&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-3.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=100 300w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-3.png?w=600&amp;amp;h=200 600w, https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-3.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=50 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In “basic browser mode”, your data is stored locally. In “signed-in” mode, your data gets shipped to Google’s servers. This is easy to understand. If you want privacy, don’t sign in. But what happens if your browser decides to switch you from one mode to the other, all on its own?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically, the privacy policy is still accurate. If you’re in basic browsing mode, your data is still stored locally. The problem is that you &lt;em&gt;no longer get to decide which mode you’re in&lt;/em&gt;. This makes a mockery out of whatever intentions the original drafters had. Maybe Google will update the document to reflect the new “sync” distinction that the Chrome developers have shared with me. We’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; After I tweeted about my concerns, I received a DM on Sunday from two different Chrome developers, each telling me the good news: Google is updating their privacy policy to reflect the new operation of Chrome. I think that’s, um, good news. But I also can’t help but note that updating a privacy policy on a weekend is an &lt;em&gt;awful&lt;/em&gt; lot of trouble to go to for a change that… apparently doesn’t even solve a problem for signed-out users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trust is not a renewable resource&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a company that sustains itself by collecting massive amounts of user data, Google has  managed to avoid the negative privacy connotations we associate with, say, Facebook. This isn’t because Google collects less data, it’s just that Google has consistently been more circumspect and responsible with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where Facebook will routinely change privacy settings and apologize later, Google has upheld clear privacy policies that it doesn’t routinely change. Sure, when it collects, it collects &lt;em&gt;gobs&lt;/em&gt; of data, but in the cases where Google explicitly makes user security and privacy promises — it tends to keep them. This seems to be changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s reputation is hard-earned, and it can be easily lost. Changes like this burn a lot of trust with users. If the change is solving an absolutely critical problem for users , then maybe a loss of trust is worth it. I wish Google could convince me that was the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post has gone on more than long enough, but before I finish I want to address two common counterarguments I’ve heard from people I generally respect in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One argument is that &lt;em&gt;Google already spies on you&lt;/em&gt; via cookies and its pervasive advertising network and partnerships, so what’s the big deal if they force your browser into a logged-in state? One individual I respect described the Chrome change as “making you wear two name tags instead of one”. I think this objection is silly both on moral grounds — just because you’re violating my privacy doesn’t make it ok to add a massive &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; violation &lt;em&gt;— but&lt;/em&gt; also because it’s objectively silly. Google has spent millions of dollars adding additional tracking features to both Chrome and Android. They aren’t doing this for fun; they’re doing this because it clearly &lt;em&gt;produces data they want.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other counterargument (if you want to call it that) goes like this: &lt;em&gt;I’m a n00b for using Google products at all, and of course they were always going to do this.&lt;/em&gt; The extreme version holds that I ought to be using lynx+Tor and DJB’s custom search engine, and if I’m not I pretty much deserve what’s coming to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reject this argument. I think It’s entirely possible for a company like Google to make good, usable open source software that doesn’t massively violate user privacy. For ten years I believe Google Chrome did just this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why they’ve decided to change, I don’t know. It makes me sad.&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>user982</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why I’m done with Chrome</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/</og:url>
<og:description>This blog is mainly reserved for cryptography, and I try to avoid filling it with random “someone is wrong on the Internet” posts. After all, that’s what Twitter is for! But from …</og:description>
<og:image>https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/untitled-3.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Murdered body found after tree ‘unusual for the area’ grew from seed in stomach</title>
<link>https://www.msn.com/en-gb/news/world/murdered-mans-body-found-after-tree-unusual-for-the-area-grew-from-seed-in-his-stomach/ar-BBNACEq?ocid=sf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.msn.com/en-gb/news/world/murdered-mans-body-found-after-tree-unusual-for-the-area-grew-from-seed-in-his-stomach/ar-BBNACEq?ocid=sf</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;storyimage fullwidth inlineimage&quot; data-aop=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image&quot; data-attrib=&quot;CEN&quot; data-caption=&quot;Remains and samples which were found at the scene where Ahmet Hergune was killed&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;a close up of a logo: Remains and samples which were found at the scene where Ahmet Hergune was killed&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BBNAHgD.img?h=200&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;m=6&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;o=f&amp;amp;l=f&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caption truncate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;© CEN&lt;/span&gt; Remains and samples which were found at the scene where Ahmet Hergune was killed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;A missing man who was murdered more than 40 years ago has been found - after a seed from a fig in his stomach grew into a tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahmet Hergune was killed during the conflict between Greek Cypriots and Turkish Cypriots in 1974, but his body remained undiscovered for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was eventually discovered because the tree which grew from him was unusual for the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incredibly, the dead man had been taken into a cave with two others and both of them had been killed by dynamite that was then thrown in after them.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the dynamite also blew a hole in the side of the cave, allowing light to flood into the darkened interior which in turn allowed the fig tree to grow from the man's body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to 200,000 people were displaced in the conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;storyimage fullwidth inlineimage&quot; data-aop=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image&quot; data-attrib=&quot;Credits: CEN&quot; data-caption=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;a group of people preparing food in a kitchen&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BBNAFhq.img?h=200&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;m=6&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;o=f&amp;amp;l=f&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caption truncate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;© Credits: CEN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-credits&quot;&gt;His sister, 87 year-old Munur Herguner, said: &quot;We used to live in a village with a population of 4,000, half Greek, half Turkish. In 1974, the disturbances began. My brother Ahmet joined the Turkish Resistance Organization (TMT). On 10th June, the Greeks took him away.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She added: &quot;For years we searched for my brother in vain.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But she said that unknown to her, the grave had ended up being marked by the fig tree that grew from the seed in his stomach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tree was spotted in 2011 by a researcher who was curious as to how the tree had ended up in the cave and especially in a mountainous area where it was not usually found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While carrying out his research and digging around the tree, he was then horrified to find a human body underneath and raised the alarm. On digging further, police recovered a total of three bodies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Munur Herguner added that her brother was believed to have been the one that had eaten the fig, and blood samples from her family matched DNA fragments which confirmed it was her brother's final resting place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As detectives investigated the killing, they discovered that the brother Ahmet and the other two had been killed by dynamite in the cave, and the blast had made a hole in the cave that let in light. He had apparently eaten the fig shortly before he died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;storyimage fullwidth inlineimage&quot; data-aop=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image&quot; data-attrib=&quot;Credits: CEN&quot; data-caption=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;a rocky mountain&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BBNAHgK.img?h=200&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;m=6&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;o=f&amp;amp;l=f&amp;amp;x=373&amp;amp;y=234&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caption truncate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;© Credits: CEN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; His sister said: &quot;The fig remnants in my brother's stomach grew into a tree as the sun crept into the cave through the hole made by the explosion. They found my brother thanks to that fig tree.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-credits&quot;&gt;The Committee on Missing Persons in Cyprus (CMP) has been searching for 2,002 people who disappeared on the Mediterranean island between 1963 and 1974.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-credits&quot;&gt;It was launched in 1981 following an agreement between the Greek Cypriot and Turkish Cypriot communities under the auspices of the United Nations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The committee was tasked with the mission of preparing a list of missing persons and discovering what had happened to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They identify missing bodies by taking blood samples from relatives and wherever possible using descriptions of the clothing people were wearing immediately before they disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A total of 1,222 excavations have been carried out in the island so far, and remains have been found in 26 percent of those excavations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Research Team, consisting of ten people led by Thomas Antoniou and S'la Murat, have identified and returned the remains of 890 people, including Ahmet, over the last 12 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahmet's story is miraculous, as his discovery decades later owes itself entirely to the life that emerged from his dead body in the unlikely shape of a fig tree.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 12:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Osiris30</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.msn.com/en-gb/news/world/murdered-mans-body-found-after-tree-unusual-for-the-area-grew-from-seed-in-his-stomach/ar-BBNACEq?ocid=sf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Let Teenagers Sleep In</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/20/opinion/sunday/sleep-school-start-time-screens-teenagers.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/20/opinion/sunday/sleep-school-start-time-screens-teenagers.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In 2014, the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://pediatrics.aappublications.org/content/early/2014/08/19/peds.2014-1697&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;American Academy of Pediatrics&lt;/a&gt; recommended that middle and high schools start no earlier than 8:30 a.m., a policy now backed by the American Medical Association, the C.D.C. and many other health organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Whenever schools have managed the transition to a later start time, students get more sleep, attendance goes up, grades improve and there is a significant reduction in car accidents. The RAND Corporation estimated that opening school doors after 8:30 a.m. would contribute &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR2109.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;at least $83 billion&lt;/a&gt; to the national economy within a decade through improved educational outcomes and reduced car crash rates. The Brookings Institution calculates that later school start times would lead to an average &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/research/organizing-schools-to-improve-student-achievement-start-times-grade-configurations-and-teacher-assignments/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;increase in lifetime earnings&lt;/a&gt; of $17,500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Since 2014, several states have passed legislation related to school start times. In August, California lawmakers &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/us/california-school-start-times.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;passed a bill&lt;/a&gt; that would have gone further. By 2021, most middle and high schools across the state would have had to start at 8:30 a.m. or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;It was landmark legislation, according to Terra Ziporyn Snider of the grass-roots organization &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.startschoollater.net/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Start School Later&lt;/a&gt;, which has been campaigning for change since 2011. “It is becoming less acceptable to run schools at unhealthy hours, and this bill reflects that sentiment,” she said. But California’s governor, Jerry Brown, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/politics/la-pol-ca-school-start-time-vetoed-20180921-story.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vetoed the bill&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday amid opposition from local officials, a deeply regrettable decision. It shows a tragic disregard for both the mental health of children and for science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But Ms. Ziporyn Snider remains upbeat: “Eventually a bill like this, created in the best interests of children, will pass. It’s only a matter of time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Parents need to be vocal about the reasons change is so important, joining forces with community leaders, sleep scientists, health professionals and educators to put school start times on the local, then state agendas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Changing the operating hours of an institution so central to the community is far from easy. It requires strong leadership and adjustments by school bus companies and businesses offering services like child care and extracurricular clubs. But despite the upheaval involved, making such a shift would pay off in the long run. It is unthinkable that a school should operate with asbestos in the ceilings, with no central heating in winter or with rats in the kitchen. Starting school before 8:30 a.m. should be equally unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-k2zj0n e1kwarht0&quot;&gt;Henry Nicholls (&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WayOfThePanda&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@WayOfThePanda&lt;/a&gt;) is a journalist, science teacher, trustee of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.narcolepsy.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Narcolepsy U.K&lt;/a&gt;. and the author of “&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/henry-nicholls/sleepyhead/9781541672574/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sleepyhead: The Neuroscience of a Good Night’s Rest&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;css-11q3cgf ewiwup50&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 08:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>anoplus</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/20/opinion/sunday/sleep-school-start-time-screens-teenagers.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Opinion | Let Teenagers Sleep In</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/09/16/opinion/sunday/16nicholls/16nicholls-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Starting schools before 8:30 a.m. shows a tragic disregard for both the mental health of children and for science.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/20/opinion/sunday/sleep-school-start-time-screens-teenagers.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gut directly connected to brain, by a newly discovered neuron circuit</title>
<link>http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/09/your-gut-directly-connected-your-brain-newly-discovered-neuron-circuit</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/09/your-gut-directly-connected-your-brain-newly-discovered-neuron-circuit</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;entity entity-paragraphs-item paragraphs-item-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure__head&quot;&gt;&lt;img sizes=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/vagus_16x9.jpg?itok=HROJsf7l&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/vagus_16x9.jpg?itok=HROJsf7l 1w, https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__699w__no_aspect/public/vagus_16x9.jpg?itok=YjwAG8Ll 700w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption__text&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut feeling: Sensory neurons inside the gut inform the vagus nerve (yellow) and brain how our stomachs and intestines are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;NICOLLE R. FULLER/Science Source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;article__header article__header--inline&quot; readability=&quot;25.491935483871&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;byline byline--article&quot;&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/author/emily-underwood&quot;&gt;Emily Underwood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;time&gt;Sep. 20, 2018 , 2:00 PM&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;The human gut is lined with more than 100 million nerve cells—it’s practically a brain unto itself. And indeed, the gut actually talks to the brain, releasing hormones into the bloodstream that, over the course of about 10 minutes, tell us how hungry it is, or that we shouldn’t have eaten an entire pizza. But a new study reveals the gut has a much more direct connection to the brain through a neural circuit that allows it to transmit signals in mere seconds. The findings could lead to new treatments for obesity, eating disorders, and even depression and autism—all of which have been linked to a malfunctioning gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study reveals “a new set of pathways that use gut cells to rapidly communicate with … the brain stem,” says Daniel Drucker, a clinician-scientist who studies gut disorders at the Lunenfeld-Tanenbaum Research Institute in Toronto, Canada, who was not involved with the work. Although many questions remain before the clinical implications become clear, he says, “This is a cool new piece of the puzzle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, neuroscientist Diego Bohórquez of Duke University in Durham, North Carolina, made a startling discovery while looking through his electron microscope. Enteroendocrine cells, which stud the lining of the gut and produce hormones that spur digestion and suppress hunger, had footlike protrusions that resemble the synapses neurons use to communicate with each other. Bohórquez knew the enteroendocrine cells could send hormonal messages to the central nervous system, but he also wondered whether they could “talk” to the brain using electrical signals, the way that neurons do. If so, they would have to send the signals through the vagus nerve, which travels from the gut to the brain stem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He and colleagues injected a fluorescent rabies virus, which is transmitted through neuronal synapses, into the colons of mice and waited for the enteroendocrine cells and their partners to light up. &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/cgi/doi/10.1126/science.aau9973&quot;&gt;Those partners turned out to be to vagal neurons&lt;/a&gt;, the researchers report today in &lt;cite&gt;Science.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a petri dish, enteroendocrine cells reached out to vagal neurons and formed synaptic connections with each other. The cells even gushed out glutamate, a neurotransmitter involved in smell and taste, which the vagal neurons picked up on within 100 milliseconds—faster than an eyeblink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s much faster than hormones can travel from the gut to the brain through the bloodstream, Bohórquez says. Hormones’ sluggishness may be responsible for the failures of many appetite suppressants that target them, he says. The next step is to study whether this gut-brain signaling provides the brain with important information about the nutrients and caloric value of the food we eat, he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some obvious advantages to superfast gut-brain signaling, such as detecting toxins and poison, but there may be other perks to sensing the contents of our guts in real time, he says. Whatever those are, there’s a good chance the benefits are ancient—gut sensory cells date back to one of the first multicellular organisms, a flat creature called &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/321/5892/1028.2https:/www.nature.com/articles/nature07191&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trichoplax adhaerens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; which arose roughly 600 million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional clues about how gut sensory cells benefit us today lie in a separate study, published today in &lt;cite&gt;Cell&lt;/cite&gt;. Researchers used lasers to stimulate the sensory neurons that innervate the gut in mice, which produced rewarding sensations the rodents worked hard to repeat. The laser stimulation also &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2018.08.049%20Authors%20Wenfei%20Han,%20Luis%20A.%20Tellez,%20Matthew%20H.%20Perkins,%20...,%20Sara%20J.%20Shammah-Lagnado,%20Guillaume%20de%20Lartigue,%20Ivan%20E.%20de%20Araujo%20Correspondence%20ivan.dearaujo@mssm.edu%20In%20Brief%20A%20gut-to-brain%20neural%20circuit%20establishes%20vagal%20neurons%20as%20an%20essential%20component%20of%20the%20reward%20neuronal%20circuitry%20linking%20sensory%20neurons%20in%20the%20upper%20gut%20to%20striatal%20dopamine%20release&quot;&gt;increased levels&lt;/a&gt; of a mood-boosting neurotransmitter called dopamine in the rodents’ brains, the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combined, the two papers help explain why stimulating the vagus nerve with electrical current can treat severe depression in people, says Ivan de Araujo, a neuroscientist at the Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai in New York City, who led the &lt;cite&gt;Cell&lt;/cite&gt; study. The results may also explain why, on a basic level, eating makes us feel good. “Even though these neurons are outside the brain, they perfectly fit the definition of reward neurons” that drive motivation and increase pleasure, he says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>everybodyknows</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/09/your-gut-directly-connected-your-brain-newly-discovered-neuron-circuit</og:url>
<og:title>Your gut is directly connected to your brain, by a newly discovered neuron circuit</og:title>
<og:description>Find could lead to new treatments for obesity, depression</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/article_main_large/public/vagus_16x9.jpg?itok=CaUsXLAG</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/09/your-gut-directly-connected-your-brain-newly-discovered-neuron-circuit</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Generative art: New and recreated vintage art, made with code and imagination</title>
<link>https://beta.observablehq.com/collection/@observablehq/generative-art</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://beta.observablehq.com/collection/@observablehq/generative-art</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.observablehq.com/collection/@observablehq/generative-art&quot;&gt;https://beta.observablehq.com/collection/@observablehq/generative-art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18048582&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18048582&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 211&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 27&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 23:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lobo_tuerto</dc:creator>
<og:title>Generative art</og:title>
<og:description>An Observable collection by Observable</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.observableusercontent.com/thumbnail/6fc0c0a3b6aaaa8d76dc648e4630ecefef08ff661f88735b711b7c2878a30aa6.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://beta.observablehq.com/collection/@observablehq/generative-art</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: How to come up with monetizable side project ideas?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4393673110721&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.829525483304&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;18047553&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: How to come up with monetizable side project ideas?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73170731707317&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_18047553&quot;&gt;352 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=sunilkumarc&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;sunilkumarc&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553&quot;&gt;1 day ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_18047553&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=18047553&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D18047553&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20to%20come%20up%20with%20monetizable%20side%20project%20ideas%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20to%20come%20up%20with%20monetizable%20side%20project%20ideas%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=18047553&amp;amp;auth=7cd8b58a62287c4880d4979ebbfc45b56a272a51&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553&quot;&gt;101 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;I love building small tools which solve problems I myself face in my day to day life. Having been worked in different companies over the last 4 years, I feel I've acquired enough knowledge to develop big applications(big enough to make money) on my own.
&lt;p&gt;I was wondering, how one can come up with side project ideas which can generate few hundred dollars per month on the side. Any inputs, resources and wisdom are appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Winter 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 19:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sunilkumarc</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18047553</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chrome is a Google Service that happens to include a Browser Engine</title>
<link>https://ha.x0r.be/posts/chrome-is-a-google-service/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ha.x0r.be/posts/chrome-is-a-google-service/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;mt4 w-100&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;f6 b helvetica tracked&quot;&gt;POSTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;time class=&quot;f6 mv4 dib tracked&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-09-22T15:46:50+01:00&quot;&gt;September 22, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting with Chrome 69, logging into a Google Site is tied to logging into Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is typically the topic where things are complex enough that tweets or 500 character Mastodon toots don’t do it justice. I’d also mention that I prefer to avoid directly linking people’s posts on this, because I dislike the practice of taking discussions out of their original audience and treating them as official or semi-official communications from a given company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what changed with Chrome 69? From that version, any time someone using Chrome logs into a Google service or site, they are also logged into Chrome-as-a-browser with that user account. Any time someone logs out of a Google service, they are also logged out of the browser. Before Chrome 69, Chrome users could decline to be logged into Chrome entirely, skipping the use of Sync and other features that require a login and they could use Chrome in a logged-out state while still making use of GMail for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to spell it out: this means Google logins for Chrome are now de-facto mandatory if you ever login to a Google site. (&lt;em&gt;Clarification&lt;/em&gt;: Sync/browser history/password sharing still requires user confirmation to happen, this is purely about the login itself.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone in the security community raised this, it turned out that apparently this is intended behaviour from Google’s side as confirmed by multiple googlers and they were wondering why the new behaviour might feel abusive to some people. Some folks working on Chrome pointed out that most people can’t differentiate between logging into a Google Site and logging into Chrome and this has lead to problems with shared computers, where person A logs into GMail, but person B is logged into Chrome. This prompted Chrome developers to come up with the change that erases the distinction entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this point that I should note that I don’t personally use Chrome, as I felt it was too closely corporate Google even before this change. This is also not a post arguing that “some users can tell the difference, therefor…”, I do believe software should be written with the common users in mind. Interestingly, the common user belief that strongly equates Chrome with a Google Service (and not an application or tool) is probably the more accurate view of Chrome, post release 69. It’s worth wondering from where users got that impression and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if this change is just about bringing Chrome in line with what most users believe anyway, what’s the fuss? Perhaps it’s not about what people believe, but what is right. Perhaps Google doesn’t want Chrome, currently having majority browser market share, to be a neutral platform. A lot of people, developers especially, believe that Chrome is a Google-influenced but more or less neutral tool and then this widespread belief has to be reconciled with the Chrome-as-a-service thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violating the content vs browser separation layer doesn’t just conform to what a lot of users believe, it also ties what’s happening inside the browser to Google on an unprecedented level, throwing the neutrality of Chrome as a platform into question. What’s the next thing that Google and only Google can make Chrome do? Concerned about shared computers but you’re not Google? There is no neutral API to log someone out from Chrome and prevent data from being synced if it’s about person A logging into Facebook in person B’s Chrome profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sidenote&lt;/em&gt;: Most Google services have for me this in common with Facebook: these services are too deeply integrated and impossible to use in part or isolation. It’s either the entire system or nothing, based on how the question of consent is approached. You would like to use GMail (logged in obviously) but Google search, Youtube, Chrome etc without a login? No can do. You selected strict settings in Facebook for your profile data? You’re just an API/permission redesign away from having your choices nullified. Part of me feels that this Chrome shared computer issue that Googlers mentioned is real, but it’s also just too convenient to solve this by tieing Chrome closer to Google, you know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;update&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;- Compare the basic (local) and signed-in mode in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/privacy/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome’s privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;. Silently upgrading from basic mode to signed-in mode makes quite a large difference.&lt;br/&gt;- Chromium is apparently also affected by this.&lt;br/&gt;- There is a workaround to disable this behaviour. I deliberately don’t include it here, as that relies on internal flags and the point of this post wasn’t to try to revert this change, but rather to think about Chrome’s direction in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;update 2&lt;/em&gt;: Added a clarification that Sync doesn’t automatically turn on with the autologin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&quot;w-30-l mt6-l&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 18:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dredmorbius</dc:creator>
<og:title>Chrome is a Google Service that happens to include a Browser Engine</og:title>
<og:description>Starting with Chrome 69, logging into a Google Site is tied to logging into Chrome.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://ha.x0r.be/posts/chrome-is-a-google-service/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ha.x0r.be/posts/chrome-is-a-google-service/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>3D engine entirely made of MS Excel formulae</title>
<link>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/CBel/20180213/308549/3D_engine_entirely_made_of_MS_Excel_formulae__Enjoy_this_Doomxls_file_.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/CBel/20180213/308549/3D_engine_entirely_made_of_MS_Excel_formulae__Enjoy_this_Doomxls_file_.php</guid>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;The following blog post, unless otherwise noted, was written by a member of Gamasutra’s community.&lt;br/&gt;The thoughts and opinions expressed are those of the writer and not Gamasutra or its parent company.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is on how I could write a 3D engine using only excel formula, including following functionalities :&lt;br/&gt;- infinite procedural generated maze map&lt;br/&gt;- real time ray tracer rendering&lt;br/&gt;- occlusion calculation&lt;br/&gt;- basic illumination rendering&lt;br/&gt;- illumination and compute shader&lt;br/&gt;- natural displacement engine&lt;br/&gt;- No macro at all used by the 3D engine,&lt;br/&gt;    * to enjoy the game using key press, some macro trigger the displacements, using just one simple copy instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reho.st/self/4811655ae53dd1ad1462e74ec790e16ebd2d1c33.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Endless series of walls, and monsters !&quot; src=&quot;https://reho.st/preview/self/4811655ae53dd1ad1462e74ec790e16ebd2d1c33.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In-game screen capture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can freely download the file and test it by yourself !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Demonstration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/iCeOEQVUWZ0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A computer science teacher once told us &quot;a given computation can be achieved with any programming language, even spreadsheet formula&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, as wise at it could have been, including Excel in the comparison sounded definitively stupid ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thereafter, while studying Turing machine, it then sounded correct, yet not very fulfilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several years of experience with Excel, we will mostly remind Excel formula only are definitively limited with the lack of input/outputs.&lt;br/&gt;But, the set of problems that can be simply solved with formula only remain impressive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this work is not just some kind of performance ... There is was a good reason for me to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spreadsheet are a powerful tool that everyone has to learn to use for almost every business jobs.&lt;br/&gt;Yet, when most people come to solve most complexes problems, they want to use VBA language, without even knowing why.&lt;br/&gt;And once they started learning it, they try to use it for any kind of problem, even simple search or rendering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, as an excel teacher, I'm trying to explain to these people why writing VBA macro for any problem while not being educated on computer programming is not only a real waste of time, but also a serious risk for their spreadsheet quality.&lt;br/&gt;In a business environment, using formula rather than macro is :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Faster to write for anyone but professional analyst programmer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier to maintain for anyone but professional analyst programmer. (while macro are mostly unusable once the initial developer is gone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A guaranteed quality, due to permanent value checking. (a forced Test Driven Development method)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More efficient in the long run, due to the &quot;think before you write&quot; process with formula design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And definitively, much better integrated in the overall spreadsheet tool, following the initial design pattern of the spreadsheet, while macro often appear like specific developments requiring extensive maintenance afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nota : these concerns mostly apply to procedure used as macro, while additional function written in VBA can increase the efficiency without lowering the quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I came to write this game : an applied demonstration, that macro was not necessary at first, even for some of the most complex problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be more precise, I found only 2 cases when VBA is required :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Adding specifics input or output (as I did here to get key events), while formula is always limited to change on the cell itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some complex problems (like optimization, try-and-check problems), those in which the computation time is too long, and/or taking too much space. But theses problems are quite rare in real business life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This said, now, I'll only focus on the rest of this article on how the spreadsheet actually works, for its different aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spreadsheet is meant to be a doom-like game, in a sort of maze environment.&lt;br/&gt;It could have been a fixed, manually-constructed map, possibly looping on borders, but it would require storage, lookup, and an initial design.&lt;br/&gt;In the meantime, using a procedural generated infinite map sounded much more worth of the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a random generated map, we need it to be self-consistent over time, so rand() function could not be used, as we do not control the random seed.&lt;br/&gt;The seeds for the random generator have to be the position (x;y) on the map, to get a different value for each position, and we cannot take the result of the previous random as seed for the next, or we would have to store all the map from the beginning.&lt;br/&gt;While providing high quality random, usual hash functions are too expensive, so I needed to find an other one.&lt;br/&gt;Trying to use fractal generator appeared to be also quite costly, and providing interesting result only for a small part of the map.&lt;br/&gt;Then I found the middle-square method, which isn't very &quot;random&quot; when consecutive seed are used, but gave me the idea of taking decimal of any other calculation.&lt;br/&gt;I found out that taking decimals of sin(x)+cos(y) finally provided nice decimals, without any visible pattern, and a computation time surprisingly short.&lt;br/&gt;To get decimals, mathematical function mod() and floor() are much more efficient compared to text function substring mid()&lt;br/&gt;Trying to get the map looking like a rat maze, I didnt made block of solid block, otherwise it would have looked like a cavern (minecraft style) rather than a maze.&lt;br/&gt;So we needed thin walls, with 2 possible walls for each square. We can then take 2 blocks of digits among the same random value.&lt;br/&gt;2 parameters controlling the density of walls.&lt;br/&gt;Given theses rules, we can either display the maze, or test any wall given it's position for raytracing.&lt;br/&gt;Note that the map is &quot;flat&quot;, without any top/down. It would be possible to add relief using relief generator (diamond-square algorithm could apply, as it is possible to write it with a non-recursive function), but the solution of cutting holes in both ceiling and floor, with an additional level value would greatly ease the whole following process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ok, we're definitively in hell&quot; src=&quot;https://reho.st/self/fd27e421d28e211d575353940119722d94c665f1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ok, we're definitively in hell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The raycaster solution imply to determine for each pixel which face the ray would touch first, and retrieve some information from it, (distance, angle with light, color ...).&lt;br/&gt;Raytracer also require additional ray to spread from this point (reflections, transparencies), with a direct massive increase on computation cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Occlusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problematic will be to find the first object in the course of each ray.&lt;br/&gt;Since the maze is actually flat, with horizontal walls, the nearest wall found will be the same for all pixels of a given column.&lt;br/&gt;The process can then be simplified as an horizontal radar, on 1 dimension.&lt;br/&gt;Then, there is no choice but testing for a wall on the first possible wall, then the second possible, until we find one.&lt;br/&gt;It's only a trigonometrical problem to determine which wall are to be tested.&lt;br/&gt;And as we have 2 kind of walls, we have to test both of kinds, and then keep only the nearer.&lt;br/&gt;One of the limit in excel is that condition loop does not exist, and the loop body can only be skipped to save time. So we should cut the maximum checking distance, assuming there is no wall at all if not found until then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Floor and Ceiling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To represent floor and ceiling, we just have to find where wall does stop.&lt;br/&gt;A dedicated sheet mesure the distance of the floor or ceiling depending of the vertical angle.&lt;br/&gt;Then, for each pixel, we decide if the wall is further or not than the ceiling of the floor, and decide the pixel color accordingly.&lt;br/&gt;The comparison is made efficiently by using only the projection of the distance of both wall and ceiling/floor on the camera axis. The final distance is then obtained using the pre-calculated distance factor in the distance shader. The fixed pre-calculated is mean to save resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Illumination&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final light is obtained from a light shader representing a torch light, in the direction of the camera (and weapon sight).&lt;br/&gt;Some reflection is also added, when a surface is exactly horizontal to the light ray.&lt;br/&gt;Only wall can be horizontal (if a pitch is added, it would only displace the screen pane up and down, not turning the camera)&lt;br/&gt;For each angle of the radar, we get the angle between the ray and the nearest found wall.&lt;br/&gt;Then, the reflection factor is a basic function of this angle.&lt;br/&gt;In the end, the light is the product of a factor function of the distance, the ceiling/floor or wall resolution, the reflection factor, and the light shader factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Display&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effective display is made from conditional formatting - gradient of color based on the value of the cell.&lt;br/&gt;Hiding the value is achieved by cell formatting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The player is not supposed to move through wall, or it would defeat the idea of a maze.&lt;br/&gt;Wall would not either stuck the player as he reach them. The movement should slip unless he reach a corner.&lt;br/&gt;In addition, a minimum distance should be kept from the player to avoid graphical issues, and make wall have some width.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appeared to be particularly tricky to manage all the possible cases of wall, and positions of the player compared to this wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2^5 possibilities were studied, and the 3 potentials outcome (for each displacement axis) where mapped to get the result within fewer possible tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While appearing one of the smaller, the displacement tab was one of the most complex to realize. (10 times more than the map, twice as much as the wall detection)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reho.st/view/self/39e896009b375a3aa97c175c2bd9f04d4039b2a3.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Oh, hi, Mr Red Ghost !&quot; src=&quot;https://reho.st/preview/self/39e896009b375a3aa97c175c2bd9f04d4039b2a3.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The bad guy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Graphical rendering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge for enemies was to obtain a shape that could be easily added before wall, easily rendered at any distance, and who would be more interesting than a simple cube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A complete tab is dedicated to calculation of the shape of spheres, considering the horizontal radius, and vertical height of the ovoid. The height/width ratio is used to animate the creature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wall and ceiling rendering only used the gradient on 1 color, while excel allow 2 successive (not merged) gradient. Then, the enemies can be displayed in an other color. The value range bellow 0 can be used for this gradient, the value 0 being black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The progressive transparency appeared to be not harder than the smooth rendering of a sphere surface. The ray is getting the thickness of the sphere, the thicker making the pixel more colored.&lt;br/&gt;On the border of the sphere, the low thickness is only keeping the default value of the wall behind, with a negative factor to turn it on the color of monster. The light color filter providing a transparency on the border of the sphere.&lt;br/&gt;Once again, calculation are made on the horizontal plane, and the maximum calculations are prepared before finalizing the 3d calculation for each pixel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enemies behavior&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid a complex and unsatisfying procedural behavior, enemies does not react to the player action. Their position is determined only by the time, on a complex trajectory designed to provide no explicit pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep the position, speed, and all acceleration continuous (so the movement is fluid), the trajectory is a sort of finite fractal of a big circle, and small circular variations added on it. Ratio factor between circle (and even x/y ratio) are random an non-natural, so the trajectory never loop on itself. A separate sheet was made to display the trajectory to achieve a good random generator of deterministic trajectories.&lt;br/&gt;Since the trajectories cannot take account of walls, the ability of monster to go through walls is forced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several trajectories are then computed at each instant. The entire maze is populated by the same 10 enemies repeated on a grid with a sufficient distance so the player cannot see 2 instances of the same enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The repetition grid can be zoom in/zoom out to decrease/increase the enemy density. This should be made while taking great care of excessive resulting displacement of the monster, and effective speed due to scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we have a limited number of enemies to manage, these being copied everywhere in the maze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enemies attacks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The animation of the enemies is made using the radius/height ratio. Since the attack of the enemy should be clearly visible, and yet, slow enough for the player to be able to react, enemies simply increase in radius wether they have the player in sight. The grow follow an exponential function to simulate an explosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light of sight is calculated for each enemy in the radar tab, considering walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, the player simply get damage if it turn to be inside the radius of an enemy. It works the same is the player goes on purpose inside the enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This make the damage effect on the player a simple effect of negative color on the entire screen.&lt;br/&gt;An other effect is to cancel the rendering of any other enemy when the player get damaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The life of the player is one of the element of its status, which managed though steps like its position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Player attacks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each enemy get a status value, defining either its remaining life and attacking phase. For some values, enemies are simply not displayed, for some other, the enemy slowly regenerate, and the last one make the enemy explode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This simplified model allow the player to prevent attack by decreasing the life of the enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase the challenge, the player will have difficulties to aim a small enemy by staying at long range, and the ammunition will require reload action after a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On kill, the enemy simply turn into a slow regeneration state of inactivity. Since there are few enemies repeated everywhere, there cannot be a definitive elimination of one of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Death and rebi.. restart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the life of the player goes bellow 0, most of its actions are frozen, and the game-over screen appear.&lt;br/&gt;This screen is rendered using an other light shader, and a negative effect is made on color to keep with the idea of damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The progressive display of the &quot;game over&quot; message is achieved with small factor, which are elevated with an exponential function. This allow future pixels to stay hidden before appearing once the exponent is big enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, the slide down is a simple displacement of the light shader, which include some other message, like high score and restart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The score have to be written using pixels, with a very low resolution font.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restart generate new starting parameter, and send the player elsewhere at an other instant to avoid the player to meet the same enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 17:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>samfisher83</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/CBel/20180213/308549/3D_engine_entirely_made_of_MS_Excel_formulae__Enjoy_this_Doomxls_file_.php</og:url>
<og:title>3D engine entirely made of MS Excel formulae : Enjoy this Doom.xls file !</og:title>
<og:description>A 3D engine on MS Excel, using only excel formula. This engine is applied on a complete - yet basic - doom-like game. Rendering is made through ray casting, pixel per pixel. The exercice intend to demonstrate what can be done with formula only.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/CBel/20180213/308549/3D_engine_entirely_made_of_MS_Excel_formulae__Enjoy_this_Doomxls_file_.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Little Typer</title>
<link>https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-typer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-typer</guid>
<description>&lt;div tabindex=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;30.889364739472&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;l-tabs--left&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;tab-content__title&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An introduction to dependent types, demonstrating the most beautiful aspects, one step at a time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A program's type describes its behavior. Dependent types are a first-class part of a language, and are much more powerful than other kinds of types; using just one language for types and programs allows program descriptions to be as powerful as the programs they describe. &lt;em&gt;The Little Typer&lt;/em&gt; explains dependent types, beginning with a very small language that looks very much like Scheme and extending it to cover both programming with dependent types and using dependent types for mathematical reasoning. Readers should be familiar with the basics of a Lisp-like programming language, as presented in the first four chapters of &lt;em&gt;The Little Schemer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first five chapters of &lt;em&gt;The Little Typer&lt;/em&gt; provide the needed tools to understand dependent types; the remaining chapters use these tools to build a bridge between mathematics and programming. Readers will learn that tools they know from programming—pairs, lists, functions, and recursion—can also capture patterns of reasoning. &lt;em&gt;The Little Typer&lt;/em&gt; does not attempt to teach either practical programming skills or a fully rigorous approach to types. Instead, it demonstrates the most beautiful aspects as simply as possible, one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;l-tabs--right&quot; readability=&quot;6.6534653465347&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;tab-content__rail-title&quot;&gt;Paperback&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span property=&quot;price&quot;&gt;$38.00 S&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;ISBN: &lt;span property=&quot;isbn&quot;&gt;9780262536431&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span property=&quot;numPages&quot;&gt;424&lt;/span&gt; pp. | 9 in x 7 in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;23 b&amp;amp;w illus.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;time property=&quot;publishDate&quot; content=&quot;2018-09-18&quot;&gt;September 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div tabindex=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;36.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;l-tabs--left&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;tab-content__title--small&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;tab-content__title&quot;&gt;Daniel P. Friedman&lt;/h4&gt;
Daniel P. Friedman is Professor of Computer Science in the School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering at Indiana University and is the author of many books published by the MIT Press, including &lt;em&gt;The Little Schemer&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Seasoned Schemer&lt;/em&gt; (with Matthias Felleisen); &lt;em&gt;The Little Prover&lt;/em&gt; (with Carl Eastlund); and &lt;em&gt;The Reasoned Schemer&lt;/em&gt; (with William E. Byrd, Oleg Kiselyov, and Jason Hemann).
&lt;h4 class=&quot;tab-content__title&quot;&gt;David Thrane Christiansen&lt;/h4&gt;
David Thrane Christiansen is a member of the technical staff at Galois, Inc., in Portland, Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tab-content__section tab-content__section__contributors&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;tab-content__title--small&quot;&gt;Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Harper and Conor McBride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 16:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kakashi19</dc:creator>
<og:type>books.book</og:type>
<og:url>https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-typer</og:url>
<og:title>The Little Typer</og:title>
<og:description>An introduction to dependent types, demonstrating the most beautiful aspects, one step at a time. A program's type describes its behavior. Dependent types are a first-class part of a language, and are much more powerful than other kinds of types; using just one language for types and programs allows program descriptions to be as powerful as the programs they describe. The Little Typer explains dependent types, beginning with a very small language that looks very much like Scheme and extending it to cover both programming with dependent types and using dependent types for mathematical reasoning. Readers should be familiar with the basics of a Lisp-like programming language, as presented in the first four chapters of The Little Schemer. The first five chapters of The Little Typer provide the needed tools to understand dependent types; the remaining chapters use these tools to build a bridge between mathematics and programming. Readers will learn that tools they know from programming—pairs, lists, functions, and recursion—can also capture patterns of reasoning. The Little Typer does not attempt to teach either practical programming skills or a fully rigorous approach to types. Instead, it demonstrates the most beautiful aspects as simply as possible, one step at a time.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-typer</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>