<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>I Now Have a Cardiologist</title>
<link>https://joecieplinski.com/blog/2019/03/28/i-now-have-a-cardiologist/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://joecieplinski.com/blog/2019/03/28/i-now-have-a-cardiologist/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;With Apple’s release of watchOS 5.2, I see the ECG feature is now more widely available throughout Europe and other regions. That’s great news.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want to encourage those of you with Apple Watch devices in those supported regions to go grab the update and try out the ECG. Not just because it’s extremely cool tech. But because, well, let me put it this way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now have a cardiologist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That isn’t a statement I was planning to make in my forties. But there it is. And it’s only true because of Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me back up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last fall, when the ECG feature was finally released, I couldn’t wait to try it out. I’m a total geek for this sort of thing, and I believe health is &lt;em&gt;the next big thing&lt;/em&gt; as far as technology is concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t expecting to see anything other than good old-fashioned Sinus Rhythm. I didn’t know what a good heart rhythm was supposed to look like as it was being recorded, really. So I was just enjoying the cool animations, not noticing the strange pattern. Then the recording finished:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signs of Atrial Fibrillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm. That has to be a bug, right? Experimental new feature. Maybe I was shaking or moving my wrist a bit. So I try it again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signs of Atrial Fibrillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, I read the rest of the text more carefully. I didn’t write down the exact wording, but it read something like: “If this is a surprise, you should contact your doctor and talk about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now is a good point in the story to point out that at the time, I didn’t have a doctor. I’m an indie software consultant in his mid-forties, living in the US, the world’s worst industrialized country for health care. Since I don’t have a “job job,” I pay roughly $500 a month for “health insurance” out of my own pocket. But for most things, this insurance is essentially useless. My deductible is so high that pretty much any doctor visits I make are out of pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continue to pay for my insurance because thanks to the Affordable Care Act, I have to. It’s the law. And I’m okay with that. Because I know paying into the system helps others who make less money than me have access to care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that having this insurance also protects me against very serious costs from various serious illnesses, or accidents, etc. If I had &lt;em&gt;cancer&lt;/em&gt;, I’d eat through my deductible pretty quick. But that’s the thing. I’ve never really had &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; serious health issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s actually an understatement. With the exception of appendicitis when I was about 13, I haven’t been to the hospital since I was born. I’ve never had any drugs prescribed to me for more than a few weeks. I barely take aspirin when I get the occasional headache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I had my first &lt;em&gt;common cold&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;fifteen years&lt;/em&gt;. This is how &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; prone to health issues I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no need to go to a doctor beyond the occasional physical, is what I’m saying. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth noting at this point in the story that Atrial Fibrillation is extremely rare in men my age. Less than two percent of people in my demographic have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go figure. When I do something, I go big I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I found a primary care physician and set up an appointment for a routine physical. It had been a while, anyway. I asked him to take an ECG (an official one, with all the wires and stuff). That was going to cost me extra, as it’s not part of a routine physical, but I told him about the watch readings, and he agreed I should take a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results? While admitting he was no heart specialist, the primary care doc said my ECG results were definitely a bit of a concern. “Your heart is a little fast, and little irregular.” He was trying not to scare me. I wasn’t going to drop dead that day, but something was definitely up. My watch wasn’t lying to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then he sent me to the cardiologist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the cardiologist asked why I came in for a visit, I told him about my Apple Watch ECG. “I know, this is new tech. And maybe it’s not scientifically as accurate as the real thing, but it told me I should come in. And I thought I’d better not take a chance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doctor didn’t scoff. Quite the opposite, in fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh yeah? Can I see how it works?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was fascinated. I started up a new ECG reading, and within seconds, he said “Yep. That’s AFib.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persistent AFib, in my case. Over the course of the next month or so, as the doc prescribed some beta blockers and instructed me to continue monitoring my condition, I continued to take readings. No doubt about it. I was in a constant state of AFib. The doctor is still at a loss as to why. (I have none of the genetic indicators and no habits that would increase my chances of this happening. I just have a heart that wants to beat in odd time, as I’ve gotten into the habit of saying.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More alarmingly, I had very few symptoms that I could easily identify. I felt a bit more sluggish than usual (a direct result of my resting heart rate being in the 113-120 bpm range). But I’m not in the best shape, so sluggish isn’t exactly strange for me. I had the occasional discomfort in my chest. And even more occasionally, I’d feel my heart fluttering a bit, as if I had just watched a scene in a scary movie. But it would pass in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was enough to tell me that something was off, but probably not enough for me to go to a doctor. Seeing the watch reading definitely gave me the push I needed to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In trying to figure out when this condition may have started, the best we could conclude was sometime during the previous summer. It was post-WWDC; I was running betas of iOS and watchOS, as I was developing a new app and wanted to utilize some of the new notification and Siri features. (ECG wasn’t part of the beta.) Once or twice, while sitting on the couch watching tv, I got a notification on my watch saying my heart rate had suddenly jumped into the hundreds, with no indication of a change in activity on my part. I wrote it off as a beta bug, of course. That was certainly more likely than me having a heart condition. And it only happened once or twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cardiologist now thinks I was in AFib all the way back then. Almost six months before I made my first appointment. Maybe even earlier. That’s how subtle the symptoms were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, fast forward to this January. I had an echocardiogram done. (Basically a sonogram for your heart.) Other than the weird rhythm, my heart was perfectly normal. The fast beating and strange rhythm hadn’t caused any muscle or tissue damage—yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step was to get me out of persistent AFib. This involved what’s called an electro cardioversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with an electro cardioversion is that while it will zap the patient back into sinus rhythm in most cases, since we don’t know what caused the AFib, there’s every chance that it will come back in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it does come back, you can do the electro cardioversion again, but the next real step is something called a cardiac ablation, which involves sticking a probe up through your leg into your heart, and burning the areas where the incorrect electrical impulses are happening. When you hear the procedure described, it sounds super cool; then you realize it’s &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; heart they want to burn holes in. But hey, it does cure AFib permanently, with relatively low side-effect risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it’s all the same to you, though, I’d prefer to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, luckily, since my cardioversion in January, my heart has stayed in sinus rhythm. So I haven’t needed to go the ablation route yet. But that remains a possibility for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I’m off all prescriptions, and I’m taking ECGs with my watch regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All told, I’m several thousand dollars out of pocket, still not having hit my deductible, but my heart is doing what it’s supposed to, so I think I’ll call that a win. My useless insurance will become dramatically more expensive next year, while remaining just as useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still. A win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You have all you need to monitor this on your own” the cardiologist told me, pointing to my wrist. “So we’ll know if and when this ever comes back.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did my Apple Watch save my life? I think in my case, that’s a bit of an overstatement. I’ve seen a lot of the stories about people whose lives really have been saved by technology. I'm not in their league. My Apple Watch did help me discover a condition that would likely have gone untreated for a long while. I wasn’t going to die that afternoon. But I might have had a stroke (the most likely result of leaving AFib untreated) a few years down the line. So I’m very grateful to the team at Apple who added this functionality. If any of you are going to be at WWDC in San Jose this June, get in touch. I’d love to buy you all a drink and thank you in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen some news articles where certain doctors expressed concern that false positives from Apple Watches could lead to panic, with patients going to the emergency room needlessly, etc. To those doctors, I have two middle fingers I would happily like to extend. At no point did my watch give me any indication that I was in a true emergency. It just encouraged me to talk to a professional about what seemed to be abnormal heart rhythm. If I had gone to my doctor, and the official ECG had turned up completely normal, the worst thing I’d have to say is that I now had confirmation that my heart rhythm was normal. How could that be a bad thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ECG function in Apple Watch represents the best value for money I’ve ever spent in technology. There may only be a few people like me who are helped out by this, versus the millions who will just run the ECG for fun and get confirmation of their normal heart rhythms. But helping those few is totally worth it. Trust me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait to see even more functions built into wearable technology that will help diagnose even more conditions for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Cook believes Apple’s contributions to health will end up dwarfing everything else the company does, when looking back a hundred years from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have good reason to believe him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 01:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Aaronn</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>I Now Have a Cardiologist</og:title>
<og:description>With Apple’s release of watchOS 5.2, I see the ECG feature is now more widely available throughout Europe and other regions. That’s great news. I want to encourage those of you with Apple Watch devices in those supported regions to go grab the update and try out</og:description>
<og:url>http://joecieplinski.com/blog/2019/03/28/i-now-have-a-cardiologist/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://joecieplinski.com/blog/2019/03/28/i-now-have-a-cardiologist/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Bill Would Stop NSA’s Mass Collection of U.S. Phone Data</title>
<link>https://www.thedailybeast.com/wyden-paul-amash-lofgren-bill-would-stop-nsa-mass-collection-of-us-phone-data</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thedailybeast.com/wyden-paul-amash-lofgren-bill-would-stop-nsa-mass-collection-of-us-phone-data</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Since the 9/11 attacks, the National Security Agency has operated a dragnet of the phone records of hundreds of millions of Americans without specific suspicion of their involvement in terrorism. Almost 18 years later, civil-libertarian legislators from both parties are introducing a bill to abolish a vestige of one of the most infamous surveillance programs in American history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Ending Mass Collection of Americans’ Phone Records Act would remove any authority for the NSA and FBI to domestically collect phone records “other than those identified by the specific selection term included in [a warrant] application.” Sens. Rand Paul (R-Ky.) and Ron Wyden (D-Ore.) and Reps. Justin Amash (R-Mich.) and Zoe Lofgren (D-Calif.), four of Congress’ leading surveillance skeptics, unveiled the bill on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s time, finally, to put a stake in the heart of this unnecessary government surveillance program and start to restore some of Americans’ liberties,” Wyden said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, the bill would kill off what’s called the Call Detail Records program under an effort to restrict the domestic phone-data dragnet in the wake of Edward Snowden’s surveillance revelations. Before the so-called USA FREEDOM Act became law in 2015, some civil libertarians warned that its privacy protections, &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jun/05/edward-snowden-one-year-nsa-surveillance-reform&quot;&gt;watered down by intelligence officials and their allies&lt;/a&gt;, would prove &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/apr/17/surveillance-reform-usa-freedom-act-nsa-civil-libertarians&quot;&gt;inadequate&lt;/a&gt;. They turned out to be prescient: the FREEDOM Act led to &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/nsa-admits-it-improperly-collected-a-huge-amount-of-americans-call-records&quot;&gt;an overcollection of call data so massive&lt;/a&gt; that the NSA announced last it was deleting the entire FREEDOM Act trove, which included &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.dni.gov/files/documents/icotr/2018-ASTR----CY2017----FINAL-for-Release-5.4.18.pdf&quot;&gt;some 685 million phone records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote__quote&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“U.S. officials have conceded that the post-9/11 domestic phone-records dragnet has not stopped a single terrorist attack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The failure of the USA FREEDOM Act was &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/04/us/politics/nsa-phone-records-program-shut-down.html&quot;&gt;significant enough&lt;/a&gt; that the Trump administration “actually hasn’t been using it for the past six months,” a national-security aide to House Republican Leader Kevin McCarthy &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.lawfareblog.com/lawfare-podcast-luke-murry-and-daniel-silverberg-national-security-congress&quot;&gt;told the Lawfare podcast earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That apparent shutdown prompted speculation in surveillance-policy circles that the NSA might have either migrated its domestic phone-data dragnets under authorities outside of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA) – something the NSA &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/27/james-comey-justice-department-data-monitoring&quot;&gt;has repeatedly done with its post-9/11 warrantless surveillance efforts&lt;/a&gt; – or shut down the collection out of an assessment that analyzing call patterns at scale is an outmoded form of counterterrorism surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, however, U.S. officials have conceded that the post-9/11 domestic phone-records dragnet &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jan/23/nsa-barack-obama-phone-data-collection-illegal-privacy-board&quot;&gt;has not stopped a single terrorist attack&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/18/nsa-surveillance-limited-focused-hearing&quot;&gt;despite misleadingly suggesting otherwise&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/06/nsa-phone-records-verizon-court-order&quot;&gt;The Guardian exposed the surveillance in June 2013&lt;/a&gt;, thanks to Snowden. In 2015, a federal appeals court ruled &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/may/07/nsa-phone-records-program-illegal-court&quot;&gt;that the bulk collection of Americans’ phone data was illegal&lt;/a&gt;, adding momentum to the USA FREEDOM Act, whose provisions expire on Dec 15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The director of the NSA has equivocated on the importance of retaining the domestic phone-records dragnet. “We’re in a deliberative process right now,” Gen. Paul Nakasone &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/nsa-chief-hedges-on-future-of-phone-surveillance-dragnet&quot;&gt;told the RSA Conference in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; on Mar. 6. “We will work very, very closely with the administration and Congress.”   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, privacy advocates on Capitol Hill see a rare opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, the balance of legislative forces favor preserving wide-ranging authorities for NSA surveillance. Despite then-Sen. Barack Obama’s criticisms of “&lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;http://archive.boston.com/news/politics/2008/specials/CandidateQA/ObamaQA/&quot;&gt;unlawful and unconstitutional&lt;/a&gt;” surveillance by the Bush administration, Obama &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.govtrack.us/congress/votes/110-2008/s168&quot;&gt;voted&lt;/a&gt; for what would prove to be a seminal NSA authority for collecting &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/06/us-tech-giants-nsa-data&quot;&gt;massive amounts of Internet, email and other digital records&lt;/a&gt;, including from Americans’ international communications. Despite President Donald Trump’s heated criticisms of the intelligence agencies, that authority, known as FISA Section 702, &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/president-trump-threatens-nsa-mass-surveillance-with-a-tweet&quot;&gt;survived a 2018 reauthorization battle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Call Detail Records program created by the USA FREEDOM Act – one that outsourced much of the surveillance activity to telecommunications companies in a cumbersome way – never had substantial support, even before the revelations of the overcollection and subsequent purge and shutdown. While civil libertarians, having lived through numerous legislative defeats since 9/11, are wary of overconfidence, one congressional aide contended that “there’s a clear path forward for abolishing this program.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amash, who &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jul/25/nsa-surveillance-amash-amendment-narrow-defeat&quot;&gt;led the charge in the House of Representatives&lt;/a&gt; to constrain the NSA after the Snowden revelations, said in a statement: “Getting rid of this program will vindicate Americans’ rights and begin the process of making the broader PATRIOT Act reforms that are going to be necessary to address the law’s serious constitutional flaws.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 23:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JumpCrisscross</dc:creator>
<og:title>New Bill Would Finally Stop NSA’s Mass Collection of U.S. Phone Data</og:title>
<og:description>The surveillance giant shut down its flawed dragnet last year. Four legislators are trying to stop one of the security state’s most infamous post-9/11 programs from returning.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.thedailybeast.com/wyden-paul-amash-lofgren-bill-would-stop-nsa-mass-collection-of-us-phone-data</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://img.thedailybeast.com/image/upload/c_crop,d_placeholder_euli9k,h_1687,w_3000,x_0,y_0/dpr_2.0/c_limit,w_740/fl_lossy,q_auto/v1553796696/190328-nsa-tease_s7vwne</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thedailybeast.com/wyden-paul-amash-lofgren-bill-would-stop-nsa-mass-collection-of-us-phone-data</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Miss Rails</title>
<link>https://chanind.github.io/rails/2019/03/28/why-i-miss-rails.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://chanind.github.io/rails/2019/03/28/why-i-miss-rails.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The world of tech moves fast, and there’s always new frameworks and paradigms popping up that make developers’ lives easier and allow us to build more and more powerful applications. But, these transitions don’t always just make things better for developers - sometimes we take steps backwards and undo the progress we made in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know Rails isn’t universally beloved by developers, and I’m not suggesting that we give up React and es7 and go back to writing server-templated web-apps like it’s 2012 again. However, I do think that in the transition to the modern web stack (something like React / nodejs / graphql / etc), we’ve unsolved some of what tools like Rails made easy 10 years ago - and I don’t think it needs to be that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rails took all the boilerplate that comes with building any web application and make it trivial to implement. Since Rails owned the whole application stack, it was easy for the community to contribute plugins that would add any typical functionality you may need. Do you need user accounts with signup / login / forgot password emails / email confirmation? Install devise and you’re done. Do you want to be able to upload images, resize them, and upload them to s3? Great - install paperclip and you’re done. Need to index your data in elasticsearch or sphinx? Easy - just install a rails plugin to do that. Do you need Google and Facebook login? Cool - install omniauth and you’re done. Do you want to clean up your tests using factories? Install factory-girl and everything just works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compare that to the state of the typical web stack now, with something like a nodejs / typescript graphql backend and React / Apollo on the frontend. There’s no longer a standardized way to get user accounts with a login/signup, forgot password and email confirmation flow, despite every application needing it, so instead we need to spend days rewriting this functionality anew on each project. Users need a way to change their account info? Get ready to spend a day working on a standard account settings page. Want to allow users to upload avatar images? Spend a day writing an image upload, resize, push to s3 flow from scratch. Do you want to add a search engine? Great - spend a day writing the code to index and search your documents from scratch. Need to add Google login? Get ready to spend another day on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these things that used to be easy in Rails take a fair bit of manual effort today because there’s not a standardized setup and eco-system. We’re spending a lot of time re-solving all these boilerplate issues that every web app needs and everyone has already solved countless times before. Part of this may be inevitable now that there’s both web and mobile frontends to think about, but I think the majority of the problem is just a result of fragmetation in the modern ecosystem. It’s no longer possible to make libraries that automatically handle all the glue code of integration into our apps because there’s no standard setup at all anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, there are some good attempts at unified frameworks out there. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meteor.com/&quot;&gt;Meteor&lt;/a&gt; was the closest the JS world has come to something like Rails, but may have come too early and missed the graphQL / React / Typescript wave. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt; is amazing as well, and is the closest project I’ve seen to what Rails used to provide, but it only generates static sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hopeful that a framework will emerge that can be the Rails of the modern web stack. Gatsby and Meteor show that it’s possible. And if the modern equivalent of Rails already exists, please let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 23:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chanind</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why I miss Rails</og:title>
<og:description>The world of tech moves fast, and there’s always new frameworks and paradigms popping up that make developers’ lives easier and allow us to build more and more powerful applications. But, these transitions don’t always just make things better for developers - sometimes we take steps backwards and undo the progress we made in the past.</og:description>
<og:url>https://chanind.github.io/rails/2019/03/28/why-i-miss-rails.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://chanind.github.io/rails/2019/03/28/why-i-miss-rails.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lyft prices IPO at top of range</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/28/lyft-prices-ipo-at-top-of-range/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/28/lyft-prices-ipo-at-top-of-range/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/lyft&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;lyft&quot;&gt;Lyft&lt;/a&gt; raised more than $2 billion Thursday afternoon after pricing its shares at $72 apiece, the top of the expected range of $70 to $72 per share. This gives Lyft a fully diluted market value of $24 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company will debut on the Nasdaq stock exchange Friday morning, trading under the ticker symbol “LYFT.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial public offering is the first-ever for a ride-hailing business and represents a landmark liquidity event for private market investors, which had invested billions of dollars in the San Francisco-based company. In total, Lyft had raised $5.1 billion in debt and equity funding, reaching a valuation of $15.1 billion last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyft’s blockbuster IPO is unique for a number of reasons, in addition to being amongst transportation-as-a-service companies to transition from private to public. Lyft has the largest net losses of any pre-IPO business, posting losses of $911 million on revenues of $2.2 billion in 2018. However, the company is also raking in the largest revenues, behind only Google and Facebook, for a pre-IPO company. The latter has made it popular on Wall Street, garnering buy ratings from analysts prior to pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber is the next tech unicorn, or company valued north of $1 billion, expected out of the IPO gate. It will trade on the New York Stock Exchange in what is one of the most anticipated IPOs in history. The company, which reported $3 billion in Q4 2018 revenues with net losses of $865 million, is reportedly planning to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/14/uber-will-reportedly-file-for-ipo-next-month/&quot;&gt;unveil its IPO prospectus&lt;/a&gt; next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next in the pipeline is Pinterest, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/22/pinterest-drops-its-ipo-filing/&quot;&gt;dropped its S-1&lt;/a&gt; last week and revealed a path to profitability that is sure to garner support from Wall Street investors. The visual search engine will trade on the NYSE under the symbol “PINS.” It posted revenue of $755.9 million last year, up from $472.8 million in 2017. The company’s net loss, meanwhile, shrank to $62.9 million last year from $130 million in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other notable companies planning 2019 stock offerings include Slack, Zoom — &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/22/zoom-a-profitable-unicorn-files-to-go-public/&quot;&gt;a rare, profitable pre-IPO unicorn&lt;/a&gt; — and, potentially, Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updating&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 21:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jkw</dc:creator>
<og:title>Lyft prices IPO at top of range</og:title>
<og:description>Lyft begins trading on the Nasdaq under the ticker symbol &quot;LYFT&quot; tomorrow.</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-909455640.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/03/28/lyft-prices-ipo-at-top-of-range/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/28/lyft-prices-ipo-at-top-of-range/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An amphibian fungus has become “the most deadly pathogen known”</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/28/science/frogs-fungus-bd.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/28/science/frogs-fungus-bd.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;On Thursday, 41 scientists published the first worldwide analysis of a fungal outbreak that’s been wiping out frogs for decades. The devastation &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/cgi/doi/10.1126/science.aav0379&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;turns out to be far worse than anyone had previously realized&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Writing in the journal Science, the researchers conclude that populations of more than 500 species of amphibians have declined significantly because of the outbreak — including at least 90 species presumed to have gone extinct. The figure is more than twice as large as earlier estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“That’s fairly seismic,” said Wendy Palen, a biologist at Simon Fraser University who is a co-author of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/cgi/doi/10.1126/science.aax0002&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a commentary accompanying the study&lt;/a&gt;. “It now earns the moniker of the most deadly pathogen known to science.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;[&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://on.fb.me/1paTQ1h&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Like the Science Times page on Facebook.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;| Sign up for the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1MbHaRU&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Science Times newsletter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Scientists first noticed in the 1970s that some frog populations were declining quickly; by the 1980s, some species appeared to be extinct. The losses were puzzling, because the frogs were living in pristine habitats, unharmed by pollution or deforestation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In the late 1990s, researchers discovered that frogs in both Australia and Panama &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pnas.org/content/95/15/9031&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;were infected with a deadly fungus&lt;/a&gt;, which they named Batrachochytrium dendrobatidis &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;—&lt;/em&gt; Bd, for short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The fungus turned up in other countries, but studies of its DNA suggest that Bd &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/10/science/frogs-fungus-korea.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;originated on the Korean Peninsula&lt;/a&gt;. In Asia, amphibians seem impervious to Bd, but when it got to other parts of the world — probably via the international trade in pet amphibians — the pathogen reached hundreds of vulnerable species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Amphibians are infected with Bd by contact with other animals or by spores floating in the water. The fungus invades skin cells and multiplies. An infected frog’s skin will start to peel away as the animal grows sluggish. Before it dies, a frog may manage to hop its way to a new stream or pond, spreading the fungus further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2007, researchers speculated that Bd &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10393-007-0093-5&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;might be responsible for all known declines of frogs&lt;/a&gt; that had no other apparent cause — about 200 species. For the most part, however, scientists studied Bd at the local level, looking at its impacts on particular species in particular places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We knew that frogs were dying all around the world, but no one had gone back to the start and actually assessed what the impact was,” said Benjamin Scheele, an ecologist at Australian National University and the lead author of the new study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2015, Dr. Scheele and his colleagues gathered data from over 1,000 published papers on Bd, and traveled around the world to meet with experts and hear their unpublished observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Not only did the team analyze data on living amphibians, but they also looked at data from museums, where scientists found Bd DNA embedded in preserved specimens tucked away in cabinets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The new study showed that some amphibians are at greater risk than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The fungus thrives in cool, moist conditions. As a result, frogs that live in cloud forests on mountainsides have been hit particularly hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/28/science/28SCI-ZIMMER/28SCI-ZIMMER-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/28/science/28SCI-ZIMMER/28SCI-ZIMMER-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/28/science/28SCI-ZIMMER/28SCI-ZIMMER-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/28/science/28SCI-ZIMMER/28SCI-ZIMMER-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1644w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/28/science/28SCI-ZIMMER/28SCI-ZIMMER-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Espada’s marsupial frog, near the Gocta Waterfall in the Chachapoyas province of Peru.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tiffany Kosch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Big frogs are at a greater risk, too, possibly because they don’t multiply as quickly as small ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Dr. Scheele and his colleagues identified 501 species in decline, far greater than the previous estimate of 200. Certain factors once thought to account for the decimation of frog populations — like climate change and deforestation — are not the greatest threats, the scientists found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“A lot of those hypotheses have been discredited,” said Dr. Scheele. “And the more we find out about the fungus, the more it fits with the pattern.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As it turns out, Bd wiped out some species long before it was discovered. Only by going back to museum specimens were scientists able to estimate the toll. “It’s scary that so many species can become extinct without us knowing,” said Dr. Scheele.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The decimation of frogs peaked in the 1980s, the researchers found, a decade before the discovery of Bd. Today, 39 percent of the species that suffered population declines in the past are still declining. Twelve percent are showing signs of recovery, possibly because natural selection is favoring resistant animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As dire as the study’s results turned out to be, Dr. Scheele is guardedly optimistic about future wildlife outbreaks. The element of surprise may have had a lot to do with Bd’s devastating success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It wasn’t expected or predicted, and so it took the research community a long time to catch up,” said Dr. Scheele.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2013, researchers discovered that a related fungus was attacking fire salamanders in Belgium. Called Batrachochytrium salamandrivorans (Bsal for short), it seemed &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/08/04/science/importing-both-salamanders-and-their-potential-destruction.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;poised to do to salamanders what Bd has done to frogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But this time, things are playing out differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Researchers discovered the outbreak and identified Bsal quickly. They immediately began running experiments to understand the threat it posed. Thanks to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/13/science/us-restricts-movement-of-salamanders-for-their-own-good.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;barriers to trade now in place&lt;/a&gt;, Bsal has yet to threaten another species anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We’ve learned, and we’re dealing with it better,” said Dr. Scheele. “I guess the question is always, ‘Are we doing enough?’ And that’s debatable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;There’s still plenty of reason to worry about outbreaks to come. Bd has yet to reach New Guinea, home to a wealth of amphibian species found nowhere else on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;If a Bd-infected frog got there — through the pet trade, or as an accidental stowaway — the fungus would have a vast number of vulnerable hosts to attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It could be a meltdown of the ecosystems over there,” said Daniel Greenberg, a graduate student at Simon Fraser University and co-author of the Science commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The loss of frogs can alter entire ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Without tadpoles to guzzle algae, blooms may choke streams. Without frogs to eat insects, some disease-carrying species may become more common. Birds and other predators that eat frogs have to find alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Scientists are not even resting easy about the species that have emerged intact from the Bd assault. Another strain of Bd, or some different species of fungus altogether, may prove to be even deadlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It’s just Russian roulette, with moving pathogens around the world,” said Dr. Scheele.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-g92qtk epkadsg3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1owp1gq epkadsg0&quot;&gt;Earlier reporting on frogs under threat&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-15g2oxy epkadsg2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-2b3w4o e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1hma5rr e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;Frog-Killing Fungus Found to Have Origins on Korean Peninsula&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1yil5bp e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-05-10&quot;&gt;May 10, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/05/15/science/11TB-FUNGUS1/11TB-FUNGUS1-threeByTwoSmallAt2X.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-2b3w4o e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1hma5rr e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;A Few Species of Frogs That Vanished May Be on the Rebound&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1yil5bp e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-03-29&quot;&gt;March 29, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/04/03/science/30Zimmer-1/30Zimmer-1-threeByTwoSmallAt2X.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-2b3w4o e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1hma5rr e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;Frogs That Escaped Extinction&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1yil5bp e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-05-26&quot;&gt;May 26, 2016&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2016/05/27/science/27tb-frogs1/27tb-frogs1-videoLarge.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-2b3w4o e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1hma5rr e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;A Reprieve for Fungus-Battered Frogs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1yil5bp e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-01-04&quot;&gt;Jan. 4, 2016&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2016/01/05/science/05FUNG/0105-SCI-FUNG-videoLarge.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 18:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jchanimal</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/28/science/frogs-fungus-bd.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Plague Killing Frogs Everywhere Is Far Worse Than Scientists Thought</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/02/science/28SCI-ZIMMER1/28SCI-ZIMMER1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>As a threat to wildlife, an amphibian fungus has become “the most deadly pathogen known to science.”</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/28/science/frogs-fungus-bd.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lucet: Native WebAssembly Compiler and Runtime</title>
<link>https://www.fastly.com/blog/announcing-lucet-fastly-native-webassembly-compiler-runtime</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.fastly.com/blog/announcing-lucet-fastly-native-webassembly-compiler-runtime</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we are thrilled to announce the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fastly/lucet&quot; title=&quot;Lucet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;open sourcing of Lucet&lt;/a&gt;, Fastly’s native WebAssembly compiler and runtime. WebAssembly is a technology created to enable web browsers to safely execute programs at near-native speeds. It has been shipping in the four major browsers since early 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucet is designed to take WebAssembly beyond the browser, and build a platform for faster, safer execution on Fastly’s edge cloud. WebAssembly is already supported by many languages including Rust, TypeScript, C, and C++, and many more have WebAssembly support in development. We want to enable our customers to go beyond &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fastly.com/vcl/&quot; title=&quot;VCL&quot;&gt;Fastly VCL&lt;/a&gt; and move even more logic to the edge, and use any language they choose. Lucet is the engine behind Terrarium, our experimental platform for edge computation using WebAssembly. Soon, we will make it available on Fastly’s edge cloud as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major design requirement for Lucet was to be able to execute on every single request that Fastly handles. That means creating a WebAssembly instance for each of the tens of thousands of requests per second in a single process, which requires a dramatically lower runtime footprint than possible with a browser JavaScript engine. Lucet can instantiate WebAssembly modules in under 50 microseconds, with just a few kilobytes of memory overhead. By comparison, Chromium’s V8 engine takes about 5 milliseconds, and tens of megabytes of memory overhead, to instantiate JavaScript or WebAssembly programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Lucet, Fastly’s edge cloud can execute tens of thousands of WebAssembly programs simultaneously, in the same process, without compromising security. The Lucet compiler and runtime work together to ensure each WebAssembly program is allowed access to only its own resources. This means that Fastly’s customers will be able to write and run programs in more common, general-purpose languages, without compromising the security and safety we’ve always offered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucet separates responsibility for executing WebAssembly into two components: a compiler, which compiles WebAssembly modules to native code, and a runtime which manages resources and traps runtime faults. Lucet is designed for ahead-of-time (AOT) compilation of WebAssembly to native code, which dramatically simplifies the design and overhead of the runtime compared to the just-in-time (JIT) compilation strategy employed in browser engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How we built Lucet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucet is built on top of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CraneStation/cranelift&quot; title=&quot;Cranelift code generator&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Cranelift code generator&lt;/a&gt;. The Cranelift project was created by Mozilla for use in Firefox’s WebAssembly and JavaScript JIT engines, and presently can be enabled by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/9mvnrk/in_firefox_nightly_an_option_has_arrived_to_use/&quot; title=&quot;Reddit Firefox Nightly&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;preference flag in Firefox Nightly&lt;/a&gt;. We &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CraneStation/cranelift/graphs/contributors&quot; title=&quot;Cranelift Github&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;contributed&lt;/a&gt; to the design and implementation of Cranelift, and are excited that our efforts help make the web better for Firefox users as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucet supports the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wasi.dev&quot; title=&quot;WASI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;WebAssembly System Interface (WASI)&lt;/a&gt; — a new proposed standard for safely exposing low-level interfaces to the filesystem, networking, and other system facilities to WebAssembly programs. The Lucet team has partnered with Mozilla and others on the design, implementation, and standardization of this system interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been working on this project behind the scenes since 2017, so we’re thrilled to finally make it public. Lucet also happens to be the first project started at Fastly using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/&quot; title=&quot;Rust&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Rust programming language&lt;/a&gt;, and we’re happy to report that Rust has been a huge success on this project. We found that new Rust users were able to become productive with the language quickly, and the library ecosystem provides many mature libraries for working with WebAssembly. Early in Lucet’s development, we implemented the first version of the runtime in C. However, we recently went back and translated the C runtime into Rust, and in the process, discovered and fixed several safety and concurrency bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the engine behind the Terrarium project, Lucet has gotten months of production testing, running many thousands of different WebAssembly programs since launching in late 2018. It has also been the subject of an in-depth third-party security assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A quick demo of Lucet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, clone the Lucet repository from GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$ git clone --recurse-submodules https://github.com/fastly/lucet&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fastly/lucet/blob/master/README.md&quot; title=&quot;README&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; contains instructions on using Docker to setup a development environment. If you already have Docker installed, there is just one step. It may take a few minutes to complete building everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ cd lucet  
$ source devenv_setenv.sh
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, lets create a small C program, and use Clang to compile it to WebAssembly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ mkdir demo
$ cd demo
$ cat &amp;gt; hello.c &amp;lt;&amp;lt;EOT

#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;
int main(int argc, char* argv[])
{
    if (argc &amp;gt; 1) {
            printf(&quot;Hello from Lucet, %s!\n&quot;, argv[1]);
    } else {
            puts(&quot;Hello, world!&quot;);
    }
    return 0;
}
EOT
$ wasm32-unknown-wasi-clang hello.c -o hello.wasm
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can compile the WebAssembly to native code, using the Lucet compiler, configured for use with WASI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$ lucetc-wasi hello.wasm -o hello.so&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we can execute the native code using the Lucet runtime configured for use with WASI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ lucet-wasi hello.so  
Hello, world!  
$ lucet-wasi hello.so world  
Hello from Lucet, world!  
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation and additional examples are available in the Lucet repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Beyond the edge cloud&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to open source Lucet because of all the possibilities WebAssembly holds beyond the web browser and edge cloud. For instance, Lucet’s support for WASI is a big step towards WebAssembly programs that can run on whatever platform the user wants — in the cloud, at the edge, on the browser, or natively on your laptop or smartphone — all while keeping the same strong guarantees about security in place. We want to enable WebAssembly to thrive inside any program that allows scripting or extensions, while using fewer resources than current solutions built on dynamic languages, interpreters, and JIT compilers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, we want to collaborate with the open-source community on Lucet, Cranelift, WASI, and other WebAssembly-enabling technologies. Fastly is built on, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastly.com/open-source&quot; title=&quot;Open source&quot;&gt;committed to supporting&lt;/a&gt;, open source. Without it, we could never have built Lucet — and we hope that Lucet allows you to build new things that we haven’t even dreamed of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span data-swiftype-index=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;You may also like:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;cards&quot; readability=&quot;18.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;card__article&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;newsletter-form-content&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;&gt;Subscribe to our newsletter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;&gt;Get the latest news and industry insights in your inbox.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;newsletter-form-confirm&quot; class=&quot;hide&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;Subscribe to our newsletter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;Thanks for subscribing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;/&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;card__article&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;&gt;Memory management in WebAssembly: guide for C and Rust programmers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;&gt;Recently we launched Fastly Terrarium, a multi-language, browser-based editor and deployment platform where you can experiment with edge technology. Now, for those well-versed in C and Rust, we’ll explore WebAssembly memory management and implementation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;/&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;card__article&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;&gt;Edge programming with Rust and WebAssembly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;&gt;Take a developer deep dive into Terrarium, our multi-language, browser-based editor and deployment platform at the edge. Learn how to compile Rust programs to WebAssembly right on your local machine, interact with the Terrarium system,…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;/&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;card__article&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;&gt;How Terrarium reframes the compiler and sandbox relationship&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;card&quot;&gt;Get hands-on with Terrarium, a Fastly project that lets developers harness the power of edge computing in the languages they already use. See how this technology demonstration came to be (and why we’re even using…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blog-authors&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;6.5759162303665&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.fastly.com/cimages/6pk8mg3yh2ee/5Mo709jMas0gIi2WMsmQ6K/14662889605f1ad566bcc03a5699ca4b/pat-hickey.jpg?width=150&amp;amp;height=150&amp;amp;fit=crop&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bio&quot; readability=&quot;9.0418848167539&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastly.com/blog/pat-hickey&quot;&gt;Pat Hickey | Sr. software engineer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pat Hickey is a senior software engineer on Fastly’s isolation team. Previously, he worked on operating systems and compilers for safety-critical systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 17:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kickdaddy</dc:creator>
<og:title>Announcing Lucet: Fastly’s native WebAssembly compiler and runtime</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.fastly.com/blog/announcing-lucet-fastly-native-webassembly-compiler-runtime/</og:url>
<og:description>Today, we’re thrilled to announce the open sourcing of Lucet, our native WebAssembly compiler and runtime. WebAssembly is a technology created to enable web browsers to safely execute programs at near-native speeds, and it’s been shipping in the four major browsers since early 2017.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.fastly.com/cimages/6pk8mg3yh2ee/4RGJh4DHD4HX2Zpa2NY1h8/87fe66f5db89c1f1b105c6306b4f2e3a/social_header_image_lucet.jpg?canvas=1200:630&amp;width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=FFFFFF</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.fastly.com/blog/announcing-lucet-fastly-native-webassembly-compiler-runtime</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The FCC has fined robocallers $208M and collected $7k</title>
<link>https://www.foxnews.com/tech/the-fcc-has-fined-robocallers-208-million-its-collected-6790</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.foxnews.com/tech/the-fcc-has-fined-robocallers-208-million-its-collected-6790</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;speakable&quot;&gt;America’s telecommunications watchdogs have levied hefty financial penalties against illegal robocallers and demanded that bad actors repay millions to their victims. But years later, little money has been collected.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;speakable&quot;&gt;Since 2015, the Federal Communications Commission has ordered violators of the Telephone Consumer Protection Act, a law governing telemarketing and robodialing, to pay $208.4 million. That sum includes so-called forfeiture orders in cases involving robocalling, Do Not Call Registry and telephone solicitation violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foxnews.com/tech/palantir-wins-800-million-army-contract-for-battlefield-intelligence-system&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PALANTIR WINS $800M CONTRACT FOR ARMY'S BATTLEFIELD INTELLIGENCE SYSTEM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, the government has collected $6,790 of that amount, according to records obtained by The Wall Street Journal through a Freedom of Information Act request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total amount of money secured by the Federal Trade Commission through court judgments in cases involving civil penalties for robocalls or National Do Not Call Registry-related violations, plus the sum requested for consumer redress in fraud-related cases, is $1.5 billion since 2004. It has collected $121 million of that total, said Ian Barlow, coordinator of the agency’s Do Not Call program, or about 8%. The agency operates the National Do Not Call Registry and regulates telemarketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That number stands on its own. We’re proud of it; we think our enforcement program is pretty strong,” Mr. Barlow said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An FCC spokesman said his agency lacks the authority to enforce the forfeiture orders it issues and has passed all unpaid penalties to the Justice Department, which has the power to collect the fines. Many of the spoofers and robocallers the agency tries to punish are individuals and small operations, he added, which means they are at times unable to pay the full penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Fines serve to penalize bad conduct and deter future misconduct,” the FCC spokesman said. A spokeswoman for the Justice Department, which can settle or drop cases, declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foxnews.com/tech/facebook-bans-white-nationalism-and-white-separatism&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FACEBOOK BANS WHITE NATIONALISM AND WHITE SEPARATISM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dearth of financial penalties collected by the U.S. government for violations of telemarketing and auto-dialing rules shows the limits the sister regulators face in putting a stop to illegal robocalls. It also shows why the threat of large fines can fail to deter bad actors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s great that we have these laws; it’s great that we have public enforcement, but because there are so many calls and so many callers, the public enforcement is a joke,” said Margot Saunders, senior counsel at consumer advocacy group National Consumer Law Center. “It doesn’t even make a dent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were 26.3 billion unwanted robocalls made to U.S. mobile phones in 2018, by one measure from robocall-blocking app Hiya. Another company that offers such services, YouMail Inc., puts the number of unwanted and illegal robocalls made in the U.S. last year even higher, at nearly 48 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-fcc-has-fined-robocallers-208-million-its-collected-6-790-11553770803&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more of this story at The Wall Street Journal, where it was first published. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 17:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mudil</dc:creator>
<og:title>The FCC has fined robocallers $208 million. It's collected $6,790.</og:title>
<og:description>America’s telecommunications watchdogs have levied hefty financial penalties against illegal robocallers and demanded that bad actors repay millions to their victims. But years later, little money has been collected.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2018/09/robocall.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.foxnews.com/tech/the-fcc-has-fined-robocallers-208-million-its-collected-6790</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.foxnews.com/tech/the-fcc-has-fined-robocallers-208-million-its-collected-6790</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The World’s Cheapest Hospital Has to Get Even Cheaper</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-03-26/the-world-s-cheapest-hospital-has-to-get-even-cheaper</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-03-26/the-world-s-cheapest-hospital-has-to-get-even-cheaper</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-03-26/the-world-s-cheapest-hospital-has-to-get-even-cheaper&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-03-26/the-world-s-cheapest-hospital-has-to-get-even-cheaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19513912&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19513912&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 203&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 186&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 16:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=efa77cf0-523b-11e9-9e75-4fcc3a0ec85b&amp;url=L25ld3MvZmVhdHVyZXMvMjAxOS0wMy0yNi90aGUtd29ybGQtcy1jaGVhcGVzdC1ob3NwaXRhbC1oYXMtdG8tZ2V0LWV2ZW4tY2hlYXBlcg==</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Internal Documents Show Apple Is Capable of Implementing Right to Repair</title>
<link>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/d3mqna/internal-documents-show-apple-is-capable-of-implementing-right-to-repair-legislation</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/d3mqna/internal-documents-show-apple-is-capable-of-implementing-right-to-repair-legislation</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As Apple &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/nz85y7/apple-is-lobbying-against-your-right-to-repair-iphones-new-york-state-records-confirm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;continues to fight legislation&lt;/a&gt; that would make it easier for consumers to repair their iPhones, MacBooks, and other electronics, the company appears to be able to implement many of the requirements of the legislation, according to an internal presentation obtained by Motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the presentation, titled “Apple Genuine Parts Repair” and dated April 2018, the company has begun to give some repair companies access to Apple diagnostic software, a wide variety of genuine Apple repair parts, repair training, and notably places no restrictions on the types of repairs that independent companies are allowed to do. The presentation notes that repair companies can “keep doing what you’re doing, with … Apple genuine parts, reliable parts supply, and Apple process and training.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is, broadly speaking, what &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/nex3dz/insurance-giant-allstate-buys-icracked-phone-repair-company-joins-right-to-repair-movement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;right to repair activists&lt;/a&gt; have been asking state legislators to require companies to offer for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This looks to me like a framework for complying with right to repair legislation,” Kyle Wiens, CEO of iFixit and a prominent member of the right to repair movement, told me on the phone. “Right now, they are only offering it to a few megachains, but it seems clear to me that it would be totally possible to comply with right to repair.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1553537098400-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-20443-PM.png?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1553537098400-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-20443-PM&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1553537098400-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-20443-PM.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manufacturers across the board—including &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/kz5qgw/california-farm-bureau-john-deere-tractor-hacking-right-to-repair&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tractor companies like John Deere&lt;/a&gt;, appliance &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbxk3b/appliance-companies-are-lobbying-against-right-to-repair&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;companies like LG&lt;/a&gt;, and tech companies like Apple, Microsoft, and Samsung—have slowly but surely monopolized the repair of their devices by implementing software that prevents repair, “authorized repair” programs, and by tightly controlling the sale of replacement parts to independent companies. Right to repair legislation that has been introduced in 20 states would return access to consumer goods to the consumers themselves by requiring electronics manufacturers to sell replacement parts and repair tools to independent repair shops and the general public. It would also require them to make internal repair guides and diagnostic tools public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1553536700485-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-15743-PM.png?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1553536700485-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-15743-PM&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1553536700485-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-15743-PM.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple, John Deere, and the trade organizations that represent them have lobbied against this legislation all over the country over the past few years and have thus far been able to prevent any bills from becoming the law of the land. In the past, for example, Apple’s lobbyists told a Nebraska state lawmaker that the legislation &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/pgxgpg/apple-tells-lawmaker-that-right-to-repair-iphones-will-turn-nebraska-into-a-mecca-for-hackers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;would turn the state into a “Mecca” for hackers and “bad actors&lt;/a&gt;.” A letter obtained by Motherboard that was sent last month to a Georgia lawmaker by 17 trade organizations that represent consumer tech, video game, wireless, home appliance, and air conditioning companies (including Apple) says that right to repair legislation “threatens consumer security and safety” and “stifles innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internal Apple presentation does not say who the company plans on rolling out its program to, but it notes that there are “3,700+ Apple Authorized Service Providers” and shows photos of four repair chains: Mobile Kangaroo, based in California; AA Mac, based in the United Kingdom; Simply Mac, based in Salt Lake City, Utah; and Makina Technologies, based in Dubai. Mobile Kangaroo, AA Mac, and Makina Technologies all say that they have “access to Apple diagnostic tools” on their websites, suggesting that it has already been rolled out to these companies. Mobile Kangaroo told me in an email that it recently got &quot;premium status&quot; from Apple but did not answer questions about the Apple Genuine Parts Repair presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple did not respond to a request for comment, and neither did Makina Technologies, AA Mac, or Simply Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program described in Apple’s presentation is different from Apple’s standard Authorized Service Provider program, which allows repair companies to only complete specific, Apple-approved repairs; harder repairs require those companies to mail the phone back to Apple for service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Apple authorized technicians can switch out screens and batteries and they essentially can’t do anything else,” Nathan Proctor, who is leading consumer rights group US PIRG’s right to repair campaign, told me on the phone. “Reversing that policy to let them do more standard repairs is a step toward right to repair and evidence that the people working on this issue have forced them to change.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1553536718224-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-15730-PM.png?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1553536718224-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-15730-PM&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1553536718224-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-15730-PM.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internal Apple presentation undercuts many of the arguments that electronics industry lobbyists have made, namely ones that note that repair is too difficult for any “unauthorized” people to do or that argue the security of products could be undermined by giving diagnostic tools to independent companies. Apple executives have in the past argued that &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/xwgg8z/apple-iphones-are-too-complex-to-allow-unauthorized-repair&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iPhones are too &quot;complex&quot;&lt;/a&gt; for the company to open its repair supply chain. The presentation, however, notes that people outside of Apple are perfectly capable of doing good repair work. It says that independent repair companies will “own [their] customer” and that “you stand behind your workmanship.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Manufacturers say it would undermine their security model, but if it’s possible for them to do what this document is saying and roll out their diagnostic software to thousands of unaffiliated companies, then lobbyists have been lying to legislators,” Wiens said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This raises questions, then, about why Apple is opening up its repair programs—even on a limited basis—while its lobbyists continue to fight legislation that would do just that. Wiens and Proctor believe that Apple is trying to kill the legislation by telling lawmakers that it's given the repair community what they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s an attempt to reduce pressure from the public for right to repair legislation,” Wiens said. “They’re negotiating on their own terms.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1553536747694-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-15722-PM.png?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1553536747694-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-15722-PM&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1553536747694-Screen-Shot-2019-03-25-at-15722-PM.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/kz5qgw/california-farm-bureau-john-deere-tractor-hacking-right-to-repair&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;already a precedent for this in the right to repair world&lt;/a&gt;. Last year, soon after California introduced a right to repair bill, the Equipment Dealers Association, which represents John Deere and other agricultural giants, agreed to give farmers some minor concessions by promising to make repair manuals, product guides, and diagnostic service tools (but not parts) available to farmers by 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the California Farm Bureau Federation, which nominally represents farmers, ultimately stopped pursuing right to repair, and the legislation was dropped (it was reintroduced this year.) Which was the point all along: “There are several big wins that come to mind as we look back on 2018,” John Lagemann, a sales and marketing executive at John Deere, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aem.org/news/strong-focus-on-customer-connections-advocacy-strategic-planning-for-aem-ag-sector-board/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;told an agricultural trade organization&lt;/a&gt; at the end of last year. “We rallied around the Right-to-Repair issue and were successful in thwarting that legislation in several states.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so while Apple may be softening its stance on independent repair and may be preparing to make important concessions, it’s not a reason to give up on fighting for legislation that actually enshrines fair repair policies for all consumers, not just a few larger independent chains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s still short of giving freedom to the consumer to make decisions to fix their own devices,” Proctor said. “I think it’s a sign that they know that we’ve kind of won the public messaging that they’re changing their policy to something they didn’t want to do, but what we’re asking for is the freedom to make choices for ourselves about the products we’ve bought and own.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 16:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kaboro</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Internal Documents Show Apple Is Capable of Implementing Right to Repair Legislation</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5c9916780b09d6000812dce6/lede/1553537166942-shutterstock_759694303.jpeg?crop=1xw:0.8438589693917087xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/d3mqna/internal-documents-show-apple-is-capable-of-implementing-right-to-repair-legislation</og:url>
<og:description>A leaked internal document obtained by Motherboard outlines a program that looks almost exactly like the requirements of right to repair legislation that has been proposed in 20 states.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/d3mqna/internal-documents-show-apple-is-capable-of-implementing-right-to-repair-legislation</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tone.js – A framework for making interactive music in the browser</title>
<link>https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/Tonejs/Tone.js&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/0d6618bc2cc7c53dae521f5737b68dc61e8f7da1/68747470733a2f2f7472617669732d63692e6f72672f546f6e656a732f546f6e652e6a732e7376673f6272616e63683d646576&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/Tonejs/Tone.js.svg?branch=dev&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://codecov.io/gh/Tonejs/Tone.js&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/e6168a0ef6f96e93368d3823b062b311214025cb/68747470733a2f2f636f6465636f762e696f2f67682f546f6e656a732f546f6e652e6a732f6272616e63682f6465762f67726170682f62616467652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;codecov&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://codecov.io/gh/Tonejs/Tone.js/branch/dev/graph/badge.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tone.js is a Web Audio framework for creating interactive music in the browser. The architecture of Tone.js aims to be familiar to both musicians and audio programmers looking to create web-based audio applications. On the high-level, Tone offers common DAW (digital audio workstation) features like a global transport for scheduling events and prebuilt synths and effects. For signal-processing programmers (coming from languages like Max/MSP), Tone provides a wealth of high performance, low latency building blocks and DSP modules to build your own synthesizers, effects, and complex control signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/examples/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/demos&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Demos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unpkg.com/tone&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install tone&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dev -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;npm install tone@next&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Installation&quot;&gt;Full Installation Instruction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;create a synth and connect it to the master output (your speakers)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; synth &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Tone.Synth&lt;/span&gt;().&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;toMaster&lt;/span&gt;();

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;play a middle 'C' for the duration of an 8th note&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;synth&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;triggerAttackRelease&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;C4&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;8n&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Tone.Synth&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#Synth&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tone.Synth&lt;/a&gt; is a basic synthesizer with a single &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#OmniOscillator&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;oscillator&lt;/a&gt; and an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synthesizer#ADSR_envelope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ADSR envelope&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;triggerAttackRelease&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;triggerAttackRelease&lt;/code&gt; is a combination of two methods: &lt;code&gt;triggerAttack&lt;/code&gt; when the amplitude is rising (for example from a 'key down' or 'note on' event), and &lt;code&gt;triggerRelease&lt;/code&gt; is when the amplitude is going back to 0 ('key up' / 'note off').&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first argument to &lt;code&gt;triggerAttackRelease&lt;/code&gt; is the frequency which can either be a number (like &lt;code&gt;440&lt;/code&gt;) or as &quot;pitch-octave&quot; notation (like &lt;code&gt;&quot;D#2&quot;&lt;/code&gt;). The second argument is the duration that the note is held. This value can either be in seconds, or as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Time&quot;&gt;tempo-relative value&lt;/a&gt;. The third (optional) argument of &lt;code&gt;triggerAttackRelease&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; along the AudioContext time the note should play. It can be used to schedule events in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tone.js abstracts away the AudioContext time. Instead of defining all values in seconds, any method which takes time as an argument can accept a number or a string. For example &lt;code&gt;&quot;4n&quot;&lt;/code&gt; is a quarter-note, &lt;code&gt;&quot;8t&quot;&lt;/code&gt; is an eighth-note triplet, and &lt;code&gt;&quot;1m&quot;&lt;/code&gt; is one measure. These values can even be composed into expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Time&quot;&gt;Read about Time encodings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most browsers will not play &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; audio until a user clicks something (like a play button). Execute the above example only after a users invokes &lt;code&gt;resume()&lt;/code&gt; on Tone's context, or simply &lt;code&gt;Tone.start()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;attach a click listener to a play button&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;querySelector&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;button&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;addEventListener&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;click&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, () &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Tone&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;())
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transport&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#Transport&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tone.Transport&lt;/a&gt; is the master timekeeper, allowing for application-wide synchronization and scheduling of sources, signals and events along a shared timeline. Time expressions (like the ones above) are evaluated against the Transport's BPM which can be set like this: &lt;code&gt;Tone.Transport.bpm.value = 120&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Loops&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tone.js provides higher-level abstractions for scheduling events. &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#Loop&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tone.Loop&lt;/a&gt; is a simple way to create a looped callback that can be scheduled to start and stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;play a note every quarter-note&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; loop &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Tone.Loop&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;){
        &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;synth&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;triggerAttackRelease&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;C2&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;8n&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, time);
}, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;4n&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Javascript callbacks are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; precisely timed, the sample-accurate time of the event is passed into the callback function. &lt;strong&gt;Use this time value to schedule the events&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can then start and stop the loop along the Transport's timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;loop between the first and fourth measures of the Transport's timeline&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;loop&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;1m&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;stop&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;4m&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then start the Transport to hear the loop:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Tone&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Transport&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;();
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Events&quot;&gt;Read about Tone.js' Event classes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Transport&quot;&gt;scheduling events with the Transport.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tone has a number of instruments which all inherit from the same &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#Instrument&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Instrument base class&lt;/a&gt;, giving them a common API for playing notes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#Synth&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tone.Synth&lt;/a&gt; is composed of one oscillator and an amplitude envelope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;pass in some initial values for the filter and filter envelope&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; synth &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Tone.Synth&lt;/span&gt;({
        &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;oscillator&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
                &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;type&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;pwm&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;modulationFrequency&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;0.2&lt;/span&gt;
        },
        &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;envelope&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
                &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;attack&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;0.02&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;decay&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;0.1&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;sustain&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;0.2&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;release&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/span&gt;,
        }
}).&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;toMaster&lt;/span&gt;();

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;start the note &quot;D3&quot; one second from now&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;synth&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;triggerAttack&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;D3&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;+1&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All instruments are monophonic (one voice) but can be made polyphonic when the constructor is passed in as the second argument to &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#PolySynth&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tone.PolySynth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;a 4 voice Synth&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; polySynth &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Tone.PolySynth&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Tone&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Synth&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;toMaster&lt;/span&gt;();
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;play a chord&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;polySynth&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;triggerAttackRelease&lt;/span&gt;([&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;C4&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;E4&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;G4&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;B4&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;], &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;2n&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Instruments&quot;&gt;Read more about Instruments.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above examples, the synthesizer was always connected directly to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#Master&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;master output&lt;/a&gt;, but the output of the synth could also be routed through one (or more) effects before going to the speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;create a distortion effect&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; distortion &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Tone.Distortion&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;0.4&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;toMaster&lt;/span&gt;();
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;connect a synth to the distortion&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;synth&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;connect&lt;/span&gt;(distortion);
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Effects&quot;&gt;Read more about Effects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tone has a few basic audio sources like &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#Oscillator&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tone.Oscillator&lt;/a&gt; which has sine, square, triangle, and sawtooth waveforms, a buffer player (&lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#Player&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tone.Player&lt;/a&gt;), a noise generator (&lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#Noise&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tone.Noise&lt;/a&gt;), a few additional oscillator types (&lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#PWMOscillator&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;pwm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#PulseOscillator&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;pulse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#FatOscillator&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;fat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#FMOscillator&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;fm&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/docs/#UserMedia&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;external audio input&lt;/a&gt; (when &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/#feat=stream&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;WebRTC is supported&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;a pwm oscillator which is connected to the speaker and started right away&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; pwm &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Tone.PWMOscillator&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;Bb3&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;toMaster&lt;/span&gt;().&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;();
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Sources&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the underlying Web Audio API, Tone.js is built with audio-rate signal control over nearly everything. This is a powerful feature which allows for sample-accurate synchronization and scheduling of parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Signals&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tone.js creates an AudioContext when it loads and shims it for maximum browser compatibility. The AudioContext can be found at &lt;code&gt;Tone.context&lt;/code&gt;. Or set your own AudioContext using &lt;code&gt;Tone.setContext(audioContext)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use MIDI files, you'll first need to convert them into a JSON format which Tone.js can understand using &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/Midi/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Midi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tone.js makes extensive use of the native Web Audio Nodes such as the GainNode and WaveShaperNode for all signal processing, which enables Tone.js to work well on both desktop and mobile browsers. It uses no ScriptProcessorNodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Performance&quot;&gt;This wiki&lt;/a&gt; article has some suggestions related to performance for best practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tone.js runs an extensive test suite using &lt;a href=&quot;https://mochajs.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;mocha&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://chaijs.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;chai&lt;/a&gt; with nearly 100% coverage. Each commit and pull request is run on &lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/Tonejs/Tone.js/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Travis-CI&lt;/a&gt; across multiple versions of Chrome, Safari and Firefox to ensure backwards and future compatibility. Passing builds on the 'dev' branch are published on npm as &lt;code&gt;tone@next&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to contribute to Tone.js. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js/wiki/Contributing&quot;&gt;this wiki&lt;/a&gt; if you're interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have questions (or answers) that are not necessarily bugs/issues, please post them to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/tonejs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tomcam</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/11019186?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>Tonejs/Tone.js</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js</og:url>
<og:description>A Web Audio framework for making interactive music in the browser. - Tonejs/Tone.js</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/Tonejs/Tone.js</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>