<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Show HN: A retro video game console I&amp;#039;ve been working on in my free time</title>
<link>https://internalregister.github.io/2019/03/14/Homebrew-Console.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://internalregister.github.io/2019/03/14/Homebrew-Console.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Building a ‘Homebrew’ Video Game Console | Internal Register&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;generator&quot; content=&quot;Jekyll v3.7.4&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;Building a ‘Homebrew’ Video Game Console&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:locale&quot; content=&quot;en_US&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Software and hardware projects for fun from a guy who loves retro computing&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;Software and hardware projects for fun from a guy who loves retro computing&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;/2019/03/14/Homebrew-Console.html&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;/2019/03/14/Homebrew-Console.html&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;Internal Register&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;article&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;article:published_time&quot; content=&quot;2019-03-14T00:00:00+00:00&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#157878&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;apple-mobile-web-app-status-bar-style&quot; content=&quot;black-translucent&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/css/style.css?v=16073548bf11952f4b5e2d57f37627aa4be813fa&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;503.72928994083&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;skip-to-content&quot; href=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/2019/03/14/Homebrew-Console.html#content&quot;&gt;Skip to the content.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/console2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Console 2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post serves as an introduction to a “homebrew” video game console made from scratch, using a lot of inspiration from retro consoles and modern projects but with a unique architecture.&lt;br/&gt;Some friends of mine have told me again and again not to keep this project to myself and to put this information online, so here it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Sérgio Vieira and I’m a portuguese guy who grew up in the 80s and 90s, I’ve always been nostalgic towards retro-gaming, specifically the third and forth generation consoles.&lt;br/&gt;A few years ago I’ve decided to learn more about electronics and try to build my own video game console.&lt;br/&gt;Professionally I work as a software engineer and had no experience with electronics other than ocasionally building and upgrading my desktop computer (which doesn’t really count).&lt;br/&gt;Even though I had no experience, I said to myself “why not?”, bought a few books, a few electronics kits and started to learn what I felt I needed to learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to build a console that would be similar to those which are nostalgic to me, I wanted something between an &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Nintendo_Entertainment_System&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NES&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Super_Nintendo_Entertainment_System&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Super Nintendo&lt;/a&gt; or between a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Master_System&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sega Master System&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Sega_Genesis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mega Drive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;These video game consoles had a CPU, a custom video chip (in those days it wasn’t called a GPU) and an audio chip either integrated or separate.&lt;br/&gt;Games were distributed in cartridges, which were basically hardware extensions with a ROM chip and sometimes other components as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The initial plan was to build a console with the following characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;No emulation, the games/programs had to run on real hardware, not necessarilly hardware of the time, but hardware that is just fast enough for the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a dedicated “retro” CPU chip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With TV output (analog signal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to produce sound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With support for 2 controllers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scrolling background and moving sprites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to support Mario-style platform games (and of course other types of games as well)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games/Programs available through an SD Card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason I wanted SD card support instead of cartridge support, it’s mainly because it’s a lot more practical to have programs available in an SD card, as it makes it a lot easier to copy files from a PC to it. Having cartridges would mean to make even more hardware and to have a new hardware for each program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-signal&quot;&gt;Video signal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I worked on was the video signal generation.&lt;br/&gt;Each video game console of the era I was aiming for had different proprietary graphics chips which made them all have different characteristics.&lt;br/&gt;For this reason I didn’t want to use any pre-made graphics chip, I wanted my console to have unique graphical capabilities. And because it was impossible for me to make my own chip, and I didn’t know how to use an FPGA, I opted for a software based graphics-chip using a 20Mhz 8-bit microcontroller.&lt;br/&gt;It’s not overkill and has just enough performance to generate the kind of graphics I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I started by using an Atmega644 microcontroller running at 20Mhz to send a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/PAL&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PAL&lt;/a&gt; video signal to a TV (because the microcontroller doesn’t support this protocol natively, I had to bit bang the PAL video signal protocol):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/vpuTest1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VPU Test 1&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/vpuTest2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VPU Test 2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The microcontroller produces 8-bit color (RGB332, 3 bits for red, 3 bits for green and 2 bits for blue) and a passive DAC is used to convert this to analog RGB. Luckily in Portugal one common way to connect an external device to a TV is through a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/SCART&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SCART&lt;/a&gt; connector and most TVs accept RGB input through SCART.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-proper-graphics-system&quot;&gt;A proper graphics system&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I wanted to have a microcontroller only drive the TV signal (I call it the VPU, Video Processing Unit), I decided to use a double-buffer technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the second microcontroller (PPU, Picture Processing Unit, which is an Atmega1284 also at 20Mhz) generate an image to a RAM chip (VRAM1) while the first one would dump the contents of another RAM chip (VRAM2) to the TV.&lt;br/&gt;After one frame (2 frames in PAL or 1/25th of a second), the VPU switches the RAMs, and dumps the image generated into VRAM1 while the PPU generates an image to VRAM2.&lt;br/&gt;The video board turned out quite complex as I had to use some external hardware to allow for the two microcontrollers to access the same RAM chips and also to speed up the access to RAM that also had to be bit-banged, so I added some 74 series chips such as counters, line selectors, transceivers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The firmware for VPU and especially the PPU also became quite complex as I had to do extremely performant code to be able to have all the graphical capabilities I wanted, originally it was all done in assembly, later I coded some of it in C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/videoBoard2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Video Board 1&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/videoBoard3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Video Board 2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up having the PPU generate a 224x192 pixel image that is then sent to the TV by the VPU. This resolution might seem low, but it is in fact only a bit lower than the consoles mentioned above that usually had resolutions of 256x224 pixels. The lower resolution allowed me to cram more graphical features into the time I had to draw each frame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like in the old days the PPU has “fixed” capabilities that can be configured. The background that can be rendered is composed of 8x8 pixel characters (sometimes called tiles). This means a screen background has the size of 28x24 tiles.&lt;br/&gt;In order to have per-pixel scrolling and the ability to update the background seamlessly I made it so there are 4 virtual screens each one having 28x24 tiles that are contiguous and wrap around one other:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/background.png&quot; alt=&quot;Background&quot; width=&quot;448&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/virtualBackground.png&quot; alt=&quot;Virtual Background&quot; width=&quot;448&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above the background, the PPU can render 64 &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Sprite_(computer_graphics)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sprites&lt;/a&gt; that can have a width and height of either 8 or 16 pixels (1, 2 or 4 characters) and can be flipped horizontally or vertically or in both axes.&lt;br/&gt;Also above the background an “overlay” can be rendered, which is a patch composed of 28x6 tiles. This is useful for games that need a HUD and in which the background is scrolling and sprites are being used for other purposes than to show information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other “advanced” feature is the ability to scroll the background in different directions in separate lines, this enables games to have effetcs such as a limited &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallax_scrolling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;parallax scrolling&lt;/a&gt; or split-screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there’s also the attribute table, which is the possibility of giving each tile a value from 0 to 3, and then it’s possible to set all the tiles of a given attribute to a certain tile page or increment their character number. This is useful when there are certain parts of the background that change constantly, the CPU doesn’t need to update each one of the tiles, it only needs to say something like: “all tiles with attribute 1 will increment their character number by 2” (using different techniques, this effect can be seen for example in block tiles with a moving question mark in Mario games or in waterfall tiles that seem to be changing constantly seen in other games).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cpu&quot;&gt;CPU&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having a functional video board, I started working with the CPU I chose for the console, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Zilog_Z80&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zilog Z80&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;One of the reasons I chose the Z80 (other than it just being a cool retro CPU) was because the Z80 has access to a 16bit memory space and a 16bit IO space, something that other similar 8-bit CPUs do not have, such as the famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/MOS_Technology_6502&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;6502&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;The 6502, for example, only has a 16bit memory space, which means that the whole 16bits were not reserved just for memory but had to be shared between memory access and external device access, such as video, audio, inputs, etc. By having an IO space together with a memory space, I could have the whole of the 16bit memory space reserved for memory (64KB of code and data) and have the IO space for communication with external devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started by connecting the CPU to an EEPROM with some test code and also connecting it via the IO space to a microcontroller I had set up to communicate with a PC via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/RS-232&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RS232&lt;/a&gt; in order to check if the CPU was functioning well as well as all the connections I was making. This microcontroller (an Atmega324 operating at 20Mhz) was to become the IO MCU (or input/output microcontroller unit), responsible for managing access to the game controllers, SD Card, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/PS/2_port&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PS/2&lt;/a&gt; Keyboard and the RS232 communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/cpuBoard1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CPU Board 1&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CPU was then connected to a 128KB RAM Chip, from which 56KB was accessible (this seems like a waste but I could only get either 128KB or 32KB RAM chips). This way the CPUs memory space is composed of 8KB of ROM and 56KB of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After this I updated the IO MCU’s firmware with the help of this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roland-riegel.de/sd-reader/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;library&lt;/a&gt; and added SD Card support.&lt;br/&gt;The CPU was now able to navigate through directories, browse their contents, open and read from files. All this by reading and writing to specific IO space addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;connecting-the-cpu-and-the-ppu&quot;&gt;Connecting the CPU and the PPU&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I implemented was the interaction between the CPU and the PPU.&lt;br/&gt;For this I found “an easy solution” which was to get dual-port RAM (a RAM chip that can be simultaneously connected to two different buses), it saves me from having to place more ICs like line selectors and such and also it makes the accesses to the RAM between both chips virtually simultaneous. The PPU also comunicates with the CPU directly by activating its NMI (non-masking interrupt) every frame. This means the CPU has an interrupt every frame, which makes it valuable for timing and knowing when to update graphics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each frame the interaction between CPU, PPU and VPU is as following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The PPU copies the information of the PPU-RAM to internal RAM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The PPU sends an NMI signal to the CPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the same time:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the CPU jumps to the NMI interrupt function and starts updating the PPU-RAM with the new graphical frame state. (the program should return from the interrupt before the start of the next frame)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the PPU renders the image based on the information it had previously copied to one of the VRAMs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the VPU sends the image in the other VRAM to the TV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around this time I also added support for game controllers, I originally wanted to use Super Nintendo controllers, but the socket for this type of controller is proprietary and was hard to come by, therefore I chose the Mega Drive/Genesis compatible 6-button controllers, they use standard &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/D-subminiature&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DB-9&lt;/a&gt; sockets that are widely available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/jointBoard1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Joint Board 1&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;time-for-the-first-real-game&quot;&gt;Time for the first real game&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I had a CPU with game controller support that could control the PPU and could load programs from an SD Card, so…time to make a game in Z80 assembly of course, it took me a couple of days of my free time to make this (&lt;a href=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/miniBreakout.asm&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2Pcrg1fesBk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;video&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;adding-custom-graphics&quot;&gt;Adding custom graphics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was awesome, I now had a working video game console, but…it still wasn’t enough, there was no way for a game to have custom graphics, it had to use the graphics stored in the PPU firmware that would only be changed when its firmware was updated, so I tried to figure out a way of adding a RAM chip with graphics (Character RAM) and somehow load it with information coming from the CPU and making it accessible to the PPU, all this with as little components I could, because the console was getting really big and complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I came up with a way: only the PPU would have access to this new RAM, the CPU would be able to load information into it through the PPU and while this transfer was happening, the RAM wouldn’t be used for graphics, but only the internal graphics would be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CPU can then switch from internal graphics to Character RAM (CHR-RAM) mode and the PPU will use these custom graphics, it’s possibly not the ideal solution, but it works. In the end the new RAM has 128KB and can store 1024 8x8 pixel characters for background and another 1024 characters of the same size for sprites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/jointBoard2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Joint Board 2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-finally-sound&quot;&gt;And finally sound&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the sound, it was the last thing to be implemented. Originally I intended to give it similar capabilities as those seen in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://uzebox.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Uzebox&lt;/a&gt;, basically to have a microcontroller generate 4 channels of PWM sound.&lt;br/&gt;However I found out I could get my hands on vintage chips relatively easily, and I ordered a few YM3438 &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Frequency_modulation_synthesis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FM synthesis&lt;/a&gt; chips, these sound chips are fully compatible with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Yamaha_YM2612&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YM2612&lt;/a&gt; which is the one found in the Mega Drive/Genesis. By integrating this chip, I could have Mega Drive quality music along with sound effects produced by a microcontroller.&lt;br/&gt;The CPU controls the SPU (Sound Processor Unit, the name I gave to the microcontroller that controls the YM3438 and produces sound on its own) again through a dual-port RAM, this time only 2KB in size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Similarly to the graphics module, the sound module has 128KB for storing sound patches and PCM samples, the CPU can load information to this memory through the SPU. This way the CPU can either tell the SPU to play commands stored in this RAM or update commands to the SPU every frame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CPU controls the 4 PWM channels through 4 circular buffers present in the SPU-RAM.&lt;br/&gt;The SPU will go through these buffers and execute the commands present in them.&lt;br/&gt;In the same way there is another circular buffer in the SPU-RAM for the FM synthesis chip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, similar to how it works with graphics, the interaction between CPU and SPU works like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The SPU copies the information in the SPU-RAM to internal RAM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The SPU waits for the NMI signal sent by the PPU. (for synchronization purposes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the same time:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The CPU updates the buffers for the PWM channels and for the FM synthesis chip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the SPU executes the commands in the buffers regarding the information in its internal memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuously while all of the above happens, the SPU updates the PWM sound at a frequency of 16Khz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/soundBoard1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sound Board 1&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all the modules were developed, some were put into protoboards.&lt;br/&gt;As for the CPU module, I’ve managed to design and order a custom PCB, don’t know if I’ll do the same for the other modules, I think I was pretty lucky to get a working PCB on the first try.&lt;br/&gt;Only the sound module remains as a breadboard (for now).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the video game console now (at time of writing):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/console1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Console 1&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;architecture&quot;&gt;Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This diagram helps illustrate what components are in each module and how they interact with one another. (the only things missing are the signal the PPU sends to the CPU directly every frame in the form of an NMI and the same signal being sent to the SPU as well)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/architecture2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Architecture&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPU&lt;/em&gt;: Zilog Z80 operating at 10Mhz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPU-ROM&lt;/em&gt;: 8KB EEPROM, holds the bootloader code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPU-RAM&lt;/em&gt;: 128KB RAM (56KB usable), holds the code and data of the programs/games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;IO MCU&lt;/em&gt;: Atmega324, serves as an interface between the CPU and the RS232, PS/2 Keyboard, Controllers and SD Card filesystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;PPU-RAM&lt;/em&gt;: 4KB Dual-port RAM, it’s the interface RAM between the CPU and the PPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CHRRAM&lt;/em&gt;: 128KB RAM, holds the custom background tiles and sprites graphics (in 8x8 pixel characters).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;VRAM1, VRAM2&lt;/em&gt;: 128KB RAM (43008 bytes used), they are used to store the framebuffer and are written to by the PPU and read by the VPU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;PPU (Picture Processing Unit)&lt;/em&gt;: Atmega1284, draws the frame to the framebuffers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;VPU (Video Processing Unit)&lt;/em&gt;: Atmega324, reads the framebuffers and generates an RGB and PAL Sync signal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPU-RAM&lt;/em&gt;: 2KB Dual-port RAM, serves as an interface between the CPU and the SPU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SNDRAM&lt;/em&gt;: 128KB RAM, holds PWM Patchs, PCM samples and FM Synthesis instruction blocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;YM3438&lt;/em&gt;: YM3438, FM Synthesis chip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPU (Sound Processing Unit)&lt;/em&gt;: Atmega644, generates PWM-based sound and controls the YM3438.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-final-specs&quot;&gt;The final specs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPU:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;8-bit CPU Zilog Z80 operating at 10Mhz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8KB of ROM for bootloader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;56KB of RAM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IO:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reading data from FAT16/FAT32 SD Card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading/writing to RS232 port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 MegaDrive/Genesis-compatible controllers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PS2 Keyboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;224x192 pixel resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25 fps (half PAL fps).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;256 Colors (RGB332).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x2 virtual background space (448x384 pixels), with bi-directional per-pixel scrolling, described using 4 name tables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;64 sprites with width and height 8 or 16 pixels with possibility of being flipped in X or Y axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background and sprites composed of 8x8 pixels characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Character RAM with 1024 background characters and 1024 sprite characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;64 independent background horizontal scrolling in custom lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 independent background vertical scrolling in custom lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overlay plane with 224x48 pixels with or without colorkey transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background attribute table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RGB and Composite PAL output through SCART socket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sound:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PWM generated 8-bit 4 channel sound, with pre-defined waveforms (square, sine, sawtooth, noise, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8-bit 8Khz PCM samples in one of PWM channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YM3438 FM synthesis chip updated with instructions at 50Hz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One piece of software that was written for the console was the bootloader. The bootloader is stored in the CPU-ROM and can occupy up to 8KB. It uses the first 256 bytes of the CPU-RAM. It’s the first software to be run by the CPU. It’s purpose is to show the programs available in the SD Card.&lt;br/&gt;These programs are in files that contain the compiled code and may also contain custom graphics data and sound data.&lt;br/&gt;After being selected, the program is then loaded into the CPU-RAM, CHR-RAM and SPU-RAM. And the respective program is executed. The code of the programs that can be loaded into the console, can take up the 56KB of the RAM, except the first 256 bytes and of course have to take into account the stack and also leave space for data.&lt;br/&gt;Both the bootloader and programs for this console are developed in a similar fashion, here’s a brief explanation on how these programs are made.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;memoryio-mapping&quot;&gt;Memory/IO Mapping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to note when developing for the console is how the CPU can access the other modules of the console, therefore memory and io space mapping are crucial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CPU accesses its bootloader ROM and RAM through the memory space.&lt;br/&gt;CPU memory space mapping:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/memoryMapping.png&quot; alt=&quot;Memory Mapping&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It accesses the PPU-RAM, SPU-RAM and the IO MCU through IO space.&lt;br/&gt;CPU IO space mapping:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/ioMapping.png&quot; alt=&quot;IO Mapping&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inside IO space mapping, the IO MCU, PPU and SPU have specific mappings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;controlling-the-ppu&quot;&gt;Controlling the PPU&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can control the PPU through writing to the PPU-RAM and we know from the information above that the PPU-RAM is accessible through IO space from address 1000h to 1FFFh.&lt;br/&gt;This is how that address range looks like seen in more detail:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/ppuMapping.png&quot; alt=&quot;PPU Mapping&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The PPU Status has the following values:&lt;br/&gt;0 - Internal graphics mode&lt;br/&gt;1 - Custom graphics mode (CHR-RAM)&lt;br/&gt;2 - Write to CHR-RAM mode&lt;br/&gt;3 - Write complete, waiting for CPU to aknowledge mode&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, this is how we can work with sprites:&lt;br/&gt;The console has the ability to render 64 simultaneous sprites. The information on these sprites are accessible through the CPU io mapping from address 1004h to 1143h (320 bytes), each sprite has 5 bytes of information (5 x 64 = 320 bytes):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous byte (each of its bits is a flag: Active, Flipped_X, Flipped_Y, PageBit0, PageBit1, AboveOverlay, Width16 and Height16)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Character byte (which character is the sprite in the page described by the corresponding flags above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color key byte (which color is to be transparent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X position byte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Y position byte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, to make a sprite visible, we must put the Active flag to 1 and put the sprite in coordinates in which it is visible (coordinates x=32 and y=32 puts the sprite in the top left of the screen, less than that and he’s off screen or partially visible).&lt;br/&gt;Then we can also set its character and what is its transparent color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if we want to set the 10th sprite as visible we would set io address 4145 (1004h + (5 x 9)) to 1 and then set its coordinates to, for example, x=100 and y=120, so we would set address 4148 to 100 and 4149 to 120.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-assembly-to-code&quot;&gt;Using Assembly to code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the ways to code a program for the console is using assembly language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below is a sample code of making the first sprite move and bump into the corners of the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-asm&quot; data-lang=&quot;asm&quot;&gt;ORG 2100h

PPU_SPRITES: EQU $1004
SPRITE_CHR: EQU 72
SPRITE_COLORKEY: EQU $1F
SPRITE_INIT_POS_X: EQU 140
SPRITE_INIT_POS_Y: EQU 124

jp main

DS $2166-$
nmi:
    ld bc, PPU_SPRITES + 3
    ld a, (sprite_dir)
    and a, 1
    jr z, subX
    in a, (c) ; increment X
    inc a
    out (c), a
    cp 248
    jr nz, updateY
    ld a, (sprite_dir)
    xor a, 1
    ld (sprite_dir), a
    jp updateY
subX:
    in a, (c) ; decrement X
    dec a
    out (c), a
    cp 32
    jr nz, updateY    
    ld a, (sprite_dir)
    xor a, 1
    ld (sprite_dir), a
updateY:
    inc bc
    ld a, (sprite_dir)
    and a, 2
    jr z, subY
    in a, (c) ; increment Y
    inc a
    out (c), a
    cp 216
    jr nz, moveEnd
    ld a, (sprite_dir)
    xor a, 2
    ld (sprite_dir), a
    jp moveEnd
subY:
    in a, (c) ; decrement Y
    dec a
    out (c), a
    cp 32
    jr nz, moveEnd
    ld a, (sprite_dir)
    xor a, 2
    ld (sprite_dir), a
moveEnd:
    ret

main:
    ld bc, PPU_SPRITES
    ld a, 1
    out (c), a  ; Set Sprite 0 as active
    inc bc
    ld a, SPRITE_CHR
    out (c), a  ; Set Sprite 0 character
    inc bc
    ld a, SPRITE_COLORKEY
    out (c), a  ; Set Sprite 0 colorkey
    inc bc
    ld a, SPRITE_INIT_POS_X
    out (c), a  ; Set Sprite 0 position X
    inc bc
    ld a, SPRITE_INIT_POS_Y
    out (c), a  ; Set Sprite 0 position Y
mainLoop:    
    jp mainLoop

sprite_dir:     DB 0&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-a-c-toolchain&quot;&gt;Using a C toolchain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also possible to develop programs using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sdcc.sourceforge.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SDCC&lt;/a&gt; compiler and some custom tools to use C language.&lt;br/&gt;This makes development quicker, although it could lead to less performant code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sample code with an equivalent result to the above assembly code, here I’m using a library to help with the calls to the PPU:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot; data-lang=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;#include &amp;lt;console.h&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;#define SPRITE_CHR 72
#define SPRITE_COLORKEY 0x1F
#define SPRITE_INIT_POS_X 140
#define SPRITE_INIT_POS_Y 124
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;s_sprite&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SPRITE_CHR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SPRITE_COLORKEY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SPRITE_INIT_POS_X&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SPRITE_INIT_POS_Y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;uint8_t&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite_dir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;nmi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite_dir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;248&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite_dir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;^=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite_dir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;^=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite_dir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;216&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite_dir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;^=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite_dir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;^=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;set_sprite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sprite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;custom-graphics&quot;&gt;Custom Graphics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The console has graphics read-only predefined graphics stored in the PPU firmware (1 page of background tiles and another page of sprite graphics), however it is possible to use custom graphics for the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective is to have all the necessary graphics in the binary form that the console’s bootloader can then load into the CHR-RAM. In order to do this I start with several images already in the right size, in this case to be used as background in several situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/tetrisTileComponents.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sample tile components&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since custom graphics are composed of 4 pages of 256 8x8 characters for background and 4 pages of 256 8x8 characters for sprites.&lt;br/&gt;I convert the graphics above to a PNG file for every page using a custom tool (eliminating duplicate 8x8 resulting characters):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/tetrisTilesSheet.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sample character sheet&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then use another custom tool to convert it to an RGB332 binary file of 8x8 pixel characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/graphicsCmd.png&quot; alt=&quot;Graphics command line&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result are binary files composed of 8x8 pixel characters that are contiguous in memory (each one occupying 64 bytes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sound&quot;&gt;Sound&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wave samples are converted to 8-bit 8Khz PCM samples.&lt;br/&gt;Patches for PWM SFX/music can be composed using pre-defined instructions.&lt;br/&gt;And as for Yamaha YM3438 FM Synthesis chip, I found that the application called &lt;a href=&quot;http://deflemask.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DefleMask&lt;/a&gt; can be used to produce PAL-clocked music targeting the Genesis sound-chip YM2612 which is compatible with the YM3438.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DefleMask can then export the music to VGM and then I can use another custom tool to convert VGM to a homebrew sound binary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the binaries from all 3 types of sound are combined into a single binary file that can then be loaded to the SNDRAM by the bootloader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/soundCmd.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sound command line&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;putting-it-all-together&quot;&gt;Putting it all together&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program’s binary, the graphics and the sound are combined into a PRG file.&lt;br/&gt;A PRG file has a header indicating if the program has custom graphics and/or sound and what’s the size for each as well as all the corresponding binary information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This file can then be put into and SD Card and the console bootloader will read it and load it into all the specific RAMs and run the program as described above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/prgCmd.png&quot; alt=&quot;PRG command line&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-the-emulator&quot;&gt;Using the emulator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help with the development of software for the console I’ve developed an emulator in C++ using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wxwidgets.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wxWidgets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;In order to emulate the CPU I’ve used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggambetta/libz80&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;libz80&lt;/a&gt; library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve added some debugging features to the emulator, I can stop in a given breakpoint and step through the assembly instructions of it, there’s also some source mapping available if the game was the result of compiled C code.&lt;br/&gt;As for graphics I can check what’s stored in the tile pages/name tables (the background mapping that’s the size of 4 screens) and I can check what’s stored in CHRRAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of running a program using the emulator and then using some of the debugging tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://internalregister.github.io/assets/emulatorDemo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Emulator Demo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(The following videos are the console’s video output to a CRT TV captured by a cellphone camera, I’m sorry for the quality not being the very best)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A BASIC implementation running on the console and using the PS/2 keyboard, in this video, after the first program, I write directly into PPU-RAM through IO space to enable and configure a sprite and finally move it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2UNjKx4uZGY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;video&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Graphics demo, this video shows a program that bounces 64 16x16 sprites, over a background with custom scrolling and with the overlay plane enabled and moving up and down above or behind sprites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OA0q3_Krgxc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;video&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sound demo showing the YM3438 capabilities as well as PCM sample playback, the FM music plus the PCM samples in this demo take up almost all of the 128KB of the SNDRAM:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xDsTGmqxLzM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;video&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tetris, using almost just background tiles for graphics, for music it uses the YM3438 and for sound effects PWM sound patches :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E77XZUwKd54&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;video&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This project was truly a dream come true, I have been working on it for some years now, on and off during my free time, I never thought I would reach this far into building my own retro-style video game console. It certainly is not perfect, I’m still by no means an expert on electronic design, the console has way too many components and undoubtedly could be made better and more efficient and probably someone reading this is thinking exactly that.&lt;br/&gt;However, while building this project, I’ve learned a lot about electronics, game console and computer design, assembly language and other interesting topics, and above all it gives me great satisfaction to play a game I’ve made on hardware I’ve made and designed myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have plans to build other consoles/computers. In fact I have another video game console in the making, almost complete, which is a simplified retro-style console based of a cheap FPGA board and a few extra components (not nearly as many as in this project, obviously), designed to be a lot cheaper and replicable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though there’s a lot I’ve written about this project, there certainly would be a lot more to talk about, I barely mentioned how the sound engine works and how the CPU interacts with it, there’s also a lot more that can be said about the graphics engine, the other IO available and pretty much the console itself.&lt;br/&gt;Depending on the feedback I might write other articles focusing on updates, more indepth information on the different modules of the console or other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;projectswebsitesyoutube-channels-that-helped-me-for-inspiration-and-technical-knowledge&quot;&gt;Projects/Websites/Youtube channels that helped me for inspiration and technical knowledge:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These websites/channels not only gave me inspiration but also helped me with solutions to some of the dificulties I have encountered in the making of this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve read this far, thank you. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you have any feedback to give or any questions, please comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;noscript readability=&quot;1.15625&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pkiller</dc:creator>
<og:title>Building a ‘Homebrew’ Video Game Console</og:title>
<og:description>Software and hardware projects for fun from a guy who loves retro computing</og:description>
<og:url>/2019/03/14/Homebrew-Console.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://internalregister.github.io/2019/03/14/Homebrew-Console.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Loses Top Executives, Including Chris Cox</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/14/technology/facebook-chris-cox.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/14/technology/facebook-chris-cox.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO — Two of Facebook’s top executives — one regarded as the company’s No. 3, and the other the head of its WhatsApp messaging service — are leaving after disagreements with Mark Zuckerberg, the chief executive, over the social network’s future direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The differences stemmed from Mr. Zuckerberg’s asserting control over his company and its apps — Instagram, WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger — by rolling out a plan to integrate the services into &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/06/technology/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-privacy.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;a single privacy-focused platform&lt;/a&gt;, according to six people involved in the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The change is a substantial shift for Facebook, which has traditionally encouraged people to publicly share posts, videos and photos. Executives at Facebook who had run the various services were concerned that knitting together the apps would take a toll on the popularity and growth of their individual products, said the people, who were not authorized to speak publicly. And with Mr. Zuckerberg exerting more control, the executives were also fearful of losing autonomy and power, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Chris Cox, Facebook’s chief product officer and a member of Mr. Zuckerberg’s inner circle, is one of the two executives leaving. He alluded to the disagreements on Thursday &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://m.facebook.com/story.php?story_fbid=10104525464789083&amp;amp;id=213466&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in a public post&lt;/a&gt; about his departure. “As Mark has outlined, we are turning a new page in our product direction,” wrote Mr. Cox, 36. “This will be a big project and we will need leaders who are excited to see the new direction through.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The other executive who is exiting is Chris Daniels, 43, who runs WhatsApp. Neither one responded to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/14/business/14cox2/merlin_152079030_f939427f-6d9b-4180-b737-e33cb655e76d-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/14/business/14cox2/merlin_152079030_f939427f-6d9b-4180-b737-e33cb655e76d-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/14/business/14cox2/merlin_152079030_f939427f-6d9b-4180-b737-e33cb655e76d-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/14/business/14cox2/merlin_152079030_f939427f-6d9b-4180-b737-e33cb655e76d-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/14/business/14cox2/merlin_152079030_f939427f-6d9b-4180-b737-e33cb655e76d-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Chris Daniels, the head of WhatsApp, is also leaving Facebook.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Guillermo Legaria/Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook is undergoing a tricky transition as it tries to recover from two years of scandals over data privacy and disinformation. Those issues have &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/14/technology/facebook-data-russia-election-racism.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=inline&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;buffeted the Silicon Valley giant&lt;/a&gt;, causing internal turmoil as its leaders have tried to find a way to adjust. Mr. Zuckerberg has made several attempts to rid Facebook of toxic content, false news and other problems, with limited success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Now, Mr. Zuckerberg is barreling ahead with his shift to focus Facebook on private messaging and away from public broadcasting, even if it means shedding some of his top lieutenants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Cox has worked with Mr. Zuckerberg for 13 years and joined Facebook as one of its first 15 software engineers. Mr. Cox also was instrumental in building the News Feed, the stream of posts that people see when they log into the service, and which more recently has been under scrutiny for being a hive of misinformation. Among some in Silicon Valley, he had been mentioned as a possible successor to Mr. Zuckerberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Embarking on this new vision represents the start of a new chapter for us,” Mr. Zuckerberg said in a note to staff on Thursday. “While it is sad to lose such great people, this also creates opportunities for more great leaders who are energized about the path ahead to take on new and bigger roles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The departures add to the executive turnover at Facebook, which for years had been stable in its top ranks. Mr. Zuckerberg kept close many key executives, including his chief operating officer, Sheryl Sandberg, as well as Mr. Cox and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But that bench has undergone numerous changes more recently as Facebook has grappled with its lapses and tried to reorient itself. Last year, Kevin Systrom and Mike Krieger, the co-founders of Instagram, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/24/technology/instagram-cofounders-resign.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;left the company after clashing&lt;/a&gt; with Mr. Zuckerberg over the future of the photo-sharing network. Jan Koum and Brian Acton, the co-founders of WhatsApp, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/30/technology/whatsapp-facebook-jan-koum.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;also left&lt;/a&gt; after similar disagreements with Mr. Zuckerberg. Other executives, including Facebook’s head of communications and policy and its security chief, have also departed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ben Horowitz, a venture capitalist at Andreessen Horowitz, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bhorowitz/status/1106300167295131648&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that Mr. Zuckerberg’s new direction for Facebook was controversial because it was such a cultural departure for what had been an open and public social network. But he said Mr. Zuckerberg appeared committed to privacy by plowing ahead with the changes even “in the face of extremely strong dissent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“So much so, that he is willing to lose outstanding executives who disagree with this direction,” Mr. Horowitz said. (Mr. Horowitz is a partner at Andreessen Horowitz with Marc Andreessen, a venture capitalist who sits on Facebook’s board.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Inside Facebook, frustration over Mr. Zuckerberg’s planned changes have been mounting for months, said the people involved the situation. Combining Instagram, WhatsApp and Messenger will be a companywide effort that will take years of infrastructure work and deep changes to some of its products, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Daniels, who previously ran Facebook’s business development team and had other roles, was appointed head of WhatsApp last May. He became upset at some of the choices that were being made to connect the apps, said people familiar with his thinking. He was also concerned that Mr. Zuckerberg’s plan would harm the success of WhatsApp, which is particularly popular outside the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Because of those changes, Mr. Daniels handed in his resignation months ago, said two of the people, though the decision did not become public until Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Cox has also been frustrated with Mr. Zuckerberg’s decisions in recent months, some of the people said. Less than a year ago, Mr. Cox &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2018/5/8/17330048/chris-cox-facebook-whatsapp-instagram-messenger-mark-zuckerberg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shifted into&lt;/a&gt; one of the most powerful positions at Facebook as chief product officer, responsible for overseeing Instagram, WhatsApp, Messenger and Facebook itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Almost immediately, Mr. Cox ran into difficulties, the people said. Employees said he disagreed with some of Mr. Zuckerberg’s product ideas and changes, including the “unified messaging” project intended to connect the apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Mr. Zuckerberg had already made his decision. Mr. Cox informed Facebook of his decision to leave on Monday, according to a company filing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“For over a decade, I’ve been sharing the same message that Mark and I have always believed: Social media’s history is not yet written, and its effects are not neutral,” Mr. Cox said in his post. “As its builders we must endeavor to understand its impact — all the good, and all the bad — and take up the daily work of bending it towards the positive, and towards the good.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Zuckerberg has promoted others to take the place of those who have left. Adam Mosseri, a longtime Facebook employee, was promoted to head of Instagram last year. On Thursday, Mr. Zuckerberg said Will Cathcart, another Facebook employee, would run WhatsApp, and Fidji Simo would lead Facebook’s main app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/14/technology/facebook-chris-cox.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook Loses Top Executives, Including Chris Cox</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/14/business/14cox/14cox-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Chris Cox, who is one of the social network’s highest ranking executives, and Chris Daniels, head of WhatsApp, are leaving Facebook.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/14/technology/facebook-chris-cox.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>DARPA Is Building a $10M, Open-Source, Secure Voting System</title>
<link>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/yw84q7/darpa-is-building-a-dollar10-million-open-source-secure-voting-system</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/yw84q7/darpa-is-building-a-dollar10-million-open-source-secure-voting-system</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For years security professionals and election integrity activists have been pushing voting machine vendors to build more secure and verifiable election systems, so voters and candidates can be assured election outcomes haven’t been manipulated.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now they might finally get this thanks to a new $10 million contract the Defense Department’s Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) has launched to design and build a secure voting system that it hopes will be impervious to hacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first-of-its-kind system will be designed by an Oregon-based firm called Galois, a longtime government contractor with experience in designing secure and verifiable systems. The system will use fully open source voting software, instead of the closed, proprietary software currently used in the vast majority of voting machines, which no one outside of voting machine testing labs can examine. More importantly, it will be built on secure open source hardware, made from special secure designs and techniques developed over the last year as part of a special program at DARPA. The voting system will also be designed to create fully verifiable and transparent results so that voters don’t have to blindly trust that the machines and election officials delivered correct results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But DARPA and Galois won’t be asking people to blindly trust that their voting systems are secure—as voting machine vendors currently do. Instead they’ll be publishing source code for the software online and bring prototypes of the systems to the Def Con Voting Village this summer and next, so that hackers and researchers will be able to freely examine the systems themselves and conduct penetration tests to gauge their security. They’ll also be working with a number of university teams over the next year to have them examine the systems in formal test environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Def Con is great, but [hackers there] will not give us as much technical details as we want [about problems they find in the systems],” Linton Salmon, program manager in DARPA’s Microsystems Technology Office who is overseeing the project, said in a phone call. “Universities will give us more information. But we won’t have as many people or as high visibility when we do it with universities.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The systems Galois designs won’t be available for sale. But the prototypes it creates will be available for existing voting machine vendors or others to freely adopt and customize without costly licensing fees or the millions of dollars it would take to research and develop a secure system from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We will not have a voting system that we can deploy. That’s not what we do,” said Salmon. “We will show a methodology that could be used by others to build a voting system that is completely secure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Kiniry is the principal scientist at Galois who is leading the project at his company. Kiniry has been involved in efforts to secure elections for years as part of a separate company he runs called Free &amp;amp; Fair. He’s consulted with foreign governments about their election systems, and his company has been working with states in the US to design robust post-election audits. But the idea to create a secure voting system didn’t come from Kiniry; it came from DARPA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“DARPA was searching for a sexy demonstration for the [secure hardware] program. What could you put on secure hardware that people would care about and understand?” Kiniry said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They needed a project that would be unclassified so DARPA could talk about it publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We wanted something where there could be a lot of people who could look at this in an open way and critique it and find problems,” said Salmon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project will leverage the hefty resources of DARPA and its considerable security experience, and if it works, it could help solve a pressing national problem around election security and integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If we were to build a fake radar system, it could demonstrate secure hardware, but it wouldn’t be useful to anybody. [DARPA] love the fact that we’re building a demonstrator that might actually be useful to the world,” Kiniry said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiniy said Galois will design two basic voting machine types. The first will be a ballot-marking device that uses a touch-screen for voters to make their selections. That system won’t tabulate votes. Instead it will print out a paper ballot marked with the voter’s choices, so voters can review them before depositing them into an optical-scan machine that tabulates the votes. Galois will bring this system to Def Con this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many current ballot-marking systems on the market today have been criticized by security professionals because they print bar codes on the ballot that the scanner can read instead of the human-readable portion voters review. Someone could subvert the bar code to say one thing, while the human-readable portion says something else. Kiniry said they’re aiming to design their system without barcodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The optical-scan system will print a receipt with a cryptographic representation of the voter’s choices. After the election, the cryptographic values for all ballots will be published on a web site, where voters can verify that their ballot and votes are among them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That receipt does not permit you to prove anything about how you voted, but does permit you to prove that the system accurately captured your intent and your vote is in the final tally,” Kiniry said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the public will also be able to use the cryptographic values to independently tally the votes to verify the election results so that tabulating the votes isn't a closed process solely in the hands of election officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Any organization [interested in verifying the election results] that hires a moderately smart software engineer [can] write their own tabulator,” Kiniry said. “We fully expect that Common Cause, League of Women Voters and the [political parties] will all have their own tabulators and verifiers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second system Galois plans to build is an optical-scan system that reads paper ballots marked by voters by hand. They’ll bring that system to Def Con next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voting system project grew out of a larger DARPA program focused on developing secure hardware. That program, called System Security Integrated Through Hardware and Firmware or SSITH, was launched in 2017 and is aimed at developing secure hardware, and design tools to build that hardware, so that hardware would be impervious to most of the software attacks prevalent today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently most security is focused on software protections for operating systems, browsers, and other programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;“This is only the beginning. This is a problem that is so big that one DARPA program isn’t going to solve even 20 percent of the problem.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In general, software has been the way people try to solve the problems because software is adaptable,” Salmon noted. There are some hardware security solutions already, he said, &quot;but they don’t go far enough and … require too much power and performance….We want to fix this in hardware, and then no matter what [vulnerabilities] you have in software, [attackers] would not be able to [exploit] them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic problem, he said, is that most hardware is gullible and has no way of distinguishing between acceptable and unacceptable behavior. If an attacker’s exploit tells the machine to do something malicious, the hardware complies without making judgments about whether it should do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m trying to change that and make hardware part of the solution to security rather than a bystander,” said Salmon. “This is only the beginning. This is a problem that is so big that one DARPA program isn’t going to solve even 20 percent of the problem.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a voting system, this means the hardware would prevent, for example, someone entering a voting booth and slipping a malicious memory card into the system and tricking the system into recording 20 votes for one vote cast, as researchers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usenix.org/legacy/event/evt07/tech/full_papers/feldman/feldman_html/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;have shown could be done with some voting systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our goal is to make this so that the hardware is blocked against all of these various types of attack from the external world. If this is successful, and if the software put on top is equally successful, then it means people can’t hack in and … alter votes. It would also mean that the person who votes would get some verification that they did vote and all of that would be done in a manner that hackers couldn’t change,” Salmon said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DARPA secure hardware program involves six teams from several universities as well as Lockheed Martin. Each team was tasked with creating three secure CPU designs. Galois, which is part of the SSITH project, plans to build its voting system on top of the secure hardware designed by these teams, and will create a prototype for each CPU design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s normal, open source voting system software, which just happens to be running on top of those secure CPUs,” said Kiniry. “Our contention is… that a normal voting system running on COTS [commercial off-the-shelf hardware] will be hacked. A normal voting system running on the secure hardware will probably not be hacked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only are teams developing secure CPUs but to best take advantage of what a secure CPU offers, they’re developing new versions of open source C-compilers so they can recompile the entire software stack on a system—the operating system, the kernel, all the libraries and all the user software that’s written in C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So it really is a powerful software play and hardware play,” Kiniry said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program isn’t about re-architecting new CPUs, but proving that existing hardware can be modified to be made secure, thereby avoiding the need to re-design hardware from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;“Galois and DARPA have just stepped up and filled a vacuum of leadership at the federal level to address the well-documented vulnerabilities in US voting machines that constitute a national security crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even so, the secure designs are expected to change how new CPUs are architected going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Fitzpatrick, a noted hardware security expert who trains professionals on hardware hacking and security, calls the DARPA secure hardware project a lofty goal that will be great if it succeeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I can’t tell if they truly are architecting a new CPU that is truly resistant to all these [attacks]. But if they designed a new CPU that was able to understand and determine malicious or correct operations from the software, that’s not trivial. That would be pretty amazing,” said Fitzpatrick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peiter “Mudge” Zatko, a former program manager at DARPA and &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2016/07/29/a-famed-hacker-is-grading-thousands-of-programs-and-may-revolutionize-software-in-the-process/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;noted security professional&lt;/a&gt; who has testified to Congress on security issues, said this and other DARPA projects are beneficial because they usually spawn new solutions. But he cautions that secure CPUs won’t solve all security problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We should [also] work towards building processors that have more security principles inherent in them,” he told Motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Susan Greenhalgh, policy director for the for the National Election Defense Coalition, an election integrity group, hopes the systems Galois and DARPA are building will finally change the status quo of insecure voting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The [current systems are] woefully equipped and too prosaic to drive the quantum changes needed to face the nation-state actors that are threatening our democracy,” she told Motherboard. “Galois and DARPA have just stepped up and filled a vacuum of leadership at the federal level to address the well-documented vulnerabilities in US voting machines that constitute a national security crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 17:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>shpat</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>DARPA Is Building a $10 Million, Open Source, Secure Voting System</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5c8a6c35a123c60008a49cdf/lede/1552575668247-shutterstock_1046168680.jpeg?crop=1xw:0.8439609902475619xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/yw84q7/darpa-is-building-a-dollar10-million-open-source-secure-voting-system</og:url>
<og:description>The system will be fully open source and designed with newly developed secure hardware to make the system not only impervious to certain kinds of hacking, but also allow voters to verify that their votes were recorded accurately.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/yw84q7/darpa-is-building-a-dollar10-million-open-source-secure-voting-system</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rudder issue that plagued the Boeing 737 throughout the 1990s</title>
<link>https://m.imgur.com/a/5wcFx8M</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://m.imgur.com/a/5wcFx8M</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;qN6ShPU&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;44.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Perhaps the single most complex, insidious, and long-lasting mechanical problem in the history of commercial aviation was the mysterious rudder issue that plagued the Boeing 737 throughout the 1990s. Although it had long been rumoured to exist, the defect was suddenly thrust into the spotlight when United Airlines flight 585 crashed on approach to Colorado Springs on the third of March, 1991, killing all 25 people on board. The crash resulted in the longest investigation in NTSB history, years of arduous litigation, and a battle with Boeing over the safety of its most popular plane. Flight 585 proved to be hardly alone; over the subsequent years, more planes crashed due to the same rudder defect, including USAir flight 427, which killed 132 people when it suddenly rolled over and crashed on approach to Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania in 1994. As it turned out, these were but two of the most serious of hundreds of incidents involving the rudder on the Boeing 737. This is the story of the origin of the defect, its consequences, and Boeing’s efforts to cover it up. Images sourced from The Seattle Times, the NTSB, Boeing, Tails Through Time, the Colorado Springs Gazette, The Times of India, Wikipedia, TribLIVE, The Flight 427 Air Disaster Support League, and Forbes. Video clips courtesy of Cineflix and the Weather Channel. Special thanks to the Seattle Times for its series of articles on the subject in 1996, which brought to light many of the details referenced here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;36Ne1XK&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;The long and complex story begins with the original design of the Boeing 737 in the 1960s. Unlike other Boeing aircraft, the 737 had only one rudder and only one Power Control Unit (PCU), a device which translates pilot inputs into motion of the rudder. This gave it less redundancy than other models, but Boeing got the design certified by showing that a failure of the PCU was so unlikely that it was a non-issue. Nevertheless, reports of mostly minor uncommanded rudder deflections on the 737 began almost immediately. Boeing blamed the yaw damper, a device that constantly adjusts the rudder a few degrees in either direction to counteract an aircraft’s natural tendency to stray off a straight course. These issues were frequently “fixed” by replacing or repairing parts of the yaw damper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;hJ7EL4S&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;36.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Pilots continued to report problems with the rudder on the 737, however. No one was keeping track, but there are estimated to be several hundred reported incidents, including some that were very serious. Among these were four reported in-flight upsets on Frontier Airlines 737s, including two on the same airplane in 1973. In the two latter cases, both over the Dakotas, flight attendants had been injured by the sudden rolling movement, but the pilots were able to regain control. Boeing again responded by modifying the yaw damper; no attention was paid to the PCU, despite the fact that the yaw damper was limited from moving the rudder far enough to cause the sort of major upsets reported by the Frontier crews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;NvSIrF7&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;It is now known that the problem was probably with the PCU all along. To understand the crashes that occurred later, it is first necessary to summarize the specific vulnerability that was causing these incidents. The most important component of the PCU is a small device called the dual servo valve, shown in the above diagram from the Seattle Times. In simple terms, the valve consists of an inner and outer slide which, when lined up in different ways, can direct the flow of hydraulic fluid to push the rudder left or right. (A more detailed explanation can be seen in the diagram.) A spring and an end cap are supposed to prevent the slides from moving too far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;bdCBke8&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;However, if the spring and the end cap were slightly misaligned, the slides could extend beyond their design limit. This would cause a “rudder hardover,” where the rudder suddenly moves to its maximum deflection, resulting in extremely serious control problems. But this was only one part of the issue. When the slides in the dual servo valve extended too far, it would also misalign the openings on the outer slide and the valve body, allowing hydraulic fluid to move into the wrong channels and causing a rare phenomenon called “rudder reversal.” Essentially, the misaligned valve would allow hydraulic pressure intended to push the rudder in one direction to be channeled into a part of the actuator that would push the rudder in the opposite direction. In a rudder reversal, the effects of the rudder pedals would be reversed; trying to turn the rudder left would in fact turn it right, and vice versa. Because a rudder reversal could only happen when the slides were extended too far, it could only happen at the same time as a rudder hardover, right when pilots need to react quickly to counter the sudden roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;AVYYb34&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot; readability=&quot;37.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;On the third of March 1991, this hidden flaw turned deadly for the first time. United Airlines flight 585, a Boeing 737, took off from Denver, Colorado with 20 passengers and 5 crew members on board for a short 23-minute hop to Colorado Springs. As the plane approached Colorado Springs, all appeared normal. Suddenly, the plane rolled hard to the right and dived toward the ground. The pilots fought to save their plane, but they didn’t have enough time or altitude, and flight 585 nosedived into a park in the Colorado Springs suburb of Security-Widefield, killing all 25 people on board. The plane came in so low that witnesses saw terrified passengers inside, and the explosion shattered apartment windows in a nearby apartment complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;ZkZcxZ3&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Witnesses and emergency services rushed to the scene, but soon realized that no one could possibly have survived. The wreckage had been thrust into a 10-foot-deep crater and crumpled like an accordion; there was virtually nothing at the site that was recognizable as having been part of a plane. Investigators faced an enormous challenge, but they did soon cast their suspicions on the PCU. However, the yaw damper, which was an early suspect, had been compressed to one tenth of its original size and could not be examined. The servo valve was also heavily damaged, but investigators wanted to test it anyway, so they took it to the manufacturer for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;Hazh8Ze&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;39.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;The remains of the valve were taken from the United Airlines headquarters to the headquarters of Parker Bertea, the company that designed and built the valve, in Irvine, California. Investigators discovered upon their arrival that someone had made off with the spring and end cap, but at the time they did not know the significance of this act. The NTSB and Parker Bertea replaced the spring, the end cap, and several other parts that were ruined in the crash and began running tests on the valve. Nothing abnormal was found. Boeing, which had packed the valve for shipping, did not explain why it kept the spring and the end cap. It instead tried to steer the NTSB toward a conclusion that the crash was caused by a wind rotor, a phenomenon similar to a sideways tornado that could sometimes be found along the Rocky Mountains. The NTSB did not buy the theory, but it also could not find any evidence that the dual servo valve had failed. Then, in 1993, the captain of a United Airlines flight alerted maintenance to apparent problems with the plane’s rudder while on the tarmac in Chicago, and the dual servo valve was found to be faulty. But investigators were unable to prove that this same malfunction had happened on flight 585, and the investigation ended without determining a probable cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;a6KyWFy&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Three more significant incidents possibly involving this malfunction occurred in 1994. In April of that year, a Continental Airlines Boeing 737 suddenly rolled hard to the right while flying near Honduras. The pilots struggled against the roll for 18 minutes before making a successful emergency landing. When Boeing got wind of the incident, it blamed it on the yaw damper, even though it was demonstrated that the yaw damper couldn’t cause a roll as severe or long-lasting as the one the pilots of the Continental Airlines plane experienced. In a report acquired by the Seattle Times, the flight’s captain, Ray Miller, wrote: “I have been told by my company . . . that the FAA and Boeing (were) aware of the problems with the spurious rudder inputs but considered them to be more of a nuisance problem than a flight safety issue. I was informed, that so far as everyone was concerned, the rudder hardovers were a problem but that the `industry' felt the losses would be in the acceptable range. I was being mollified into thinking the incident did not happen, and for the `greater good' it would be best not to pursue the matter. In other words I am expendable as are the passengers I am responsible for, because for liability reasons the FAA, Boeing et al cannot retroactively redesign the rudder mechanisms to improve their reliability.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;ZFYtmtu&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;In August 1994, a Sahara India Airlines Boeing 737 conducting training approaches at New Delhi airport suddenly rolled over and crashed after a touch-and-go takeoff, striking an Ilyushin aircraft that was parked on the tarmac. All four crew members were killed, as well as five people working on the Ilyushin. Indian investigators said that the trainee pilot had pressed the wrong rudder pedal while responding to a simulated engine failure, but American investigators also found that the spring and end cap on the servo valve were non-standard; they had actually had their original serial numbers scrubbed off and replaced with new ones. Tests on the unusual servo valve found that it would sometimes reverse, but the crash was not officially blamed on a PCU malfunction despite this evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;19H4NgC&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot; readability=&quot;41.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Finally, in September 1994, the series of events took a new, disturbing turn. USAir flight 427, a Boeing 737 carrying 127 passengers and 5 crew from Chicago, Illinois to Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, was on final approach when it suddenly rolled violently to the left. The pilots, caught by surprise, fought to bring the wings level, but due to the rudder reversal, they were actually steering their plane into the ground. It entered a vertical dive straight toward the ground, spinning around like a top. The captain managed to make a radio call to air traffic control, exclaiming, “Four two seven, emergency!” He accidentally left the radio on, broadcasting the final seconds of the flight into the control tower, until the plane slammed into a wooded ravine, killing all 132 people on board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;SIcg2rT&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;38.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;This time, NTSB investigators suspected that the dual servo valve was responsible and they wanted to prove it. They ensured that the device was carefully preserved and was not tampered with, but again, they couldn’t test it without replacing some parts. The tests were inconclusive. However, metal particulate matter was discovered in the hydraulic fluid, which could have caused the valve to jam in the rudder hardover position. Boeing tried to dismiss this claim by showing that a metal particle jammed inside the valve would leave scratch marks when the valve moved; such scratch marks were not present on the valve from USAir flight 427. The NTSB was not convinced, and investigators believed that smaller particles in large concentrations, or fewer small particles in low temperatures, could cause a jam without leaving a mark. They also were able to demonstrate that cooling the valve to -40˚C and commanding it to pump hot hydraulic fluid could cause it to jam, but could not explain how such a large temperature differential could occur in flight. However, they did also discover that one in five Boeing 737s had much more particulate matter in their hydraulic fluid than recommended, and that the outer slide of the dual servo valve could jam for long periods without being noticed, making the otherwise rare simultaneous jam of the inner and outer slides much more probable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;fQbsPxI&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot; readability=&quot;37.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;While the USAir investigation was ongoing, more incidents continued to happen. In June 1996, Eastwind Airlines flight 517, a Boeing 737 carrying 53 passengers and crew from Trenton, New Jersey to Richmond, Virginia rolled sharply to the right on landing. The pilots applied full left ailerons to right the plane, but reported that the rudder pedals were unresponsive, indicating that a jam had taken place. The captain held the plane in a precarious sort of sideways flight for thirty seconds. After this harrowing half-minute, the plane leveled itself, and the pilots landed the plane. One flight attendant was injured, but a catastrophic accident had been avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;GckDfUS&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;After the Eastwind incident, Boeing took the captain of that flight on a test run in which they simulated a yaw damper failure. The result did not at all resemble what the Eastwind pilot had actually encountered. Boeing’s narrative was further undermined when tests of an alternative theory for the USAir crash failed to support their hypothesis. Instead, Boeing tried to claim that flight 427 crashed because a pilot had a seizure and depressed the rudder. NTSB investigators dismissed this as ridiculous. Now with all the evidence they needed thanks to the additional information provided by having an intact aircraft and living pilot after the Eastwind Airlines incident, they were ready to blame Boeing’s PCU valve. The NTSB report recommended that the valve be redesigned, and the Federal Aviation Administration mandated that the changes be implemented by November 2002. Since then, no 737s have crashed due to rudder hardover or rudder reversal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;9pz66TE&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;34.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Boeing had no choice but to carry out the changes, but the company never stopped trying to deflect blame. While the investigation was ongoing, it adopted a philosophy of trying to avoid paying out damages to families of crews because this could be legally interpreted as an admission of responsibility. It had tampered with the PCU from the Colorado Springs crash and repeatedly tried to misdirect the investigation with “alternative” theories. It is widely suspected that Boeing knew about the problems with the PCU for decades but had done nothing, despite the hundreds of reported incidents. Because no one was collecting all the accounts of rudder deflections, it was likely that no one except Boeing realized how common they were. It was not until people started dying in crashes that enough scrutiny was placed on the 737 to uncover this history of ignoring the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;pKjd7jm&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;34.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Another lesson to come from this sorry series of events is the paramount importance of finding the cause of every disaster. Families of victims believe that if the investigation into the crash of United flight 585 had been conducted properly, the tragedy of USAir flight 427 never would have happened. And there are other crashes that might be connected to the same failure—some still argue that rudder hardover caused the 1992 crash of Copa Airlines flight 201 in Panama, ruled to be pilot error in response to a malfunctioning instrument; and the 1997 crash of Silkair flight 185 in Indonesia, ruled by the NTSB to be pilot suicide, but determined to be rudder hardover by its Indonesian counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;VSwQQBz&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-meta post-image-meta--last&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-image-description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;The crashes also highlighted the vulnerability of the NTSB to corporate meddling. In 1996, According to the Seattle Times, the safety board had only 90 employees and relied on manufacturers to provide technical expertise in cases like the United 585 and USAir 427 crashes, which made it much harder to investigate cases where the manufacturer knew that it was responsible. Boeing’s obfuscation at every turn was pure corporate expediency: fixing the problem would require a massive recall costing hundreds of millions of dollars, not to mention millions more in compensation that would have to be paid out if Boeing admitted responsibility. Even when the flaw began to result in deadly crashes, Boeing stuck by this policy. Had the failure been easier to detect and prove, they might not have been able to get away with it, but—thanks in part to Boeing’s muddying of the waters—they never faced the massive backlash that they should have received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>IFR</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://imgur.com/a/5wcFx8M</og:url>
<og:title>Imgur</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.imgur.com/qN6ShPU.jpg?fb</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://imgur.com/a/5wcFx8M</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Roll Your Own Analytics</title>
<link>https://www.pcmaffey.com/roll-your-own-analytics/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.pcmaffey.com/roll-your-own-analytics/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Google Analytics runs on over &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://w3techs.com/technologies/details/ta-googleanalytics/all/all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;56% of all websites.&lt;/a&gt; It’s the backbone of ad-tech across the web. Unfortunately, for site owners like me who just want to learn how people are using their website—while respecting their privacy—there simply aren't any alternatives that meet all my requirements. So in two days, after a couple dead-ends, I built my own using React, AWS Lambda, and a spreadsheet. This is how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H3-___styles__h3___3gUoQ&quot;&gt;My Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;No 3rd-party tracking -&lt;/strong&gt; When you visit my site, no one else is listening in. That means, no calls to any 3rd-party domains &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;from the client.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; No tracking snippets or pixels. No 3rd-party cookies. (Also, don’t use Google Fonts!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Anonymous -&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t store any personal data, unless given with permission (eg. email for newsletter). Don’t store IP addresses or superfluous session data that could be used for fingerprinting. This way, my site is GDPR compliant by default. And while not a hard requirement, I don’t use cookies to track visitors across multiple sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Avoid ad-blockers -&lt;/strong&gt; My goal with analytics is to learn how people use my site so I can improve it and serve them better. I'm not using ad-tech so there's no point in getting blocked by 25% of visitors with an ad-blocker. That means doing 1st-party analytics, without using a 3rd-party tracking snippet—&lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;even self-hosted!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;No bloat -&lt;/strong&gt; What’s the minimum number of network calls required to log a full session? Turns out, the answer is 1. &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;Unlike every tracking snippet.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Free -&lt;/strong&gt; I spin up a lot of sites for various projects. Having a free tier when getting started is critical. So everything in this stack needs to be free up to a certain level—beyond that, I’m happy to upgrade and pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Easily replicable -&lt;/strong&gt; I want to be able to copy and paste a few things and set up analytics for a new site’s analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;No server -&lt;/strong&gt; I use (and love!) &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;’s free static site hosting. It doesn’t provide access to server logs though—which rules out log-based analytics, like &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://goaccess.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Go Access&lt;/a&gt; (which would satisfy most of the other requirements). Fortunately, Netlify does provide free proxied access to AWS Lambda functions…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H3-___styles__h3___3gUoQ&quot;&gt;The Stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;I wanted to set this up quickly, so I decided on the most easily accessible tools for my &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;current go-to stack.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; You could swap out any of these layers for your preferred tech. If you're expecting higher usage, you'll almost certainly want a &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;more robust data store.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Here's how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;src-elements-text-List-___styles__list___1KvBZ&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;1.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Log a session on the client&lt;/strong&gt; (React, state + context API)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;When the session ends...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;2.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Call a lambda function&lt;/strong&gt; (AWS Lambda via Netlify)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;3.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Store the data in Google Sheets&lt;/strong&gt; (Google Sheets, Google App Scripts)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H3-___styles__h3___3gUoQ&quot;&gt;3.3 Define the Data Model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Working backwards, I start by defining what data I care about tracking. This is actually one of the biggest ancillary benefits of rolling your own analytics. I get to perfectly fit my analytics to my application. How much of GA do you really understand and use anyways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;My initial use case is a common one. I'm building &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.featherbubble.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;featherbubble.com&lt;/a&gt;, an interactive children's story. The site has a landing page and a waitlist conversion page. I'll soon add a pilot episode people can read through to preview. So, a site with a few pages and a conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Track sessions, not people, mostly events.&lt;/strong&gt; All I want to know is referrer and some session metadata like language, timezone, and device. And then I want to log what happened &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;using events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; and summarize that in the session table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;I create a new Google Sheet &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://sheet.new&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;(sheet.new)&lt;/a&gt; with two sheets:&lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;Sessions&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;Events&lt;/code&gt;. Put the column headers in the first row. A logged session looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H4-___styles__h4___14T42&quot;&gt;Sessions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.pcmaffey.com/sessions.png&quot; class=&quot;src-elements-images-PImg-___styles__img___qJhzQ&quot; title=&quot;Sessions Sheet Headers&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;Here's some more details about each field.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H4-___styles__h4___14T42&quot;&gt;Events&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.pcmaffey.com/events.png&quot; class=&quot;src-elements-images-PImg-___styles__img___qJhzQ&quot; title=&quot;Events Sheet Headers&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;And details about the event fields.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Again, you can customize these fields to your heart's content. Instead of shoehorning all your data into the complicated event mappings of Category/Action/Label/Value fields (or Segment’s analytics.js `properties` field), you can simply create a new column with what you want to track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H3-___styles__h3___3gUoQ&quot;&gt;3.2 Save the Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;I initially tried to use Google’s Sheets API. This is a dead-end. Even with an API key, while you can read data from a spreadsheet, &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/36755576&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&quot;anonymous edits aren’t currently supported.&quot;&lt;/a&gt; The API needs an auth token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Fortunately, there’s an even easier way (without needing to walk through the complexity of Oauth configuration): Google App Scripts. From your spreadsheet menu, &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;Tools &amp;gt; Script Editor&lt;/code&gt;, you can publish a script that will run operations on your spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;I got the idea &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@dmccoy/how-to-submit-an-html-form-to-google-sheets-without-google-forms-b833952cc175&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;from here&lt;/a&gt;, and modified the script to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;src-elements-text-List-___styles__list___1KvBZ&quot; readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;a.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Handle POST requests (instead of GET) to receive a JSON object of Session data, with an array of Events:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__code___3vQrL&quot;&gt;  {
    
    sessionId: &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'1234'&lt;/span&gt;,
    device: &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'iPad'&lt;/span&gt;,
    ...,
    Events: [{
      
      sessionId: &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'1234'&lt;/span&gt;,
      event: &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'/'&lt;/span&gt;,
      ...,
    }]
  }&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;b.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Parse and write that data to the Sessions and Events sheets. The script will match whatever column headers you use for each sheet to the keys in your JSON blob&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;c.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aggregate daily totals to a 3rd sheet called ‘Analytics’ (more on that below)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;d.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Send me an email if it errors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/pcmaffey/54dee24efe02ef5d6d7b38595be1d8a0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Here's the full gist.&lt;/a&gt; Copy that into the script editor, make your changes and save it. To publish, in the menu go to &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;Publish &amp;gt; Deploy to web app...&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;A few important gotchas about publishing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;src-elements-text-List-___styles__list___1KvBZ&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;✱&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;You must execute the app as yourself (ie. an authenticated google account)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;✱&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Give access to &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;Anyone, even anonymous&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;✱&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Save the web app URL and treat it like an API KEY. Don’t publish to Git.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;✱&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;When you make changes to the script, you will need to redeploy it and update the project version to &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;New&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;✱&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;You need to manually run the &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;setup&lt;/code&gt; function. From the menu, &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;Run function &amp;gt; setup&lt;/code&gt; You only ever need to do this once.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Now you’ve got an API endpoint you can use to store analytics data in your spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H3-___styles__h3___3gUoQ&quot;&gt;3.1 Bonus: Aggregate Daily Totals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Getting the data in is only half the battle. I want to make my analytics easily consumable. For me, that means a daily summary, in my inbox. So, because my spreadsheet-fu is not very good, instead of figuring out pivot tables, I decided to write a script that aggregates the session data each day, adds it to a 3rd “Analytics” sheet, and emails me a report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H4-___styles__h4___14T42&quot;&gt;Analytics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.pcmaffey.com/analytics.png&quot; class=&quot;src-elements-images-PImg-___styles__img___qJhzQ&quot; title=&quot;Analytics Sheet Headers&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;Here's what I'm aggregating.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Instead of running a daily cron job, whenever a new session is saved, I check to see if the previous day’s sessions have been aggregated. If not, I total them up and email myself a report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;dailyTotals&lt;/code&gt; function is &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;included in the gist above.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;With the daily summaries in a spreadsheet, I can easily turn that into a chart and view by week, month, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H3-___styles__h3___3gUoQ&quot;&gt;2. The Lambda Function&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Serverless lambda functions are perfect for an analytics API. Logging doesn't require a response. This makes the cold start issue with lambda functions negligible. Of course, there's no reason you couldn't use a regular server endpoint, especially if you've already got an API. But for a static site, the free and easy setup with Netlify along with the potential to scale effortlessly makes it an obvious choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Using Netlify's &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;free tier,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; access to AWS Lambda functions are easy to setup. I won't go into the details, since there are plenty of resources out there already. Here are the important parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;src-elements-text-List-___styles__list___1KvBZ&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;1.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Setup your functions -&lt;/strong&gt; Check out Netlify's &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/netlify/create-react-app-lambda&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;create-react-app-lambda&lt;/a&gt; package or &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/blog/2018/07/09/building-serverless-crud-apps-with-netlify-functions--faunadb/#3-create-a-function&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; for how to get started with Lamda functions in a React app. I'm using the &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/netlify/netlify-lambda&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;netlify-lambda package&lt;/a&gt; to build my functions with webpack.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;2.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Get a proxied endpoint -&lt;/strong&gt; Once setup, you'll be able to post data to &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;example.com/.netlify/functions/my-function&lt;/code&gt;, and viola, your analytics API calls are to your own domain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;3.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Parse and format data -&lt;/strong&gt; When the lambda function receives the raw session data from the client, I have it do most of the work to format the data and do things like: generate a sessionId and add it to each event, count the number of PAGE events, check for a conversion, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;4.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Post it -&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, I post the formatted Session data as JSON to the Google Sheets / App Script url, which I'm storing as an environment variable in Netlify.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Here's my lambda function code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__code___3vQrL&quot;&gt;
import &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'regenerator-runtime/runtime'&lt;/span&gt;

import fetch from &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'node-fetch'&lt;/span&gt;


const { GOOGLE_SHEETS_URL } = process.env


import genId from &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'./helpers/genId'&lt;/span&gt;
import getDevice from &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'./helpers/getDevice'&lt;/span&gt;
import isBot from &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'./helpers/isBot'&lt;/span&gt;

export const handler = async event =&amp;gt; {
  const data = JSON.parse(event.body)

  
  if (!data || !data.events) return throw &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'Invalid data'&lt;/span&gt;
  
  if (isBot(data.userAgent)) return

  let waitlist
  let pages = 0

  
  const events = data.events.sort((a, b) =&amp;gt; {
    
    if (~a.event.indexOf(&lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'joined waitlist'&lt;/span&gt;)) waitlist = true
    
    if (a.label === &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'PAGE'&lt;/span&gt;) pages += 1
    if (a.timestamp &amp;gt; b.timestamp) return 1
    else if (a.timestamp &amp;lt; b.timestamp) return -1
    return 0
  })

  
  const Session = {
    
    sessionId: genId(events[0].timestamp),
    startedAt: events[0].timestamp,
    ref: data.ref,
    
    device: getDevice(data.userAgent),
    userAgent: data.userAgent,
    language: data.language,
    timezone: data.timezone,
    latency: data.latency,
    pageLoad: data.pageLoad,
    
    length: events[events.length - 1].timestamp - events[0].timestamp,
    waitlist: waitlist || null,
    pages: pages,
  }

  
  Session.Events = events.map((e, i) =&amp;gt; ({
    sessionId: Session.sessionId,
    timestamp: e.timestamp,
    event: e.event,
    label: e.label || null,
    
    length: i &amp;lt; events.length - 1 ? events[i + 1].timestamp - e.timestamp : 0,
  }))

  
  try {
    const response = await fetch(GOOGLE_SHEETS_URL, {
      body: JSON.stringify(Session),
      method: &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'POST'&lt;/span&gt;,
      headers: {
        &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'Content-Type'&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'application/json'&lt;/span&gt;,
      },
    })

    return {
      statusCode: 200,
      body: JSON.stringify({ response }),
    }
  } catch (error) {
    console.log(error) 
    return {
      statusCode: 500,
      body: JSON.stringify({ msg: error.message }),
    }
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H3-___styles__h3___3gUoQ&quot;&gt;1.3 One Call (to rule them all)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Now that I've got a serverless endpoint, I just need to log a visitor's session and events from the client. There are a couple major differences with how I'm doing things vs. a &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;standard analytics implementation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;I make a single call at the end of a session, posting the entire session log as JSON to my lambda function. How do I know when a session ends? Unfortunately, there's no magic bullet for universal coverage across all browsers and all cases. Instead, I'm listening for several exit events and gracefully degrading based on what's happening in the client's browser. While I haven't done a side-by-side test with a standard implmentation, I'd estimate I'm covering around &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;95% of visitor sessions.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;I'm sending the data with &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;navigator.sendBeacon&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;if it's available,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; which posts the session data in the background without waiting for a response. As a fallback, I have several levels of degradation that get called based on browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Here's the simplified version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__code___3vQrL&quot;&gt;
window.addEventListener(&lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'pagehide'&lt;/span&gt;, endSession)
window.addEventListener(&lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'beforeunload'&lt;/span&gt;, endSession)
window.addEventListener(&lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'unload'&lt;/span&gt;, endSession)

if (iOS) window.addEventListener(&lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'blur'&lt;/span&gt;, endSession)

let skip

const endSession = () =&amp;gt; {
  
  if (skip) return
  skip = true

  
  const data = SESSION_DATA
  const url = FUNCTION_URL

  const { vendor } = window.navigator

  
  
  if (window.navigator.sendBeacon &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !~vendor.indexOf(&lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'Apple'&lt;/span&gt;)) {
    
    const beacon = window.navigator.sendBeacon(url, data)
    if (beacon) return
    
  }

  
  
  const async = !iOS
  const request = new XMLHttpRequest()
  request.open(&lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'POST'&lt;/span&gt;, url, async) 
  request.setRequestHeader(&lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'Content-Type'&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'application/json'&lt;/span&gt;)
  request.send(data)

  
  

  
  if (!async || ~vendor.indexOf(&lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'Google'&lt;/span&gt;)) return

  
  const latency = data.latency || 0
  const t = Date.now() + Math.max(300, latency + 200)
  while (Date.now() &amp;lt; t) {
    
    
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;The benefit to this strategy is a lightweight solution, both for the client and the API—which is subject to usage rates. You could certainly implement a more standard approach to log each interaction as it happens, but it will likely cost much more at any kind of scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H3-___styles__h3___3gUoQ&quot;&gt;1.2 Log Session Metadata&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;With React, it's easy to make a few reusable components for all my analytics. I use react-router, and render my main Analytics component with every route: &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;Route component={Analytics} /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;This component has 3 main functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;src-elements-text-List-___styles__list___1KvBZ&quot; readability=&quot;23.125628140704&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;1.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Start session -&lt;/strong&gt; Rather than calling this onMount, I'm registering an on &quot;load&quot; event listener that starts the session once the document has fully loaded. This way, if a visitor bounces before the page finishes loading, I ignore it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;  &lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then, I log the initial PAGE event (more about event logging in the next section), save some session and &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/webperformance/basics/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;page performance&lt;/a&gt; metadata in the component's state, and then register my endSession event listeners.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;2.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;End session -&lt;/strong&gt; As described in the previous section, when the session ends, I grab the session data from the component store and post it to my lambda function's url.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__li___3Ki4R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-Li-___styles__b___2JgSN&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;3.&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Listen to route changes -&lt;/strong&gt; When the &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;path changes,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; I log a page view as an event.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__code___3vQrL&quot;&gt;if (location.pathname !== prevProps.location.pathname) {
  event(location.pathname, { label: &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'PAGE'&lt;/span&gt; })
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H3-___styles__h3___3gUoQ&quot;&gt;1.1 Log Events&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;The event logging component is a tad more complicated, as the &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;event()&lt;/code&gt; function needs to be accessible anywhere in the code I want to log an event from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;To accomplish this, I'm using &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/docs/context.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;React Context&lt;/a&gt; as a &quot;global&quot; store for both my array of events and the push function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;I create an Events component for the &lt;a class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__link___3rhcE&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;context provider,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;src-elements-text-Note-___styles__char___TpOpp&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand&quot;&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; that stores the events in local state, and passes into &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;Context.Provider&lt;/code&gt; a function that adds a new event to the array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__code___3vQrL&quot;&gt;
event(name, properties = {}) {
  const event = {
    event: name,
    timestamp: new Date().getTime(),
    ...properties,
  }

  events.push(event)
  this.setState({ events })

  
  if (dev) {
    const { label, ...rest } = properties
    console.log(label + &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;': '&lt;/span&gt; + name, JSON.stringify(rest))
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;I can then create a &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;Context.Consumer&lt;/code&gt; anywhere in my code to access the context. I try and avoid render functions as a pattern, so I turn my context consumer into a helpful higher-order component:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__code___3vQrL&quot;&gt;
const Event = Component =&amp;gt; {
  const setContext = props =&amp;gt; (
    &amp;lt;SetContext.Consumer&amp;gt;
      {context =&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Component {...props} event={context} /&amp;gt;}
    &amp;lt;/SetContext.Consumer&amp;gt;
  )
  return setContext
}


import Event from &lt;span class=&quot;src-elements-text-CodeBlock-___styles__string___3MaeI&quot;&gt;'..'&lt;/span&gt;
const MyComponent = ({ event }) =&amp;gt; {}
export default Event(MyComponent)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;You could probably do this even easier now with Hooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;The final step is to grab from context the array of events in the &lt;code class=&quot;src-elements-text-Code-___styles__code___3-kjQ&quot;&gt;endSession()&lt;/code&gt; function and post it as part of the session data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;src-elements-text-H3-___styles__h3___3gUoQ&quot;&gt;A Final Note&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;On performance -&lt;/strong&gt; I'm just starting to use this this analytics setup with a couple brand new sites (including this one, first post!). As I learn how this performs with traffic, I will update this section with details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;src-elements-text-B-___styles__b___7SctX&quot;&gt;Asking for help -&lt;/strong&gt; If you need help setting this up for yourself, feel free to send me an email at &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.pcmaffey.com/pc.png&quot; class=&quot;src-modules-site-MyEmail-___styles__img___3ijTX&quot;/&gt;, and I will do my best to answer your questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;src-elements-text-P-___styles__p___2XSos&quot;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 12:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pcmaffey</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.pcmaffey.com/roll-your-own-analytics</og:url>
<og:title>Roll Your Own Analytics - PC Maffey</og:title>
<og:description>How to build a free, privacy-focused alternative to Google Analytics</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.pcmaffey.com/roll.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.pcmaffey.com/roll-your-own-analytics/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Krita 4.2.0: First painting application with HDR support on Windows</title>
<link>https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-2-0-the-first-painting-application-to-bring-hdr-support-to-windows</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-2-0-the-first-painting-application-to-bring-hdr-support-to-windows</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Published    3/14/2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re deep in bug fixing mode now, because in May we want to release the next major version of Krita: Krita 4.2.0. While there will be a host of new features, a plethora of bug fixes and performance improvements, one thing is unique: support for painting in HDR mode. Krita is the very first application, open source or proprietary, that offers this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, today we release a preview version of Krita 4.2.0 with HDR support baked in, so you can give the new functionality a try!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, at this moment, only &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/4040263/windows-10-hdr-advanced-color-settings&quot;&gt;Windows 10 supports HDR&lt;/a&gt; monitors, and only with some very specific hardware. Your CPU and GPU need to be new enough, and you need to have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://displayhdr.org/certified-products/&quot;&gt;monitor that supports HDR&lt;/a&gt;. We know that the brave folks at Intel are working on HDR support for Linux, though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is HDR?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HDR stands for High Dynamic Range. The opposite is, of course, Low Dynamic Range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, many people when hearing the word “HDR” will think of the HDR mode of their phone’s cameras. Those cameras map together images taken at different exposure levels in one image to create, within the small dynamic range of a normal image, the illusion of a high dynamic range image, with often quite unnatural results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not that! Tone-mapping is old-hat. These days, manufacturers are bringing out new monitors that can go much brighter than traditional monitors, up to a 1000 nits (a standard for brightness), or even brighter for professional monitors. And modern systems, Intel 7th generation Core CPU’s, support these monitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it’s not just brightness, these days most normal monitors are manufactured to display the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SRGB&quot;&gt;sRGB&lt;/a&gt; gamut. This is fairly limited, and lacks quite a bit of greens (some profession monitors have a wider gamut, of course). HDR monitors use a far wider gamut, with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rec._2020&quot;&gt;Rec. 2020&lt;/a&gt; colorspace. And instead of using traditional exponential gamma correction, they use &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-dynamic-range_video#Perceptual_Quantizer&quot;&gt;Perceptual Quantizer (PQ)&lt;/a&gt;, which not just extends the dynamic range to sun-bright values, but also allows to encode very dark areas, not available in usual sRGB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-9053&quot; src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;423&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image3.png 640w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image3-300x198.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, many laptop panels only support 6 bits per channel; most monitors only 8 bits, monitors for graphics professionals 10 bits per channel — but HDR monitors support from 10 to 16 bits per channel. This means much nicer gradations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s early days, though, and from a developers’ point of view, the current situation is messy. It’s hard to understand how everything fits together, and we’ll surely have to update Krita in the future when things straighten out, or if we discover we’ve misunderstood something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So… The only platform that supports HDR is Windows 10 via DirectX. Linux, nope, OpenGL, nah, macOS, not likely. Since Krita speaks OpenGL, not DirectX, we had to hack the OpenGL to DirectX compatibility layer, Angle, to support the extensions needed to work in HDR. Then we had to hack Qt to make it possible to convert the UI (things like buttons and panels) from sRGB to p2020-pq, while keeping the main canvas unconverted. We had to add, of course, a HDR capable color selector. All in all, quite a few months of hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s just the technical bit: the important bit is how people actually can create new HDR images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;So, why is this cool?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve got a wider range of colors to work with. You’ve got a wider range of dark to light to work with: you can actually paint with pure light, if you want to. What you’re doing when creating an HDR image is, in a way, not painting something as it should be shown on a display, but as the light falls on a scene. There’s so much new flexibility here that we’ll be discovering new ways to make use of it for quite some time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d have a HDR compatible set-up, and a browser that would support HDR, well, this video could be in HDR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4O1kxEL9naw?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Image by Wolthera van Hövell tot Westerflier)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;And how do I use it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have a HDR capable monitor, a D&lt;span class=&quot;ng-isolate-scope&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ng-scope&quot;&gt;isplayPort 1.4 or HDMI 2.0&lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt; (the ‘a’ is important!) or higher&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; cable, the latest version of Windows 10 with WDDM 2.4 drivers and a CPU and GPU that supports hits, this is how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/4040263/windows-10-hdr-advanced-color-settings&quot;&gt;switch the display to HDR mode manually, in the Windows settings utility&lt;/a&gt;. Now Windows will start talking to the display in p2020-pq mode. To make sure that you don’t freak out because everything looks weird, you’ll have to select a default SDR brightness level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_settings.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-9055&quot; src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_settings.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1199&quot; height=&quot;1222&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_settings.png 1199w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_settings-294x300.png 294w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_settings-768x783.png 768w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_settings-1005x1024.png 1005w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1199px) 100vw, 1199px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to configure Krita to support HDR. In the &lt;em&gt;Settings → Configure Krita → Display&lt;/em&gt; settings panel you need to select your preferred surface. You’ll also want to select the HDR-capable &lt;strong&gt;small color selector&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;em&gt;Settings → Dockers&lt;/em&gt; menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_krita_settings.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-9056&quot; src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_krita_settings.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1456&quot; height=&quot;1224&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_krita_settings.png 1456w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_krita_settings-300x252.png 300w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_krita_settings-768x646.png 768w, https://krita.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/hdr_krita_settings-1024x861.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1456px) 100vw, 1456px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a proper HDR image, you will need to make a canvas using a profile with the rec 2020 gamut and a linear tone-response-curve: “Rec2020-elle-V4-g10.icc” is the profile you need to choose. HDR images are standardized to use the Rec2020 gamut, and the PQ trc. However, a linear TRC is easier to edit images in, so we don’t convert to PQ until we’re satisfied with our image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krita’s native .kra file format can save HDR images just fine. You should use that as your working format. For sharing with other image editors, you should use the OpenEXR format. For sharing on the Web, you can use the expanded PNG format. Since all this is so new, there’s not much support for that standard yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also make HDR animations… Which is pretty cool! And you can export your animations to mp4 and H.265. You need a version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.ffmpeg.org/wiki/Encode/H.265&quot;&gt;FFMpeg&lt;/a&gt; that supports H.265. And after telling Krita where to find that, it’s simply a matter of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have an animation open.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select File → Render Animation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select Video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select Render as MPEG-4 video or Matroska&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press the configure button next to the fileformat dropdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select at the top ‘H.265, MPEG-H Part 2 (HEVC)’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select for the Profile: ‘main10’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The HDR Mode checkbox should now be enabled: toggle it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click ‘HDR Metadata’ to configure the HDR metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, when done, click ‘render’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have a CPU of 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; gen Core or later with intel Graphics integrated you can take advantage of HW accelerated encode to save time in the export stage: ffmpeg does that for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, this version of Krita is &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; useful for Windows users. Linux graphics developers, get a move on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Windows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ssba-classic-2 ssba ssbp-wrap left ssbp--theme-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;linkedin&quot; class=&quot;ssba_linkedin_share ssba_share_link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/shareArticle?mini=true&amp;amp;url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-2-0-the-first-painting-application-to-bring-hdr-support-to-windows/&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/linkedin.png&quot; title=&quot;LinkedIn&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on LinkedIn&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linkedin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a data-site=&quot;pinterest&quot; class=&quot;ssba_pinterest_share&quot; href=&quot;javascript:void((function()%7Bvar%20e=document.createElement('script');e.setAttribute('type','text/javascript');e.setAttribute('charset','UTF-8');e.setAttribute('src','//assets.pinterest.com/js/pinmarklet.js?r='+Math.random()*99999999);document.body.appendChild(e)%7D)());&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/pinterest.png&quot; title=&quot;Pinterest&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Pin on Pinterest&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pinterest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; ssba_sharecount&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;reddit&quot; class=&quot;ssba_reddit_share&quot; href=&quot;http://reddit.com/submit?url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-2-0-the-first-painting-application-to-bring-hdr-support-to-windows/&amp;amp;title=Krita%204.2.0:%20the%20First%20Painting%20Application%20to%20bring%20HDR%20Support%20to%20Windows&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/reddit.png&quot; title=&quot;Reddit&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Reddit&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reddit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; ssba_sharecount&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;ssba_facebook_share&quot; href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-2-0-the-first-painting-application-to-bring-hdr-support-to-windows/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/facebook.png&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Facebook&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; ssba_sharecount&quot;&gt;141&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;tumblr&quot; class=&quot;ssba_tumblr_share&quot; href=&quot;http://www.tumblr.com/share/link?url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-2-0-the-first-painting-application-to-bring-hdr-support-to-windows/&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/tumblr.png&quot; title=&quot;tumblr&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Tumblr&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumblr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; ssba_sharecount&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;ssba_twitter_share&quot; href=&quot;http://twitter.com/share?url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-2-0-the-first-painting-application-to-bring-hdr-support-to-windows/&amp;amp;text=Krita%204.2.0%3A%20the%20First%20Painting%20Application%20to%20bring%20HDR%20Support%20to%20Windows%20&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/twitter.png&quot; title=&quot;Twitter&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Tweet about this on Twitter&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a data-site=&quot;vk&quot; class=&quot;ssba_vk_share ssba_share_link&quot; href=&quot;http://vkontakte.ru/share.php?url=https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-2-0-the-first-painting-application-to-bring-hdr-support-to-windows/&quot; target=&quot;&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krita.org/wp-content/plugins/simple-share-buttons-adder/buttons/somacro/vk.png&quot; title=&quot;VK&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on VK&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 10:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Bro6666</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krita.org/en/item/krita-4-2-0-the-first-painting-application-to-bring-hdr-support-to-windows/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Telegram gets 3M new signups during Facebook apps’ outage</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/14/telegram-gets-3m-new-signups-during-facebook-apps-outage/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/14/telegram-gets-3m-new-signups-during-facebook-apps-outage/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Messaging platform Telegram claims to have had a surge in signups during a period of downtime for &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook’s&lt;/a&gt; rival messaging services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a message sent to his Telegram channel, founder &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/person/pavel-durov&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;person&quot; data-entity=&quot;pavel-durov&quot;&gt;Pavel Durov&lt;/a&gt; wrote: “I see 3 million new users signed up for Telegram within the last 24 hours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s probably not a coincidence that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and its related family of apps went down for most of Wednesday, as we &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/13/facebook-instagram-and-messenger-are-down-for-some-users/&quot;&gt;reported earlier&lt;/a&gt;. At the time of writing, Instagram’s service has been officially confirmed restored. Unofficially, Facebook also appears to be back online, at least here in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durov doesn’t offer an explicit explanation for Telegram’s sudden spike in signups, but he does take a thinly veiled swipe at social networking giant Facebook — whose founder recently claimed he now &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/06/mark-zuckerberg-discovers-privacy/&quot;&gt;plans to pivot the ad platform to “privacy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Good,” adds Durov on his channel, welcoming Telegram’s 3M newbies. “We have true privacy and unlimited space for everyone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A contact at Telegram confirmed to TechCrunch that the Facebook apps’ downtime is the likely cause of its latest signup spike, telling us: “These outages always drive new users.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though they also credited growth to “the mainstream overall increasing understanding about Facebook’s abusive attention harvesting practices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year ago Telegram announced passing &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/23/telegram-chalks-up-200m-maus-for-its-messaging-app/&quot;&gt;200 million monthly active users&lt;/a&gt;. Though the platform has faced restrictions and/or blocks in some markets (principally Russia and Iran, as well as China) — apparently for refusing government requests for encryption keys and/or user information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Durov’s home country of Russia the government is also now moving to tighten internet restrictions via new legislation — and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-russia-internet-protests/thousands-of-russians-protest-against-internet-restrictions-idUSKBN1QR0HI&quot;&gt;thousands of people&lt;/a&gt; took to the streets in Moscow and other Russian cities this weekend to protest growing internet censorship, per Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such restrictions could increase demand for Telegram’s encrypted messaging service in the country as the app does appear to still be partially accessible there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durov, who famously left Russia in 2014 — stepping away from his home country and an earlier social network he founded (VK.com) because of his stance on free speech — has &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/19/russias-game-of-telegram-whack-a-mole-grows-to-19m-blocked-ips-hitting-twitch-spotify-and-more/&quot;&gt;sought to thwart the Russian government’s Telegram blocks&lt;/a&gt; via legal and technical measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Telegram messaging platform has of course also had its own issues with less political downtime too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/telegram/status/1051190854004674560&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; last fall the company confirmed a server cluster had gone down, potentially affecting users in the Middle East, Africa and Europe, although in that case the downtime only lasted a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 10:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ours90</dc:creator>
<og:title>Telegram gets 3M new signups during Facebook apps’ outage</og:title>
<og:description>Messaging platform Telegram claims to have had a surge in signups during a period of downtime for Facebook’s rival messaging services. In a message sent to his Telegram channel, founder Pavel Durov wrote: “I see 3 million new users signed up for Telegram within the last 24 hours.”…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Telegram-3m.jpg?w=598</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/03/14/telegram-gets-3m-new-signups-during-facebook-apps-outage/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/14/telegram-gets-3m-new-signups-during-facebook-apps-outage/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Startup failed after years of work – Can I even get a job now?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19386758</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19386758</guid>
<description>&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389337&quot; readability=&quot;11.767981438515&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8839907192575&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.767981438515&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;17.161639597834&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390234&quot; readability=&quot;10.443579766537&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.2217898832685&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.443579766537&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.5447470817121&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390392&quot; readability=&quot;5.3947368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6973684210526&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.3947368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.4956140350877&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391765&quot; readability=&quot;3.1780821917808&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391301&quot; readability=&quot;14.594594594595&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.2972972972973&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;14.594594594595&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;16.054054054054&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390317&quot; readability=&quot;4.4534412955466&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2267206477733&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4534412955466&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392410&quot; readability=&quot;9.4358974358974&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7179487179487&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.4358974358974&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391830&quot; readability=&quot;5.2037914691943&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6018957345972&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.2037914691943&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.3364928909953&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387337&quot; readability=&quot;12.890410958904&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.4452054794521&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.890410958904&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.5885518591&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390946&quot; readability=&quot;8.6502242152466&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3251121076233&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.6502242152466&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.2473841554559&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390915&quot; readability=&quot;4.4212962962963&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2106481481481&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4212962962963&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391046&quot; readability=&quot;0.72289156626506&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391351&quot; readability=&quot;1.828125&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391378&quot; readability=&quot;11.79347826087&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8967391304348&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.79347826087&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.810688405797&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392325&quot; readability=&quot;6.634328358209&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3171641791045&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.634328358209&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391442&quot; readability=&quot;7.6727272727273&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8363636363636&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6727272727273&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.7545454545455&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391885&quot; readability=&quot;9.3139841688654&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.6569920844327&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.3139841688654&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.122691292876&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391272&quot; readability=&quot;13.729281767956&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.8646408839779&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13.729281767956&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;13.238950276243&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391899&quot; readability=&quot;6.3738019169329&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.1869009584665&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.3738019169329&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392397&quot; readability=&quot;1.5280898876404&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391726&quot; readability=&quot;9.7424103035879&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8712051517939&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.7424103035879&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.3068077276909&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392016&quot; readability=&quot;4.7713097713098&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3856548856549&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.7713097713098&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.7713097713098&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391900&quot; readability=&quot;8.3617021276596&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.1808510638298&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.3617021276596&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.5744680851064&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391920&quot; readability=&quot;3.3372781065089&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6686390532544&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3372781065089&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392271&quot; readability=&quot;3.5876288659794&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7938144329897&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5876288659794&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391094&quot; readability=&quot;10.729166666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.3645833333333&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.729166666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.3153409090909&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391204&quot; readability=&quot;2.2627118644068&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387739&quot; readability=&quot;7.425&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7125&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.425&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389187&quot; readability=&quot;5.5888324873096&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7944162436548&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5888324873096&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390202&quot; readability=&quot;7.6871508379888&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8435754189944&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6871508379888&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.7653631284916&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391914&quot; readability=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.75&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.9583333333333&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392036&quot; readability=&quot;8.5670103092784&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2835051546392&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.5670103092784&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.5189003436426&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392357&quot; readability=&quot;5.6715789473684&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8357894736842&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.6715789473684&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1989473684211&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389132&quot; readability=&quot;7.433242506812&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.716621253406&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.433242506812&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390059&quot; readability=&quot;9.6784073506891&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8392036753446&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.6784073506891&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.8713629402757&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390126&quot; readability=&quot;3.5670995670996&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7835497835498&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5670995670996&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390142&quot; readability=&quot;3.214953271028&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.607476635514&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.214953271028&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387302&quot; readability=&quot;8.5052854122622&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2526427061311&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.5052854122622&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1976744186047&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388667&quot; readability=&quot;2.5161290322581&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.258064516129&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5161290322581&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390302&quot; readability=&quot;5.7347368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8673684210526&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.7347368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388757&quot; readability=&quot;2.5508021390374&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2754010695187&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5508021390374&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389230&quot; readability=&quot;2.6424870466321&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3212435233161&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6424870466321&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388849&quot; readability=&quot;5.3362831858407&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6681415929204&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.3362831858407&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.5575221238938&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389324&quot; readability=&quot;3.4074074074074&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7037037037037&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4074074074074&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389728&quot; readability=&quot;4.2548076923077&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1274038461538&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.2548076923077&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389814&quot; readability=&quot;1.3932584269663&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390526&quot; readability=&quot;2.2285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389340&quot; readability=&quot;1.4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387171&quot; readability=&quot;6.7222222222222&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3611111111111&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.7222222222222&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.083333333333&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389408&quot; readability=&quot;2.3846153846154&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388114&quot; readability=&quot;1.4736842105263&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390975&quot; readability=&quot;9.5840867992767&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7920433996383&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.5840867992767&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.3128390596745&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388810&quot; readability=&quot;3.59375&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.796875&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.59375&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.59375&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388970&quot; readability=&quot;5.4368231046931&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7184115523466&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4368231046931&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.9837545126354&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389945&quot; readability=&quot;5.438202247191&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7191011235955&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.438202247191&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.8913857677903&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388872&quot; readability=&quot;2.3379310344828&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388422&quot; readability=&quot;16.517730496454&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.258865248227&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16.517730496454&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;12.145390070922&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391357&quot; readability=&quot;4.7745901639344&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3872950819672&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.7745901639344&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.6844262295082&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391278&quot; readability=&quot;3.6747967479675&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8373983739837&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6747967479675&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389425&quot; readability=&quot;6.5649717514124&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2824858757062&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5649717514124&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.0960451977401&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391156&quot; readability=&quot;5.5112359550562&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7556179775281&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5112359550562&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.1334269662921&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386792&quot; readability=&quot;6.4776119402985&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2388059701493&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4776119402985&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388774&quot; readability=&quot;6.5990453460621&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.299522673031&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5990453460621&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389739&quot; readability=&quot;3.5138121546961&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7569060773481&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5138121546961&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.5138121546961&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389970&quot; readability=&quot;5.5740740740741&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.787037037037&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5740740740741&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.1805555555556&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387101&quot; readability=&quot;4.1768292682927&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.0884146341463&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.1768292682927&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388705&quot; readability=&quot;1.1466666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386821&quot; readability=&quot;6.4521739130435&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2260869565217&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4521739130435&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.6086956521739&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386857&quot; readability=&quot;1.6615384615385&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388260&quot; readability=&quot;6.6539923954373&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3269961977186&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6539923954373&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.7034220532319&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389560&quot; readability=&quot;16.697411003236&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.3487055016181&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16.697411003236&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;14.241909385113&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390976&quot; readability=&quot;3.4626865671642&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7313432835821&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4626865671642&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389766&quot; readability=&quot;6.4496855345912&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2248427672956&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4496855345912&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.685534591195&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391513&quot; readability=&quot;9.4969818913481&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.748490945674&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.4969818913481&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.5472837022133&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388813&quot; readability=&quot;2.4121621621622&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2060810810811&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4121621621622&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390590&quot; readability=&quot;4.4930875576037&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2465437788018&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4930875576037&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391091&quot; readability=&quot;6.5955555555556&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2977777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5955555555556&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389428&quot; readability=&quot;7.7124183006536&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8562091503268&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.7124183006536&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.7483660130719&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389115&quot; readability=&quot;3.4759825327511&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7379912663755&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4759825327511&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19393849&quot; readability=&quot;8.5936454849498&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2968227424749&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.5936454849498&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.2968227424749&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19393917&quot; readability=&quot;6.1833333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.0916666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.1833333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.3&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390348&quot; readability=&quot;4.6701846965699&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.335092348285&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6701846965699&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390012&quot; readability=&quot;7.4691943127962&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7345971563981&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4691943127962&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.4691943127962&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389449&quot; readability=&quot;9.7856553998351&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8928276999176&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.7856553998351&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;13.699917559769&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391800&quot; readability=&quot;11.520833333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.7604166666667&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.520833333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.1206597222222&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19393694&quot; readability=&quot;5.6538461538462&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8269230769231&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.6538461538462&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19394428&quot; readability=&quot;9.5769230769231&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7884615384615&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.5769230769231&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.1403846153846&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19394935&quot; readability=&quot;14.753424657534&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.3767123287671&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;14.753424657534&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;18.687671232877&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19395129&quot; readability=&quot;1.5869565217391&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391670&quot; readability=&quot;7.6501901140684&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8250950570342&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6501901140684&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392250&quot; readability=&quot;4.7248803827751&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3624401913876&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.7248803827751&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.7248803827751&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392825&quot; readability=&quot;4.6165191740413&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3082595870206&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6165191740413&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.0781710914454&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386890&quot; readability=&quot;4.8464912280702&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.4232456140351&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.8464912280702&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391213&quot; readability=&quot;7.5109170305677&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7554585152838&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5109170305677&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.7554585152838&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389942&quot; readability=&quot;9.6472392638037&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8236196319018&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.6472392638037&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;11.094325153374&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391506&quot; readability=&quot;8.7238095238095&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3619047619048&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.7238095238095&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391589&quot; readability=&quot;9.1940298507463&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.5970149253731&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.1940298507463&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.9761194029851&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389226&quot; readability=&quot;4.5575221238938&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2787610619469&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5575221238938&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387166&quot; readability=&quot;7.6071428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8035714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6071428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389652&quot; readability=&quot;3.5024875621891&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7512437810945&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5024875621891&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389700&quot; readability=&quot;2.3669724770642&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389619&quot; readability=&quot;2.1923076923077&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390856&quot; readability=&quot;6.5036674816626&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2518337408313&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5036674816626&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.5745721271394&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390046&quot; readability=&quot;10.504291845494&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.2521459227468&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.504291845494&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.7296137339056&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390841&quot; readability=&quot;3.6450511945392&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8225255972696&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6450511945392&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392405&quot; readability=&quot;4.3260869565217&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1630434782609&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3260869565217&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389426&quot; readability=&quot;7.6155268022181&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8077634011091&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6155268022181&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.235674676525&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391495&quot; readability=&quot;2.9753694581281&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389152&quot; readability=&quot;4.6882793017456&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3441396508728&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6882793017456&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392385&quot; readability=&quot;2.5629139072848&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2814569536424&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5629139072848&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391825&quot; readability=&quot;4.4600938967136&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2300469483568&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4600938967136&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.5680751173709&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391849&quot; readability=&quot;5.1764705882353&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.5882352941176&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.1764705882353&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391184&quot; readability=&quot;1.8222222222222&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389756&quot; readability=&quot;10.243553008596&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.121776504298&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.243553008596&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.1905444126074&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386973&quot; readability=&quot;6.4409722222222&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2204861111111&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4409722222222&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.4409722222222&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392194&quot; readability=&quot;4.1176470588235&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.0588235294118&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.1176470588235&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387945&quot; readability=&quot;3.0640776699029&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392844&quot; readability=&quot;1.5434782608696&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389921&quot; readability=&quot;5.325&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6625&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.325&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390651&quot; readability=&quot;8.4837905236908&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2418952618454&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.4837905236908&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389891&quot; readability=&quot;1.4526315789474&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388760&quot; readability=&quot;3.0924369747899&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390328&quot; readability=&quot;3.5402298850575&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7701149425287&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5402298850575&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389923&quot; readability=&quot;2.5796178343949&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2898089171975&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5796178343949&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389261&quot; readability=&quot;8.423645320197&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2118226600985&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.423645320197&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389829&quot; readability=&quot;2.4458598726115&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2229299363057&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4458598726115&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390672&quot; readability=&quot;2.4094488188976&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2047244094488&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4094488188976&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389926&quot; readability=&quot;2.4929577464789&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2464788732394&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4929577464789&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389530&quot; readability=&quot;2.5833333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2916666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5833333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386802&quot; readability=&quot;6.3777777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.1888888888889&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.3777777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386822&quot; readability=&quot;6.4685863874346&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2342931937173&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4685863874346&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389471&quot; readability=&quot;11.661176470588&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8305882352941&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.661176470588&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.8870588235294&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389662&quot; readability=&quot;5.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7142857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388882&quot; readability=&quot;3.2638888888889&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387143&quot; readability=&quot;3.5555555555556&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7777777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5555555555556&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389590&quot; readability=&quot;9.4698354661792&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7349177330896&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.4698354661792&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.7349177330896&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390397&quot; readability=&quot;2.4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389620&quot; readability=&quot;2.5764705882353&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2882352941176&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5764705882353&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.8647058823529&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391389&quot; readability=&quot;4.4907407407407&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2453703703704&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4907407407407&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391872&quot; readability=&quot;2.5227272727273&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2613636363636&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5227272727273&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392368&quot; readability=&quot;11.446740858506&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.7233704292528&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.446740858506&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.7694753577107&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388127&quot; readability=&quot;1.2926829268293&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387165&quot; readability=&quot;4.3965517241379&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.198275862069&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3965517241379&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391990&quot; readability=&quot;2.4295774647887&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2147887323944&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4295774647887&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389885&quot; readability=&quot;1.4526315789474&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387997&quot; readability=&quot;3.25&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.625&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.25&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387025&quot; readability=&quot;2.5372340425532&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2686170212766&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5372340425532&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.3829787234043&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19388419&quot; readability=&quot;9.6344647519582&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8172323759791&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.6344647519582&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.1527415143603&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389534&quot; readability=&quot;16.671232876712&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.3356164383562&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16.671232876712&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;15.200241740532&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389816&quot; readability=&quot;1.2058823529412&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390285&quot; readability=&quot;1.0746268656716&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387209&quot; readability=&quot;2.2781954887218&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19392103&quot; readability=&quot;31.763802775317&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;15.881901387659&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;31.763802775317&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;41.689991142604&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment&quot; readability=&quot;57.91381872214&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;I shut down my first major startup at 28 after 6 years of back-breaking work. In the process, I raised $xx million, experienced the highest highs and the lowest lows. I was devastated and burnt out, and it took a long time to fully process everything and move on.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;It's great that you're planning out your next steps now. Finding a decent-paying job to make ends meet is first priority. From what you've revealed in this thread, I'm confident you'll figure something out quickly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;Eventually, after the stress from shutting down the company and finding a new job dies down, you'll have time to do some serious reflecting on what's come to pass. It doesn't sound like you're at that stage yet, but here's some advice when you reach it:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;1) Recognize What Was Lost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;Don't get stuck in denial. Be honest with yourself about what you've lost, and don't try to trivialize it (yet). Perhaps you had giant hopes and dreams and they were crushed. Perhaps you feel like shit because you didn't meet your goals. Whatever it is, lay it out and don't hold back.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;2) Recognize What You've Gained&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;We tend to lose sight of the positives during a time of crisis/failure, but trust me, even if you can't see them right now, they exist :). Being the founder of a startup is one of the highest pressure jobs you can ask for. That pressure can feel like shit sometimes, but it also forces you to grow. That growth is valuable, in and of itself. Perhaps you grew your engineering skill set. Perhaps you became a savier business person. And, perhaps there were tangible assets or friendships that you gained -- those count too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;3) Honestly Assess the Situation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;One thing I hate more than anything else is when people say &quot;I wouldn't have chosen it any other way&quot;. Fuck that haha. The stress of shutting down a company and operating in close-to-failure mode sucks! Running a wildly successful company would have been much preferred.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;That said, also be honest about how it's not all bad. You grew as a person and there are lessons you learned (or can learn) from the experience. And, you have an awesome story to tell one day :).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;Don't label yourself as a failure. Your company was a failure. You failed to achieve your goal. You are not a failure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;4) Recalibrate Your Values and Move Forward&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;So, why are YOU not a failure? To answer this question, you have to take a hard look at your personal values. What do you think is important in life? What are you chasing after?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;To me, values are the measuring sticks by which people quantify success in life. Whether or not we realize it, we constantly measure our actions against our values, and how we 'measure up' determines our self-worth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;If what you value most in life is being a successful founder, you are gonna feel like shit!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;But, what if what you value most in life is becoming the best version of yourself OR acting with integrity OR contributing postiviely to society?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;In my opinion, there's no such thing as 'good' or 'bad' values, but some values sure are hard to live up to (primarily because they're largely outside our control). The good thing is you can change your values to make sure they realistically align with your life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;If your values are straight, you're ready to move forward. Take some time off if you need it to completely unwind. The motivation will come back with time -- it's only human to have drive. Good luck!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386796&quot; readability=&quot;4.5408163265306&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2704081632653&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5408163265306&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389684&quot; readability=&quot;4.5985401459854&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2992700729927&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5985401459854&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386833&quot; readability=&quot;1.3626373626374&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386943&quot; readability=&quot;1.1320754716981&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386817&quot; readability=&quot;3.2666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6333333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.2666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386830&quot; readability=&quot;4.4105691056911&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2052845528455&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4105691056911&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386843&quot; readability=&quot;6.6226765799257&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3113382899628&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6226765799257&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19386856&quot; readability=&quot;1.1470588235294&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389543&quot; readability=&quot;6.4985074626866&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2492537313433&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4985074626866&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19390206&quot; readability=&quot;1.2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389358&quot; readability=&quot;7.5893805309735&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7946902654867&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5893805309735&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.2176991150442&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391181&quot; readability=&quot;5.6585365853659&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8292682926829&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.6585365853659&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19387037&quot; readability=&quot;1.44&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19389365&quot; readability=&quot;3.8190954773869&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19391582&quot; readability=&quot;7.67585089141&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.837925445705&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.67585089141&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.1961102106969&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 05:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>perfect_loop</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19386758</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gwern&amp;#039;s Law: Ads cost you a tenth of your users</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/gwern/status/1103855323100708866</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/gwern/status/1103855323100708866</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Well yes, of course, but the widespread assumption, which I shared when I began my A/B experiment mostly for statistical wankery, before those other 3 datapoints came out, is that it's something relatively small and negligible like 0-5%. Not 15%! Still surprised it's so large.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 05:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ascertain</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/gwern/status/1103855323100708866</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Companies may be losing millions due to emails buried in collapsed Gmail threads</title>
<link>https://thehftguy.com/2019/02/12/the-gmail-bug-thats-been-stealing-187m-a-year-from-expedia/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thehftguy.com/2019/02/12/the-gmail-bug-thats-been-stealing-187m-a-year-from-expedia/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: The events depicted in this story are purely factual and described to the best of my memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prelude&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, in the City of London…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Expedia empire reigns. Having conquered the world of travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s two heads, Expedia and Hotels.com share the wealth in roughly equal measure, a few tens of billions each every year, for holding a tight grip and a large commission on all planes and hotels ever used in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a cold day of winter in London, where the Hotels headquarters is located. A perfectly regular business meeting is about to take place, as every last Tuesday of month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 1 – Free buffet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams and leaders will give numerous presentations about the business, products, partners, competitions and many more topics. Attendance is mandatory for all new employees and contractors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some talks prove to be interesting. One would learn why are there constant harassment popups like “&lt;em&gt;Over 9000 people have booked this hotel in the last 24 hours.&lt;/em&gt;” and whether there actually were 9000 people who booked rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the presenters gather people and improvise a usability test at some point. Think of a place you’d like to go for holidays, search it and go through the booking, as if you were intending to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unbeknownst to all, one of the most trivial yet impactful bug in history is about to be discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 2 – What Could Go Wrong?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll spare you the full narrative of the session. Except, one insignificant detail toward the end, one person in the back of the room saying she cannot login to the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a decade of experience has taught me anything, it’s that for every user who complains of an issue, there could be another million who don’t, in spite of the issue being very real and painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always investigate feedback, no matter how stupid or irrelevant it could be, it could be the tree that hides the forest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;11952&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://thehftguy.com/2019/02/12/the-gmail-bug-thats-been-stealing-187m-a-year-from-expedia/the_golden_forest/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/the_golden_forest.jpg?fit=500%2C440&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;500,440&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;the_golden_forest&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/the_golden_forest.jpg?fit=300%2C264&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/the_golden_forest.jpg?fit=500%2C440&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11952&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/the_golden_forest.jpg?resize=500%2C440&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;the_golden_forest.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/the_golden_forest.jpg?w=500&amp;amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/the_golden_forest.jpg?resize=300%2C264&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/the_golden_forest.jpg?resize=341%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 341w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;For reference a small tree made of pure gold would be worth a few hundreds million dollars
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 3 – Debugging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor’s Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The scene was originally happening on mobile. Screenshots were captured on desktop for illustration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be so special that it doesn’t work for her? Let’s find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She cannot login because she forgot her password. She did the “&lt;em&gt;reset password&lt;/em&gt;” many times and it does NOT work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would this not work? Let’s have her try and reset it one more time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgot Password =&amp;gt; Reset =&amp;gt; “Instructions have been sent to …”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The email is allegedly sent… and it is received by her Gmail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;8584&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://thehftguy.com/?attachment_id=8584&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/screenshot-gmail-subject.png?fit=979%2C24&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;979,24&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;screenshot gmail subject&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/screenshot-gmail-subject.png?fit=300%2C7&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/screenshot-gmail-subject.png?fit=809%2C20&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-8584&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/screenshot-gmail-subject.png?resize=809%2C20&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot gmail subject&quot; width=&quot;809&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;A new message in the inbox! (desktop screenshot)
&lt;p&gt;She opens it and click the reset link and it doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does this not work? The page says “&lt;em&gt;invalid or expired link, try again to be sent a new email&lt;/em&gt;“.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s try again. Except this time, it’s my turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reset the password again. Open Gmail open, it shows that there is a new unread message again. Great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open it. Looking carefully, there is something unusual at the bottom of it…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;8657&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://thehftguy.com/?attachment_id=8657&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/screenshot-gmail-hidden1.png?fit=799%2C228&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;799,228&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;screenshot gmail hidden&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/screenshot-gmail-hidden1.png?fit=300%2C86&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/screenshot-gmail-hidden1.png?fit=799%2C228&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-8657&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/screenshot-gmail-hidden1.png?resize=799%2C228&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot gmail hidden&quot; width=&quot;799&quot; height=&quot;228&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;There are messages collapsed at the bottom, as in an old discussion (desktop screenshot)
&lt;p&gt;The latest message is not shown upon opening. It’s showing an old message instead (in the middle of the page that was truncated for the screenshot). The newer messages are collapsed at the bottom. They have to be opened manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that Gmail hides new messages that look similar to previous messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The password reset messages are there, hidden at the bottom, each with its own unique link. We open the latest email manually and it works! The password is reset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debugging complete. It’s not a bug, it’s a feature.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She’s been opening the same old reset email every single time, with an obsolete link. That’s why reset didn’t work for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gmail displays an old obsolete email when opening the discussion. No matter how many newer emails are received, they’re all systematically ignored and collapsed. She never noticed the hidden messages at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every reset message comes with a unique link, that gets invalidated when a new reset request is done, hence the errors about using an invalid link. She would never be able to reset her password without being able to view the latest email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collapsed messages are fairly hard to spot on desktop and almost impossible to spot on mobile. She doesn’t stand a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 4 – Estimation of Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The password reset procedure is failing for a multi billion dollar website with hundreds of millions of customers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers buy accommodation when they travel, more or less frequently. It’s reasonable to expect a sizeable user base to forget their password as often as every single time they return, especially if they travel sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue is impacting all users who forgot their password, use Gmail (not sure about other clients) and don’t notice the hidden messages being at the bottom (it’s really hard to spot).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s estimate the impact. Incidentally, all the required metrics were distilled through today’s presentations and the data team just introduced themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming some percentages of some percentages of some statistics from users and sales. (read: private numbers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The direct impact of this bug is a direct loss of revenues of $187M dollars per year, simply accounting for people who are unable to login and place any order.&lt;/strong&gt; Existing users cannot use the service, new users can register but not return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there is the indirect loss that is very hard to measure. If you were in the room, you would notice participants switch to the competition (booking.com) within a minute of frustration, especially if already familiar with it. It is brutal from a business perspective. Not sure if users might be giving up any faster or slower because of the artificial circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full impact accounting for direct losses, plus indirect losses, plus recurring losses, plus reputation loss, plus competitors stealing our business, well, forever stealing our business because the site is unusable and lost users won’t switch back, etc… is hard to put an estimate on. It’s easily a multiple of the number above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 5 – Fix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to force Gmail to stop hiding similar emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, let’s make the email dissimilar. Adding the current time to the subject line ought to be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software is in Java, a verbose language. It takes 60 characters to format a date. An easy patch, easier done than said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;8541&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://thehftguy.com/?attachment_id=8541&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/pic-i-dont-often-write-code-but-when-i-do-its-3m-per-character.jpg?fit=500%2C627&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;500,627&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;pic – i dont often write code but when i do its 3M per character&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/pic-i-dont-often-write-code-but-when-i-do-its-3m-per-character.jpg?fit=239%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/pic-i-dont-often-write-code-but-when-i-do-its-3m-per-character.jpg?fit=500%2C627&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-8541 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/pic-i-dont-often-write-code-but-when-i-do-its-3m-per-character.jpg?resize=500%2C627&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;i dont often write code but when i do its 3m dollars per character&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;627&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;You knew the 10X developer, a developer who is as profitable as 10 of his peers. Allow me to introduce the unicorn developer, a developer who is worth a billion dollar by himself.
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actually, the bug is still active. I never had the opportunity to fix it, didn’t stay long.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the hallway testing, I noticed at least 2 other people who couldn’t login and talked about it out loud. That’s a minimum of 3 out of 30 people impacted, proving with certainty that a major percentage of users were affected. Some guys actually said that there was a known issue with password reset and it was being worked on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short. It was not worked on at all. The bug is still there and it’s been there all along. I got it recently when I booked a travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s been going on for many years. It must be well over a billion dollar loss by now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen the email change a couple of times. Pretty sure it was rewritten from scratch, possibly more than once, yet the issue persists. I genuinely wonder if anyone ever investigated, let alone understood the root cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is truly a global Gmail bug. I’ve noticed a handful of collapsed emails from various sources since then. The impact is not limited to Expedia.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It would be nice if Google could fix it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this article:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-108084023-11951-5c8aeab89139d&quot; data-src=&quot;https://widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=108084023&amp;amp;post_id=11951&amp;amp;origin=thehftguy.com&amp;amp;obj_id=108084023-11951-5c8aeab89139d&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-108084023-11951-5c8aeab89139d&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 03:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>eaguyhn</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Gmail bug that’s been stealing $187M a year from Expedia</og:title>
<og:url>https://thehftguy.com/2019/02/12/the-gmail-bug-thats-been-stealing-187m-a-year-from-expedia/</og:url>
<og:description>Disclaimer: The events depicted in this story are purely factual and described to the best of my memory. Prelude Many years ago, in the City of London… The Expedia empire reigns. Having conqu…</og:description>
<og:image>https://thehftguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/the_golden_forest.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thehftguy.com/2019/02/12/the-gmail-bug-thats-been-stealing-187m-a-year-from-expedia/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>