<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>How to Fall Asleep in Two Minutes or Less</title>
<link>https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/03/21/fall-asleep-fast/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/03/21/fall-asleep-fast/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-82405&quot; src=&quot;https://content.artofmanliness.com/uploads/2018/02/Fall-Asleep-Header.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;https://content.artofmanliness.com/uploads/2018/02/Fall-Asleep-Header.jpg 650w, https://content.artofmanliness.com/uploads/2018/02/Fall-Asleep-Header-320x197.jpg 320w, https://content.artofmanliness.com/uploads/2018/02/Fall-Asleep-Header-640x394.jpg 640w, https://content.artofmanliness.com/uploads/2018/02/Fall-Asleep-Header-400x246.jpg 400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever unexpectedly found yourself with a snatch of time in which to steal a nap? You tried to settle into the chair or nook in which you found yourself, closed your eyes, and then . . . you just sat there, drowsy but awake. Despite feeling quite tired, you couldn’t fall asleep, and soon the time was up before you had gotten in so much as a wink. Talk about frustrating! Not only did you not get to nap, you didn’t do anything else either; if you weren’t going to fall asleep, you could have done something productive instead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s quite a knack to be able to fall asleep at the drop of a hat, regardless of where you are and what’s going on around you. To steal some shuteye at airports and on flights, on break times and car rides, in public places and private spaces — in all the interstices of life. Not to mention how grand it is to be able to go out like a light as soon as your head hits the pillow each night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It probably seems, however, that this is simply a knack that some folks have and others don’t, with the latter group being much larger than the former.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the ability to fall asleep in two minutes or less, anywhere, anytime, is actually a skill like any other, and one anyone can learn. The technique for how to do so was in fact developed for Naval aviators during World War II, and today we’ll share it with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;u&gt;How to Fall Asleep in 2 Minutes or Less&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple years into WWII, the U.S. military realized it had a problem on its hands. Due to the enormous pressures of aerial combat, many of its pilots were accumulating levels of stress so debilitating that they were cracking under it. The tension caused them to lock up in flight and make fatal mistakes — accidentally shooting down friendly planes, or becoming an avoidable casualty themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an effort to stem the loss of pilots and planes, the military brought in Naval Ensign Bud Winter to research, develop, and test a scientific method for teaching relaxation. Before the war, Winter had been a successful college football and track coach, who had also worked with a professor of psychology on techniques to help athletes relax and perform better under the stress of competition. Stationed at the Del Monte Naval Pre-Flight School in California, his mission now was to coordinate with other coaches and professors to create a course that would similarly instruct cadets on how to stay calm and loose under the pressures of combat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end goal of the program was to teach the Naval aviators how to relax, so that they could learn more quickly, speed up their reaction time, sharpen their focus, and diminish their fear. The course also aimed to teach “combat aviators to be able to go to sleep in two minutes any time, day or night, under any and all conditions”; instruction in this skill was included to ensure that pilots got adequate sleep, and could sneak in extra shuteye whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accomplish the first goal, Winter taught the men how to &lt;em&gt;physically&lt;/em&gt; relax. To accomplish the second, he taught them how to &lt;em&gt;mentally&lt;/em&gt; relax. In fact, he essentially defined sleep as the state of being both physically and mentally relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fall asleep at the drop of a hat, first you work on the former, and then the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to Physically Relax&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0498025411/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0498025411&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=stucosuccess&amp;amp;linkId=FSXA3GZUT5SFDAZ4&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Relax and Win&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the book Winter wrote about the program he developed for combat aviators and then used with athletes after the war, he lays out the exact instructions he gave to cadets to teach them how to relax their bodies; here we give them slightly condensed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Sit back in your chairs and put your feet flat on the deck. Knees apart, your hands limp on the inside of your lap. Now, close your eyes and drop your chin until it rests on your chest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s breathe slowly, deeply, and regularly. Take all the wrinkles out of your forehead. Relax your scalp. Just let go. Now let your jaw sag-g-g. Let it drop open. Now relax the rest of your face muscles. Get the brook trout look on your face. Even relax your tongue and lips. Just let them go loose. Breathe slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s go after the eight muscles that control your eyes. Let them go limp in their sockets. No focus, just let them go limp. Breathe slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now drop your shoulders as low as they will go. You think that they are low, but let them go more.  Did you feel the muscles in the back of your neck go limp? When you think you are really relaxed, let them go even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s relax your chest. Take a deep breath. Hold it. Exhale and blow out all your tensions. Just let your chest collapse. Let it sag-g-g. Imagine you are a big, heavy blob on the chair, a jellyfish. Breathe slowly. When you exhale, release more and more of your tensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s go after your arms. Talk directly to your arm muscles. First, talk to your right bicep. Tell it to relax, go limp. Do the same to your right forearm. Now to the right hand and fingers. Your arm should feel like a dead weight on your leg. Repeat the relaxation process with your left arm. Breathe slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your entire upper body has been exposed to relaxation and a warm, pleasant feeling comes over you. You feel good. A sense of well-being invades your body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for your lower body. Talk to your right thigh muscles. Let them go to a dead weight on the chair. Let the meat hang on the bones. Go through the same routine for the right calf muscles. Then all the muscles of your right ankle and foot. Tell yourself that your right leg has no bones in it. It is just a flabby, heavy weight on the deck. Repeat the process with your left thigh, calf, ankle, and foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present you are all relaxed physically, or think you are. For a little insurance, let’s take three deep breaths and when you let them out, blow out all the remaining tensions, one . . . whoosh, two . . . whoosh, three . . . whoosh.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have trouble getting any of your body parts to feel sufficiently relaxed and jellyfish-like, try tensing them up first, and then letting them go loose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By following the above protocol, you can achieve a nice general level of relaxation. Winter taught the cadets to cultivate this state in any pressure-filled situation, as it would loosen them up, dial down their nerves, enhance their concentration, and allow them to make better decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this physically calm condition, Winter then taught the cadets how to “slip over the threshold into a deep, relaxed sleep” by becoming completely mentally relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to Mentally Relax&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-82161&quot; src=&quot;https://content.artofmanliness.com/uploads/2018/02/pilotssleep2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;465&quot; height=&quot;594&quot; srcset=&quot;https://content.artofmanliness.com/uploads/2018/02/pilotssleep2.jpg 465w, https://content.artofmanliness.com/uploads/2018/02/pilotssleep2-320x409.jpg 320w, https://content.artofmanliness.com/uploads/2018/02/pilotssleep2-400x511.jpg 400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 465px) 100vw, 465px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter argues that once you’re physically relaxed, if you get “your mind clear of any active thoughts for just ten seconds, you will be asleep.” The key to falling asleep quick is thus to stop the train of thoughts that is usually rumbling through your head. You have to stop ruminating on the regrets, worries, and problems of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter particularly warns against having any thoughts in which you are in motion; studies done by placing electrodes on the cadets’ bodies showed that even when you simply &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; of performing an activity, the muscles involved in that activity actually contract. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-to-grow-stronger-without-lifting-weights/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Modern studies have in fact confirmed this observation&lt;/a&gt;, showing that simply imagining yourself exercising activates the same parts of the brain that come online when you’re physically in motion, and actually strengthens the muscles you imagine yourself using. While there might be some benefit to using your mind to “sit and be fit,” thinking about being active while trying to go to sleep can create muscular tension and inhibit its onset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when you’re looking to nod off, you just want to fill your head with the stillest, calmest of contemplations. Winter suggests three good ones to use, though you don’t have to use all three; just pick one, and if it doesn’t work, try another:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;“First, we want you to fantasize that it is a warm spring day and you are lying in the bottom of a canoe on a very serene lake. You are looking up at a blue sky with lazy, floating clouds. Do not allow any other thought to creep in. Just concentrate on this picture and keep foreign thoughts out, particularly thoughts with any movement or motion involved. Hold this picture and enjoy it for ten seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second sleep-producing fantasy, imagine that you are in a big, black, velvet hammock and everywhere you look is black. You must also hold this picture for ten seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third trick is to say the words ‘don’t think . . . don’t think . . . don’t think,’ etc. Hold this, blanking out other thoughts for at least ten seconds.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cadets at the pre-flight school had been broken into two groups: one which took the relaxation course, and the other a control group. The former outperformed the latter in every mentally-taxing class, discipline-requiring drill, and physically-intensive test. And after six weeks of practice, 96% of the aviators were able to fall asleep in 2 minutes or less — anywhere and anytime. Not only that, they could do it even when they drank coffee (though having caffeine in your system does make it harder), and even while the simulated noise of machine gunfire and cannon blasts played in the background!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the war, Winter taught the track athletes he coached the same relaxation techniques, and became one of the greatest sprint coaches of all time, producing 102 All-Americans and 27 Olympians; at one time, his runners held all 10 world records for sprinting events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter strongly believed that the wartime program for relaxation he helped develop to fight combat stress, and which athletes subsequently used to deal with the pressures of competition, was just as applicable to the tensions and fatigue civilians faced in their everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use this general relaxation method to get physically relaxed whenever you’re feeling stressed out, and then tack on the mental relaxation exercise when you want to fall asleep fast. It’s handy for when you find yourself with a short window of time for a snooze; Winter thought even a 5-minute nap was incredibly refreshing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2015/02/18/hypnagogic-nap/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;internal&quot;&gt;You could also use it to take a “hypnagogic nap”&lt;/a&gt; — a micro nap that artists like Salvador Dali used, in which you allow yourself to doze off for just a second in order to glean the creative insights that can arise on the threshold between sleep and wakefulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, of course, you can simply use this technique when you go to bed, to more quickly and contentedly enter your nightly block of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that being able to relax physically and mentally, and thus being able to fall asleep at the drop of a hat, is a skill, and like all skills, you shouldn’t expect to get the hang of it and have it work the first few times you try. You have to practice over and over again, until you get better and better at loosening up and calming down. That doesn’t mean you should work &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; at trying to relax; that will just backfire and create tension. But you do have to practice this routine &lt;em&gt;consistently&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;modified-date&quot;&gt;Last updated: &lt;span class=&quot;date updated&quot; itemprop=&quot;dateModified&quot;&gt;March 22, 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 12:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rhapsodic</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How to Fall Asleep Fast - In Less Than 2 Minutes | The Art of Manliness</og:title>
<og:description>Have you ever unexpectedly found yourself with a snatch of time in which to steal a nap? You tried to settle into the chair or nook in which you found yourself, closed your eyes, and then . . . you just sat there, drowsy but awake. Despite feeling quite tired, you couldn’t fall asleep, and …</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/03/21/fall-asleep-fast/</og:url>
<og:image>https://content.artofmanliness.com/uploads/2018/02/Fall-Asleep-Header.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/03/21/fall-asleep-fast/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook scraped call, text message data for years from Android phones</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/facebook-scraped-call-text-message-data-for-years-from-android-phones</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/facebook-scraped-call-text-message-data-for-years-from-android-phones</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/29511279_211342699598625_4779335535636250624_o-800x1422.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/29511279_211342699598625_4779335535636250624_o.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;2560&quot; data-width=&quot;1440&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; This screen in the Messenger application offers to conveniently track all your calls and messages. But Facebook was already doing this surreptitiously on some Android devices until October 2017, exploiting the way an older Android API handled permissions.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;132 posters participating, including story author.&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/facebook-scraped-call-text-message-data-for-years-from-android-phones/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;220&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;This past week, a New Zealand man was looking through the data Facebook had collected from him in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/help/131112897028467?helpref=page_content&quot;&gt;an archive&lt;/a&gt; he had pulled down from the social networking site. While scanning the information Facebook had stored about his contacts, Dylan McKay discovered something distressing: Facebook also had about two years' worth of phone call metadata from his Android phone, including names, phone numbers, and the length of each call made or received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Downloaded my facebook data as a ZIP file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow it has my entire call history with my partner's mum &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/CIRUguf4vD&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/CIRUguf4vD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Dylan McKay (@dylanmckaynz) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dylanmckaynz/status/976368845635035138?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience has been shared by a number of other Facebook users who spoke with Ars, as well as independently by us—my own Facebook data archive, I found, contained call-log data for &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/07/paint-it-black-revisiting-the-blackphone-and-its-cloudy-future/&quot;&gt;a certain Android device I used&lt;/a&gt; in 2015 and 2016, along with SMS and MMS message metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/callog-150x150.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/callog.jpg&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/callog.jpg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/callog.jpg 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1281685&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Calls I made to my office number to check my voicemail, and from my office number to find my phone, found in my Facebook data archive. In total, there were two years of call data, from the period I used my Blackphone as my primary phone.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/getyourfbdata-150x150.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/getyourfbdata.jpg&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/getyourfbdata.jpg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/getyourfbdata.jpg 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1281681&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;To retrieve a .zip file of your Facebook data, go to the Settings page on Facebook and click the link circled in this screen shot.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to an email inquiry by Ars about this data gathering, a Facebook spokesperson replied, &quot;The most important part of apps and services that help you make connections is to make it easy to find the people you want to connect with. So, the first time you sign in on your phone to a messaging or social app, it's a widely used practice to begin by uploading your phone contacts.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spokesperson pointed out that contact uploading is optional and installation of the application explicitly requests permission to access contacts. And users can delete contact data from their profiles using a tool accessible via Web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook uses phone-contact data as part of its friend recommendation algorithm. And in recent versions of the Messenger application for Android and Facebook Lite devices, a more explicit request is made to users for access to call logs and SMS logs on Android and Facebook Lite devices. But even if users didn't give that permission to Messenger, they may have given it inadvertently for years through Facebook's mobile apps—because of the way Android has handled permissions for accessing call logs in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you granted &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/Manifest.permission.html#READ_CONTACTS&quot;&gt;permission to read contacts during Facebook's installation on Android&lt;/a&gt; a few versions ago—specifically before Android 4.1 (Jelly Bean)—that permission also granted Facebook access to call and message logs by default. The permission structure was changed in the Android API in version 16. But Android applications could bypass this change if they were written to earlier versions of the API, so Facebook API could continue to gain access to call and SMS data by specifying an earlier Android SDK version. Google deprecated version 4.0 of the Android API in October 2017—the point at which the latest call metadata in Facebook users' data was found. Apple iOS has never allowed silent access to call data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook provides a way for users to purge collected contact data from their accounts, but it's not clear if this deletes just contacts or if it also purges call and SMS metadata. After purging my contact data, my contacts and calls were still in the archive I downloaded the next day—though this may be because the archive was still the same cache I had requested on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, if you're really concerned about privacy, you should not share address book and call-log data with any mobile application. And you may want to examine the rest of what can be found in the downloadable Facebook archive, as it includes all the advertisers that Facebook has shared your contact information with, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 02:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>node-bayarea</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/facebook-scraped-call-text-message-data-for-years-from-android-phones/</og:url>
<og:title>Facebook scraped call, text message data for years from Android phones</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/29511279_211342699598625_4779335535636250624_o-760x380.png</og:image>
<og:description>Maybe check your data archive to see if Facebook’s algorithms know who you called.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/facebook-scraped-call-text-message-data-for-years-from-android-phones/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook was warned about app permissions in 2011</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/24/facebook-was-warned-about-app-permissions-in-2011/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/24/facebook-was-warned-about-app-permissions-in-2011/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Who’s to blame for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/17/trump-campaign-linked-data-firm-cambridge-analytica-reportedly-collected-info-on-50m-facebook-profiles/&quot;&gt;leaking of 50 million Facebook users’ data&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/facebook/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; founder and CEO Mark Zuckerberg broke several days of silence in the face of a raging privacy storm to go on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v18dGTpzUCM&quot;&gt;CNN&lt;/a&gt; this week to say he was sorry. He also admitted the company had made mistakes; said it had breached the trust of users; and said he regretted not telling Facebookers at the time their information had been misappropriated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, shares in the company have been taking a battering. And Facebook is now facing &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/23/facebook-hit-with-shareholder-lawsuits-over-data-misuse-crisis/&quot;&gt;multiple shareholder and user lawsuits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pressed on why he didn’t inform users, in 2015, when Facebook says it found out about this policy breach, Zuckerberg avoided a direct answer — instead fixing on what the company did (asked &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/cambridge-analytica/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;cambridge-analytica&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt; and the developer whose app was used to suck out data to delete the data) — rather than explaining the thinking behind the thing it did not do (tell affected Facebook users their personal information had been misappropriated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially Facebook’s line is that it believed the data had been deleted — and presumably, therefore, it calculated (wrongly) that it didn’t need to inform users because it had made the leak problem go away via its own backchannels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except of course it hadn’t. Because people who want to do nefarious things with data rarely play exactly by your rules just because you ask them to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s an interesting parallel here with &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/21/uber-data-breach-from-2016-affected-57-million-riders-and-drivers/&quot;&gt;Uber’s response to a 2016 data breach&lt;/a&gt; of its systems. In that case, instead of informing the ~57M affected users and drivers that their personal data had been compromised, Uber’s senior management also decided to try and make the problem go away — by asking (and in their case paying) hackers to delete the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aka the trigger response for both tech companies to massive &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/data-protection/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;data-protection&quot;&gt;data protection&lt;/a&gt; fuck-ups was: Cover up; don’t disclose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook denies the Cambridge Analytica instance is a &lt;em&gt;data&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;breach&lt;/em&gt; — because, well, its systems were so laxly designed as to actively encourage vast amounts of data to be sucked out, via API, without the check and balance of those third parties having to gain individual level consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in that sense Facebook is entirely right; technically what Cambridge Analytica did wasn’t a breach at all. It was a feature, not a bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly that’s also the opposite of reassuring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet Facebook and Uber are companies whose businesses rely entirely on users trusting them to safeguard personal data. The disconnect here is gapingly obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s also crystal clear is that rules and systems designed to &lt;em&gt;protect and control&lt;/em&gt; personal data, combined with &lt;em&gt;active enforcement&lt;/em&gt; of those rules and robust security to safeguard systems, are absolutely essential to prevent people’s information being misused at scale in today’s hyperconnected era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before you say hindsight is 20/20 vision, &lt;span&gt;the history of this epic Facebook privacy fail is even longer than the under-disclosed events of 2015 suggest — i.e. when Facebook claims it found out about the breach as a result of investigations by journalists.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the company very clearly turned a blind eye to is the risk posed by its own system of loose app permissions that in turn enabled developers to suck out vast amounts of data without having to worry about pesky user consent. And, ultimately, for Cambridge Analytica to get its hands on the profiles of ~50M US Facebookers for dark ad political targeting purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/privacy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt; campaigner and lawyer Max Schrems — a &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2012/06/01/facebook-forced-by-privacy-activist-to-put-policy-changes-up-for-worldwide-vote/&quot;&gt;long time critic of Facebook&lt;/a&gt; — was actually raising concerns about the Facebook’s lax attitude to data protection and app permissions as long ago as 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, in August 2011 Schrems filed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europe-v-facebook.org/Complaint_13_Applications.pdf&quot;&gt;a complaint&lt;/a&gt; with the Irish Data Protection Commission exactly flagging the app permissions data sinkhole (Ireland being the focal point for the complaint because that’s where Facebook’s European HQ is based).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[T]his means that not the data subject but “friends” of the data subject are consenting to the use of personal data,” wrote Schrems in the 2011 complaint, fleshing out consent concerns with Facebook’s friends’ data API. “Since an average facebook user has 130 friends, it is very likely that only one of the user’s friends is installing some kind of spam or phishing application and is consenting to the use of all data of the data subject. There are many applications that do not need to access the users’ friends personal data (e.g. games, quizzes, apps that only post things on the user’s page) but Facebook Ireland does not offer a more limited level of access than “all the basic information of all friends”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The data subject is not given an unambiguous consent to the processing of personal data by applications (no opt-in). Even if a data subject is aware of this entire process, the data subject cannot foresee which application of which developer will be using which personal data in the future. Any form of consent can therefore never be specific,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of Schrems’ complaint, the Irish DPC &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europe-v-facebook.org/Facebook_Ireland_Audit_Report_Final.pdf&quot;&gt;audited&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europe-v-facebook.org/ODPC_Review.pdf&quot;&gt;re-audited&lt;/a&gt; Facebook’s systems in 2011 and 2012. The result of those data audits included a recommendation that Facebook tighten app permissions on its platform, according to a spokesman for the Irish DPC, who we spoke to this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spokesman said the DPC’s recommendation formed the basis of the major platform change &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.techcrunch.com/2014/05/02/f8/?_ga=2.27993406.364962070.1521621827-362044370.1515940976&quot;&gt;Facebook announced in 2014&lt;/a&gt; — aka &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/28/facebook-api-shut-down/&quot;&gt;shutting down the Friends data API&lt;/a&gt; — albeit too late to prevent Cambridge Analytica from being able to harvest millions of profiles’ worth of personal data via a survey app because Facebook only made the change gradually, finally closing the door in May 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Following the re-audit… one of the recommendations we made was in the area of the ability to use friends data through social media,” the DPC spokesman told us. “And that recommendation that we made in 2012, that was implemented by Facebook in 2014 as part of a wider platform change that they made. It’s that change that they made that means that the Cambridge Analytica thing cannot happen today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They made the platform change in 2014, their change was for anybody new coming onto the platform from 1st May 2014 they couldn’t do this. They gave a 12 month period for existing users to migrate across to their new platform… and it was in that period that… Cambridge Analytica’s use of the information for their data emerged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But from 2015 — for absolutely everybody — this issue with CA cannot happen now. And that was following our recommendation that we made in 2012.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given his 2011 complaint about Facebook’s expansive and abusive historical app permissions, Schrems has this week raised an eyebrow and expressed surprise at Zuckerberg’s claim to be “outraged” by the Cambridge Analytica revelations — now snowballing into a massive privacy scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://noyb.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Media-Update-Cambridge-Analytica-en.pdf&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; reflecting on developments he writes: “Facebook has millions of times illegally distributed data of its users to various dodgy apps — without the consent of those affected. In 2011 we sent a legal complaint to the Irish Data Protection Commissioner on this. Facebook argued that this data transfer is perfectly legal and no changes were made. Now after the outrage surrounding Cambridge Analytica the Internet giant suddenly feels betrayed seven years later. Our records show: Facebook knew about this betrayal for years and previously argues that these practices are perfectly legal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why did it take Facebook from September 2012 — when the DPC made its recommendations — until May 2014 and May 2015 to implement the changes and tighten app permissions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regulator’s spokesman told us it was “engaging” with Facebook over that period of time “to ensure that the change was made”. But he also said Facebook spent some time pushing back — questioning why changes to app permissions were necessary and dragging its feet on shuttering the friends’ data API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think the reality is Facebook had questions as to whether they felt there was a need for them to make the changes that we were recommending,” said the spokesman. “And that was, I suppose, the level of engagement that we had with them. Because we were relatively strong that we felt yes we made the recommendation because we felt the change needed to be made. And that was the nature of the discussion. And as I say ultimately, ultimately the reality is that the change has been made. And it’s been made to an extent that such an issue couldn’t occur today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That is a matter for Facebook themselves to answer as to why they took that period of time,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course we asked Facebook why it pushed back against the DPC’s recommendation in September 2012 — and whether it regrets not acting more swiftly to implement the changes to its APIs, given the crisis its business is now faced having breached user trust by failing to safeguard people’s data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also asked why Facebook users should trust Zuckerberg’s claim, also made in the CNN interview, that it’s now ‘open to being regulated’ — when its historical playbook is packed with examples of the polar opposite behavior, including ongoing &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/25/facebooks-least-favorite-austrian-can-now-press-privacy-suit-in-vienna/&quot;&gt;attempts to circumvent existing EU privacy rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Facebook spokeswoman acknowledged receipt of our questions this week — but the company has not responded to any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DPCIreland/status/976887241204289542&quot;&gt;Irish DPC chief, Helen Dixon, also went on CNN&lt;/a&gt; this week to give her response to the Facebook-Cambridge Analytica data misuse crisis — calling for assurances from Facebook that it will properly police its own data protection policies in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Even where Facebook have terms and policies in place for app developers, it doesn’t necessarily give us the assurance that those app developers are abiding by the policies Facebook have set, and that Facebook is active in terms of overseeing that there’s no leakage of personal data. And that conditions, such as the prohibition on selling on data to further third parties is being adhered to by app developers,” said Dixon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So I suppose what we want to see change and what we want to oversee with Facebook now and what we’re demanding answers from Facebook in relation to, is first of all what pre-clearance and what pre-authorization do they do before permitting app developers onto their platform. And secondly, once those app developers are operative and have apps collecting personal data what kind of follow up and active oversight steps does Facebook take to give us all reassurance that the type of issue that appears to have occurred in relation to Cambridge Analytica won’t happen again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefighting the raging privacy crisis, Zuckerberg has committed to conducting a historical audit of every app that had access to “a large amount” of user data around the time that Cambridge Analytica was able to harvest so much data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it remains to be seen what other data misuses Facebook will unearth — and have to confess to now, long after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But any other embarrassing data leaks will sit within the same unfortunate context — which is to say that Facebook &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; have prevented these problems if it had listened to the very valid concerns data protection experts were raising more than six years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, it chose to drag its feet. And the list of awkward questions for the Facebook CEO keeps getting longer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 21:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>domevent</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook was warned about app permissions in 2011</og:title>
<og:description>Who’s to blame for the leaking of 50 million Facebook users’ data? Facebook founder and CEO Mark Zuckerberg broke several days of silence in the face of a raging privacy storm to go on CNN this week to say he was sorry. He also admitted the company had made mistakes; said it had breache…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/screen-shot-2018-03-24-at-8-03-42-pm.png?w=761</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/03/24/facebook-was-warned-about-app-permissions-in-2011/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/24/facebook-was-warned-about-app-permissions-in-2011/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Facebook Really Scarier Than Google?</title>
<link>http://nautil.us/blog/is-facebook-really-scarier-than-google</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://nautil.us/blog/is-facebook-really-scarier-than-google</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.nautil.us/14405_630d790d0716246ca1aa250a6f86f755.jpg&quot; width=&quot;733&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Twitter, in a thread that went viral, François Chollet, an A.I. software engineer at Google DeepMind, argued, “Facebook is, in effect, in control of your political beliefs and your worldview.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Photograph by Joe Penniston / Flickr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap mqw&quot;&gt;M&lt;/span&gt;ark Zuckerberg, the founder and C.E.O. of Facebook, admitted recently his company knew, in 2015, that the data firm Cambridge Analytica, which assisted with Donald Trump’s election campaign, had improperly acquired information on 50 million Facebook users. “This was a breach of trust,” Zuckerberg said, in a Facebook &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10104712037900071&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;. “We need to fix that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that’s not the only thing Facebook needs to fix. “The problem with Facebook is not &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; the loss of your privacy and the fact that it can be used as a totalitarian panopticon,” said François Chollet, an artificial intelligence and machine learning software engineer at Google DeepMind, in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fchollet/status/976563870322999296&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; yesterday. “The more worrying issue, in my opinion, is its use of digital information consumption as a psychological control vector.” He elaborated on this point in a thread that’s been shared thousands of times. I caught it when global-surveillance critic and &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; writer Glenn Greenwald &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ggreenwald/status/976825393960378368&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;quote-retweeted&lt;/a&gt; Chollet, calling it a “great thread” on “Facebook’s menacing use” of psychology-manipulating A.I. “But remember,” Greenwald added, “Google is also a major exploiter of artificial intelligence with very little transparency or public oversight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chollet bristled at this. “This is the laziest kind of thinking—just because two things share some superficial similarity (they’re large tech [companies]) doesn’t mean they’re equivalent,” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fchollet/status/976783608219279360&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. Why? Look to the Newsfeed, Facebook’s signature feature, Chollet went on, in this Twitter thread. “If Facebook gets to decide, over the span of many years, which news you will see (real or fake), whose political status updates you’ll see, and who will see yours, then Facebook is, in effect, in control of your political beliefs and your worldview.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fil Menczer, Professor of Informatics and Computer Science at Indiana University, told &lt;em&gt;Nautilus&lt;/em&gt;, in a discussion about his &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/359/6380/1094&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;work on fake news&lt;/a&gt;, that the algorithms used on social media platforms, like Facebook, bias our decision-making in ways that exploit our socio-cognitive biases—but search engines like Google &lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/52/the-hive/modern-media-is-a-dos-attack-on-your-free-will&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;aren’t entirely innocent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Zuckerberg is morally bankrupt, he’s trying to hide it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The algorithmic biases feed into social and cognitive biases, like confirmation bias, which in turn feed into the algorithmic biases. Before, people were looking at the evening news on TV, or reading the local paper, for example. But the fact that the medium has changed to online social networks, where you shape the sources of information to which you are exposed, now means that you become even more vulnerable,” he said. “Search engines and social media, for example, try to predict what content may be most engaging for someone. Ranking algorithms use popularity as one of the ingredients in their formulas. That means that the more people in your group interact or engage with a piece of fake news, the more likely you are to see it. The social network can act as an amplifier because the people near you have opinions similar to you, so they are more likely to be tricked by a certain kind of fake news, which means you are more likely to see it, too.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.nautil.us/14406_793aaa24e931c05d077f434e33485574.png&quot; width=&quot;733&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;François Chollet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Image from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UeheTiBJ0Io&quot;&gt;Google Developers / YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Chollet, though, the sort of danger Facebook poses is unique. “There’s only one company where the product is an opaque algorithmic newsfeed, that has been running large-scale mood/opinion manipulation experiments, that is neck-deep in an election manipulation scandal, that has shown time and time again to have morally bankrupt leadership. Essentially nothing about the threat described applies to Google. Nor Amazon. Nor Apple. It could apply to Twitter, in principle, but in practice it almost entirely doesn’t,” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fchollet/status/976784465245515776&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. What seems to clinch it for him is that Facebook is ambitiously pursuing advances in A.I. “What do you use AI…for, when your product is a newsfeed?” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fchollet/status/976569278328549378&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wondered&lt;/a&gt;. “Personally, it really scares me. If you work in A.I., please don’t help them. Don’t play their game. Don’t participate in their research ecosystem. Please show some conscience.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He takes the decision to work for his current employer, Alphabet—former motto “Don’t be evil,” and now “Do the right thing”—as a demonstration of scrupulousness. “For me, working at Google”—an Alphabet subsidiary—“is a deliberate choice,” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fchollet/status/976786099254181888&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. “If I start feeling uncomfortable, I’ll definitely leave. If I had been working at [Facebook], I would have left in 2017.” For now, he’s glad to labor for a company whose products—like Gmail and Android—are “anti-Facebook,” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fchollet/status/976935081817251840&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;went on&lt;/a&gt;. These empower people, while Facebook’s Newsfeed “seeks to maximally waste your time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Zuckerberg is morally bankrupt, he’s trying to hide it. On Wednesday, he told CNN that he’d be “happy to” to testify to Congress and, on Facebook, announced several changes that will, supposedly, rectify what went wrong with the Cambridge Analytica data-breach scandal. “I started Facebook,” he wrote, “and at the end of the day I’m responsible for what happens on our platform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is worth keeping in mind, though: That, also at the end of the day, “The motivation for Facebook is not to make you a better person—to improve you morally or intellectually—and it’s not even designed to improve your social group,” Simon DeDeo, an assistant professor at Carnegie Mellon University, where he runs the Laboratory for Social Minds, and external faculty at the Santa Fe Institute, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/12/feedback/ingenious-simon-dedeo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Nautilus&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s designed to make money, to show you things you want to see to hopefully induce you to purchase things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-w=&quot;733&quot; data-h=&quot;410&quot; class=&quot;vimeo-breakers&quot; src=&quot;https://i.vimeocdn.com/video/472613010_640.jpg&quot; data-video-id=&quot;92765955&quot; data-capper=&quot;&quot; data-credits=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brian Gallagher is the editor of Facts So Romantic, the&lt;/em&gt; Nautilus &lt;em&gt;blog. Follow him on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brianga11agher&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@brianga11agher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Victor Gomes, an editorial intern at&lt;/em&gt; Nautilus&lt;em&gt;, contributed reporting to this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 19:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dnetesn</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://nautil.us/blog/is-facebook-really-scarier-than-google</og:url>
<og:title>Is Facebook Really Scarier Than Google? - Facts So Romantic - Nautilus</og:title>
<og:description>On Twitter, in a thread that went viral, François Chollet, an A.I. software engineer at Google DeepMind, argued, “Facebook is,&amp;#8230;</og:description>
<og:image>http://static.nautil.us/14405_630d790d0716246ca1aa250a6f86f755.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://nautil.us/blog/is-facebook-really-scarier-than-google</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sex Workers Say Porn on Google Drive Is Suddenly Disappearing</title>
<link>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/9kgwnp/porn-on-google-drive-error</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/9kgwnp/porn-on-google-drive-error</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Porn performer &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Avey_Moon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Avey Moon&lt;/a&gt; was trying to send the lucky winner of her Chaturbate contest his prize—one of her videos, titled &quot;POV Blowjob&quot;—through her Google Drive account. But it wouldn’t send, and Google wasn’t telling her why.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I thought there was something wrong with my file and I got rather worried,” Moon told me in a Twitter message. “I had promised this guy his content and he was so good to me. I was panicked because I thought if I couldn't give him his prize, he would feel like he got ripped off and never come back again or worse, he could actually file a complaint with Chaturbate about me and they can take money from me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s not alone. Six porn performers I talked to and more on social media said that they suddenly can't download adult content they keep on Google Drive. They also said they can't a share that content with other accounts or send to clients. In some cases, the adult content is disappearing from Drive without warning or explanation. The porn performers I talked to started sounding the alarm on Twitter last week. They said that Google Drive no longer seemed sex-trade friendly, detailing error messages and sharing cloud storage alternatives with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I asked about sexual content being blocked on Drive, a spokesperson for Google directed me to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/docs/answer/148505?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Drive policy page&lt;/a&gt;—specifically the section on sexually explicit material, which says, “Do not publish sexually explicit or pornographic images or videos.... Additionally, we do not allow content that drives traffic to commercial pornography.” Writing about porn and sex is permitted, the policy states, as long as it’s not accompanied by sexually explicit images or videos. According to Google, Drive uses a combination of automated systems and manual review to decide what’s in violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;“It's very oppressive. And it's making my job hellish.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I heard randomly that someone got one piece of their adult content flagged, that was stored on Google Drive,” adult performer &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MelodyKush/status/974323910002069509&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Melody Kush&lt;/a&gt; told me in Twitter direct messages. She’s been using Google Drive for most of the last five and a half years she’s worked as a performer full-time, but started using it more heavily for work in the last three years. “I didn't think anything of it. Then I heard it again, different person. Then it happened to me.” She said she tried to send a video to a client that she’d successfully sent to one other person before, but this time, she received an error message, saying that the item may violate Google's Terms of Service, with a link to request a review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video title contained the phrase “cum show,” which Kush suspected triggered the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unlike Kush and Moon, others have gotten this error on videos even when the title isn’t explicit. “It's just the content, which is the strange part,” adult performer &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Stonedsexy66&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lilly Stone&lt;/a&gt; told me in a Twitter direct message. Her Drive account contains mostly adult content, but her images aren’t affected by this error—only videos, some of which have begun to disappear without warning or explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more: &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/zmz3yw/why-is-my-google-doc-locked-terms-of-service-bug&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Docs Is Randomly Flagging Files for Violating its Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It seems like all of our videos in Google Drive are getting flagged by some sort of automated system,” Stone said. “We're not even really getting notified of it, the only way we really found out was one of our customers told us he couldn't view or download the video we sent him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stone’s files aren’t removed from Drive, but when she tries to play the video or download it, she said Google gives her an error message: &quot;Whoops! There was a problem playing this video” with an option to download the item, but the download link doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some sex workers are wondering if this has something to do with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/neqxaw/sex-trafficking-bill-sesta-fosta-vote&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;impending vote on the SESTA-FOSTA bill&lt;/a&gt;, which is on the Senate floor for debate this week. Performer Hailey Heartless told me that she’s not sure if it’s a “blitz” that Google is doing, or if it’s just something many sex workers noticed at once, and got the conversation started—but she’s heard from dozens of people in the industry about the issue, after tweeting about her own experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could also be that Google is simply, suddenly, deciding to enforce its Terms of Service. The fact remains that Google Drive is either glitching out and impacting people’s livelihoods, or suddenly enforcing its Terms of Service without warning. Adult performer &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RamonaFlour/status/974377170675032064&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ramona Flour&lt;/a&gt; told me in an email that she’s been using a paid version of Drive with 1 TB of storage, which costs $9.99 a month, for five years, but she just started getting error messages last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It's very oppressive. And it's making my job hellish,” Moon told me. “I'm still stressing about finding a way around this. I don't believe that Google should be allowed to dictate what you and another consenting adult send to each other through email.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 19:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MilnerRoute</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Sex Workers Say Porn on Google Drive Is Suddenly Disappearing</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5ab27189111f6e0008f8e607/lede/1521644290441-driveporn.jpeg?crop=1xw:1xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/9kgwnp/porn-on-google-drive-error</og:url>
<og:description>Sex workers are reporting that their Google Drive files are mysteriously locked or vanishing.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/9kgwnp/porn-on-google-drive-error</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fred&amp;#039;s ImageMagick Scripts</title>
<link>http://www.fmwconcepts.com/imagemagick/index.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.fmwconcepts.com/imagemagick/index.php</guid>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Detailed information and examples are available for each script on separate pages linked above and below as well as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fmwconcepts.com/imagemagick/script_list.txt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;summary list&lt;/a&gt; of them all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also try many of them in an interactive environment at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jqmagick.imagemagick.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JqMagic&lt;/a&gt;. This is a collaborative effort with Jd Audibert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To download a script, go the examples page for that script and simply click on the link. The links are controlled by a counter script and are set to download automatically upon a single left button click.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These scripts are bash unix shell scripts and should work on Linux and Mac OSX with IM 6.3.5.0 or higher. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that they were not designed for multi-page/multi-layer/multi-frame images&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;p&gt;Pointers for use:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be sure you have installed the unix calculator, bc. It is an option that you may have to select when installing unix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the script&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the name to remove the suffix .dms (if it exists) and optionally replace with .sh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set the script to executable (chmod u+x)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the full path to where IM (convert) resides by typing in a shell terminal window: type -a convert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If type -a convert returns more than one path, type in a shell terminal window: path2/convert -version, where path2 is each of the paths found. Decide which version of IM you want to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modify your PATH environment variable so that it includes the full path to where IM (convert) resides (often /usr/bin or /usr/local/bin). This can be done by editing your .profile file.&lt;br/&gt;Alternately, edit the script somewhere between the comments and the first use of any IM command, such as just below the defaults section to add the following two lines:&lt;br/&gt;imdir=&quot;path2&quot; #(such as imdir=&quot;/usr/local/bin&quot; or imdir=&quot;/usr/bin&quot;)&lt;br/&gt;PATH=&quot;${imdir}:${PATH}&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a shell terminal window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SYNTAX: bash /fullpathto/scriptname(.sh) arguments /fullpathto/inputimage /fullpathto/outputimage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To avoid the bash and just use scriptname(.sh) ... set your PATH to contain the location of the script. I strongly suggest you create a directory to contain all my scripts and put the path to that directory in your PATH environment variable. That will also avoid issues for scripts that make calls to any of my other scripts and also messages regarding locating my scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optionally edit the script to change the default directory (found after the defaults section) from dir=&quot;.&quot; to dir=&quot;/tmp&quot; and be sure it has read/write permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have trouble with filenames with spaces in them, then you will need to edit the script in several places until I have time to review and fix all my scripts.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find where infile and outfile (maskfile or any others) are defined at the end of the argument trapping section. Make sure to enclose in double quotes any declarations of those files that include $1, $2, etc, such as infile=&quot;$1&quot;, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find any occurrences of $infile or $outfile and enclose them in double quotes as &quot;$infile&quot;, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On some Linux systems, there may be an issue with duplicate lines of documentation when using the -help option. If this is the case, try changing the following two lines in functions usage1() and usage2(), respectively, just below the commented section at the top of the script as follows (suggested by Stefan Vorkoetter and Ted Baker):&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;sed &amp;gt;&amp;amp;2 -e '1,/^####/d; /^###/g; /^#/!q; s/^#//; s/^ //; 4,$p' &quot;$PROGDIR/$PROGNAME&quot;&lt;br/&gt;To:&lt;br/&gt;sed -e '1,/^####$/d; /^###$/,$d; s/^#//; s/^ //' &quot;$PROGDIR/$PROGNAME&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sed &amp;gt;&amp;amp;2 -e '1,/^####/d; /^######/g; /^#/!q; s/^#*//; s/^ //; 4,$p' &quot;$PROGDIR/$PROGNAME&quot;&lt;br/&gt;To:&lt;br/&gt;sed -e '1,/^####$/d; /^######$/,$d; s/^#*//; s/^ //' &quot;$PROGDIR/$PROGNAME&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;or&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;sed &amp;gt;&amp;amp;2 -n -e '1,/^####/d; /^###/g; /^#/!q; s/^#//; s/^ //; 4,$p' &quot;$PROGDIR/$PROGNAME&quot;&lt;br/&gt;To:&lt;br/&gt;sed -e '1,/^####$/d; /^###$/,$d; s/^#//; s/^ //' &quot;$PROGDIR/$PROGNAME&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sed &amp;gt;&amp;amp;2 -n -e '1,/^####/d; /^######/g; /^#/!q; s/^#*//; s/^ //; 4,$p' &quot;$PROGDIR/$PROGNAME&quot;&lt;br/&gt;To:&lt;br/&gt;sed -e '1,/^####$/d; /^######$/,$d; s/^#*//; s/^ //' &quot;$PROGDIR/$PROGNAME&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;These scripts can be used with PHP exec command.&lt;p&gt;Pointers for use:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be sure you have installed the unix calculator, bc. It is an option that you may have to select when installing unix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the script&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the name to remove the suffix .dms (if it exists) and optionally replace with .sh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set the script to executable (chmod u+x)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the full path to where IM (convert) resides by typing in a shell terminal window: type -a convert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If type -a convert returns more than one path, type in a shell terminal window: path2/convert -version, where path2 is each of the paths found. Decide which version of IM you want to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modify your PATH environment variable so that it includes the full path to where IM (convert) resides (often /usr/bin or /usr/local/bin). This can be done by editing your .profile file.&lt;br/&gt;Alternately, edit the script somewhere between the comments and the first use of any IM command, such as just below the defaults section to add the following two lines:&lt;br/&gt;imdir=&quot;path2&quot; #(such as imdir=&quot;/usr/local/bin&quot; or imdir=&quot;/usr/bin&quot;)&lt;br/&gt;PATH=&quot;${imdir}:${PATH}&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the script to change the default directory (found after the defaults section) from dir=&quot;.&quot; to dir=&quot;/tmp&quot; and be sure it has read/write permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the exec command use bash /fullpathto/scriptname(.sh) arguments /fullpathto/inputimage /fullpathto/outputimage.&lt;br/&gt;Note that &quot;bash&quot; may or may not be necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To avoid the bash and just use scriptname(.sh) ... set your PATH to contain the location of the script. I strongly suggest you create a directory to contain all my scripts and put the path to that directory in your PATH environment variable. That will also avoid issues for scripts that make calls to any of my other scripts and also messages regarding locating my scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have trouble with filenames with spaces in them, then you will need to edit the script in several places until I have time to review and fix all my scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find where infile and outfile (maskfile or any others) are defined at the end of the argument trapping section. Make sure to enclose in double quotes any declarations of those files that include $1, $2, etc, such as infile=&quot;$1&quot;, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find any occurrences of $infile or $outfile and enclose them in double quotes as &quot;$infile&quot;, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows users can run my scripts, if they install the unix Cygwin system for Windows and then install the IM Cygwin binary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Windows 10 (64-bit) users can also run my scripts without the need for Cygwin. Bruce Rusk reports: All that was need was the installation of the Unix bc tool and Imagemagick through apt/apt-get. Everything else worked right out of the box, no changes to PATH variables required. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.howtogeek.com/249966/how-to-install-and-use-the-linux-bash-shell-on-windows-10/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How to Install and Use the Linux Bash Shell on Windows 10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My earliest scripts were developed under ImageMagick-6.3.5.0 on Mac OS 10.4x. I have tried to keep them updated with changes in IM versions. All were developed using Q16 IM. I do not know how compatible they are to older version of ImageMagick, nor to other Q levels or other versions of Unix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;red&quot;&gt;NOTE: Starting with IM 6.3.5.7, -matte/+matte were deprecated in favor of -alpha set or on/-alpha off. Therefore, many of my scripts may not work with IM versions prior to that unless replaced with the deprecated syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use at your own risk. The argument testing may not be foolproof nor do I bear any responsibility for any problems that may occur by their use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like to thank Anthony Thyssen for his patience with all my newbie questions about IM and Unix. His replies were invaluable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My background involves image processing with a specialty in image perspective transformations from arial photography. For details, see my &lt;a href=&quot;linkcounter.php?dir=http://&amp;amp;linkname=www.fmwconcepts.com/fmw/fmw.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;personal information page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have also written a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fmwconcepts.com/imagemagick/linkcounter.php?dir=./&amp;amp;linkname=digital_image_filtering.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;digital image filtering tutorial&lt;/a&gt; (2MB PDF). It supplements the description of the following scripts below with more mathematical detail: binomial, derivative, gradient, laplacian, statsfilt, isonoise, sharp and space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And I have created a tutorial for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fmwconcepts.com/imagemagick/linkcounter.php?dir=fourier_transforms/&amp;amp;linkname=fourier.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fourier Transform Processing With ImageMagick&lt;/a&gt;. It supplements the description of the following scripts below with more mathematical detail: spectrum, fftconvol, fftdeconvol, fftfilter, cepstrum, camerablur, cameradeblur, normcrosscorr and notch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also see my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fmwconcepts.com/imagemagick/tidbits/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ImageMagick Tidbits&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comments and bug reports are always welcome. My contact information is fmw at alink dot net&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you find any of these scripts are particularly useful, please let the folks at ImageMagick know. Perhaps they will consent to implement them as IM functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;purple&quot;&gt;NOTE: I fix problems that I find with the scripts or make improvements often. So please check the last modified dates below or the revision dates in the scripts for updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Latest Updates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;polyring: Feb 28, 2018 - added new script to create a polygon ring image from one or more images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shadows: Feb 23, 2018 - added new script to apply drop shadows to an image that has an alpha channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outfitwarper: Jan 6, 2018 - added new script to transform a pattern image onto an image of some piece of clothing or outfit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outfit: Jan 3, 2018 - added new script to transform a pattern image onto an image of some piece of clothing or outfit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tshirwarper: Dec 20, 2017 - added new script to transform an image to place it in a region of a tshirt image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mandalascope: Dec 7, 2017 - added new script to convert an image into a mandala-like kaleidoscope image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mandala: Dec 1, 2017 - added new script to create a Mandala type image from simple graphic figures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;radialgrid: Nov 29, 2017 - added new script to superimpose a set of circulare grid lines on an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vibrance2: Nov 15, 2017 - added new script to apply a non-linear change to the chroma channel of an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;toonify: Nov 11, 2017 - added new script to apply a cartoon-like effect to an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;toonizarro: Nov 5, 2017 - added new script to apply a Superman Bizarro-like cartoon effect to an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turbulence: Oct 28, 2017 - added new script to apply a turbulence-like warping of the image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multicrop &amp;amp; multicrop2: Oct 18, 2017 - improved scripts to permit innertrim of extracted areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trimcorners: Oct 13, 2017 - added new script to automatically crop the image to removed rounded corners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adaptivegamma: Oct 2, 2017 - added new script to enhance the contrast/brightness in an image using a locally adaptive gamma method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sphericalpano2rect: Sep 20, 2017 - added new script to generate a perspective image from a region of a spherical panorama.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cube2sphericalpano: Sep 18, 2017 - added new script to transform 6 cube face images into a spherical panorama image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sphericalpano2cube: Sep 18, 2017 - added new script to transform a spherical panorama into a cubical representation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tinyplanet: Aug 12, 2017 - added new script to transform a spherical panorama to a linear fisheye view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pano2fisheye: Aug 11, 2017 - added new script to transform a spherical panorama to a fisheye view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smarttrim: Jul 14, 2017 - added new script to automatically trim an image around the region of highest detail in the images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smartcrop: Jul 3, 2017 - added new script to automatically crop an image to a given size around the hightest detail region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watercolor: Jun 30, 2017 - added new script to apply a watercolor effect to an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sketching: Jun 27, 2017 - added new script to apply a sketch effect to an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;colorfulness: Jun 12, 2017 - added new script to compute a metric that represents the colorfulness of an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sketchetch: Jun 10, 2017 - added new script to create an etch-like sketch from an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shapecluster: Jun 5, 2017 - added new script to create a division of the image into 5 separated rectangular regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;textdistort: Jun 2, 2017 - added new script to distort repeated text to warp it to the shape of the image content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pip: May 29, 2017 - added new script to create a picture-in-picture effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;colorcells: May 18, 2017 - added new script to randomly modify the color of rectangular cells of an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;painteffect: Apr 20, 2017 - added new script to apply a paint effect to an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;contour: Apr 1, 2017 - added new script to apply a contour outline to the image content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removecolorcast: Jan 31, 2017 - added new script to remove a color cast from an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;corners: Jan 27, 2017 - added new script to detect corner structures in an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;transfercolor: Jan 14, 2017 - added new script to transfer the coloring from one image to another image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The following scripts are superceded by newer IM functions:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Superceded Scripts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;adjoin script is superceded by IM -append&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anglegradient script is superceded multigradient script&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;autogamma script is superceded by IM -auto-gamma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;autolevel script is superceded by the sequence of IM -auto-level -auto-gamma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bcimage script is superceded by IM -brightness-contrast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bilinearwarp script is superceded by IM -distort bilinearforward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fisheye2pano script is mostly superceded by IM -distort depolar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flicker script is superceded by Anthony's script flicker_cmp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;levelcolors script is superceded by IM -level-colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moments script is superceded by IM identify -verbose -moments (IM 6.8.8.2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;morphology script is superceded by IM -morphology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pinbarrel script is superceded by IM -distort barrel and -distort barrelinverse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;polar script is superceded by IM -distort polar and -distort depolar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;profile script is superceded by Anthony's script im_profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;saturation script is superceded by IM -modulate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;separate script is superceded by IM -connected-components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;similar script is superceded by IM compare -metric ncc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;skew script is superceded by IM -shear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssim script is superceded by IM compare -metric ssim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stretch script is superceded by IM -auto-level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 19:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>primogen</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.fmwconcepts.com/imagemagick/index.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fediverse – Federated social networks running on free open software</title>
<link>https://fediverse.party</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://fediverse.party</guid>
<description>&lt;a class=&quot;grid__item f-Socialhome&quot; href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/socialhome&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;grid__item__image&quot; src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/socialhome.png&quot; alt=&quot;Socialhome&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;grid__item__title&quot;&gt;Socialhome&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;grid__card&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/socialhome.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Socialhome&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federated personal profile with social networking functionality, suitable for image based content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;grid__item f-GangGo&quot; href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/ganggo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;grid__item__image&quot; src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/ganggo.png&quot; alt=&quot;GangGo&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;grid__item__title&quot;&gt;GangGo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid__card&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/ganggo.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;GangGo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decentralized social network written in GoLang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;grid__item f-Aardwolf&quot; href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/aardwolf&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;grid__item__image&quot; src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/aardwolf.png&quot; alt=&quot;Aardwolf&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;grid__item__title&quot;&gt;Aardwolf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid__card&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/aardwolf.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aardwolf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New platform for powering communities across the web, written in Rust-lang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;grid__item f-Hubzilla&quot; href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/hubzilla&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;grid__item__image&quot; src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/hubzilla.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hubzilla&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;grid__item__title&quot;&gt;Hubzilla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid__card&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/hubzilla.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Hubzilla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powerful platform for creating sites with a decentralized nomadic identity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;grid__item f-diaspora&quot; href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/diaspora&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;grid__item__image&quot; src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/diaspora.png&quot; alt=&quot;diaspora&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;grid__item__title&quot;&gt;diaspora&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid__card&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/diaspora.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;diaspora&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online world where you are in control. Own your data. Choose your audience. Be who you want to be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;grid__item f-Pleroma&quot; href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/pleroma&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;grid__item__image&quot; src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/pleroma.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pleroma&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;grid__item__title&quot;&gt;Pleroma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid__card&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/pleroma.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pleroma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federated networking platform, compatible with GNU social and OStatus. Light as a feather&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;grid__item f-Mastodon&quot; href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/mastodon&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;grid__item__image&quot; src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/mastodon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mastodon&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;grid__item__title&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid__card&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/mastodon.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mastodon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social networking, back in your hands. Find your perfect community. Take control of your content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;grid__item f-postActiv&quot; href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/postactiv&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;grid__item__image&quot; src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/postactiv.png&quot; alt=&quot;postActiv&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;grid__item__title&quot;&gt;postActiv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid__card&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/postactiv.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;postActiv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social networking platform with many additional features, plugins and an open, free software codebase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;grid__item f-Friendica&quot; href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/friendica&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;grid__item__image&quot; src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/friendica.png&quot; alt=&quot;Friendica&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;grid__item__title&quot;&gt;Friendica&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid__card&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/friendica.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Friendica&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal network with no central authority or ownership. Keep in contact with people you care about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;grid__item f-GNUSocial&quot; href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/gnusocial&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;grid__item__image&quot; src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/gnusocial.png&quot; alt=&quot;GNUSocial&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;grid__item__title&quot;&gt;GNU Social&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid__card&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fediverse.party/img/gnusocial.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;GNU Social&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecting free and independent communities across the web&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;introduction&quot; class=&quot;intro&quot; readability=&quot;6.4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intro__content&quot; readability=&quot;8.8&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;u-emphasize&quot;&gt;Hello, traveller!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave the familiar Web behind, and dive into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/en/fediverse&quot;&gt;unique part of the Internet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the world of independence and diversity.&lt;br/&gt;A universe that you shape, refine and expand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://the-federation.info&quot; rel=&quot;external nofollow noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JOIN FEDIVERSE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 15:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jaywink</dc:creator>
<og:title>Fediverse Wiki</og:title>
<og:description>Fediverse Wiki</og:description>
<og:image>https://fediverse.gitlab.io/tile.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://fediverse.party/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Look for the duct tape</title>
<link>http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2018/03/23/ducttape/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2018/03/23/ducttape/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I've been having some wonderful conversations in the real world since resigning and jumping off the merry-go-round. Besides just talking about what happened, why I left, and how to succeed in the &quot;2018 version&quot; of the culture which now exists, I'm also still doing the same mentoring stuff I always did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these conversations have yielded some real gems, and one I had not long ago is no exception. I didn't realize it at first, but it was actually a conversation about how to find interesting things to work on. It started as a simple question: what bugged me about the (X) environment when I was there? What would I change?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally when something bugs me and has outstanding issues, there's this mental laundry list in my head and I can rattle off a few things. But for this, I didn't have anything. I wasn't sure if it was because I've been free for about a month now, but the answers just weren't forthcoming. Still, I tried to give some kind of answer because this person needed direction. If I said &quot;it's all good&quot;, that wouldn't help them at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit of pondering and feeling really bad about not having anything to say, it hit me. I had rigged up a bunch of local tools in my own &quot;bin&quot; directory to do things that the &quot;X&quot; environment did not handle. Those &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; been issues for me, but were no longer, because I had covered the rough edges with my own workarounds. The system now worked in a way that didn't annoy me too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I was able to rattle off a whole bunch of dumb little shell scripts and other tools that I had written over the past 4.5 years to make my life better when operating in that space. This turned out to be a treasure trove of things worth digging into. To think that I almost said that everything was fine and nothing was wrong!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I tried to pop up a level to give a general tenet instead of just a laundry list of dumb things I had worked around, and looking around at the public furniture in the town square, it came to me: look for the duct tape. Look for the patches to the original system which were done by people who actually work in a given space. Track down the sharp edges which have been systematically covered up by users who were more interested in being productive and weren't willing to fight with the owners of the system to get things changed upstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In concrete terms, go around and find out what kind of little one-off tools people have designed. Talk to them and hear their stories. Look in their personal bin directories. Take notes and look for patterns. See if anything stands out, or if anything particularly compelling grabs you during the interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, if you go off and build something new to soften a rough edge, not only do they get to remove the duct tape, but you have a bunch of interested users from day one. Also, just think of the goodwill that is bound to follow when they realize that finally, someone cares about the end-user experience, and is willing to adapt upstream to make their lives better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for the duct tape.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fanf2</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2018/03/23/ducttape/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>TLS 1.3 approved</title>
<link>https://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf-announce/current/msg17592.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf-announce/current/msg17592.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Protocol Action: 'The Transport Layer Security (TLS) Protocol Version 1.3' to Proposed Standard (draft-ietf-tls-tls13-28.txt)&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;36.813326090893&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf-announce/current/msg17591.html&quot;&gt;Date Prev&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf-announce/current/msg17593.html&quot;&gt;Date Next&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf-announce/current/msg17591.html&quot;&gt;Thread Prev&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf-announce/current/msg17593.html&quot;&gt;Thread Next&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf-announce/current/maillist.html#17592&quot;&gt;Date Index&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf-announce/current/threads.html#17592&quot;&gt;Thread Index&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;To&lt;/em&gt;: &quot;IETF-Announce&quot; &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ietf-announce@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;ietf-announce at ietf.org&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subject&lt;/em&gt;: Protocol Action: 'The Transport Layer Security (TLS) Protocol Version 1.3' to Proposed Standard (draft-ietf-tls-tls13-28.txt)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt;: The IESG &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:iesg-secretary@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;iesg-secretary at ietf.org&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date&lt;/em&gt;: Wed, 21 Mar 2018 03:02:02 -0700&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Archived-at&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;lt;https://mailarchive.ietf.org/arch/msg/ietf-announce/IhM9JJHVs_ZeK-_1eaVZrqxbnL8&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Auto-submitted&lt;/em&gt;: auto-generated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cc&lt;/em&gt;: The IESG &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:iesg@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;iesg at ietf.org&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:draft-ietf-tls-tls13@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;draft-ietf-tls-tls13 at ietf.org&lt;/a&gt;, Sean Turner &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sean@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;sean at sn3rd.com&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Kathleen.Moriarty.ietf@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;Kathleen.Moriarty.ietf at gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:tls-chairs@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;tls-chairs at ietf.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rfc-editor@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;rfc-editor at rfc-editor.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sean@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;sean at sn3rd.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:tls@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;tls at ietf.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Delivered-to&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ietf-announce@DOMAIN.HIDDEN&quot;&gt;ietf-announce at ietfa.amsl.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;List-archive&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mailarchive.ietf.org/arch/browse/ietf-announce/&quot;&gt;https://mailarchive.ietf.org/arch/browse/ietf-announce/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;List-help&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ietf-announce-request@ietf.org?subject=help&quot;&gt;mailto:ietf-announce-request@ietf.org?subject=help&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;List-id&lt;/em&gt;: &quot;IETF announcement list. No discussions.&quot; &amp;lt;ietf-announce.ietf.org&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;List-post&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ietf-announce@ietf.org&quot;&gt;mailto:ietf-announce@ietf.org&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;List-subscribe&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ietf.org/mailman/listinfo/ietf-announce&quot;&gt;https://www.ietf.org/mailman/listinfo/ietf-announce&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ietf-announce-request@ietf.org?subject=subscribe&quot;&gt;mailto:ietf-announce-request@ietf.org?subject=subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;List-unsubscribe&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ietf.org/mailman/options/ietf-announce&quot;&gt;https://www.ietf.org/mailman/options/ietf-announce&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ietf-announce-request@ietf.org?subject=unsubscribe&quot;&gt;mailto:ietf-announce-request@ietf.org?subject=unsubscribe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
The IESG has approved the following document:
- 'The Transport Layer Security (TLS) Protocol Version 1.3'
  (draft-ietf-tls-tls13-28.txt) as Proposed Standard

This document is the product of the Transport Layer Security Working Group.

The IESG contact persons are Kathleen Moriarty and Eric Rescorla.

A URL of this Internet Draft is:
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-tls-tls13/&quot;&gt;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-tls-tls13/&lt;/a&gt;




Technical Summary

   This document specifies version 1.3 of the Transport Layer Security
   (TLS) protocol.  TLS allows client/server applications to communicate
   over the Internet in a way that is designed to prevent eavesdropping,
   tampering, and message forgery.

Working Group Summary

  The document is the work product of the members of the TLS
  WG.  There is strong consensus in the working group for this
  document.  The area that was most controversial was around
  the inclusion of a 0-RTT mode that has different security
  properties than the rest of TLS.  s1.3 lists the major differences
  from TLS1.2, as agreed by the contributors; we do not think
  that the RFC needs to list the changes that occurred between
  each draft.

  The draft has had 3 WGLCs to address various issues and the
  chairs assessment was fair in each of these discussions.  At this
  point there are no known outstanding issue.

  While I personally do not agree with inclusion of 0-RTT because
  there are bound to be successful attacks against the mitigations
  in the future, I do agree with the chair's assessment of the WG
  consensus and am pleased with the additional text on mitigating
  the associated risks with 0-RTT.

Document Quality

  There are over 10 interoperable implementations of the
  protocol from different sources written in different
  languages.  The major web browser vendors and TLS
  libraries vendors have draft implementations or have
  indicated they will support the protocol in the future.  In
  addition to having extensive review in the TLS working
  group, the protocol has received unprecedented security
  review by the academic community.  Several TRON (TLS
  Ready or Not) conferences were held with academic
  community to give them a chance to present their
  findings for TLS.  This has resulted in improvements to
  the protocol.  There was also much consideration and 
  discussion around any contentious points, resolved through
  polls and working group last calls.

  Please note that ID-nits complains about the obsoleted/
  updated RFCs not being listed in the abstract. This is
  intentional because the abstract is now a concise and
  comprehensive overview and is free form citations, as
  per RFC7322.

Personnel

   The Document Shepherd is Sean Turner.
   The responsible AD is Kathleen Moriarty.
   
   The IANA Expert(s) for the registries
   in this document are 
     Yoav Nir &amp;lt;ynir.ietf at gmail.com&amp;gt;, 
     Rich Salz &amp;lt;rsalz at akamai.com&amp;gt;, and 
     Nick Sullivan &amp;lt;nick at cloudflare.com&amp;gt; .

IANA Note

  This document requests the creation of the TLS SignatureScheme
  Registry with values assigned via Specification Required [RFC8126].

  This document requests the reference for several registries be 
  updated to point to this document.  The registries include:
  - TLS Cipher Suite Registry, updated via via Specification Required [RFC8126]
  - TLS ContentType Registry, future values allocated via Standards Action [RFC8126]
  - TLS Alert Registry, future values allocated via Standards Action [RFC8126]
  - TLS HandshakeType Registry, future values allocated via Standards Action [RFC8126]
  - TLS ExtensionType Registry, the policy is changed in ietf-tls-iana-registry-updates and this will be reflected in version 25 of the draft


RFC Editor Note

Please ensure a reference is added prior to final publication for the
text added in section
E.6. PSK Identity Exposure
of draft-ietf-tls-tls13

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 11:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Shoothe</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf-announce/current/msg17592.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New research suggests new ways to nurture gifted children</title>
<link>https://www.economist.com/news/international/21739144-new-research-suggests-new-ways-nurture-gifted-children-how-and-why-search-young</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.economist.com/news/international/21739144-new-research-suggests-new-ways-nurture-gifted-children-how-and-why-search-young</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;EVERY year in Singapore 1% of pupils in the third year of primary school bring home an envelope headed “On government service”. Inside is an invitation to the city-state’s Gifted Education Programme. To receive the overture, pupils must ace tests in maths, English and “general ability”. If their parents accept the offer, the children are taught using a special curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Singapore’s approach is emblematic of the traditional form of “gifted” education, one that uses intelligence tests with strict thresholds to identify children with seemingly innate ability. Yet in many countries it is being overhauled in two main ways. The first is that educationists are using a broader range of methods to identify highly intelligent children, especially those from poor households. The second is an increasing focus on fostering the attitudes and personality traits found in successful people in an array of disciplines—including those who did not ace intelligence tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form newsletter-form--inline&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form__message&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get our daily newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrade your inbox and get our Daily Dispatch and Editor's Picks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__container latest-updates-panel__container--blog-post&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__body&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Students lead a vast protest against gun violence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Ukraine convinces Ryanair to return&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Britain pulls off a diplomatic coup against Russia at the EU&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Another jihadist killer strikes in France&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;What do Democrats and Republicans both like?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Markets think trade war is good for &quot;absolutely nothing&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New research lies behind these shifts. It shows that countries which do not get the most from their best and brightest face big economic costs. The research also suggests that the nature-or-nurture debate is a false dichotomy. Intelligence is highly heritable and perhaps the best predictor of success. But it is far from the only characteristic that matters for future eminence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of gifted children goes back at least a century. In 1916 Leta Hollingworth—a psychologist whose doctorate refuted the idea that women struggled at science because of destabilising menstrual cycles—began some of the earliest research on children with high IQs. Two decades later she started work at the Speyer School in New York City, one of the first schools with a challenging curriculum for these pupils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;xhead&quot;&gt;Like, really smart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IQ tests have attracted furious criticism. Speaking for the sceptics, Christopher Hitchens, a journalist, argued that: “There is...an unusually high and consistent correlation between the stupidity of a given person and [his] propensity to be impressed by the measurement of IQ.” Like any assessment, IQ tests are not perfect. But as Stuart Ritchie of the University of Edinburgh points out in “Intelligence”, researchers in cognitive science agree that general intelligence—not book-learning but the ability to reason, plan, solve problems, think abstractly and so on—is an identifiable and important attribute which can be measured by IQ tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just how important is suggested by the Study of Mathematically Precocious Youth (SMPY), founded in 1971. Julian Stanley, then a psychologist at Johns Hopkins University, over 25 years recruited 5,000 precocious children, each of whom had intelligence-test scores in early adolescence high enough to gain entry to university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research into how these children did in adulthood has emerged over the past two decades. Of the SMPY participants who scored among the top 0.5% for their age-group in maths and verbal tests, 30% went on to earn a doctorate, versus 1% of Americans as a whole. These children were also much more likely to have high incomes and to file patents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;component-image blog-post__image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20180324_IRC147.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;component-image__img blog-post-article-image blog-post-article-image__slim&quot; srcset=&quot;/sites/default/files/imagecache/200-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRC147.png 200w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/300-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRC147.png 300w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/400-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRC147.png 400w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/640-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRC147.png 640w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/800-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRC147.png 800w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1000-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRC147.png 1000w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1200-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRC147.png 1200w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1280-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRC147.png 1280w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1600-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRC147.png 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 600px) 640px, calc(100vw - 20px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is variation even among the top scorers (see chart). This runs contrary to the idea, proposed by some psychologists, that there is a ceiling to IQ, after which its influence wanes. Of the top 0.01% of children, 50% went on to earn a PhD, medical or law degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Findings from studies led by Ian Deary of the University of Edinburgh, meanwhile, undermine the idea that gifted children go on to become disproportionately troubled. There are of course exceptions. But on average having a high IQ as a child is associated with better physical and mental health as an adult. Being moved up a school-year, as many are, tends to do them little harm. SMPY pupils who skipped at least one grade were 60% more likely to file patents than those who did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officials often cite the SMPY as the inspiration for the creation in 2014 of two specialist maths schools in England. Based on the Kolmogorov School in Moscow, these schools accept only those pupils who excel in maths at exams at age 16. In January the government said it wanted to open more as part of its “industrial strategy”, a plan to boost Britain’s woeful productivity growth. Linking gifted education to economic growth may horrify some people. But it has long seemed like common sense in countries without many natural resources, such as Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, however, the potential of poor bright children is often wasted. In December Raj Chetty of Stanford University and colleagues published a paper lamenting “lost Einsteins”. They found that children who score in the top 5% of standardised tests in the third year of primary school are many times more likely than the other 95% to file patents in later life. But the likelihood is still much greater among smart kids from rich families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philippe Aghion of the London School of Economics and colleagues found similar results in Finland. Those with high IQs but from poor backgrounds were especially at risk of not fulfilling their potential. That is not only unfair. It also implies that a lot of talent, which could have been harnessed to cure diseases or design better toasters, is being squandered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why poor-but-smart children struggle. Yet gifted schemes have often not helped. When applications are voluntary, they come mostly from rich or pushy parents. In New York City, for example, tutoring companies often charge $200 per hour to help four-year-olds prepare for admissions tests for gifted-education programmes starting in kindergarten. Tutoring may temporarily bump up scores by only a few points, but that can make all the difference. In 2015 70% of pupils admitted to such programmes were white or Asian, though they represent just 30% of the school-age population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps when schools test every child, rather than rely on parents to put children forward. In a paper from 2015, economists David Card and Laura Giuliano found that when a school district in Florida introduced universal screening for its gifted-education scheme, admissions increased by 180% among poor children, 130% among Hispanics and 80% for black pupils. (Admissions among white children fell.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some programmes go further. Miami-Dade, America’s fourth-largest school district, uses universal screening. It has a lower IQ threshold for poor children or those for whom English is a second language, so long as they show other signs of promise, such as learning English quickly or high scores in other tests. In Miami-Dade 6.9% of black pupils are in the gifted programme, versus 2.4% and 3.6% in Florida as a whole and nationwide respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In America 48 out of 50 states have programmes for brainy children, but in the decade before 2013, 24 redefined them, typically ditching the “gifted” label in favour of “high-ability”. Today no state relies on a single IQ score to select students. In his book “Ungifted” Scott Barry Kaufman of the University of Pennsylvania calls this a “huge change from just 20 years ago”. European countries have seen similar shifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School districts are also testing for other attributes, including spatial ability (ie, the capacity to generate, manipulate and store visual images). Jonathan Wai, a psychologist, notes that spatial ability as a child is strongly linked to achievement in science and technology in later life. The Finnish study also found this. But it is less correlated with income during childhood than are verbal and mathematical scores. So testing for it gives talented poor children a better chance to shine, says Mr Wai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;xhead&quot;&gt;The power of persistence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other researchers worry, though, that no matter how good the selection process, relying only on measures of intelligence will fail to find children with the potential to excel in adult life. Psychologists such as Mr Kaufman argue that there are many more possible paths to success in adulthood than often assumed, and that education must do more to foster attributes such as passion, determination and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether termed “grit”, “task-motivation” or “conscientiousness”, more psychologists are emphasising the role of persistence. “As much as talent counts, effort counts twice,” writes Angela Duckworth of the University of Pennsylvania, in “Grit”, published in 2016. For Anders Ericsson of Florida State University, deliberate practice over a long period (popularly understood as 10,000 hours) is critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such statements are simplistic. But few researchers disagree with the idea that talent requires development, and that should involve promoting hard work as well as intelligence. Gifted programmes from Singapore’s to England’s specialist maths schools make it a priority to help children pursue their passion. Robotics prodigies, for example, may be given the opportunity to shadow university students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is evidence that aspects of gifted education should influence education more broadly. Project Bright Idea, developed at Duke University, saw 10,000 typical nursery and primary-school pupils taught using methods often reserved for brainier kids—fostering high expectations, complex problem-solving and cultivating meta-cognition (or “thinking about thinking”). Nearly every one of them went on to do much better on tests than similar peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some researchers go further. Carol Dweck of Stanford University emphasises children’s “mindset” (the beliefs they have about learning). Children who think they can change their intelligence have a “growth mindset”, she says. Those who believe they cannot do much to change their “D” grades have a “fixed” one. According to Ms Dweck, children who adopt the first mindset quickly start to do better in tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching methods that draw on Ms Dweck’s work are now found in schools across Britain and America. The World Bank is running trials of the approach in countries such as Peru. One technique, for example, might see a pupil told to add the word “yet” to their statements, as in “I can’t do long-division—yet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a recent meta-analysis suggests that interventions based on growth-mindset are less effective than their hype implies. The study suggests that the effects of interventions drawing on the idea have no effect on the typical student’s outcomes and at best a small effect on those of poorer students. Other psychologists have struggled to replicate Ms Dweck’s results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;component-image blog-post__image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD002_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;component-image__img blog-post-article-image&quot; srcset=&quot;/sites/default/files/imagecache/200-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD002_0.jpg 200w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/300-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD002_0.jpg 300w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/400-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD002_0.jpg 400w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/640-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD002_0.jpg 640w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/800-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD002_0.jpg 800w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1000-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD002_0.jpg 1000w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1200-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD002_0.jpg 1200w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1280-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD002_0.jpg 1280w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1600-width/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD002_0.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 600px) 640px, calc(100vw - 20px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that intelligence is highly malleable also jars with research on its heritability. Studies led by Robert Plomin of King’s College London suggest that roughly 50% of the variance in IQ scores is due to genetic differences. These findings do not dismiss the role of nurture; hard work and social background matter. But they undermine the idea that supreme intelligence can simply be willed into being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A broader approach to gifted education ensures that more children reach their potential. But the evidence suggests that, so long as they are open to everyone, IQ tests still have a vital role to play. To find lost Einsteins, you have to look for them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 10:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nopinsight</dc:creator>
<og:description>New research suggests new ways to nurture gifted children</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20180324_IRD001_0.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.economist.com/news/international/21739144-new-research-suggests-new-ways-nurture-gifted-children-how-and-why-search-young</og:url>
<og:title>How and why to search for young Einsteins</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.economist.com/news/international/21739144-new-research-suggests-new-ways-nurture-gifted-children-how-and-why-search-young</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>