<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Mumbai bans plastic bags, bottles, and single-use plastic containers</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/jun/25/mumbai-india-bans-plastic-bags-and-bottles</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/jun/25/mumbai-india-bans-plastic-bags-and-bottles</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Mumbai has the become the largest Indian city to ban single-use plastics, with residents caught using plastic bags, cups or bottles to face penalties of up to 25,000 rupees (£276) and three months in jail from Monday.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Council inspectors in navy blue jackets have been posted across the city to catch businesses or residents still using plastic bags. Penalties have already kicked in for businesses and several, reportedly including a McDonald’s and Starbucks, have already been fined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penalties range from 5,000 rupees for first-time offenders to 25,000 rupees and the threat of three months’ jail for those caught repeatedly using single-use plastics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;“For the pollution situation it’s fine to do this but for the people it is a big problem,” said Kamlash Mohan Chaudhary, a Mumbai resident. “People here carry everything in plastic bags.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaudhary, a taxi driver, said he had started carrying a cloth bag and that his local mutton vendor had begun wrapping the meat in newspaper rather than plastic sheets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local media have reported complaints from vendors who say some inspectors are using &lt;a draggable=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/mumbai/plastic-ban-turns-into-extortion-as-inspectors-fine-permitted-items-too/articleshow/64723938.cms&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;confusion over the ban&lt;/a&gt; to extort money from businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/india&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;India&lt;/a&gt; recently hosted World Environment Day, which this year focused on the epidemic of plastic waste. About 6.3bn tonnes of plastic globally has been discarded into the environment since 1950, most of which will not break down for at least 450 years.&lt;br tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half of the world’s plastic was created in the past 13 years and about half of that is thought to be for products used once and thrown away, such as bags, cups or straws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India’s use of plastic is less than half of the global average: about 11kg a year per capita compared with 109kg in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India has among the highest rates of &lt;a draggable=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.earthday.org/2018/04/06/top-20-countries-ranked-by-mass-of-mismanaged-plastic-waste/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;mismanaging plastic waste&lt;/a&gt; in the world, according to a 2015 study. Strewn plastic wrappers, cups and bags are a common sight on the streets of Indian cities and beaches and make up part of the mountain-sized landfills on the outskirts of major metropolitan areas such Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Children plays amid plastic waste near the Arabian Sea coast at Mahim beach in Mumbai&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6bf6a0b3a6f1c15c1282172b9fdfc733ccf22de9/0_112_5354_3212/master/5354.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=40a7e1edce153fc9997c18fb81d95448&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Children plays amid plastic waste near the Arabian Sea coast at Mahim beach in Mumbai. Photograph: Divyakant Solanki/EPA
&lt;p&gt;Discontent about Mumbai’s ban was made worse on Monday by torrential rain, which Chaudhary said had soaked through the jute or cloth bags many people were using as an alternative to plastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messages were circulated on WhatsApp with stories of people who had been fined, prompting many to comply. “We are all very afraid,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 04:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hw</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/jun/25/mumbai-india-bans-plastic-bags-and-bottles</og:url>
<og:description>Indian city to fine or jail residents caught using single-use plastics</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6fc839efa780ec6d6a1786bc1c57cc53ab6dc6d3/0_70_4890_2934/master/4890.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=5daf484895b621ef88ee56d203e97e5b</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Mumbai bans plastic bags and bottles</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/jun/25/mumbai-india-bans-plastic-bags-and-bottles</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Massacring C Pointers</title>
<link>https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/Massacring-C-Pointers/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/Massacring-C-Pointers/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I'm taking a break from debugging books to talk about a calamitous shitshow of textbook writing: &lt;em&gt;Mastering C Pointers: Tools for Programming Power&lt;/em&gt;, by Robert J. Traister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned of the book through a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8SUkrR7ZfTA&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Kernighan where he refers to the book as probably “the worst C programming textbook ever written.” He doesn't name it but &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johnregehr/status/1003411102791692288&quot;&gt;with some help&lt;/a&gt; I was able to track down his obliquely accurate reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book has become my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=white%20whale&quot;&gt;white whale&lt;/a&gt;. Since I started reading debugging books, and especially now that I'm digging through older ones, I find bits of advice that simply don't work today. While some of it could be construed as useless or idiotic, I've always found the authors come from a position of earnestness, attempting to draw the best conclusions based on decent principles and what they knew at the time they wrote it. In some cases they may not have known much, but they're honestly and humbly trying to impart some wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Kernighan put up the following example, I saw what seemed to be the opposite of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;
char *combine(s, t)
char *s, *t;
{

      int x, y;
      char r[100];

      strcpy(r, s);
      y = strlen(r);
      for (x = y; *t != '\0'; ++x)
           r[x] = *t++;

      r[x] = '\0';

      return(r);

}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This program (formatting preserved) is taken from the first edition of the book (p.146). It's horrific (Kernighan calls it “malpractice”). It does not exhibit the genuineness I have seen with, say, books from the late 1970s on how to debug BASIC programs. I didn't know what it was. Deceit? Laziness? Unremitting ignorance? What is the mindset of someone who writes this, presumably thinking it's a good idea? Can the whole book be that bad? Kernighan said it was. I had to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book has two editions: the first was published in 1990, the second in 1993. The fact that there are two editions piqued my curiosity even more. It sold enough to make another version? Is that horrible example corrected? I obtained a copy of each and read them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the book is pointless. Kernighan was right: it's garbage. And the second edition only makes things worse. Teaching from either one would be a breach of ethics. If you follow Traister’s coding practices, even adjusted for today's standards, you are &lt;em&gt;guaranteed&lt;/em&gt; to create defects and vicious, latent bugs. A subtly pernicious aspect of the book is the casual tone of the writing. It’s informal enough that if you don’t really know much about C what he says sort of makes sense, despite the sloppy terminology and mixed, inaccurate metaphors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any trained programmer will recognize the lessons as worthless. His terminology is all over the map and typically inaccurate, if not plainly wrong. Expressions “return a value.” Values are “handed” into locations. Constants are “written directly into the program.” A union is a “specialized pointer.” The terminology isn’t even consistent. Micro-optimizations are stressed at all times, and program efficiency is valued over comprehension. He can’t even define a pointer correctly: “A pointer is a special variable that returns the address of a memory location.” It does not take long to realize Traister has no idea what he’s talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I’m not going to go over the content (that would take far too long since there’s nothing redeeming there), I did take extensive notes. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/Massacring-C-Pointers/notes.html&quot;&gt;read them&lt;/a&gt;, if you are so inclined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must, however, take a moment to single out the code. It is universally bad and much of it is simply wrong. (Imagine trying to learn programming principles from a book that contains a large number of programs that don’t even compile.) I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/Massacring-C-Pointers/code.html&quot;&gt;transcribed&lt;/a&gt; some of the programs and annotated them with comments so that you can get a taste of how inept Traister is as a C programmer. One thing to keep in mind (both for the programs and the notes) is that C89/C90 was new at the time and that the code was written on (and for) MS-DOS systems of the late 1980s/early 1990s. Things were a bit different then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough about the material. I want to explore the question of how something so wrong even got written. It’s not that everything in the book is wrong, but it feels like when it’s right, it’s right by accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traister has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Robert-J.-Traister/e/B001H6UPHY/ref=sr_ntt_srch_lnk_1?qid=1529540256&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot;&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; other books, some about electronics and some about programming, one called &lt;em&gt;Going from BASIC to C&lt;/em&gt;. In &lt;em&gt;Mastering C Pointers&lt;/em&gt;, he talks about a product he created called CBREEZE that converts BASIC code to C. Throughout the book he makes passing, roundabout references to BASIC and uses terminology that suggests he’s written a lot of BASIC code. For example, there is a whole chapter on using pointers to access memory, where reading and writing memory is instead called “peeking” and “poking”, based on the PEEK and POKE instructions in BASIC. He also says that it took him a couple of tries to learn C coming from BASIC. In short, I’m convinced he’s knowledgeable about BASIC and has worked on writing software for small, electronic devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this important? As I read the book (and if you read my notes, you know where this is going) I started to notice something in the wording and tone. The further I progressed the more I became convinced of it, and I think it explains how he managed to mangle the explanation of C pointers so badly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think he understands the call stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My argument for this interpretation requires a little knowledge of BASIC and embedded devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With BASIC, the key thing to know about most implementations at the time is that there were no functions and no scope aside from the global scope. The closest thing to a function in BASIC is the GOSUB command. The GOSUB command jumps to a line and executes code until it gets to a RETURN statement, where control is transferred back to the line following the GOSUB command. Within a GOSUB you can jump somewhere else with another GOSUB. The control follows a stack principle, but no arguments are passed. GOSUB routines are a way to factor out common code, but that common code has to work on global variables. (And yes, it’s as terrible as it sounds.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, consider the case of simple electronic devices. Even today some embedded devices, usually programmed using C, do not have a call stack that dynamically allocates space for automatic variables. There simply isn’t enough memory for it. Instead, the compiler lays out memory such that each function’s local variables have fixed memory addresses (a “compiled stack” model). The only stack you have is for return addresses and it is probably handled in hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you’re used to writing BASIC for small memory electronic devices and you learn about C. You read about pointers and realize something: it’s possible to write a subroutine that can change variables &lt;em&gt;without knowing their names&lt;/em&gt;. It’s manna from heaven! You don’t have to devote global variables to being the “parameters” of your subroutines anymore. Life is great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the mindset I think Traister had and never got past. In the book there is one fleeting mention of the stack in reference to excessive (automatic) memory allocation. (On MS-DOS, if the space for local variables is too large in the program, it might not compile.) He consistently describes variables as having “exclusive” addresses in the program. His writing about pointers suggests that he thinks, for each function, space is set aside to hold the local variables for the duration of the program, but you can only access them when inside the function in which they were declared. So pointers are really powerful because you can provide this address to another function and it can change the value using only a parameter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further evidence for his lack of understanding is that he frequently cites ridiculous space micro-optimizations within functions, such as avoiding the use of integers for index variables, if possible. Another one, mentioned often, is local &lt;code&gt;char&lt;/code&gt; arrays that have a fixed size. There are good reasons to not use them but his are not among them. His admonishment is that they waste space. Technically, that is true, but they don't exist until they're on the stack. And he never talks about global or file variables. He only refers to locals with “exclusive” addresses “set aside” for variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This interpretation runs into some problems once you start asking how functions with malloc will work, but it's worth pointing out that there is almost no discussion about memory management. In a book devoted to C pointers, that's a toxic mix of gross negligence and incompetence. There is literally one short paragraph devoted to talking about the &lt;code&gt;free&lt;/code&gt; function—and it's characterized as a “side note.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another sticking point in this interpretation is Traister’s incomprehensible approach to writing functions that take a variable number of arguments. He does this by passing an arbitrary number of arguments to a function (the first being the number of arguments) and accessing them using offsets from the address of the first argument. This suggests he has some idea about parameters being passed in a dynamic fashion, but it is so spectacularly wrong you’re left wondering if he even tried his programs out before publishing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, this is the most generous interpretation of the text I could come up with, and it still paints a terrible picture. Occam's Razor suggests that Traister is just clueless. But like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=01l1WIC9mBo&quot;&gt;analyzing a terrible movie&lt;/a&gt; that somehow gets made, it's more fun to reason through the “behind the scenes” parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the ineptness of the book, you'd think it was self-published. You would be wrong. It was published through Academic Press, which was a division of Harcourt, Brace &amp;amp; World at the time, but is now an “imprint of Elsevier.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the preface of the second edition it says that the first edition was reviewed “by a professional C programmer hired by the publisher.” That programmer said it should not be published. That programmer was right, but the publisher went ahead and published it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there was a second edition, the assumption is that the book sold well. According to WorldCat, &lt;em&gt;Mastering C Pointers&lt;/em&gt; is in at least &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/mastering-c-pointers/oclc/898329209&amp;amp;referer=brief_results&quot;&gt;242 libraries&lt;/a&gt;, most appearing to be the first edition, but I didn’t check them all. It claims to be one of the first books to tackle the subject of pointers in C, which is often a sticking point for novice programmers. The lack of material in this area at the time is probably why it sold. I could not track down a review of this book anywhere (and yes, I looked through scans of Byte Magazine et al.), but I did find reviews for other C books in the 1980s and what I found suggested that pointers were not covered well, if at all. In other words, like many books—and tech books in particular—it sold because of its title and good timing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you browse search results for other books by Traister you’ll find a lot of questionable sounding titles: &lt;em&gt;Making money with your microcomputer&lt;/em&gt; (1982), &lt;em&gt;Leaping from BASIC to C++&lt;/em&gt; (1994), &lt;em&gt;Learn C in Two Weeks with Run/C and CBreeze&lt;/em&gt; (1987). The breadth of topics covered in his works seems exhausting: &lt;em&gt;Beginner’s Guide to Reading Schematics&lt;/em&gt; (1991), &lt;em&gt;Astronomy and Telescopes: A Beginner’s Handbook&lt;/em&gt; (1983), &lt;em&gt;Make your own professional home video recordings&lt;/em&gt; (1982), &lt;em&gt;Cave Exploring&lt;/em&gt; (1983), just to name a few. You start to wonder if this is actually the same person who writes all this. Then you start to wonder if maybe all these books just touch on the topics, and are churned out mainly to try and make a buck. I had a hard time finding a review for any of them (the best resource was &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/search.php?query=robert%20j%20traister&amp;amp;sin=TXT&quot;&gt;archive.org&lt;/a&gt;). Practically all I could find about his books was ads for them—and even then it wasn’t that much, which is odd given the apparent volume of output from him. I did manage to find two reviews for his book &lt;em&gt;Programming in C for the Microcomputer User&lt;/em&gt; (1984): one was favourable (80 Micro, Nov. 1984), the other was not (Practical Computing, Oct. 1985). The only other book I can find of his that seems to have some staying power is the schematics book, which went to a third edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the aspect of &lt;em&gt;Mastering C Pointers&lt;/em&gt; that truly disturbs me is that there are probably a fair number of people who actually learned C pointers from it. There’s no way to know how much of an impact this book had on programmers in the 1990s, but given the number of copies in libraries it must have had some. It’s hard not to wonder how much of the terrible C code that has made its way into production can be attributed to the awful advice in Traister’s travesty of a text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to John Regehr for helping me track down the book in the first place. The title was &lt;del&gt;stolen&lt;/del&gt; inspired by one of his tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;timestamp&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 25, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 04:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>signa11</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/Massacring-C-Pointers/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>U.S. Supreme Court to hear civil forfeiture case</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/25/us/politics/supreme-court-civil-asset-forfeiture.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/25/us/politics/supreme-court-civil-asset-forfeiture.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;45&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;WASHINGTON — Tyson Timbs would like his Land Rover back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The State of Indiana took it, using a law that lets it seize vehicles used to transport illegal drugs. Last week, the Supreme Court agreed to decide whether the Constitution has anything to say about such civil forfeiture laws, which allow states and localities to take and keep private property used to commit crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Timbs bought the Land Rover after his father died. The life insurance money amounted to around $73,000, and he spent $42,000 of it on the vehicle. He blew most of the rest on drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Unfortunately, I had a whole bunch of money, which isn’t a good idea for a drug addict to have,” Mr. Timbs recalled the other day. “I used a lot, and eventually the money ran out. It was an addict’s life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Timbs’s habit started with an opioid addiction and progressed to heroin. He used his Land Rover to get drugs and, on at least two occasions, to sell them. The buyers were undercover police officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;49.176062445794&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;44.258456201214&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Timbs pleaded guilty to one of the drug sales, in which $225 had changed hands, and he was sentenced to a year of house arrest followed by five years of probation. He also agreed to pay an array of fees and fines adding up to about $1,200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But Indiana wanted more. Using the civil forfeiture law, it took the Land Rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Timbs, 37, has put his life back together, but it has not been easy. “I have to go to meetings, to counseling, to probation appointments,” he said, making clear that he was not complaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“They want you to get a job,” he said. “It’s hard to do without a vehicle. Plus, I was a felon, which makes it even harder to find a job.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;He found work as a machinist in a factory some 40 minutes from his home in Marion, Ind., where he lives with his aunt. He borrows her car to get to work, and he feels guilty about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“She has to take a bus back and forth to her kidney dialysis appointments,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As Justice Clarence Thomas &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/16pdf/16-122_1b7d.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;explained last year&lt;/a&gt; in an opinion urging the Supreme Court to examine civil forfeiture laws, government seizures of property used to commit crimes have become worrisomely popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Forfeiture has in recent decades become widespread and highly profitable,” Justice Thomas wrote. “And because the law enforcement entity responsible for seizing the property often keeps it, these entities have strong incentives to pursue forfeiture.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;45.464337700146&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;39.371179039301&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“This system — where police can seize property with limited judicial oversight and retain it for their own use — has led to egregious and well-chronicled abuses,” he wrote, citing excellent reporting from &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/sf/investigative/2014/09/06/stop-and-seize/?utm_term=.3476f50ca105&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2013/08/12/taken&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The burdens of civil forfeiture fall disproportionately on the poor, said &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://ij.org/staff/whottot/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wesley P. Hottot&lt;/a&gt;, a lawyer with the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://ij.org/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Institute for Justice&lt;/a&gt;, which represents Mr. Timbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Tyson’s case illustrates how civil forfeiture makes it harder for people who have made mistakes to correct those mistakes and re-enter society,” Mr. Hottot said. “It shouldn’t take the United States Supreme Court to make clear that you don’t take everything from a person who’s facing the kinds of challenges Tyson is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Timbs won the early rounds in Indiana’s lawsuit seeking to take his vehicle, based on the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/constitution/eighth_amendment&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eighth Amendment&lt;/a&gt;, which says that “excessive bail shall not be required, nor excessive fines imposed, nor cruel and unusual punishments inflicted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Judge Jeffrey D. Todd, of the Grant County Superior Court, said the amendment’s second clause — the one barring “excessive fines” — protected Mr. Timbs. The Land Rover, the judge wrote, was worth about four times the maximum fine Mr. Timbs could have been ordered to pay, which was $10,000. It was also worth more than 30 times the fines that were actually imposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;50.227272727273&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;47.329545454545&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“The amount of the forfeiture sought is excessive and is grossly disproportional to the gravity of the defendant’s offense,” Judge Todd wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.in.gov/judiciary/opinions/pdf/10201602pdm.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;An appeals court agreed&lt;/a&gt;. In dissent, Judge Michael P. Barnes wrote that civil forfeiture laws can be abused but that Mr. Timbs should lose the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I am keenly aware of the overreach some law enforcement agencies have exercised in some of these cases,” Judge Barnes wrote. “Entire family farms are sometimes forfeited based on one family member’s conduct, or exorbitant amounts of money are seized. However, it seems to me that one who deals heroin, and there is no doubt from the record we are talking about a dealer, must and should suffer the legal consequences to which he exposes himself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The Indiana Supreme Court &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.scotusblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/17-1091-opinion-below.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ruled against Mr. Timbs&lt;/a&gt;, on interesting grounds. It said the Eighth Amendment’s prohibition of excessive fines did not apply to ones imposed by states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;This is, surprisingly, an open question. The Bill of Rights originally restricted the power of only the federal government, but the Supreme Court has ruled that most of its protections apply to the states under the due process clause of the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.senate.gov/civics/constitution_item/constitution.htm#amdt_14_(1868)&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;14th Amendment&lt;/a&gt;, one of the post-Civil War amendments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But there are a few exceptions, and the Supreme Court has been inconsistent about where it stands on the excessive fines clause. Mr. Timbs’s case is poised to resolve the question. It will be argued in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In the meantime, Mr. Timbs sometimes lapses into frustration and bitterness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I don’t deserve this,” he said. “Nobody does. It’s an unnecessary stressor. I struggle with more than addiction. I struggle with anxiety and depression. I don’t feel like much of a man, because I don’t have a vehicle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;26.854251012146&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;css-3glrhn&quot; readability=&quot;8.1094527363184&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page A20 of the New York edition with the headline: Indiana Seized His $42,000 Car Over a $225 Drug Deal&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 20:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wcbeard10</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/25/us/politics/supreme-court-civil-asset-forfeiture.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>He Sold Drugs for $225. Indiana Took His $42,000 Land Rover.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/06/26/us/26dc-bar1/26dc-bar1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The Supreme Court has agreed to decide whether the Constitution has anything to say about civil forfeiture laws that let states take property used in crimes.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/25/us/politics/supreme-court-civil-asset-forfeiture.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introducing A16Z Crypto</title>
<link>https://a16zcrypto.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://a16zcrypto.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Historically, new models of computing have tended to &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/software-is-eating-the-world/what-s-next-in-computing-e54b870b80cc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;emerge&lt;/a&gt; every 10-15 years: mainframes in the 60s, PCs in the late 70s, the internet in the early 90s, and smartphones in the late 2000s. Each computing model enabled new classes of applications that built on the unique strengths of the platform. For example, smartphones were the first truly personal computers with built-in sensors like GPS and high-resolution cameras. Applications like Instagram, Snapchat, and Uber/Lyft took advantage of these unique capabilities and are now used by billions of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain computers were first proposed in 2008 by Satoshi Nakamoto in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Bitcoin whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;. Those original ideas have since been dramatically expanded by developers and researchers around the world. Blockchain computers are new types of computers where the unique capability is &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; between users, developers, and the platform itself. This trust &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cdixon/status/563223999543382017&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;emerges&lt;/a&gt; from the mathematical and game-theoretic properties of the system, without depending on the trustworthiness of individual network participants. In exchange for these new capabilities, blockchain computers trade off other capabilities such as transaction scalability. This can lead people to dismiss them, in the same way people dismissed early smartphones because they traded off computing power and screen size for portability and new sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is a new software primitive from which other components can be constructed. The first and most prominent example is digital money, made famous by Bitcoin. But, as we’ve discovered over the past few years, many other software components can be constructed using the building blocks of trust. Smart contract platforms like Ethereum enable the creation of, among other things, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ERC20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;application-specific currencies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/eips/issues/721&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;digital property rights&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/EIPs/issues/1068&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;open financial instruments&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davesag/ERC884-reference-implementation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;software-based organizations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From these components, in turn, new infrastructure and applications can be constructed. For example, developers are working on upgrading the core infrastructure of the internet, including storage, networking, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ens.domains/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;identity&lt;/a&gt;, and distributed &lt;a href=&quot;https://truebit.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;computation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/stablecoins-designing-a-price-stable-cryptocurrency-6bf24e2689e5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Stablecoins&lt;/a&gt; can enable more mainstream user experiences for digital payments and financial services. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/eips/issues/721&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Cryptogoods&lt;/a&gt; can unlock new experiences and business models for games and other forms of media. Entrepreneurs are developing crypto-powered financial services like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/traditional-asset-tokenization-b8a59585a7e0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;tokenization&lt;/a&gt; of traditional assets, and payment services for the unbanked. We expect many other applications to emerge in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new primitive of trust also means that 3rd-party developers, entrepreneurs, and creators can build on top of crypto-powered platforms &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cdixon/why-decentralization-matters-5e3f79f7638e&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;without worrying&lt;/a&gt; about whether the rules of the game will change later on. In an era in which the internet is increasingly &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cdixon/crypto-tokens-a-breakthrough-in-open-network-design-e600975be2ef&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;controlled&lt;/a&gt; by a handful of large tech incumbents, it’s more important than ever to create the right economic conditions for developers, creators, and entrepreneurs. Trust also enables new kinds of governance where communities collectively make important decisions about how networks evolve, what behaviors are permitted, and how economic benefits are distributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other important trends happening in computing, including the emergence of next-gen computing devices like VR &amp;amp; AR, self-driving cars, drones, and IoT devices. Recent developments in artificial intelligence are extremely exciting and will enable computers to more intelligently interact with the world. We believe that just as the last three megatrends -- mobile, social, and cloud -- intersected and reinforced each other, so will the next three megatrends -- next-gen computing devices, AI, and crypto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the Bitcoin whitepaper is now almost 10 years old, we believe we are still early in the crypto movement. The infrastructure needs to be improved and the applications are difficult for non-early adopters to use. Many crypto applications still get &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdixon.org/2010/01/03/the-next-big-thing-will-start-out-looking-like-a-toy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;dismissed as toys&lt;/a&gt;. We believe this will change quickly. For one, crypto is purely a software movement and doesn’t depend on a hardware buildout, in contrast to, say, the internet, which required laying cables and building cell towers. Second, the space is developing extremely rapidly, partly because the code, data, and knowledge is largely open source, and partly because of the increasing inflow of talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we are optimistic because we are deep believers in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2016/08/20/why-software-is-eating-the-world/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;power of software&lt;/a&gt;. Software is simply &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cdixon/why-decentralization-matters-5e3f79f7638e&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;the encoding of human thought&lt;/a&gt;, and as such has an almost unbounded design space. We find ourselves consistently surprised and excited by the wide variety of creative crypto ideas we encounter. For those of us who have been involved in software for a long time, it feels like the early days of the internet, web 2.0, or smartphones all over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The a16z crypto fund&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we are announcing the launch of a16z crypto, a $300M venture fund that will invest in crypto companies and protocols. Our fund is designed to include the best features of traditional venture capital, updated to the modern crypto world:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are long-term, patient investors&lt;/em&gt;. We’ve been investing in crypto assets for 5+ years. We’ve never sold any of those investments, and don’t plan to any time soon. We structured the a16z crypto fund to be able to hold investments for 10+ years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have an “all weather” fund&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; We plan to invest consistently over time, regardless of market conditions. If there is another “crypto winter,” we’ll keep investing aggressively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We provide operational support to entrepreneurs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Our crypto investments have access to the same 80+ person a16z &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/about/team/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;operating teams&lt;/a&gt; as do our non-crypto investments. Our operating teams have deep expertise in executive and technical recruiting, regulatory affairs, communications and marketing, and general startup management. We are responsible participants in the governance of companies and the governance of networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are flexible with respect to stage, asset type, and geography&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; One reason we created a new fund is to have maximum flexibility. We invest at all stages, from seed stage pre-launch projects to fully developed later-stage networks like Bitcoin and Ethereum. We’ll invest in traditional financial instruments like equity or convertible notes, and new instruments including the direct purchase of coins/tokens. Crypto is a global phenomenon, with great projects all around the world, and we’ll invest accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are focused on non-speculative use case&lt;/em&gt;. We want services powered by crypto protocols to be used by hundreds of millions and eventually billions of people. Crypto tokens are the native asset class of digital networks, but their value is driven by the underlying, practical uses cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve assembled a team of crypto specialists to lead our investment effort: &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/chris-dixon/&quot;&gt;myself&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/ali-yahya/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Ali&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/hilary-kivitz/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Hilary&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/jesse-walden/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Jesse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/denis-nazarov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Denis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/corban-bell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Corban&lt;/a&gt;, Michelle, and our newest General Partner, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/kathryn-haun/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Katie Haun&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an entrepreneur working on a crypto project, we’d love to talk to you -- please &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/contact/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;send&lt;/a&gt; us a note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For important additional information regarding statements on this page, please go &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/disclosures/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 20:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mdelias</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>a16zcrypto</og:title>
<og:url>https://a16zcrypto.com/</og:url>
<og:image>https://a16zcrypto.com/wp-content/themes/a16z-crypto/client/images/a16z-logo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://a16zcrypto.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We&amp;#039;re Baking ‘Have I Been Pwned’ into Firefox and 1Password</title>
<link>https://www.troyhunt.com/were-baking-have-i-been-pwned-into-firefox-and-1password/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.troyhunt.com/were-baking-have-i-been-pwned-into-firefox-and-1password/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty much every day, I get a reminder from someone about how little people know about their exposure in data breaches. Often, it's after someone has searched &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/&quot;&gt;Have I Been Pwned&lt;/a&gt; (HIBP) and found themselves pwned somewhere or other. Frequently, it's some long-forgotten site they haven't even thought about in years and also frequently, the first people know of these incidents is via HIBP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;3.4878048780488&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;large &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ticketfly?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ticketfly&lt;/a&gt; data breach. thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/troyhunt?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@troyhunt&lt;/a&gt; for the excellent &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/haveibeenpwned?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@haveibeenpwned&lt;/a&gt; service that notifies users of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/privacy?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#privacy&lt;/a&gt; disasters like this :) &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/xgklY59sOU&quot;&gt;https://t.co/xgklY59sOU&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/jlqnKXteDG&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/jlqnKXteDG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Yale Privacy Lab (@YalePrivacyLab) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/YalePrivacyLab/status/1003628398772711424?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 4, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;6.4086021505376&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Well, that's annoying: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ticketfly?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@TicketFly&lt;/a&gt; data breach attacker publicly posted my info (along w 26MM others). I at least know about it, thx to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/haveibeenpwned?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@haveibeenpwned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Tim Plas (@TJPlas) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TJPlas/status/1003337886463397888?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 3, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;4.9143835616438&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ticketfly?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ticketfly&lt;/a&gt; a heads up would have been nice. Thankfully &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/troyhunt?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@troyhunt&lt;/a&gt; built an amazing tool ( &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/haveibeenpwned?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@haveibeenpwned&lt;/a&gt; )for issues like this. Only used you guys once for tickets to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TravisGreeneTV?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@TravisGreeneTV&lt;/a&gt; concert. 😞🤦🏾‍♂️😡 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/tcs282i5lA&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/tcs282i5lA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Tope Akinwande (@takinwande) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/takinwande/status/1003278452848394240?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 3, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases like Ticketfly, loading the data into HIBP meant notifying 105k of my subscribers. That's out of a subscriber base that just recently ticked over the 2M million mark:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;6.0627802690583&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Wow, just realised &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/haveibeenpwned?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@haveibeenpwned&lt;/a&gt; passed the 2 million *verified* subscribers mark whilst I've been travelling. That's amazing, never expected to see that! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/uTfoZud7wk&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/uTfoZud7wk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Troy Hunt (@troyhunt) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/troyhunt/status/1009352425197719552?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 20, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 million is more than I ever expected, if I'm honest, but it's also only a tiny, tiny drop in the ocean. Of the 5.1 billion &lt;em&gt;records&lt;/em&gt; that are in HIBP today, there's 3.1B unique email addresses. I'm reaching 0.06% of them via the notification service and not a whole lot more in terms of people coming to the site and doing an ad hoc search (usually 100k - 200k people a day). Don't get me wrong - I'm enormously happy and personally fulfilled by having been able to do even this - but clearly, I'm barely scratching the surface. However, that scope is about to expand dramatically via 2 new partnerships which I'm announcing today, starting with Firefox:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mozillaandfirefoxmonitor&quot;&gt;Mozilla and Firefox Monitor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last November, there was much press about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/mozilla-pwned-function-firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla integrating HIBP into Firefox&lt;/a&gt;. I was a bit surprised at the time as it was nothing more than their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techrepublic.com/article/firefox-breach-alerts-will-warn-users-if-they-visit-a-hacked-site/&quot;&gt;Breach Alerts feature&lt;/a&gt; which simply highlighted if the site being visited had previously been in a data breach (it draws this from &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/API/v2#AllBreaches&quot;&gt;the freely accessible breach API on HIBP&lt;/a&gt;). But the press picked up on some signals which indicated that in the long term, we had bigger plans than that and the whole thing got a heap of &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; positive attention. I ended up fielding a heap of media calls just on that one little feature - people &lt;em&gt;loved&lt;/em&gt; the idea of HIBP in Firefox, even in a very simple form. As it turns out, we had &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; bigger plans and that's what I'm sharing here today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over the coming weeks, Mozilla will begin trialling integration between HIBP and Firefox to make breach data searchable via a new tool called &quot;Firefox Monitor&quot;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/06/Firefox-Monitor-Website---General-Homepage-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Firefox Monitor Website&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is major because Firefox has an install base of hundreds of millions of people which &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; expands the audience that can be reached once this feature rolls out to the mainstream. You can read &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2018/06/25/testing-firefox-monitor-a-new-security-tool/&quot;&gt;Mozilla's announcement of the new feature&lt;/a&gt; and how they plan to conduct the testing and rollout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really happy to see Firefox integrating with HIBP in this fashion, not just to get it in front of as many people as possible, but because I have a great deal of respect for their contributions to the technology community. In particular, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let%27s_Encrypt#History&quot;&gt;Mozilla was instrumental in the birth of Let's Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;, the free and open certificate authority that's massively increased the adoption of HTTPS on the web. Arguably, the work done by Mozilla's Josh Aas and Eric Rescorla (still the Mozilla CTO today) has been one of the greatest contributions to online privacy and security we've seen and &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/sponsors/&quot;&gt;Mozilla remains a platinum sponsor to this day&lt;/a&gt;. They've also been instrumental in helping define the model which HIBP uses to feed them data &lt;em&gt;without Mozilla disclosing the email addresses being searched for&lt;/em&gt;. I'm going to talk more about the mechanics of that model in a moment but first, let me talk about 1Password:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1password&quot;&gt;1Password&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My relationship with 1Password stretches all the way back to 2011 when I came to the realisation that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/only-secure-password-is-one-you-cant/&quot;&gt;the only secure password is the one you can't remember&lt;/a&gt;. Over the last 7 years, I've continued to buy their product and use it every single day across all my devices &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; my entire family's devices. In February, only the day after I launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/ive-just-launched-pwned-passwords-version-2/&quot;&gt;Pwned Passwords V2&lt;/a&gt;, 1Password turned around and built it into their product so that users of the password manager could see if their password had been previously exposed in a breach. That effort was a large factor in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/have-i-been-pwned-is-now-partnering-with-1password/&quot;&gt;choosing 1Password to partner with HIBP back in March&lt;/a&gt; and since that time, they've built Pwned Passwords into the desktop apps for Mac and Windows and provided the ability to check all your passwords &lt;em&gt;in one single go&lt;/em&gt;. But today, we're announcing something much bigger:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As of now, you can search HIBP from directly within 1Password via the Watchtower feature in the web version of the product.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helps Watchtower become &quot;mission control&quot; for accounts and introduces the &quot;Breach Report&quot; feature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/06/1Password-Breach-Report.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1Password Breach Report&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/06/1Password-Breach-Info.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1Password Breach Info&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/06/1Password-Disqus-Breach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1Password Disqus Breach&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with Pwned Passwords, by pushing this out in the web-based version of the product they can get it to customers quickly then over time, bake it right into the desktop versions as well. There's also a bunch of other ways 1Password can use the data to streamline how users protect their accounts and that's something we're actively discussing. I expect we'll see the existing functionality enhanced in the not too distant future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a 1Password user you can use this feature right now, just head on over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://start.1password.com/signin&quot;&gt;the 1Password login page&lt;/a&gt;. And if you're not already putting all your passwords in 1Password, go and &lt;a href=&quot;https://1password.com/sign-up/&quot;&gt;grab a free trial&lt;/a&gt; and give it a go. You can also find a more detailed write-up on 1Password's implementation in the very aptly titled blog post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.agilebits.com/2018/06/25/watchtower-we-shall-fight-on-the-breaches/&quot;&gt;we shall fight on the breaches&lt;/a&gt; (why didn't I ever think of that?!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;enablinganonymoussearcheswithkanonymity&quot;&gt;Enabling Anonymous Searches with k-Anonymity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about protecting the identities of Firefox and 1Password users because more than ever - and regardless of where you are in the world - we're becoming increasingly conscious of our online privacy. We're also becoming increasingly connected and sharing unprecedented volumes of data which, let's face it, isn't exactly analogous with privacy and anonymity! But we &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; have both and I want to illustrate that by talking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&quot;&gt;the Pwned Passwords model&lt;/a&gt; for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this feature launched, Cloudflare (hat-tip again to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/icyapril&quot;&gt;Junade Ali&lt;/a&gt; there) did some great work on a &quot;k-anonymity&quot; model which works like this: when searching HIBP for a password, the client SHA-1 hashes it then takes the first 5 characters and sends this to the API. In response, a collection of hashes is returned that match that prefix (477 on average). By looking at the hash prefix sent to the service, I have no idea what the password is. It &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be any one of those 477 or it could be something totally different, I don't know. Of course, I could always speculate based on the prevalence of each password but it would never be anything more than that - speculation. (Just to add to that, I've never got any idea of the username attached to the password either so even if I take an educated guess at it, there's nothing I can actually do with it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The email address being searched for by Firefox and 1Password works in the same fashion, albeit it with slightly different numbers due to the significantly larger data set at play. When I processed the source HIBP data in preparation for this feature, out of the 5B records in the system at the time there were 3.1B unique email addresses. (In other words, each address has been in an average of 1.6 data breaches.) I took each one of those 3.1B addresses, hashed it and stored it in a new data construct I'll talk about later. That gave me a repository to search against, now let's cover the mechanics of that search:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of anonymity, I needed to decide on how many characters of the SHA-1 hash to allow searching by such that a sufficiently large number was returned to have no reasonable way of knowing which address was searched for, but also for the system to respond quickly. For Pwned Passwords, that number was 5 characters resulting in 16^5 possible search ranges which, across a data set of 500M records, meant the aforementioned 477 results per range. However, if I'd used 5 chars with the 3.1B email addresses, each range would contain an average of almost 3K results which is starting to get pretty sizeable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I settled on 6 characters which means 16^6 possible ranges with an average of 185 results per range. Now, on the one hand you might say &quot;that's less than Pwned Passwords therefore provides less protection&quot;, but it's a bit more nuanced than that. Firstly, because this number will grow &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; over time; more data breaches means more new email addresses means larger results in the range search. More importantly though, email addresses are &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; less predictable than passwords; as I mentioned earlier, if I was to spy on searches for Pwned Passwords (and I don't, but this is the threat k-anonymity is protecting us from), the prevalence of passwords in the system beginning with that hash can indicate the &lt;em&gt;likelihood&lt;/em&gt; of what was searched by. But when we're talking about email addresses, there's no such indicator, certainly the number of breaches each has been exposed in divulges nothing in terms of which one is likely being searched for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what a search for an email address ultimately looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Address: test@example.com
SHA-1 hash: 567159D622FFBB50B11B0EFD307BE358624A26EE
6 char prefix: 567159
API endpoint: https://[host]/[path]/567159&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which results in a response containing the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/06/Pwned-Email-Range-Search-Result.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pwned Email Range Search Result&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, the searched address is the last one because the hash suffix matches with the SHA-1 hash of &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:test@example.com&quot;&gt;test@example.com&lt;/a&gt;. The associated websites next to that hash are the ones that the email address appeared in and can be matched back to the full breach details via &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/API/v2#AllBreaches&quot;&gt;the public breach list API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the way 1Password implements Pwned Passwords by calling the API directly from the client, this model is only consumable by an authenticated request from Firefox's or 1Password's infrastructure. What this means is that consumers only ever call their API then they call HIBP's API. Both these organisations implement all the same controls that HIBP does on the existing public email search API, namely the rate limit, not returning sensitive breaches to non-verified addresses and employing a range of other abuse-protection mechanisms. Why not call the API directly from each client? Let's talk about that next:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theviabilityofusingthisapipublicly&quot;&gt;The Viability of Using This API Publicly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's one fundamentally important (and perhaps quite obvious) reason why I don't expect to make this service available publicly: it could &lt;em&gt;massively&lt;/em&gt; accelerate enumeration activities. Back in 2016, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/the-have-i-been-pwned-api-rate-limiting-and-commercial-use/&quot;&gt;I implemented a rate limit on the public API&lt;/a&gt; to greatly reduce the potential to abuse the service. This meant the ability to check records was limited to 1 request every 1,500ms. If I was to offer the k-anonymity service publicly, that jumps massively to 185 every 1,500ms (and it will grow as the data does) because that's how many results are returned. In fairness, you'd only get back hashed suffixes of email addresses but if someone had a &lt;em&gt;massive&lt;/em&gt; list of them they wanted to work through (and that's one of the key patterns the rate limit is designed to curtail), they could hash the lot then grab those first 6 chars of each and get back a bunch of results in one go. Granted, they almost certainly wouldn't have the source email addresses of all 185 returned suffixes, but it still provides a vector to greatly accelerate search rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A (somewhat) middle ground, however, would be to allow searching the repository of hashed addresses by complete hash. Rather than the current model which needs a full email address, now that I have a mirrored data set containing only hashes I could always roll the search over to query that repository instead. I could also adapt the web front end to hash an entered email address client-side then only send that to the server. &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.uservoice.com/forums/275398-general/suggestions/8234421-allow-users-to-search-for-an-email-address-by-hash&quot;&gt;I actually closed a User Voice idea along these lines&lt;/a&gt; (and you can read about why in that idea), but now that I have that collection of hashes already in storage, it'd be trivial to stand up an endpoint to query it even if there's not always a lot of privacy upside. The main reason I can't do that immediately is that the email addresses for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/introducing-paste-searches-and/&quot;&gt;the paste service&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;are not hashed&lt;/em&gt; and the existing search model on the website needs to search both sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just on that, let me refer quickly back to my post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/the-ethics-of-running-a-data-breach-search-service/&quot;&gt;The Ethics of Running a Data Breach Search Service&lt;/a&gt;. This explains in detail &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; the service allows addresses to be searched in the way it presently does and provides both technical and logical reasons. Do read that if you're curious, it was very carefully thought-out and explains the detailed thinking behind it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;scalingsearcheswithazureandcloudflare&quot;&gt;Scaling Searches with Azure and Cloudflare&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the k-anonymity model itself, I've leaned heavily on the Pwned Passwords experience in designing how this model works. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/azure-functions-in-practice/&quot;&gt;Azure Functions&lt;/a&gt; provide the API layer (they're serverless and scale beautifully) and Cloudflare does the reverse-proxying and caching. Unfortunately, I can't cache anywhere &lt;em&gt;near&lt;/em&gt; as aggressively as with Pwned Passwords because instead of 16^5 different ranges (and therefore unique request patterns), it's 16^6. Also, I have a one-month cache expiration on Pwned Passwords because they rarely change but at present, only a 15-minute cache expiration on the email address search. I didn't want someone searching for a breach I'd just loaded, finding it in HIBP then &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; finding it in Firefox or 1Password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One major difference between Pwned Passwords and this feature here is the underlying storage construct. For the passwords, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/i-wanna-go-fast-why-searching-through-500m-pwned-passwords-is-so-quick/&quot;&gt;I ended up putting them all in blob storage&lt;/a&gt; so there's one file per hash range. That was faster than the original Table Storage construct I used and because the files rarely ever change (I'll probably only update the passwords a couple of times a year), they could remain relatively static files. For emails in breaches, however, I don't have that luxury; breaches are continually loaded into the system and I needed a queryable construct that allowed for fast inserts and reads which means that like the existing HIBP email address storage, the hash ranges for this service are also in Azure Table Storage. It's an entirely separate table to the one that's been there from day one and just holds email addresses so obviously that's also impacted the data load process which now needs to do twice as much record handling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this means is that the entire record for &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:test@example.com&quot;&gt;test@example.com&lt;/a&gt; looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Partition key: 567159
Row key: D622FFBB50B11B0EFD307BE358624A26EE
Websites: [delimited array of pwned site names]&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partitioning in this fashion means that when a search is done, it's easy to return every single suffix for the hash prefix which is used as the partition key. Some quick performance testing last week resulted in the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/06/Distribution-of-Requests.png&quot; alt=&quot;Distribution of Requests&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's fine as a starting point and median load time of 280ms means that even with network latency and processing on Firefox's and 1Password's end should mean results are turned around in well under a second. Functions also seem to accelerate in execution time as infrastructure warms up so I expect we'll only see improvements in this area. I'll share some perf info once the volumes really ramp up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, like the existing search services and regardless of the fact requests only ever contain 6 characters of a hash, no searches are ever explicitly logged. They'll pass through very short-term transient logs and that's it - all I'll have is very broad-brush stats on things like the number of calls and the duration of executions. So, in summary, everything will be fast, efficient and above all, anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;thenotificationservice&quot;&gt;The Notification Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me talk briefly about one last thing that's on the horizon - notifications. The service above is a point-in-time representation of breach state which is great, but clearly, it's a state that will continue to evolve over time. There needs to be a construct to notify Firefox and 1Password of &lt;em&gt;deltas&lt;/em&gt; to the data set as new breaches are loaded so that in the future, they have the ability to offer subscriptions in the same way as &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/NotifyMe&quot;&gt;the HIBP notification service&lt;/a&gt;. Re-querying all the data every time a breach is loaded would be &lt;em&gt;massively&lt;/em&gt; inefficient so that's not going to happen, we need to be smarter than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years back &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/have-i-been-pwned-goes-little-bit/#mylifeandcallbacks&quot;&gt;I wrote about a callback model&lt;/a&gt; and an equivalent paradigm will be used here. What this boils down to is the ability to subscribe a hash prefix for notifications so in that &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:test@example.com&quot;&gt;test@example.com&lt;/a&gt; scenario, &quot;567159&quot; would be subscribed then a callback sent to Firefox or 1Password when an address that hashes down to that prefix is loaded. The callback will contain the name of the breach that's just been loaded and all the hash suffixes for that prefix that were found in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm building that feature out next and in time I expect we'll see that flow through to Firefox and 1Password. It's a neat way of ensuring that anonymity is still protected &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; that subscribers of those services stay abreast of security incidents that impact them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As HIBP grows, I keep coming back to this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can HIBP do good things for people in the wake of bad events?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really happy this initiative furthers that objective and does it in a way that puts privacy first. The leverage these two organisations have to drive positive outcomes in the wake of data breaches is massive and I'm &lt;em&gt;enormously&lt;/em&gt; excited to see the impact they both make in partnership with HIBP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 20:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edward</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>We're Baking Have I Been Pwned into Firefox and 1Password</og:title>
<og:description>Pretty much every day, I get a reminder from someone about how little people know about their exposure in data breaches. Often, it's after someone has searched Have I Been Pwned (HIBP) and found themselves pwned somewhere or other. Frequently, it's some long-forgotten site they haven't even thought about in</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.troyhunt.com/were-baking-have-i-been-pwned-into-firefox-and-1password/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/06/Firefox-Monitor-Website---General-Homepage-1.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.troyhunt.com/were-baking-have-i-been-pwned-into-firefox-and-1password/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>John Oliver is erased from Chinese internet following segment on China</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/25/john-oliver-is-erased-from-chinese-internet-following-segment-on-china/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/25/john-oliver-is-erased-from-chinese-internet-following-segment-on-china/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;HBO’s Last Week Tonight has led to some drastic measures in China. After an episode aired on June 17th, the Chinese government is now trying to erase all signs of &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/person/john-oliver-comedian/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;person&quot; data-entity=&quot;john-oliver-comedian&quot;&gt;John Oliver&lt;/a&gt; on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show had a 20-minute segment on Xi Jinping and the Chinese government. In particular, Oliver mentioned Xi’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/25/world/asia/china-xi-jinping.html&quot;&gt;abolition of term limits&lt;/a&gt; and even compared him to Mao Zedong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oliver also mentioned torture of political opponents, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/age-of-social-credit/&quot;&gt;infamous experiment&lt;/a&gt; to leverage WeChat data to give you a score and determine if you’re a good citizen, Tiananmen Square protests, Nobel Peace Prize winner &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liu_Xiaobo&quot;&gt;Liu Xiaobo’s&lt;/a&gt; recent death and, yes, online censorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a bit ironic that Oliver’s show itself is now censored in China as a result of this episode. It proves Oliver’s point that China still has a long way to go when it comes to human rights and freedom of the press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube embed breakout embed--video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OubM8bD9kck?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oliver also made sure to mention that Xi doesn’t like to be compared to Winnie the Pooh. Last year, Chinese authorities &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/blogs-china-blog-40627855&quot;&gt;have banned&lt;/a&gt; all mentions of Winnie the Pooh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/21/world/asia/john-oliver-china-ban.html&quot;&gt;the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, many posts on social network platform &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sina_Weibo&quot;&gt;Weibo&lt;/a&gt; mentioned John Oliver after the segment aired. Users didn’t specifically talked about the segment — they focused on the host. But now, if you try to write a post that says “John Oliver”, you’ll get an error message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GreatFire.org also &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.greatfire.org/https/www.hbo.com/last-week-tonight-with-john-oliver&quot;&gt;shows&lt;/a&gt; that HBO’s website has been blocked since Saturday or Sunday. Unless you have a working VPN or proxy &lt;a href=&quot;https://shadowsocks.org/&quot;&gt;solution&lt;/a&gt;, you won’t find Oliver anywhere on the Chinese internet. It’s impressive to see the pace of Chinese censors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 17:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mikece</dc:creator>
<og:title>John Oliver is erased from Chinese internet following segment on China</og:title>
<og:description>HBO’s Last Week Tonight has led to some drastic measures in China. After an episode aired on June 17th, the Chinese government is now trying to erase all signs of John Oliver on the internet. The show had a 20-minute segment on Xi Jinping and the Chinese government. In particular, Oliver mentioned …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/John-Oliver.png?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/06/25/john-oliver-is-erased-from-chinese-internet-following-segment-on-china/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/25/john-oliver-is-erased-from-chinese-internet-following-segment-on-china/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Docker Considered Harmful (2016)</title>
<link>http://catern.com/posts/docker.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://catern.com/posts/docker.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We'll start off with how Docker builds a container image for you. You pull down some kind of image from the Docker hub, and Docker hums excitingly for a bit while you watch things scroll and progress bars fill. What you end up with is a filesystem tree from some Linux distro, with a few things added in on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be surprising to some that we have been doing exactly this for multiple decades now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, you do this every time you install GNU/Linux on a machine. The majority of the files in that filesystem tree come from packages from some distro. And package managers are certainly capable of installing packages into arbitrary directories; that's how they install a new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, most even have neat little wrapper scripts to do it for you! And these are only an &lt;code&gt;apt-get install debootstrap&lt;/code&gt; (or equivalent) away! To build filesystem trees for a few of the most popular distros&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;org-ul&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;debootstrap trusty /srv/trees/ubuntu&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;debootstrap stable /srv/trees/debian&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yum -y --nogpg --releasever=22 --disablerepo='*' --enablerepo=fedora install fedora-release systemd passwd dnf fedora-release vim-minimal --installroot=/srv/trees/fedora&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;pacstrap /srv/trees/arch&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And of course you can select additional packages to install using these commands, or make other changes. This has been used for decades to build chroots, which I'll say more about a bit later. There are even more novel package managers, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://nixos.org/nix/&quot;&gt;nix&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/guix/&quot;&gt;guix&lt;/a&gt;, which have interesting features that can make things even easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, the distro version of node.js (for example) is too out of date! How am I going to get the latest version?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the first thing you should do if you need more up to date versions is enable the updated package repositories for your distro: Ubuntu backports, Debian backports, CentOS EPEL. It may be surprising to some, but distros and package managers actually exist for a reason, and one of those reasons is that they make it easy to keep your system up to date. (There are other advantages which I won't go into here&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a suitably updated version is not available through distro channels, I am obligated to suggest that the next best option is to download the source of the distro package, update and rebuild it yourself, and install using that package. Or, build the package yourself if one isn't available. This can be a bit of a pain if you are in the early development stages (though there are tools to make it easier&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) but again, there are many advantages.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people, however, use the traditional hacks. You can chroot in and just do your usual &lt;code&gt;pip install foo&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;gem install bar&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;npm install baz&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;./configure &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install&lt;/code&gt;, just as you would with some &quot;RUN&quot; directives in a Dockerfile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow! It's just like Docker! No, Docker is just like this. Hopefully it is becoming obvious that here, at least, there is no real advantage of Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crucially, you can use all the same install scripts that you would use with a normal Linux machine. You don't need to rewrite everything into Dockerfiles. You can do it manually, you can use shell scripts, you can use Ansible, you can write a boutique ConfigurationManagementFactory in Java, you can do whatever you like. It's just installing software. It's not complicated unless you make it complicated. Supposedly, Dockerfiles are simpler than running &lt;code&gt;debootstrap&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of your script, but I'm not sure I understand why. It seems to me that Docker is no simpler or easier than the standard way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it's true that Docker uses layering to be efficient in terms of disk space and time to build new containers. It defaults to using &lt;a href=&quot;http://aufs.sourceforge.net/aufs.html&quot;&gt;AUFS&lt;/a&gt; to do this.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I think you could reimplement it easily yourself with a small shell script and some calls to mount; but I haven't bothered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I just use &lt;a href=&quot;https://btrfs.wiki.kernel.org/index.php/Manpage/btrfs-subvolume&quot;&gt;man 8 btrfs-subvolume&lt;/a&gt;. btrfs is a copy on write filesystem which can instantly make space-efficient copies of filesystem trees in &quot;subvolumes&quot;, which the user sees as just regular directories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can build a stock Ubuntu filesystem tree into a subvolume with &lt;code&gt;btrfs subvolume create /srv/trees/ubuntu &amp;amp;&amp;amp; debootstrap trusty /srv/trees/ubuntu/&lt;/code&gt;. Then, when you want to build a new container with specific software, you just copy that subvolume and perform your modifications on the copy; that is, &lt;code&gt;btrfs subvolume snapshot /srv/trees/debian /srv/containers/webapp&lt;/code&gt; and work on &lt;code&gt;/srv/containers/webapp&lt;/code&gt;. If you want to copy those modifications, you just take another snapshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is arguably better, because there's no need to maintain a lot of state about the mount layerings and set them up again on reboot. Your container filesystem just sits there in a volume waiting for you to start it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, if you don't like btrfs for some reason, you're perfectly able to use zfs, OverlayFS, AUFS, or whatever; no need to have a &quot;storage driver&quot; implemented just to do some simple copy-on-write or layering operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you want to do some kind of change tracking as you build the system, you should keep it at the proper layer, or use dedicated tools. &lt;code&gt;/usr&lt;/code&gt; should be immutable and built from packages, your application data should live in &lt;code&gt;/srv&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;/var&lt;/code&gt; and be mounted in, and so all the configuration data that is part of the system build should be in &lt;code&gt;/etc&lt;/code&gt;. To track this, you can just use &lt;a href=&quot;http://etckeeper.branchable.com/&quot;&gt;etckeeper&lt;/a&gt; and store your &lt;code&gt;/etc&lt;/code&gt; in a git repository. which is right and proper since &lt;code&gt;/usr&lt;/code&gt; should be immutable. If you must, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.gnome.org/action/show/Projects/OSTree&quot;&gt;OSTree&lt;/a&gt; lets you version whole filesystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you still need to pull in a Docker image for some reason, you can treat it as just another way to build a filesystem tree. There are tools that will let you do that, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freedesktop.org/software/systemd/man/machinectl.html&quot;&gt;machinectl pull-dkr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>signa11</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://catern.com/posts/docker.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Workers Facing Firing Can Appeal to a Jury of Their Co-Workers</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-25/amazon-workers-facing-firing-can-appeal-to-a-jury-of-their-co-workers</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-25/amazon-workers-facing-firing-can-appeal-to-a-jury-of-their-co-workers</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Jane was working in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/AMZN:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Amazon.com Inc.&lt;/a&gt;’s Seattle headquarters when she was asked to a meeting with her manager and a human resources representative. They gave her a document outlining concerns about her work performance and spelled out three choices. She could quit and receive severance pay, spend the next several weeks trying to keep her job by meeting certain performance goals, or square off with her manager in a videoconference version of the Thunderdome, pleading her case with a panel of co-workers while her boss argued against her. Jane, who asked that her real name not be used to discuss a personal matter, chose the last one.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The employee appeal process is Amazon’s latest experiment in managing its growing workforce of more than 500,000. When it announced the program &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-launches-pivot-program-help-employees-in-danger-of-being-fired-2017-1&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon acknowledged it had been quick to fire people instead of trying to resolve problems in other ways. Executives recognized that poorly defined roles, dysfunctional teams, and peremptory managers were among the factors that often remained unexamined, according to a person familiar with the matter. Workers facing termination also lacked a forum to discuss such factors, the person says.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Amazon is borrowing a page from union grievance processes that don’t apply to most corporate employees. But only about 30 percent of those who appeal their manager’s criticisms prevail, meaning they can keep their jobs or seek new ones within the company with different bosses, according to people familiar with the matter. Eighteen months after its debut, the hearing process has created resentment and raised questions about fairness, according to current and former workers as well as attorneys familiar with their situations. “It’s a kangaroo court,” says George Tamblyn, a Seattle employment lawyer who helped one former Amazon worker plan her appeal earlier this year. “My impression of the process is it’s totally unfair.”&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Amazon declined to share metrics about the program or answer specific questions. &lt;span&gt;“Pivot is a uniquely Amazonian program that was thoughtfully designed to provide a fair and transparent process for employees who need support,” the company said in an emailed statement. “When employees are placed in Pivot, they have the option of working with their manager and HR to improve with a clear plan forward, of leaving Amazon with severance, or of appealing if they feel they shouldn’t be in the program. Just over a year into program, we’re pleased with the support it offers our employees and we’re continuing to iterate based on employee feedback and their needs.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Employees whose direct managers recently changed tend to make compelling appeals, according to a person familiar with the process. Workers who lose still get to choose between severance pay or a performance-improvement plan. &lt;span&gt;The downsides of appealing include the stress of litigating a case before strangers and against their bosses and trying to get along with your manager after publicly challenging them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jane says her manager had recently changed her job responsibilities and set impossible new goals for her (dayslong deadlines for projects that required weeks). She had an hourlong meeting with a company-appointed “career ambassador” who listened to her concerns and said she’d have a &lt;span&gt;few thousand words&lt;/span&gt; to rebut her manager’s complaints about her performance. The ambassador later suggested revisions to her draft, including removing details Jane thought were important for the panel to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jane had the option of choosing one manager or three nonmanagers as her jury. She got a list of potential panelists in advance, so she could look up their job titles, biographies, or work backgrounds, using an internal phone tool and LinkedIn. Employees can dismiss some panelists they worry will be unsympathetic. It didn’t help much, she says: At the hearing, the videoconference made it difficult to connect with any of the panelists or engage on a personal level, and she sweated through her shirt. She wasn’t invited to watch her boss’s presentation, and he got the last word. She waited by the phone until the career ambassador called to tell her she’d lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a company of Amazon’s size, the system could pay for itself by reducing the high cost of worker departures. A company with a 10 percent turnover rate, meaning 1 in 10 workers leave each year (&lt;span&gt;a low-ball estimate for a tech company)&lt;/span&gt; has to dedicate about 5 percent of its annual payroll to recruit, hire, and train replacements, says Fred Whittlesey, a compensation expert who previously worked for Amazon. For a company the size of Amazon, those costs run into the hundreds of millions of dollars. “There’s a huge financial incentive to reduce turnover, if you can do it in a sensible way,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon hired dozens of “career ambassadors” around the world to explain the new process to employees. Yet the appeal process is so baffling that it’s created a steady stream of work for employment lawyers giving consultations to help workers prepare for their appeal, say attorneys familiar with the process. Tamblyn says the process can be unfair, and that his client was forced to focus on performance issues highlighted by her manager instead of the fact she’d recently changed jobs within the company and had little time to adjust. “The fact that she was hired for one job and switched to another was a very important fact,” says Tamblyn. “She wasn’t allowed to present her case.” Amazon declined to address this specific concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seattle employment lawyer Alex Higgins says he has consulted with about 10 Amazon employees presented with performance-improvement plans. Four of those clients appealed, and one prevailed, he says. But even that client left for another job shortly afterward because the tension remained with his boss. “It doesn’t really provide a long-term solution,” Higgins says. “The people on the appeal panel say you’re right, and they go away. Then you’re still with the same boss, who thinks you aren’t doing a good job.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Jane’s career ambassador called to tell her she’d lost the appeal, she had one business day to decide if she wanted to accept about one month of severance pay to leave or attempt to meet the goals of her performance-improvement plan. She chose to keep working.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 16:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jsoc815</dc:creator>
<og:description>The hearing process has raised questions about fairness, according to workers and their attorneys.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i0_BbLsteQDU/v0/1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Amazon Workers Facing Firing Can Appeal to a Jury of Their Co-Workers</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-25/amazon-workers-facing-firing-can-appeal-to-a-jury-of-their-co-workers</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-25/amazon-workers-facing-firing-can-appeal-to-a-jury-of-their-co-workers</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Layoffs at Watson Health Reveal IBM’s Problem with AI</title>
<link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzA4MDQ5Nw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration of IBM logo with stethoscope.&quot;/&gt; Illustration: IEEE Spectrum; Images: IBM; iStockphoto
&lt;section id=&quot;side-module&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;medium-top-ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-module&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;recommended-side&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor’s Picks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;article-rec&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MjQ0MTEyMg.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;140&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;IBM Invests $1 Billion to Grow Watson Supercomputer's Struggling Business&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MjE4NzQ1Mg.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration: Eddie Guy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;IBM’s Watson Goes to Med School&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MjkzOTk3Mg.jpg&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; alt=&quot;An illustration shows a transparent human head in profile with a brain tumor highlighted in red.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;IBM Watson Makes a Treatment Plan for Brain-Cancer Patient in 10 Minutes; Doctors Take 160 Hours&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;IBM, a venerable tech company on a mission to stay relevant, has staked much of its future on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/watson/&quot;&gt;IBM Watson&lt;/a&gt;. The company has touted Watson, its flagship artificial intelligence, as the premier product for turning our data-rich but disorganized world into a smart and tidy planet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just last month, IBM CEO Ginni Rometty &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/events/vivatech?social_post=1552907884&amp;amp;linkId=52107359&quot;&gt;told a convention audience&lt;/a&gt; that we’re at an inflection point in history. Putting AI into everything will enable businesses to improve on “an exponential curve,” she said—a phenomenon that might one day be referred to as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.channelweb.co.uk/crn-uk/news/3032963/watsons-law-will-rival-moores-law-claims-ginni-rometty-in-ai-keynote&quot;&gt;Watson’s Law&lt;/a&gt;.”   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But according to engineers swept up in a major round of layoffs within IBM’s Watson division last month, the company’s promotions of its “cognitive computing” platform mask its own real difficulties in turning its AI into a profitable business. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“IBM Watson has great AI,” one engineer said, who asked to remain anonymous so he wouldn’t lose his severance package. “It’s like having great shoes, but not knowing how to walk—they have to figure out how to use it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layoffs at the end of May cut a swath through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/watson/health/&quot;&gt;Watson Health&lt;/a&gt; division. According to anonymous accounts submitted to the site &lt;a href=&quot;https://watchingibm.com/ibm-job-cuts/&quot;&gt;Watching IBM&lt;/a&gt;, the cuts primarily affecting workers from three acquired companies: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibm.com/watson/health/phytel/&quot;&gt;Phytel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/watson/health/explorys/&quot;&gt;Explorys&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://truvenhealth.com/&quot;&gt;Truven&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three companies, acquired in 2015 and 2016, brought with them hefty troves of healthcare data as well as proprietary analytics systems to mine the data for insights. The companies also brought existing customers: healthcare providers that used the analytics to improve both their care and their finances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inlay pullquote rt med&quot;&gt;“We thought IBM would take our company to the next level—not destroy it within three years.” &lt;span class=&quot;pq-attrib&quot;&gt;—laid-off worker from Phytel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two laid-off engineers from Phytel spoke to &lt;em&gt;IEEE Spectrum&lt;/em&gt; in depth. They allege that IBM’s leadership mismanaged their company since its acquisition, and say the problems at Phytel are emblematic of IBM’s struggles to make Watson profitable. Several other Phytel employees corroborated the basic facts of their accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both engineers worked for Phytel since before &lt;a href=&quot;https://www-03.ibm.com/press/us/en/pressrelease/46767.wss&quot;&gt;its 2015 acquisition&lt;/a&gt;, and say they were excited to become part of Big Blue. “Everyone expected that we would join IBM and be propelled by their support, that it would be the beginning of great things,” says the first engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Phytel was a really good company, it was really strong,” says the second, who also asked for anonymity to preserve his severance package. “Many people who got laid off are disappointed because they helped build this company and they really thought IBM would take it to the next level—not destroy it within three years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phytel had more than 150 clients when it was acquired by IBM, the engineers say. Today it has about 80. “Smaller companies are eating us alive,” says the first engineer. “They’re better, faster, cheaper. They’re winning our contracts, taking our customers, doing better at AI.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“A small percentage of the workforce”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM spokesman Ian Colley has declined to answer &lt;em&gt;IEEE Spectrum&lt;/em&gt;’s questions about Phytel, and won’t comment specifically on the engineers’ allegations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead Colley provided the following statement about the layoffs: “This activity affects a small percentage of our Watson Health workforce, as we move to more technology-intensive offerings, simplified processes, and automation to drive speed. IBM is continuing to reposition our team to focus on the high-value segments of the IT market, and we continue to hire aggressively in critical new areas that deliver value for our clients and IBM.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colley also references a &lt;a href=&quot;https://thefly.com/landingPageNews.php?id=2738971&amp;amp;headline=IBM-Morgan-Stanley-says-report-on-mass-layoffs-in-IBMs-Watson-Health-misleading&quot;&gt;Morgan Stanley analyst’s note&lt;/a&gt;, which argues that the layoffs represent restructuring that typically follows an acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inlay pullquote rt med&quot;&gt;Are you an IBM employee with something to say about Watson Health? Write to e.strickland@ieee.org &lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;But not all financial analysts have been bullish on IBM Watson. Last July, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://javatar.bluematrix.com/pdf/fO5xcWjc&quot;&gt;report from Jefferies LLC&lt;/a&gt; argued that despite IBM’s heavy investment in Watson (which the analyst estimated at $15 billion from 2010 to 2015 alone), the division won’t be profitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though IBM Watson “remains one of the most complete off-the-shelf [AI] platforms available on the marketplace,” the analyst wrote, customers face serious difficulties in integrating Watson with their existing data and analytics systems. As an example, he cited the MD Anderson Cancer Center in Texas, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beckershospitalreview.com/healthcare-information-technology/5-things-to-know-about-the-md-anderson-ibm-watson-breakup.html&quot;&gt;suspended its Watson project&lt;/a&gt; after spending $62 million on it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jefferies analyst also argued that IBM is “outgunned in the war for AI talent and will likely see increasing competition”—a situation that probably won’t be helped as disgruntled engineers leave IBM Watson with tales of mismanagement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Healthcare: the killer app? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM Watson first wowed the public in 2011 with its &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/automaton/robotics/artificial-intelligence/ibm-watson-jeopardy-computer-shuts-down-humans&quot;&gt;triumphant performance&lt;/a&gt; on the game show &lt;em&gt;Jeopardy!&lt;/em&gt;. The AI owed its victory to its natural language processing abilities, which enabled it to parse the show’s complicated and pun-filled clues, then scan its vast library for the solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&amp;quot;Jeopardy!&amp;quot; champions Ken Jennings, left, looks on as &amp;quot;Watson&amp;quot; beats him to the buzzer.&quot; src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzA4MDQ0MA.jpeg&quot;/&gt; Photo: Seth Wenig/AP IBM’s Watson beats champion Ken Jennings to the buzzer during a 2011 episode of the game show Jeopardy!.
&lt;p&gt;Two years after that televised tour de force, IBM declared that Watson would find its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2013/02/08/ibms-watson-gets-its-first-piece-of-business-in-healthcare/#6860d0b54028&quot;&gt;first killer app in healthcare&lt;/a&gt;. It seemed a natural fit: With hospitals and doctors switching to electronic health records for their patients, data troves were becoming available to machines like Watson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For its first job, Watson was supposed to go to work at &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/computing/software/ibms-watson-goes-to-med-school&quot;&gt;cancer treatment centers&lt;/a&gt;, scanning the medical literature and patient records to advise doctors on treatment plans. Three years later, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2017/09/05/watson-ibm-cancer/&quot;&gt;an investigation&lt;/a&gt; by the publication &lt;em&gt;Stat&lt;/em&gt; alleged that Watson Oncology hadn’t lived up to expectations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, &lt;em&gt;IEEE Spectrum&lt;/em&gt; has reported that IBM was &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/computing/software/ibm-invests-1-billion-to-grow-watson-supercomputer-struggling-business&quot;&gt;investing billions&lt;/a&gt; in the Watson business, but that “Doctor Watson” &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/biomedical/diagnostics/ibms-dr-watson-will-see-yousomeday&quot;&gt;wasn’t yet revolutionizing medicine&lt;/a&gt;. We didn’t neglect its significant achievements, though, also reporting on a study in which Watson &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/biomedical/diagnostics/ibm-watson-makes-treatment-plan-for-brain-cancer-patient-in-10-minutes-doctors-take-160-hours&quot;&gt;came up with a treatment plan&lt;/a&gt; for a brain cancer patient in 10 minutes—as compared to the human experts’ 160 hours of deliberation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Everything stopped”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM acquired the three companies Phytel, Explorys, and Truven for their databases of patient information and their data analytics that helped physicians and insurance companies provide more effective care. (A fourth acquisition, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.merge.com/&quot;&gt;Merge&lt;/a&gt;, brought in analytics relating to medical imaging, a very promising field for AI.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watson Health hoped to use these assets to help healthcare systems switch over from the traditional &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.insight-txcin.org/post/value-based-care-vs-fee-for-service&quot;&gt;fee-for-service model to the new value-based model&lt;/a&gt; emphasized under Obamacare. In the new model, healthcare systems aren’t paid for each procedure and visit, but are instead rewarded for keeping patients healthy and achieving better outcomes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phytel’s contribution was analytics paired with an automated patient communication system. A clinic could use the system to search its patient records and find, for example, all the men over age 45 who were overdue for a colonoscopy, and then use an autocall to remind them to schedule the dreaded appointment. Finding these patients who are “out of compliance” is a key part of preventative care, in which regular checkups can catch problems early, before they’re difficult (and expensive) to treat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phytel came to IBM as a sucessful business with a great reputation. In a 2014 survey of companies working on population health management, the research firm KLAS &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/klas-ranks-phytel-highest-among-population-health-management-vendors-300008156.html&quot;&gt;ranked Phytel as #1&lt;/a&gt; and called it the “clear leader” in the market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 2015 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www-03.ibm.com/press/us/en/pressrelease/46584.wss&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; announcing the acquisition, IBM announced that Phytel would be part of its brand new Watson Health division, which would augment Phytel’s offerings with IBM’s “powerful cognitive computing.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the acquisition, IBM management started the process known internally as “bluewashing,” in which an acquired company’s branding and operations are brought into alignment with IBM’s way of doing things. During this bluewashing, “everything stopped,” the first Phytel engineer says, and the workers were told not to focus on improving their existing product for current clients. “People were sitting around doing nothing for almost a year,” the second engineer says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, they were instructed to work on a grand project of merging Phytel’s databases and analytics with those of Explorys. The integration was a massive task, the engineers say, which required a huge investment of time and money from IBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coding without a map&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both engineers lay the blame squarely on IBM’s “offering management” department, which is responsible for coming up with the products that IBM sells to customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;A University of Texas MD uses IBM's Watson cognitive system while consulting with patient.&quot; src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzA4MDU0OA.jpeg&quot;/&gt; Photo: IBM Courtney DiNardo, a clinical researcher at MD Anderson Cancer Center in Texas, consults IBM Watson while speaking with a patient.
&lt;p&gt;IBM’s goal, the Phytel employees said, was to create a fancy new product that combined the capabilities of Phytel and Explorys. However, the offering managers didn’t have a clear idea of what that product would be. “They couldn’t decide on a roadmap,” says the second engineer. “We pivoted so many times.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Phytel engineers say the offering managers didn’t have technical backgrounds and sometimes came up with ideas for new products that were simply impossible. While the engineers tried to follow the shifting directions from above, Phytel didn’t deliver anything new to the market. “And we were burning through money,” the second engineer says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the engineers say, the offering managers did come up with a plan for a new product that would utilize both the Phytel and Explorys resources. But they note that there was no talk of bringing real artificial intelligence into the product. Watson, in other words, was absent. “They’re not anywhere close to injecting AI into the provider space,” says the second engineer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM recently began demoing its new product for patient communication with potential international customers, the engineers say—but these potential customers weren’t impressed. Instead they asked for something resembling Phytel’s old system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layoffs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM hasn't released the total number of Watson Health employees laid off in May, but the Phytel workers estimate that at least 300 people were given notice at their company, Explorys, and Truven. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Phytel, the engineers estimate that IBM laid off about 80 percent of employees—upward of 120 people from engineering, sales, and project management. “These are key technical people, and people working hands-on with the clients,” the first engineer says. “It’s not that they’re trimming down administrative staff or getting rid of non-essential workers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The engineers say that Phytel’s office, in Dallas, will soon have only a skeleton crew to support the existing products. How effectively that crew will perform, however, is an open question. The engineers say they were trying to help several major customers meet government-defined deadlines, such as starting with a value-based care model in July. “Now, it will be a big surprise to me if this goes as planned,” the first engineers says. “These layoffs will heavily undermine these efforts. If you cut all these people out, who will build the products? Who will deliver in the end?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The engineers see these cuts as IBM’s retreat from making products for healthcare providers such as hospitals, clinics, and doctors’ offices. They say that the employees who escaped the layoffs at the three companies work on products intended instead for insurance companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The laid-off employees say they aren’t too worried about finding new jobs. Hiring season is coming in August and September, they say, when companies plan their budgets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While an AI revolution in healthcare may be inevitable, they don’t believe that IBM will lead the charge. While Watson Health was floundering, they say, competitors have been racing ahead. “IBM has great potential, but in modern business, you adapt or go away. Workers will go to other companies,” says the first engineer. “The winner will not be IBM.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 16:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amynordrum</dc:creator>
<og:title>Layoffs at Watson Health Reveal IBM’s Problem with AI</og:title>
<og:url>https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai</og:url>
<og:description>Axed engineers say IBM isn't always smart about artificial intelligence</og:description>
<og:image>https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzA4MDUzNQ.jpeg</og:image>
<og:type>blog-the-human-os</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why nobody ever wins the car at the mall</title>
<link>https://thehustle.co/why-nobody-ever-wins-the-mall-car-giveaway</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thehustle.co/why-nobody-ever-wins-the-mall-car-giveaway</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the middle of the Great Mall in Milpitas, California, a shiny, brand-new, blue 2018 Acura TLX (MSRP $33k) sits ready for the taking.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Surrounding the vehicle are 10 screens, where mall-goers can enter their personal data — full name, phone number, income, credit card type — for a chance to win the “grand prize.” In the course of an hour on a Wednesday afternoon, 22 hopefuls fill out the digital form.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In a few weeks’ time, they’ll all be bombarded with the same scammy call:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Congratulations! Your name was recently drawn! All you have to do is come down to [X] and attend a presentation to claim your prize.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Who runs these sweepstakes? What do they do with our information? Does anyone ever win the damn car?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;These seemingly simple questions led me down a vortex of shady marketing tactics, timeshare salesmen, and third-party resale markets — and exposed the dirty underbelly of how our information is brokered.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The company behind the curtain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;First thing’s first: the mall isn’t behind these giveaways; they merely rent out the advertising space (for around&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://mallimages.mallfinder.com/images2/Cambridge/mall-csg/mimages/csg.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$1.5k per day&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;). And as it turns out, their partnership standards are pretty low.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After 4 calls to the Great Mall, a receptionist finally relinquishes the name of the firm running the car giveaway:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/GreatDestinationsVacations/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Great Destinations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;— a timeshare vacation rental company based in Orange County, California.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_9300&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9300&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/car.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;A giveaway at the Great Mall in Silicon Valley strongly implies that the prize is a 2018 Acura TLX (The Hustle)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I call them up and a guy named Patrick answers. When I ask for the odds of winning the car, he turns hostile:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Patrick:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“What’s your name?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zack:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Zack.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Patrick:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Last name?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zack:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Why do you need my last—”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Patrick:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Last name, or I can’t do anything for you.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zack:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Okay, but—”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Patrick:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Don’t play me, okay? Thank you!” [Abruptly hangs up]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So, I pass the torch to our managing editor, Lindsey, who sets up an untraceable number and calls under the alias “Katie Sanders.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Patrick collects a rolodex of her (fake) data — full name, age, marital status — then tells her she has to be at least 28 to enter the drawing. “Tell your parent to call me,” he says, and hangs up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Her “dad” (our writer, Conor) gives it one last try. Patrick tells Conor that in order to win the car, he has to go to a local Great Destinations office and attend a 90-minute timeshare presentation. For good measure, he offers to throw in a “free vacation package to Disneyland.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“But what about the car? Does anyone ever win it?” asks Conor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Not yet!” replies Patrick. “You’re probably the one! We’re waiting for you!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fine print tells a different story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the legal disclaimer of the car giveaway, there’s a statement that contradicts Patrick’s sales bravado:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_9301&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9301&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/scam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;car giveaway&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;“Any vehicle, boat or other representation displayed are examples only,” reads the terms of service on a car giveaway (The Hustle)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The car is a loaner from local dealer, Acura of Fremont — and despite what the sweepstakes’ marketing may suggest, it’s not up for grabs. (We called the dealer and they confirmed that the vehicle on display isn’t part of the giveaway at all.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;What you’re really signing up for is the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;opportunity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;to win an&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;opportunity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;possibly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;win a small amount of taxable cash.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Here’s what actually happens: 1) You enter the sweepstakes; 2) You have to attend a 90-minute timeshare presentation; 3) You get a scratch-off lotto ticket; 4) If you’re a “grand prize winner,” you get to play a game for a chance to win $100k.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The “game” is that the finalist gets to open 4 “mystery envelopes” with random amounts of cash. Last year’s two “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1Jg884gMDek&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;big winners&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;” walked away with checks for $575 and $700 — about enough to buy one side view mirror for your Acura..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That’s the absolute best-case scenario of entering one of these contests. Other aren’t so lucky.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Days after entering to win the car, Maggie Nicholson received a call informing her that her name was drawn. After sitting through a 2-hour timeshare presentation with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boiler Room&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;-like sales tactics, she was told there was no car — but she was eligible for a vacation package.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“[When I declined], they proceeded to tell our 12 year old daughter, ‘I guess your parents won’t take you on your dream vacation!’” she says. Then, they handed over her “prize:” a $25 restaurant voucher that required a $100 minimum spend to redeem.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_9302&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9302&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/there-is-no-car.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;The car is just a dangling carrot to get your data, n00bs (The Hustle)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In short, nobody wins the car in these telemarketing schemes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;There are other types of car giveaways run by more legitimate parties (charity raffles, event promotions) that&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;deliver the goods — but if you win, you’re liable to pay a hefty gift tax.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicagotribune.com/suburbs/post-tribune/opinion/ct-ptb-davich-casino-car-winner-st-1028-20151027-story.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a man who won a 2015 Tesla Model S at a casino would have had to pony up $38k in fees to take it home, and ended up selling it instead. He walked away with less than $25k on a $92k vehicle.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s a marketing gimmick to get your information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To enter a car contest at the mall, you have to enter a sweeping range of your personal information:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mobile number&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Full name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Marital Status&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Age&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Where you like to go on vacation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Combined annual income&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;What type of credit card(s) you own&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Only&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;after&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;you enter all of this are you presented with the terms — and buried at the very end of them, in small print, is something rather scary:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_9303&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9303&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/data.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Also in the fine print of a car giveaway: your data can be used for virtually any purpose by telemarketers (The Hustle)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In simple terms: when you enter one of these contests, you’re allowing telemarketers to not only use your data to make robocalls in perpetuity, but sell it and share it with any “subsidiaries” it chooses. Conveniently, it also renders void any “do not call” lists you might be on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;information from these forms is&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cockeyed.com/citizen/telemarketing/telemarketing_car.shtml&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;collected&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;en masse, entered into a large database, and delivered directly to the telemarketing company running the promotion (in this case, Great Destinations).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;From there, telemarketing calls are placed and the data is split into two “piles:” those who express interest, and those who don’t.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As an ex-telemarketer tells us, parties who express interest are hounded with up to 5-7 “follow-up” calls per week. The  “repackaged” into a new data set and sold to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;another&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;telemarketing company.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In essence, when you sign up for a car giveaway, your personal data is sucked into an neverending maelstrom of call lists which can be bounced around between data brokers and telemarketers for years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The system is like quicksand: once you’re in, it’s incredibly challenging to dislodge yourself.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The business of “free”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In today’s digital economy, the practice of offering a free service, product, or opportunity in exchange for data is widespread.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Companies like Facebook and Google give free access to their platforms in exchange for a wide, sweeping range of your personal information, which they analyze and use to sell targeted ads. Other free services, like Unroll.me,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/25/15423516/unrollme-privacy-policy-read-terms-of-service&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;your anonymized data to third-parties outright.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_9304&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9304&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/entraped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Attempts to remove information after entering a car contest just result in the telemarketing company requesting even more information from you (Via BBB)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the words of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/05/03/technology/personaltech/how-to-protect-your-privacy-as-more-apps-harvest-your-data.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lee Tien&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a lawyer with the Electronic Frontier Foundation,  “If you’re not paying for it with money, you’re paying for it with data.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But this is starting to change. Amid governmental and consumer concerns, Facebook finally provided clear instructions on how to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2018/03/privacy-shortcuts/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;download and delete data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;; the EU’s recent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehustle.co/gdpr-500-alex/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;GDPR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;ruling gives individuals more control over their data privacy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The same can’t be said for the proprietors of car giveaways.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Next time you see that shiny new sedan at the mall, just remember one thing: if an opportunity or service is free, the product is probably you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Share and discuss&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;6.44&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;8.28&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thehustle.co/&quot; onclick=&quot;ga('send', 'event', 'nav', 'advertorial', 'ps');&quot;&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt; for our daily news email to get all the non-political news you never knew you needed. All it takes is 5 minutes and BOOM, you're smarter.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 15:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sxv</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why nobody ever wins the car at the mall</og:title>
<og:description>We had a hunch that no one ever actually wins those mall car giveaways. But we had no idea how deep the rabbit hole went…</og:description>
<og:url>https://thehustle.co/why-nobody-ever-wins-the-mall-car-giveaway</og:url>
<og:image>https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/car.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thehustle.co/why-nobody-ever-wins-the-mall-car-giveaway</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>