<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>ActorDB – Distributed SQL database</title>
<link>https://github.com/biokoda/actordb</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/biokoda/actordb</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;ActorDB is a distributed SQL database...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with the scalability of a KV store, while keeping the query capabilities of a relational database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ActorDB is ideal as a server side database for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.actordb.com/docs-examples.html#example_filesync&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt;. Think of running a large mail service, dropbox, evernote, etc. They all require server side storage for user data, but the vast majority of queries is within a specific user. With many users, the server side database can get very large. Using ActorDB you can keep a full relational database for every user and not be forced into painful scaling strategies that require you to throw away everything that makes relational databases good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ActorDB is a database that does not hide sharding from you. It makes it explicit, so you can keep fully relational chunks (i.e. actors) for the 99% of your database queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if your data model is not easily partitioned, ActorDB has a powerful KV data type that you can use instead. An &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.actordb.com/docs-kvstore.html#about_kv_store&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ActorDB KV&lt;/a&gt; type is an sql table that is partitioned across all servers. That table can have sub tables linked to it using foreign keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can run queries or transactions on a single actor or across any number of actors. ActorDB can run on a single server or many servers. Writing to one actor is completely independent of writes to another actor, unless they are participating in the same transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Servers can be added and schema can be updated at any time while the database is running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homepage: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.actordb.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.actordb.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any questions you can use: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/actordb/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://gitter.im/actordb/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ActorDB is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A distributed relational SQL database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistent (not eventually consistent).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redundant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Massively concurrent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No single point of failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connectable over MySQL protocol and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/biokoda/actordb/blob/master/adbt.thrift&quot;&gt;Thrift&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replicated safely using the Raft distributed consensus algorithm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advantages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Complete horizontal scalability. All nodes are equivalent and you can have as many nodes as you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full featured ACID database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suitable for very large datasets over many actors and servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No special drivers needed. Use the mysql driver of your language of choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to configure and administer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No global locks. Only the actors (one or many) involved in a transaction are locked during a write. All other actors are unaffected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses stable reliable SQL and storage engines: SQLite on top of LMDB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inherits SQLite features like JSON support and common table expressions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Would you like to contribute?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we would most like to see is more client libraries on top of Thrift. Thrift generated code can be a bit verbose. Generally it is much nicer to implement an interface to it that hides some boilerplate code and uses nicer types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also if you have any ideas, thoughts on possible improvements or bugs to report, contact us using github issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you're interested in contributing. Use your language of choice. Generate a thrift interface using our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/biokoda/actordb/blob/master/adbt.thrift&quot;&gt;adbt.thrift&lt;/a&gt;, then write a clean interface to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will list any outside contributions here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Learn more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.actordb.com/docs-about.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.actordb.com/docs-about.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story: &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.biokoda.com/post/112206754025/why-we-built-actordb&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://blog.biokoda.com/post/112206754025/why-we-built-actordb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How SQLite runs on top of LMDB: &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.biokoda.com/post/133121776825/actordb-how-and-why-we-run-sqlite-on-top-of-lmdb&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://blog.biokoda.com/post/133121776825/actordb-how-and-why-we-run-sqlite-on-top-of-lmdb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to configure and run: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.actordb.com/docs-configuration.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.actordb.com/docs-configuration.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change log: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/biokoda/actordb/blob/master/CHANGES.md&quot;&gt;https://github.com/biokoda/actordb/blob/master/CHANGES.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Client libs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erlang: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/biokoda/actordb_client&quot;&gt;https://github.com/biokoda/actordb_client&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.NET 2.0: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hq-io/actordb-net&quot;&gt;https://github.com/hq-io/actordb-net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Builds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ubuntu/debian package (64bit)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dzbscw1ubdtyw.cloudfront.net/actordb_0.10.25-1_amd64.deb&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://dzbscw1ubdtyw.cloudfront.net/actordb_0.10.25-1_amd64.deb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;osx package (64bit):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dzbscw1ubdtyw.cloudfront.net/actordb-0.10.25-OSX-x86_64.tar.gz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://dzbscw1ubdtyw.cloudfront.net/actordb-0.10.25-OSX-x86_64.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;red hat/centos package (64bit):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centos 7: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dzbscw1ubdtyw.cloudfront.net/actordb-0.10.25-1.el7.centos.x86_64.rpm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://dzbscw1ubdtyw.cloudfront.net/actordb-0.10.25-1.el7.centos.x86_64.rpm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;general linux build (64bit)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dzbscw1ubdtyw.cloudfront.net/actordb-0.10.25-linux.tar.gz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://dzbscw1ubdtyw.cloudfront.net/actordb-0.10.25-linux.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;windows package (64bit):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dzbscw1ubdtyw.cloudfront.net/actordb-0.10.25-win-x86_64.zip&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://dzbscw1ubdtyw.cloudfront.net/actordb-0.10.25-win-x86_64.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 11:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>iamd3vil</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/3921287?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>biokoda/actordb</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/biokoda/actordb</og:url>
<og:description>actordb - ActorDB distributed SQL database</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/biokoda/actordb</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>MIT Career Development Handbook [pdf]</title>
<link>https://gecd.mit.edu/sites/default/files/about/files/career-handbook.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gecd.mit.edu/sites/default/files/about/files/career-handbook.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://gecd.mit.edu/sites/default/files/about/files/career-handbook.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 07:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pagade</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/3921287?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>biokoda/actordb</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/biokoda/actordb</og:url>
<og:description>actordb - ActorDB distributed SQL database</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gecd.mit.edu/sites/default/files/about/files/career-handbook.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Eight hours a night isn’t enough, according to a leading sleep scientist</title>
<link>https://qz.com/1301123/why-eight-hours-a-night-isnt-enough-according-to-a-leading-sleep-scientist/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://qz.com/1301123/why-eight-hours-a-night-isnt-enough-according-to-a-leading-sleep-scientist/</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For something that we spend a third of our lives doing (if we’re lucky), sleep is something that we know relatively little about. “Sleep is actually a relatively recent discovery,” says Daniel Gartenberg, a sleep scientist who is currently an assistant adjunct professor in biobehavioral health at Penn State. “Scientists only started looking at sleep 70 years ago.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As anyone who has lay awake at night contemplating the complexities of the universe can attest, sleep is a slippery beast. It involves a complex web of biological and neurological processes, all of which can be thrown off by something as simple as a partner’s nasal trumpeting or a coffee too late in the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also many, many misconceptions about sleep: that you can “&lt;a href=&quot;https://sleepjunkies.com/features/the-33-biggest-myths-about-sleep-and-insomnia-de-bunked/&quot;&gt;catch up&lt;/a&gt;” on the weekend for lost hours of shuteye. That you can get by on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webmd.com/sleep-disorders/sleep-fact-fiction&quot;&gt;four hours’ sleep&lt;/a&gt; a night. That a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webmd.com/sleep-disorders/news/20130118/alcohol-sleep&quot;&gt;nip of whiskey&lt;/a&gt; before bed helps you sleep better. Even that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20120417-does-cheese-give-you-nightmares&quot;&gt;eating cheese before snoozing&lt;/a&gt; causes nightmares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set the record straight about being horizontal, Quartz spoke to one of the world’s most-talked-about sleep scientists. &lt;a href=&quot;http://danielgartenberg.com/&quot;&gt;Daniel Gartenberg&lt;/a&gt; is currently working on research funded by the National Science Foundation and the National Institute of Aging and is also a TED resident. (Watch his talk on deep sleep &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_gartenberg_the_brain_benefits_of_deep_sleep_and_how_to_get_more_of_it&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.) He’s also an entrepreneur who has launched several cognitive-behavioral-therapy apps, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/id1193763939&quot;&gt;Sonic Sleep Coach alarm clock&lt;/a&gt;. All that with 8.5 hours’ of sleep a night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some topics we cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;why 8.5 hours of sleep is the new eight hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the genes that dictate if you’re a morning person or a night owl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why you should take a nap instead of meditating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how sleep deprivation can be a tool to fight depression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why sleep should be the new worker’s rights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and tips on how to get a better night’s rest (hint: it’s not your Fitbit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also read Gartenberg’s comments on “sleep inertia”—the scientific reason why you feel so groggy when you wake up—&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1301170/sleep-inertia-explains-why-you-feel-so-groggy-when-you-wake-up/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This interview has been lightly condensed and edited for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quartz: Why do we need sleep?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Gartenberg: Every organism on the planet sleeps in some fashion, to some degree—even the basic fruit fly. What makes sleep so essential for our wellbeing comes down to three main things: to save our energy, to help our cells recover, and to help us process and understand our environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This third one is what I study. The “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/14638388&quot;&gt;synaptic homeostasis hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;” is this idea that during the day, we make all these connections with the world around us. It used to be like, “Don’t go over there—the lions live there now.” Now it’s like, “What did Barbara say to me in the office?” These excitatory connections we make during the day result in the neurons in our brains getting overall higher activation. Then during the nighttime when we sleep, we have a downregulating process where the things that didn’t really matter to your survival sink to the bottom, and the things that are most relevant to your survival rise to the top. What deep sleep does is all the neural processing, and what REM sleep [rapid-eye-movement sleep] and light sleep do is basically integrate that into your long-term personality and understanding of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What other differences are there between deep sleep and REM sleep?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people don’t understand that these are two very, very different processes. A lot of people probably learned from basic psych in high school that you have these sleep stages: light sleep &amp;gt; deep sleep &amp;gt; light sleep &amp;gt; REM, and repeat. As you sleep more, you get less and less deep sleep, and also if you sleep-deprive yourself, you get more deep sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During deep sleep, you get these long-burst brainwaves that are called delta waves, but during REM, your brainwaves are actually functioning very similarly to waking life. Your body is also paralyzed during REM—it’s a very noticeable physiological difference. You also lose thermo-regulation, meaning if it’s hot in your environment, your body gets hot, kind of like you’re a chameleon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your whole thing is that deep sleep is more important than REM sleep. Why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an ongoing debate in the literature—really, it’s both. Deep sleep is really important, but REM sleep is also important. We know that the human growth hormone, cell-recovery things, and the ability to process new information are associated with deep sleep. REM sleep is basically the processing of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asking for the workaholics in the room: Do we &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need that much sleep?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A professor I collaborate with at Penn State named Orfeu Buxton says that 8.5 hours of sleep is the new eight hours. In order to get a healthy eight hours of sleep, which is the amount that many people need, you need to be in bed for 8.5 hours. The standard in the literature is that healthy sleepers spend more than 90% of the time in bed asleep, so if you’re in bed for eight hours, a healthy sleeper might actually sleep for only about 7.2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;8.5 hours of sleep is the new eight hours.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;That being said, some people are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/genetic-mutation-sleep-less/&quot;&gt;short sleepers&lt;/a&gt;: You can do a test to find out if you have genetic makeup that makes you a short sleeper. That’s rare, though, so by and large, people are not getting enough sleep. Getting half an hour less than what you need to really adds up over a week period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see how much sleep you really need, my professor suggests that when you go on vacation, try to stick to your normal bedtime and then see what time you wake up. With no stressors or time to get up, you’ll just fall into a natural pattern, and that’s probably how much sleep you actually need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I normally get around six to seven hours of sleep a night and feel fine. But is that just because how I feel has become my normal operating mode, and I could really be functioning at a higher level?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right. That’s like the fish and the fish bowl phenomenon: The fish doesn’t know that he’s in the fishbowl, nonetheless that he’s in water. Also, when you’re sleep deprived, research has shown that you’re really bad at being able to tell that you’re sleep deprived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this has to do with stress in our environment and our external need to work all the time. This is what’s driving the fact that we’re sleeping so poorly nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How else does the workplace affect sleep?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of sleep like the new worker’s rights: We’re being worked to the point that we’re not sleeping, and it’s having physical detriments on our health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People should be able to sleep like they’re able to get healthcare. This also means making our work environments more conducive to sleep. For optimum productivity, we need around eight hours of sleep, right? But that doesn’t have to be in one go. Maybe I’ll get a little less than that during the night, and then I’ll take a 20-to-30-minute power nap at midday. There’s a siesta for a reason! New Yorkers oftentimes try to pound through with coffee and whatever, but giving in to your natural circadian rhythm during that afternoon lull might be a good thing. We weren’t made to produce for eight hours straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s talk more about circadian rhythms. What are they, and why are they responsible for that mid-afternoon slump?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We evolved from bacteria in the ocean that could differentiate sunlight from darkness—that’s what ended up forming the human eye. That means every organism is responsive to a circadian rhythm that’s largely dictated by sunlight. The photo receptors in our eyes pick up on sunlight, which controls the release of melatonin and all these other neurotransmitters that dictate your energy levels throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a peak moment of awakeness during the morning. After lunch you usually have a glucose spike, especially if you have a big heavy lunch, like a cheeseburger. That glucose spike combined with a circadian dip gives you a period of fatigue between around 2 and 4pm. You’ll then have another spike in alertness right before dinner, and then you’ll start getting tired again closer to bedtime. That’s your 24-hour circadian rhythm, basically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s also something called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chronobiology.com/about-chronobiology/&quot;&gt;chronobiology&lt;/a&gt;.” You actually have genes that dictate whether you’re a morning person or an evening person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wait—what? Really?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah! If you’re a morning person, they call it a lark. If you’re a night person, they call it a night owl. Your genes give you a greater proclivity to being a lark or an owl. And then some people have genes that make them very flexible. The environmental cues they react against are called &lt;em&gt;zeitgebers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lightsabers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zeitgebers&lt;/em&gt;! It’s this weird German word. There’s a lot of cool words in sleep: like the photo receptors control the release of melatonin by sending signals to the &lt;em&gt;suprachiasmatic nucleus&lt;/em&gt;, just like &lt;em&gt;supercalifragilisticexpialidocious&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;You actually have genes that dictate whether you’re a morning person or an evening person.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Anyway, basically your biggest zeitgeber is sunlight, and that’s the environmental cue that controls energy levels as well. But then also timing of meals, exercise, and having a consistent bedtime are all zeitgebers that impact your circadian rhythm. A bigger part of the problem is that we’re indoors so much now, so we don’t get that natural occurring sunlight when you wake up in the morning. That’s one of the best things that you can do to entrench your circadian rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your circadian rhythm is off, it negatively impacts your sleep quality. So having that consistent rhythm of going to bed and getting up at the same time will actually make your sleep more regenerative at night. Going for a walk outside and getting that sunlight in the morning is the best thing to do to wake up. Your circadian rhythm isn’t a fixed thing: It’s actually shiftable based on your environmental cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you wake up in the middle of the night (say, to go to the bathroom) but get back to sleep quickly, does that screw around with your sleep quality?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It varies. There’s no clear answer. In our studies, we’ll play really loud sounds that people have no conscious awareness of at all: We can play a sound literally at 70 decibels, which is like someone screaming, and that’ll wake them up briefly and then they’ll go right back into the sleep stage that they were in. Other times you can get a full awakening, and you’ll have to go through the process again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s actually pretty normal to wake up during the night, anyway. In &lt;em&gt;The Canterbury Tales&lt;/em&gt;, one of the oldest manuscripts in English culture, they describe “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencealert.com/humans-used-to-sleep-in-two-shifts-maybe-we-should-again&quot;&gt;second sleep&lt;/a&gt;.” There’s some evidence that we used to go to bed when the sun went down, then wake up for a little bit at night—putter around, make sure we’re not getting eaten by a lion—and then go back to sleep. So it’s pretty normal to like wake up in the middle of the night and use the bathroom or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is society changing our relationship with sleep? What will be the consequences of this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gallup has reported that over the past 50 years, &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.gallup.com/poll/166553/less-recommended-amount-sleep.aspx&quot;&gt;we’re sleeping a whole hour less per night&lt;/a&gt; than we did in the 1950s. That’s a lot. A lot of that has to do with having TV on all the time, and mobile phones are taking it to the next level. But I think the biggest issue right now is the lack of work/life balance. I mean, I’m an entrepreneur, so I feel like I’m basically always “on”. A lot of people have jobs where they’re getting emails all hours the night, and there’s no longer a nine-to-five schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that’s why meditation is so in vogue right now. But I actually think sleep is a more regenerative process than meditation. A lot of times people talk about doing meditation around midday, but for most people I would recommend a quick power nap instead of a quick meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But if I try to take a powernap at lunch and can’t get to sleep, haven’t I just wasted 20 minutes of my day that I could have been meditating—or working?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when you close your eyes and turn off your brain for little bit—even if you don’t fully fall asleep—your brain creeps into theta waves. Similarly, when you meditate, you get a little bit of theta. So if you’re one of these people who really has a hard time with napping, maybe meditation could be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Taking a break—whether it’s meditation or nap—during the circadian dip can be much more conducive to productivity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The most important thing is taking that time off—it’s more conducive to your productivity. A lot of times people think they can like fight through and push harder and harder and harder to get better results, but sleep can give you that, too. When you transition in and out of sleep, your brain produces theta waves, which help you think more divergently. That’s why a lot of times when you wake up from a power nap or from sleeping, you’ll be able to solve that intractable problem that you couldn’t earlier in the day. That’s one of the reasons I think taking a break—whether it’s meditation or nap—during that circadian dip can be much more conducive to productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially true for creative jobs. Jobs used to be very manual, but as jobs are becoming more and more cognitive, I think caring for your cognition is going to become increasingly important for the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some tips for getting a better sleep?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want a cold, quiet environment with no light: That’s basically the ideal way to improve your sleep quality. However, people have a different ideal sound, light, and temperature environment to improve their sleep quality. We need stimulus control: You want to save the bedroom for sleep and sex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOUND&lt;/strong&gt;: We focus on sound a lot. Quiet environments are going to improve your sleep quality. Your brain has these micro arousals throughout the night without you being consciously aware of it—even an air-conditioning unit turning on wakes up your brain. So blocking out noises is a low-hanging fruit to improve your sleep quality. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bose.com/en_us/products/headphones/noise_masking_sleepbuds/noise-masking-sleepbuds.html&quot;&gt;Bose just released an earbud&lt;/a&gt; that you can sleep with, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s this new finding where playing sounds at a certain frequency when your brain is in deep sleep actually increases the percentage of time spent in deep sleep. We’re publishing this paper in Society for Neuroscience Conference in a couple of weeks, and it’s basically &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_gartenberg_the_brain_benefits_of_deep_sleep_and_how_to_get_more_of_it&quot;&gt;what my TED talk is about&lt;/a&gt;. Playing these pulses at the same frequency as your deep-sleep brainwaves primes more deep sleep. Scientifically speaking, it’s a similar process as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/psychiatry/specialty_areas/brain_stimulation/tdcs.html&quot;&gt;transcranial direct-current stimulation&lt;/a&gt;, except it doesn’t use electricity—just sound. Sound gets transmitted into electricity because you’re picking up on the auditory cortex while you’re sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEMPERATURE&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a big problem, especially if you have a sleep partner. Everyone has different natural body temperatures, and usually men run hotter than women, but it can go either way. That can be a big issue if you have a different body temperature, because then no one’s happy. I wrote this article called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/im-thinking-about-sleeping-and-science_us_593aaa5ae4b014ae8c69df9e&quot;&gt;Split blankets, not beds&lt;/a&gt;,” where I said that you shouldn’t share the same comforter. Of course it’s nice to share, and I do that at some points, but it’s also important to have different bedding on your bed so you can have that lighter sheet or comforter to try to mitigate differences in body temperature. There’s also something called a &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1301123/why-eight-hours-a-night-isnt-enough-according-to-a-leading-sleep-scientist/chilly%20pad&quot;&gt;chili pad&lt;/a&gt;. You put on half of your bed and it’ll dictate the temperature level on your half if you run at a different temperature than your sleep partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIGHT&lt;/strong&gt;: The other thing is no blue light close to bedtime. There are a lot of studies that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.health.harvard.edu/staying-healthy/blue-light-has-a-dark-side&quot;&gt;screen time close to bed is bad&lt;/a&gt;. One of the ideal ways of using our app is to connect it to your Bluetooth speakers so that you can put your phone in another room: There is something important to not having your phone in reach, because then you’re looking at the screen and getting the brightness. If you live in the city and there’s bright lights at night, having blackout shade can also be super useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STRESS&lt;/strong&gt;: When you’re stressed, your flight-or-fight response is active during the night, and your sleep quality is going to be shallow. It’s natural: If you have kids, you are programmed to be able to respond to your environment during the night to make sure you’re not getting eaten by a predator. Parents have this issue when their fight-or-flight response system is overly activated by worrying about their kid, and that worry actually makes their sleep quality worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I recommend to people who have a racing mind and worrying thoughts about work is to segment a time to get it out during the day—encapsulate it in a little mental box so you’re not laying down in bed and just having your mind race about all these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you feel about sleep trackers and wearables?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the most common wearable to measuring sleep right now is the Fitbit. I’ve studied these devices in depth in a well-controlled laboratory experiment where we’re monitoring brainwaves. I can say the Fitbit is pretty accurate in measuring when you’re asleep and when you’re wake, but when it comes to measuring sleep stages, basically any device that measures heart rate, like the Apple Watch, is totally inaccurate. That’s because they don’t sample at the frequency necessary to get a good read on your sleep stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitbits can also cause bigger problems, because they stress you out about the fact you think you’re not getting enough deep sleep—even though they’re not good at accurately measuring sleep stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about people who mess with their sleep cycle and try things like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/430415/i-once-tried-to-cheat-sleep-and-for-a-year-i-succeeded/&quot;&gt;da Vinci method&lt;/a&gt;, where you take a 20-minute nap every four hours?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/5063665/what-is-polyphasic-sleep/&quot;&gt;polyphasic sleep&lt;/a&gt; stuff? I mean, it’s just not enough sleep. It’s ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t seen a study that empirically shows that it’s helpful. There is certainly a false myth that we need eight hours of &lt;em&gt;continuous&lt;/em&gt; sleep: I think it’s possible to have your sleep be a little bit broken up and be perfectly healthy—but getting that eight hours is crucially important. The thing is that the placebo effect in some of these polyphasic sleep methods runs really high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There have also been some studies showing that &lt;a href=&quot;https://mosaicscience.com/story/staying-awake-surprisingly-effective-way-treat-depression/&quot;&gt;sleep deprivation&lt;/a&gt; could be a tool to combat persistent depression. How do you feel about that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was really interesting. If you have an extreme case of depression, sometimes some therapists will sleep deprive you a little bit. It’s basically to activate your fight-or-flight response and jolt you out of your depression. But things like empathy and working with others are also impacted when you’re sleep deprived, and you’re also more sensitive to pain. Some people are studying this link to address the opioid epidemic and through actually sleeping better: Chronic pain might be associated with deep sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read next: &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1301170/sleep-inertia-explains-why-you-feel-so-groggy-when-you-wake-up/&quot;&gt;“Sleep inertia” explains why you feel so groggy when you wake up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qz.com/re/ideas&quot;&gt;Quartz Ideas&lt;/a&gt;, our home for bold arguments and big thinkers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-aside&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;popular-stories-module&quot;&gt;&lt;article&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;module-title&quot;&gt;Most Popular&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1301123/why-eight-hours-a-night-isnt-enough-according-to-a-leading-sleep-scientist/&quot; title=&quot;Why eight hours a night isn’t enough, according to a leading sleep scientist&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rtr2zg6d-e1516291250249.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=240&quot; alt=&quot;A woman sleeps on a bed&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1301123/why-eight-hours-a-night-isnt-enough-according-to-a-leading-sleep-scientist/&quot; title=&quot;Why eight hours a night isn’t enough, according to a leading sleep scientist&quot;&gt;Why eight hours a night isn’t enough, according to a leading sleep scientist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;button class=&quot;read-full-story-button&quot;&gt;Read full story&lt;/button&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 03:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why eight hours a night isn’t enough, according to a leading sleep scientist</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rtr2zg6d-e1516291250249.jpg?quality=80&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1600</og:image>
<og:url>https://qz.com/1301123/why-eight-hours-a-night-isnt-enough-according-to-a-leading-sleep-scientist/</og:url>
<og:description>Your genes can determine whether you're a morning person or night owl.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://qz.com/1301123/why-eight-hours-a-night-isnt-enough-according-to-a-leading-sleep-scientist/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>No Copyright Law: The Real Reason for Germany’s Industrial Expansion? (2010)</title>
<link>http://m.spiegel.de/international/zeitgeist/no-copyright-law-the-real-reason-for-germany-s-industrial-expansion-a-710976.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://m.spiegel.de/international/zeitgeist/no-copyright-law-the-real-reason-for-germany-s-industrial-expansion-a-710976.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-function-box clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-function-date&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;timeformat&quot; datetime=&quot;2010-08-18 16:52:06&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 18, 2010&lt;/strong&gt;  04:52 PM&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire country seemed to be obsessed with reading. The sudden passion for books struck even booksellers as strange and in 1836 led literary critic Wolfgang Menzel to declare Germans &quot;a people of poets and thinkers.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&quot;That famous phrase is completely misconstrued,&quot; declares economic historian Eckhard Höffner, 44. &quot;It refers not to literary greats such as Goethe and Schiller,&quot; he explains, &quot;but to the fact that an incomparable mass of reading material was being produced in Germany.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Höffner has researched that early heyday of printed material in Germany and reached a surprising conclusion -- unlike neighboring England and France, Germany experienced an unparalleled explosion of knowledge in the 19th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;German authors during this period wrote ceaselessly. Around 14,000 new publications appeared in a single year in 1843. Measured against population numbers at the time, this reaches nearly today's level. And although novels were published as well, the majority of the works were academic papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation in England was very different. &quot;For the period of the Enlightenment and bourgeois emancipation, we see deplorable progress in Great Britain,&quot; Höffner states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equally Developed Industrial Nation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, only 1,000 new works appeared annually in England at that time -- 10 times fewer than in Germany -- and this was not without consequences. Höffner believes it was the chronically weak book market that caused England, the colonial power, to fritter away its head start within the span of a century, while the underdeveloped agrarian state of Germany caught up rapidly, becoming an equally developed industrial nation by 1900.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even more startling is the factor Höffner believes caused this development -- in his view, it was none other than copyright law, which was established early in Great Britain, in 1710, that crippled the world of knowledge in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Germany, on the other hand, didn't bother with the concept of copyright for a long time. Prussia, then by far Germany's biggest state, introduced a copyright law in 1837, but Germany's continued division into small states meant that it was hardly possible to enforce the law throughout the empire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Höffner's diligent research is the first academic work to examine the effects of the copyright over a comparatively long period of time and based on a direct comparison between two countries, and his findings have caused a stir among academics. Until now, copyright was seen as a great achievement and a guarantee for a flourishing book market. Authors are only motivated to write, runs the conventional belief, if they know their rights will be protected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet a historical comparison, at least, reaches a different conclusion. Publishers in England exploited their monopoly shamelessly. New discoveries were generally published in limited editions of at most 750 copies and sold at a price that often exceeded the weekly salary of an educated worker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;London's most prominent publishers made very good money with this system, some driving around the city in gilt carriages. Their customers were the wealthy and the nobility, and their books regarded as pure luxury goods. In the few libraries that did exist, the valuable volumes were chained to the shelves to protect them from potential thieves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Germany during the same period, publishers had plagiarizers -- who could reprint each new publication and sell it cheaply without fear of punishment -- breathing down their necks. Successful publishers were the ones who took a sophisticated approach in reaction to these copycats and devised a form of publication still common today, issuing fancy editions for their wealthy customers and low-priced paperbacks for the masses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Multitude of Treatises&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This created a book market very different from the one found in England. Bestsellers and academic works were introduced to the German public in large numbers and at extremely low prices. &quot;So many thousands of people in the most hidden corners of Germany, who could not have thought of buying books due to the expensive prices, have put together, little by little, a small library of reprints,&quot; the historian Heinrich Bensen wrote enthusiastically at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prospect of a wide readership motivated scientists in particular to publish the results of their research. In Höffner's analysis, &quot;a completely new form of imparting knowledge established itself.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially the only method for disseminating new knowledge that people of that period had known was verbal instruction from a master or scholar at a university. Now, suddenly, a multitude of high-level treatises circulated throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &quot;Literature Newspaper&quot; reported in 1826 that &quot;the majority of works concern natural objects of all types and especially the practical application of nature studies in medicine, industry, agriculture, etc.&quot; Scholars in Germany churned out tracts and handbooks on topics such as chemistry, mechanics, engineering, optics and the production of steel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In England during the same period, an elite circle indulged in a classical educational canon centered more on literature, philosophy, theology, languages and historiography. Practical instruction manuals of the type being mass-produced in Germany, on topics from constructing dikes to planting grain, were for the most part lacking in England. &quot;In Great Britain, people were dependent on the medieval method of hearsay for the dissemination of this useful, modern knowledge,&quot; Höffner explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The German proliferation of knowledge created a curious situation that hardly anyone is likely to have noticed at the time. Sigismund Hermbstädt, for example, a chemistry and pharmacy professor in Berlin, who has long since disappeared into the oblivion of history, earned more royalties for his &quot;Principles of Leather Tanning&quot; published in 1806 than British author Mary Shelley did for her horror novel &quot;Frankenstein,&quot; which is still famous today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'Lively Scholarly Discourse'&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade in technical literature was so strong that publishers constantly worried about having a large enough supply, and this situation gave even the less talented scientific authors a good bargaining position in relation to publishers. Many professors supplemented their salaries with substantial additional income from the publication of handbooks and informational brochures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Höffner explains that this &quot;lively scholarly discourse&quot; laid the basis for the Gründerzeit, or foundation period, the term used to describe the rapid industrial expansion in Germany in the late 19th century. The period produced later industrial magnates such as Alfred Krupp and Werner von Siemens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market for scientific literature didn't collapse even as copyright law gradually became established in Germany in the 1840s. German publishers did, however, react to the new situation in a restrictive way reminiscent of their British colleagues, cranking up prices and doing away with the low-price market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authors, now guaranteed the rights to their own works, were often annoyed by this development. Heinrich Heine, for example, wrote to his publisher Julius Campe on October 24, 1854, in a rather acerbic mood: &quot;Due to the tremendously high prices you have established, I will hardly see a second edition of the book anytime soon. But you must set lower prices, dear Campe, for otherwise I really don't see why I was so lenient with my material interests.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 20:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gballan</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.spiegel.de/international/zeitgeist/no-copyright-law-the-real-reason-for-germany-s-industrial-expansion-a-710976.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>No Copyright Law: The Real Reason for Germany's Industrial Expansion? - SPIEGEL ONLINE - International</og:title>
<og:description>Did Germany experience rapid industrial expansion in the 19th century due to an absence of copyright law? A German historian argues that the massive proliferation of books, and thus knowledge, laid the foundation for the country's industrial might.</og:description>
<og:image>http://cdn1.spiegel.de/images/image-117294-860_poster_16x9-vord-117294.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.spiegel.de/international/zeitgeist/no-copyright-law-the-real-reason-for-germany-s-industrial-expansion-a-710976.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fibonacci Hashing: The Optimization That the World Forgot</title>
<link>https://probablydance.com/2018/06/16/fibonacci-hashing-the-optimization-that-the-world-forgot-or-a-better-alternative-to-integer-modulo/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://probablydance.com/2018/06/16/fibonacci-hashing-the-optimization-that-the-world-forgot-or-a-better-alternative-to-integer-modulo/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I recently posted a blog post about a new hash table, and whenever I do something like that, I learn at least one new thing from my comments. In my last comment section Rich Geldreich talks about his hash table which uses “Fibonacci Hashing”, which I hadn’t heard of before. I have worked a lot on hash tables, so I thought I have at least heard of all the big important tricks and techniques, but I also know that there are so many small tweaks and improvements that you can’t possibly know them all. I thought this might be another neat small trick to add to the collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out I was wrong. This is a big one. And everyone should be using it. Hash tables should not be prime number sized and they should not use an integer modulo to map hashes into slots. Fibonacci hashing is just better. Yet somehow nobody is using it and lots of big hash tables (including all the big implementations of std::unordered_map) are much slower than they should be because they don’t use Fibonacci Hashing. So let’s figure this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all how do we find out what this Fibonacci Hashing is? Rich Geldreich called it “Knuth’s multiplicative method,” but before looking it up in The Art of Computer Programming, I tried googling for it. The top result right now is &lt;a href=&quot;http://book.huihoo.com/data-structures-and-algorithms-with-object-oriented-design-patterns-in-c++/html/page214.html&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; which is old, with a copyright from 1997. Fibonacci Hashing is not mentioned on Wikipedia. You will find a few more pages mentioning it, mostly from universities who present this in their “introduction to hash tables” material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From that I thought it’s one of those techniques that they teach in university, but that nobody ends up using because it’s actually more expensive for some reason. There are plenty of those in hash tables: Things that get taught because they’re good in theory, but they’re bad in practice so nobody uses them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except somehow, on this one, the wires got crossed. Everyone uses the algorithm that’s unnecessarily slow and leads to more problems, and nobody is using the algorithm that’s faster while at the same time being more robust to problematic patterns. Knuth talked about Integer Modulo and about Fibonacci Hashing, and everybody should have taken away from that that they should use Fibonacci Hashing, but they didn’t and everybody uses integer modulo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into this, let me just show you the results of a simple benchmark: Looking up items in a hash table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;9650&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://probablydance.com/2018/06/16/fibonacci-hashing-the-optimization-that-the-world-forgot-or-a-better-alternative-to-integer-modulo/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font.png?w=650&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1176,593&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;unordered_map_comparison_larger_font&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font.png?w=650?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font.png?w=650?w=650&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-9650&quot; src=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font.png?w=650&quot; alt=&quot;unordered_map_comparison_larger_font&quot; srcset=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font.png?w=650 650w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font.png?w=150 150w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font.png?w=300 300w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font.png?w=768 768w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font.png?w=1024 1024w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/unordered_map_comparison_larger_font.png 1176w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this benchmark I’m comparing various unordered_map implementations. I’m measuring their lookup speed when the key is just an integer. On the X-axis is the size of the container, the Y-axis is the time to find one item. To measure that, the benchmark is just spinning in a loop calling find() on this container, and at the end I divide the time that the loop took by the number of iterations in the loop. So on the left hand side, when the table is small enough to fit in cache, lookups are fast. On the right hand side the table is too big to fit in cache and lookups become much slower because we’re getting cache misses for most lookups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the main thing I want to draw attention to is the speed of ska::unordered_map, which uses Fibonacci hashing. Otherwise it’s a totally normal implementation of unordered_map: It’s just a vector of linked lists, with every element being stored in a separate heap allocation. On the left hand side, where the table fits in cache, ska::unordered_map can be more than twice as fast as the Dinkumware implementation of std::unordered_map, which is the next fastest implementation. (this is what you get when you use Visual Studio)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you use std::unordered_map and look things up in a loop, that loop could be twice as fast if the hash table used Fibonacci hashing instead of integer modulo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How it works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let me explain how Fibonacci Hashing works. It’s related to the golden ratio &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Cphi%3D1.6180339...&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\phi=1.6180339...&quot; title=&quot;\phi=1.6180339...&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; which is related to the Fibonacci numbers, hence the name. One property of the Golden Ratio is that you can use it to subdivide any range roughly evenly without ever looping back to the starting position. What do I mean by subdividing? For example if you want to divide a circle into 8 sections, you can just make each step around the circle be an angle of &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=360%5E%5Ccirc%2F8&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;360^\circ/8&quot; title=&quot;360^\circ/8&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; degrees. And after eight steps you’ll be back at the start. And for any &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=n&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;n&quot; title=&quot;n&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; number of steps you want to take, you can just change the angle to be &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=360%5E%5Ccirc%2Fn&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;360^\circ/n&quot; title=&quot;360^\circ/n&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;. But what if you don’t know ahead of time how many steps you’re going to take? What if the &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=n&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;n&quot; title=&quot;n&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; value is determined by something you don’t control? Like maybe you have a picture of a flower, and you want to implement “every time the user clicks the mouse, add a petal to the flower.” In that case you want to use the golden ratio: Make the angle from one petal to the next &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=360%5E%5Ccirc%2F%5Cphi&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;360^\circ/\phi&quot; title=&quot;360^\circ/\phi&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; and you can loop around the circle forever, adding petals, and the next petal will always fit neatly into the biggest gap and you’ll never loop back to your starting position. Vi Hart has a good video about the topic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;312&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lOIP_Z_-0Hs?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The video is part two of a three-part series, part one is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ahXIMUkSXX0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew about that trick because it’s useful in procedural content generation: Any time that you want something to look randomly distributed, but you want to be sure that there are no clusters, you should at least try to see if you can use the golden ratio for that. (if that doesn’t work, Halton Sequences are also worth trying before you try random numbers) But somehow it had never occurred to me to use the same trick for hash tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s the idea: Let’s say our hash table is 1024 slots large, and we want to map an arbitrarily large hash value into that range. The first thing we do is we map it using the above trick into the full 64 bit range of numbers. So we multiply the incoming hash value with &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=2%5E%7B64%7D%2F%5Cphi+%5Capprox+11400714819323198485&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;2^{64}/\phi \approx 11400714819323198485&quot; title=&quot;2^{64}/\phi \approx 11400714819323198485&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;. (the number 11400714819323198486 is closer but we don’t want multiples of two because that would throw away one bit) Multiplying with that number will overflow, but just as we wrapped around the circle in the flower example above, this will wrap around the whole 64 bit range in a nice pattern, giving us an even distribution across the whole range from &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=0&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;0&quot; title=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; to &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=2%5E%7B64%7D&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;2^{64}&quot; title=&quot;2^{64}&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;. To illustrate, let’s just look at the upper three bits. So we’ll do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: cpp; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
size_t fibonacci_hash_3_bits(size_t hash)
{
    return (hash * 11400714819323198485llu) &amp;gt;&amp;gt; 61;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will return the upper three bits after doing the multiplication with the magic constant. And we’re looking at just three bits because it’s easy to see how the golden ratio wraparound behaves when we just look at the top three bits. If we pass in some small numbers for the hash value, we get the following results from this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(0) == 0&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(1) == 4&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(2) == 1&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(3) == 6&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(4) == 3&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(5) == 0&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(6) == 5&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(7) == 2&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(8) == 7&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(9) == 4&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(10) == 1&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(11) == 6&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(12) == 3&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(13) == 0&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(14) == 5&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(15) == 2&lt;br/&gt;fibonacci_hash_3_bits(16) == 7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives a pretty even distribution: The number 0 comes up three times, all other numbers come up twice. And every number is far removed from the previous and the next number. If we increase the input by one, the output jumps around quite a bit. So this is starting to look like a good hash function. And also a good way to map a number from a larger range into the range from 0 to 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact we already have the whole algorithm right here. All we have to do to get an arbitrary power of two range is to change the shift amount. So if my hash table is size 1024, then instead of just looking at the top 3 bits I want to look at the top 10 bits. So I shift by 54 instead of 61. Easy enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if you actually run a full hash function analysis on this, you find that it doesn’t make for a great hash function. It’s not terrible, but you will quickly find patterns. But if we make a hash table with a STL-style interface, we don’t control the hash function anyway. The hash function is being provided by the user. So we will just use Fibonacci hashing to map the result of the hash function into the range that we want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The problems with integer modulo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why is integer modulo bad anyways? Two reasons: 1. It’s slow. 2. It can be real stupid about patterns in the input data. So first of all how slow is integer modulo? If you’re just doing the straightforward implementation like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: cpp; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
size_t hash_to_slot(size_t hash, size_t num_slots)
{
    return hash % num_slots;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then this is real slow. It takes roughly 9 nanoseconds on my machine. Which, if the hash table is in cache, is about five times longer than the rest of the lookup takes. If you get cache misses then those dominate, but it’s not good that this integer modulo is making our lookups several times slower when the table is in cache. Still the GCC, LLVM and boost implementations of unordered_map use this code to map the hash value to a slot in the table. And they are really slow because of this. The Dinkumware implementation is a little bit smarter: It takes advantage of the fact that when the table is sized to be a power of two, you can do an integer modulo by using a binary and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: cpp; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
size_t hash_to_slot(size_t hash, size_t num_slots_minus_one)
{
    return hash &amp;amp; num_slots_minus_one;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which takes roughly 0 nanoseconds on my machine. Since num_slots is a power of two, this just chops off all the upper bits and only keeps the lower bits. So in order to use this you have to be certain that all the important information is in the lower bits. Dinkumware ensures this by using a more complicated hash function than the other implementations use: For integers it uses a FNV1 hash. It’s much faster than a integer modulo, but it still makes your hash table twice as slow as it could be since FNV1 is expensive. And there is a bigger problem: If you provide your own hash function because you want to insert a custom type into the hash table, you have to know about this implementation detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been bitten by that implementation detail several times at work. For example we had a custom ID type that’s just a wrapper around a 64 bit integer which is composed from several sources of information. And it just so happens that that ID type has really important information in the upper bits. It took surprisingly long until someone noticed that we had a slow hash table in our codebase that could literally be made a hundred times faster just by changing the order of the bits in the hash function, because the integer modulo was chopping off the upper bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other tables, like google::dense_hash_map also use a power of two hash size to get the fast integer modulo, but it doesn’t provide it’s own implementation of std::hash&amp;lt;int&amp;gt; (because it can’t) so you have to be real careful about your upper bits when using dense_hash_map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about google::dense_hash_map, integer modulo brings even more problems with it for open addressing tables it. Because if you store all your data in one array, patterns in the input data suddenly start to matter more. For example google::dense_hash_map gets really, really slow if you ever insert a lot of sequential numbers. Because all those sequential numbers get assigned slots right next to each other, and if you’re then trying to look up a key that’s not in the table, you have to probe through a lot of densely occupied slots before you find your first empty slot. You will never notice this if you only look up keys that are actually in the map, but unsuccessful lookups can be dozens of times slower than they should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these flaws, all of the fastest hash table implementations use the “binary and” approach to assign a hash value to a slot. And then you usually try to compensate for the problems by using a more complicated hash function, like FNV1 in the Dinkumware implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Fibonacci Hashing is the Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fibonacci hashing solves both of these problems. 1. It’s really fast. It’s a integer multiplication followed by a shift. It takes roughly 1.5 nanoseconds on my machine, which is fast enough that it’s getting real hard to measure. 2. It mixes up input patterns. It’s like you’re getting a second hashing step for free after the first hash function finishes. If the first hash function is actually just the identity function (as it should be for integers) then this gives you at least a little bit of mixing that you wouldn’t otherwise get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But really it’s better because it’s faster. When I worked on hash tables I was always frustrated by how much time we are spending on the simple problem of “map a large number to a small number.” It’s literally the slowest operation in the hash table. (outside of cache misses of course, but let’s pretend you’re doing several lookups in a row and the table is cached) And the only alternative was the “power of two binary and” version which discards bits from the hash function and can lead to all kinds of problems. So your options are either slow and safe, or fast and losing bits and getting potentially many hash collisions if you’re ever not careful. And everybody had this problem. I googled a lot for this problem thinking “surely somebody must have a good method for bringing a large number into a small range” but everybody was either doing slow or bad things. For example &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lemire/fastrange&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is an approach (called “fastrange”) that almost re-invents Fibonacci hashing, but it exaggerates patterns where Fibonacci hashing breaks up patterns. It’s the same speed as Fibonacci hashing, but when I’ve tried to use it, it never worked for me because I would suddenly find patterns in my hash function that I wasn’t even aware of. (and with fastrange your subtle patterns suddenly get exaggerated to be huge problems) Despite its problems it is being used in Tensorflow, because everybody is desperate for a faster solution of this the problem of mapping a large number into a small range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If Fibonacci Hashing is so great, why is nobody using it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a tricky question because there is so little information about Fibonacci hashing on the Internet, but I think it has to do with a historical misunderstanding. In The Art of Computer Programming, Knuth introduces three hash functions to use for hash tables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Integer Modulo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fibonacci Hashing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something related to CRC hashes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inclusion of the integer modulo in this list is a bit weird from today’s perspective because it’s not much of a hash function. It just maps from a larger range into a smaller range, and doesn’t otherwise do anything. Fibonacci hashing is actually a hash function, not the greatest hash function, but it’s a good introduction. And the third one is too complicated for me to understand. It’s something about coming up with good coefficients for a CRC hash that has certain properties about avoiding collisions in hash tables. Probably very clever, but somebody else has to figure that one out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s happening here is that Knuth uses the term “hash function” differently than we use it today.  Today the steps in a hash table are something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hash the key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map the hash value to a slot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the item in the slot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it’s not the right item, repeat step 3 with a different item until the right one is found or some end condition is met&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use the term “hash function” to refer to step 1. But Knuth uses the term “hash function” to refer to something that does both step 1 and step 2. So when he refers to a hash function, he means something that both hashes the incoming key, and assigns it to a slot in the table. So if the table is only 1024 items large, the hash function can only return a value from 0 to 1023. This explains why “integer modulo” is a hash function for Knuth: It doesn’t do anything in step 1, but it does work well for step 2. So if those two steps were just one step, then integer modulo does a good job at that one step since it does a good job at our step 2. But when we take it apart like that, we’ll see that Fibonacci Hashing is an improvement compared to integer modulo in both steps. And since we’re only using it for step 2, it allows us to use a faster implementation for step 1 because the hash function gets some help from the additional mixing that Fibonacci hashing does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this difference in terms, where Knuth uses “hash function” to mean something different than “hash function” means for std::unordered_map, explains to me why nobody is using Fibonacci hashing. When judged as a “hash function” in today’s terms, it’s not that great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I found that Fibonacci hashing is not mentioned anywhere, I did more googling and was more successful searching for “multiplicative hashing.” Fibonacci hashing is just a simple multiplicative hash with a well-chosen magic number. But the language that I found describing multiplicative hashing explains why nobody is using this. For example Wikipedia has &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_function#Multiplicative_hashing&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; to say about multiplicative hashing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiplicative hashing is a simple type of hash function often used by teachers introducing students to hash tables. Multiplicative hash functions are simple and fast, but have higher collision rates in hash tables than more sophisticated hash functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So just from that, I certainly don’t feel encouraged to check out what this “multiplicative hashing” is. Or to get a feeling for how teachers introduce this, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0M_kIqhwbFo&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is MIT instructor Erik Demaine (who’s videos I very much recommend) introducing hash functions, and he says this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to give you three hash functions. Two of which are, let’s say common practice, and the third of which is actually theoretically good. So the first two are not good theoretically, you can prove that they’re bad, but at least they give you some flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he talks about integer modulo, multiplicative hashing, and a combination of the two. He doesn’t mention the Fibonacci hashing version of multiplicative hashing, and the introduction probably wouldn’t inspire people to go seek out more information it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think people just learn that multiplicative hashing is not a good hash function, and they never learn that multiplicative hashing is a great way to map large values into a small range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course it could also be that I missed some unknown big downside to Fibonacci hashing and that there is a real good reason why nobody is using this, but I didn’t find anything like that. But it could be that I didn’t find anything bad about Fibonacci hashing simply because it’s hard to find anything at all about Fibonacci hashing, so let’s do our own analysis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analyzing Fibonacci Hashing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have to confess that I don’t know much about analyzing hash functions. It seems like the best test is to see how close a hash function gets to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avalanche_effect&quot;&gt;strict avalanche criterion&lt;/a&gt; which “is satisfied if, whenever a single input bit is changed, each of the output bits changes with a 50% probability.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To measure that I wrote a small program that takes a hash &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=H&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;H&quot; title=&quot;H&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;, and runs it through Fibonacci hashing to get a slot in the hash table &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=S&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;S&quot; title=&quot;S&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;. Then I change a single bit in &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=H&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;H&quot; title=&quot;H&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;, giving me &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=H%27&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;H'&quot; title=&quot;H'&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;, and after I run that through Fibonacci hashing I get a slot &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=S%27&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;S'&quot; title=&quot;S'&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;. Then I measure depending on which bit I changed in &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=H%27&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;H'&quot; title=&quot;H'&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;, which bits are likely to change in &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=S%27&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;S'&quot; title=&quot;S'&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; compared to &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=S&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;S&quot; title=&quot;S&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; and which bits are unlikely to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then run that same test every time after I doubled a hash table, because with different size hash tables there are more bits in the output: If the hash table only has four slots, there are only two bits in the output. If the hash table has 1024 slots, there are ten bits in the output. Finally I color code the result and plot the whole thing as a picture that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;9634&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://probablydance.com/2018/06/16/fibonacci-hashing-the-optimization-that-the-world-forgot-or-a-better-alternative-to-integer-modulo/avalanche_fibonacci/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibonacci1.png?w=650&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1100,256&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Avalanche_fibonacci&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibonacci1.png?w=650?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibonacci1.png?w=650?w=650&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-9634&quot; src=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibonacci1.png?w=650&quot; alt=&quot;Avalanche_fibonacci.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibonacci1.png?w=650 650w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibonacci1.png?w=150 150w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibonacci1.png?w=300 300w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibonacci1.png?w=768 768w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibonacci1.png?w=1024 1024w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibonacci1.png 1100w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain this picture. Each row of pixels represents one of the 64 bits of the input hash. The bottom-most row is the first bit, the topmost row is the 64th bit. Each column represents one bit in the output. The first two columns are the output bits for a table of size 4, the next three columns are the output bits for a table of size 8 etc. until the last 23 bits are for a table of size eight million. The color coding means this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A black pixel indicates that when the input pixel for that row changes, the output pixel for that column has a 50% chance of changing. (this is ideal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A blue pixel means that when the input pixel changes, the ouput pixel has a 100% chance of changing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A red pixel means that when the input pixel changes, the output pixel has a 0% chance of changing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a really good hash function the entire picture would be black. So Fibonacci hashing is not a really good hash function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst pattern we can see is at the top of the picture: The last bit of the input hash (the top row in the picture) can always only affect the last bit of the output slot in the table. (the last column of each section) So if the table has 1024 slots, the last bit of the input hash can only determine the bit in the output slot for the number 512. It will never change any other bit in the output. Lower bits in the input can affect more bits in the output, so there is more mixing going on for those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it bad that the last bit in the input can only affect one bit in the output? It would be bad if we used this as a hash function, but it’s not necessarily bad if we just use this to map from a large range into a small range. Since each row has at least one blue or black pixel in it, we can be certain that we don’t lose information, since every bit from the input will be used. What would be bad for mapping from a large range into a small range is if we had a row or a column that has only red pixels in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s also look at what this would look like for integer modulo, starting with integer modulo using prime numbers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;9635&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://probablydance.com/2018/06/16/fibonacci-hashing-the-optimization-that-the-world-forgot-or-a-better-alternative-to-integer-modulo/avalanche_prime/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png?w=650&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1188,256&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Avalanche_prime&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png?w=650?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png?w=650?w=650&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-9635&quot; src=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png?w=650&quot; alt=&quot;Avalanche_prime.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png?w=650 650w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png?w=150 150w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png?w=300 300w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png?w=768 768w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png?w=1024 1024w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png 1188w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one has more randomness at the top, but a clearer pattern at the bottom. All that red means that the first few bits in the input hash can only determine the first few bits in the output hash. Which makes sense for integer modulo. A small number modulo a large number will never result in a large number, so a change to a small number can never affect the later bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture is still “good” for mapping from a large range into a small range because we have that diagonal line of bright blue pixels in each block. To show a bad function, here is integer modulo with a power of two size:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;9636&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://probablydance.com/2018/06/16/fibonacci-hashing-the-optimization-that-the-world-forgot-or-a-better-alternative-to-integer-modulo/avalanche_power_of_two/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_power_of_two1.png?w=650&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1100,256&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Avalanche_power_of_two&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_power_of_two1.png?w=650?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_power_of_two1.png?w=650?w=650&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-9636&quot; src=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_power_of_two1.png?w=650&quot; alt=&quot;Avalanche_power_of_two.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_power_of_two1.png?w=650 650w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_power_of_two1.png?w=150 150w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_power_of_two1.png?w=300 300w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_power_of_two1.png?w=768 768w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_power_of_two1.png?w=1024 1024w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_power_of_two1.png 1100w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is obviously bad: The upper bits of the hash value have completely red rows, because they will simply get chopped off. Only the lower bits of the input have any effect, and they can only affect their own bits in the output. This picture right here shows why using a power of two size requires that you are careful with your choice of hash function for the hash table: If those red rows represent important bits, you will simply lose them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally let’s also look at the “fastrange” algorithm that I briefly mentioned above. For power of two sizes it looks really bad, so let me show you what it looks like for prime sizes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;9637&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://probablydance.com/2018/06/16/fibonacci-hashing-the-optimization-that-the-world-forgot-or-a-better-alternative-to-integer-modulo/avalanche_fastrange_prime/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fastrange_prime.png?w=650&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1188,256&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Avalanche_fastrange_prime&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fastrange_prime.png?w=650?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fastrange_prime.png?w=650?w=650&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-9637&quot; src=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fastrange_prime.png?w=650&quot; alt=&quot;Avalanche_fastrange_prime.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fastrange_prime.png?w=650 650w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fastrange_prime.png?w=150 150w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fastrange_prime.png?w=300 300w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fastrange_prime.png?w=768 768w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fastrange_prime.png?w=1024 1024w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fastrange_prime.png 1188w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we see here is that fastrange throws away the lower bits of the input range. It only uses the upper bits. I had used it before and I had noticed that a change in the lower bits doesn’t seem to make much of a difference, but I had never realized that it just completely throws the lower bits away. This picture totally explains why I had so many problems with fastrange. Fastrange is a bad function to map from a large range into a small range because it’s throwing away the lower bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back to Fibonacci hashing, there is actually one simple change you can make to improve the bad pattern for the top bits: Shift the top bits down and xor them once. So the code changes to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: cpp; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
size_t index_for_hash(size_t hash)
{
    hash ^= hash &amp;gt;&amp;gt; shift_amount;
    return (11400714819323198485llu * hash) &amp;gt;&amp;gt; shift_amount;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s almost looking more like a proper hash function, isn’t it? This makes the function two cycles slower, but it gives us the following picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;9640&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://probablydance.com/2018/06/16/fibonacci-hashing-the-optimization-that-the-world-forgot-or-a-better-alternative-to-integer-modulo/avalanche_fibxor/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibxor.png?w=650&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1100,256&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Avalanche_fibxor&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibxor.png?w=650?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibxor.png?w=650?w=650&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-9640&quot; src=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibxor.png?w=650&quot; alt=&quot;Avalanche_fibxor&quot; srcset=&quot;https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibxor.png?w=650 650w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibxor.png?w=150 150w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibxor.png?w=300 300w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibxor.png?w=768 768w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibxor.png?w=1024 1024w, https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_fibxor.png 1100w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks a bit nicer, with the problematic pattern at the top gone. (and we’re seeing more black pixels now which is the ideal for a hash function) I’m not using this though because we don’t really need a good hash function, we need a good function to map from a large range into a small range. And this is on the critical path for the hash table, before we can even do the first comparison. Any cycle added here makes the whole line in the graph above move up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I keep on saying that we need a good function to map from a large range into a small range, but I haven’t defined what “good” means there. I don’t know of a proper test like the avalanche analysis for hash functions, but my first attempt at a definition for “good” would be that every value in the smaller range is equally likely to occur. That test is very easy to fulfill though: all of the methods (including fastrange) fulfill that criteria. So how about we pick a sequence of values in the input range and check if every value in the output is equally likely. I had given the examples for numbers 0 to 16 above. We could also do multiples of 8 or all powers of two or all prime numbers or the Fibonacci numbers. Or let’s just try as many sequences as possible until we figure out the behavior of the function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the above list we see that there might be a problematic pattern with multiples of 4: fibonacci_hash_3_bits(4) returned 3, for fibonacci_hash_3_bits(8) returned 7, fibonacci_hash_3_bits(12) returned 3 again and fibonacci_hash_3_bits(16) returned 7 again. Let’s see how this develops if we print the first sixteen multiples of four:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;4 -&amp;gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;8 -&amp;gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;12 -&amp;gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;16 -&amp;gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;20 -&amp;gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;24 -&amp;gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;28 -&amp;gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;32 -&amp;gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;36 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;40 -&amp;gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;44 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;48 -&amp;gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;52 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;56 -&amp;gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;60 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;64 -&amp;gt; 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn’t look too bad actually: Every number shows up twice, except the number 1 shows up three times. What about multiples of eight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;8 -&amp;gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;16 -&amp;gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;24 -&amp;gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;32 -&amp;gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;40 -&amp;gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;48 -&amp;gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;56 -&amp;gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;64 -&amp;gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;72 -&amp;gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;80 -&amp;gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;88 -&amp;gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;96 -&amp;gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;104 -&amp;gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;112 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;120 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;128 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again doesn’t look too bad, but we are definitely getting more repeated numbers. So how about multiples of sixteen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;16 -&amp;gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;32 -&amp;gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;48 -&amp;gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;64 -&amp;gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;80 -&amp;gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;96 -&amp;gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;112 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;128 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;144 -&amp;gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;160 -&amp;gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;176 -&amp;gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;192 -&amp;gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;208 -&amp;gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;224 -&amp;gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;240 -&amp;gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;256 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks a bit better again, and if we were to look at multiples of 32 it would look better still. The reason why the number 8 was starting to look problematic was not because it’s a power of two. It was starting to look problematic because it is a Fibonacci number. If we look at later Fibonacci numbers, we see more problematic patterns. For example here are multiples of 34:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;34 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;68 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;102 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;136 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;170 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;204 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;238 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;272 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;306 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;340 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;374 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;408 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;442 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;476 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;510 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;544 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s looking bad. And later Fibonacci numbers will only look worse. But then again how often are you going to insert multiples of 34 into a hash table? In fact if you had to pick a group of numbers that’s going to give you problems, the Fibonacci numbers are not the worst choice because they don’t come up that often naturally. As a reminder, here are the first couple Fibonacci numbers: 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, 34, 55, 89, 144, 233, 377, 610, 987, 1597, 2584… The first couple numbers don’t give us bad patterns in the output, but anything bigger than 13 does. And most of those are pretty harmless: I can’t think of any case that would give out multiples of those numbers. 144 bothers me a little bit because it’s a multiple of 8 and you might have a struct of that size, but even then your pointers will just be eight byte aligned, so you’d have to get unlucky for all your pointers to be multiples of 144.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But really what you do here is that you identify the bad pattern and you tell your users “if you ever hit this bad pattern, provide a custom hash function to the hash table that fixes it.” I mean people are happy to use integer modulo with powers of two, and for that it’s ridiculously easy to find bad patterns: Normal pointers are a bad pattern for that. Since it’s harder to come up with use cases that spit out lots of multiples of Fibonacci numbers, I’m fine with having “multiples of Fibonacci numbers” as bad patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are Fibonacci numbers a bad pattern for Fibonacci hashing anyways? It’s not obvious if we just have the magic number multiplication and the bit shift. First of all we have to remember that the magic constant came from dividing by the golden ratio: &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=2%5E%7B64%7D%2F%5Cphi+%5Capprox+11400714819323198485&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;2^{64}/\phi \approx 11400714819323198485&quot; title=&quot;2^{64}/\phi \approx 11400714819323198485&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;. And then since we are truncating the result of the multiplication before we shift it, there is actually a hidden modulo by &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=2%5E%7B64%7D&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;2^{64}&quot; title=&quot;2^{64}&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; in there. So whenever we are hashing a number &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=x&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;x&quot; title=&quot;x&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; the slot is actually determined by this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=slot%5C_before%5C_shift%28x%29+%3D+%28x+%2A+2%5E%7B64%7D%2F%5Cphi%29+%5C%25+2%5E%7B64%7D&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;slot\_before\_shift(x) = (x * 2^{64}/\phi) \% 2^{64}&quot; title=&quot;slot\_before\_shift(x) = (x * 2^{64}/\phi) \% 2^{64}&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m leaving out the shift at the end because that part doesn’t matter for figuring out why Fibonacci numbers are giving us problems. In the example of stepping around a circle (from the Vi Hart video above) the equation would look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=angle%5C_for%5C_leaf%28x%29+%3D+%28x+%2A+360%2F%5Cphi%29+%5C%25+360&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;angle\_for\_leaf(x) = (x * 360/\phi) \% 360&quot; title=&quot;angle\_for\_leaf(x) = (x * 360/\phi) \% 360&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would give us an angle from 0 to 360. These functions are obviously similar. We just replaced &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=2%5E%7B64%7D&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;2^{64}&quot; title=&quot;2^{64}&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; with &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=360&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;360&quot; title=&quot;360&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;. So while we’re in math-land with infinite precision, we might as well make the function return something in the range from 0 to 1, and then multiply the constant in afterwards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=hash%5C_0%5C_to%5C_1%28x%29+%3D+frac%28x%2F%5Cphi%29&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;hash\_0\_to\_1(x) = frac(x/\phi)&quot; title=&quot;hash\_0\_to\_1(x) = frac(x/\phi)&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=frax%28x%29&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;frax(x)&quot; title=&quot;frax(x)&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; returns the fractional part of a number. So &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=frax%281.1%29+%3D+0.1&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;frax(1.1) = 0.1&quot; title=&quot;frax(1.1) = 0.1&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;. In this last formulation it’s easy to find out why Fibonacci numbers give us problems. Let’s try putting in a few Fibonacci numbers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=hash%5C_0%5C_to%5C_1%28144%29+%3D+frac%28144%2F%5Cphi%29+%5Capprox+frac%2889%29+%3D+0&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;hash\_0\_to\_1(144) = frac(144/\phi) \approx frac(89) = 0&quot; title=&quot;hash\_0\_to\_1(144) = frac(144/\phi) \approx frac(89) = 0&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=hash%5C_0%5C_to%5C_1%281587%29+%3D+frac%281597%2F%5Cphi%29+%5Capprox+frac%28987%29+%3D+0&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;hash\_0\_to\_1(1587) = frac(1597/\phi) \approx frac(987) = 0&quot; title=&quot;hash\_0\_to\_1(1587) = frac(1597/\phi) \approx frac(987) = 0&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=hash%5C_0%5C_to%5C_1%288%29+%3D+frac%288%2F%5Cphi%29+%5Capprox+frac%284.94%29+%3D+0.94&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;hash\_0\_to\_1(8) = frac(8/\phi) \approx frac(4.94) = 0.94&quot; title=&quot;hash\_0\_to\_1(8) = frac(8/\phi) \approx frac(4.94) = 0.94&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we see here is that if we divide a Fibonacci number by the golden ratio, we just get the previous Fibonacci number. There is no fractional part so we always end up with 0. So even if we multiply the full range of &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=2%5E%7B64%7D&amp;amp;bg=fff&amp;amp;fg=444444&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;2^{64}&quot; title=&quot;2^{64}&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; back in, we still get 0. But for smaller Fibonacci numbers there is some imprecision because the Fibonacci sequence is just an integer approximation of golden ratio growth. That approximation gets more exact the further along we get into the sequence, but for the number 8 it’s not that exact. That’s why 8 was not a problem, 34 started to look problematic, and 144 is going to be real bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except that when we talk about badness, we also have to consider the size of the hash table. It’s really easy to find bad patterns when the table only has eight slots. If the table is bigger and has, say 64 slots, suddenly multiples of 34 don’t look as bad:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;34 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;68 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br/&gt;102 -&amp;gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;136 -&amp;gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;170 -&amp;gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;204 -&amp;gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;238 -&amp;gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;272 -&amp;gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;306 -&amp;gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;340 -&amp;gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;374 -&amp;gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;408 -&amp;gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;442 -&amp;gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;476 -&amp;gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;510 -&amp;gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;544 -&amp;gt; 13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if the table has 1024 slots we get all the multiples nicely spread out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;34 -&amp;gt; 13&lt;br/&gt;68 -&amp;gt; 26&lt;br/&gt;102 -&amp;gt; 40&lt;br/&gt;136 -&amp;gt; 53&lt;br/&gt;170 -&amp;gt; 67&lt;br/&gt;204 -&amp;gt; 80&lt;br/&gt;238 -&amp;gt; 94&lt;br/&gt;272 -&amp;gt; 107&lt;br/&gt;306 -&amp;gt; 121&lt;br/&gt;340 -&amp;gt; 134&lt;br/&gt;374 -&amp;gt; 148&lt;br/&gt;408 -&amp;gt; 161&lt;br/&gt;442 -&amp;gt; 175&lt;br/&gt;476 -&amp;gt; 188&lt;br/&gt;510 -&amp;gt; 202&lt;br/&gt;544 -&amp;gt; 215&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At size 1024 even the multiples of 144 don’t look scary any more because they’re starting to be spread out now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;144 -&amp;gt; 1020&lt;br/&gt;288 -&amp;gt; 1017&lt;br/&gt;432 -&amp;gt; 1014&lt;br/&gt;576 -&amp;gt; 1011&lt;br/&gt;720 -&amp;gt; 1008&lt;br/&gt;864 -&amp;gt; 1004&lt;br/&gt;1008 -&amp;gt; 1001&lt;br/&gt;1152 -&amp;gt; 998&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the bad pattern of multiples of Fibonacci numbers goes away with bigger hash tables. Because Fibonacci hashing spreads out the numbers, and the bigger the table is, the better it gets at that. This doesn’t help you if your hash table is small, or if you need to insert multiples of a larger Fibonacci number, but it does give me confidence that this “bad pattern” is something we can live with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I am OK with living with the bad pattern of Fibonacci hashing. It’s less bad than making the hash table a power of two size. It can be slightly more bad than using prime number sizes, as long as your prime numbers are well chosen. But I still think that on average Fibonacci hashing is better than prime number sized integer modulo, because Fibonacci hashing mixes up sequential numbers. So it fixes a real problem I have run into in the past while introducing a theoretical problem that I am struggling to find real examples for. I think that’s a good trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also prime number integer modulo can have problems if you choose bad prime numbers. For example boost::unordered_map can choose size 196613, which is 0b110000000000000101 in binary, which is a pretty round number in the same way that 15000005 is a pretty round number in decimal. Since this prime number is “too round of a number” this causes lots of hash collisions in one of my benchmarks, and I didn’t set that benchmark up to find bad cases like this. It was totally accidental and took lots of debugging to figure out why boost::unordered_map does so badly in that benchmark. (the benchmark in question was set up to find problems with sequential numbers) But I won’t go into that and will just say that while prime numbers give fewer problematic patterns than Fibonacci hashing, you still have to choose them well to avoid introducing hash collisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fibonacci hashing may not be the best hash function, but I think it’s the best way to map from a large range of numbers into a small range of numbers. And we are only using it for that. When used only for that part of the hash table, we have to compare it against two existing approaches: Integer modulo with prime numbers and Integer modulo with power of two sizes. It’s almost as fast as the power of two size, but it introduces far fewer problems because it doesn’t discard any bits. It’s much faster than the prime number size, and it also gives us the bonus of breaking up sequential numbers, which can be a big benefit for open addressing hash tables. It does introduce a new problem of having problems with multiples of large Fibonacci numbers in small hash tables, but I think those problems can be solved by using a custom hash function when you encounter them. Experience will tell how often we will have to use this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of my hash tables now use Fibonacci hashing by default. For my flat_hash_map the property of breaking up sequential numbers is particularly important because I have had real problems caused by sequential numbers. For the others it’s just a faster default. It might almost make the option to use the power of two integer modulo unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s surprising that the world forgot about this optimization and that we’re all using primer number sized hash tables instead. (or use Dinkumware’s solution which uses a power of two integer modulo, but spends more time on the hash function to make up for the problems of the power of two integer modulo) Thanks to Rich Geldreich for writing a hash table that uses this optimization and for mentioning it in my comments. But this is an interesting example because academia had a solution to a real problem in existing hash tables, but professors didn’t realize that they did. The most likely reason for that is that it’s not well known how big the problem of “mapping a large number into a small range” is and how much time it takes to do an integer modulo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For future work it might be worth looking into Knuth’s third hash function: The one that’s related to CRC hashes. It seems to be a way to construct a good CRC hash function if you need a n-bit output for a hash table. But it was too complicated for me to look into, so I’ll leave that as an exercise to the reader to find out if that one is worth using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/skarupke/flat_hash_map/blob/master/unordered_map.hpp&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is the link to my implementation of unordered_map. My other two hash tables are also there: flat_hash_map has very fast lookups and bytell_hash_map is also very fast but was designed more to save memory compared to flat_hash_map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-22872755-9623-5b26f52d431f3&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20180319#blog_id=22872755&amp;amp;post_id=9623&amp;amp;origin=probablydance.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=22872755-9623-5b26f52d431f3&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-22872755-9623-5b26f52d431f3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 18:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Fibonacci Hashing: The Optimization that the World Forgot (or: a Better Alternative to Integer Modulo)</og:title>
<og:url>https://probablydance.com/2018/06/16/fibonacci-hashing-the-optimization-that-the-world-forgot-or-a-better-alternative-to-integer-modulo/</og:url>
<og:description>I recently posted a blog post about a new hash table, and whenever I do something like that, I learn at least one new thing from my comments. In my last comment section Rich Geldreich talks about h…</og:description>
<og:image>https://probablydance.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/avalanche_prime1.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://probablydance.com/2018/06/16/fibonacci-hashing-the-optimization-that-the-world-forgot-or-a-better-alternative-to-integer-modulo/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The “Doorway Effect” – forgetting why you entered a room</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20160307-why-does-walking-through-doorways-make-us-forget</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20160307-why-does-walking-through-doorways-make-us-forget</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve all done it. Run upstairs to get your keys, but forget that it is them you’re looking for once you get to the bedroom. Open the fridge door and reach for the middle shelf only to realise that we can't remember why we opened the fridge in the first place. Or wait for a moment to interrupt a friend to find that the burning issue that made us want to interrupt has now vanished from our minds just as we come to speak: “What did I want to say again?” we ask a confused audience, who all think “how should we know?!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt; We can appreciate those temporary moments of forgetfulness may be more than just an annoyance &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although these errors can be embarrassing, they are also common. It’s known as the “Doorway Effect”, and it reveals some important features of how our minds are organised. Understanding this might help us appreciate those temporary moments of forgetfulness as more than just an annoyance (although they will still be annoying).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These features of our minds are perhaps best illustrated by a story about a woman who meets three builders on their lunch break. “What are you doing today?” she asks the first. “I’m putting brick after sodding brick on top of another,” sighs the first. “What are you doing today?” she asks the second. “I’m building a wall,” is the simple reply. But the third builder swells with pride when asked, and replies: “I’m building a cathedral!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe you heard that story as encouragement to think of the big picture, but to the psychologist in you the important moral is that any action has to be thought of at multiple levels if you are going to carry it out successfully. The third builder might have the most inspiring view of their day-job, but nobody can build a cathedral without figuring out how to successfully put one brick on top of another like the first builder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we move through our days our attention shifts between these levels – from our goals and ambitions, to plans and strategies, and to the lowest levels, our concrete actions. When things are going well, often in familiar situations, we keep our attention on what we want and how we do it seems to take care of itself. If you’re a skilled driver then you manage the gears, indicators and wheel automatically, and your attention is probably caught up in the less routine business of navigating the traffic or talking to your passengers. When things are less routine we have to shift our attention to the details of what we’re doing, taking our minds off the bigger picture for a moment. Hence the pause in conversation as the driver gets to a tricky junction, or the engine starts to make a funny sound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The way our attention moves up and down the hierarchy of action is what allows us to carry out complex behaviours, stitching together a coherent plan over multiple moments, in multiple places or requiring multiple actions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Doorway Effect occurs when our attention moves between levels, and it reflects the reliance of our memories – even memories for what we were about to do – on the environment we’re in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine that we’re going upstairs to get our keys and forget that it is the keys we came for as soon as we enter the bedroom. Psychologically, what has happened is that the plan (“Keys!”) has been forgotten even in the middle of implementing a necessary part of the strategy (“Go to bedroom!”). Probably the plan itself is part of a larger plan (“Get ready to leave the house!”), which is part of plans on a wider and wider scale (“Go to work!”, “Keep my job!”, “Be a productive and responsible citizen”, or whatever). Each scale requires attention at some point. Somewhere in navigating this complex hierarchy the need for keys popped into mind, and like a circus performer setting plates spinning on poles, your attention focussed on it long enough to construct a plan, but then moved on to the next plate (this time, either walking to the bedroom, or wondering who left their clothes on the stairs again, or what you’re going to do when you get to work or one of a million other things that it takes to build a life).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And sometimes spinning plates fall. Our memories, even for our goals, are embedded in webs of associations. That can be the physical environment in which we form them, which is why revisiting our childhood home can bring back a flood of previously forgotten memories, or it can be the mental environment – the set of things we were just thinking about when that thing popped into mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Doorway Effect occurs because &lt;a href=&quot;http://digest.bps.org.uk/2011/11/how-walking-through-doorway-increases.html&quot;&gt;we change both the physical and mental environments&lt;/a&gt;, moving to a different room and thinking about different things. That hastily thought up goal, which was probably only one plate among the many we’re trying to spin, gets forgotten when the context changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a window into how we manage to coordinate complex actions, matching plans with actions in a way that – most of the time – allows us to put the right bricks in the right place to build the cathedral of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have an everyday psychological phenomenon you'd like to see written about in these columns please get in touch with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomstafford&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;@tomstafford&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter, or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ideas@idiolect.org.uk&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ideas@idiolect.org.uk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join 500,000+ Future fans by liking us on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BBCFuture&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, or follow us on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bbc_future&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/107828172298602173375/posts&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google+&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/bbc-com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/bbcfuture_official/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instagram&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you liked this story, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.emails.bbc.com/subscribe/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;sign up for the weekly bbc.com features newsletter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, called “If You Only Read 6 Things This Week”. A handpicked selection of stories from BBC Future, Earth, Culture, Capital, Travel and Autos, delivered to your inbox every Friday.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        </description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 18:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edwinksl</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why does walking through doorways make us forget?</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20160307-why-does-walking-through-doorways-make-us-forget</og:url>
<og:description>Forgetting why you entered a room is called the “Doorway Effect”, and it may reveal as much about the strengths of human memory, as it does the weaknesses.</og:description>
<og:image>http://ichef.bbci.co.uk/wwfeatures/live/624_351/images/live/p0/3l/td/p03ltdj1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20160307-why-does-walking-through-doorways-make-us-forget</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Berlin-Munich high-speed train services carry 2M passengers in first six months</title>
<link>https://www.railjournal.com/index.php/high-speed/berlin-munich-hs-services-carry-2-million-passengers-in-first-six-moths.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.railjournal.com/index.php/high-speed/berlin-munich-hs-services-carry-2-million-passengers-in-first-six-moths.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TWO million passengers have used German Rail’s (DB) Berlin - Munich high-speed line within six months of the opening of the final section of the line, more than double the amount traveling on the old line during the same period last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;57&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;DB says it sells an average of 15,000 tickets a day for the connections along the 623km route, and had already doubled the number of advance tickets for the summer holidays during July and August, which usually have weak demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From December, DB will add two more Sprinter limited-stop trains taking DB’s connections to five a day each way, providing 23,000 seats between Berlin and Munich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also announced it will double the number of seats on two weekend services between the cities from June 30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will also offer a new direct train on the Berlin - Halle - Nuremberg - Vienna route from December, the first international service on the new Erfurt - Ebensfeld line which will reduce the time to Vienna by between 30 and 70 minutes. On Fridays, the train to Berlin will be extend to Rostock on the Baltic coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DB will introduce the nre ICE 4 train on the route, which allow bicycles to be taken for the first time and with 830 seats provide 10% more capacity than the previous model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 18:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:title>Berlin - Munich HS services carry 2 million passengers in first six months</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.railjournal.com/media/k2/items/cache/07f65054a1d6ebec3aa4565519d8597b_L.jpg?t=1529095906</og:image>
<og:description>TWO million passengers have used German Rail’s (DB) Berlin - Munich high-speed line within six months of the opening of the final section of the line, more than double the amount traveling on the old line during the same period last year. DB says it...</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.railjournal.com/index.php/high-speed/berlin-munich-hs-services-carry-2-million-passengers-in-first-six-moths.html</og:url>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.railjournal.com/index.php/high-speed/berlin-munich-hs-services-carry-2-million-passengers-in-first-six-moths.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Elizabeth Holmes has 200 patents – if tech didn&amp;#039;t work, why not noticed?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17328664</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17328664</guid>
<description>&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328743&quot; readability=&quot;15.697594501718&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.8487972508591&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.697594501718&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;15.697594501718&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331584&quot; readability=&quot;2.4458598726115&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2229299363057&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4458598726115&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17334096&quot; readability=&quot;3.5445544554455&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7722772277228&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5445544554455&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329099&quot; readability=&quot;3.6521739130435&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8260869565217&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6521739130435&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.6521739130435&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331088&quot; readability=&quot;7.6847826086957&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8423913043478&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6847826086957&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329438&quot; readability=&quot;4.7674418604651&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3837209302326&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.7674418604651&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328896&quot; readability=&quot;8.6623164763458&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3311582381729&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.6623164763458&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.2561174551387&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329084&quot; readability=&quot;3.6830188679245&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8415094339623&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6830188679245&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329691&quot; readability=&quot;11.761038961039&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8805194805195&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.761038961039&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.3705627705628&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331416&quot; readability=&quot;3.3986928104575&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6993464052288&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3986928104575&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329156&quot; readability=&quot;8.3653846153846&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.1826923076923&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.3653846153846&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329103&quot; readability=&quot;5.5737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7868852459016&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329142&quot; readability=&quot;4.2469135802469&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329386&quot; readability=&quot;2.6117647058824&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3058823529412&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6117647058824&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329852&quot; readability=&quot;2.6440677966102&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3220338983051&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6440677966102&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330049&quot; readability=&quot;3.6422764227642&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8211382113821&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6422764227642&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.0975609756098&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329291&quot; readability=&quot;1.5483870967742&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331818&quot; readability=&quot;2.5573770491803&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2786885245902&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5573770491803&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329248&quot; readability=&quot;2.49&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.245&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.49&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330325&quot; readability=&quot;1.921875&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329631&quot; readability=&quot;4.7286821705426&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3643410852713&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.7286821705426&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.7829457364341&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329669&quot; readability=&quot;5.5181058495822&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329854&quot; readability=&quot;5.4752851711027&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7376425855513&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4752851711027&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331034&quot; readability=&quot;8.0196428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.0098214285714&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.0196428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.9107142857143&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17332212&quot; readability=&quot;5.3707865168539&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.685393258427&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.3707865168539&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329923&quot; readability=&quot;2.6491228070175&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3245614035088&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6491228070175&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330053&quot; readability=&quot;4.553264604811&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2766323024055&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.553264604811&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.553264604811&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330404&quot; readability=&quot;3.4619883040936&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7309941520468&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4619883040936&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331408&quot; readability=&quot;1.4222222222222&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330096&quot; readability=&quot;2.4159292035398&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2079646017699&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4159292035398&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330311&quot; readability=&quot;1.1940298507463&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328870&quot; readability=&quot;11.630026809651&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8150134048257&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.630026809651&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329424&quot; readability=&quot;2.6774193548387&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3387096774194&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6774193548387&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.5698924731183&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328909&quot; readability=&quot;1.5324675324675&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329596&quot; readability=&quot;8.6101694915254&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3050847457627&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.6101694915254&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328978&quot; readability=&quot;3.4012738853503&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329059&quot; readability=&quot;14.948491537896&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.4742457689478&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;14.948491537896&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;14.508830022075&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329149&quot; readability=&quot;7.3730407523511&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6865203761755&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.3730407523511&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.5297805642633&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329876&quot; readability=&quot;1.36&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331604&quot; readability=&quot;1.3417721518987&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329606&quot; readability=&quot;1.2222222222222&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331938&quot; readability=&quot;1.1272727272727&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329809&quot; readability=&quot;2.6379310344828&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3189655172414&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6379310344828&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328877&quot; readability=&quot;4.847775175644&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.423887587822&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.847775175644&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.443793911007&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329259&quot; readability=&quot;12.703422053232&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.351711026616&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.703422053232&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;11.237642585551&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329413&quot; readability=&quot;5.4238410596026&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329108&quot; readability=&quot;10.487745098039&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.2438725490196&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.487745098039&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.0575980392157&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329300&quot; readability=&quot;8.6036697247706&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3018348623853&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.6036697247706&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.1697247706422&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330282&quot; readability=&quot;10.823179791976&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.4115898959881&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.823179791976&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.372213967311&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328797&quot; readability=&quot;9.4313725490196&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7156862745098&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.4313725490196&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.1303921568627&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329096&quot; readability=&quot;11.697699890471&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8488499452355&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.697699890471&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;14.622124863089&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329719&quot; readability=&quot;6.6876267748479&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3438133874239&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6876267748479&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.1653144016227&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329758&quot; readability=&quot;9.4949494949495&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7474747474747&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.4949494949495&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.1717171717172&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331709&quot; readability=&quot;3.4736842105263&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7368421052632&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4736842105263&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329846&quot; readability=&quot;2.5217391304348&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2608695652174&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5217391304348&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331746&quot; readability=&quot;4.359756097561&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1798780487805&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.359756097561&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329032&quot; readability=&quot;5.7219512195122&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8609756097561&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.7219512195122&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.1987804878049&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329748&quot; readability=&quot;6.4555555555556&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2277777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4555555555556&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330776&quot; readability=&quot;3.6760563380282&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8380281690141&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6760563380282&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17332375&quot; readability=&quot;11.342756183746&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.6713780918728&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.342756183746&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17332890&quot; readability=&quot;8.6806451612903&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3403225806452&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.6806451612903&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.7870967741935&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330885&quot; readability=&quot;1.4838709677419&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330852&quot; readability=&quot;4.7183098591549&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3591549295775&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.7183098591549&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329781&quot; readability=&quot;7.4455445544554&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7227722772277&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4455445544554&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.049504950495&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329033&quot; readability=&quot;3.632&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.816&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.632&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329351&quot; readability=&quot;5.7849056603774&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8924528301887&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.7849056603774&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.7132075471698&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329544&quot; readability=&quot;11.65&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.825&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.65&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.825&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330940&quot; readability=&quot;4.9008390541571&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.4504195270786&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.9008390541571&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;11.271929824561&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330785&quot; readability=&quot;3.6036036036036&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8018018018018&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6036036036036&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.0540540540541&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330710&quot; readability=&quot;5.3698630136986&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6849315068493&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.3698630136986&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328885&quot; readability=&quot;26.351385390428&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;13.175692695214&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;26.351385390428&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;32.939231738035&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment&quot; readability=&quot;41.591139240506&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;The book, &quot;Bad Blood&quot; (written by the WSJ reporter) goes into great detail about how Holmes and Theranos were able to get away with their scam. &quot;Fake it till you make it&quot; is a thing not particularly bound by physics, especially when you have charisma and the friendship and backing of influential investors and board members.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;Incidentally, the book does contain a lot of discussion about patents. Holmes offended a longtime family friend, Richard Fuisz -- who, incidentally, was a former CIA agent -- around 2005-2006. He was mad Holmes and her family never consulted with him about the Threanos idea, so he wrote his own patent (made public on Jan 3, 2008) that he described as &quot;the Theranos killer&quot;. It turned into a big legal battle that caught the eye of a &lt;em&gt;Fortune&lt;/em&gt; writer, who ended up writing the first big magazine cover story on Holmes/Theranos:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2014/06/12/theranos-blood-holmes/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://fortune.com/2014/06/12/theranos-blood-holmes/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;The whole subplot is quite remarkable. Fuisz's battle with Theranos led to some damaging testimony in deposition. Fuisz's son became determined to take down Theranos and from what I can tell, had a big (but mostly unknown) part in the unraveling of Theranos. He found in a Google search a blog post [0] (now taken down) that made serious accusations about Theranos after the New Yorker cover story.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;Joe Fuisz, Richard's son, ended up contacting the blog author and telling him about the Fuisz vs. Holmes fight [1]. This blog author ended up contacting a WSJ reporter that he had previously worked with, John Carreyrou.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;So rather than science/engineering directly leading to Threanos's downfall, it seems a personal spat played a bigger part. And ironically, this spat involved a guy who wanted to out-patent-troll Elizabeth Holmes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;An excerpt from the book about what started Richard Fuisz's feud:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Richard Fuisz was a vain and prideful man. The thought that the daughter of longtime friends and former neighbors would launch a company in his area of expertise and that they wouldn’t ask for his help or even consult him deeply offended him. As he would put it years later in an email, “The fact that the Holmes family was so willing to partake of our hospitality (New York apartment, dinners, etc.) made it particularly bitter to me that they would not ask for advice. Essentially the message was, ‘I’ll drink your wine but I won’t ask you for advice in the very field that paid for the wine.’  ”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carreyrou, John. Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup (p. 71). Knopf Doubleday Publishing Group. Kindle Edition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;[0] edit: Here's an archive snapshot of the now taken down blog post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.is/BGtRJ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://archive.is/BGtRJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;Carreyrou gives a lot of credit to the author for giving the tip that turned Carreyrou's interest toward Theranos. Strangely, there's not mention of why the blog suddenly shut down. If you google around, you'll see it closed up a few weeks after Carreyrou's first big Theranos story.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;[1] edit: via a comment on the oldest HN post (Sept. 2013) about Theranos, I found a link an online summary of the patent dispute:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6349870&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6349870&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leagle.com/decision/infdco20121203541&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.leagle.com/decision/infdco20121203541&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17333241&quot; readability=&quot;3.6266666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8133333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6266666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330809&quot; readability=&quot;7.3947368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6973684210526&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.3947368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329729&quot; readability=&quot;4.6851385390428&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3425692695214&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6851385390428&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329789&quot; readability=&quot;7.4545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7272727272727&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.2121212121212&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330366&quot; readability=&quot;6.4703947368421&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2351973684211&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4703947368421&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329800&quot; readability=&quot;6.647355163728&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.323677581864&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.647355163728&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331073&quot; readability=&quot;4.5245901639344&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2622950819672&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5245901639344&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329568&quot; readability=&quot;8.5627530364372&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2813765182186&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.5627530364372&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.7085020242915&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330991&quot; readability=&quot;6.3830508474576&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.1915254237288&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.3830508474576&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328947&quot; readability=&quot;2.5783783783784&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2891891891892&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5783783783784&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329001&quot; readability=&quot;11.935064935065&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.9675324675325&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.935064935065&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.1808191808192&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329008&quot; readability=&quot;16.720762155059&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.3603810775296&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16.720762155059&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;14.753613666229&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329095&quot; readability=&quot;7.8517823639775&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.9258911819887&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.8517823639775&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.4155722326454&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329115&quot; readability=&quot;6.4291845493562&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2145922746781&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4291845493562&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329007&quot; readability=&quot;7.2478632478632&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6239316239316&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.2478632478632&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328833&quot; readability=&quot;1.1864406779661&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328705&quot; readability=&quot;4.2857142857143&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.2857142857143&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328869&quot; readability=&quot;6.7123287671233&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3561643835616&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.7123287671233&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.2739726027397&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329286&quot; readability=&quot;4.4063926940639&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.203196347032&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4063926940639&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329467&quot; readability=&quot;11.575638506876&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.7878192534381&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.575638506876&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.128683693517&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17333671&quot; readability=&quot;5.4491803278689&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7245901639344&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4491803278689&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329458&quot; readability=&quot;2.6134969325153&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3067484662577&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6134969325153&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329975&quot; readability=&quot;2.5975609756098&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2987804878049&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5975609756098&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329182&quot; readability=&quot;9.7050938337802&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8525469168901&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.7050938337802&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.7050938337802&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328768&quot; readability=&quot;9.6716417910448&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8358208955224&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.6716417910448&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.2208955223881&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329047&quot; readability=&quot;7.5521628498728&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7760814249364&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5521628498728&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.7760814249364&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17328769&quot; readability=&quot;0.97872340425532&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329672&quot; readability=&quot;2.6229508196721&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3114754098361&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6229508196721&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329688&quot; readability=&quot;4.2281879194631&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1140939597315&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.2281879194631&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329002&quot; readability=&quot;2.5804195804196&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2902097902098&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5804195804196&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329381&quot; readability=&quot;2.2135922330097&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331648&quot; readability=&quot;1.2142857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329202&quot; readability=&quot;6.8312284730195&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.4156142365098&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.8312284730195&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331314&quot; readability=&quot;3.8207547169811&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329031&quot; readability=&quot;9.4490358126722&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7245179063361&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.4490358126722&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329613&quot; readability=&quot;6.6741379310345&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3370689655172&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6741379310345&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.1043103448276&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329401&quot; readability=&quot;6.6908517350158&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3454258675079&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6908517350158&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.6466876971609&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329868&quot; readability=&quot;5.3114754098361&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.655737704918&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.3114754098361&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.8688524590164&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17329827&quot; readability=&quot;10.384615384615&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.1923076923077&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.384615384615&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.7202797202797&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330468&quot; readability=&quot;13.131918819188&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.5659594095941&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13.131918819188&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;14.882841328413&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330286&quot; readability=&quot;7.203187250996&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.601593625498&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.203187250996&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330803&quot; readability=&quot;6.3931888544892&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.1965944272446&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.3931888544892&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17330487&quot; readability=&quot;2.5448275862069&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2724137931034&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5448275862069&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17331864&quot; readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.25&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 18:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>anonymousmoose</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17328664</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Is Complicit in Online Sales of Counterfeit Goods: Report</title>
<link>http://www.ipwatchdog.com/2018/06/15/amazon-ceo-bezos-knowingly-complicit-online-sales-counterfeit-goods-according-report/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.ipwatchdog.com/2018/06/15/amazon-ceo-bezos-knowingly-complicit-online-sales-counterfeit-goods-according-report/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;96.55933277027&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://depositphotos.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-98147 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Depositphotos_144789731_s-2015-300x200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Depositphotos_144789731_s-2015-300x200.jpg 300w, http://www.ipwatchdog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Depositphotos_144789731_s-2015.jpg 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;There is little doubt that Seattle, WA-based online retailer Amazon.com (NASDAQ:AMZN) is a titan in the world of commerce and its effects on the world of e-commerce have had a definite effect even on brick-and-mortar retailers.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2017/10/24/16534100/amazon-market-share-ebay-walmart-apple-ecommerce-sales-2017&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Online merchandise sale analysis released last year by market research firm eMarketer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;indicated that Amazon’s share of the U.S. e-commerce market was expected to rise from 38.1 percent of U.S. online retail sales in 2016 up to 43.5 percent of U.S. e-commerce by the end of 2017. This January, e-commerce analytics provider One Click Retail announced that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/01/03/amazon-grabbed-4-percent-of-all-us-retail-sales-in-2017-new-study.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Amazon sales accounted for 4 percent of all U.S. retail sales online or offline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To paraphrase a timeless maxim from the Gospel of Luke, to whom much is given, from that entity much is also expected. Many consumers who go to Amazon and spend their money there expect that the item they are purchasing is an authentic article (although doubtless some consumers knowingly choose cheap articles which are clearly counterfeits), especially if there’s some expectation of the quality of the product because of that product’s brand. It’s safe to assume that no one who shells out top dollars for diamonds is all that happy to find out that they’ve instead bought cubic zirconia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/2LPRHTN&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/RedPoints-Brand-Protection-Report-350x250.png&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; height=&quot;250px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;However, news reports in recent years show that there is an actual and pervasive issue of counterfeit products which have no problem being bought by consumers through Amazon’s retail platform.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elevationlab.com/blogs/news/amazon-is-complicit-with-counterfeit-sellers#&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In a blog post published on March 1st of this year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, Elevation Lab founder Casey Hopkins ripped Amazon and the company’s CEO, Jeff Bezos, for allowing a Chinese wholesaler to market knockoff versions of Elevation’s Anchor headphone mount. Hopkins noted that, although an untrained eye might not spot the differences, the poor quality of the counterfeits did not live up to the authentic article and was likely to hurt Elevation’s reputation in the eyes of consumers receiving fake products.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is something extremely simple Amazon could do about&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;[counterfeit products]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;If you have a registered brand in the Brand Registry and don’t sell the product wholesale – there could be one box to check for that. And anyone else would have to get approval or high vetting to sell the product, especially if they are sending large quantities to FBA. I imagine there are some algorithmic solutions that could catch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;most of it too… Why Amazon doesn’t do this is mind-blowing and makes them complicit in the rampant counterfeiting on their platform. We are definitely not the first seller for this to happen to. And it lowers Amazon customers trust in the platform when they unknowingly receive knockoffs. And the real sellers also have to police this themselves, Amazon isn’t active in going after them – and Amazon can hide behind the fact that independent sellers are doing the counterfeiting.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Last October, German luxury automaker Daimler AG&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/2017/11/15/daimler-trademark-lawsuit-amazon-infringement-counterfeits/id=90101/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sued Amazon in California federal court over claims of trademark infringement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Daimler accused Amazon of being complicit in the sale of counterfeit wheel center caps which bear the branding of Mercedes-Benz automobiles. Amazon web pages selling these items indicated that Amazon was selling and shipping those infringing, unlicensed items which were produced by Otis Inc. LA.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Daimler is not the only owner of a well-known brand which has been targeted by copycat artists selling counterfeits on Amazon. Apple, Chanel, Kylie Jenner and Louis Vuitton are all popular brands which have attracted counterfeiters to Amazon’s e-commerce platform&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/30/17301714/amazon-counterfeit-goods-crackdown&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;according to recent news reports&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Although Amazon is typically quick to reference&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://sellercentral.amazon.com/gp/help/external/201165970?language=en-US&amp;amp;ref=mpbc_201166010_cont_201165970&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;its anti-counterfeit policy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;as proof of its commitment to weeding out inauthentic products from its retail platform, watchdog groups continue to point at major concerns regarding Amazon’s true intentions regarding the sale of counterfeits. Most recent among these is&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://thecounterfeitreport.com/press_release_details.php?date=2018-06-05&amp;amp;id=762&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;a press release issued on June 5th by The Counterfeit Report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;which strongly suggests that Amazon and Jeff Bezos have every intention of skirting the rules to continue the financial benefits they receive from the sale of counterfeits. The Counterfeit Report received multiple e-mail responses to counterfeit product issues it presented to Amazon. Those official Amazon e-mails indicate that Bezos received e-mails from The Counterfeit Report and that the e-mail sender was answering on Bezos’ behalf. Amazon’s official stance, as outlined by these e-mails, counterfeit products will continue to be listed on Amazon’s website in countries where the trademark covering the brand isn’t registered. As The Counterfeit Report notes, these counterfeits, of which Amazon is knowingly enabling sales, include both consumer goods as well as fake badges for the Secret Service, Federal Bureau of Investigations and the New York Police Department.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Think about that: Amazon and Bezos are so willing to profit from the sale of counterfeits that they’re fine with the potential of consumers being capable of impersonating federal law enforcement officials. This isn’t the first time that The Counterfeit Report has pushed Amazon rather publicly on its unwillingness to deal with a major problem posed by counterfeiters. In the early months of 2017, the watchdog organization announced that&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://247wallst.com/retail/2017/03/02/is-amazon-doing-enough-to-combat-counterfeit-product-sales/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;it had sent more than 32,000 notices of counterfeit items on Amazon’s platform to Amazon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;but that many of those items remained available for purchase online, even items which Amazon was notified of multiple times. There were also instances where infringing items were taken off of Amazon’s U.S. website but remained available on Amazon’s foreign e-commerce platforms, which are still available to consumers in the U.S. through the Internet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It should be pretty shocking to most that Bezos would personally be encouraging of such black market activity to take place on his very valuable e-commerce platform. However, it’s hardly surprising to those who are aware of Amazon’s involvement in the major push by American tech giants to devalue intellectual property overall, especially where patents are concerned.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/2017/07/16/high-tech-inventors-alliance-newest-efficient-infringer-lobby/id=85597/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Amazon is a founding member of the High Tech Inventors Alliance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;(HTIA), one of the newest lobbying institutions serving the efficient infringer cabal in Washington. Amazon’s own Echo Show smart speaker&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/2018/03/21/tech-giants-maintain-dominance-copying-technologies/id=94596/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;is closely reminiscent of a Wi-Fi home intercom and video conferencing product developed by Nucleus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a startup which Amazon decided to compete against after investing $5.6 million into the company. And although Facebook has been taking nearly all the flak in the recent debate over the rights that Internet consumers have to keeping their data private,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/2018/05/03/amazons-big-brother-technologies-tracking-life-milestones/id=96129/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Amazon has been developing its own data tracking technologies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;which can pinpoint a person’s physical location using an Internet protocol address or even to identify users of bitcoin, a cryptocurrency which is supposed to offer its users complete anonymity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Selling counterfeit products on the markets available in the United States is illegal. It would just be nice if the law applied to Amazon like it does to everyone else.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;38.636550308008&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Steve-Brachmann-300-b-copy-80x100.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Steve Brachmann&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/author/sbrachmann/&quot;&gt;Steve Brachmann&lt;/a&gt; is a writer located in Buffalo, New York. He has worked professionally as a freelancer for more than a decade. He has become a regular contributor to IPWatchdog.com, writing about technology, innovation and is the primary author of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/category/companies/&quot;&gt;Companies We Follow&lt;/a&gt; series. His work has been published by &lt;em&gt;The Buffalo News&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Hamburg Sun&lt;/em&gt;, USAToday.com, Chron.com, Motley Fool and OpenLettersMonthly.com. &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/116275452101893310100?rel=author&quot;&gt;Steve&lt;/a&gt; also provides website copy and documents for various business clients.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 15:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vezycash</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Amazon CEO Bezos is Knowingly Complicit in Online Sales of Counterfeit Goods, According to Report - IPWatchdog.com | Patents &amp; Patent Law</og:title>
<og:description>Although Amazon is typically quick to reference its anti-counterfeit policy as proof of its commitment to weeding out inauthentic products from its retail platform, watchdog groups continue to point at major concerns regarding Amazon’s true intentions regarding the sale of counterfeits. Most recent among these is a press release issued on June 5th by The Counterfeit Report which strongly suggests that Amazon and Jeff Bezos have every intention of skirting the rules to continue the financial benefits they receive from the sale of counterfeits. The Counterfeit Report received multiple e-mail responses to counterfeit product issues it presented to Amazon. Those official Amazon e-mails indicate that Bezos received e-mails from The Counterfeit Report and that the e-mail sender was answering on Bezos’ behalf. Amazon’s official stance, as outlined by these e-mails, counterfeit products will continue to be listed on Amazon’s website in countries where the trademark covering the brand isn’t registered.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.ipwatchdog.com/2018/06/15/amazon-ceo-bezos-knowingly-complicit-online-sales-counterfeit-goods-according-report/id=98145/</og:url>
<og:image>http://www.ipwatchdog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Depositphotos_144789731_s-2015.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.ipwatchdog.com/2018/06/15/amazon-ceo-bezos-knowingly-complicit-online-sales-counterfeit-goods-according-report/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Confessions of a Disk Cracker: The Secrets of 4am</title>
<link>https://paleotronic.com/2018/06/15/confessions-of-a-disk-cracker-the-secrets-of-4am/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://paleotronic.com/2018/06/15/confessions-of-a-disk-cracker-the-secrets-of-4am/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-700&quot; src=&quot;http://paleotronic.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/prf2--1024x724.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;724&quot; data-lazy-srcset=&quot;https://paleotronic.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/prf2--1024x724.png 1024w, https://paleotronic.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/prf2--300x212.png 300w, https://paleotronic.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/prf2--768x543.png 768w&quot; data-lazy-sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-700&quot; src=&quot;http://paleotronic.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/prf2--1024x724.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;724&quot; srcset=&quot;https://paleotronic.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/prf2--1024x724.png 1024w, https://paleotronic.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/prf2--300x212.png 300w, https://paleotronic.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/prf2--768x543.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why did you choose to start aggressively de-protecting, archiving and re-distributing Apple II software?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;It’s tempting to rewrite history and give myself some noble purpose for starting this hobby, but in this case the truth makes for a better story. My parents bought themselves an Apple //e when I was 10, and it quickly came to dominate my leisure time. Pirated software was rampant, and I idolized the crackers whose names I saw flash and scroll on the crack screens of the games I traded with my friends. I also admired the few who documented their methods in cracking tutorials, initially distributed as BBS text files and later collated and redistributed on disk. I PEEK’d and POKE’d and CALL’d many late nights as a teenager, but I could never quite put it all together.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In late 2013, I acquired a real Apple //e and bought a few lots of original disks on eBay, mostly arcade games that I had acquired illicitly in my youth: Sneakers, Repton, Dino Eggs. To my surprise, the originals had more content than I remembered! Sneakers has an animated boot sequence. Repton has a multi-page introduction that explains the “back story” of the game. So I set out to create “complete” cracks that faithfully reproduced the original experience. I decided to document my methods because I enjoy technical writing and because I had admired the classic crackers who had done so. I decided to leave out the crack screens, although a handful of my early cracks do have Easter eggs where you can see “4am” if you know how to trigger it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;One of those eBay lots had an educational game, “Ten Little Robots.” After cracking it, I couldn’t find any copies of it online, which seemed odd. Surely everything has been cracked? Perhaps it was just mis-named or mis-filed? Then I found another disk that seemed to be a first-time preservation. And another. And it slowly dawned on me that maybe not everything has been cracked.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I mentioned this to Jason Scott, and he set me straight. Preservation is driven by pirates, who are driven by ego but constrained by the technical limitations of their era. In the 1980s, this meant storage space and network speed. Nobody got kudos for cracking “Irregular Spanish Verbs in the Future Tense,” no BBS would waste the hard drive space to host it, and no user would sacrifice their phone line to download it. So it never got preserved in any form.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And even the things that did get cracked weren’t fully preserved. Those same technical constraints led to a culture where the smallest version of a game always won. That meant stripping out the animated boot sequence, the title screen, the multi-page introduction, the cut scenes, anything deemed “non-essential” to the pirates. The holy grail was cutting away so much that you could distribute the game (or what was left of it) as a single file that could be combined with other unrelated games on a single floppy disk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;30 years later, that’s exactly what I saw: half-preserved arcade games, a smattering of educational software, and virtually nothing else. I realized I could have a real impact while having just as much fun, just as much intellectual challenge. Along the way, I’ve discovered that educational software is rich with history, personality, humor, and technical achievement. It’s been delightful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Did you have any concerns over copyright? Do you feel the ethical considerations over lost software outweigh the rights of the copyright owner to restrict distribution of their works?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I host the write-ups and deprotected software (as disk images) on archive.org. They fully comply with DMCA takedown notices. They’ve never received one for anything in the 4am collection. In fact, just the opposite – I’ve had several authors find their own software and thank me for preserving it. One author even apologized for the copy protection. He understood it was a “necessary evil” at the time, but he was so glad that someone had finally bothered to cut through it. He said it was so exciting to be able to experience his own work again, for the first time in decades.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since most of the Disk II’s higher-level functionality is based in software loaded from the disk itself, this allowed for a large variety of copy protection schemes. How has this been a hindrance to saving Apple II software?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We still can’t make perfect digital representations of Apple II floppy disks. Disks are analog, physical objects, made up of hundreds of thousands of magnetic flux changes. Those changes are stored in a physical layout on a physical disk and read by physical drives with their own variances and limitations. Disk II drives leave most of the functionality to software, and software exploits every possible edge case.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Where copy programs would drop bits, protection schemes checked for missing bits. Where copy programs would misalign data across tracks, protection schemes checked for cross-track alignment. Oh, your copy program can’t read some data on the disk when it’s physically too close to other data? Guess how we’re laying out our data on our next disk! And so on. It was a big cat-and-mouse game, an endless war that only ended when everyone lost.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;All of that physicality is hard to capture digitally, and for decades there were no serious attempts to try. In the 1990s, people devised ways to digitize some approximation of a disk, just the post-processed nibbles and bytes. This was sufficient for digitizing cracked software, because the crackers had already normalized the original disks down to bytes so they could distribute them via BBS.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the modern era, there is some specialized hardware that can digitize a floppy disk at the level of magnetic flux changes. For a variety of reasons, the hardware developers focused on non-Apple II platforms, and a few unresolved technical differences prevented a community of Apple II-specific preservationists from reusing it. There is some new development on this front, and I’m optimistic that collectors will soon be able to create flux-level digital copies of Apple II floppy disks, and users will be able to boot original software in emulators.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What copy protection schemes are the most common, and which one is the most tricky, in your experience?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The most common protection schemes were the ones that were productized and resold to hundreds of publishers. This was coordinated through the disk duplication houses, who offered copy protection as a “value add” on top of mastering the disks themselves. Publishers got the benefit of the latest and greatest copy protection without needing to play the cat-and-mouse game themselves.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The E7 bitstream, a.k.a. “generic bit slip protection,” was the most common. It was a sequence of 1s and 0s, specially crafted so the first half could be read “in phase,” then the code would intentionally skip half a byte and read the second half “out of phase.” Bit copiers would drop bits due to hardware limitations, and the out-of-phase values would be wrong. It was brilliant.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;E7 was invented in 1983 and immediately productized. It protected “Moptown Parade” in 1984, “Rocky’s Boots” in 1985, and “Prince of Persia” in 1989. I’ve found it on disks from Addison-Wesley, Advanced Ideas, DesignWare, Edu-Ware, Microcomputer Workshops, Mindscape, Scholastic, Scott Foresman and Company, The Learning Company, Unicorn Software, Broderbund, Data East, Epyx, and Windham Classics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The trickiest protections are the ones that are deeply integrated with the program itself, instead of being bolted on by a separate company. Some publishers chose to invest in copy protection themselves, to hire that expertise and keep it in-house. So you get “Gumball” by Broderbund Software, where the author of the game worked directly with the author of the copy protection. If you think you’ve removed all the copy protection because you got the game to boot, you’re in for a surprise on level 3 when the game starts misbehaving on purpose.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Which software developers or manufacturers disks (or individual pieces of software) have been the most difficult to de-protect?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Delayed protections in games were the worst. Sierra On-Line was famous for this. If you bypass the call to the self-decrypting protection check in “Threshold,” it lets you play the game but you can only move your ship to the right. If you change the protection check itself so it always succeeds, “Threshold” lets you play level 1 but glitches out on level 2. There was a separate anti-tamper check that only ran after level 1!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Scott Adams’ “Strange Odyssey” doesn’t run its protection check until you’ve started the game, climbed down the stairs, and taken the shovel. “The Count” doesn’t check until you’ve climbed into the dumbwaiter, which is about 15 moves into the game. And those are the easy ones, because they just reboot or crash immediately if they fail. “Transylvania” has a delayed protection check that deletes a vital location from the map and renders the game unwinnable. “Prince of Persia” neutralizes the effect of a potion you need to drink to finish level 7. “Conflict in Vietnam” has both on- and off-disk protection and 13 separate anti-tamper checks that can trigger a fatal error up to an hour later!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Have I removed all the copy protection” is functionally equivalent to the Halting Problem. The day we can prove that we’ve removed all the protection from all the disks is the day the universe ends.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Although you obviously prefer creating “clean cracks” of software, is there a place for “cracked” disks that have been altered? Do they have their own historical significance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Everything has historical significance. The choices those pirates made were driven by constraints that are largely absent today. Nobody born in this millenium has had a download fail at 99% because someone picked up the phone downstairs. Nobody cares about the difference between a 1K download and a 1.1K download. I’ve never needed to advertise the phone number of my BBS. I can read and search every issue of Hardcore Computist on the supercomputer I carry around in my pocket. Classic pirates did more with less.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You de-protect a great deal of educational software. Is this just for completeness and / or because historical “crackers” largely ignored the genre, or do you feel this software is potentially still useful in the education area?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m under no illusions that anyone will actually use this software for its original purpose. At best, it would be a technology demonstration, “look how far we’ve come, but 1 + 1 is still 2,” that kind of thing. But its original purpose was important! These were not just bits on a disk or disks in a box. This was curriculum. This was how we taught math and science and grammar and history to an entire generation of children. That seems like something worth saving.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;You wrote a utility called Passport to help de-protect Apple II software, so that others could convert their own disk collections into functional emulator files. Could you explain a bit about that utility, and how it works?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;There were a number of cracking utilities back in the day. The most versatile was called “Advanced Demuffin.” It used a protected disk as a weapon against itself, reading every sector of the disk with the disk’s own code (“RWTS”), then writing out the data to an unprotected copy. Two problems: first, you had to capture or extract the RWTS yourself; Advanced Demuffin wouldn’t help you with that. Second, you had to patch the code on the unprotected copy so it could read itself.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The vast majority of my early cracks followed the same 3-step process: capture the RWTS, run Advanced Demuffin, patch up the copy. After 8 cracks, I wrote a tool to automate step 1, capturing the RWTS. After 152 cracks, I wrote a tool to automate step 3, patching up the unprotected copy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;After 688 cracks, I wrote Passport.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Passport is an automated disk verification and copy program. And when I say “automatic,” I mean it. Unlike classic bit copiers, there are no parameters, no options, nothing to set beyond destination slot and drive. It either works or it doesn’t.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Also unlike classic copiers, the copy it produces is fully unprotected. It handles all 3 steps of that 3-step process. No fiddling with boot tracing on the front end, no fiddling with sector editors on the back end. It’s all built-in. Passport is a distillation of everything I’ve learned about cracking: every disk, every variation, every edge case.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Of my first 688 cracks, 478 could have been automated with Passport.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;This has completely changed my hobby. Passport ensures consistency. I don’t worry about missing a patch or mistyping a hex value. I don’t spend any time doing the grunt work that computers can do for me. If I find two disks with the same protection, I write a new Passport module to automate it. Remember, protection was productized. If I’ve found 2, there are 20 more. They’re out there, rotting away on physical media.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Automation frees me to look beyond the bits. I can spend more time on in-depth write-ups of protection schemes that can’t be automated. I can take screenshots and make boot videos to show off all this wonderful educational software. The copy protection is the least interesting part of these disks. It’s just the part that prevented us from studying all the other parts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p5&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;As of February 2018, &lt;span class=&quot;s4&quot;&gt;4am&lt;/span&gt; has deprotected &lt;span class=&quot;s4&quot;&gt;1673&lt;/span&gt; Apple II software titles, and that number is still climbing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 4am collection is online at&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p5&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/apple_ii_library_4am&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/details/apple_ii_library_4am&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p5&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most of the software titles listed there can be accessed using the Internet Archive’s in-browser Apple II emulator.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Passport is available from&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p5&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/Passport4am&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/details/Passport4am&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 14:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>empressplay</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Confessions of a Disk Cracker: the secrets of 4am. - Paleotronic Magazine</og:title>
<og:description>Why did you choose to start aggressively de-protecting, archiving and re-distributing Apple II software? It’s tempting to rewrite history and give myself some noble purpose for starting this hobby, but in this case the truth [more...]</og:description>
<og:url>https://paleotronic.com/2018/06/15/confessions-of-a-disk-cracker-the-secrets-of-4am/</og:url>
<og:image>https://paleotronic.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/prf2--1024x724.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://paleotronic.com/2018/06/15/confessions-of-a-disk-cracker-the-secrets-of-4am/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>