<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Google staff walk out over women&amp;#039;s treatment</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-46054202</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-46054202</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staff at Google offices around the world are staging an unprecedented series of walkouts in protest at the company's treatment of women.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The employees are demanding several key changes in how sexual misconduct allegations are dealt with at the firm, including a call to end forced arbitration - a move which would make it possible for victims to sue. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google chief executive Sundar Pichai has told staff he supports their right to take the action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I understand the anger and disappointment that many of you feel,&quot; he said in an all-staff email. &quot;I feel it as well, and I am fully committed to making progress on an issue that has persisted for far too long in our society… and, yes, here at Google, too.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Twitter feed titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GoogleWalkout&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;@googlewalkout&lt;/a&gt; has documented the movement at Google's international offices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google staff in Zurich, London, Tokyo, Singapore and Berlin were among those to take part.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;PA&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Dublin
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    London
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Twitter @TedonPrivacy/@googlewalkout via Reuters&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Zurich
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Walkout organisers&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The first walkout was at Google’s Singapore office
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web developer Sam Dutton who joined the walkout in London told the BBC: &quot;We're walking out to support colleagues in any workplace that have suffered harassment and to ensure that perpetrators aren't protected or rewarded.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What led to the walkout? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/25/technology/google-sexual-harassment-andy-rubin.html&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Anger at the firm has boiled over in the past week since the New York Times alleged&lt;/a&gt; that one high profile executive received a $90m payout after he left the firm, despite what Google considered a “credible” allegation of sexual misconduct made against him. Andy Rubin, known as the “creator” of the Android mobile operating system, denies the allegation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, another executive - this time from the company’s X research lab - also resigned. Richard DeVaul was said to have made unwanted advances towards a woman who was recently interviewed for a job in which she would have reported to Mr DeVaul. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr DeVaul has not commented since his resignation, but in the past called the incident an &quot;error of judgement&quot;.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At least 48 other employees have been sacked for sexual harassment without receiving a payout, Mr Pichai told staff. He admitted the New York Times’ report had been &quot;difficult to read&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What do the employees want? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Staff involved in Thursday's walkout will leave a note on their desks telling colleagues: &quot;I’m not at my desk because I’m walking out with other Googlers and contractors to protest sexual harassment, misconduct, lack of transparency, and a workplace culture that’s not working for everyone.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They are also making formal demands to Google’s management. They are: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol class=&quot;story-body__ordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;A commitment to end pay and opportunity inequality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;A publicly disclosed sexual harassment transparency report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;A clear, uniform, globally inclusive process for reporting sexual misconduct safely and anonymously&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;The elevation of the chief diversity officer to answer directly to the CEO, and make recommendations directly to the board of directors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;The appointment of an employee representative to the board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;An end to forced arbitration in cases of harassment and discrimination for all current and future employees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What is forced arbitration?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forced arbitration, a common contract clause for Silicon Valley workers, demands any disputes are dealt with internally rather than through other methods such as the courts. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Critics of forced arbitration say it is used to not only protect the reputations of both the company and the accused, but also to silence victims who are unable to appeal against decisions or take further action. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Employees have raised constructive ideas for how we can improve our policies and our processes going forward,” said Mr Pichai in a statement on Wednesday evening. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We are taking in all their feedback so we can turn these ideas into action.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What else are Google employees angry about? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-ordinated action of this scale is unprecedented at a Silicon Valley company, but follows a trend for increasingly impassioned employee activism. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Women are fed up, and I don't think it's just women,” said Prof Kellie McElhaney, from the Haas School of Business. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;There are a lot of ‘manbassadors' out there who are equally as fed up and using their positions of power and voice, which can cost Google money. I think you have to hit these companies where it hurts. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I think it empowers other Google offices when women and men are watching this happen, that they can do a similar action that's not just sitting by or making comments to one another or sharing emails.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-portrait has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Twitter/Googlewalkout&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    This leaflet will be left on the desks of Google employees choosing to take part in the coordinated action
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past year, Google employees have spoken out strongly against the company’s work with the US Department of Defense, as well as plans to re-enter the Chinese market with a search product. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Tech Workers Coalition, a San Francisco-based advocacy group, said the day’s dispute was just one of several tech companies need to address. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We stand in solidarity with the Google workers,” a spokesperson for the group said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s clear the executives won’t do this for us so we’re taking matters into our own hands.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you a Google employee who is taking part in industrial action?  Tell us about your experiences by emailing &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk?subject=Googlestrike46054202&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-email&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;icon email&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;story-body__link-email-text&quot;&gt;haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please include a contact number if you are willing to speak to a BBC journalist. You can also contact us in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;WhatsApp: &lt;strong&gt;+44 7555 173285&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Tweet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/BBC_HaveYourSay&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;@BBC_HaveYourSay&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Send pictures/video to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:yourpics@bbc.co.uk&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-email&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;icon email&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;story-body__link-email-text&quot;&gt;yourpics@bbc.co.uk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bbcnewsupload.streamuk.com/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Upload your pictures / video here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Text an SMS or MMS to &lt;strong&gt;61124 &lt;/strong&gt;or &lt;strong&gt;+44 7624 800 100&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Please read our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/terms/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;terms &amp;amp; conditions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/privacy-policy/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 09:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>oneeyedpigeon</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google staff walk out over women's treatment</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>A reported huge payout for an executive accused of sexual misconduct provokes an unprecedented protest.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-46054202</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/9B85/production/_104131893_11a7511c-d716-4bbf-acc2-80ef70a40082.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-46054202</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sales mistakes that software engineers make</title>
<link>https://www.pipelinedb.com/blog/three-sales-mistakes-software-engineers-make</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.pipelinedb.com/blog/three-sales-mistakes-software-engineers-make</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Everybody is selling something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For software engineers this can translate to selling products directly to customers on the front lines or selling new product feature ideas internally within an organization. In either case, sales in some form cannot be avoided. As such, software engineers can benefit greatly from observing and avoiding the more impactful and common mistakes other developers have made in the past, and learning what they should have done instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we went through Y-Combinator during the winter of 2014 and were just starting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pipelinedb.com/&quot;&gt;PipelineDB&lt;/a&gt;, one of the things that surprised me most about the other founders in our YC batch, who were mostly technical, was their bewilderment at the prospect of selling. Here were some of the most brilliant minds I’d ever met, building things ranging from self driving cars to aerial imagery analytics platforms for agriculture, and the aspect of their startups that seemed to cause them the most anxiety was sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then it occurred to me that it wasn’t because sales is prohibitively complex or difficult that these genius technical minds were baffled by it. It was simply a situation where they didn’t know what they didn’t know. Ambiguity is inherently stressful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post aims to help software engineers bridge the gap between conceptualizing valuable software products and winning deals by observing three significant mistakes developers commonly make when approaching sales. We’ll frame these mistakes in a positive light, more as opportunities for progress than as liabilities, focusing on solutions in each instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these mistakes is fairly unintuitive, so it’s not surprising that any salesperson, including software engineers, would make any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sales Mistake #1 - Building &lt;em&gt;Before&lt;/em&gt; you Start Selling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest mistake I see developers make is assuming that they are building something that people both want and will pay a meaningful amount of money for. Many engineering teams spend a great deal of time and money building products that people either don’t actually want, or want but aren’t willing to pay enough money for, such that the company building the product can establish a feasible business model. Both of these issues can be resolved simply by talking to potential customers before the product is ever built and asking strategic questions, a step which many developers fail to take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, the amount of work required to talk to potential customers and prove demand for a potential product is almost exactly the same as the amount of work required to sell an existing product. So, the sales work we’re talking about here has to be done at some point, regardless. One benefit of doing this sales work in advance of building the product is that if you’re right about the extent to which people want what you’re building, you’ll be lining up customers for sales as soon as the product is ready and learning more about what features people need and will pay for in the process. If you’re wrong, you’ll save time and money by not building something people don’t want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, if you’re a startup looking to raise money and haven’t built the product yet, or are working at a company and looking to win internal support for the development of a new product or feature, there is no better ammunition for pitching investors or internal champions than hard, documented customer demand. This documented customer demand will carry weight only if it demonstrates a propensity, or better yet, a contractual obligation, to pay a meaningful amount of money for whatever you’re building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategically engaging with and selling to potential customers before you build your product is a far superior strategy than building a product and then taking it to customers and trying to sell it, so do yourself a gigantic favor and check your assumptions before you start building and test your hypothesis about both people’s interest &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; willingness to pay for what you want to build, &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; you build it. No amount of salesmanship will enable you to make up for building the wrong product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do we accomplish this? Below is a quick overview of the steps required to find and engage potential customers, along with a couple of helpful tools and strategies to help you get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;23.681315207082&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearly articulate your hypothesis&lt;/strong&gt; about what you’re building. What is the product? Who wants this? Why do they want it? What will they pay for it? How do you know they’ll pay that much? How many potential customers exist? Be as concise as possible with your answers to these questions. The simpler the response, the better. Without a well thought through hypothesis you’ll have nothing to test or measure against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;18.875816993464&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a list of companies&lt;/strong&gt; (or users) that you think fit your hypothesis in a spreadsheet or simple CRM (customer relationship management) tool like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.streak.com&quot;&gt;Streak&lt;/a&gt;, a lightweight CRM offered as a Gmail plugin. This CRM will be your data management platform for all customer interaction and can be used to organize your target list of companies, monitor your sales progress, document customer conversations and feedback, and ultimately measure your sales results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common way to organize a CRM is by grouping companies you’re targeting by the stage of the conversation that each company is in with you. I’d suggest using (“lead”, “reached out”, “active contact”, “demo/free trial”, “closed/won”, “closed/lost”, and “future interest”) or some close variant, as your stage names. It is imperative to have and use a well organized CRM of some sort, even if it’s just a simple spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;14.596110695587&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find relevant contacts at each company&lt;/strong&gt; on your target list and document their names, titles, and contact information in your CRM. You can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;'s search feature to find employees who work at each company you’re targeting, along with their titles and oftentimes descriptions of their roles. You can also browse the “about us” section of the websites of the companies you’re targeting and conduct basic Google searches to find the names and titles of employees you want to talk to. Try to identify a handful of relevant contacts at each company. Having multiple points of entry for each company increases your chances of successfully setting up a meeting with that company, which should be your goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use tools like Linkedin’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/linkedin-sales-navigator/hihakjfhbmlmjdnnhegiciffjplmdhin?hl=en&quot;&gt;Sales Navigator Gmail plugin&lt;/a&gt; (was called Rapportive) to help you find contact info for the folks on your list. If you don’t connect with the right contact initially, ask the person you do connect with who they would suggest you talk to and if they’d be willing to make a quick email introduction to that person. I’m always surprised at people’s willingness to be helpful when I’m direct, sincere, and respectful of their time. And work your own personal network. The best introductions are warm intros from people you already know, so leverage your network as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reach out to each of the contacts you found.&lt;/strong&gt; In my experience, the optimal strategy is to write concise and highly personalized outreach emails to each contact explaining who you are, why you’re reaching out, and why they should care. Conclude by asking if they would be open to a brief introductory conversation with you to learn more about your product and how it might help them. The goal is to get them on the phone to discuss your product and test your hypothesis from step one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Effective selling requires a thoughtful strategy, rigorous effort, and tenacity. There is obviously more to sales than can be articulated in this post alone, but this high-level framework for finding and engaging potential customers is something that software engineers can use to get sales conversations started and generate the type of crucial customer feedback discussed above, &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; building. Be scrappy and creative in how you find and engage contacts, but make sure that you don’t stop until you have a significant amount of clear feedback that either proves or disproves your hypothesis. And don’t be afraid to iterate on your hypothesis and pivot your product strategy or business model. Iteration is a normal and expected part of a successful product development process, so let go of any attachment you have to what &lt;em&gt;you think&lt;/em&gt; people want, and build &lt;em&gt;what they tell you they actually want&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;will pay for&lt;/em&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sales Mistake #2 - Talking Instead of &lt;em&gt;Listening&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second biggest mistake I see developers make in the sales process is entering into sales conversations with potential customers and proceeding to immediately talk about product features and perceived benefits for the customer, without taking advantage of the opportunity to ask strategic, open-ended questions, and then &lt;strong&gt;listen intently&lt;/strong&gt;. The responses that customers give to thoughtful, open-ended questions inform how customers think about their problems, needs, budgets, timeline, decision making process, fears, alternative options to your product, and the extent to which they perceive that your product solves their problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to sales, it does not matter what &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think about your product. It only matters what &lt;em&gt;customers&lt;/em&gt; think about your product. In order to win customers you must set aside your own thinking and get into the mind of your customer. The best way to do this is by asking good questions, and then listening carefully and taking notes. Open-ended questions like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How do you think about this problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To what extent is this a priority?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are you interested in this topic?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will the decision to do this or not be made?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are your most important considerations with this type of project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How exactly did this need surface in the first place?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would solving this problem do for your team, and the business as a whole?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;are particularly effective sales questions because they offer the sales prospect an opportunity to respond with a large volume of unbiased feedback to each of your questions. The goal is to get sales prospects talking about their thought process so that you can understand their perspective, needs, and motives. Without this information you are essentially flying blind in the sales process and likely inundating sales prospects with information that may or may not be relevant. With this information you can deliver a concise, tactical proposal about how your product would add value for them, or determine that your solution actually isn’t a good fit for them and save both you and the prospect time by disqualifying them and moving on to another sales conversation that is likely a better fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many engineers I've talked to report experiencing social anxiety and a sense of discomfort during sales conversations. This is especially true when it's time to ask sales prospects some of the harder questions surrounding their willingness to pay for your product, budgets, next steps, and getting all of the decision makers on their end involved and taking action. The natural human response to this type of discomfort is to react somehow, oftentimes by talking unnecessarily, which is a tactical mistake. The optimal approach to sales is to ask the kind of strategic, open-ended questions mentioned above, &lt;strong&gt;then wait&lt;/strong&gt;. Listen. Let the silence linger longer than you're comfortable with, so that the sales prospect can consider your question, experience their own emotions, and then respond. Get comfortable being uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asking good questions is the key to sales. This key can be used to unlock the door to the customer’s thought process. Once the door is open, valuable information can be passed from the customer to you, enabling you to deliver value to the customer. And by delivering value, you will earn revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sales Mistake #3 - Mistaking Interest for &lt;em&gt;Demand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software engineers, especially those who are emotionally attached to the value propositions they assume their products’ deliver, have a tendency to mistake interest for demand. If you’re building a product that delivers any incremental value, you’ll likely be able to win the interest of potential users, but that does not mean that you have created enough incremental value for customers to make them willing to pay you a meaningful amount of money for your product. The delta between enthusiasm and willingness to pay is the difference between interest and demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What typically happens is that customer prospects will express some level of enthusiasm about a product during a sales call, or even go as far to articulate that they want and would use the product in question. This response from the customer is then interpreted as proof that customers want to buy the product. Software engineers in this situation have a tendency to assume that their sales work is now done and that the only remaining step is to deliver the product and collect their cash. This is incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More investigation must be conducted to determine whether or not the customer is willing to pay for the product, and if so, how much they are willing to pay. The acronym “BANT” (budget, authority, need, timeline), which was developed by IBM salespeople for qualifying sales leads, is a useful checklist for determining whether not a sales prospect has demonstrated demand for your product. If you can determine that a customer truly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;needs&lt;/strong&gt; your product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has enough &lt;strong&gt;budget&lt;/strong&gt; to purchase your product at a price that works for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that you are in contact with a person who has the &lt;strong&gt;authority&lt;/strong&gt; to make the purchase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that the transaction will likely be completed in a &lt;strong&gt;timeline&lt;/strong&gt; that is acceptable to you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;then you have successfully bridged the gap between interest and demand. Once you have determined that a sales lead has met these criteria, ask them if they’d be willing to sign an agreement to purchase your product at a specific price if it meets a certain set of requirements. The ideal situation for you is to have as many signed, legally binding customer contracts as possible, as early on in the product development process as as possible. You may not be able to get these, but you should try. Even getting customers to sign non-binding “letters of intent” to purchase your product, ideally at a set price, is valuable and can be used to build your case to any relevant parties. You must push customers to agree to as much as possible. Without doing this, you will not have a good sense for the extent to which demand for your product exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t fall into the trap of mistaking people’s enthusiasm and language around how much they want and will use your product for real demand that satisfies your business hypothesis. It’s possible to waste an infinite amount of time chasing unqualified leads, or worse, mistaking interest for demand and building the wrong product entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of software products and companies that fail do so because they neglect to perform the kind of thorough customer development work described above. The process of strategically engaging customers and transforming their feedback into valuable software products is the best way to ensure that you build something that delivers enough value to these customers for them to be willing to pay you a meaningful amount of money in return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This iterative process of talking to customers and building what they need and will pay for is not only an exercise to be conducted before building products, but should also serve as a continuous feedback loop between customers and developers. Don’t deny yourself the opportunity to harvest mission-critical information needed to build game changing software products that support successful business models, simply by neglecting to engage the very people you’re aiming to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to your customers, build what they want and will pay for, and iterate relentlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 07:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Fergi</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.pipelinedb.com/blog/three-sales-mistakes-software-engineers-make</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Howler.js – JavaScript audio library for the modern web</title>
<link>https://howlerjs.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://howlerjs.com</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;feature-item&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplified API&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single, consistent API for all of your audio needs makes building your audio experiences fun and easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-item&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio Sprites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easily define and control segments of files with audio sprites for more precise playback and lower resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-item&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatial Audio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether a simple stereo pan or advanced 3D game audio, howler.js makes it easy to keep it all straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-item&quot; readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full Codec Support&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports all browser-ready files: MP3, MPEG, OPUS, OGG, OGA, WAV, AAC, CAF, M4A, MP4, WEBA, WEBM, DOLBY, FLAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-item&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Works Everywhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defaults to Web Audio and falls back to HTML5 Audio to provide full coverage across all browsers and platforms including IE9 and Cordova.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-item&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full Control&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control everything from play, pause and seek to rate, fade and loop, just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-item&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auto Caching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loaded sounds are automatically cached and re-used on subsequent calls for better performance and bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-item&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modular&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use only what you need with the new modular architecture. Easily extend the library to add custom features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-item&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero Dependencies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;howler.js is as light as 7KB gzipped and is 100% JavaScript with no outside dependencies or plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 23:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>glassworm</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://howlerjs.com</og:url>
<og:title>howler.js - JavaScript audio library for the modern web</og:title>
<og:description>howler.js makes working with audio in JavaScript easy and reliable across all platforms.</og:description>
<og:image>https://howlerjs.com/assets/images/twittercard.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://howlerjs.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>JavaScript is now required to sign in to Google</title>
<link>https://security.googleblog.com/2018/10/announcing-some-security-treats-to.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://security.googleblog.com/2018/10/announcing-some-security-treats-to.html</guid>
<description></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 22:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amaccuish</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Announcing some security treats to protect you from attackers’ tricks</og:title>
<og:image>http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-7bZ5EziliZQ/VynIS9F7OAI/AAAAAAAASQ0/BJFntXCAntstZe6hQuo5KTrhi5Dyz9yHgCK4B/s1600/googlelogo_color_200x200.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://security.googleblog.com/2018/10/announcing-some-security-treats-to.html</og:url>
<og:description>Posted by Jonathan Skelker, Product Manager It’s Halloween 🎃 and the last day of Cybersecurity Awareness Month 🔐, so we’re celebrating t...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://security.googleblog.com/2018/10/announcing-some-security-treats-to.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Compare career levels across companies</title>
<link>https://www.levels.fyi/SE/Google/Facebook/Microsoft</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.levels.fyi/SE/Google/Facebook/Microsoft</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.levels.fyi/SE/Google/Facebook/Microsoft&quot;&gt;https://www.levels.fyi/SE/Google/Facebook/Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18349421&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18349421&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 715&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 351&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 21:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kposehn</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google vs Facebook vs Microsoft Engineering Levels and Compensation</og:title>
<og:description>Levels.fyi makes it easy to compare and contrast different career levels across different companies. Find out your new title and how much you'll be making!</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.imgur.com/oyk4RcG.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://levels.fyi/SE/Google/Facebook/Microsoft</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.levels.fyi/SE/Google/Facebook/Microsoft/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Build Your Own Professional-Grade Audio Amp on the Sort-Of Cheap</title>
<link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/consumer-electronics/audiovideo/build-your-own-professionalgrade-audio-amp-on-the-sort-of-cheap</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://spectrum.ieee.org/consumer-electronics/audiovideo/build-your-own-professionalgrade-audio-amp-on-the-sort-of-cheap</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/consumer-electronics/audiovideo/build-your-own-professionalgrade-audio-amp-on-the-sort-of-cheap&quot;&gt;https://spectrum.ieee.org/consumer-electronics/audiovideo/build-your-own-professionalgrade-audio-amp-on-the-sort-of-cheap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18349396&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18349396&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 392&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 215&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 21:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chablent</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://spectrum.ieee.org/consumer-electronics/audiovideo/build-your-own-professionalgrade-audio-amp-on-the-sort-of-cheap</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Pencils Are Yellow (2017)</title>
<link>https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-little-known-reason-pencils-yellow</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-little-known-reason-pencils-yellow</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visitors to the 1889 Exposition Universelle in Paris entered the fairgrounds under the shadow of the newly-built Eiffel Tower—a gleaming marvel of wrought iron lattice that stretched almost a thousand feet into the air. Once inside, they could gawk at a massive reconstruction of the Bastille or gasp as Annie Oakley demonstrated her legendary marksmanship in Buffalo Bill’s Wild West show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst this myriad of spectacles was a rather less dramatic—but no less influential—innovation from a Czech manufacturing company named Hardtmuth Pencil. Its latest creation was formed, as all pencils are, of a graphite core housed in a protective wooden sheath. What stood out was its color—Hardtmuth’s “luxury pencil” was painted yellow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to 1889, the highest-quality pencils were left “natural polished.” Manufacturers usually painted their pencils if they were looking to cover up imperfections in the wood. Accordingly, typical paint colors were dark: purple, red, maroon, or black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Hardtmuth was looking for a way to advertise the caliber of its graphite rather than its wood. “For a long time the best graphite came from the west—England, in particular,” explained Duke University professor Henry Petroski, author of &lt;em&gt;The Pencil: A History of Design and Circumstance&lt;/em&gt;. (The very first graphite deposit was discovered in Borrowdale, England, in 1564, centuries before yellow pencils arrived on the scene.) Although the British supply of graphite eventually ran out, soon “a new and superior source was found in Siberia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 17:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>colinprince</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Little-Known Reason Pencils Are Yellow</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-little-known-reason-pencils-yellow</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Pencils weren’t always yellow. We have the marketing genius of a 19th-century Czech manufacturer to thank for their now-ubiquitous hue.</og:description>
<og:image>https://artsy-media-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/QLbuWKkapyx4UHkcjAIX7Q%2FPencils.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-little-known-reason-pencils-yellow</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hawaii Supreme Court Rules in Favor of Building Thirty Meter Telescope</title>
<link>http://www.staradvertiser.com/2018/10/30/breaking-news/supreme-court-rules-in-favor-of-tmt/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.staradvertiser.com/2018/10/30/breaking-news/supreme-court-rules-in-favor-of-tmt/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;article-excerpt&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;excerpt&quot;&gt;The Hawaii Supreme Court issued a decision today that supports the construction of the Thirty Meter Telescope atop Mauna Kea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-content&quot; readability=&quot;94.684696150175&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;carousel-story&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;bxslider&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;carousel-story-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; src=&quot;http://www.staradvertiser.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/web1_2018-WEB-TMT-rendering.jpg&quot; class=&quot;attachment-full size-full&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.staradvertiser.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/web1_2018-WEB-TMT-rendering.jpg 640w, http://www.staradvertiser.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/web1_2018-WEB-TMT-rendering-300x200.jpg 300w, http://www.staradvertiser.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/web1_2018-WEB-TMT-rendering-600x400.jpg 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COURTESY NAOJ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An artist’s rendering of the Thirty Meter Telescope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box-ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;title-ads&quot;&gt;ADVERTISING&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hawaii Supreme Court issued a decision today that supports the construction of the Thirty Meter Telescope atop Mauna Kea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 73-page ruling, the court affirmed 4-1 the state Board of Land and Natural Resources’ decision to issue a construction permit for the $1.43 billion project. The DLNR’s decision to issue the conservation district use permit had been appealed by TMT opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The telescope would be the biggest and most expensive in the Northern Hemisphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“On behalf of the TMT International Observatory, we are grateful for the Hawaii State Supreme Court’s ruling that will allow TMT to be built on Mauna Kea. We thank all of the community members who contributed their thoughtful views during this entire process,” Henry Yang, chair of the TMT International Observatory Board of Governors, said in a statement in response to the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We remain committed to being good stewards on the mountain and inclusive of the Hawaiian community. We will honor the culture of the islands and its people and do our part to contribute to its future through our ongoing support of education and Hawaii Islands’ young people. We are excited to move forward in Hawaii and will continue to respect and follow state and county regulations, as we determine our next steps. We are deeply grateful to our many friends and supporters for their tremendous support over the years,” Yang said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court in June heard oral arguments in the case, having rescinded the telescope’s permit 2-1/2 years ago on procedural grounds after protests had prevented construction on the mountaintop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protesters in 2014 broke up a groundbreaking for the TMT and then blockaded the mountain, preventing any construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mauna Kea is part of so-called “ceded lands” that originally belonged to the Hawaiian kingdom and are now administered by the state. In 1968, the University of Hawaii leased the top 11,000 acres of the mountain for a dollar a year, and began awarding subleases to various observatories for telescopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But some environmentalists and Native Hawaiian groups say the spread of observatories on the summit has polluted the mountain, interfering with traditional cultural and religious practices, or are actually infringing on the sovereignty of the Hawaiian kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent poll showed that a growing majority of Hawaiians favor building the telescope on Mauna Kea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The telescope, the Thirty Meter (named for the diameter of its main light-collecting mirror), has been 15 years in the planning. It would be one of three gargantuan telescopes now in the works that could transform astronomy in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirty Meter astronomers had said if they didn’t get a green light to build on Mauna Kea, they would build it on La Palma in the Canary Islands, off Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had been estimated that the telescope would be completed in 2029 if construction starts next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;View Hawaii Supreme Court Opinion on TMT on Scribd&quot; href=&quot;https://www.scribd.com/document/392007050/Hawaii-Supreme-Court-Opinion-on-TMT#from_embed&quot;&gt;Hawaii Supreme Court Opinion on TMT&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a title=&quot;View Honolulu Star-Advertiser's profile on Scribd&quot; href=&quot;https://www.scribd.com/user/31661381/Honolulu-Star-Advertiser#from_embed&quot;&gt;Honolulu Star-Advertiser&lt;/a&gt; on Scribd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;View Hawaii Supreme Court Opinion on Thirty Meter Telescope on Scribd&quot; href=&quot;https://www.scribd.com/document/392005015/Hawaii-Supreme-Court-Opinion-on-Thirty-Meter-Telescope#from_embed&quot;&gt;Hawaii Supreme Court Opinion on Thirty Meter Telescope&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a title=&quot;View Honolulu Star-Advertiser's profile on Scribd&quot; href=&quot;https://www.scribd.com/user/31661381/Honolulu-Star-Advertiser#from_embed&quot;&gt;Honolulu Star-Advertiser&lt;/a&gt; on Scribd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 17:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>okket</dc:creator>
<og:title>Hawaii Supreme Court rules in favor of building Thirty Meter Telescope</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.staradvertiser.com/2018/10/30/breaking-news/supreme-court-rules-in-favor-of-tmt/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The Hawaii Supreme Court issued a decision today that supports the construction of the Thirty Meter Telescope atop Mauna Kea.</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.staradvertiser.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/web1_2018-WEB-TMT-rendering.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.staradvertiser.com/2018/10/30/breaking-news/supreme-court-rules-in-favor-of-tmt/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Unicode Dicks</title>
<link>https://www.revk.uk/2018/10/unicode-dicks.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.revk.uk/2018/10/unicode-dicks.html</guid>
<description>One of the things that has always slightly amused and puzzled me is that unicode lacks a &quot;cock&quot; glyph. I mean, it seems to have characters and symbols from modern and historic cultures and forms of writing, and surely cave men have been drawing dicks on cave walls for tens of thousands of years, so why is this missing?&lt;p&gt;I can only assume someone is being prudish, and oddly enough people have used the eggplant 🍆 emoji for this, amongst others, so clearly there is a &quot;demand&quot; for this emoji.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I never realised, until now, is there would appears to be one already, thanks to Egyptian Hieroglyphs!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There seem to be three of them!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;𓂸𓂹 𓂺&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And for those of you on Windows with a censored font (what a thing!) this is what they look like.&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eL5uYschigc/W9m501E6q5I/AAAAAAAAHo8/gIiDg_MngawELXQsxSlqf3se4bfgplMlgCLcBGAs/s1600/Screenshot%2B2018-10-31%2Bat%2B14.14.02.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;227&quot; data-original-width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;172&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eL5uYschigc/W9m501E6q5I/AAAAAAAAHo8/gIiDg_MngawELXQsxSlqf3se4bfgplMlgCLcBGAs/s320/Screenshot%2B2018-10-31%2Bat%2B14.14.02.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are rather innocuously named U+130B8: EGYPTIAN HIEROGLYPH D052, U+130B9: EGYPTIAN HIEROGLYPH D052A, and U+130BA: EGYPTIAN HIEROGLYPH D053.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I cannot actually work out what the middle one is meant to be doing, to be honest. Looks painful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Someone will no doubt explain to me that in fact that is not what the hieroglyph is and that I just have a dirty mind, but if that were true, why are they apparently censored in some fonts?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reference: &lt;a href=&quot;http://xahlee.info/comp/unicode_egyptian_hieroglyph.html&quot;&gt;http://xahlee.info/comp/unicode_egyptian_hieroglyph.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who knew?!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;P.S. Why was I looking for unicode dicks? I was not, but was checking if hieroglyphs worked on my new card printing system, and to my surprise, they do! May have to be time for a new SSID I think :-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;P.P.S. (yes, all the daft ones are on 2.4GHz so don't impact any of our devices)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-WEsxF9KkmY8/W9nYpDVP17I/AAAAAAAAHpI/wKjiIoqevUoIqz4JdTUw--Xdir1oGs-wwCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_1383.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1402&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1125&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-WEsxF9KkmY8/W9nYpDVP17I/AAAAAAAAHpI/wKjiIoqevUoIqz4JdTUw--Xdir1oGs-wwCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_1383.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;P.P.P.S Wow, what a time to be alive!&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HDv8OUz4LRk/W9nawV_WLBI/AAAAAAAAHpU/MhZm-t_-3RwsUaqFzefuCv6oYeJQBJWbQCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_1385.PNG&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;739&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HDv8OUz4LRk/W9nawV_WLBI/AAAAAAAAHpU/MhZm-t_-3RwsUaqFzefuCv6oYeJQBJWbQCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_1385.PNG&quot; width=&quot;183&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 16:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>henkdevries</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.revk.uk/2018/10/unicode-dicks.html</og:url>
<og:title>𓂸</og:title>
<og:description>One of the things that has always slightly amused and puzzled me is that unicode lacks a &quot;cock&quot; glyph. I mean, it seems to have characters a...</og:description>
<og:image>https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eL5uYschigc/W9m501E6q5I/AAAAAAAAHo8/gIiDg_MngawELXQsxSlqf3se4bfgplMlgCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/Screenshot%2B2018-10-31%2Bat%2B14.14.02.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.revk.uk/2018/10/unicode-dicks.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Neuron, a new VS Code extension for data science</title>
<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/uk_faculty_connection/2018/10/29/data-science-in-visual-studio-code-using-neuron-a-new-vs-code-extension/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/uk_faculty_connection/2018/10/29/data-science-in-visual-studio-code-using-neuron-a-new-vs-code-extension/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Guest post by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/silvestri-lorenzo&quot;&gt;Lorenzo Silvestri&lt;/a&gt;, Electronic and Information Engineering Student at Imperial College London.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’ll give a short explanation of &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt;, a Visual Studio Code extension that aims to be a one-stop-shop for data scientists. It’s an extension I developed as part of a team of students at Imperial College London, in collaboration with Microsoft, in the summer of 2018.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A bit of context – a.k.a. why &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; exists in the first place&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science is the buzz-word of the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; century. From IoT devices generating thousands of data points per day, to social media connecting people’s information on a scale never seen before, a lot of the development that goes on today sooner or later comes into contact with “data science”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data scientists come from various different technical backgrounds, but the vast majority of them use a standard set of tools of the trade: Python, &lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;insert name of trending machine-learning library&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;, and Jupyter Notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Microsoft approached us with an idea. Can we integrate all of these tools into a single, intuitive workspace? More specifically, can we create an extension to Visual Studio Code that provided ways to run data analysis directly next to the code, without breaking the developer’s workflow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits of this are obvious. You get the power of an intelligent Python editor (Visual Studio Code), combined with the rapidity of execution and visualisation abilities of Jupyter Notebooks. All in a single window. Thus, &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; was born.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; does, and how to use it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principle of &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; is dead simple. You start off with your regular Python or R code editor – the bit you type code into – inside Visual Studio Code. Alongside it, taking up the other half of the screen, is &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a blank page at first, but as you run snippets of your code, the output gets turned into interactive cards. They can be plain text, tables, images, graphs, maps… you name it. Here’s a first look:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image0022.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;826&quot; height=&quot;536&quot; title=&quot;clip_image002&quot; alt=&quot;clip_image002&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image002_thumb2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Installing the extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; on the marketplace at &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=neuron.neuron-IPE&quot;&gt;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=neuron.neuron-IPE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once installed, a button will come up in the editor pane whenever you’re editing a supported file (currently, Python or R).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image0043.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;605&quot; height=&quot;62&quot; title=&quot;clip_image004&quot; alt=&quot;clip_image004&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image004_thumb3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking it will bring up the main &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; output pane, and you’re good to go.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Setting up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extension uses Jupyter Notebooks in the background to produce the visualisations that you know and love. If you’re a data scientist, chances are you already have Jupyter installed on your machine. If not, &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; will offer to install it for you when you first open the extension.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Using the interface&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to write some code. The extension currently supports Python and R, as they are the two most common languages used by data scientists. Let’s open a new Python file and write some code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image0064.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;455&quot; title=&quot;clip_image006&quot; alt=&quot;clip_image006&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image006_thumb4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not exactly Big Data, but you get the idea. To run this code and get the output, all we need to do is select it and hit &lt;strong&gt;Alt+Enter&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;option+return&lt;/strong&gt; on Macs). You can also right-click on your selection and select “Send code to output pane”, if you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And… here it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image0083.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;855&quot; height=&quot;536&quot; title=&quot;clip_image008&quot; alt=&quot;clip_image008&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image008_thumb3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A card with the output of your code appears on the right-hand side. You can delete it, move it up and down the list, minimise it, or expand it into a separate window. Neuron keeps track of the code snippets associated with each card, so that you can keep track of them and re-run them if needed.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Moving on to richer outputs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complicated visualisation of data is where &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; really shines. It supports more output types than Jupyter Notebooks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, a standard way of creating graphs in Python is through the popular library &lt;em&gt;plotly&lt;/em&gt;. Let’s try plotting some simple data points on a 2D plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from plotly.offline import download_plotlyjs, init_notebook_mode, plot, iplot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from plotly.graph_objs import Scatter, Figure, Layout&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iplot([{&quot;x&quot;: [1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8], &quot;y&quot;: [0, 1, 1, 2, 2, 3, 3, 4]}])&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, select the text, hit &lt;strong&gt;Alt+Enter&lt;/strong&gt;, and the card is generated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image0102.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;852&quot; height=&quot;1059&quot; title=&quot;clip_image010&quot; alt=&quot;clip_image010&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image010_thumb2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The card is interactive, so you can zoom and pan as necessary, as well as mark values on the graph or export the image to a PNG. If you want to edit the data points, all you need to do is go back to your original code, change some values, and run it again. The new card will appear just below the old one: &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; keeps track of your code’s history until you close Visual Studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neuron also supports 3D graphs, geographical maps, LaTeX formulas, markdown, HTML, and various static image types. The steps to generate them are the same as what I’ve demonstrated above, and you can find examples of all of them in our demo file below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image0122.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;786&quot; height=&quot;1135&quot; title=&quot;clip_image012&quot; alt=&quot;clip_image012&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image012_thumb2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image014.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;855&quot; height=&quot;408&quot; title=&quot;clip_image014&quot; alt=&quot;clip_image014&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image014_thumb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Try it yourself&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a hands-on tutorial to get started with &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt;, try our demo file that walks you through &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt;’s most useful features: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lorenzo2897/vscode-ipe/blob/master/test/demo.py&quot;&gt;https://github.com/lorenzo2897/vscode-ipe/blob/master/test/demo.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tips and tricks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filtering your output cards:&lt;/strong&gt; the list of cards can get a bit overwhelming to navigate if you’ve been running lots of code snippets. Filter the cards by keywords or by card type, using the search box and the filter button in the toolbar of the output pane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is Jupyter acting up?&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re getting strange and inconsistent errors when running your Python code, it might be helpful to restart the Jupyter instance running in the background. There’s an option in the command palette called “IPE: Restart active kernels” that does just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharing your output with others:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; supports interoperability with Jupyter notebooks. You can import an existing notebook using the “IPE: Import Jupyter notebook” command, and it will convert all Jupyter cells to cards. Likewise, you can export the state of your output pane into a notebook, via the “Export” button in the extension’s toolbar.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m really excited to share with you that Microsoft has decided to integrate the work that we did in &lt;em&gt;neuron&lt;/em&gt; into the Python extension for Visual Studio Code. You can track the project’s progress at the Python extension’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://emea01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2FMicrosoft%2Fvscode-python&amp;amp;data=02%7C01%7Cleestott%40microsoft.com%7C7437400eef1f43dbeb2208d63f69571b%7C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%7C1%7C0%7C636766119012741564&amp;amp;sdata=sTyOq0ZOT0D6yaDjrSzNxENMWzbzoT1IhlvchvwdRns%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&quot;&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt;. I look forward to seeing what you create with it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 14:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>starbugs</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Data Science in Visual Studio Code using Neuron, a new VS Code extension</og:title>
<og:url>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/uk_faculty_connection/2018/10/29/data-science-in-visual-studio-code-using-neuron-a-new-vs-code-extension/</og:url>
<og:description>Guest post by Lorenzo Silvestri, Electronic and Information Engineering Student at Imperial College London. Introduction In this post, I’ll give a short explanation of neuron, a Visual Studio Code extension that aims to be a one-stop-shop for data scientists. It’s an extension I developed as part of a team of students at Imperial College London,...</og:description>
<og:image>https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/10/clip_image002_thumb2.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/uk_faculty_connection/2018/10/29/data-science-in-visual-studio-code-using-neuron-a-new-vs-code-extension/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>