<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Motel 6 to Pay $12M after Improperly Giving Guest Lists to ICE</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/2019/04/05/710137783/motel-6-to-pay-12-million-after-improperly-giving-guest-lists-to-ice</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/2019/04/05/710137783/motel-6-to-pay-12-million-after-improperly-giving-guest-lists-to-ice</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res710147682&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/04/05/ap_19094713817781-80df9f9bcc6c9efff3a74138906ef8cb1b9dd8e5-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/04/05/ap_19094713817781-80df9f9bcc6c9efff3a74138906ef8cb1b9dd8e5-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hotel chain Motel 6 agreed on Thursday to pay $12 million to settle a lawsuit filed by Washington state claiming hotel guest information was improperly provided to immigration officials, according to Attorney General Bob Ferguson. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Elaine Thompson/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Elaine Thompson/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/04/05/ap_19094713817781-80df9f9bcc6c9efff3a74138906ef8cb1b9dd8e5-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The hotel chain Motel 6 agreed on Thursday to pay $12 million to settle a lawsuit filed by Washington state claiming hotel guest information was improperly provided to immigration officials, according to Attorney General Bob Ferguson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Elaine Thompson/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated at 7:50 a.m. ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hotel chain Motel 6 has agreed to pay $12 million to settle a lawsuit filed by the state of Washington after several locations gave information on thousands of guests to Immigration and Customs Enforcement without warrants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington state Attorney General Bob Ferguson said Thursday that Motel 6 shared the information of about 80,000 guests in the state from 2015 to 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That led to targeted investigations of guests with Latino-sounding names, according to Ferguson. He said many guests faced questioning from ICE, detainment or deportation as a result of the disclosures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's the second settlement over the company's practice in recent months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motel 6 also has signed a legally binding &lt;a href=&quot;https://agportal-s3bucket.s3.amazonaws.com/uploadedfiles/Another/News/Press_Releases/ConsentDecreeMotel6.pdf&quot;&gt;commitment&lt;/a&gt; to no longer share guest information without a warrant at any of its locations nationwide, a practice the chain says it has already ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Motel 6's actions tore families apart and violated the privacy rights of tens of thousands of Washingtonians,&quot; Ferguson said &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atg.wa.gov/news/news-releases/ag-ferguson-motel-6-will-pay-12m-violating-privacy-tens-thousands-washingtonians&quot;&gt;in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Our resolution holds Motel 6 accountable for illegally handing over guests' private information without a warrant.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company told NPR in an emailed statement that, as part of the agreement, it would &quot;continue to enforce its guest privacy policy, which prohibits the sharing of guest information except in cases where a judicially enforceable warrant or subpoena is present, or local law requires this information.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The company has also implemented a system of additional controls to ensure corporate oversight and compliance in cases where law enforcement requests are made.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res710146248&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage575567251&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/01/04/575567251/motel-6-gave-guest-information-to-immigration-agents-lawsuit-says&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/thetwo-way\/2018\/01\/04\/575567251\/motel-6-gave-guest-information-to-immigration-agents-lawsuit-says&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/01/04/ap_18003719615954_sq-5f16860179246fdec13d36bea2afa26c09ae1299-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/01/04/ap_18003719615954_sq-5f16860179246fdec13d36bea2afa26c09ae1299-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Motel 6 Gave Guest Information To Immigration Agents, Lawsuit Says&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoenixnewtimes.com/news/motel-6-calling-ice-undocumented-guests-phoenix-immigration-lawyers-9683244&quot;&gt;The Phoenix New Times&lt;/a&gt; first uncovered the practice in September 2017 when reporter Antonia Farzan investigated two Motel 6 locations in Phoenix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We got a tip that this was happening, started talking to local immigration attorneys and definitely kept hearing from people that this was a trend,&quot; Farzan told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2017/09/15/551339907/motel-6-locations-in-phoenix-share-guest-lists-with-ice-agents&quot;&gt;NPR's Ari Shapiro&lt;/a&gt; at the time. &quot;They didn't really know what was behind it but that they kept seeing people get picked up at Motel 6.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following initial media reports, Motel 6 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/motel6/status/908453005296619521&quot;&gt;released a statement&lt;/a&gt; saying that the practice had been discontinued and that it would issue a directive to each of its locations to clarify &quot;that they are prohibited from voluntarily providing daily guest lists to ICE.&quot; The hotel said at the time that the practice was implemented &quot;at the local level without the knowledge of senior management.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington state &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/01/04/575567251/motel-6-gave-guest-information-to-immigration-agents-lawsuit-says&quot;&gt;sued the company&lt;/a&gt; a few months later, alleging employees at seven locations in the Puget Sound region violated state consumer-protection law when they also released guest information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferguson said at the time that the hotels would turn over entire guest lists to authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;According to our interviews with employees at Motel 6,&quot; he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2018/01/06/576197682/washington-state-sues-motel-6-over-sharing-guest-immigration-data&quot;&gt;told NPR's Scott Simon&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;ICE agents would circle the names that looked Latino-sounding and ran those names through a database and then would detain individuals based on those random checks.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res710146517&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage664737581&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2018/11/06/664737581/motel-6-agrees-to-pay-millions-after-giving-guest-lists-to-immigration-authoriti&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/2018\/11\/06\/664737581\/motel-6-agrees-to-pay-millions-after-giving-guest-lists-to-immigration-authoriti&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/06/ap_18190606841302_sq-08a5bd63c0d56943c9d26d8ec554941d5f409b33-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/06/ap_18190606841302_sq-08a5bd63c0d56943c9d26d8ec554941d5f409b33-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Motel 6 Agrees To Pay Millions After Giving Guest Lists To Immigration Authorities &quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statement from Ferguson about Thursday's settlement detailed several cases of guests whose names were provided to ICE, including one Seattle man who stayed at a Motel 6 near Sea-Tac for one night, wrapping Christmas presents for his children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;ICE agents approached him in the hotel's parking lot, detained him and deported him some days later,&quot; the statement reads. &quot;The man was the sole provider for the household, and his wife is currently struggling to support their toddler and four other children.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motel 6 has agreed to also train its employees not to release guest information improperly and maintain a 24-hour hotline to help employees when they receive requests for information. The company will also be required to create a tool on its website for guests to report possible violations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state says more than $10 million of the settlement fund will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atg.wa.gov/motel-6-settlement-claim-information&quot;&gt;paid out&lt;/a&gt; to affected guests — including those who did not have any contact with ICE after their information was disclosed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November, Motel 6 settled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2018/11/08/665833059/motel-6-agrees-to-pay-7-6-million-to-former-guests-to-settle-lawsuit&quot;&gt;a separate lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; filed in Arizona by the Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund. That lawsuit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/01/23/580149434/motel-6-sued-for-identifying-latino-guests-for-immigration-agents&quot;&gt;identified eight Latino plaintiffs&lt;/a&gt; who were detained, including one who was deported.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 18:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>duxup</dc:creator>
<og:title>Motel 6 To Pay $12 Million After Improperly Giving Guest Lists To ICE</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/2019/04/05/710137783/motel-6-to-pay-12-million-after-improperly-giving-guest-lists-to-ice</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Washington state's attorney general said Motel 6 shared information about approximately 80,000 guests in the state and that guests faced questioning from ICE, detainment and deportation as a result.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/04/05/ap_19094713817781_wide-dcb31694083bcbd7dce2f482d64601e8ebb5e8e6.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/2019/04/05/710137783/motel-6-to-pay-12-million-after-improperly-giving-guest-lists-to-ice</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Battery Power&amp;#039;s Latest Plunge in Costs Threatens Coal, Gas</title>
<link>https://about.bnef.com/blog/battery-powers-latest-plunge-costs-threatens-coal-gas/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://about.bnef.com/blog/battery-powers-latest-plunge-costs-threatens-coal-gas/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;London and New York, March 26, 2019&lt;/em&gt; – Two technologies that were immature and expensive only a few years ago but are now at the center of the unfolding low-carbon energy transition have seen spectacular gains in cost-competitiveness in the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest analysis by research company BloombergNEF (BNEF) shows that the benchmark levelized cost of electricity,&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.bnef.com/blog/battery-powers-latest-plunge-costs-threatens-coal-gas/#_ftn1&quot; name=&quot;_ftnref1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or LCOE, for lithium-ion batteries has fallen 35% to $187 per megawatt-hour since the first half of 2018. Meanwhile, the benchmark LCOE for offshore wind has tumbled by 24%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onshore wind and photovoltaic solar have also gotten cheaper, their respective benchmark LCOE reaching $50 and $57 per megawatt-hour for projects starting construction in early 2019, down 10% and 18% on the equivalent figures of a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elena Giannakopoulou, head of energy economics at BNEF, commented: “Looking back over this decade, there have been staggering improvements in the cost-competitiveness of these low-carbon options, thanks to technology innovation, economies of scale, stiff price competition and manufacturing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our analysis shows that the LCOE per megawatt-hour for onshore wind, solar PV and offshore wind have fallen by 49%, 84% and 56% respectively since 2010. That for lithium-ion battery storage has dropped by 76% since 2012, based on recent project costs and historical battery pack prices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most striking finding in this LCOE Update, for the first-half of 2019, is on the cost improvements in lithium-ion batteries. These are opening up new opportunities for them to balance a renewables-heavy generation mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Batteries co-located with solar or wind projects are starting to compete, in many markets and without subsidy, with coal- and gas-fired generation for the provision of ‘dispatchable power’ that can be delivered whenever the grid needs it (as opposed to only when the wind is blowing, or the sun is shining).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electricity demand is subject to pronounced peaks and lows inter-day. Meeting the peaks has previously been the preserve of technologies such as open-cycle gas turbines and gas reciprocating engines, but these are now facing competition from batteries with anything from one to four hours of energy storage, according to the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tifenn Brandily, energy economics analyst at BNEF, said: “Solar PV and onshore wind have won the race to be the cheapest sources of new ‘bulk generation’ in most countries, but the encroachment of clean technologies is now going well beyond that, threatening the balancing role that gas-fired plant operators, in particular, have been hoping to play.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offshore wind has often been seen as a relatively expensive generation option compared to onshore wind or solar PV. However, auction programs for new capacity, combined with much larger turbines, have produced sharp reductions in capital costs, taking BNEF’s global benchmark for this technology below $100 per MWh, compared to more than $220 just five years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giannakopoulou said: “The low prices promised by offshore wind tenders throughout Europe are now materializing, with several high-profile projects reaching financial close in recent months. Its cost decline in the last six months is the sharpest we have seen for any technology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the LCOE of solar PV has fallen 18% in the last year, the great majority of that decline happened in the third quarter of 2018, when a shift in Chinese policy caused there to be a huge global supply glut of modules, rather than over the most recent months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-163444 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://data.bloomberglp.com/professional/sites/24/LCOE-press-release-edited.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;944&quot; height=&quot;776&quot; srcset=&quot;https://data.bloomberglp.com/professional/sites/24/LCOE-press-release-edited.jpg 944w, https://data.bloomberglp.com/professional/sites/24/LCOE-press-release-edited-300x247.jpg 300w, https://data.bloomberglp.com/professional/sites/24/LCOE-press-release-edited-768x631.jpg 768w, https://data.bloomberglp.com/professional/sites/24/LCOE-press-release-edited-793x652.jpg 793w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 944px) 100vw, 944px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BNEF’s LCOE analysis is based on information on real projects starting construction and proprietary pricing information from suppliers. Its database covers nearly 7,000 projects across 20 technologies (including the various types of coal, gas and nuclear generation as well as renewables), situated in 46 countries around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.bnef.com/blog/battery-powers-latest-plunge-costs-threatens-coal-gas/#_ftnref1&quot; name=&quot;_ftn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; LCOE measures the all-in expense of producing a MWh of electricity from a new project, taking into account the costs of development, construction and equipment, financing, feedstock, operation and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veronika Henze&lt;br/&gt;BloombergNEF&lt;br/&gt;+1-646-324-1596&lt;br/&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:vhenze@bloomberg.net&quot;&gt;vhenze@bloomberg.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 17:46:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>matt4077</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Battery Power's Latest Plunge in Costs Threatens Coal, Gas | Bloomberg NEF</og:title>
<og:description>Lithium-ion batteries and offshore wind both see dramatic gains in competitiveness during the last year compared to longer-established energy options.</og:description>
<og:url>https://about.bnef.com/blog/battery-powers-latest-plunge-costs-threatens-coal-gas/</og:url>
<og:image>https://data.bloomberglp.com/professional/sites/24/south-korea-wind-farm.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://about.bnef.com/blog/battery-powers-latest-plunge-costs-threatens-coal-gas/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Computer Graphics from Scratch (2017)</title>
<link>http://www.gabrielgambetta.com/computer-graphics-from-scratch/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.gabrielgambetta.com/computer-graphics-from-scratch/</guid>
<description>&lt;header&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt; This book will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; teach you how to use OpenGL or DirectX; instead, it can teach you how OpenGL and DirectX &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt;. In practice you won’t write a software renderer for production use, but understanding how and why a renderer works will let you use OpenGL and DirectX more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer Graphics is a fascinating topic - how do you make &lt;em&gt;Toy Story&lt;/em&gt; out of algorithms and some geometric data? Interestingly enough, it’s a mysterious topic not only for the average cinema fan, but also for world-class engineers who just haven’t been exposed to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer Graphics is also a frighteningly broad topic. From 3D rendering to photographic image filters, from fonts to particle systems, there’s a multitude of disciplines that can be categorized under CG. This work focuses exclusively on 3D rendering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computer Graphics from scratch&lt;/strong&gt; is my humble attempt to demystify that slice of Computer Graphics in an accessible way. It can be easily understood by high-school students, while covering the same topics of an university course. It is, in fact, based on my years of teaching the subject at my university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s little pre-requisite knowledge, nor hardware or software dependencies. The only primitive used in the book is a method that lets us set the color of a pixel - hence &lt;strong&gt;“from scratch”&lt;/strong&gt;. The algorithms are conceptually simple, and the math is straightforward. There is some high-school level trigonometry. There’s some basic Linear Algebra as well, but I’m including an appendix that can be consulted as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is divided in two main parts, &lt;strong&gt;Raytracing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Rasterization&lt;/strong&gt;, which focus on the two main ways to make pretty pictures out of data. The &lt;strong&gt;Common concepts&lt;/strong&gt; chapter introduces some basic knowledge necessary to understand these two parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus of this work is not on performance, but on clear conceptual exposition. The sample code is, well, &lt;em&gt;sample code&lt;/em&gt;, written in the most &lt;em&gt;clear&lt;/em&gt; way possible, which may not be the most &lt;em&gt;efficient&lt;/em&gt; way to implement the algorithms. Where there are different ways to do something, I’ve chosen the easiest to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “end result” of this work is two complete, fully functional renderers: a raytracer and a rasterizer. Although they follow very different approaches, they produce similar results when used to render a simple scene:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.gabrielgambetta.com/computer-graphics-from-scratch/images/comparison-1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;While their sets of features have considerable overlap, they aren’t identical, so this book covers their specific strenghts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.gabrielgambetta.com/computer-graphics-from-scratch/images/comparison-2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book provides sample code throughout the text, as somewhat informal pseudocode; it also provides fully working implementations written in JavaScript that can run directly on your browser, rendering to a &lt;code&gt;canvas&lt;/code&gt; element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-read-this&quot;&gt;Why read this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work should give you all the knowledge necessary to write software renderers. Although in the age of GPUs few people have good reasons to write a pure software renderer, the experience of writing one is valuable for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shaders&lt;/strong&gt;. The first GPUs had their algorithms hardcoded in hardware, but in modern ones you’re expected to write your own shaders. In other words, you’re still implementing big chunks of rendering software, except it now runs on the GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether you’re using a fixed pipeline or writing your own shaders, &lt;em&gt;understanding&lt;/em&gt; what’s going on behind the scenes lets you use the fixed pipeline better and write better shaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fun&lt;/strong&gt;. Few areas of Computer Science have the kind of immediately visible results offered by Computer Graphics. The sense of accomplishment you get when your SQL query runs just right is &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; compared to what you feel the first time you get ray traced reflections right. I taught Computer Graphics at my university for 5 years. I often wondered why I enjoyed teaching the same thing semester after semester for so long; in the end, what made it worth it was seeing the faces of my students light up and use their first renders as desktop backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;work-in-progress&quot;&gt;Work in progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a work in progress. Here’s a non-exhaustive to do list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Texture filtering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Normal mapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textures in the raytracer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shadows in the rasterizer (stencil and shadow maps)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reflection in the rasterizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand the CSG and Refraction sections into chapters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linear algebra appendix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make demos interactive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean up demo code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to contribute or to correct mistakes - all the text, diagrams and demos are in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggambetta/computer-graphics-from-scratch&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. PRs welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-author&quot;&gt;About the author&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a software engineer who founded and ran a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mysterystudio.com&quot;&gt;game development company&lt;/a&gt; (which you haven’t heard of), worked at Google (which you have heard of), and now works at &lt;a href=&quot;http://improbable.io&quot;&gt;Improbable&lt;/a&gt; (who have a good shot at building the Matrix, for real - or at the very least revolutionise multiplayer game development).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I taught Computer Graphics for 5 years at my university, where it was a semester-long 3rd year subject. I am grateful to all of my students, who served as unwitting guinea pigs for the materials that have inspired this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have other interests besides Computer Graphics, engineering-related and otherwise. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://gabrielgambetta.com&quot;&gt;my website&lt;/a&gt; for more details and contact information.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;centered&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Found an error?&lt;/span&gt; Everything is in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggambetta/computer-graphics-from-scratch&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 17:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pcr910303</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.gabrielgambetta.com/computer-graphics-from-scratch/introduction.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>2.7M Americans Still Get Netflix DVDs in the Mail</title>
<link>https://edition.cnn.com/2019/04/04/media/netflix-dvd-subscription-mail-trnd/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://edition.cnn.com/2019/04/04/media/netflix-dvd-subscription-mail-trnd/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2019/04/04/media/netflix-dvd-subscription-mail-trnd/&quot;&gt;https://edition.cnn.com/2019/04/04/media/netflix-dvd-subscription-mail-trnd/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19584540&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19584540&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 348&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 311&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 16:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.gabrielgambetta.com/computer-graphics-from-scratch/introduction.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mate: Netflix browser extension for learning words via subtitles</title>
<link>https://www.matetranslate.com/netflix</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.matetranslate.com/netflix</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;comp-jab8xt7y&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.matetranslate.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.wixstatic.com/media/862b71_524c980e615b4d66b669336e03690178%7Emv2.png_srz_136_40_85_22_0.50_1.20_0.00_png_srz&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentURL&quot; width=&quot;136&quot; height=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;container&quot; id=&quot;comp-jtyaxo7i&quot; readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;comp-jty7wpuh&quot; class=&quot;Text&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_8&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Learn new vocabulary in a fun and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_8&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;efficient way – with your favorite series.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;comp-jtyaxa39&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.wixstatic.com/media/862b71_bc9f6b84d0cd46fc9bf9e9aa7ff1694e%7Emv2.png_srz_600_301_85_22_0.50_1.20_0.00_png_srz&quot; alt=&quot;Artboard.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentURL&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;301&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;comp-jtybyyxu&quot; class=&quot;Text&quot; readability=&quot;22.666666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_8&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Free download: &lt;span&gt;Mate Translate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/instant-translate-transla/ihmgiclibbndffejedjimfjmfoabpcke&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chrome&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/instant-translate/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Firefox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.opera.com/en/extensions/details/instant-translate-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; or&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/mate-translate-translator-dictionary/9pj8vl1pqs7v?rtc=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Edge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;comp-jtyiyecb&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.wixstatic.com/media/862b71_adad56884f7a46578bfd55b50fda6e10%7Emv2.png_srz_383_383_85_22_0.50_1.20_0.00_png_srz&quot; alt=&quot;landing-netflix-3.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentURL&quot; width=&quot;383&quot; height=&quot;383&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;font_6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Click on words or select phrases&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;font_6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;with the mouse to translate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;font_6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;See a translation right in the player. With synonyms, phonetic transcription and the speak-out feature to learn pronunciation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;font_6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;You can save translated vocabulary to learn in future in one click!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;font_6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Words are automatically categorized by&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;font_6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;series and episode names. No mess.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;comp-jtyj1n17&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.wixstatic.com/media/862b71_3a4d371985b045b79ced043ae56874a0%7Emv2.png_srz_600_300_85_22_0.50_1.20_0.00_png_srz&quot; alt=&quot;landing-netflix-2.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentURL&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;comp-jtybvr61&quot; class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;font_6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Export saved vocab to &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/id1328924282&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reji&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to practice spelling and pronunciation with spaced repetition on iOS. For free.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;comp-jtzte5b6&quot; class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;font_6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reji.me/blog/learn-new-words-with-favorite-netflix-series/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Read about export and learning on our blog →&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;font_6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;A video is worth 1,000 words:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/328216046&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;277&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;comp-jtybwvi4&quot; class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;font_6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mate is available as a browser extension for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/instant-translate-transla/ihmgiclibbndffejedjimfjmfoabpcke&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chrome&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/instant-translate/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Firefox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/p/instant-translate-select-and-translate/9pj8vl1pqs7v?rtc=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Edge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.opera.com/en/extensions/details/instant-translate-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Opera&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It supports 103 languages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;comp-jtyj9cdx&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;comp-ju4f0yfv&quot; class=&quot;Text&quot; readability=&quot;31.293103448276&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_8&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mate is an all-in-one translator to help you understand and learn 103 languages. Also available as &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twopeoplesoftware.com/mate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/id1073473333&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; apps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;comp-ju4f214f&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;comp-jtyi3ozi&quot; class=&quot;Text&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_8&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;If you want this for YouTube, too, leave your email.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_8&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We'll let you know when it's available!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;container&quot; id=&quot;comp-ju4eudvw&quot;&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;container&quot; id=&quot;comp-ju4eurol&quot; readability=&quot;0.98571428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;comp-ju4eusdw&quot;/&gt; &lt;a id=&quot;comp-ju4eusdb&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;Button&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;comp-ju4eused&quot; class=&quot;Text&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_8&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Thanks for submitting! We'll let you know as soon as it's available!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 16:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<og:title>Mate Translate for Netflix – learn and translate words from subtitles</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.matetranslate.com/netflix</og:url>
<og:image>https://static.wixstatic.com/media/862b71_7f3f594b205f400291d65c6c4df3fc03%7Emv2_d_2560_1286_s_2.png/v1/fill/w_1200%2Ch_627%2Cal_c%2Cusm_0.66_1.00_0.01/862b71_7f3f594b205f400291d65c6c4df3fc03%7Emv2_d_2560_1286_s_2.png</og:image>
<og:description>Click on words in the Netflix's subtitles to translate and save words. Learn vocabulary with your favorite series in 103 languages. Available for Chrome, Firefox, Opera and Edge.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.matetranslate.com/netflix?_escaped_fragment_=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I&amp;#039;m Joining CloudFlare</title>
<link>https://words.steveklabnik.com/i-m-joining-cloudflare</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://words.steveklabnik.com/i-m-joining-cloudflare</guid>
<description>&lt;time datetime=&quot;2019-04-05&quot; class=&quot;article_time&quot;&gt;April 5, 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/jpH1brqXUvSAz1tNQ8uVKb0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/jpH1brqXUvSAz1tNQ8uVKb0xspap_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cloudflare logo.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I signed an offer letter from Cloudflare. I’ll be the product manager of Storage, which is the part of the company that’s working on data storage products for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/products/cloudflare-workers/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare Workers&lt;/a&gt; platform. I’ll be starting at the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of you will say “that makes perfect sense,” but many more will say “wait, what?”. I hope this post will make things a bit more clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we start, I also want to say that I’ll still be continuing my work on Rust, though obviously in a more limited capacity. I’ll still be working on revisions to &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/book/&quot;&gt;The Rust Programming Language&lt;/a&gt;, and doing core team work, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before I worked on Rust, I worked on and with Ruby on Rails. When I got out of the web application game, the hot topic was this new “platform as a service” stuff. I’ve been watching all of the latest changes from afar, and they’ve been quite interesting. I’ve always loved the web, and the people building it. In the last 18 months or so, I’ve also been extremely interested in WebAssembly. Working at Cloudflare is the intersection of four things for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Edge compute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebAssembly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal and career growth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;edge-compute_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/i-m-joining-cloudflare#edge-compute_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;Edge Compute&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s sort of been four eras of “how do I web server”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Physical servers (“on premise”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infrastructure as a service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platform as a service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Function as a service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of people see the relationship between these things as “what you control” vs “what does the provider control”, but I don’t think that’s quite right. But I’m getting ahead of myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the day, if you wanted a web site, you bought a physical server, and you put it in a data center somewhere. I wasn’t around for those days. The point is, you managed everything: the hardware, the software. All of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shapeways.com/blog/archives/305-CloudFab-Distributed-Fabrication-3D-printing,-Nick-Pinkston-interview.html&quot;&gt;my days as a startup CTO&lt;/a&gt;, my services were deployed to a Virtual Private Server. Instead of owning servers ourselves, we rented a virtual machine, running on someone else’s servers. This is “infrastructure as a service”; I didn’t have to worry about machines, I could just ask for one, and it’d be given to me. I still had to manage the operating system and everything above it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun side note: CloudFab was a Rails application with a big C extension to do data processing that was too much for Ruby. This later informed a lot of my Rust work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up came “platform as a service.” To me, Heroku was the platonic ideal of this era. Now, you didn’t even need to manage servers. You got to worry about your application, and that’s it. Maybe you’d need to set a slider to scale during times of demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading a lot about “functions as a service” over the past few years. Instead of deploying an entire application, each endpoint becomes an application, basically. This is where I think the previous thinking about the relationships between these categories of service is a little wrong. The actual underlying trend here is something else: what affordances do I have to scale?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the on-premise days, if I wanted to add capacity, I’d need to buy new servers, install them, set everything up. There’s a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of latency there. And if I need to remove capacity, well, I have to sell those servers? The move to infrastructure as a service was significant, because it more clearly separated concerns. Each company didn’t need a data center; a data center provides homogeneous compute. As a user, if I need to scale, I can spin up some more virtual servers much more quickly than I can physical ones. Managing that required a lot of tooling, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the insight that led to platform as a service: by managing this tooling, you could make it even easier for users to scale. There’s a reason why the slider became the ubiquitous synonym with PaaS. There’s nothing that you could do with PaaS that was impossible with IaaS, but it was much, much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings us to Functions as a Service, also known as “serverless.” The reason that this architecture matters is one very similar to previous insights. By breaking your application into multiple functions, they can scale independently. This is one of the dreams of microservice architecture, but there’s a bit of a difference. Microservice architecture focuses on how you build your system, and how you split up components internally. FaaS focuses on how people interact with your system, and splits up the components according to that. This framing is a bit more significant to your ability to scale, because it means that during times of high load, you can scale only the parts under that load. In the same way that IaaS said “let’s not force people to buy servers to scale” and PaaS said “let’s not force people to build out infrastructure to scale”, FaaS says “let’s not force people to scale their help page to scale their shopping cart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings us to edge compute. Edge compute is a particular kind of FaaS, but an interesting take on it. Here’s the concept: your users are all over the world. Why do their packets need to go to &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;us-east-1&lt;/code&gt; and back? To which you might say, “sure, that’s why we’ve developed our application to work in multiple regions.” That’s the same relationship between IaaS and PaaS. That is, why should you have to worry about making your application be available across multiple regions? You may not be worrying about individual physical servers anymore, but you’re still worrying about data centers. And some FaaS products, like AWS Lambda, can already run easily across multiple regions, and with some setup, go between them. However, Amazon has about 20 total regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how is edge compute different? Well, at some point, various CDN companies realized “wait a minute. We have severs around the world. Why can’t we run compute on them as well?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: Cloudflare is not really a CDN company, though that’s how I always thought of them. They do a lot more stuff than CDNs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is interesting because, well, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/&quot;&gt;here’s those 20 Amazon regions&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/qxGa9h6TshtRrXZmh6tsRU0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/qxGa9h6TshtRrXZmh6tsRU0xspap_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;awsregions.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compare this with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastly.com/network-map&quot;&gt;Fastly’s network&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/ePzMAv7Q4NVLARUKambWH80xspap.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/ePzMAv7Q4NVLARUKambWH80xspap_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;map_POP.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/network/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare’s network&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/bQzn9XqBY98mw269Q1tsdH0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/bQzn9XqBY98mw269Q1tsdH0xspap_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;cloudflarenetwork.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(the page is animated, so those highlighted ones don’t mean anything)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re much likely to be physically closer to a Fastly or Cloudflare server than you are an AWS one. And that’s what we mean by “edge compute”, that is, you’re running your code on the edge, rather than in the data center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I should also mention that there is a form of Lambda called Lambda@Edge that runs off of CloudFront locations, rather than the above map. So that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/vwJvtVvGK7DpGZYEPcrjzW0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/vwJvtVvGK7DpGZYEPcrjzW0xspap_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;cloudfront.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much better! My point about regions is more applicable to “edge compute” vs more general compute, than saying something about Lambda as a particular product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CloudFlare Workers don’t require you to think about where your service is deployed: when you upload it, it’s automatically running on all 175 locations, within minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this space is interesting and significant. Cloudflare has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/products/cloudflare-workers/&quot;&gt;Workers&lt;/a&gt;, and Fastly has &lt;a href=&quot;https://wasm.fastlylabs.com/&quot;&gt;Terrarium&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon has &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/lambda/latest/dg/lambda-edge.html&quot;&gt;Lambda@Edge&lt;/a&gt;. These are all very interesting platforms for building high performance applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My role as part of Storage will be to consider “what does data access and storage look like in this world?” If your code is moved to the edge, but your data is still in a central server, you don’t gain the full benefit of having the code close to the client. There’s a lot of interesting stuff in this space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;webassembly_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/i-m-joining-cloudflare#webassembly_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;WebAssembly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both ClouldFlare Workers and Fastly’s Terrarium use &lt;a href=&quot;https://webassembly.org/&quot;&gt;WebAssembly&lt;/a&gt; as a core part of the platform. And that’s significant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;7.0778816199377&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;If WASM+WASI existed in 2008, we wouldn’t have needed to created Docker. That’s how important it is. Webassembly on the server is the future of computing. A standardized system interface was the missing link. Let’s hope WASI is up to the task! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/wnXQg4kwa4&quot;&gt;https://t.co/wnXQg4kwa4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Solomon Hykes (@solomonstre) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/solomonstre/status/1111004913222324225?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 27, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for this stuff to work, you need a runtime for WebAssembly. One interesting thing we’re seeing in this space is sort of two parallel paths emerge: do you want to support JavaScript, or not? Recently, Fastly open sourced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastly.com/blog/announcing-lucet-fastly-native-webassembly-compiler-runtime&quot;&gt;Lucet&lt;/a&gt;, the WebAssembly runtime that powers Terrarium. It’s an impressive bit of tech. There are others too, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://wasmer.io/&quot;&gt;Wasmer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CraneStation/wasmtime&quot;&gt;Wasmtime&lt;/a&gt;. By focusing purely on WebAssembly, you can build specialized tech, and it can be really, really fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, you can’t compile JavaScript to WebAssembly. You can sort of do it with AssemblyScript, a TypeScript subset the compiles to wasm. But JavaScript is arguably the most popular programming language in the world. I personally believe in JavaScript, even with the rise of WebAssembly. And so Cloudflare is taking a different approach than those projects. Instead of building a wasm-only runtime, they’re building on top of Google’s V8. This means that they can support both WebAssembly and JavaScript in workers. Additionally, by leaning on V8, you can take advantage of all of the excellent engineering resources that Google pours into it, similar to how the Rust compiler gets to take advantage of people working on improving LLVM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the point is, WebAssembly is core to this new edge compute world. And so I’m excited to be in the space. I know people that work at Fastly, wasmer, and Mozilla, and they’re all doing great work. I think there’s space for both approaches, but I’m mostly excited to be there and see how it all turns out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, one other thing I wanted to say: right now, everything around Workers is closed source. Kudos to Fastly for open-sourcing Lucet. I asked about this in my interview, and Cloudflare is very interested in doing more open source work, and so I’m hoping it doesn’t take us long to catch up in this regard. We’ll see, of course, I haven’t actually started yet. But I think that this stuff needs to be open source, personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may remember a little story called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloudbleed&quot;&gt;CloudBleed&lt;/a&gt;. In short, Cloudflare had a pretty bad security bug in 2017. This bug happened because of a parser, written in Ragel. Here, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/incident-report-on-memory-leak-caused-by-cloudflare-parser-bug/&quot;&gt;I’ll let Cloudflare explain it&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ragel code is converted into generated C code which is then compiled. The C code uses, in the classic C manner, pointers to the HTML document being parsed, and Ragel itself gives the user a lot of control of the movement of those pointers. The underlying bug occurs because of a pointer error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CloudBleed happened due to memory unsafety. When talking to Cloudflare today, it’s pretty clear that this bug was taken extremely seriously, to the point where it created a culture change inside the company itself. These days, it seems to me (I haven’t started yet, mind you) that you have to use a memory safe language by default, and only use a memory unsafe one if you have an extremely good justification. But Cloudflare needs to be able to have a lot of performance, and control latency, in much of their stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter Rust. Cloudflare started exploring Rust after CloudBleed, and now uses a significant amount of Rust in production. They host the local Rust meetup here in Austin, and sometimes the one in San Francisco. I’m excited to help Cloudflare be successful with Rust, and to use that experience to help improve Rust too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My understanding is that I’ll be dealing with a bunch of TypeScript and possibly Go as well, which is also pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;career-growth_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/i-m-joining-cloudflare#career-growth_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;Career growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the move to product management. I really enjoy product work, and have had several jobs that were sorta-kinda product jobs. I don’t think that management jobs are inherently better than engineer jobs, of course, but it’s a way for me to grow. My role at Balanced was sorta-kinda-PM-y, and I loved that job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t have too much more to say about this, just that it’s a bit different, but something I’m really excited to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;i39m-excited-for-the-future_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/i-m-joining-cloudflare#i39m-excited-for-the-future_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;I’m excited for the future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, that’s my extremely long-winded explanation of what’s going on. I’m not starting until the end of the month, so I’ve got a few weeks to purely enjoy. I’ll still be playing a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.celestegame.com/&quot;&gt;Celeste&lt;/a&gt; and Fortnite, writing blog posts, and working on some Rust open source. But then I get to get back to work. I’m pumped about all of this! New role, building some new tech with tech I already love.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;583&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;583&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 16:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steveklabnik</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://words.steveklabnik.com/i-m-joining-cloudflare</og:url>
<og:title>I'm joining Cloudflare • Steve Klabnik</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Yesterday, I signed an offer letter from Cloudflare. I’ll be the product manager of Storage, which is the part of the company that’s working on data storage products for the Cloudflare Workers platform. I’ll be starting at the end of the month. I... | Steve Klabnik | “The most violent element in society is ignorance.” - Emma Goldman</og:description>
<og:image>https://svbtleusercontent.com/jpH1brqXUvSAz1tNQ8uVKb0xspap.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://words.steveklabnik.com/i-m-joining-cloudflare</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The U.S. just had the most Q1 layoffs in a decade</title>
<link>https://www.axios.com/us-q1-layoffs-in-a-decade-6309b133-5212-4204-976b-347de6f4ad41.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.axios.com/us-q1-layoffs-in-a-decade-6309b133-5212-4204-976b-347de6f4ad41.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Embed__root--xU4tk&quot;&gt;

Data: Challenger, Gray &amp;amp; Christmas, Inc; Chart: Axios Visuals&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;qa-keep-reading KeepReading__keepReadingOpen--24exR&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;KeepReading__centeringWrapper--3lH-G&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;KeepReading__keepReading--3wXA5&quot;&gt;Go deeper&lt;span class=&quot;KeepReading__wordCount--1PMdk&quot;&gt;178 Words&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;hidden-6309b133-5212-4204-976b-347de6f4ad41&quot; class=&quot;&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;false&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StoryBody__paragraph--2-Doz&quot;&gt;The U.S. saw its highest level of layoffs in a first quarter since 2009, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.challengergray.com/press/press-releases/march-2019-job-cuts-report-60587-cuts-add-highest-quarterly-total-q3-2015&quot; class=&quot;StoryBody__link--10w8x&quot;&gt;data from staffing firm Challenger, Gray &amp;amp; Christmas&lt;/a&gt; released Thursday showed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StoryBody__paragraph--2-Doz&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By the numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; Employers cut 190,410 jobs in the first 3 months of the year — 10.3% higher than the number of layoffs announced in the fourth quarter of 2018 and 35.6% higher than job cuts announced in the same quarter of 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StoryBody__paragraph--2-Doz&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The impact:&lt;/strong&gt; It's the highest number of job cuts in a quarter since 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StoryBody__paragraph--2-Doz&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details:&lt;/strong&gt; The financial industry saw the third highest number of layoffs and the year-to-date total was 239% higher than it was in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;StoryBody__item--1cHYD&quot;&gt;Retailers continue to lead all sectors in job cuts this year with 46,061 in Q1. However, that number is 18.5% lower than retail cuts announced in Q1 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;StoryBody__item--1cHYD&quot;&gt;Retailers have announced plans to close 4,048 stores so far this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;StoryBody__paragraph--2-Doz&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bottom line:&lt;/strong&gt; The report said worry about an economic slowdown was the main driver of companies' layoff intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StoryBody__paragraph--2-Doz&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go deeper ...&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/job-growth-march-hit-18-month-low-private-payrolls-underperformed-527299b5-b9da-4764-87fe-67b8c7e8e70c.html&quot; class=&quot;InternalLoadLink__root--17C4m StoryBody__link--10w8x 527299b5-b9da-4764-87fe-67b8c7e8e70c-6309b133-5212-4204-976b-347de6f4ad41&quot;&gt;&quot;Job market is weakening&quot;: Private payroll job growth hits 18-month low&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 15:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Reedx</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.axios.com/us-q1-layoffs-in-a-decade-6309b133-5212-4204-976b-347de6f4ad41.html</og:url>
<og:title>The U.S. just had the most Q1 layoffs in a decade</og:title>
<og:description>Employers cut 190,410 jobs in the first 3 months of 2019.</og:description>
<og:image>https://images.axios.com/5c6Z936PySenBWTbkB1gOZWVOTo=/0x515:4942x3295/1920x1080/2019/04/05/1554471963074.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.axios.com/us-q1-layoffs-in-a-decade-6309b133-5212-4204-976b-347de6f4ad41.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>CityBound – An open source city simulation game in Rust</title>
<link>https://github.com/citybound/citybound</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/citybound/citybound</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/citybound/citybound/blob/master/cb.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/citybound/citybound/raw/master/cb.png&quot; alt=&quot;Citybound&quot; width=&quot;192&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citybound is a city building game with a focus on realism, collaborative planning and simulation of microscopic details. It is independently developed, open source and funded through Patreon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a living and open document, find out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/citybound/citybound/blob/CONTRIBUTING.md&quot;&gt;how to contribute your suggestions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citybound is a city building game with a focus on realism, collaborative planning and simulation of microscopic details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Subtopics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simulated World
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Player Interaction
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engine and Support Libraries
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aeickhoff/kay&quot;&gt;kay&lt;/a&gt; - enabling distributed simulation &amp;amp; multiplayer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aeickhoff/descartes&quot;&gt;descartes&lt;/a&gt; - computational geometry and GIS algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Games
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books/Ideas
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Citybound is a game about:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The beauty of emergent complexity,&lt;/strong&gt; in the familiar example of a city. (&lt;code&gt;EMERGENCE&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The challenge of understanding &lt;code&gt;INTERDEPENDENT SYSTEMS&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; that form a whole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The experience of &lt;code&gt;PLANNING&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; i.e. having a complex idea, developing it, carefully preparing it and making it real.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The experience of &lt;code&gt;COLLABORATION&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; the way humans work together to achieve great things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interplay between the &lt;strong&gt;player's conscious action and the cities' organic reaction&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;code&gt;CITY AS AN ORGANISM&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citybound aspires to:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;INTERACTION BY PAINTING&lt;/code&gt;, i.e. through powerful but simple tools with haptic qualities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CLARITY OF CAUSE AND EFFECT&lt;/code&gt;, making patterns of behavior and consequences of one’s actions obvious- in the small and in the large&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Gameplay Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cities are built in large continuous regions with several million inhabitants (&lt;code&gt;VASTNESS&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time progresses in &lt;code&gt;OVERLAID TIME-SCALES&lt;/code&gt;: Daily and yearly activities happen at a similar pace. (&lt;code&gt;MULTI-SCALE PHENOMENA&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cities consist of persistent &lt;code&gt;UNIQUE INDIVIDUALS&lt;/code&gt;, i.e. people &amp;amp; businesses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Develop systems from first principles, with complex behaviors emerging from simple microscopic interactions &lt;code&gt;(emergence)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solve problems generally, do not restrict thinking in specialized problem instances &lt;code&gt;(actual problem)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be brave to do things in new ways, where necessary &lt;code&gt;(radicality)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use Rust as the main programming language for high performance and a strong type system to rely on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use an actor-based model for isolation, dynamic dispatch and simple parallelization and networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a Rust &amp;amp; JavaScript combination to implement a cross-platform, WebGL based UI that communicates with a simulation backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Hierarchy of Player Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Building a city&quot;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Observation &amp;amp; Inspection&quot;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Planning&quot;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Execution &amp;amp; Finances&quot;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simulation core takes care of the progression and scales of in-game time by frequently updating continuous processes as well as sending one-off notifications and timeouts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prior Art &amp;amp; Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Compressed and overlaid timescales to make the player experience short-term and long-term phenomena at once &lt;code&gt;(multi-scale)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Subtopics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Planning
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Construction
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Road Trips &amp;amp; Pathfinding
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pedestrian Traffic (0% alpha)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Road Traffic (50% alpha)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rail Traffic (0% alpha)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water Traffic (0% beta)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Air Traffic (0% beta)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Traffic is the pulse of a city &lt;code&gt;(city = organism)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic is a chaotic emergent phenomenon (&lt;code&gt;EMERGENCE&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic shapes the city and the city shapes traffic &lt;code&gt;(interdependent systems)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic shapes lives and lives shape traffic &lt;code&gt;(interdependent systems)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People and goods use a multitude/combinations of transport systems &lt;code&gt;(diverse individuals)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pedestrians &amp;amp; vehicles move &quot;like different kinds of swarms/liquids&quot; &lt;code&gt;(diverse individuals)&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;(city = anthill)&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;(vastness)&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;(flows)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;individuals are the most visible when they are on the move&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;crowds look antsy, sprawling, colorful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cars can flow nicely but also get really pushy, different types/sizes of cars have obviously different silhouettes and movement patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trains and boats are heavy and careful, they have impressive momentum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planes are graceful and precise but need a lot of space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Always model each trip individually and microscopically (never use statistical models) &lt;code&gt;(actual problem)&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;(emergence)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Physical motion through time/space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realistic use of potentially several modes of transport in sequence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Counteract time-compression with generous behaviour parameters (but never cheat, i.e. teleport) &lt;code&gt;(actual problem) (time compression)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pedestrians, road traffic, public transport and freight transport of all kinds are all equally important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parking is a core problem &amp;amp; component of road traffic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simulation goal: trips are successful often enough and efficient enough to power all economic transaction realistically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All kinds of traffic are &quot;vessels/bodies moving along the edges of a transport network graph&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Optimal granularity of traffic simulation: simulate the most strongly locally interacting traffic entities (e.g. cars on one lane) all at once within one actor (one lane = one actor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Gameplay &amp;amp; Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Building a city&quot;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Planning&quot;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Transport Infrastructure Planning&quot;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy &amp;amp; Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep car interactions as local as possible computationally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cars themselves are not actors, one lane is the atomic actor,&lt;/strong&gt; it updates all the cars on it in one go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cars mostly move along a lane like a train, only on switch lanes they can move sideways to merge between normal lanes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cars react to general obstacles, which are either the next car on their own lane, or cars on interacting lanes, whose position is mapped onto the current lane
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Interactions are distinguished as parallel/opposing/merging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interacting lanes after each update exchange their cars as obstacles for the other lane&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use well-known 1D acceleration and breaking model and extend it to multi-lane behaviour
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cars on switch lanes have more complex behaviour, reacting to cars on their left &amp;amp; right lanes and other cars merging between them.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Based on the perceived risk/required breaking, merging cars can decide to abort their merge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/citybound/citybound/blob/lane/README.md&quot;&gt;Road Lanes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The complex fabric of real road geometry goes beyond &quot;streets&quot; and &quot;intersections&quot;, which at best can be understood as loose groups of related lanes (&lt;code&gt;EMERGENCE&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ACTUAL PROBLEM&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Design Decision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The atomic unit of road geometry in Citybound is the individual lane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roads and intersections are just collections of lanes &lt;code&gt;(emergence)&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;(flexibility)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Really make individual lanes the main abstraction, only group them into higher abstractions when absolutely necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If possible, only handle a group of &quot;nearby/related&quot; lanes temporarily while using a tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/citybound/citybound/blob/planning/README.md&quot;&gt;Road Planning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Each lane keeps track of
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;it's connectivity to preceding/following lanes (connected to it's start or end)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lanes it overlaps, distinguishing between nearly-parallel overlaps and opposing overlaps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special case: two parallel lines that can be merged between are not directly connected
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;instead, an invisible &quot;switch lane&quot; is placed along their range of overlap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lanes on either side have a special parallel overlap relation ship to the switch lane only, not to each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the reason for this is that merging car behaviour is a more complex special case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/citybound/citybound/blob/microtraffic/README.md&quot;&gt;Car Microtraffic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prior Art &amp;amp; Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All macro-economic behaviours arise from interactions of individual households (families, companies) &lt;code&gt;(emergence)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of households have both selfish and shared goals, resulting in a trade-off between individuality and cooperation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locality of households and interactions is essential and enables all kinds of logistics and distributed industries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;All resources that have to physically moved in real life have to also be moved in Citybound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real estate market is a huge factor in shaping a city&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The character of a city is largely determined by the sum of its industries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of consumed resources and services depend on complex chains of earlier resources, these resource chains/trees are at the core of shaping industries, the required logistics and thus also a city&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The player is not supposed to manage supply/demand/resource chains, but to enable them to be as effective as possible, through the means of infrastructure planning and zoning/governance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the amount of information presented in the game might go way beyond realistically knowable things, this contrast in availability of information compared to the real world has an educational and almost call-to-action aspect to it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuals act as a lens to see the game world from, other than the players birds-eye-view&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall &quot;macro&quot; appearance of the city hints at general issues which might inspire you to investigate in detail&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide both omniscient-level information about individuals as well as realistic large-scale indicators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually model the real estate market with ownership and businesses, including city government ownership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All complex resources can only be a) traded or b) created from its component parts, never &quot;out of nowhere&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having to rely on absolute amounts for resources makes balancing very hard and amplifies bugs and makes the system potentially very unstable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The amount of different resource types and how fine-grained they are is to be chosen as minimal as possible, while still producing interesting and prevalent resource chains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Resources represent both tangible goods as well as intangible (psychological, physiological, social) metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of these are measured using scalar values, from -infinity to infinity
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;these values represent how well a household is doing on a particular resource (0 representing ideal), not necessarily absolute stockpile values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One household and its associated resources are always tied to one specific building/location - if this is one location of a larger company, these cooperate mostly as if they were separate businesses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Crafting recipes&quot; to determine both how resource combine, at which costs, and which businesses do that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Parts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Households (20% alpha)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markets
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Building a city&quot;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Observation &amp;amp; Inspection&quot;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Inspecting Resource Chains&quot;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Godmode-style knowledge
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Inspect all consumers of the products of a business&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Inspect all the source producers of input resources of a business&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Inspect the full journey/lifecycle of an end product, including becoming waste/...&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Business surplus/deficits per resource category&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Infer bottlenecks/problems by showing all related &quot;nodes&quot; in the economic network of one particular business, including paths&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realistic knowledge
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Infer industry composition based on evident architectural styles&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Directly show all businesses of a precise resource category&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Infer causes of homelessness&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Learn from protests&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Learn from topical advisors&quot; ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Learn about a neighborhood by looking at it&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Planning&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Execution &amp;amp; Finances&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prior Art &amp;amp; Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Parts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Prior Art &amp;amp; Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Code version control systems and file difference visualizers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blueprints/ghost parts in Factorio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In reality it is not only physically impossible to instantaneously build infrastructure, but there are good reasons why planning is employed before even deciding what to build &lt;code&gt;(planning)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Plans are easy to revise and iterate on, changing existing structure is extremely costly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can start planning something even when you do not have the permission or resources to implement the plan yet. In fact, you might need to have a plan to show in order to acquire the necessary permission and resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning should be as flexible and forgiving as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The player only ever interacts directly with plans. The only way to affect construction of infrastructure is through implementation of plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plans have full undo/redo history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plans clearly show structures to be added and to be removed relative to what exists. &lt;code&gt;(clarity)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modifications of existing structures seamlessly become part of a plan, this should feel as tangible as creating new structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Materialized Reality&quot; and plans exists in completely different &quot;spheres&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Instead of keeping a perfect, complicated two-way mapping between plans and implemented reality at all times, they are kept separate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When new structures are added to a plan or previously planned and implemented structures are modified within the plan, they are compared geometrically in detail with the materialized reality to calculate the actual diff of what would change when implementing the new plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep pathfinding information local and dynamically changeable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make use of the &quot;highway effect&quot; (for most of each trip, only the rough source and rough destination determine the typically important main connections to choose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be able to create a trip from household to household (not necessarily precise addresses)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trips are a persistent representation of each ongoing trip (since cars themselves are not actors, but exist on road actors, or are exchanged as messages)
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trips can be created from and to &quot;rough&quot; locations (such as households), which are then first resolved to precise locations on the road network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a simple two-layer landmark model for the pathfinding itself:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;nodes&quot; (individual lanes) and &quot;landmarks&quot; (groups of lanes, represented as one rough destination)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nodes store closest-next-hop information to &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; landmarks, but only to nodes up to a certain distance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if a node is too far away, first navigate towards its parent landmark, until a direct next-hop is known&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lanes organically join/leave landmarks, keeping landmarks continuous each, and of roughly equal group size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lanes exchange information about changed/updated next-hops with their local neighbors (similar to router table updates), forming an eventually converging network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prior Art &amp;amp; Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Actions -&amp;gt; Effects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Effects -&amp;gt; Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Feedback -&amp;gt; Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Prior Art &amp;amp; Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Parts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Not only the exchange of physical goods influences the decision-making of families, but intangible psychological, physiological, social metrics play an equally if not more important role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no central happiness metric, but only individual diverse motivations that vary both over time as well as from person to person - one can only get a rough overview of &quot;how well someone is doing&quot; by looking at all of them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 15:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>formalsystem</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/15174518?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>citybound/citybound</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/citybound/citybound</og:url>
<og:description>A work-in-progress, open-source, multi-player city simulation game. - citybound/citybound</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/citybound/citybound</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Buy Yourself a Latte</title>
<link>https://ritholtz.com/2019/04/buy-yourself-a-fking-latte/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ritholtz.com/2019/04/buy-yourself-a-fking-latte/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;pf-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Latte a Day Isn’t Going to Ruin Your Retirement&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;If spending $5 a day on fancy coffee puts your retirement at risk, you’ve got bigger problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-03/buying-a-latte-every-day-won-t-ruin-your-retirement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;, April 3, 2019&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: A milder version of this was published at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-03/buying-a-latte-every-day-won-t-ruin-your-retirement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week; that version failed to fully express how I feel on the subject . . . &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Sorry, but no. If a daily latte is the difference between achieving your financial success or suffering devastating failure, then there must be something else you are doing entirely wrong…&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/eFMlr4hMqA&quot;&gt;https://t.co/eFMlr4hMqA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Barry Ritholtz (@ritholtz) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ritholtz/status/1111736455687294977?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 29, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It’s a cliché that refuses to die: personal finance guru Suzy Orman &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/03/28/suze-orman-spending-money-on-coffee-is-like-throwing-1-million-down-the-drain.html&quot;&gt;warned&lt;/a&gt; investors last week that if you “&lt;strong&gt;waste money on coffee, it’s like ‘&lt;em&gt;peeing $1 million down the drain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I disagree, and have &lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/2015/10/never-buy-a-boat-and-other-misguided-financial-advice/&quot;&gt;repeatedly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/even-if-you-could-pick-huge-winners-could-you-hold-them/2014/10/03/bd426e34-49ba-11e4-891d-713f052086a0_story.html&quot;&gt;done&lt;/a&gt; so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/get-there/a-rollicking-week-in-the-markets-is-really-a-chance-to-clean-up-your-act/2015/08/28/78451d94-4b36-11e5-bfb9-9736d04fc8e4_story.html?utm_term=.64cde832b3a2&quot;&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/2019/01/anti-resolutions/&quot;&gt;years&lt;/a&gt;. If the difference between financial success and failure is the cost of a cup of coffee, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/2016/08/inflation-look-right-places/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/wages-in-america/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/2016/08/inflation-things-need-vs-things-want/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.northwesternmutual.com/2018-05-08-1-In-3-Americans-Have-Less-Than-5-000-In-Retirement-Savings&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;bigger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2018/08/07/for-most-us-workers-real-wages-have-barely-budged-for-decades/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;problems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. A daily $5 latte does not amount to much in the grand &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.economist.com/blogs/prospero/2013/01/finance-guru-bubble&quot;&gt;scheme&lt;/a&gt; of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mind you, I am not against people saving money and we all know our society is way too materialistic.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; But we need to be honest about the actual challenges facing us; I find the &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/business/2016/05/the-latte-is-a-lie-and-buying-coffee-has-nothing-to-do-with-debt-an-excerpt-from-helaine-olens-pound-foolish.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Latte bull$hit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to be a distraction from genuine financial issues in society.*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is what really gets me annoyed: Orman tells her audience that “&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/z5pW7bFcVN4&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your Daily Coffee Habit Is Costing You $1 Million&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,” with this calculation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Let’s say you spend around $100 on coffee each month. If you were to put that $100 into a Roth IRA instead, after 40 years the money would have grown to around $1 million with a 12 percent rate of return.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nope&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a nonsense calculation. Worse, it is intellectually dishonest. The actual numbers, as we see below, are anywhere from 50 percent to 75 percent less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s consider five reasons why you should occasionally treat yourself to a cup of Joe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Numbers Don’t Add Up&lt;/strong&gt;: 12 percent annual returns for 40 years? That’s nearly 50 percent better than what markets give you (with dividends reinvested). I &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; have a billion dollars for anyone who can get my clients those fat 12 percent returns annually for the next 4 decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More realistic are returns around ~8 percent annually. If you invested $100 per month for 40 years (total contributions of $48,000), the compounded returns would be somewhere between $300-350,000.&lt;sup&gt;2 &lt;/sup&gt; And from our present highish U.S. equity valuation, even lower expected returns are not an unreasonable posture.&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; But 12% annually? &lt;em&gt;PUH-leeze.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Inflation Adjust It&lt;/strong&gt;: Note that the $350k is in nominal, not inflation-adjusted dollars. By the year 2060, assuming a modest 2-3 percent inflation rate, $300k won’t be all that big of a number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some perspective, 40 years ago the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=nuKg&quot;&gt;median house&lt;/a&gt; cost about $62,000 (its over $317,400 today); &lt;a href=&quot;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/MEHOINUSA646N&quot;&gt;median income&lt;/a&gt; was under $20,000 (its $61,372 today). In 2060, you should expect $300,000 to be about $80-100k today. When we inflation adjust the returns of not buying yourself a cup of coffee every day for 40 years, you might be able to buy yourself an okay car – assuming anyone is even buying cars in 2060.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Remove the denominator blindness&lt;/strong&gt;: Numbers out of context are so misleading, and this one is no exception. Instead, you need to put any number into context via its relationship with other related items. In this case, that six-figure latte compounded appreciation should be put into context relative to the rest of ones’ earnings and/or portfolio appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It requires a meaningful &lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/2015/10/dont-suffer-from-denominator-blindness/&quot;&gt;denominator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next 40 years, a moderate sized portfolio plus contributions and appreciation can add up to millions of dollars. And a person’s lifetime earnings? If you earn only the median income of 61,372 – and never receive a raise for 40 years – that adds up to $2,454,880. If you get a mere 3 percent raise annually, that becomes closer to 5 million dollars ($4.63m); five percent annual raises lead to almost seven and a half million dollars in cumulative gross earnings.&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing $90k (inflation adjusted) out of $5 million lifetime earnings shows how insignificant a daily cup of cappuccino actually is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Focus on large fixed costs, not small discretionary ones&lt;/strong&gt;: No doubt, Americans do not save enough. We are looking at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-07-09/the-good-and-the-bad-of-retirement-saving&quot;&gt;retirement&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/2018/07/retirement-savings-going/&quot;&gt;crisis&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here is where the coffee nonsense gets called out for the bull$hit it really is&lt;/em&gt;: We have had flat wages for three decades; economic mobility is near all-time lows. Health care keeps going up; college has become an economic absurdity as student debt is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://studentloanhero.com/student-loan-debt-statistics/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;over $1.56 trillion dollars&lt;/a&gt;. The costs of what we &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; keep rising, while the cost of the junk we &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; keeps falling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/2018/10/the-robust-no-good-excellent-terrible-recovery/&quot;&gt;fixed costs&lt;/a&gt;, is that they are well, fixed. This means they are very difficult or impossible to cut back on. Housing, health care, and education are all expensive; Coffee, even good coffee, is not. (Same with &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/153440/medias-dumb-avocado-hysteria&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;avocado toast&lt;/a&gt;).  Please excuse my lack of enthusiasm for discussing 4-dollar lattes while we ignore 30-plus years of zero real wage gains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Mental bandwidth&lt;/strong&gt;: Regardless of your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/family/archive/2018/06/marshmallow-test/561779/&quot;&gt;view&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stanford_marshmallow_experiment&quot;&gt;Stanford Marshmallow experiment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/science/sciencenow/la-sci-sn-marshmallow-test-kids-20180626-story.html&quot;&gt;delayed gratification&lt;/a&gt;, there is validity to the claim that will power is finite. All of us have more important issues to exhaust our willpower on than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are much bigger economic issues in everyone’s life, and that’s before we even bring up income inequality.  Anyone of these issues are far larger and more consequential than modest spending. All of us have better things to worry about than denying ourselves the occasional cup of fresh hot java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting out coffee is a minor issue; the big things – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2018/11/30/surprisingly-high-number-americans-getting-absolutely-no-raises/?utm_term=.acd5981f85a5&quot;&gt;income&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2016/04/why-dont-americans-save-money/478929/&quot;&gt;debt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/research/economic-mobility-is-the-american-dream-alive-and-well/&quot;&gt;economic mobility&lt;/a&gt;, inflation – matter &lt;u&gt;much, much more&lt;/u&gt;. The entire coffee nonsense is a huge distraction from the massive structural problems within our system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go enjoy a $5 Latte; and while you sip that warm, delicious brew, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/emilybinder/status/1113131366005334016&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;enjoy the benefits&lt;/a&gt;, ponder the enormous challenges facing millenials, future retirees, boomers — really anyone who is not fortunate enough to find themselves in the top 20 percent of the American economic strata. Its pretty clear that these penny-wise, pound-foolish solutions really miss the big picture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;______________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.stern.nyu.edu/~lbornkam/S15Seminar/gilovich_paper.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Thomas Gilovich&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubs.aeaweb.org/doi/pdfplus/10.1257/089533006776526030&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Alan Kreuger&lt;/a&gt;, who both have written that experiences bring greater happiness than material goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investor.gov/additional-resources/free-financial-planning-tools/compound-interest-calculator&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;According&lt;/a&gt; to the Securities and Exchange Commission’s compound interest calculator, that works out to about $350,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. We really have no idea what level reinvested dividends are going to be for the next 4 decades — they have been falling for the past 4 decades. I would surmise that $350k number is on the high side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. I understand a straight-line percentage raise of median income does not reflect the complex reality of hoe most workers’ earnings curve behaves; but it is a good ballpark figure to show some context for that &lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/2015/10/dont-suffer-from-denominator-blindness/&quot;&gt;denominator blindness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* Special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://helaineolen.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Heleine Olen&lt;/a&gt;, who has written about this extensively, both in her book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1591844894/thebigpictu09-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pound Foolish&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/business/2016/05/the-latte-is-a-lie-and-buying-coffee-has-nothing-to-do-with-debt-an-excerpt-from-helaine-olens-pound-foolish.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;online.&lt;/a&gt; As a guest on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/2016/03/masters-in-business-helene-olen/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;MIB podcast&lt;/a&gt;, she went off on the “&lt;em&gt;gurus, pundits, self-anointed experts, crackpots, cranks, and outright frauds who populate the backwaters and slipstreams of American finance&lt;/em&gt;.” You definitely want to hear what she has to say about Suze Orman…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I originally published this at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-03/buying-a-latte-every-day-won-t-ruin-your-retirement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;, April 3, 2019. All of my Bloomberg columns can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/contributors/AEq0WJRomcY/barry-l-ritholtz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ritholtz.com/category/writing/bloomberg-view-writing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;printfriendly pf-alignleft&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ritholtz.com/2019/04/buy-yourself-a-fking-latte/#&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.print(); return false;&quot; class=&quot;noslimstat&quot; title=&quot;Printer Friendly, PDF &amp;amp; Email&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.printfriendly.com/buttons/printfriendly-button.png&quot; alt=&quot;Print Friendly, PDF &amp;amp; Email&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 14:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>iron0013</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Buy Yourself a F*^king Latte - The Big Picture</og:title>
<og:description>A Latte a Day Isn’t Going to Ruin Your Retirement If spending $5 a day on fancy coffee puts your retirement at risk, you’ve got bigger problems. Bloomberg, April 3, 2019       Note: A milder version of this was published at Bloomberg earlier this week; that version failed to fully express how I…Read More</og:description>
<og:url>https://ritholtz.com/2019/04/buy-yourself-a-fking-latte/</og:url>
<og:image>https://ritholtz.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/1800x-1-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ritholtz.com/2019/04/buy-yourself-a-fking-latte/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The IRS Tried to Take on the Ultrawealthy – It Didn’t Go Well</title>
<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/ultrawealthy-taxes-irs-internal-revenue-service-global-high-wealth-audits</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.propublica.org/article/ultrawealthy-taxes-irs-internal-revenue-service-global-high-wealth-audits</guid>
<description>&lt;aside class=&quot;promo x-small left&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;top-notes&quot; readability=&quot;5.7655367231638&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note related-story&quot; readability=&quot;7.0960451977401&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProPublica is a nonprofit newsroom based in New York. Sign up for ProPublica's &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.propublica.org/20181219-apple&quot;&gt;Big Story newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to receive stories like this one in your inbox as soon as they are published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.0&quot;&gt;On June 30, 2016, an auto-parts magnate received the kind of news anyone would dread: The Internal Revenue Service had determined he had engaged in abusive tax maneuvers. He stood accused of masking about $5 billion in income. The IRS wanted over $1.2 billion in back taxes and penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.1&quot;&gt;The magnate, Georg Schaeffler, was the billionaire scion of a family-owned German manufacturer and was quietly working as a corporate lawyer in Dallas. Schaeffler had extra reason to fear the IRS, it seemed. He wasn’t in the sights of just any division of the agency but the equivalent of its SEAL Team 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.2&quot;&gt;In 2009, the IRS had formed a crack team of specialists to unravel the tax dodges of the ultrawealthy. In an age of widening inequality, with a concentration of wealth not seen since the Gilded Age, the rich were evading taxes through ever more sophisticated maneuvers. The IRS commissioner aimed to stanch the country’s losses with what he proclaimed would be “a game-changing strategy.” In short order, Charles Rettig, then a high-powered tax lawyer and today President Donald Trump’s IRS commissioner, warned that the squad was conducting “the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052748704865704575610641497495762&quot;&gt;audits from hell&lt;/a&gt;.” If Trump were being audited, Rettig wrote during the presidential campaign, this is the elite team that would do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-schaeffler-portrait-2x3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-schaeffler-portrait-2x3.jpg 400w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo800w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-schaeffler-portrait-2x3.jpg 800w&quot;/&gt; Georg Schaeffler faced a $1.2 billion tax bill after his company restructured a huge debt. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Julian Stratenschulte/picture alliance via Getty Images)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.0&quot;&gt;The wealth team embarked on a contentious audit of Schaeffler in 2012, eventually determining that he owed about $1.2 billion in unpaid taxes and penalties. But after seven years of grinding bureaucratic combat, the IRS abandoned its campaign. The agency informed Schaeffler’s lawyers it was willing to accept just tens of millions, according to a person familiar with the audit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.1&quot;&gt;How did a case that consumed so many years of effort, with a team of its finest experts working on a signature mission, produce such a piddling result for the IRS? The Schaeffler case offers a rare window into just how challenging it is to take on the ultrawealthy. For starters, they can devote seemingly limitless resources to hiring the best legal and accounting talent. Such taxpayers tend not to steamroll tax laws; they employ complex, highly refined strategies that seek to stretch the tax code to their advantage. It can take years for IRS investigators just to understand a transaction and deem it to be a violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.2&quot;&gt;Once that happens, the IRS team has to contend with battalions of high-priced lawyers and accountants that often outnumber and outgun even the agency’s elite SWAT team. “We are nowhere near a circumstance where the IRS could launch the types of audits we need to tackle sophisticated taxpayers in a complicated world,” said Steven Rosenthal, who used to represent wealthy taxpayers and is now a senior fellow at the Tax Policy Center, a joint venture of the Urban Institute and Brookings Institution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.3&quot;&gt;Because the audits are private — IRS officials can go to prison if they divulge taxpayer information — details of the often epic paper battles between the rich and the tax collectors are sparse, with little in the public record. Attorneys are also loath to talk about their clients’ taxes, and most wealthy people strive to keep their financial affairs under wraps. Such disputes almost always settle out of court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-pp-id=&quot;4&quot; data-pp-blocktype=&quot;aside&quot; class=&quot;text medium right&quot; readability=&quot;25.716981132075&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Have you been involved in a Global High Wealth audit?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so, we’d like to hear about your experiences! Email &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#3c56594f4f591259554f55525b594e7c4c4e534c495e50555f5d12534e5b&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;ff959a8c8c9ad19a968c9691989a8dbf8f8d908f8a9d93969c9ed1908d98&quot;&gt;[email protected]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or on Signal at 718-496-5233.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.0&quot;&gt;But ProPublica was able to reconstruct the key points in the Schaeffler case. The billionaire’s lawyers and accountants first crafted a transaction of unusual complexity, one so novel that they acknowledged, even as they planned it, that it was likely to be challenged by the IRS. Then Schaeffler deployed teams of professionals to battle the IRS on multiple fronts. They denied that he owed any money, arguing the agency fundamentally misunderstood the tax issues. Schaeffler’s representatives complained to top officials at the agency; they challenged document requests in court. At various times, IRS auditors felt Schaeffler’s side was purposely stalling. But in the end, Schaeffler’s team emerged almost completely victorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.1&quot;&gt;His experience was telling. The IRS’ new approach to taking on the superwealthy has been stymied. The wealthy’s lobbyists immediately pushed to defang the new team. And soon after the group was formed, Republicans in Congress began &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/how-the-irs-was-gutted&quot;&gt;slashing the agency’s budget&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, the team didn’t receive the resources it was promised. Thousands of IRS employees left from every corner of the agency, especially ones with expertise in complex audits, the kinds of specialists the agency hoped would staff the new elite unit. The agency had planned to assign 242 examiners to the group by 2012, according to a report by the IRS’ inspector general. But by 2014, it had only 96 auditors. By last year, the number had fallen to 58.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.2&quot;&gt;The wealth squad never came close to having the impact its proponents envisaged. As Robert Gardner, a 39-year veteran of the IRS who often interacted with the team as a top official at the agency’s tax whistleblower office, put it, “From the minute it went live, it was dead on arrival.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.0&quot;&gt;Most people picture IRS officials as all-knowing and fearsome. But when it comes to understanding how the superwealthy move their money around, IRS auditors historically have been more like high school physics teachers trying to operate the Large Hadron Collider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-commissioner-rettig-1x1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-commissioner-rettig-1x1.jpg 400w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo800w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-commissioner-rettig-1x1.jpg 800w&quot;/&gt; Charles Rettig, commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service, said if any group were auditing Donald Trump, it would be the Global High Wealth team. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Aaron P. Bernstein/Getty Images)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.0&quot;&gt;That began to change in the early 2000s, after Congress and the agency uncovered widespread use of abusive tax shelters by the rich. The discovery led to criminal charges, and settlements by major accounting firms. By the end of the decade, the IRS had determined that millions of Americans had secret bank accounts abroad. The agency managed to crack open Switzerland’s banking secrecy, and it recouped billions in lost tax revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.1&quot;&gt;The IRS came to realize it was not properly auditing the ultrawealthy. Multimillionaires frequently don’t have easily visible income. They often have trusts, foundations, limited liability companies, complex partnerships and overseas operations, all woven together to lower their tax bills. When IRS auditors examined their finances, they typically looked narrowly. They might scrutinize just one return for one entity and examine, say, a year’s gifts or income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.2&quot;&gt;Belatedly attempting to confront improper tax avoidance, the IRS formed what was officially called the Global High Wealth Industry Group in 2009. “The genesis was: If you think of an incredibly wealthy family, their web of entities somehow gives them a remarkably low effective tax rate,” said former IRS Commissioner Steven Miller, who was one of those responsible for creating the wealth squad. “We hadn’t really been looking at it all together, and shame on us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.3&quot;&gt;The IRS located the group within the division that audits the biggest companies in recognition of the fact that the finances of the 1 percent resemble those of multinational corporations more than those of the average rich person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-commissioner-miller-1x1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-commissioner-miller-1x1.jpg 400w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo800w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-commissioner-miller-1x1.jpg 800w&quot;/&gt; Former IRS Commissioner Steven Miller tried to fix the agency’s approach to auditing the ultrawealthy. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Nicholas Kamm/AFP/Getty Images)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.0&quot;&gt;The vision was clear, as Doug Shulman, a George W. Bush appointee who remained to helm the agency under the Obama administration, explained in a 2009 &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20120607014600/https:/www.irs.gov/newsroom/article/0,,id=216981,00.html&quot;&gt;speech&lt;/a&gt;: “We want to better understand the entire economic picture of the enterprise controlled by the wealthy individual.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.1&quot;&gt;It’s particularly important to audit the wealthy well, and not simply because that’s where the money is. That’s where the cheating is, too. Studies show that the wealthiest are more likely to avoid paying taxes. The top 0.5 percent in income account for fully a fifth of all the underreported income, according to a 2010 study by the IRS’ Andrew Johns and the University of Michigan’s Joel Slemrod. Adjusted for inflation, that’s more than $50 billion each year in unpaid taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.2&quot;&gt;The plans for the wealth squad seemed like a step forward. In a few years, the group would be staffed with several hundred auditors. A team of examiners would tackle each audit, not just one or two agents, as was more typical in the past. The new group would draw from the IRS’ best of the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.3&quot;&gt;That was crucial because IRS auditors have a long-standing reputation, at least among the practitioners who represent deep-pocketed taxpayers, as hapless and overmatched. The agents can fritter away years, tax lawyers say, auditing transactions they don’t grasp. “In private practice, we played whack-a-mole,” said Rosenthal, of the Tax Policy Center. “The IRS felt a transaction was suspect but couldn’t figure out why, so it would raise an issue and we’d whack it and they would raise another and we’d whack it. The IRS was ill-equipped.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.4&quot;&gt;The Global High Wealth Group was supposed to change that. Indeed, with all the fanfare at the outset, tax practitioners began to worry on behalf of their clientele. “The impression was it was all going to be specialists in fields, highly trained. The IRS would assemble teams with the exact right expertise to target these issues,” Chicago-based tax attorney Jenny Johnson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;The new group’s first moves spurred resistance. The team sent wide-ranging requests for information seeking details about their targets’ entire empires. Taxpayers with more than $10 million in income or assets received a dozen pages of initial requests, with the promise of many more to follow. The agency sought years of details on every entity it could tie to the subject of the audits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.6&quot;&gt;In past audits, that initial overture had been limited to one or two pages, with narrowly tailored requests. Here, a typical request sought information on a vast array of issues. One example: a list of any U.S. or foreign entity in which the taxpayer held an “at least a 20 percent” interest, including any “hybrid instruments” that could be turned into a 20 percent or more ownership share. The taxpayer would then have to identify “each and every current and former officer, trustee, and manager” from the entity’s inception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;newsletter newsletter-big-story large left&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Get Our Top Investigations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to the Big Story newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.0&quot;&gt;Taxpayers who received such requests recoiled. Attacking the core idea that Shulman had said would animate the audits, their attorneys and accountants argued the examinations sought too much information, creating an onerous burden. The audits “proceeded into a proctology exam, unearthing every aspect of their lives,” said Mark Allison, a prominent tax attorney for Caplin &amp;amp; Drysdale who has represented taxpayers undergoing Global High Wealth audits. “It was extraordinarily intrusive. Not surprisingly, these people tend to be private and are not used to sharing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.1&quot;&gt;Tax practitioners took their concerns directly to the agency, at American Bar Association conferences and during the ABA’s regular private meetings with top IRS officials. “Part of our approach was to have private sit-downs to raise issues and concerns,” said Allison, who has served in top roles in the ABA’s tax division for years. We were “telling them this was too much, unwieldy and therefore unfair.” Allison said he told high-ranking IRS officials, “You need to rein in these audit teams.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.2&quot;&gt;For years, politicians have hammered the IRS for its supposed abuse of taxpayers. Congress created a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/taxpayer-bill-of-rights&quot;&gt;Taxpayer Bill of Rights”&lt;/a&gt; in the mid-1990s. Today, the IRS often refers to its work as “customer service.” One result of constant congressional scrutiny is that senior IRS officials are willing to meet with top tax lawyers and address their concerns. “There was help there. They stuck their necks out for me,” Allison said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.3&quot;&gt;The IRS publicly retreated. Speaking at a Washington, D.C., Bar Association event in February 2013, a top IRS official, James Fee, conceded the demands were too detailed and long, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.taxnotes.com/tax-notes-today/compliance/lbis-global-high-wealth-industry-group-learning-past-mistakes/2013/02/27/f083?highlight=%22james%20fee%22%20%22global%20high%20wealth%22&quot;&gt;telling the gathering&lt;/a&gt; that the agency has “taken strides to make sure it doesn’t happen again.” The Global High Wealth group began to limit its initial document requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.4&quot;&gt;The lobbying campaign, combined with the lack of funding for the group, took its toll. One report estimated that the wealth team had audited &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.syr.edu/tracirs/newfindings/v17/&quot;&gt;only around a dozen wealthy taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; in its first two and a half years. In a September 2015 report, the IRS’ inspector general said the agency had failed to establish the team as a “standalone” group “capable of conducting all of its own examinations.” The group didn’t have steady leadership, with three directors in its first five years. When it did audit the ultrawealthy, more than 40 percent of the reviews resulted in no additional taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pym-src=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/graphics/embed-irs-assets?layout=embed&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;15.0&quot;&gt;The inspector general also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.treasury.gov/tigta/auditreports/2015reports/201530078fr.html&quot;&gt;criticized&lt;/a&gt; the IRS broadly — not just its high-wealth team — for not focusing enough on the richest taxpayers. In 2010, the IRS as a whole audited over 32,000 millionaires. By 2018, that number had fallen to just over 16,000, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.syr.edu/tracirs/latest/549/&quot;&gt;according to data compiled&lt;/a&gt; by Syracuse University. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/earned-income-tax-credit-irs-audit-working-poor&quot;&gt;Audits of the wealthiest&lt;/a&gt; Americans have collapsed 52 percent since 2011, falling more substantially than audits of the middle class and the poor. Almost half of audits of the wealthy were of taxpayers making $200,000 to $399,000. Those audits brought in $605 per audit hour worked. Exams of those making over $5 million, by contrast, brought in more than $4,500 an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;15.1&quot;&gt;The IRS didn’t even have the resources to pursue millionaires who had been hit with a hefty tax bill and simply stiffed Uncle Sam. It “appeared to no longer emphasize the collection of delinquent accounts of global high wealth taxpayers,” a 2017 inspector general report &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.treasury.gov/tigta/auditreports/2017reports/201730069fr.pdf&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;15.2&quot;&gt;In recent years, the number of Global High Wealth audits has been higher — it closed 149 audits in the last year — but tax lawyers and former IRS officials say even that improvement is deceptive. A major reason is that the audits are much less ambitious. “They were longer at the beginning and shorter as the process moved on,” Johnson, the tax attorney, said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;15.3&quot;&gt;Inside the IRS, agents seethed. “The whole organization was very frustrated,” Gardner said. “They were just really not sure what the hell their mission was, what they were supposed to be accomplishing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-300&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;18.0&quot;&gt;Georg Schaeffler, 54, has flowing salt-and-pepper hair that makes him look like he could’ve been an actor on the 1980s TV show “Dynasty.” The impression is offset by the wire rim glasses he wears and by the bookish disposition of a person who, as a teenager, once &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dmagazine.com/publications/d-magazine/2007/march/the-billionaire-next-door/&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; for a copy of the German Constitution as a present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;18.1&quot;&gt;As a younger man, Schaeffler tried to escape his legacy. He left Germany and the family company at a young age and lit out for the American West. He was trying to make it on his own “where people don’t know who you are,” as he would tell a reporter for a magazine profile years later. Some might escape to Texas to live a bit wild. Schaeffler became a corporate lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;18.2&quot;&gt;Schaeffler’s law firm colleagues didn’t know much more than that he spoke with an accent, and certainly not that he was vastly wealthy. That is, until he landed on the Forbes list of global billionaires. Rueful at the loss of his privacy, Schaeffler once declared: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dmagazine.com/publications/d-magazine/2007/march/the-billionaire-next-door/&quot;&gt;“I hate Forbes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;18.3&quot;&gt;The family’s riches stemmed from ball bearings and other automobile parts manufactured by the Schaeffler Group, which was founded by Schaeffler’s father and then passed to his mother after his father died. By 2006, Georg (pronounced GAY-org) owned 80 percent of the enterprise and his mother the remaining 20 percent. (As a Texas resident at that time, Schaeffler was required to pay U.S. income taxes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;18.4&quot;&gt;He very nearly lost it all. In 2008, Schaeffler Group made a big mistake. It offered to buy Continental AG, a tiremaker, just days before the stock and credit markets experienced their worst crisis since the Great Depression. Even as Continental’s stock price crashed, Schaeffler was legally obligated to go through with its purchase at the much higher pre-crash price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-schaeffler-3x2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-schaeffler-3x2.jpg 400w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo800w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-schaeffler-3x2.jpg 800w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo1600w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-schaeffler-3x2.jpg 1600w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo2000w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-schaeffler-3x2.jpg 2000w&quot;/&gt; Schaeffler and his mother, Maria-Elisabeth, ran into trouble after their family auto-parts company acquired tiremaker Continental AG in the middle of the financial crisis. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Julian Stratenschulte/picture alliance via Getty Images)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;20.0&quot;&gt;Schaeffler Group flirted with bankruptcy and pleaded for aid from the German government. The media began to pay closer attention to the private company and the low-profile family that ran it. German press accounts dismissed Schaeffler’s mother as the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europeanceo.com/lifestyle/highbrow-lifestyle-of-the-cunning-widow/&quot;&gt;billionaire beggar&lt;/a&gt;” for seeking a bailout and pilloried her for wearing a fur coat at a ski race while seeking government help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;20.1&quot;&gt;No German government aid came. The Schaeffler Group teetered, and the family’s fortune plummeted from $9 billion to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/joannmuller/2016/06/21/schaefflers-scary-ride-how-a-billionaire-family-lost-and-rebuilt-a-fortune-in-auto-parts/#717206c2373f&quot;&gt;almost zero&lt;/a&gt;. Amid the crisis over Continental, Georg accepted his fate and took up a more prominent role at the company; he’s now the chairman of its supervisory board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;20.2&quot;&gt;To pay for Continental, Schaeffler Group borrowed about 11 billion euros from a consortium of banks. At the time, Schaeffler’s lenders, including Royal Bank of Scotland, were desperate, too, having suffered enormous losses on home mortgages. They wanted to avoid any more write-downs that might result if the company defaulted on the loans. So in 2009 and 2010, Schaeffler’s lenders restructured the debt in a devilishly complex series of transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;20.3&quot;&gt;By 2012, these maneuvers had caught the eye of the Global High Wealth group. Paul Doerr, an experienced revenue agent, would head the audit. Eventually, the IRS discerned what it came to believe was the transaction’s essence: The banks had effectively forgiven nearly half of Schaeffler’s debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;20.4&quot;&gt;To the IRS, that had significant tax implications. In the wealth team’s view, Georg Schaeffler had received billions of dollars of income — on which he owed taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;20.5&quot;&gt;The auditors’ view reflects a core aspect of the U.S. tax system. Under American law, companies and individuals are liable for taxes on the forgiven portion of any loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;20.6&quot;&gt;This frequently comes up in the housing market. A homeowner borrows $100,000 from a bank to buy a house. Prices fall and the homeowner, under financial duress, unloads it for $80,000. If the bank forgives the $20,000 still owed on the original mortgage, the owner pays taxes on that amount as if it were ordinary income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;20.7&quot;&gt;This levy can seem unfair since it often hits borrowers who have run into trouble paying back their debts. The problem was particularly acute during the housing crisis, so in late 2007, Congress passed a bill that protected most homeowners from being hit with a tax bill after foreclosure or otherwise getting a principal reduction from their lender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;20.8&quot;&gt;Tax experts say the principle of taxing forgiven loans is crucial to preventing chicanery. Without it, people could arrange with their employers to borrow their salaries through the entire year interest-free and then have the employer forgive the loan at the very end. Voila, no taxable income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;20.9&quot;&gt;The notion that forgiven debt is taxable applies to corporate transactions, too. That means concern about such a tax bill is rarely far from a distressed corporate debtor’s mind. “Any time you have a troubled situation, it’s a typical tax issue you have to address and the banks certainly understand it, too,” said Les Samuels, an attorney who spent decades advising corporations and wealthy individuals on tax matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-300&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;22.0&quot;&gt;But the efforts to avoid tax, in the case of Schaeffler and his lenders, took a particularly convoluted form. It involved several different instruments, each with multiple moving parts. The refinancing was “complicated and unusual,” said Samuels, who was not involved in the transaction. “If you were sitting in the government’s chair and reading press reports on the situation, your reaction might be that the company was on the verge of being insolvent. And when the refinancing was completed, the government might think that banks didn’t know whether they would be repaid.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;22.1&quot;&gt;This account of the audit was drawn from conversations with people familiar with it, who were not authorized to speak on the record, as well as court and German securities filings. The IRS declined to comment for this story. Doerr did not respond to repeated calls and emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;22.2&quot;&gt;A spokesman for Schaeffler declined to make him available for an interview. “Mr. Schaeffler always strives to comply with the complex U.S. tax code,” the spokesman wrote in a statement, saying “the fact that the refinancing was with six independent, international banks in itself demonstrates that these were arm’s length, commercially driven transactions. The IRS professionally concluded the audit in 2018 without making adjustments to those transactions, and there is no continuing dispute — either administratively or in litigation — related to these matters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;22.3&quot;&gt;Schaeffler’s lenders never explicitly canceled the loan. The banks and Schaeffler maintained to the IRS that the loan was real and no debt had been forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;22.4&quot;&gt;The IRS came not to buy that. After years of trying to unravel the refinancing, the IRS homed in on what the agency contended was a disguise. The banks and Schaeffler “had a mutual interest in maintaining the appearance that the debt hadn’t gone away,” a person familiar with the transaction said. But the IRS believed the debt had, in fact, been canceled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;22.5&quot;&gt;In the refinancing, the banks and Schaeffler had agreed to split the company’s debt, which had grown to 12 billion euros at that point, into two pieces: A senior loan, to be paid back first, worth about 7 billion euros and a junior piece worth about 5 billion euros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;22.6&quot;&gt;Schaeffler’s income-producing assets were placed into the entity that held the senior debt. Schaeffler was required to repay the debt according to a schedule and to pay a meaningful interest rate: 4.25 percentage points above the rate his lenders charge each other to borrow money. In short, it appeared to be a relatively straightforward debt transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;22.7&quot;&gt;The junior debt was another matter — and its provisions would raise the hackles of the IRS. To begin with, the entity that held the junior debt did not directly hold income-producing assets. There was no schedule of payments that Schaeffler had to make on the junior debt. He wasn’t obligated to make principal payments until the end of the loan’s term. And it carried a nearly nonexistent annual interest rate of 0.1 percentage points above prevailing interbank lending rates, plus an additional 7 percent per year, which Schaeffler could choose to defer and pay at the end of the term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-300&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;24.0&quot;&gt;The banks attached two other provisions to the refinancing: A “Contingent Remuneration Payment” and a “Contingent Upside Instrument,” according to German securities filings. The two additions called for Schaeffler to make payments to the future performance of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;24.1&quot;&gt;The IRS and Schaeffler’s team fought especially over the Contingent Upside Instrument. Its value was tied to the Schaeffler Group’s future profitability, just like a share of stock would be. The IRS argued that not only was this an equitylike sweetener to the banks, but that it tainted the entire junior portion of the debt. To the IRS, it looked like the banks had a claim on future payments from Schaeffler, but they didn’t know when they’d receive it — or even if they would ever get anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;24.2&quot;&gt;To the IRS, these steps all added up to the effective cancellation of about $5 billion worth of debt, for which the banks had received something in return. That something looked and acted very much like equity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;26.0&quot;&gt;The Schaeffler audit was one of the biggest for the Global High Wealth group. The IRS assigned a larger than normal team to the exam. The agency would send 86 separate document requests to Schaeffler through July 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;26.1&quot;&gt;But there were problems almost from the beginning, according to people familiar with the audit, who provided this account and chronology. The IRS examiners disagreed with one another over strategy. The debates sometimes spilled into the view of Schaeffler’s team. “I remember a tremendous amount of turnover from the exam team and infighting. They were not presenting a coherent message,” a person in the Schaeffler camp said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;26.2&quot;&gt;By contrast, Schaeffler’s team of lawyers and accountants was large and unified. “These taxpayers aren’t exactly represented by H&amp;amp;R Block,” Gardner, the retired IRS official, said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;26.3&quot;&gt;Schaeffler’s advisers threw as much as they could back at the agency. Document requests are typically voluntary at the outset. But at one point, an IRS auditor was frustrated at what the team saw as the Schaeffler team’s resistance and delays and demanded, “Would a summons help?” according to a person familiar with the exam. Schaeffler’s team complained about the perceived threat. The IRS scolded its employee, and Doerr, the lead auditor, apologized to the Schaeffler side, according to the person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-irs-building-dc-3x2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-irs-building-dc-3x2.jpg 400w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo800w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-irs-building-dc-3x2.jpg 800w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo1600w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-irs-building-dc-3x2.jpg 1600w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo2000w/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-irs-building-dc-3x2.jpg 2000w&quot;/&gt; The IRS’ efforts to police the superwealthy have been a bust. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Michael Brochstein/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;28.0&quot;&gt;In another instance, the IRS could not get information it sought from Ernst &amp;amp; Young, the accounting firm, related to its advice to Schaeffler. So it sued the accounting firm in early 2014. Ernst &amp;amp; Young contended the material was privileged because it was prepared in anticipation of litigation. The IRS won in the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of New York, but Ernst &amp;amp; Young appealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;28.1&quot;&gt;In early November 2015, with the Ernst &amp;amp; Young appeal unresolved, top IRS officials gave the Schaeffler audit team the permission it was looking for. They allowed the auditors to notify Schaeffler that they believed he’d failed to disclose about $5 billion in income and that he could expect a $1.2 billion tax bill. That included some $200 million in penalties because the agency viewed the transaction as abusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;28.2&quot;&gt;Only days later, the IRS was dealt a defeat that would further hamstring its ability to press its case. On Nov. 10, the 2nd U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals reversed the district judge, slapping down the IRS’ efforts to get the Ernst &amp;amp; Young documents, ruling they were in fact protected by privilege. The IRS had no choice. It would have to proceed without the documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;28.3&quot;&gt;The IRS took solace that despite the adverse ruling on the documents, the appeals court appeared to bolster the IRS’ view of the transaction. Describing it as a “complex and novel refinancing,” the court said the consortium of banks “essentially insured” Schaeffler “by extending credit and subordinating its debt.” The opinion found that Schaeffler’s team had known that litigation over the transaction was “virtually inevitable,” underscoring the sense that the billionaire’s lawyers and accountants knew they were pushing legal limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;28.4&quot;&gt;The two sides wrangled even over routine procedural matters. The statute of limitations was about to run out. Usually the taxpayer voluntarily agrees to extend the time limit rather than antagonize the agents doing an audit. But Schaeffler’s team raised the prospect of refusing an extension. They ultimately relented, but succeeded in amping up the pressure on the auditors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-pp-id=&quot;29&quot; data-pp-blocktype=&quot;promo&quot; class=&quot;promo medium right&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Read More&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lead-art&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;aspect-3-2&quot; href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/graphics/eitc-audit&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/externals/_threeTwo400w/20190401-irs-map-3x2-2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/externals/_threeTwo400w/20190401-irs-map-3x2-2.jpg 400w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/externals/_threeTwo800w/20190401-irs-map-3x2-2.jpg 800w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/externals/_threeTwo1200w/20190401-irs-map-3x2-2.jpg 1200w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lead-art thumbnail&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;aspect-1-1&quot; href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/earned-income-tax-credit-irs-audit-working-poor&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_oneOne75w/20181212-earned-income-tax-credit-1x1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_oneOne75w/20181212-earned-income-tax-credit-1x1.jpg 75w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_oneOne150w/20181212-earned-income-tax-credit-1x1.jpg 150w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;30.0&quot;&gt;Even as the antagonism built between the two sides, the IRS showed deference to the Schaeffler camp. Doerr gave Schaeffler’s attorneys a heads-up that the agency was going to deliver bad news, an action that was viewed as overly solicitous, according to one person. It gave an opening for Schaeffler’s lawyers to raise their concerns with the audit team’s bosses. They expressed how wrongheaded they thought the IRS’ position was and how inappropriate its actions had been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;30.1&quot;&gt;In June 2016, the IRS sent Schaeffler the official notice that the agency would seek unpaid tax and penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;30.2&quot;&gt;Schaeffler’s attorneys continued to argue, often above the heads of the audit team, that the auditors’ interpretation was incorrect. They held conference calls with top IRS officials, saying the audit team had given the Schaeffler side mixed messages. Some on the team had assured Schaeffler’s attorneys that he would not face a large tax bill or be subject to a penalty. Top officials then met with the Global High Wealth team to discuss the issues. “The pushback is incredible,” one knowledgeable person recalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;30.3&quot;&gt;The pushback worked — and here’s where an audit is radically different from a court case. Court cases are typically accompanied by publicly available decisions and rulings that explain them in detail. By contrast, audits are shielded by the secrecy of the IRS’ process. They can end with no scrap of publicly available paper to memorialize key decisions. In August 2016, in Schaeffler’s case, officials several rungs up the IRS hierarchy told the Global High Wealth team to withdraw the penalty from its request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-300&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;32.0&quot;&gt;Even without a penalty portion, Schaeffler would still owe the original $1 billion in taxes if the IRS maintained its contention that the banks had cancelled his debt. Schaeffler’s team then went to work on that, too. It succeeded. By 2017, the IRS had abandoned its assertion that debt had been transformed into equity. After six years on a hard-fought case, the agency had effectively given up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;32.1&quot;&gt;The IRS had a few stray quibbles, so the agency said it required a payment in the “tens of millions,” according to two people familiar with the audit. There the trail goes dark. Tax experts say Schaeffler’s team would likely have appealed even that offer, which in many instances leads to further reductions in money owed, but ProPublica could not ascertain that that occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;32.2&quot;&gt;Thanks in part to the U.S. government’s bailout of the auto industry and the global economic recovery, the Schaeffler Group’s business rebounded. Despite a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-03-06/germany-s-schaeffler-family-is-down-to-its-last-16-billion&quot;&gt;dip in the car market&lt;/a&gt;, things have turned out OK for Georg Schaeffler. Today, Forbes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/billionaires/#308828c6251c&quot;&gt;estimates his fortune&lt;/a&gt; at over $13 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-pp-id=&quot;33&quot; data-pp-blocktype=&quot;promo&quot; class=&quot;promo large left&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Read More&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lead-art&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;aspect-3-2&quot; href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/how-the-irs-was-gutted&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20181211-gutting-irs-3x2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20181211-gutting-irs-3x2.jpg 400w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo800w/20181211-gutting-irs-3x2.jpg 800w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo1200w/20181211-gutting-irs-3x2.jpg 1200w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;description&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;hed&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/how-the-irs-was-gutted&quot;&gt;How the IRS Was Gutted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;An eight-year campaign to slash the agency’s budget has left it understaffed, hamstrung and operating with archaic equipment. The result: billions less to fund the government. That’s good news for corporations and the wealthy.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 14:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>iron0013</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.propublica.org/article/ultrawealthy-taxes-irs-internal-revenue-service-global-high-wealth-audits</og:url>
<og:title>The Top 0.5% Underpay $50 Billion a Year In Taxes and Crushed the IRS Plan to Stop Them — ProPublica</og:title>
<og:description>Ten years ago, the tax agency formed a special team to unravel the complex tax-lowering strategies of the nation’s wealthiest people. But with big money — and Congress — arrayed against the team, it never had a chance.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/20190405-irs-ultrawealthy-lead-illo-1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.propublica.org/article/ultrawealthy-taxes-irs-internal-revenue-service-global-high-wealth-audits</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>