<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>SageMath – Open-Source Mathematical Software System</title>
<link>https://www.sagemath.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sagemath.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;SageMath - Open-Source Mathematical Software System&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;IE=edge,chrome=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;content-type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;search&quot; type=&quot;application/opensearchdescription+xml&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sagemath.org/res/sage-search.xml&quot; title=&quot;Search sagemath.org&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;res/sage.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;shortcut icon&quot; href=&quot;pix/sageicon.png&quot; type=&quot;image/x-icon&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mask-icon&quot; href=&quot;pix/icon_only/sagemath_pinned_tab_icon.svg&quot; color=&quot;blue&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;application/rss+xml&quot; title=&quot;SageMath RSS News Feed&quot; href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/group/sage-announce/feed/atom_v1_0_msgs.xml&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;//fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=RobotoDraft:regular,bold,italic,thin,light,bolditalic,black,medium&amp;amp;lang=en,fr,de,es&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;SageMath Mathematical Software System - Sage&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;website&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.sagemath.org/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://sagemath.org/pix/logo_sagemath+icon_oldstyle.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;SageMath Mathematical Software System&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;SageMath is a free and open-source mathematical software system.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;14.401475237092&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sagemath.org/pix/index_icons-nq8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mission: &lt;em&gt;Creating a viable free open source alternative to Magma, Maple, Mathematica and Matlab&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;narrow txt announce center&quot; readability=&quot;9.2113821138211&quot;&gt;Since version 9.0 released in January 2020, SageMath is using &lt;strong&gt;Python 3&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.sagemath.org/Python3-Switch&quot;&gt;Python 3 switch wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;





&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 17:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gnramires</dc:creator>
<og:title>SageMath Mathematical Software System - Sage</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.sagemath.org/</og:url>
<og:image>https://sagemath.org/pix/logo_sagemath+icon_oldstyle.png</og:image>
<og:description>SageMath is a free and open-source mathematical software system.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sagemath.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft: Rust Is the Industry’s ‘Best Chance’ at Safe Systems Programming</title>
<link>https://thenewstack.io/microsoft-rust-is-the-industrys-best-chance-at-safe-systems-programming/#</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thenewstack.io/microsoft-rust-is-the-industrys-best-chance-at-safe-systems-programming/#</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how much investment software companies may put into tooling and training their developers, “C++, at its core, is not a safe language,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rylev&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;Ryan Levick&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; cloud developer advocate, during the AllThingsOpen virtual conference last month, explaining, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/NQBVUjdkLAA&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;in a virtual talk&lt;/a&gt;, why Microsoft is gradually switching to Rust to build its infrastructure software, away from C/C++. And it is encouraging other software industry giants to consider the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re using languages that are, because they are quite old and come from a different era, do not provide us the ability to protect ourselves from these kinds of vulnerabilities, he &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/NQBVUjdkLAA?t=580&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. “C++ is not a memory safe language and no one would really pretend that it is,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, Microsoft has deemed C++ no longer acceptable for writing mission-critical software. The industry sorely needs to move to a performant, memory-safe language for its low-level system work. And the best choice on the market today is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;, Levick said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;C/C++ Can’t Be Fixed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, C and C++ are the go-to languages for writing core system software. It is fast, with the only assembly between the code and the machine itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the industry is being crippled by all the memory-related bugs — many of which are security hazards — caused by these languages. Now, 70% of the CVEs originating at Microsoft are memory safety issues, Levick said. “There is no real trend it’s just staying the exact same,” he said. “Despite massive efforts on our part to fix this issue it still seems to be a common thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a financial perspective, it makes sense, given the soaring cost of remedying this never-ending stream of memory-related errors. Back in 2004, each memory-related error cost industry about $250,000 each, and that Microsoft estimation is probably on the lower-end, Levick said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are a number of efforts to boost C++ security, but while each is effective in the way it does, none entirely solves the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One approach that has been long floated is to do more programmer training in how to write safer code. But, “there is zero evidence that doing holistic training of C and C++ developers will actually fix this issue in any significant way,” Levick said, citing Microsoft’s own heaps of dev internal training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Static analysis is cited as another possible solution. But static analysis comes with too much overhead: It needs to be wired into the build system. “So there’s a lot of incentive not to use static analysis,” Levick said.  “If it’s not on by default it won’t it won’t help.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for runtime checks: “It’s impossible or it’s very least extremely hard to know when runtime checking contracts are used and when they’re not,” he said, adding that they also come with an operational overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Industry’s Best Chance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to this problem of memory-related errors, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/msrc&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;Microsoft Security Response Center&lt;/a&gt; launched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t3dKNcJXtbg&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;Safe Systems Programming Language&lt;/a&gt; initiative. There, some work was dedicated for shoring up C/C++. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/verona&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;Verona&lt;/a&gt;, a new programming language being created for safe low-level programming, was also created here. But the third prong of the project strategy, the one they are putting the most faith in, is to support “the industry’s best chance for addressing this issue head-on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And we believe that to be Rust,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance-wise, Rust is on par with C/C++, and maybe even slightly faster. Rust brings developer productivity, with package management, modern testing frameworks and the like. And programmers &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.blog/2020/01/20/what-is-rust-and-why-is-it-so-popular/&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;love Rust&lt;/a&gt; for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the main reason Microsoft is so enamored with Rust is that it is a memory-safe language, one with minimal runtime checking. Rust excels in creating correct programs.  &lt;strong&gt;Correctness&lt;/strong&gt; means, roughly, that a program is checked by the compiler for unsafe operations, resulting in fewer runtime errors. Unsafe keyword is an option, but not the default. Unsafe Rust code is almost always a subset of a larger body of safe code. Unsafe mode is necessary for memory-assigning jobs like writing device drivers. But even here the unsafe portions of memory are encapsulated behind an API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ability to program safely is not one that should be taken lightly, Levick said. In fact, it can provide more than a 10x improvement, making it worthwhile for investment. This is largely because pretty much all C/C++ code needs to security audits for unsafe behavior, whereas unsafe code written in Rust that would need to be checked is only a small subset of most code bases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Microsoft is bullish on Rust, Levick admits that Microsoft core developers won’t stop using C/C++ anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have a lot of C++ at Microsoft and that code is not going anywhere,” he said. “In fact, Microsoft c++ continues to be written and will continue to be written for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of tooling is built around C/C++. In particular, Microsoft binaries are now almost completely built on the Microsoft Visual C++ compiler which produces MSVC binaries, whereas Rust relies on &lt;a href=&quot;https://llvm.org/&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;LLVM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest challenge, though, is cultural. “There is just some people that just want to get their job done in the language that they already know,” Levick admitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the industry seems to be moving towards Rust. Amazon Web Services uses it, in part for deploying the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;Lambda serverless runtime&lt;/a&gt;, as well as for some parts of &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;EC2&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kylqq8pEgRs&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;started using&lt;/a&gt; Rust, as has Apple, Google, Dropbox and Cloudflare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;Ryan Levick - Rust at Microsoft&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NQBVUjdkLAA?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dates All Things Open 2020 have been announced: &lt;a href=&quot;https://2020.allthingsopen.org/&quot; class=&quot;ext-link&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; onclick=&quot;this.target='_blank';&quot;&gt;Oct. 20-22&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em data-stringify-type=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;The New Stack does not allow comments directly on this website. We invite all readers who wish to discuss a story or leave a comment to visit us on Twitter or Facebook. We also welcome your news tips and feedback via email: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em data-stringify-type=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;c-link&quot; href=&quot;mailto:feedback@thenewstack.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-sk=&quot;tooltip_parent&quot; aria-describedby=&quot;sk-tooltip-2588&quot;&gt;feedback@thenewstack.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;Amazon Web Services is a sponsor of The New Stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 15:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adamnemecek</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Microsoft has deemed C++ no longer acceptable for writing mission-critical software. The industry sorely needs to move to a performant, memory-safe language for its low-low system work. And the best choice on the market today is Rust, Levick said.</og:description>
<og:url>https://thenewstack.io/microsoft-rust-is-the-industrys-best-chance-at-safe-systems-programming/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.thenewstack.io/media/2020/06/1a99000f-microsoft-rust.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thenewstack.io/microsoft-rust-is-the-industrys-best-chance-at-safe-systems-programming/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The American Press Is Destroying Itself</title>
<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-news-media-is-destroying-itself?r=2&amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;utm_source=hackernews</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-news-media-is-destroying-itself?r=2&amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;utm_source=hackernews</guid>
<description>&lt;a class=&quot;image-link image2 image2-930-1456&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Ff1bcd347-c525-4a12-a0b8-5cd7c99f4173_5203x3325.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Ff1bcd347-c525-4a12-a0b8-5cd7c99f4173_5203x3325.jpeg&quot; data-attrs=&quot;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/f1bcd347-c525-4a12-a0b8-5cd7c99f4173_5203x3325.jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:930,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:6771607,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it seems life can’t get any worse in this country. Already in terror of a pandemic, Americans have lately been bombarded with images of grotesque state-sponsored violence, from the murder of George Floyd to countless &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nowthisnews/status/1269249681651105793&quot;&gt;scenes of police clubbing and brutalizing&lt;/a&gt; protesters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our president, Donald Trump, is a clown who makes a great reality-show villain but is uniquely toolless as the leader of a superpower nation. Watching him try to think through two society-imperiling crises is like waiting for a gerbil to solve Fermat’s theorem. &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/US/trumps-quest-dominate-amid-george-floyd-protests-sparks/story?id=71126346&quot;&gt;Calls to “dominate” marchers&lt;/a&gt; and ad-libbed speculations about Floyd’s “great day” looking down from heaven at Trump’s crisis management and new unemployment numbers (“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/06/05/george-floyd-gets-new-spokesman-donald-trump/&quot;&gt;only” 21 million&lt;/a&gt; out of work!) were pure gasoline at a tinderbox moment. The man seems determined to talk us into civil war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But police violence, and Trump’s daily assaults on the presidential competence standard, are only part of the disaster. On the other side of the political aisle, among self-described liberals, we’re watching an intellectual revolution. It feels liberating to say after years of tiptoeing around the fact, but the American left has lost its mind. It’s become a cowardly mob of upper-class social media addicts, Twitter Robespierres who move from discipline to discipline torching reputations and jobs with breathtaking casualness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leaders of this new movement are replacing traditional liberal beliefs about tolerance, free inquiry, and even racial harmony with ideas so toxic and unattractive that they eschew debate, moving straight to shaming, threats, and intimidation. They are counting on the guilt-ridden, self-flagellating nature of traditional American progressives, who will not stand up for themselves, and will walk to the Razor voluntarily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’ve conned organization after organization into empowering panels to search out thoughtcrime, and it’s established now that anything can be an offense, from a UCLA professor placed under investigation for &lt;a href=&quot;https://freebeacon.com/issues/university-to-investigate-lecturer-for-reading-mlks-letter-from-birmingham-jail/&quot;&gt;reading Martin Luther King’s “Letter from a Birmingham Jail” out loud&lt;/a&gt; to a data scientist &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jenbrea/status/1271148784316108800&quot;&gt;fired* from a research firm&lt;/a&gt; for — get this — &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidshor/status/1265998625836019712?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1265998625836019712&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nationalreview.com%2Fnews%2Fthe-cancel-counter%2F&quot;&gt;retweeting&lt;/a&gt; an academic study &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/american-political-science-review/article/agenda-seeding-how-1960s-black-protests-moved-elites-public-opinion-and-voting/136610C8C040C3D92F041BB2EFC3034C&quot;&gt;suggesting nonviolent protests may be more politically effective&lt;/a&gt; than violent ones!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this madness is coming for journalism. Beginning on Friday, June 5th, a series of controversies rocked the media. By my count, at least eight news organizations dealt with internal uprisings (it was likely more). Most involved groups of reporters and staffers demanding the firing or reprimand of colleagues who’d made politically “problematic” editorial or social media decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;New York Times,&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Intercept&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Vox,&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Philadelphia Inquirier, Variety&lt;/em&gt;, and others saw challenges to management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the most disturbing story involved &lt;em&gt;Intercept&lt;/em&gt; writer Lee Fang, one of a fast-shrinking number of young reporters actually skilled in investigative journalism. Fang’s work in the area of campaign finance especially has led to concrete impact, including a &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2019/03/11/intercept-investigation-leads-to-record-fines-over-foreign-campaign-contributions/&quot;&gt;record fine to a conservative Super PAC&lt;/a&gt;: few young reporters have done more to combat corruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet Fang found himself denounced online as a racist, then hauled before H.R. His crime? During protests, he tweeted this &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lhfang/status/1268390704645943297&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with an African-American man named Maximum Fr, who described having two cousins murdered in the East Oakland neighborhood where he grew up. Saying his aunt is still not over those killings, Max asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I always question, why does a Black life matter only when a white man takes it?... Like, if a white man takes my life tonight, it’s going to be national news, but if a Black man takes my life, it might not even be spoken of… It’s stuff just like that that I just want in the mix.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after, a co-worker of Fang’s, Akela Lacy, wrote, “Tired of being made to deal continually with my co-worker @lhfang continuing to push black on black crime narratives after being repeatedly asked not to. This isn’t about me and him, it’s about institutional racism and using free speech to couch anti-blackness. I am so fucking tired.” She followed with, “Stop being racist Lee.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tweet received tens of thousands of likes and responses along the lines of, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GenePark/status/1268561870878846979&quot;&gt;Lee Fang has been like this for years, but the current moment only makes his anti-Blackness more glaring&lt;/a&gt;,” and “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=lee%20fang%20racist&amp;amp;src=typed_query&quot;&gt;Lee Fang spouting racist bullshit it must be a day ending in day&lt;/a&gt;.” A significant number of Fang’s co-workers, nearly all white, as well as reporters from other major news organizations like the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; and MSNBC and political activists (one &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.democracyinaction.us/2020/warren/warrenorg.html&quot;&gt;former Elizabeth Warren staffer&lt;/a&gt; tweeted, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HelenBrosnan/status/1268560538486951950&quot;&gt;Get him&lt;/a&gt;!”), issued likes and messages of support for the notion that Fang was a racist. Though he had support within the organization, no one among his co-workers was willing to say anything in his defense publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many reporters, Fang has always viewed it as part of his job to ask questions in all directions. He’s written critically of political figures on the center-left, the left, and “obviously on the right,” and his reporting has inspired serious threats in the past. None of those past experiences were as terrifying as this blitz by would-be colleagues, which he described as “jarring,” “deeply isolating,” and “unique in my professional experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To save his career, Fang had to craft a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/6938336-Statement.html&quot;&gt;public apology&lt;/a&gt; for “insensitivity to the lived experience of others.” According to one friend of his, it’s been communicated to Fang that his continued employment at &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; is contingent upon avoiding comments that may upset colleagues. Lacy to her credit &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/akela_lacy/status/1269335670583164929&quot;&gt;publicly thanked Fang&lt;/a&gt; for his statement and expressed willingness to have a conversation; unfortunately, the throng of &lt;em&gt;Intercept&lt;/em&gt; co-workers who piled on her initial accusation did not join her in this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first met Lee Fang in 2014 and have never known him to be anything but kind, gracious, and easygoing. He also appears earnestly committed to making the world a better place through his work. It’s stunning that so many colleagues are comfortable using a word as extreme and villainous as &lt;em&gt;racist&lt;/em&gt; to describe him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though he describes his upbringing as “solidly middle-class,” Fang grew up in up in a diverse community in Prince George's County, Maryland, and attended public schools where he was frequently among the few non-African Americans in his class. As a teenager, he was witness to the murder of a young man outside his home by police who were never prosecuted, and also volunteered at a shelter for trafficked women, two of whom were murdered. If there’s an edge to Fang at all, it seems geared toward people in our business who grew up in affluent circumstances and might intellectualize topics that have personal meaning for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the tweets that got him in trouble with Lacy and other co-workers, he questioned the logic of protesters attacking immigrant-owned businesses “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lhfang/status/1267108732288155649&quot;&gt;with no connection to police brutality at all&lt;/a&gt;.” He also offered his opinion on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lhfang/status/1267162143578718208&quot;&gt;Martin Luther King’s attitude toward violent protest&lt;/a&gt; (Fang’s take was that King did not support it; Lacy responded, “you know they killed him too right”). These are issues around which there is still considerable disagreement among self-described liberals, even among self-described leftists. Fang also commented, presciently as it turns out, that many reporters were “terrified of openly challenging the lefty conventional wisdom around riots.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lacy says she never intended for Fang to be “fired, ‘canceled,’ or deplatformed,” but appeared irritated by questions on the subject, which she says suggest, “there is more concern about naming racism than letting it persist.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max himself was stunned to find out that his comments on all this had created a Twitter firestorm. “I couldn’t believe they were coming for the man’s job over something I said,” he recounts. “It was not Lee’s opinion. It was my opinion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By phone, Max spoke of a responsibility he feels Black people have to speak out against all forms of violence, “precisely because we experience it the most.” He described being affected by the Floyd story, but also by the story of retired African-American police captain David Dorn, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KuonjiAliceMoe/status/1268023462242680832&quot;&gt;shot to death&lt;/a&gt; in recent protests in St. Louis. He also mentioned Tony Timpa, a white man whose 2016 asphyxiation by police was only uncovered last year. In body-camera footage, police are heard joking after Timpa passed out and stopped moving, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dallasnews.com/news/investigations/2019/07/31/you-re-gonna-kill-me-dallas-police-body-cam-footage-reveals-the-final-minutes-of-tony-timpa-s-life/&quot;&gt;I don’t want to go to school! Five more minutes, Mom&lt;/a&gt;!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If it happens to anyone, it has to be called out,” Max says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max described discussions in which it was argued to him that bringing up these other incidents now is not helpful to the causes being articulated at the protests. He understands that point of view. He just disagrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They say, there has to be the right time and a place to talk about that,” he says. “But my point is, when? I want to speak out now.” He pauses. “We’ve taken the narrative, and instead of being inclusive with it, we’ve become exclusive with it. Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were other incidents. The editors of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boston.com/news/media/2020/06/09/bon-appetit-editor-adam-rapoport-resigns&quot;&gt;Bon Apetit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CBLToSInUcb/&quot;&gt;Refinery29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; both resigned amid accusations of toxic workplace culture. The editor of &lt;em&gt;Variety,&lt;/em&gt; Claudia Eller, was &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2020/06/05/claudia-eller-variety-editor-in-chief-placed-on-leave-after-twitter-spat/?utm_campaign=SocialFlow&amp;amp;utm_source=NYPTwitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=SocialFlow&quot;&gt;placed on leave&lt;/a&gt; after calling a South Asian freelance writer “bitter” in a Twitter exchange about minority hiring at her company. The self-abasing apology (“I have tried to diversify our newsroom over the past seven years, but I HAVE NOT DONE ENOUGH”) was insufficient. Meanwhile, the &lt;em&gt;Philadelphia Inquirer’s&lt;/em&gt; editor, Stan Wischowski, was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nycsouthpaw/status/1269402533212160000&quot;&gt;forced&lt;/a&gt; out after approving a headline, “Buildings matter, too.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the most discussed incident, &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; editorial page editor James Bennet was ousted for green-lighting an anti-protest editorial by Arkansas Republican Senator Tom Cotton entitled, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/03/opinion/tom-cotton-protests-military.html&quot;&gt;Send in the troops&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m no fan of Cotton, but as was the case with Michael Moore’s documentary and many other controversial speech episodes, it’s not clear that many of the people angriest about the piece in question even read it. In classic &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; fashion, the paper has already scrubbed a mistake they made misreporting what their own editorial said, in an article about Bennet’s ouster. Here’s how the piece by Marc Tracy &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200607202330/https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/07/business/media/james-bennet-resigns-nytimes-op-ed.html&quot;&gt;read originally&lt;/a&gt; (emphasis mine):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Bennet, the editorial page editor of The New York Times, has resigned after a controversy over an Op-Ed by a senator &lt;strong&gt;calling for military force against protesters&lt;/strong&gt; in American cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the piece &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/07/business/media/james-bennet-resigns-nytimes-op-ed.html&quot;&gt;reads now&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Bennet resigned on Sunday from his job as the editorial page editor of The New York Times, days after the newspaper’s opinion section, which he oversaw, published a much-criticized Op-Ed by a United States senator calling &lt;strong&gt;for a military response to civic unrest&lt;/strong&gt; in American cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cotton did not call for “military force against protesters in American cities.” He spoke of a “show of force,” to rectify a situation a significant portion of the country saw as spiraling out of control. It’s an important distinction. Cotton was presenting one side of the most important question on the most important issue of a critically important day in American history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Cotton points out in the piece, he was advancing a view arguably held by a majority of the country. A &lt;em&gt;Morning Consult&lt;/em&gt; poll showed &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.morningconsult.com/wp-uploads/2020/06/01181629/2005131_crosstabs_POLICE_RVs_FINAL_LM-1.pdf&quot;&gt;58% of Americans&lt;/a&gt; either strongly or somewhat supported the idea of “calling in the U.S. military to supplement city police forces.” That survey included 40% of self-described “liberals” and 37% of African-Americans. To declare a point of view held by that many people not only not worthy of discussion, but so toxic that publication of it without even necessarily agreeing requires dismissal, is a dramatic reversal for a newspaper that long cast itself as the national paper of record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, that &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.morningconsult.com/wp-uploads/2020/06/01181629/2005131_crosstabs_POLICE_RVs_FINAL_LM-1.pdf&quot;&gt;same poll cited by Cotton showed&lt;/a&gt; that 73% of Americans described protecting property as “very important,” while an additional 16% considered it “somewhat important.” This means the &lt;em&gt;Philadelphia Inquirer&lt;/em&gt; editor was fired for running a headline – “Buildings matter, too” – that the poll said expressed a view held by 89% of the population, including 64% of African-Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Would I have run the &lt;em&gt;Inquirer&lt;/em&gt; headline? No. In the context of the moment, the use of the word “matter” especially sounds like the paper is equating “Black lives” and “buildings,” an odious and indefensible comparison. But why not just make this case in a rebuttal editorial? Make it a teaching moment? How can any editor operate knowing that airing opinions shared by a majority of readers might cost his or her job?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing accomplished by removing those types of editorials from newspapers — apart from scaring the hell out of editors — is to shield readers from knowledge of what a major segment of American society is thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also guarantees that opinion writers and editors alike will shape views to avoid upsetting colleagues, which means that instead of hearing what our differences are and how we might address those issues, newspaper readers will instead be presented with page after page of people professing to agree with one another. That’s not agitation, that’s misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instinct to shield audiences from views or facts deemed politically uncomfortable has been in evidence since Trump became a national phenomenon. We saw it when reporters told audiences Hillary Clinton’s small crowds were a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2016-election/hillary-clinton-gambles-choosing-small-events-over-huge-rallies-n575311&quot;&gt;wholly intentional&lt;/a&gt;” campaign decision. I listened to colleagues that summer of 2016 talk about ignoring poll results, or anecdotes about Hillary’s troubled campaign, on the grounds that doing otherwise might “help Trump” (or, worse, be perceived that way).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you embrace a wholly politically utilitarian vision of the news media – I don’t, but let’s say – non-reporting of that “enthusiasm” story, or ignoring adverse poll results, didn’t help Hillary’s campaign. I’d argue it more likely accomplished the opposite, contributing to voter apathy by conveying the false impression that her victory was secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the 2016 election, we began to see staff uprisings. In one case, publishers at the &lt;em&gt;Nation&lt;/em&gt; faced a revolt – from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/joanwalsh/status/916453801552265216&quot;&gt;Editor on down&lt;/a&gt; – after articles by Aaron Mate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/erik-wemple/wp/2017/08/15/the-nation-is-reviewing-a-story-casting-doubt-on-russian-hack-of-dnc/&quot;&gt;and Patrick Lawrence&lt;/a&gt; questioning the evidentiary basis for Russiagate claims was run. Subsequent events, including the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-8299753/Declassified-transcripts-Obama-officials-not-provide-evidence-Russia-Trump-collusion.html&quot;&gt;declassification of congressional testimony&lt;/a&gt;, revealed that Mate especially was right to point out that officials had no evidence for a Trump-Russia collusion case. It’s precisely because such unpopular views often turn out to be valid that we stress publishing and debating them in the press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a related incident, the &lt;em&gt;New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; ran an article about Glenn Greenwald’s Russiagate skepticism that quoted that same &lt;em&gt;Nation&lt;/em&gt; editor, Joan Walsh, who had edited Greenwald at &lt;em&gt;Salon.&lt;/em&gt; She suggested to the &lt;em&gt;New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; that Greenwald’s reservations were rooted in “disdain” for the Democratic Party, in part because of its closeness to Wall Street, but also because of the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/09/03/glenn-greenwald-the-bane-of-their-resistance&quot;&gt;ascendance of women and people of color&lt;/a&gt;.” The message was clear: even if you win a Pulitzer Prize, you can be accused of racism for deviating from approved narratives, even on questions that have nothing to do with race (the &lt;em&gt;New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; piece also implied Greenwald’s intransigence on Russia was pathological and grounded in trauma from childhood).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Cotton, &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; staffers protested on the grounds that “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2020/6/5/21280425/new-york-times-tom-cotton-send-troops-staff-revolt&quot;&gt;Running this puts Black @NYTimes staff in danger&lt;/a&gt;.” Bennet’s editorial decision was not merely ill-considered, but literally life-threatening (note pundits in the space of a few weeks have told us that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2020/04/why-georgia-reopening-coronavirus-pandemic/610882/&quot;&gt;protesting during lockdowns&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JenniferNuzzo/status/1267885076697812993&quot;&gt;not&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JenniferNuzzo/status/1267885076697812993&quot;&gt;protesting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2020/06/11/systemic-racism-protests-coronavirus-health-risk/&quot;&gt;during lockdowns&lt;/a&gt; are both literally lethal). The &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; first attempted to rectify the situation by apologizing, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/03/opinion/tom-cotton-protests-military.html&quot;&gt;adding a long Editor’s note&lt;/a&gt; to Cotton’s piece that read, as so many recent “apologies” have, like a note written by a hostage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors begged forgiveness for not being more involved, for not thinking to urge Cotton to sound less like Cotton (“Editors should have offered suggestions”), and for allowing rhetoric that was “needlessly harsh and falls short of the thoughtful approach that advances useful debate.” That last line is sadly funny, in the context of an episode in which reporters were seeking to pre-empt a debate rather than have one at all; of course, no one got the joke, since a primary characteristic of the current political climate is a total absence of a sense of humor in any direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many guessed, the “apology” was not enough, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NYTimesPR/status/1269722985751027713&quot;&gt;Bennet was whacked&lt;/a&gt; a day later in a terse announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His replacement, Kathleen Kingsbury, issued a staff directive essentially telling employees they now had a veto over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/07/business/media/james-bennet-resigns-nytimes-op-ed.html?referringSource=articleShare&quot;&gt;anything that made them uncomfortable&lt;/a&gt;: “Anyone who sees any piece of Opinion journalism, headlines, social posts, photos—you name it—that gives you the slightest pause, please call or text me immediately.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these episodes sent a signal to everyone in a business already shedding jobs at an extraordinary rate that failure to toe certain editorial lines can and will result in the loss of your job. Perhaps additionally, you could face a public shaming campaign in which you will be denounced as a racist and rendered unemployable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tensions led to amazing contradictions in coverage. For all the extraordinary/inexplicable scenes of police viciousness in recent weeks — and there was a ton of it, ranging from police &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MotherJones/status/1270094764398964737&quot;&gt;slashing tires&lt;/a&gt; in Minneapolis, to Buffalo officers &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/waltisfrozen/status/1268729705722568704&quot;&gt;knocking over&lt;/a&gt; an elderly man, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=cops%20violence&amp;amp;src=typed_query&amp;amp;f=video&quot;&gt;Philadelphia police attacking protesters&lt;/a&gt; — there were also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/jemimamcevoy/2020/06/03/at-least-12-have-died-in-nationwide-protests-heres-who-they-were/#2abcd9a99b32&quot;&gt;12 deaths in the first nine days&lt;/a&gt; of protests, only one at the hands of a police officer (involving a man who may or may not have been aiming a gun at police).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looting in some communities has been so bad that people have been left without banks to cash checks, or pharmacies to fill prescriptions; business owners have been wiped out (“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/looting-is-second-blow-for-reeling-businesses-especially-in-minority-neighborhoods-11591214595&quot;&gt;My life is gone&lt;/a&gt;,” commented one Philly store owner); a car dealership in San Leandro, California saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ktvu.com/news/more-than-70-cars-stolen-from-san-leandro-dodge-dealership-during-looting-spree&quot;&gt;74 cars stolen&lt;/a&gt; in a single night. It isn’t the whole story, but it’s demonstrably true that violence, arson, and rioting are occurring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, because it is politically untenable to discuss this in ways that do not suggest support, reporters have been twisting themselves into knots. We are seeing headlines previously imaginable only in &lt;em&gt;The Onion,&lt;/em&gt; e.g., “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BBCNews/status/1269574979680702470&quot;&gt;27 police officers injured during largely peaceful anti-racism protests in London&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even people who try to keep up with protest goals find themselves denounced the moment they fail to submit to some new tenet of ever-evolving doctrine, via a surprisingly consistent stream of retorts: &lt;em&gt;fuck you, shut up, send money, do better, check yourself, I’m tired&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;racist&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minneapolis mayor Jacob Frey, who argued for police reform and attempted to show solidarity with protesters in his city, was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LPDonovan/status/1269432888564551680&quot;&gt;shouted down&lt;/a&gt; after he refused to commit to defunding the police. Protesters shouted “Get the fuck out!” at him, then chanted “&lt;em&gt;Shame&lt;/em&gt;!” and threw refuse, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M-9u6msqJNo&quot;&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M-9u6msqJNo&quot;&gt;-style&lt;/a&gt;, as he skulked out of the gathering. Frey’s “shame” was refusing to endorse a position polls show &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.cdn.yougov.com/s23agrrx47/20200531_yahoo_race_and_justice_crosstabs.pdf&quot;&gt;65% of Americans oppose&lt;/a&gt;, including 62% of Democrats, with just 15% of all people, and only 33% of African-Americans, in support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each passing day sees more scenes that recall something closer to cult religion than politics. White protesters in Floyd’s Houston hometown &lt;a href=&quot;https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/george-floyd-kneel-viral-video-6438938/&quot;&gt;kneeling and praying&lt;/a&gt; to black residents for “forgiveness… for years and years of racism” are one thing, but what are we to make of white police in Cary, North Carolina, kneeling and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://au.news.yahoo.com/scenes-us-protests-police-wash-feet-community-leaders-065318936.htm&quot;&gt;washing the feet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of Black pastors? What about Nancy Pelosi and Chuck Schumer kneeling while dressed in “&lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/homenews/house/501633-pelosi-schumer-kneel-in-silence-for-almost-9-minutes-to-honor-george-floyd&quot;&gt;African kente cloth scarves&lt;/a&gt;”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is symbolism here that goes beyond frustration with police or even with racism: these are orgiastic, quasi-religious, and most of all, deeply weird scenes, and the press is too paralyzed to wonder at it. In a business where the first job requirement was once the willingness to ask tough questions, we’ve become afraid to ask obvious ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On CNN, Minneapolis City Council President Lisa Bender was asked a hypothetical question about a future without police: “What if in the middle of the night, my home is broken into? Who do I call?” When Bender, who is white, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=idw83kGmwzw&amp;amp;t=29s&quot;&gt;answered&lt;/a&gt;, “I know that comes from a place of privilege,” questions popped to mind. Does privilege mean one should let someone break into one’s home, or that one shouldn’t ask that hypothetical question? (I was genuinely confused). In any other situation, a media person pounces on a provocative response to dig out its meaning, but an increasingly long list of words and topics are deemed too dangerous to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The media in the last four years has devolved into a succession of moral manias. We are told the Most Important Thing Ever is happening for days or weeks at a time, until subjects are abruptly dropped and forgotten, but the tone of warlike emergency remains: from James Comey’s firing, to the deification of Robert Mueller, to the Brett Kavanaugh nomination, to the democracy-imperiling threat to intelligence “whistleblowers,” all those interminable months of Ukrainegate hearings (while Covid-19 advanced), to fury at the death wish of lockdown violators, to the sudden reversal on that same issue, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been learned in these episodes we may freely misreport reality, so long as the political goal is righteous. It was okay to publish the now-discredited Steele dossier, because Trump is scum. MSNBC could put Michael Avenatti &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wK3DWWjlhaI&quot;&gt;on live TV&lt;/a&gt; to air a gang rape allegation without vetting, because who cared about Brett Kavanaugh – except press airing of that wild story ended up being a crucial factor in convincing key swing voter Maine Senator Susan Collins the anti-Kavanaugh campaign was a political hit job (the allegation illustrated, “why the presumption of innocence is so important,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2018/10/05/did-michael-avenatti-help-doom-case-against-brett-kavanaugh/&quot;&gt;she said&lt;/a&gt;). Reporters who were anxious to prevent Kavanaugh’s appointment, in other words, ended up helping it happen through overzealousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were no press calls for self-audits after those episodes, just as there won’t be a few weeks from now if Covid-19 cases spike, or a few months from now if Donald Trump wins re-election successfully painting the Democrats as supporters of violent protest who want to abolish police. No: press activism is limited to denouncing and shaming colleagues for insufficient fealty to the cheap knockoff of bullying campus Marxism that passes for leftist thought these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional view of the press was never based on some contrived, mathematical notion of “balance,” i.e. five paragraphs of Republicans for every five paragraphs of Democrats. The ideal instead was that we showed you everything we could see, good and bad, ugly and not, trusting that a better-informed public would make better decisions. This vision of media stressed accuracy, truth, and trust in the reader’s judgment as the routes to positive social change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all our infamous failings, journalists once had some toughness to them. We were supposed to be willing to go to jail for sources we might not even like, and fly off to war zones or disaster areas without question when editors asked. It was also once considered a virtue to flout the disapproval of colleagues to fight for stories we believed in (Watergate, for instance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today no one with a salary will stand up for colleagues like Lee Fang. Our brave truth-tellers make great shows of shaking fists &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zdFe-LmFRV8&quot;&gt;at our parody president&lt;/a&gt;, but not one of them will talk honestly about the fear running through their own newsrooms. People depend on us to tell them what we see, not what we think. What good are we if we’re afraid to do it?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 13:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cjbest</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The American Press Is Destroying Itself</og:title>
<og:description>A flurry of newsroom revolts has transformed the American press</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/h_600,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Ff1bcd347-c525-4a12-a0b8-5cd7c99f4173_5203x3325.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-news-media-is-destroying-itself?r=2</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Flow browser passes the Acid tests</title>
<link>https://www.ekioh.com/devblog/acid</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ekioh.com/devblog/acid</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The three Acid tests have a long history; they really started the push for browser compatibility that is now driven by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://web-platform-tests.org/&quot;&gt;Web Platform Tests&lt;/a&gt; project. Having finished &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ekioh.com/devblog/full-google-mail-in-a-clean-room-browser/&quot;&gt;Flow’s support for full Google Mail&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://acid3.acidtests.org/&quot;&gt;Acid3&lt;/a&gt; seemed like another interesting target.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gecko, Webkit and Blink (and, not forgetting, Presto, Trident and EdgeHTML) have obviously passed these three tests for years, but they still are very useful stress-tests for new browser engines. For us, passing the original &lt;a href=&quot;http://acid1.acidtests.org/&quot;&gt;Acid1&lt;/a&gt; test was useful early on to demonstrate to ourselves that our proof of concept layout code was taking the right approach. &lt;a href=&quot;http://acid2.acidtests.org/&quot;&gt;Acid2&lt;/a&gt; was much trickier and took a lot longer, but it was a useful milestone for our layout engine. Acid3 focuses more on JavaScript APIs than layout, although it is equally challenging to pass.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A quick note about the score: Acid3 dates back to 2008 and the web platform specs have changed over time so a perfect score, using the version hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;http://acidtests.org/&quot;&gt;acidtests.org&lt;/a&gt;, is now only 97/100. The version hosted on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wpt.live/acid/acid3/test.html&quot;&gt;web platform tests&lt;/a&gt; site has been updated to match the specs and so, using that, browsers should score 100/100. Similarly, on all browsers, Acid2 on a retina screen renders slightly differently, so the image above was taken on a non-retina display.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Acid3 comprises a number of subtests. When fixing a failing subtest, we took the approach of trying to pass all the Web Platform Tests it covers, though that was not always possible as some tests require unrelated features. Acid3 stress tests corner cases for a range of features and APIs, but isn’t very broad with its testing. We could have been cheeky and just implemented the specific features needed to pass each subtest, which would have meant we could have passed a long time ago, but that wouldn’t really help us in the long run.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A number of the subtests were for Range which we hadn’t implemented, HTML forms where our API was minimal, and the CSS Object Model (CSSOM) which we had essentially no support for.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We also had many bugs to fix – a few asserts, a redraw problem where the score was only displayed after resizing the window, our support for CSS pseudos like :nth-of-type() was buggy, and we didn’t follow the HTMLObjectElement’s fallback rules correctly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our goal for Flow is to render websites correctly the first time that anyone tries them. Most of the Acid3 subtests are going to make a real difference. In particular, implementing the CSSOM caused a massive reduction in unhandled JavaScript exceptions reported by our nightly web crawling based testing. Most of those websites, understandably, assume that APIs dating from the 1990s are implemented, and don’t fail gracefully if they are missing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It feels like quite an achievement in making Acid3 pass. No new browser engine has managed this since its creation over 12 years ago. Many fell by the wayside reflecting the complexity of the Acid tests. We are still implementing APIs so Flow will behave perfectly on more and more websites, and each milestone like this helps with its compatibility goals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to automatically receive our posts by email please &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ekioh.com/blogregister/&quot;&gt;join our mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 12:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>methyl</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Flow browser passes the Acid tests - Ekioh</og:title>
<og:description>Ekioh's multithreaded, parallel, Flow browser passes all three Acid tests.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.ekioh.com/devblog/acid/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ekioh.com/acid.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SQLite as an Application File Format (2014)</title>
<link>https://sqlite.org/appfileformat.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://sqlite.org/appfileformat.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;content-type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;sqlite.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;SQLite As An Application File Format&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;116.92252578342&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nosearch&quot; readability=&quot;3.2307692307692&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;https://sqlite.org/images/sqlite370_banner.gif&quot; alt=&quot;SQLite&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small. Fast. Reliable.&lt;br /&gt;Choose any three.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An SQLite database file with a defined schema often makes an excellent application file format. Here are a dozen reasons why this is so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simplified Application Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single-File Documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High-Level Query Language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessible Content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-Platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atomic Transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incremental And Continuous Updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily Extensible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concurrent Use By Multiple Processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Programming Languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of these points will be described in more detail below, after first considering more closely the meaning of &quot;application file format&quot;. See also the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/aff_short.html&quot;&gt;short version&lt;/a&gt; of this whitepaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Is An Application File Format?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &quot;application file format&quot; is the file format used to persist application state to disk or to exchange information between programs. There are thousands of application file formats in use today. Here are just a few examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;DOC - Word Perfect and Microsoft Office documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DWG - AutoCAD drawings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF - Portable Document Format from Adobe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XLS - Microsoft Excel Spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GIT - Git source code repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EPUB - The Electronic Publication format used by non-Kindle eBooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ODT - The Open Document format used by OpenOffice and others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PPT - Microsoft PowerPoint presentations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ODP - The Open Document presentation format used by OpenOffice and others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We make a distinction between a &quot;file format&quot; and an &quot;application format&quot;. A file format is used to store a single object. So, for example, a GIF or JPEG file stores a single image, and an XHTML file stores text, so those are &quot;file formats&quot; and not &quot;application formats&quot;. An EPUB file, in contrast, stores both text and images (as contained XHTML and GIF/JPEG files) and so it is considered an &quot;application format&quot;. This article is about &quot;application formats&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boundary between a file format and an application format is fuzzy. This article calls JPEG a file format, but for an image editor, JPEG might be considered the application format. Much depends on context. For this article, let us say that a file format stores a single object and an application format stores many different objects and their relationships to one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most application formats fit into one of these three categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;22.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fully Custom Formats.&lt;/strong&gt; Custom formats are specifically designed for a single application. DOC, DWG, PDF, XLS, and PPT are examples of custom formats. Custom formats are usually contained within a single file, for ease of transport. They are also usually binary, though the DWG format is a notable exception. Custom file formats require specialized application code to read and write and are not normally accessible from commonly available tools such as unix command-line programs and text editors. In other words, custom formats are usually &quot;opaque blobs&quot;. To access the content of a custom application file format, one needs a tool specifically engineered to read and/or write that format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pile-of-Files Formats.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes the application state is stored as a hierarchy of files. Git is a prime example of this, though the phenomenon occurs frequently in one-off and bespoke applications. A pile-of-files format essentially uses the filesystem as a key/value database, storing small chunks of information into separate files. This gives the advantage of making the content more accessible to common utility programs such as text editors or &quot;awk&quot; or &quot;grep&quot;. But even if many of the files in a pile-of-files format are easily readable, there are usually some files that have their own custom format (example: Git &quot;Packfiles&quot;) and are hence &quot;opaque blobs&quot; that are not readable or writable without specialized tools. It is also much less convenient to move a pile-of-files from one place or machine to another, than it is to move a single file. And it is hard to make a pile-of-files document into an email attachment, for example. Finally, a pile-of-files format breaks the &quot;document metaphor&quot;: there is no one file that a user can point to that is &quot;the document&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrapped Pile-of-Files Formats.&lt;/strong&gt; Some applications use a Pile-of-Files that is then encapsulated into some kind of single-file container, usually a ZIP archive. EPUB, ODT,and ODP are examples of this approach. An EPUB book is really just a ZIP archive that contains various XHTML files for the text of book chapters, GIF and JPEG images for the artwork, and a specialized catalog file that tells the eBook reader how all the XML and image files fit together. OpenOffice documents (ODT and ODP) are also ZIP archives containing XML and images that represent their content as well as &quot;catalog&quot; files that show the interrelationships between the component parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wrapped pile-of-files format is a compromise between a full custom file format and a pure pile-of-files format. A wrapped pile-of-files format is not an opaque blob in the same sense as a custom format, since the component parts can still be accessed using any common ZIP archiver, but the format is not quite as accessible as a pure pile-of-files format because one does still need the ZIP archiver, and one cannot normally use command-line tools like &quot;find&quot; on the file hierarchy without first un-zipping it. On the other hand, a wrapped pile-of-files format does preserve the document metaphor by putting all content into a single disk file. And because it is compressed, the wrapped pile-of-files format tends to be more compact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with custom file formats, and unlike pure pile-of-file formats, a wrapped pile-of-files format is not as easy to edit, since usually the entire file must be rewritten in order to change any component part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this document is to argue in favor of a fourth new category of application file format: An SQLite database file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SQLite As The Application File Format&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any application state that can be recorded in a pile-of-files can also be recorded in an SQLite database with a simple key/value schema like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
CREATE TABLE files(filename TEXT PRIMARY KEY, content BLOB);
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the content is compressed, then such an &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/sqlar.html&quot;&gt;SQLite Archive&lt;/a&gt; database is &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/affcase1.html#smaller&quot;&gt;the same size&lt;/a&gt; (±1%) as an equivalent ZIP archive, and it has the advantage of being able to update individual &quot;files&quot; without rewriting the entire document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But an SQLite database is not limited to a simple key/value structure like a pile-of-files database. An SQLite database can have dozens or hundreds or thousands of different tables, with dozens or hundreds or thousands of fields per table, each with different datatypes and constraints and particular meanings, all cross-referencing each other, appropriately and automatically indexed for rapid retrieval, and all stored efficiently and compactly in a single disk file. And all of this structure is succinctly documented for humans by the SQL schema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, an SQLite database can do everything that a pile-of-files or wrapped pile-of-files format can do, plus much more, and with greater lucidity. An SQLite database is a more versatile container than key/value filesystem or a ZIP archive. (For a detailed example, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/affcase1.html&quot;&gt;OpenOffice case study&lt;/a&gt; essay.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power of an SQLite database could, in theory, be achieved using a custom file format. But any custom file format that is as expressive as a relational database would likely require an enormous design specification and many tens or hundreds of thousands of lines of code to implement. And the end result would be an &quot;opaque blob&quot; that is inaccessible without specialized tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, in comparison to other approaches, the use of an SQLite database as an application file format has compelling advantages. Here are a few of these advantages, enumerated and expounded:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;94.90825879796&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;11.167717528373&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplified Application Development.&lt;/strong&gt; No new code is needed for reading or writing the application file. One has merely to link against the SQLite library, or include the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/amalgamation.html&quot;&gt;single &quot;sqlite3.c&quot; source file&lt;/a&gt; with the rest of the application C code, and SQLite will take care of all of the application file I/O. This can reduce application code size by many thousands of lines, with corresponding saving in development and maintenance costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQLite is one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/mostdeployed.html&quot;&gt;most used&lt;/a&gt; software libraries in the world. There are literally tens of billions of SQLite database files in use daily, on smartphones and gadgets and in desktop applications. SQLite is &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/testing.html&quot;&gt;carefully tested&lt;/a&gt; and proven reliable. It is not a component that needs much tuning or debugging, allowing developers to stay focused on application logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.7487179487179&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-File Documents.&lt;/strong&gt; An SQLite database is contained in a single file, which is easily copied or moved or attached. The &quot;document&quot; metaphor is preserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQLite does not have any file naming requirements and so the application can use any custom file suffix that it wants to help identify the file as &quot;belonging&quot; to the application. SQLite database files contain a 4-byte &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/fileformat2.html#appid&quot;&gt;Application ID&lt;/a&gt; in their headers that can be set to an application-defined value and then used to identify the &quot;type&quot; of the document for utility programs such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://linux.die.net/man/1/file&quot;&gt;file(1)&lt;/a&gt;, further enhancing the document metaphor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-Level Query Language.&lt;/strong&gt; SQLite is a complete relational database engine, which means that the application can access content using high-level queries. Application developers need not spend time thinking about &quot;how&quot; to retrieve the information they need from a document. Developers write SQL that expresses &quot;what&quot; information they want and let the database engine to figure out how to best retrieve that content. This helps developers operate &quot;heads up&quot; and remain focused on solving the user's problem, and avoid time spent &quot;heads down&quot; fiddling with low-level file formatting details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pile-of-files format can be viewed as a key/value database. A key/value database is better than no database at all. But without transactions or indices or a high-level query language or a proper schema, it is much harder and more error prone to use a key/value database than a relational database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;11.357771260997&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessible Content.&lt;/strong&gt; Information held in an SQLite database file is accessible using commonly available open-source command-line tools - tools that are installed by default on Mac and Linux systems and that are freely available as a self-contained EXE file on Windows. Unlike custom file formats, application-specific programs are not required to read or write content in an SQLite database. An SQLite database file is not an opaque blob. It is true that command-line tools such as text editors or &quot;grep&quot; or &quot;awk&quot; are not useful on an SQLite database, but the SQL query language is a much more powerful and convenient way for examining the content, so the inability to use &quot;grep&quot; and &quot;awk&quot; and the like is not seen as a loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An SQLite database is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/fileformat2.html&quot;&gt;well-defined and well-documented&lt;/a&gt; file format that is in widespread use by literally millions of applications and is backwards compatible to its inception in 2004 and which promises to continue to be compatible in decades to come. The longevity of SQLite database files is particularly important to bespoke applications, since it allows the document content to be accessed far in the future, long after all traces of the original application have been lost. Data lives longer than code. SQLite databases are &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/locrsf.html&quot;&gt;recommended by the US Library of Congress&lt;/a&gt; as a storage format for long-term preservation of digital content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-Platform.&lt;/strong&gt; SQLite database files are portable between 32-bit and 64-bit machines and between big-endian and little-endian architectures and between any of the various flavors of Windows and Unix-like operating systems. The application using an SQLite application file format can store binary numeric data without having to worry about the byte-order of integers or floating point numbers. Text content can be read or written as UTF-8, UTF-16LE, or UTF-16BE and SQLite will automatically perform any necessary translations on-the-fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;10.565605095541&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomic Transactions.&lt;/strong&gt; Writes to an SQLite database are &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/atomiccommit.html&quot;&gt;atomic&lt;/a&gt;. They either happen completely or not at all, even during system crashes or power failures. So there is no danger of corrupting a document just because the power happened to go out at the same instant that a change was being written to disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQLite is transactional, meaning that multiple changes can be grouped together such that either all or none of them occur, and so that the changes can be rolled back if a problem is found prior to commit. This allows an application to make a change incrementally, then run various sanity and consistency checks on the resulting data prior to committing the changes to disk. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fossil-scm.org/&quot;&gt;Fossil&lt;/a&gt; DVCS &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fossil-scm.org/fossil/doc/tip/www/selfcheck.wiki&quot;&gt;uses this technique&lt;/a&gt; to verify that no repository history has been lost prior to each change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;13.647532729104&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incremental And Continuous Updates.&lt;/strong&gt; When writing to an SQLite database file, only those parts of the file that actually change are written out to disk. This makes the writing happen faster and saves wear on SSDs. This is an enormous advantage over custom and wrapped pile-of-files formats, both of which usually require a rewrite of the entire document in order to change a single byte. Pure pile-of-files formats can also do incremental updates to some extent, though the granularity of writes is usually larger with pile-of-file formats (a single file) than with SQLite (a single page).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQLite also supports continuous update. Instead of collecting changes in memory and then writing them to disk only on a File/Save action, changes can be written back to the disk as they occur. This avoids loss of work on a system crash or power failure. An &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/undoredo.html&quot;&gt;automated undo/redo stack&lt;/a&gt;, managed using triggers, can be kept in the on-disk database, meaning that undo/redo can occur across session boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easily Extensible.&lt;/strong&gt; As an application grows, new features can be added to an SQLite application file format simply by adding new tables to the schema or by adding new columns to existing tables. Adding columns or tables does not change the meaning of prior queries, so with a modicum of care to ensuring that the meaning of legacy columns and tables are preserved, backwards compatibility is maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to extend custom or pile-of-files formats too, of course, but doing is often much harder. If indices are added, then all application code that changes the corresponding tables must be located and modified to keep those indices up-to-date. If columns are added, then all application code that accesses the corresponding table must be located and modified to take into account the new columns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;19.62275101567&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance.&lt;/strong&gt; In many cases, an SQLite application file format will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/fasterthanfs.html&quot;&gt;faster than a pile-of-files format&lt;/a&gt; or a custom format. In addition to being faster for raw read and writes, SQLite can often dramatically improves start-up times because instead of having to read and parse the entire document into memory, the application can do queries to extract only the information needed for the initial screen. As the application progresses, it only needs to load as much material as is needed to draw the next screen, and can discard information from prior screens that is no longer in use. This helps keep the memory footprint of the application under control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pile-of-files format can be read incrementally just like SQLite. But many developers are surprised to learn that SQLite can read and write smaller BLOBs (less than about 100KB in size) from its database faster than those same blobs can be read or written as separate files from the filesystem. (See &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/fasterthanfs.html&quot;&gt;35% Faster Than The Filesystem&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/intern-v-extern-blob.html&quot;&gt;Internal Versus External BLOBs&lt;/a&gt; for further information.) There is overhead associated with operating a relational database engine, however one should not assume that direct file I/O is faster than SQLite database I/O, as often it is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In either case, if performance problems do arise in an SQLite application those problems can often be resolved by adding one or two &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/lang_createindex.html&quot;&gt;CREATE INDEX&lt;/a&gt; statements to the schema or perhaps running &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/lang_analyze.html&quot;&gt;ANALYZE&lt;/a&gt; one time and without having to touch a single line of application code. But if a performance problem comes up in a custom or pile-of-files format, the fix will often require extensive changes to application code to add and maintain new indices or to extract information using different algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concurrent Use By Multiple Processes.&lt;/strong&gt; SQLite automatically coordinates concurrent access to the same document from multiple threads and/or processes. Two or more applications can connect and read from the same document at the same time. Writes are serialized, but as writes normally only take milliseconds, applications simply take turns writing. SQLite automatically ensures that the low-level format of the document is uncorrupted. Accomplishing the same with a custom or pile-of-files format, in contrast, requires extensive support in the application. And the application logic needed to support concurrency is a notorious bug-magnet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple Programming Languages.&lt;/strong&gt; Though SQLite is itself written in ANSI-C, interfaces exist for just about every other programming language you can think of: C++, C#, Objective-C, Java, Tcl, Perl, Python, Ruby, Erlang, JavaScript, and so forth. So programmers can develop in whatever language they are most comfortable with and which best matches the needs of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An SQLite application file format is a great choice in cases where there is a collection or &quot;federation&quot; of separate programs, often written in different languages and by different development teams. This comes up commonly in research or laboratory environments where one team is responsible for data acquisition and other teams are responsible for various stages of analysis. Each team can use whatever hardware, operating system, programming language and development methodology that they are most comfortable with, and as long as all programs use an SQLite database with a common schema, they can all interoperate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;39.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Applications.&lt;/strong&gt; If the application file format is an SQLite database, the complete documentation for that file format consists of the database schema, with perhaps a few extra words about what each table and column represents. The description of a custom file format, on the other hand, typically runs on for hundreds of pages. A pile-of-files format, while much simpler and easier to describe than a fully custom format, still tends to be much larger and more complex than an SQL schema dump, since the names and format for the individual files must still be described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a trivial point. A clear, concise, and easy to understand file format is a crucial part of any application design. Fred Brooks, in his all-time best-selling computer science text, &lt;em&gt;The Mythical Man-Month&lt;/em&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Representation is the essence of computer programming.&lt;br /&gt;...&lt;br /&gt;Show me your flowcharts and conceal your tables, and I shall continue to be mystified. Show me your tables, and I won't usually need your flowcharts; they'll be obvious.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob Pike, in his &lt;em&gt;Rules of Programming&lt;/em&gt; expresses the same idea this way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data dominates. If you've chosen the right data structures and organized things well, the algorithms will almost always be self-evident. Data structures, not algorithms, are central to programming.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linus Torvalds used different words to say much the same thing on the Git mailing list on 2006-06-27:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bad programmers worry about the code. Good programmers worry about data structures and their relationships.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is this: an SQL database schema almost always does a far better job of defining and organizing the tables and data structures and their relationships. And having clear, concise, and well-defined representation almost always results in an application that performs better, has fewer problems, and is easier to develop and maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQLite is not the perfect application file format for every situation. But in many cases, SQLite is a far better choice than either a custom file format, a pile-of-files, or a wrapped pile-of-files. SQLite is a high-level, stable, reliable, cross-platform, widely-deployed, extensible, performant, accessible, concurrent file format. It deserves your consideration as the standard file format on your next application design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 12:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>afiori</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://sqlite.org/appfileformat.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“Huh” exists in all human languages, according to research (2019)</title>
<link>https://thelanguagenerds.com/this-is-the-one-word-that-exists-in-all-human-languages-according-to-research/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thelanguagenerds.com/this-is-the-one-word-that-exists-in-all-human-languages-according-to-research/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Our languages are incredibly diverse and it is highly unlikely to find a word or a handful of words that sound the same in all languages. Except that there is a word that is shared by all human languages,  according to research. Surprise, surprise..the word is ‘&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;huh’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Weird, huh! Well, it turns out that this is probably a universal word. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-256&quot;/&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-2532438227294794&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2355638516&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot; data-full-width-responsive=&quot;true&quot;/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Let’s explain first how this word works in more detail. Consider the following made-up conversation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A: We decided to move to New York.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;B: Where?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;A: To New York.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker A makes a statement, and Speaker B follows up on that by asking the question “Where?” which targets only a portion of the original statement, i.e., it is possible to infer that Speaker B had no trouble comprehending the message that they decided to move somewhere, but s/he presumably missed the final word. So, s/he requested a repetition of this information by asking “where?” and Speaker A supplied this information in his/her next turn. And this is what is termed by conversation analysts as &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conversation_analysis#Repair&quot;&gt;repair&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-2532438227294794&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2355638516&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot; data-full-width-responsive=&quot;true&quot;/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But, what if, for some reason (i.g. extreme background noise), speaker B failed to comprehend the whole statement and wanted to request the repetition of the whole statement? How do you think the dialogue would have unfolded in this case? That’s where the word &lt;em&gt;huh &lt;/em&gt;comes in. Take the following dialogue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A: We decided to move to Alaska.&lt;br/&gt;B: Huh?&lt;br/&gt;A: We decided to move to Alaska.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-2532438227294794&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2355638516&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot; data-full-width-responsive=&quot;true&quot;/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Huh &lt;/em&gt;is a very specific repair strategy that does not traget some part of the statement but rather the statement as a whole. That is why repairs that are provided as a response for a &lt;em&gt;huh &lt;/em&gt;are quite long and elaborate, typically reiterating the whole statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, here is the fun part. The word &lt;em&gt;huh &lt;/em&gt;may very well be a universal word that is shared by all human languages. Conversation analysts Mark Dingemanse, Francisco Torreira and Nick Enfield, at the Max Planck Institute for Psycholinguistics in Nijmegen, conducted &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0078273&quot;&gt;an interesting cross-linguistic study&lt;/a&gt; in which they have shown that &lt;em&gt;huh &lt;/em&gt;is possibly a universal word. They recorded bits of informal conversation from 31 dialects across 5 continents and suggested that the word ‘&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;huh’ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;(and its variants) is possibly a universal repair initiator that exists in all languages, performs the same function and sounds roughly the same across languages. Here is a sketchy illustration: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-2532438227294794&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2355638516&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot; data-full-width-responsive=&quot;true&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;This study has had great importance in the humanities. It has enlightened us with how conversations work cross-culturally and unraveled important subtleties in human communication. That is why it is not surprising that the authors have been awarded an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mpi.nl/ig-nobel-prize-for-mpi-researchers&quot;&gt;Ig Nobel Prize&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-2532438227294794&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2355638516&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot; data-full-width-responsive=&quot;true&quot;/&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;References: &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0078273&quot;&gt;Is “Huh?” a Universal Word? Conversational Infrastructure and the Convergent Evolution of Linguistic Items&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mpi.nl/ig-nobel-prize-for-mpi-researchers&quot;&gt;Ig Nobel prize for MPI researchers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-We-Talk-Workings-Conversation/dp/0465059945&quot;&gt;How We Talk: The Inner Workings of Conversation: N. J. Enfield: 9780465059942: Amazon.com: Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-style-large&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By words we learn thoughts, and by thoughts we learn life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Jean Baptiste Girard&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;autorelaxed&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-2532438227294794&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;6245923239&quot;/&gt; &lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 08:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ColinWright</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>This is the word that exists in all human languages, according to research.</og:title>
<og:url>https://thelanguagenerds.com/this-is-the-one-word-that-exists-in-all-human-languages-according-to-research/</og:url>
<og:description>Our languages are incredibly diverse and it is highly unlikely to find a word or a handful of words that sound the same in all languages. Except that there is a word that is shared by all human lan…</og:description>
<og:image>https://i0.wp.com/thelanguagenerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/old-style-map-of-world-vintage.jpg?fit=1050%2C700&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thelanguagenerds.com/this-is-the-one-word-that-exists-in-all-human-languages-according-to-research/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>HSBC moves from 65 relational databases into one global MongoDB database</title>
<link>https://diginomica.com/hsbc-moves-65-relational-databases-one-global-mongodb-database</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://diginomica.com/hsbc-moves-65-relational-databases-one-global-mongodb-database</guid>
<description>

(Image sourced via HSBC)
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;HSBC is one of the world's most recognisable banking and financial services organisations, operating in over 60 countries and serving more than 40 million customers. However, with this scale comes a significant amount of operational complexity - not least in terms of how the bank delivers its applications and data models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Speaking at MongoDB.Live this week, Narasimha Reddy, data designer at HSBC Commercial, explained how the organisation is looking to simplify its approach to application delivery by migrating away from 65 relational databases, into one global instance of MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;In practice this means that each country will be able to maintain its individual application requirements, but without having to operate a unique country database. A single data model is being created, which is not only saving on costs and resources for HSBC, but is giving it the freedom to drive forward its own data model design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Reddy explained how the below image created a complex global data model for global applications, which created a high cost model at every step of the software development cycle, made it less flexible for changes, and led to higher costs on business as usual operations. He said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Global entities have the same application running for most of its operating countries in the world. But it is not possible to have just one version of the application running for all the countries. Each country will have its own customisations to fulfil its local or regional functions and operations. And of course regulatory requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;That makes it impossible to maintain one version of the application and one data model, in the relational database world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Consequently we end up having different code bases. We all know that the data model drives most of the system design. So what we end up having while using a relational database - one data model for each country and that makes it impossible to maintain one version of the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

Image of HSBC’s old global data model (Image sourced via HSBC presentation)
&lt;h2 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;A global model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Reddy said that HSBC has been looking to achieve a global data model and consequently a global database, so that it can get to a truer version of a ‘global application'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The benefits of this include reduced costs, flexibility and the ability to more easily run global analytics and reporting (with each country running on a single data model).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Historically, as per the image above, HSBC did have an application core program environment, which had most of an application's core functionality. But it couldn't have a single programme environment running for all the countries, due to the differences in data models and databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;As such it would have to put a country specific program environment on top of the application's core environment to fulfil each country's specific application needs. So when any country user accesses the application, it ends up having its own execution path. And then the country specific program environment and core program environment together would access the country's specific database and process the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is because each country has its own functions, fields, business logic interfaces, data rules, data life cycles and data access controls. As such, if a tweak is made to the data model, the program environment becomes incompatible with the changed data model and a new program environment would have to be stood up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Most of HSBC's applications have been running for decades on iSeries, mainframe systems and DB2. Reddy said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Due to all these concepts it becomes highly complex to design an application to run using a single instance and a single database for multiple countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This model brings additional consequences. We'll have to develop and apply another data model and database to run data analytics and reporting on global data. Which, of course, consumes additional resources. It's definitely taking cost in multiple different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;However, as per the image below, HSBC now has a new architecture. It now has operating countries across the globe using the same application, but the use of resources has reduced. It's now a one service environment, one database and one execution path for all the countries. This is made possible because of MongoDB's document model and the ability to map all the different table requirements for each country into a single collection, using sub-documents. Everything is simplified into one collection using country specific identifiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Reddy explained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Local requirements for each country will be built into the application, but there's no need to maintain separate data models or separate databases anymore. We could easily design the global data model and database using the MongoDB JSON schema model. That brings data from all operating countries into one database and the application can run on just one database. Which is a lot of reduction in resource and maintenance cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Another benefit is to use the same database for global data analytics and reporting. We don't need to translate into another data model or another database to run the analytics and reporting from that particular data. All this brings big savings in resources and cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I have learned while using MongoDB that when a database is schema-less and provides powerful querying and indexing, I drive my data model design, not the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

Image of HSBC’s new data model (Image sourced via HSBC presentation)</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 06:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>truth_seeker</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://diginomica.com/hsbc-moves-65-relational-databases-one-global-mongodb-database</og:url>
<og:title>HSBC moves from 65 relational databases into one global MongoDB database</og:title>
<og:description>HSBC Bank is one of the world’s leading financial institutions. It is simplifying its data model by running its applications on MongoDB.</og:description>
<og:image>https://diginomica.com/sites/default/files/images/2020-06/2FC6511F-F214-42BA-A7A8-EDE48CD0FBF6.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://diginomica.com/hsbc-moves-65-relational-databases-one-global-mongodb-database</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Zoom Acknowledges It Suspended Activists&amp;#039; Accounts at China&amp;#039;s Request</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/2020/06/12/876351501/zoom-acknowledges-it-suspended-activists-accounts-at-china-s-request</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/2020/06/12/876351501/zoom-acknowledges-it-suspended-activists-accounts-at-china-s-request</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res876404582&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/06/12/ap_20163378980190-eda9d9366acf60174c691c00ccc215e29aa5e22d-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/06/12/ap_20163378980190-eda9d9366acf60174c691c00ccc215e29aa5e22d-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoom acknowledged Thursday that it had suspended three accounts belonging to activists at China's request. Two of the accounts belonged to U.S.-based activists and the third to a labor leader in Hong Kong. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Mark Lennihan/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Mark Lennihan/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/06/12/ap_20163378980190-eda9d9366acf60174c691c00ccc215e29aa5e22d-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Zoom acknowledged Thursday that it had suspended three accounts belonging to activists at China's request. Two of the accounts belonged to U.S.-based activists and the third to a labor leader in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Mark Lennihan/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teleconferencing company Zoom acknowledged it shut down the accounts of several activists and online commemorations of the Tiananmen Square massacre at China's request. The revelation followed media reports, citing Hong Kong and U.S.-based activists, who found their accounts suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoom confirmed the reports, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.zoom.us/wordpress/2020/06/11/improving-our-policies-as-we-continue-to-enable-global-collaboration/&quot;&gt;in a blog post Thursday&lt;/a&gt;, saying China had notified it in late May and early June of four public gatherings hosted on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the post, China asserted the activities were illegal and requested the events and hosts' accounts be terminated. Zoom said it determined a majority of participants in three of the events came from China and shut them down. The host accounts for the gatherings were then suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Zoom does not currently have the ability to remove specific participants from a meeting or block participants from a certain country from joining a meeting,&quot; the company said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the three accounts — two belonging to U.S.-based activists and the third to a Hong Kong activist — were based in mainland China. The company said it would no longer block accounts outside of mainland China at Beijing's request, but did not say outright how it would handle such requests that affect users within mainland China. Instead, Zoom said, it would develop technology to block users based on geography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This will enable us to comply with requests from local authorities when they determine activity on our platform is illegal within their borders; however, we will also be able to protect these conversations for participants outside of those borders where the activity is allowed,&quot; the company said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday's acknowledgement also drew the attention of U.S. lawmakers, over Zoom's cooperation with Chinese authorities. On Friday, a bipartisan group of senators, including Marco Rubio, R-Fla., and Ed Markey, D-Mass., &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rubio.senate.gov/public/_cache/files/6f83f64a-d54f-481a-ba38-ee1b3d01c933/5126A480790CA66300B2C9CEAD813139.20.06.12-letter-to-zoom-ceo-re-china.pdf&quot;&gt;sent a letter&lt;/a&gt; to the company's CEO Eric Yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the letter, lawmakers asked which Chinese laws mandated that the company suspend the accounts of U.S.-based activists Zhou Fengsuo and Wang Dan. The senators also wanted to know why the company terminated the account of labor leader Lee Cheuk Yan who is based in Hong Kong. Lawmakers called the suspensions deeply concerning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Your company has admitted that it did so at the request of the Chinese government to comply with the laws of the People's Republic of China (PRC), because some of the participants resided inside the PRC. ... Zoom's millions of daily users across the world who support and demand basic freedoms deserve answers,&quot; the senators wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Lee told NPR that his event was part of a series of weekly talks: &quot;Is China's autocratic regime a threat to the world?&quot; He said he found his account was blocked just before the third session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If you said that, you know, you follow the law of [a] country, but that country [suppresses] free speech. ...Which side are you on? Free speech or suppression of free speech?&quot; Lee said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;contributors-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPR's John Ruwitch contributed to this story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 03:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dehrmann</dc:creator>
<og:title>Zoom Acknowledges It Suspended Activists' Accounts At China's Request</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/2020/06/12/876351501/zoom-acknowledges-it-suspended-activists-accounts-at-china-s-request</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The video conferencing company says Beijing had asked that four meetings and associated users be terminated. Two of the users were based in the U.S. and the third in Hong Kong.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/06/12/ap_20163378980190_wide-0c83b730ebfca91ac7e068b46bec3b6c97bc501a.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/2020/06/12/876351501/zoom-acknowledges-it-suspended-activists-accounts-at-china-s-request</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Design electronics like it is 70s at CERN</title>
<link>https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNjVlcaYM4Fre6F_AGtX6Jw0K1BIylWILAPAXds9WwPalniCJwPFOX5v8h1T-CtoQ?key=OVBmbGlwa2dXUXg1a2JBUnpvYWotNVB6cUdyTkVR</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNjVlcaYM4Fre6F_AGtX6Jw0K1BIylWILAPAXds9WwPalniCJwPFOX5v8h1T-CtoQ?key=OVBmbGlwa2dXUXg1a2JBUnpvYWotNVB6cUdyTkVR</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNjVlcaYM4Fre6F_AGtX6Jw0K1BIylWILAPAXds9WwPalniCJwPFOX5v8h1T-CtoQ?key=OVBmbGlwa2dXUXg1a2JBUnpvYWotNVB6cUdyTkVR&quot;&gt;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNjVlcaYM4Fre6F_AGtX6Jw0K1BIylWILAPAXds9WwPalniCJwPFOX5v8h1T-CtoQ?key=OVBmbGlwa2dXUXg1a2JBUnpvYWotNVB6cUdyTkVR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23505211&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23505211&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 296&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 74&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 23:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbanffy</dc:creator>
<og:title>Design electronics like it is 70's at CERN</og:title>
<og:type>google_photos:photo_album</og:type>
<og:url>https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNjVlcaYM4Fre6F_AGtX6Jw0K1BIylWILAPAXds9WwPalniCJwPFOX5v8h1T-CtoQ?key=OVBmbGlwa2dXUXg1a2JBUnpvYWotNVB6cUdyTkVR</og:url>
<og:image>https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ud9fMxAwk2Z-C7ylXZ-JdMe3BEe9hhDpLKai8tg6aML25wIC869bDn809RplV0qJLvqv81WLUqkRe5U0Wt7CBXblhxtjtBxOvC85sn3KXTVzlIcAj5EJ8THIA2Y6S3ZBc5d3omRuKA=w600-h315-p-k</og:image>
<og:description>35 new photos · Album by Daniel Valuch</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNjVlcaYM4Fre6F_AGtX6Jw0K1BIylWILAPAXds9WwPalniCJwPFOX5v8h1T-CtoQ?key=OVBmbGlwa2dXUXg1a2JBUnpvYWotNVB6cUdyTkVR</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook fires employee for publicly scolding a colleague</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-protests-firing/facebook-fires-employee-who-protested-its-inaction-on-trump-tweets-idUSKBN23J35Y</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-protests-firing/facebook-fires-employee-who-protested-its-inaction-on-trump-tweets-idUSKBN23J35Y</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;SAN FRANCISCO (Reuters) - Facebook Inc fired an employee who had criticized Chief Executive Mark Zuckerberg’s decision not to take action against inflammatory posts by U.S. President Donald Trump this month, citing his tweet challenging a colleague’s silence on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PrimaryAsset_container&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20200613&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1522100471&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPEG5B2A3&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: A Facebook logo is displayed on a smartphone in this illustration taken January 6, 2020. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: A Facebook logo is displayed on a smartphone in this illustration taken January 6, 2020. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brandon Dail, a user interface engineer in Seattle, wrote on Twitter that he was dismissed for publicly scolding a colleague who had refused to include a statement of support for the Black Lives Matter movement on developer documents he was publishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dail sent the tweet a day after joining dozens of employees, including the six other engineers on his team, in abandoning their desks and tweeting objections to Zuckerberg’s handling of Trump’s posts in a rare protest at the social media company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Intentionally not making a statement is already political,” Dail wrote in the tweet, sent on June 2. He said on Friday that he stood by what he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook confirmed Dail’s characterization of his dismissal, but declined to provide additional information. The company said during the walkout that participating employees would not face retaliation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dail did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s posts which prompted the staff outcry included the racially charged phrase “when the looting starts, the shooting starts” in reference to demonstrations against racism and police brutality held after the May 25 killing of George Floyd, a black man who died in police custody in Minneapolis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter affixed a warning label to the same post, saying it glorified violence. Facebook opted to leave the post untouched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zuckerberg defended his decision at a tense all-hands meeting with employees that week. During the meeting, Dail tweeted that it was “crystal clear today that leadership refuses to stand with us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dail again voiced objections this week after both Facebook and Twitter declined to take action against a Trump post that contained an unsubstantiated conspiracy theory about Martin Gugino, a 75-year-old protester who was critically injured by police in Buffalo, New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Trump’s attack on Martin Gugino is despicable and a clear violation [of] Facebook’s anti-harassment rules. It’s again extremely disappointing that we (and Twitter) haven’t removed it,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internal dissent is often encouraged at Silicon Valley tech giants, but the companies have been accused of penalizing workers who organise and air complaints publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alphabet’s Google fired at least five workplace activists late last year, while Amazon dismissed critics of its warehouse conditions during the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both companies denied firing employees for speaking out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by Katie Paul; additional reporting by Paresh Dave; Editing by Greg Mitchell, Will Dunham, Cynthia Osterman and Daniel Wallis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 22:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>TangerineDream</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook fires employee who protested inaction on Trump posts</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-protests-firing-idUSKBN23J35Y</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Facebook Inc fired an employee who had criticized Chief Executive Mark Zuckerberg's decision not to take action against inflammatory posts by U.S. President Donald Trump this month, citing his tweet challenging a colleague's silence on the issue.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20200613&amp;t=2&amp;i=1522100471&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEG5B2A3</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-protests-firing/facebook-fires-employee-who-protested-its-inaction-on-trump-tweets-idUSKBN23J35Y</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>