<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Facebook documents show plans to sell access to user data discussed for years</title>
<link>https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/mark-zuckerberg-leveraged-facebook-user-data-fight-rivals-help-friends-n994706</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/mark-zuckerberg-leveraged-facebook-user-data-fight-rivals-help-friends-n994706</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;tabletNewsletter___Av6eE&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container___jsHMh news___34TC8 dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;newsletter-signup&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;signupBackground___27LhS&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;signupTitle___15fvr&quot;&gt;Breaking News Emails&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;signupForeground___2FAE6&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get breaking news alerts and special reports. The news and stories that matter, delivered weekday mornings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;animateSubscribeButton___EAiad signupButton___Vnoko founders-cond lh-none f4 fs-normal ls-normal pv6&quot;&gt;SUBSCRIBE&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;mb7&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;relative z-1&quot; datetime=&quot;Tue Apr 16 2019 08:30:00 GMT+0000 (UTC)&quot;&gt;April 16, 2019, 8:30 AM GMT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Olivia Solon and Cyrus Farivar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg oversaw plans to consolidate the social network’s power and control competitors by treating its users’ data as a bargaining chip, while publicly proclaiming to be protecting that data, according to about 4,000 pages of leaked company documents largely spanning 2011 to 2015 and obtained by NBC News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The documents, which include emails, webchats, presentations, spreadsheets and meeting summaries, show how Zuckerberg, along with his board and management team, found ways to tap Facebook’s trove of user data — including information about friends, relationships and photos — as leverage over companies it partnered with.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In some cases, Facebook would reward favored companies by giving them access to the data of its users. In other cases, it would deny user-data access to rival companies or apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;inlineVideo___3ZAlE&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pt4 pl4 pr8 pt5-m pl6-m pr9-m info___3BGcG&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;infoText___2xq7T f2 ttu mt3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date___2i7u0&quot;&gt;April 16, 2019&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;03:26&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;For example, Facebook gave Amazon extended access to user data because it was spending money on Facebook advertising and partnering with the social network on the launch of its Fire smartphone. In another case, Facebook discussed cutting off access to user data for a messaging app that had grown too popular and was viewed as a competitor, according to the documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;All the while, Facebook was formulating a strategy to publicly frame these moves as a way of protecting user privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Private communication between users is “increasingly important,” Zuckerberg said in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/23/technology/facebook-offers-privacy-checkup-to-all-1-28-billion-users.html&quot;&gt;2014 New York Times interview&lt;/a&gt;. “Anything we can do that makes people feel more comfortable is really good.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But the documents show that behind the scenes, in contrast with Facebook’s public statements, the company came up with several ways to require third-party applications to compensate Facebook for access to its users’ data, including direct payment, advertising spending and data-sharing arrangements. While it’s not unusual for businesses that are working together to share information about their customers, Facebook has access to sensitive data that many other companies don’t possess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook ultimately decided not to sell the data directly but rather to dole it out to app developers who were considered personal “friends” of Zuckerberg or who spent money on Facebook and shared their own valuable data, the documents show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook denied that it gave preferential treatment to developers or partners because of their ad spending or relationship with executives. The company has not been accused of breaking the law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;mr3&quot;&gt;A man poses for photos in front of the Facebook sign on the company's campus in Menlo Park, California, in 2014.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;f2 ls-tight gray-80 ws-tight founders-mono dib&quot;&gt;Jeff Chiu / AP file&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;About 400 of the 4,000 pages of documents have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/05/technology/facebook-emails-privacy-data.html&quot;&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-considered-charging-for-access-to-user-data-1543454648&quot;&gt;been&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/mar/02/facebook-global-lobbying-campaign-against-data-privacy-laws-investment&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; by other media outlets, and also by a member of the British Parliament who has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5775204-Note-by-Chair-and-Selected-Documents-Ordered.html&quot;&gt;investigating&lt;/a&gt; Facebook’s data privacy practices in the wake of the Cambridge Analytica scandal. However, this cache represents the clearest and most comprehensive picture of Facebook’s activities during a critical period as the company struggled to adapt to the rise of smartphones following its rocky debut as a public company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The thousands of newly shared documents were anonymously leaked to the British investigative journalist Duncan Campbell, who shared them with a handful of media organizations: NBC News, Computer Weekly and Süddeutsche Zeitung. Campbell, a founding member of the International Consortium of Investigative Journalists, is a computer forensics expert who has worked on international investigations including on offshore banking and big tobacco. The documents appear to be the same ones &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parliament.uk/documents/commons-committees/culture-media-and-sport/Further-selected-documents-ordered-from-Six4Three-Feb19.pdf&quot;&gt;obtained by Parliament in late 2018&lt;/a&gt; as part of an investigation into Facebook. Facebook did not question the authenticity of the documents NBC News obtained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related related--relatedContent related___2RfEH single___1bpFv dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The documents stem from a California court case between the social network and the little-known startup Six4Three, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law360.com/articles/701688/facebook-aims-to-kill-bikini-finding-app-developer-s-suit&quot;&gt;sued Facebook in 2015&lt;/a&gt; after the company announced plans to cut off access to some types of user data. Six4Three’s app, Pikinis, which soft-launched in 2013, relied on that data to allow users to easily find photos of their friends in bathing suits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook has acknowledged that it considered &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-considered-charging-for-access-to-user-data-1543454648&quot;&gt;charging for access to user data&lt;/a&gt;. But Facebook has challenged the significance of those discussions, telling the Wall Street Journal last year and NBC News this month that the company was merely mulling various business models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook has also repeatedly said that the documents had been “&lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2018/12/response-to-six4three-documents/&quot;&gt;cherry-picked&lt;/a&gt;” and were misleading. Facebook reiterated this stance when NBC News contacted the social media company for comment on the newly leaked documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“As we’ve said many times, Six4Three — creators of the Pikinis app — cherry picked these documents from years ago as part of a lawsuit to force Facebook to share information on friends of the app's users,” Paul Grewal, vice president and deputy general counsel at Facebook, said in a statement released by the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“The set of documents, by design, tells only one side of the story and omits important context. We still stand by the platform changes we made in 2014/2015 to prevent people from sharing their friends' information with developers like the creators of Pikinis. The documents were selectively leaked as part of what the court found was evidence of a crime or fraud to publish some, but not all, of the internal discussions at Facebook at the time of our platform changes. But the facts are clear: we've never sold people’s data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The finding of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.com/therecorder/2019/03/16/judge-grants-facebooks-crime-fraud-exception-request-for-opposing-counsels-documents/&quot;&gt;“evidence of a crime or fraud”&lt;/a&gt; came from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5771597-2019-03-15-SCARA-Order-Re-Def-s-Mot-to-Open-Disc.html&quot;&gt;preliminary decision&lt;/a&gt; by the judge in the Six4Three case about an earlier round of leaked documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;NBC News has not been able to determine whether the documents represent a complete picture. Facebook declined to provide additional evidence to support the claim of cherry-picking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Still, these freshly leaked documents show that the plans to sell access to user data were discussed for years and received support from Facebook’s most senior executives, including Zuckerberg, chief operating officer Sheryl Sandberg, chief product officer Chris Cox and VP of growth Javier Olivan. Facebook declined to make them available for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;After NBC News contacted Facebook for comment, Facebook’s lawyers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5837524-CIV533328-36.html&quot;&gt;wrote to the judge&lt;/a&gt; in the Six4Three case, claiming that Six4Three had leaked the documents to a “national broadcast network” and seeking to depose Six4Three’s founders. NBC News received the documents from Campbell, who received them from an anonymous source. Six4Three denied leaking the documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related related--relatedContent related___2RfEH single___1bpFv dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;When Facebook ultimately cut off broad access to user data in 2015, the move contributed to the decline of thousands of competitors and small businesses that relied on what Facebook had previously &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scribd.com/doc/81196/Facebook-f8-Platform-FAQ-FINAL&quot;&gt;described as a “level-playing field”&lt;/a&gt; in terms of access to data. In addition to Pikinis, the casualties included Lulu, an app that let women rate the men they dated; an identity fraud-detecting app called Beehive ID; and Swedish breast cancer awareness app Rosa Bandet (Pink Ribbon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The strategy orchestrated by Zuckerberg had some of his employees comparing the company to villains from Game of Thrones, while David Poll, a senior engineer, called the treatment of outside app developers “sort of unethical,” according to the documents. But Zuckerberg’s approach also earned admiration: Doug Purdy, Facebook’s director of product, described the CEO as a “master of leverage,” according to the documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook declined to comment on these employee communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;A PRIVACY MYTH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;One of the most striking threads to emerge from the documents is the way that Facebook user data was horse-traded to squeeze money or shared data from app developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In the wake of the Cambridge Analytica scandal in early 2018 and rising awareness of the Six4Three case, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10105559172610321&quot;&gt;Facebook has attempted to frame changes&lt;/a&gt; it made to its platform in 2014 and 2015 as being driven by concerns over user privacy. In statements to media organizations, Facebook has said it locked down its platform to protect users from companies that mishandled user data, such as Cambridge Analytica, as well as apps that spammed users’ news feeds or were creepy, such as Six4Three’s bikini-spotting app Pikinis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related related--relatedContent related___2RfEH single___1bpFv dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;However, among the documents leaked, there’s very little evidence that privacy was a major concern of Facebook’s, and the issue was rarely discussed in the thousands of pages of emails and meeting summaries. Where privacy is mentioned, it is often in the context of how Facebook can use it as a public relations strategy to soften the blow of the sweeping changes to developers’ access to user data. The documents include several examples suggesting that these changes were designed to cement Facebook’s power in the marketplace, not to protect users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In Six4Three’s case, for example, Facebook’s head of policy Allison Hendrix acknowledged in a June 2017 deposition obtained by NBC News that the social network never received any complaints about the Pikinis app, nor did Facebook send Six4Three any policy or privacy violation notices. Six4Three, Hendrix confirmed, was playing within the rules Facebook had set for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Despite this, Six4Three’s access to data, specifically access to a user’s friends’ photos, was cut off in April 2015 as part of sweeping changes to Facebook’s platform announced a year earlier, which affected as many as 40,000 apps. Six4Three shut down the app soon afterward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;mr3&quot;&gt;Ted Kramer, founder of Six4Three.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;f2 ls-tight gray-80 ws-tight founders-mono dib&quot;&gt;Peter DaSilva / for NBC News&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Our case is about Zuckerberg’s decision to weaponize the reliance of companies on his purportedly neutral platform and to weaponize the private and sensitive data of billions of people,” said Six4Three founder Ted Kramer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;A TURNING POINT FOR FACEBOOK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook recognized early on that working with third-party app developers could help make the social network more interesting and drive the platform’s expansion. Beginning in early 2010, Facebook created tools that allowed the makers of games (remember Farmville?) and other apps to connect with its audience in return for ensuring those users spent more time on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook achieved this through its “Graph API” (Application Programming Interface), a common means to allow software programs to interact with each other. In Facebook’s case, this meant that third-party apps such as games could post updates on people’s profiles, which would be seen by players’ friends and potentially encourage them to play, too. Beyond that, it allowed the makers of those games to access a slew of data from Facebook users, including their connections to friends, likes, locations, updates, photos and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Graph API — and particularly the way it let third parties promote their products to and extract data from a user’s social connections — was a key feature of Facebook that Six4Three and thousands of other companies relied upon for viral marketing and user growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;However, after a few years, Facebook decided the app developers were getting more value from the user data they extracted from Facebook than Facebook was getting out of the app developers, the documents show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;embedWidget small___1S8zc&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;After Facebook went public in May 2012, its stock price plummeted, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/tomiogeron/2012/09/11/live-facebooks-mark-zuckerberg-at-techcrunch-disrupt/#6f6c6f6b4fe6&quot;&gt;Zuckerberg later characterized as “disappointing.”&lt;/a&gt; The company was in a desperate position, documents show, with users sharing fewer photos and posts on the platform as they spent more time on their cellphones. An internal Facebook presentation looking back at this period used the phrase “terminal decline” to describe the fall in engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook executives, including Zuckerberg and Sandberg, spent months brainstorming ways to turn the company around. An idea that they kept returning to: make money from the app partners, by charging them for access to Facebook’s users and their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;‘SELL DATA FOR $”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Several proposals for charging developers for access to Facebook’s platform and data were put forward in a presentation to the company’s board of directors, according to emails and draft slides from late August 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Among the suggestions: a fixed annual fee for developers for reviewing their apps; an access fee for apps that requested user data; and a charge for “premium” access to data, such as a user trust score or a ranking of the strongest relationships between users and their friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Today the fundamental trade is ‘data for distribution’ whereas we want to change it to either ‘data for $’ and/or ‘$ for distribution,’” Chris Daniels, a Facebook business development director, wrote in an August 2012 email to other top leaders in the company discussing the upcoming presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Discussions continued through October, when Zuckerberg explained to close friend Sam Lessin the importance of controlling third-party apps’ ability to access Facebook’s data and reach people’s friends on the platform. Without that leverage, “I don’t think we have any way to get developers to pay us at all,” Zuckerberg wrote in an email to Lessin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In the same week, Zuckerberg floated the idea of pursuing 100 deals with developers “as a path to figuring out the real market value” of Facebook user data and then “setting a public rate” for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“The goal here wouldn’t be the deals themselves, but that through the process of negotiating with them we’d learn what developers would actually pay (which might be different from what they’d say if we just asked them about the value), and then we’d be better informed on our path to set a public rate,” Zuckerberg wrote in a chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook told NBC News that it was exploring ways to build a sustainable business, but ultimately decided not to go forward with these plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quote___U_LGF small___2-X0R&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;collapseContainer___3IP99&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container___1YAfH mt8 mt2-m mb8&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pullQuote___PESSR&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;content___3WSQL f8 lh-none founders-cond pt6 mt0 mb5&quot;&gt;&quot;I just can’t think of any instances where that data has leaked from developer to developer and caused a real issue for us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Zuckerberg was unfazed by the potential privacy risks associated with Facebook’s data-sharing arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“I’m generally skeptical that there is as much data leak strategic risk as you think,” he wrote in the email to Lessin. “I think we leak info to developers but I just can’t think of any instances where that data has leaked from developer to developer and caused a real issue for us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook told NBC News that this was an example of a cherry-picked email designed to bolster Six4Three’s case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Zuckerberg didn’t know it at the time, but a privacy bug affecting an unnamed third-party app would create precisely this kind of strategic risk the following year, according to a panicked chatlog between Michael Vernal, who was director of engineering, and other senior employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;It’s not clear exactly what happened or which app was involved, but it appears that Zuckerberg’s private communications could have leaked from Facebook to the external app in an unexpected way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Vernal said that it “could have been near-fatal for Facebook platform” if “Mark had accidentally disclosed earnings ahead of time because a platform app violated his privacy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Holy crap,” replied Avichal Garg, then director of product management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“DO NOT REPEAT THIS STORY OFF OF THIS THREAD,” added Vernal. “I can’t tell you how terrible this would have been for all of us had this not been caught quickly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Vernal and Garg did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;‘GOOD FOR THE WORLD’ BUT NOT ‘GOOD FOR US’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In late November 2012, Zuckerberg sent a long email to Facebook’s senior leadership team saying that Facebook shouldn’t charge developers for access to basic data feeds. However, he said that access to Facebook data should be contingent on the developers sharing all of the “social content” generated by their apps back to Facebook, something Zuckerberg calls “full reciprocity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The existing arrangement, where developers weren’t required to share their data back with Facebook, might be “good for the world” but it’s not “good for us,” Zuckerberg wrote in the email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;He noted that though Facebook could charge developers to access user data, the company stood to benefit more from requiring developers to compensate Facebook in kind — with their own data — and by pushing those developers to pay for advertising on Facebook’s platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The endgame: to ensure Facebook maintained its dominant position in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“The purpose of the platform is to tie the universe of all the social apps together so we can enable a lot more sharing and still remain the central social hub,” Zuckerberg said in the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook told NBC News that the focus of “full reciprocity” was to enable users to share their experiences within external apps with their friends on Facebook, not about providing Facebook with user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;CUTTING DEALS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;With Zuckerberg’s vision for Facebook set, the company began making deals with some of its most valued partners, including dozens of app developer friends of Zuckerberg and Sandberg. Facebook whitelisted their access to feeds of user data while restricting that same access to apps that Facebook viewed as competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;These data access deals prepared key partners, including Tinder, Sony and Microsoft, for sweeping changes to the Facebook platform that the company planned to announce at its annual developer conference in April 2014 and enforce within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In one instance, described in June 2013 documents, Amazon received special treatment for the launch of a group gifting product, despite the fact that it competed with one of Facebook’s own products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Remind me, why did we allow them to do this? Do we receive any cut of purchases?” Chris Daniels, then Facebook’s director of business development, asked in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“No, but Amazon is an advertiser and supporting this with advertisement ... and working with us on deeper integrations for the Fire,” Amazon’s smartphone, replied Jackie Chang, who worked with Facebook’s “strategic partners.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon released a statement to NBC News: “Amazon uses publicly available APIs provided by Facebook in order to enable Facebook experiences for our products and only uses information in accordance with our privacy policy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Apps that were not considered “strategic partners” got different treatment. In a March 2013 discussion, Justin Osofsky, then director of platform partnerships, described restricting the MessageMe app from accessing Facebook data because it had grown too popular and could compete with Facebook messages. He asked colleagues to see if any other messenger apps have “hit the growth team’s radar recently.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“If so, we'd like to restrict them at the same time to group this into one press cycle,&quot; he wrote in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;‘IT’S SORT OF UNETHICAL’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Deal negotiations created confusion among partners who had grown accustomed to unfettered access to Facebook user data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“We gave a bunch of stuff ‘for free’ historically (data, distribution) and now we’re making you ‘pay’ for it via reciprocal value,” Vernal, director of engineering, wrote in an email in June 2013. He added, “The confusing thing here is that we haven’t really announced these changes publicly/broadly yet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Some Facebook employees were unhappy about this direction, particularly the way the company appeared to be blocking competitors from accessing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Here’s an extract from a December 2013 chatlog between several senior engineers talking about the changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bryan Klimt: “So we are literally going to group apps into buckets based on how scared we are of them and give them different APIs? ... So the message is, ‘if you’re going to compete with us at all, make sure you don’t integrate with us at all’? I’m just dumbfounded.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Kevin Lacker: “Yeah this is complicated.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;David Poll: “More than complicated, it’s sort of unethical.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Lacker and Poll declined to comment. Vernal and Klimt did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook declined to comment on the employee exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;THE PR SPIN&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;When it came to publicly announcing the sweeping changes at Facebook’s annual F8 developer conference in April 2014, members of the communications team worked with Zuckerberg to craft a narrative around user trust, not competition or profitability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In a March 2014 email discussing Zuckerberg’s keynote speech at the event, where he was due to announce the removal of developers’ access to friends’ data, Jonny Thaw, a director of communications, wrote that it “may be a tough message for some developers as it may inhibit their growth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“So one idea that came up today was potentially talking in the keynote about some of the trust changes we’re making on Facebook itself. So the message would be: ‘trust is really important to us — on Facebook, we’re doing A, B and C to help people control and understand what they’re sharing — and with platform apps we’re doing D, E and F.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;If that doesn’t work, he added, “we could announce some of Facebook’s trust initiatives in the run up to F8” to make the changes for developers “seem more natural.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook told NBC News that it was “completely reasonable” for someone on the communications team to discuss the best way to get the message out on changes to the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;User trust was crucial when Zuckerberg delivered his speech at the event on April 30, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;mr3&quot;&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg delivers the keynote address at the F8 developer conference in San Francisco in 2014.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;f2 ls-tight gray-80 ws-tight founders-mono dib&quot;&gt;Ben Margot / AP file&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Over the years, one of the things we’ve heard over and over again is that people want more control over how they share their information, especially with apps, and they want more say and control over how apps use their data,” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DVu311G5qvI&quot;&gt;told the audience of journalists and developers&lt;/a&gt;. “And we take this really seriously because if people don’t have the tools they need to feel comfortable using your apps, that’s bad for them and that’s bad for you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But despite Facebook’s public focus on privacy, staff member emails described confusion over the way third-party apps could override users’ privacy settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Even if users locked down their account so that their photos and other data were visible to “only me,” those photos could still be transferred to third parties, according to the documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In April 2015, Connie Yang, a product designer, told her colleagues that she’d discovered apps collecting profile data she had marked as “only me” and displaying it to “both you and *other people* using that app.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“While ‘whoa how did you start working at Casterly Rock’ is a fun opener,” she wrote, referring to the ancestral stronghold of the most fearsome family in “Game of Thrones,” “isn’t this directly violating what we tell users is ‘only me’?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Yang did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook said this was another example of cherry-picked emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;THE DOCUMENTS’ LEGACY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Even though Facebook eventually decided not to charge developers directly for access to user data, the extensive discussions around its monetary value, shown in the leaked documents, could create lasting problems for the company, privacy and policy experts say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The biggest threat Facebook faces now is not competition but antitrust regulation, which is designed to promote fair competition among companies for the benefit of consumers, using fines or restrictions on mergers and acquisitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Regulators have typically struggled to build robust antitrust cases against technology companies that offer services to users for free. If the product is free, then it’s harder to argue that the consumer is being harmed by a monopoly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But if regulators can show that users were paying for access to Facebook with their personal data, and that Facebook valued that data as leverage against competitors, that could expose Facebook to an antitrust complaint, said Jason Kint, CEO of Digital Content Next, a trade association representing digital publishers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“These emails clearly establish the value of consumer data to Facebook,” Kint said. “It shows that it is not free.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook said that the service has always been free for users and developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related related--relatedContent related___2RfEH single___1bpFv dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In February, the Federal Trade Commission announced a task force to monitor anti-competitive behavior in the tech industry to, in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2019/02/ftcs-bureau-competition-launches-task-force-monitor-technology&quot;&gt;words of FTC chair Joseph Simons&lt;/a&gt;, “ensure consumers benefit from free and fair competition.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Policymakers have called for the FTC to investigate Facebook specifically for violating antitrust laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The company “appears to have used its dominance to cripple other competitive threats by cutting them off from its massive network,” Rep. David Cicilline, D-R.I., chairman of the House Judiciary antitrust subcommittee, wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/19/opinion/facebook-antitrust-investigation.html&quot;&gt;New York Times op-ed last month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook appears to be preparing for the inevitable, with Zuckerberg writing his own op-ed in The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/mark-zuckerberg-the-internet-needs-new-rules-lets-start-in-these-four-areas/2019/03/29/9e6f0504-521a-11e9-a3f7-78b7525a8d5f_story.html?utm_term=.bd2bcf695b30&quot;&gt;Washington Post in March calling for regulation&lt;/a&gt; in areas including harmful content and election integrity, but not antitrust. Facebook watchers saw this show of willingness as an attempt by Zuckerberg to curry favor with policymakers at a time when many are baying for the company’s blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Ashkan Soltani, a privacy expert and former FTC chief technologist, said that Zuckerberg is approaching the looming threat of regulation with “bravado” and trying to “leverage things for his benefit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/profcarroll?lang=en&quot;&gt;David Carroll&lt;/a&gt;, a professor at the New School, who pursued legal claims in the U.K. in the wake of the Cambridge Analytica data scandal, says Zuckerberg is “bracing for impact.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“When the penalty hits they can be like, ‘Yeah, we agree, we deserve this fine.’ It positions them to be conciliatory,” Carroll said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The “master of leverage” strikes again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lastMarkupItem&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This report has been prepared and published in conjunction with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.duncancampbell.org&quot;&gt;Duncan Campbell&lt;/a&gt; (U.K.), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computerweekly.com&quot;&gt;Computer Weekly&lt;/a&gt; (U.K.) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sueddeutsche.de&quot;&gt;Süddeutsche Zeitung&lt;/a&gt; (Germany).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleBylineContainer mt8&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleByline byline___2NGv_ noImage___3G0GY pt3 pb2&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__name name___32ZJk founders-mono f3 lh-title ls-tight pt1 pt4-m ml9 ml0-m ml0-print&quot;&gt;Olivia Solon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__social social___kAOJV f2 mt2 mt4-m ml9 ml0-m dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;article-byline__social&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;articleByline__bio bio___3q2CD publico-txt f2 lh-copy mt3 mt0-m ml9-m&quot;&gt;Olivia Solon is a tech investigations editor for NBC News in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleByline byline___2NGv_ hasImage___1TEVp pt3 pb2&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner___y8Zvr mt2 mt0-m&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__image image___c6bcD mr4&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media1.s-nbcnews.com/i/newscms/2019_11/2784541/cyrus-farivar-1500_600ddbe81f24c1b47efb34ab66625731.jpg&quot; class=&quot;headshot___3D_6B w3-print&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__name name___32ZJk founders-mono f3 lh-title ls-tight pt1 pt4-m ml9 ml0-m ml0-print&quot;&gt;Cyrus Farivar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__social social___kAOJV f2 mt2 mt4-m ml9 ml0-m dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;article-byline__social&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;articleByline__bio bio___3q2CD publico-txt f2 lh-copy mt3 mt0-m ml9-m&quot;&gt;Cyrus Farivar is a reporter on the tech investigations unit of NBC News in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Abbruzzese, Michael Cappetta, David Ingram and Ben Popken contributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 11:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/mark-zuckerberg-leveraged-facebook-user-data-fight-rivals-help-friends-n994706</og:url>
<og:title>Thousands of leaked Facebook documents show Mark Zuckerberg as ‘master of leverage’ in plan to trade user data</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook’s leaders seriously discussed selling access to user data — and privacy was an afterthought.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media2.s-nbcnews.com/j/newscms/2019_16/2813741/190408-facebook-documents-privacy-main-kh_f4a6bfef6b06cef6f61fdc00decbc67e.nbcnews-fp-1200-630.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/mark-zuckerberg-leveraged-facebook-user-data-fight-rivals-help-friends-n994706</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Source Code for Zork, Hitchhiker’s Guide, and Other Infocom Games on GitHub</title>
<link>https://github.com/historicalsource?tab=repositories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/historicalsource?tab=repositories</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/historicalsource?tab=repositories&quot;&gt;https://github.com/historicalsource?tab=repositories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19672436&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19672436&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 387&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 108&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 10:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>laurent123456</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/49599193?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>profile</og:type>
<og:title>historicalsource - Overview</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/historicalsource</og:url>
<og:description>A collection of historical source files, for education and perusal. - historicalsource</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/historicalsource?tab=repositories</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple: Rotate tracking IDs on iPhone each month</title>
<link>https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/campaigns/privacy-thats-iphone-but-is-it/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/campaigns/privacy-thats-iphone-but-is-it/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There is a unique ID living on your iPhone right now that allows advertisers to track the ads you click on, the videos you play, and the apps you install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is, &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074&quot;&gt;you can turn this identifier off&lt;/a&gt;. The bad news: most people don’t know that feature exists, let alone that they should turn it off. And we don’t think that they should have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s why we’re asking Apple to change the unique IDs that advertisers use to track us on each iPhone, every month.&lt;/strong&gt; That means we could still get relevant ads – but there’s a real cap that makes it harder for companies to build profiles of us over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will you add your name to the petition?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 09:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>denzil_correa</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://foundation.mozilla.org/en/campaigns/privacy-thats-iphone-but-is-it/</og:url>
<og:title>“Privacy. That’s iPhone.” But is it?</og:title>
<og:description>Tell Apple to protect iPhone users’ privacy</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.mofoprod.net/network/images/mozilla-og-image-min.original.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/campaigns/privacy-thats-iphone-but-is-it/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why software projects take longer than you think – a statistical model</title>
<link>https://erikbern.com/2019/04/15/why-software-projects-take-longer-than-you-think-a-statistical-model.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://erikbern.com/2019/04/15/why-software-projects-take-longer-than-you-think-a-statistical-model.html</guid>
<description>&lt;time datetime=&quot;2019-04-15T00:00:00-04:00&quot; class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;2019-04-15&lt;/time&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who built software for a while knows that estimating how long something is going to take is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. It’s hard to come up with an unbiased estimate of how long something will take, when fundamentally the work in itself is about &lt;em&gt;solving&lt;/em&gt; something. One pet theory I’ve had for a really long time, is that some of this is really just a statistical artifact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot; readability=&quot;6.0783783783784&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;5.6108108108108&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I suspect devs are actually decent at estimating the *median* time to complete a task. Planning is hard because they suck at the *average*.&lt;/p&gt;
— Erik Bernhardsson (@fulhack) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fulhack/status/862791164759617536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 11, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you estimate a project to take 1 week. Let’s say there are three equally likely outcomes: either it takes 1/2 week, or 1 week, or 2 weeks. The &lt;em&gt;median&lt;/em&gt; outcome is actually the same as the estimate: 1 week, but the &lt;em&gt;mean&lt;/em&gt; (aka &lt;em&gt;average&lt;/em&gt;, aka &lt;em&gt;expected value&lt;/em&gt;) is 7/6 = 1.17 weeks. The estimate is actually calibrated (unbiased) for the median (which is 1), but not for the the mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reasonable model for the “blowup factor” would be something like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Log-normal_distribution&quot;&gt;log-normal distribution&lt;/a&gt;. If the estimate is one week, then let’s model the real outcome as a random variable distributed according to the log-normal distribution around one week. This has the property that the median of the distribution is exactly one week, but the mean is much larger:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://erikbern.com/assets/software-estimation/log_normal.png&quot; alt=&quot;log normal&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we take the logarithm of the blowup factor, we end up with a plain old normal distribution centered around 0. This assumes the median blowup factor is 1x, and as you hopefully remember, . However, different tasks may have different uncertainties around 0. We can model this by varying the σ parameter which corresponds to the standard deviation of the normal distribution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://erikbern.com/assets/software-estimation/normal.png&quot; alt=&quot;normal&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to put some numbers on this: when log(actual / estimated) = 1 then the blowup factor is exp(1) = e = 2.72. It’s equally likely that a project blows up by a factor of exp(2) = 7.4 as it is that it completes in exp(-2) = 0.14 i.e. completes in 14% of the estimated time. Intuitively the reason the mean is so large is that tasks that complete faster than estimated have no way to compensate for the tasks that take much longer than estimated. We’re bounded by 0, but unbounded in the other direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this just a model? You bet! But I’ll get to real data shortly and show that this in fact maps to reality reasonably well using some empirical data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;software-estimation&quot;&gt;Software estimation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far so good, but let’s really try to understand what this means in terms of software estimation. Let’s say we look at the roadmap and it consists of 20 different software projects and we’re trying to estimate: how long is it going to take to complete &lt;em&gt;all of them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s where the the mean becomes crucial. Means add, but medians do not. So if we want to get an idea of how long it will take to complete the sum of  projects, we need to look at the mean. Let’s say we have three different projects in the pipeline with the exact same :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Median&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mean&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;99%&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SUM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.98&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.95&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;18.85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that the means add up and 4.95 = 1.65*3, but the other columns don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s add up three projects with different sigmas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Median&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mean&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;99%&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task A ()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task B ()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task C ()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.39&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104.87&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SUM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;107.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The means still add up, but are nowhere near the naïve 3 week estimate you might come up with. Note that the high-uncertainty project with  basically ends up &lt;em&gt;dominating&lt;/em&gt; the mean time to completion. For the 99% percentile, it doesn’t just dominate it, it basically absorbs all the other ones. We can do a bigger example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Median&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mean&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;99%&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task A ()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task B ()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task C ()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task D ()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task E ()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task F ()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Task G ()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.39&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104.87&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SUM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9.74&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15.71&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;112.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, one single misbehaving task basically ends up dominating the calculation, at least for the 99% case. Even for mean though, the one freak project ends up taking over roughly half the time spend on these tasks, despite all of these tasks having a similar median time to completion. To make it simple, I assumed that all tasks have the same estimated size, but different uncertainties. The same math applies if we vary the size as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny thing is I’ve had this gut feeling for a while. Adding up estimates rarely work when you end up with more than a few tasks. Instead, figure out which tasks have the highest uncertainty – those tasks are basically going to dominate the mean time to completion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot; readability=&quot;7.6623376623377&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;8.6201298701299&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I have two methods for estimating project size:&lt;br/&gt;(a) break things down into subprojects, estimate them, add it up&lt;br/&gt;(b) gut feeling estimate based on how nervous i feel about unexpected risks&lt;br/&gt;So far (b) is vastly more accurate for any project more than a few weeks&lt;/p&gt;
— Erik Bernhardsson (@fulhack) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fulhack/status/1103871565685391360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 8, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chart summarizes the mean and 99th percentile as a function of the uncertainty (σ):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://erikbern.com/assets/software-estimation/sigmas.png&quot; alt=&quot;sigmas&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is math to this now! I’ve started appreciating this during project planning: I truly think that adding up task estimates is a really misleading picture of how long something will take, because you have these crazy skewed tasks that will end up taking over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wheres-the-empirical-data&quot;&gt;Where’s the empirical data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I filed this in my brain under “curious toy models” for a long time, occasionally thinking that it’s a neat illustration of a real world phenomenon I’ve observed. But surfing around on the interwebs one day, I encountered an interesting dataset of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Derek-Jones/SiP_dataset&quot;&gt;project estimation and actual times&lt;/a&gt;. Fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s do a quick scatter plot of estimated vs actual time to completion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://erikbern.com/assets/software-estimation/scatter.png&quot; alt=&quot;scatter&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The median “blowup factor” (actual time divided by estimated time) turns out to be &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; 1x for this dataset, whereas the mean blowup factor is 1.81x. Again, this confirms the hunch that developers estimate the &lt;em&gt;median&lt;/em&gt; well, but the mean ends up being much higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at the distribution of the blowup factor. We’re going to look at the logarithm of it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://erikbern.com/assets/software-estimation/distribution.png&quot; alt=&quot;distribution&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see that it’s pretty well centered around 0, where the blowup factor is exp(0) = 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to get a bit fancy with statistics now – feel free to skip if it’s not your cup of tea. What can we infer from this empirical distribution? You might expect that the logarithms of the blowup factor would distribute according to a normal distribution, but that’s not quite true. Note that the σs are themselves random and vary for each project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One convenient way to model the σs is that they are sampled from an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inverse-gamma_distribution&quot;&gt;inverse Gamma distribution&lt;/a&gt;. If we assume (like previously) that the log of the blowup factors are distributed according to a normal distribution, then the “global” distribution of the logs of blowup factors ends up being &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Student%27s_t-distribution&quot;&gt;Student’s t-distribution&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s fit a Student’s t-distribution to the distribution above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://erikbern.com/assets/software-estimation/distribution_plus_t.png&quot; alt=&quot;distribution&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decent fit, in my opinion! The parameters of the t-distribution also define the inverse Gamma distribution of the σ values:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://erikbern.com/assets/software-estimation/sigma_distribution.png&quot; alt=&quot;sigma distribution&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that values like  are incredibly unlikely, but when they happen, they cause a mean blowup of several thousand times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-software-tasks-always-take-longer-than-you-think&quot;&gt;Why software tasks always take longer than you think&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming this dataset is representative of software development (questionable!), we can infer some more numbers. We have the parameters for the t-distribution, so we can compute the mean time it takes to complete a task, without knowing the σ for that task is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the median blowup factor imputed from this fit is 1x (as before), the 99% percentile blowup factor is 32x, but if you go to 99.99% percentile, it’s a whopping 55 &lt;em&gt;million&lt;/em&gt;! One (hand wavy) interpretation is that some tasks end up being essentially impossible to do. In fact, these extreme edge cases have such an outsize impact on the &lt;em&gt;mean&lt;/em&gt;, that the mean blowup factor of &lt;em&gt;any task&lt;/em&gt; ends up being &lt;em&gt;infinite&lt;/em&gt;. This is pretty bad news for people trying to hit deadlines!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my model is right (a big &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt;) then here’s what we can learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;People estimate the &lt;em&gt;median&lt;/em&gt; completion time well, but not the mean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mean turns out to be substantially worse than the median, due to the distribution being skewed (log-normally).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you add up the estimates for n tasks, things get even worse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tasks with the most uncertainty (rather the biggest size) can often dominate the mean time it takes to complete all tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mean time to complete a task we know nothing about is actually &lt;em&gt;infinite&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This is obviously just based on one dataset I found online. Other datasets may give different results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My model is of course also highly subjective, like any statistical model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would ❤️ to apply the model to a much larger data set to see how well it holds up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I assumed all tasks independent. In reality they might have a correlation which would make the analysis a lot more annoying but (I think) ultimately with similar conclusions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sum of log-normally distributed value is not another log-normally distributed value. This is a weakness with that distribution, since you could argue most tasks is really just a sum of sub-tasks and it would be nice if our distribution was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stable_distribution&quot;&gt;stable&lt;/a&gt; like that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I removed small tasks (estimated time less than or equal to 7 hours) from the histogram since small tasks skew the analysis and there there was an odd spike at exactly 7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/erikbern/software-estimation&quot;&gt;code is on my Github&lt;/a&gt;, as usual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s some &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19671673&quot;&gt;discussion on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 07:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mzl</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why software projects take longer than you think – a statistical model</og:title>
<og:description>Anyone who built software for a while knows that estimating how long something is going to take is hard. It’s hard to come up with an unbiased estimate of how long something will take, when fundamentally the work in itself is about solving something.</og:description>
<og:url>https://erikbern.com/2019/04/15/why-software-projects-take-longer-than-you-think-a-statistical-model.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://erikbern.com/assets/software-estimation/log_normal.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://erikbern.com/2019/04/15/why-software-projects-take-longer-than-you-think-a-statistical-model.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“I worked at Boeing for about 1.5 years in the 2008-9 time period”</title>
<link>https://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/bdfqm4/the_real_reason_boeings_new_plane_crashed_twice/ekyyd9g/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/bdfqm4/the_real_reason_boeings_new_plane_crashed_twice/ekyyd9g/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;s14dydj4-10 kiAEUp&quot;&gt;I worked at Boeing for about 1.5 years in the 2008-9 time period and I can absolutely guarantee this happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s14dydj4-10 kiAEUp&quot;&gt;First, Boeing's corporate culture is the worst shitshow I have ever experienced. All large corporations have a lot of internal issues and problems but nothing like the Lazy B. It was like working in a company designed by Kafka. I signed up at Boeing as a programmer. When I showed up at my first day of work, the first words out of my supervisor's mouth were, &quot;I don't know why you are here, we have no need for programmers.&quot; (The Boeing interview process is done so that at no point, do you ever have contact or communication with the team you will be working with.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s14dydj4-10 kiAEUp&quot;&gt;So, basically, I was cutting and pasting cells in Excel spreadsheets and doing ad hoc project management during my time there. They did have need for a programmer, but I didn't have access to install any programming software on my machine because no one knew who the local IT person was. No one. It was a year before I was able to figure that out and only because I was bored one day and was walking around the building and found the guy's cubicle by accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s14dydj4-10 kiAEUp&quot;&gt;To be fair, the aging aircraft division that I was in was notoriously bad, even for Boeing. It was where they put people that the union wouldn't let Boeing fire. I would conservatively estimate 30% of my co-workers were full-blown sociopaths who would actively work to sabotage and ruin other people's work. Another 50% of the people there blatantly goofed off all day, reading the newspaper or books with their feet up on their desks (literally). The remaining 20% were people who actually cared about airplane passengers not dying and worked themselves half to death to keep things afloat. I'll give a quick shout out to Anastasia, James and all the contract workers who actually did their jobs. There are probably a few thousand people around the world who aren't dead because of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s14dydj4-10 kiAEUp&quot;&gt;Anyhow, James (or was it Jim? It's been a while.) was a grouchy old engineer they stuck me next to. He was close to retirement and clearly wasn't too stoked about losing half his cubicle to an unwanted programmer that showed up one day. James had a bunch of photos of an old 747 and structural diagrams pinned to his cubicle wall. One day, I asked what those were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s14dydj4-10 kiAEUp&quot;&gt;They were pictures and failure analysis diagrams of &lt;a class=&quot;s14dydj4-27 gUNsVq&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japan_Airlines_Flight_123&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JAL 123&lt;/a&gt;, the single worst single airplane disaster in history. 520 people died. It was because a couple of Boeing engineers fucked up. That 747SR had had a tailstrike incident on takeoff that damaged the rear pressure dome. A team of Boeing AOG (Airplane On the Ground) mechanics were flown out there to fix it. To oversimplify, they rushed and accidentally did the equivalent of 1+1=1 on one of their stress calculations. It was an error very similar to the infamous &lt;a class=&quot;s14dydj4-27 gUNsVq&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyatt_Regency_walkway_collapse&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyatt Regency walkway collapse&lt;/a&gt;. 12,318 flights later, (well before what should have been at least 25-30,000 flight cycles that the crack inspection cycle would have assumed) the rear bullkhead ripped out mid flight and severed all hydraulic control lines. The plane lost all control and flew in a rollercoaster trajectory for 32 minutes before running into the side of a mountain. Many of the passengers had time to write goodbye letters to their loved ones. James had those photos and diagrams on his cubicle so that every day, he could look at them and remind himself of why his job was important and why he couldn't cut corners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s14dydj4-10 kiAEUp&quot;&gt;James was clearly an incredibly knowledgeable and talented engineer. He was the widely acknowledged expert in the entire department. If any other engineer had a question, they would always come to him for advice. So why was such a good engineer relegated to a department full of fuckups and malcontents? Because he wouldn't cut corners on safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s14dydj4-10 kiAEUp&quot;&gt;This was the final stages of the 787 rollout, which was behind schedule and full of issues. James had constantly raised red flags about safety corners Boeing was cutting on the 787 rollout. Things like putting the plane out before there was a good understanding of crack propagation speed, nondestructive testing protocols and repair protocols for all the carbon fiber on the plane. These were extremely serious issues that Boeing swept under the rug to get the 787 out faster. Because he wouldn't toe the line on this, James got exiled to the shitty little backwater I ran into him at where he was counting the days until he could retire and spend his time SCUBA diving out at Edmonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s14dydj4-10 kiAEUp&quot;&gt;To this day, I refuse to fly on a 787. I'm sure that the Dreamliners that came off the assembly line after about a year or so were fine but there's that first year of production that, as far as I'm concerned, are ticking time bombs. I talked to many engineers who had worked on that program to know just how badly they rushed that initial production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s14dydj4-10 kiAEUp&quot;&gt;So, as far as I'm concerned, fuck Boeing. This was inevitable. I'm honestly shocked it took this long for something like this to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 06:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thereare5lights</dc:creator>
<og:title>r/videos - The real reason Boeing's new plane crashed twice</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/bdfqm4/the_real_reason_boeings_new_plane_crashed_twice/ekyyd9g</og:url>
<og:description>47,076 votes and 5,991 comments so far on Reddit</og:description>
<og:image>https://external-preview.redd.it/_SMTWkXVI-SFsWm-FE79VxtI5HubUD0qtlH7fn3BJr4.jpg?auto=webp&amp;s=0d4d44b29d8374c62a299ebe0e37dfbf164509a0</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/bdfqm4/the_real_reason_boeings_new_plane_crashed_twice/ekyyd9g/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsimulation of Traffic Flow</title>
<link>http://traffic-simulation.de/ring.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://traffic-simulation.de/ring.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;startStopDiv&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;startStop&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/buttonStop3_small.png&quot; onclick=&quot;myStartStopFunction()&quot; name=&quot;startStop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;infoDiv&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/infoBlue.png&quot; onclick=&quot;showInfo()&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lanePlusDiv&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/autobahn_plus.png&quot; onclick=&quot;addOneLane()&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;laneMinusDiv&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/autobahn_minus.png&quot; onclick=&quot;subtractOneLane()&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;scenarios&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;18%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/iconRing_small.jpg&quot; onclick=&quot;myRedirectRing()&quot; /&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;20%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/iconOnrampFig_small.jpg&quot; onclick=&quot;myRedirectOnramp()&quot; /&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;20%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/iconOfframpFig_small.jpg&quot; onclick=&quot;myRedirectOfframp()&quot; /&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;20%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/iconRoadworksFig_small.jpg&quot; onclick=&quot;myRedirectRoadworks()&quot; /&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;20%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/iconUphillFig_small.jpg&quot; onclick=&quot;myRedirectUphill()&quot; /&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;20%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/iconRoutingFig_small.jpg&quot; onclick=&quot;myRedirectRouting()&quot; /&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;22%&quot; src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/figs/iconRoundabout_small.jpg&quot; onclick=&quot;myRedirectRoundabout()&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your browser does not support the HTML5 canvas tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;impressum&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/impressum.html&quot;&gt;© Martin Treiber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sliders&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Traffic Flow and General&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table id=&quot;mainTable&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;important&quot;&gt;Density/lane&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_density&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0&quot; max=&quot;100&quot; step=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Truck Perc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_truckFrac&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0&quot; max=&quot;50&quot; step=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Timewarp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_timewarp&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0.2&quot; max=&quot;20&quot; step=&quot;0.1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Car-Following Behavior&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table id=&quot;mainTable&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;important&quot;&gt;Max Accel a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_IDM_a&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0.3&quot; max=&quot;4&quot; step=&quot;0.1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Max Speed v0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_IDM_v0&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;20&quot; max=&quot;160&quot; step=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Time Gap T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_IDM_T&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0.6&quot; max=&quot;3&quot; step=&quot;0.1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Min Gap s0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_IDM_s0&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0.5&quot; max=&quot;5&quot; step=&quot;0.1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Comf Decel b&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_IDM_b&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;0.5&quot; max=&quot;5&quot; step=&quot;0.1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Lane-Changing Behavior&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table id=&quot;mainTable&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Politeness&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_MOBIL_p&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;-0.2&quot; max=&quot;1&quot; step=&quot;0.1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;LC Threshold&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_MOBIL_bThr&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;-0.1&quot; max=&quot;1&quot; step=&quot;0.1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Right Bias Cars&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_MOBIL_bBiasRight_car&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;-1&quot; max=&quot;2&quot; step=&quot;0.1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Right Bias Trucks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;slider_MOBIL_bBiasRight_truck&quot; type=&quot;range&quot; min=&quot;-1&quot; max=&quot;2&quot; step=&quot;0.1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;linkDiv&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;infoTable&quot; readability=&quot;0.039473684210526&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.078947368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/movsim/traffic-simulation-de&quot;&gt;Sources at GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.movsim.org&quot;&gt;MovSim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.verkehrsdynamik.de&quot;&gt;Buch &quot;Verkehrsdynamik&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic-flow-dynamics.org/&quot;&gt;Book &quot;Traffic Flow Dynamics&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;infoFlags&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/icons/flagUSA.png&quot; width=&quot;45%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/index_ger.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://traffic-simulation.de/icons/flagGerman.png&quot; width=&quot;45%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 03:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>social_quotient</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://traffic-simulation.de/ring.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon ‘flooded by fake five-star reviews’ – report</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-47941181</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/business-47941181</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Amazon warehouse in Germany&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/13FF2/production/_102560918_amazongermany_getty.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Online retail giant Amazon's website is flooded with fake five-star reviews for products from unfamiliar brands, consumer group Which? has claimed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Household names were largely absent from top-rated reviews on popular items such as headphones, smart watches and fitness trackers, it concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thousands of reviews were unverified, meaning there was no evidence the reviewer bought the product, it said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon said it was using automated technology to weed out false reviews.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It said it invested &quot;significant resources&quot; to protect its review system &quot;because we know customers value the insights and experiences shared by fellow shoppers&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Even one inauthentic review is one too many,&quot; it added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Which?'s probe suggested fake reviews were commonplace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it searched for headphones, it found all the products on the first page of results were from unknown brands - which it defines as ones its experts have never heard of - rather than known brands, which it defines as household names.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of 12,000 reviews for these, the majority (87%) were from unverified purchases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One example, a set of headphones by an unknown brand called Celebrat, had 439 reviews, all of which were five-star, unverified and were posted on the same day, suggesting they had been automated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Celebrat could not be reached for comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;How to spot a fake review&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Do not rely on ratings - delve deeper and read the reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Check the dates - look at when the reviews were posted. If many of them were posted in a short time period, it's likely they have been computer generated and are fake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Filter reviews to remove unverified reviews. Only reviews marked as verified are those that Amazon can confirm were purchased on its website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt; If products have hundreds or thousands of largely positive reviews be wary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source: Which?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;ReviewMeta, a US-based website that analyses online reviews, said it was shocked at the scale of the unverified reviews, saying they were &quot;obvious and easy to prevent&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The popularity of online review sites mean they are increasingly relied on by both businesses and their customers, with the government's Competition and Markets Authority estimating such reviews potentially influence £23bn of UK customer spending every year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which? says its findings mean that customers should take reviews with &quot;a pinch of salt&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Look to independent and trustworthy sources when researching a purchase,&quot; says Which? head of home products Natalie Hitchins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you write fake reviews on Amazon? Or have you fallen foul of a fake review? Email &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk?subject=FakeReviews47941181&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-email&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;icon email&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;story-body__link-email-text&quot;&gt;haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please include a contact number if you are willing to speak to a BBC journalist. You can also contact us in the following ways: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;WhatsApp: &lt;strong&gt;+44 7555 173285&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Tweet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/BBC_HaveYourSay&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;@BBC_HaveYourSay&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Send pictures/video to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:yourpics@bbc.co.uk&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-email&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;icon email&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;story-body__link-email-text&quot;&gt;yourpics@bbc.co.uk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bbcnewsupload.streamuk.com/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Upload your pictures / video here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Text an SMS or MMS to &lt;strong&gt;61124 &lt;/strong&gt;or &lt;strong&gt;+44 7624 800 100&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Please read our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/terms/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;terms of use&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/privacy-policy/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 23:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>drugme</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon 'flooded by fake five-star reviews'</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Top-rated reviews on popular items are dominated by unknown brands, consumer group Which? finds.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-47941181</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13FF2/production/_102560918_amazongermany_getty.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-47941181</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ripgrep 11 Released</title>
<link>https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/releases/tag/11.0.0</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/releases/tag/11.0.0</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;ripgrep 11 is a new major version release of ripgrep that contains many bug&lt;br/&gt;fixes, some performance improvements and a few feature enhancements. Notably,&lt;br/&gt;ripgrep's user experience for binary file filtering has been improved. See the&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/blob/11.0.0/GUIDE.md#binary-data&quot;&gt;guide's new section on binary data&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you haven't heard of it before, ripgrep is a line-oriented search&lt;br/&gt;tool that recursively searches your current directory for a regex pattern. By&lt;br/&gt;default, ripgrep will respect your &lt;code&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; and automatically skip hidden&lt;br/&gt;files/directories and binary files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release also marks a change in ripgrep's versioning. Where as the previous&lt;br/&gt;version was &lt;code&gt;0.10.0&lt;/code&gt;, this version is &lt;code&gt;11.0.0&lt;/code&gt;. Moving forward, ripgrep's&lt;br/&gt;major version will be increased a few times per year. ripgrep will continue to&lt;br/&gt;be conservative with respect to backwards compatibility, but may occasionally&lt;br/&gt;introduce breaking changes, which will always be documented in this CHANGELOG.&lt;br/&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1172&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1172/hovercard&quot;&gt;issue 1172&lt;/a&gt; for a bit&lt;br/&gt;more detail on why this versioning change was made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release increases the &lt;strong&gt;minimum supported Rust version&lt;/strong&gt; from 1.28.0 to&lt;br/&gt;1.34.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BREAKING CHANGES&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ripgrep has tweaked its exit status codes to be more like GNU grep's. Namely,&lt;br/&gt;if a non-fatal error occurs during a search, then ripgrep will now always&lt;br/&gt;emit a &lt;code&gt;2&lt;/code&gt; exit status code, regardless of whether a match is found or not.&lt;br/&gt;Previously, ripgrep would only emit a &lt;code&gt;2&lt;/code&gt; exit status code for a catastrophic&lt;br/&gt;error (e.g., regex syntax error). One exception to this is if ripgrep is run&lt;br/&gt;with &lt;code&gt;-q/--quiet&lt;/code&gt;. In that case, if an error occurs and a match is found,&lt;br/&gt;then ripgrep will exit with a &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; exit status code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supplying the &lt;code&gt;-u/--unrestricted&lt;/code&gt; flag three times is now equivalent to&lt;br/&gt;supplying &lt;code&gt;--no-ignore --hidden --binary&lt;/code&gt;. Previously, &lt;code&gt;-uuu&lt;/code&gt; was equivalent&lt;br/&gt;to &lt;code&gt;--no-ignore --hidden --text&lt;/code&gt;. The difference is that &lt;code&gt;--binary&lt;/code&gt; disables&lt;br/&gt;binary file filtering without potentially dumping binary data into your&lt;br/&gt;terminal. That is, &lt;code&gt;rg -uuu foo&lt;/code&gt; should now be equivalent to &lt;code&gt;grep -r foo&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;avx-accel&lt;/code&gt; feature of ripgrep has been removed since it is no longer&lt;br/&gt;necessary. All uses of AVX in ripgrep are now enabled automatically via&lt;br/&gt;runtime CPU feature detection. The &lt;code&gt;simd-accel&lt;/code&gt; feature does remain available&lt;br/&gt;(only for enabling SIMD for transcoding), however, it does increase&lt;br/&gt;compilation times substantially at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Performance improvements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feature enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added or improved file type filtering for Apache Thrift, ASP, Bazel, Brotli,&lt;br/&gt;BuildStream, bzip2, C, C++, Cython, gzip, Java, Make, Postscript, QML, Tex,&lt;br/&gt;XML, xz, zig and zstd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/855&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/855/hovercard&quot;&gt;FEATURE #855&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;--binary&lt;/code&gt; flag for disabling binary file filtering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/pull/1078&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1078/hovercard&quot;&gt;FEATURE #1078&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;--max-columns-preview&lt;/code&gt; flag for showing a preview of long lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/pull/1099&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1099/hovercard&quot;&gt;FEATURE #1099&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Add support for Brotli and Zstd to the &lt;code&gt;-z/--search-zip&lt;/code&gt; flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/pull/1138&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1138/hovercard&quot;&gt;FEATURE #1138&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;--no-ignore-dot&lt;/code&gt; flag for ignoring &lt;code&gt;.ignore&lt;/code&gt; files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/pull/1155&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1155/hovercard&quot;&gt;FEATURE #1155&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;--auto-hybrid-regex&lt;/code&gt; flag for automatically falling back to PCRE2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/pull/1159&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1159/hovercard&quot;&gt;FEATURE #1159&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;ripgrep's exit status logic should now match GNU grep. See updated man page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/pull/1164&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1164/hovercard&quot;&gt;FEATURE #1164&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;--ignore-file-case-insensitive&lt;/code&gt; for case insensitive ignore globs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/pull/1185&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1185/hovercard&quot;&gt;FEATURE #1185&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;-I&lt;/code&gt; flag as a short option for the &lt;code&gt;--no-filename&lt;/code&gt; flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/pull/1207&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1207/hovercard&quot;&gt;FEATURE #1207&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;none&lt;/code&gt; value to &lt;code&gt;-E/--encoding&lt;/code&gt; to forcefully disable all transcoding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/commit/da9d7204&quot;&gt;FEATURE da9d7204&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;--pcre2-version&lt;/code&gt; for querying showing PCRE2 version information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/306&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/306/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #306&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/855&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/855/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #855&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Improve the user experience for ripgrep's binary file filtering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/373&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/373/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #373&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1098&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1098/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1098&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;**&lt;/code&gt; is now accepted as valid syntax anywhere in a glob.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/916&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/916/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #916&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;ripgrep no longer hangs when searching &lt;code&gt;/proc&lt;/code&gt; with a zombie process present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1052&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1052/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1052&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix bug where ripgrep could panic when transcoding UTF-16 files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1055&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1055/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1055&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Suggest &lt;code&gt;-U/--multiline&lt;/code&gt; when a pattern contains a &lt;code&gt;\n&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1063&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1063/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1063&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Always strip a BOM if it's present, even for UTF-8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1064&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1064/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1064&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix inner literal detection that could lead to incorrect matches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1079&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1079/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1079&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fixes a bug where the order of globs could result in missing a match.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1089&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1089/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1089&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix another bug where ripgrep could panic when transcoding UTF-16 files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1091&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1091/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1091&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Add note about inverted flags to the man page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/pull/1093&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;pull_request&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/pull/1093/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1093&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix handling of literal slashes in gitignore patterns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1095&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1095/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1095&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix corner cases involving the &lt;code&gt;--crlf&lt;/code&gt; flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1101&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1101/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1101&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix AsciiDoc escaping for man page output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1103&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1103/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1103&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Clarify what &lt;code&gt;--encoding auto&lt;/code&gt; does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1106&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1106/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1106&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;--files-with-matches&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--files-without-match&lt;/code&gt; work with one file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1121&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1121/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1121&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix bug that was triggering Windows antimalware when using the &lt;code&gt;--files&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1125&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1125/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1125&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1159&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1159/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1159&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;ripgrep shouldn't panic for &lt;code&gt;rg -h | rg&lt;/code&gt; and should emit correct exit status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1144&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1144/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1144&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fixes a bug where line numbers could be wrong on big-endian machines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1154&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1154/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1154&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Windows files with &quot;hidden&quot; attribute are now treated as hidden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1173&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1173/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1173&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix handling of &lt;code&gt;**&lt;/code&gt; patterns in gitignore files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1174&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1174/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1174&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix handling of repeated &lt;code&gt;**&lt;/code&gt; patterns in gitignore files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1176&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1176/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1176&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix bug where &lt;code&gt;-F&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;-x&lt;/code&gt; weren't applied to patterns given via &lt;code&gt;-f&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1189&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1189/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1189&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Document cases where ripgrep may use a lot of memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1203&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/BurntSushi/ripgrep/issues/1203/hovercard&quot;&gt;BUG #1203&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Fix a matching bug related to the suffix literal optimization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/commit/8f14cb18&quot;&gt;BUG 8f14cb18&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;Increase the default stack size for PCRE2's JIT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 23:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>burntsushi</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/456674?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>BurntSushi/ripgrep</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep</og:url>
<og:description>ripgrep recursively searches directories for a regex pattern - BurntSushi/ripgrep</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/releases/tag/11.0.0</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mass Production of iPhones to Start in India</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-15/foxconn-is-poised-to-begin-mass-production-of-iphones-in-india</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-15/foxconn-is-poised-to-begin-mass-production-of-iphones-in-india</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-15/foxconn-is-poised-to-begin-mass-production-of-iphones-in-india&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-15/foxconn-is-poised-to-begin-mass-production-of-iphones-in-india&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19669716&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19669716&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 225&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 95&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 23:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sarthakjain</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=ebc4a210-6060-11e9-bdb1-6f1726c11aea&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wNC0xNS9mb3hjb25uLWlzLXBvaXNlZC10by1iZWdpbi1tYXNzLXByb2R1Y3Rpb24tb2YtaXBob25lcy1pbi1pbmRpYQ==</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>LeBron James school that was considered an experiment is showing promise</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/12/education/lebron-james-school-ohio.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/12/education/lebron-james-school-ohio.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;AKRON, Ohio — The students paraded through hugs and high-fives from staff, who danced as Sister Sledge’s “We Are Family” blared through the hallways. They were showered with compliments as they walked through a buffet of breakfast foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The scene might be expected on a special occasion at any other public school. At LeBron James’s I Promise School, it was just Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Every day, they are celebrated for walking through the door. This time last year, the students at the school — Mr. James’s biggest foray into educational philanthropy — were identified as the worst performers in the Akron public schools and branded with behavioral problems. Some as young as 8 were considered at risk of not graduating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Now, they are helping close the achievement gap in Akron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/12/us/politics/12dc-lebron15/merlin_153292611_f1acadcf-1632-43e8-9d4b-38814380a24c-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/12/us/politics/12dc-lebron15/merlin_153292611_f1acadcf-1632-43e8-9d4b-38814380a24c-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/12/us/politics/12dc-lebron15/merlin_153292611_f1acadcf-1632-43e8-9d4b-38814380a24c-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/12/us/politics/12dc-lebron15/merlin_153292611_f1acadcf-1632-43e8-9d4b-38814380a24c-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 80vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/12/us/politics/12dc-lebron15/merlin_153292611_f1acadcf-1632-43e8-9d4b-38814380a24c-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Students at I Promise lining up for a free breakfast.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The academic results are early, and at 240, the sample size of students is small, but the inaugural classes of third and fourth graders at I Promise posted extraordinary results in their first set of district assessments. Ninety percent met or exceeded individual growth goals in reading and math, outpacing their peers across the district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“These kids are doing an unbelievable job, better than we all expected,” Mr. James said in a telephone interview hours before a game in Los Angeles for the Lakers. “When we first started, people knew I was opening a school for kids. Now people are going to really understand the lack of education they had before they came to our school. People are going to finally understand what goes on behind our doors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Unlike other &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.voanews.com/a/lebron-james-celebrities-launch-schools/4508036.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;schools connected to celebrities&lt;/a&gt;, I Promise is not a charter school run by a private operator but a public school operated by the district. Its population is 60 percent black, 15 percent English-language learners and 29 percent special education students. Three-quarters of its families meet the low-income threshold to receive help from the Ohio Department of Job and Family Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The school’s $2 million budget is funded by the district, roughly the same amount per pupil that it spends in other schools. But Mr. James’s foundation has provided about $600,000 in financial support for additional teaching staff to help reduce class sizes, and an additional hour of after-school programming and tutors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The school is unusual in the resources and attention it devotes to parents, which educators consider a key to its success. Mr. James’s foundation covers the cost of all expenses in the school’s family resource center, which provides parents with G.E.D. preparation, work advice, health and legal services, and even a quarterly barbershop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The school opened with some skepticism — not only for its high-profile founder, considered by some to be the best basketball player ever, but also for an academic model aimed at students who by many accounts were considered irredeemable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We are reigniting dreams that were extinguished — already in third and fourth grade,” said Brandi Davis, the school’s principal. “We want to change the face of urban education.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Angela Whorton, an intervention specialist, hugging Ibn al-Qaadir. The school aims to help children in academics as well as social life.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The students’ scores reflect their performance on the Measures of Academic Progress assessment, a nationally recognized test administered by NWEA, an evaluation association. In reading, where both classes had scored in the lowest, or first, percentile, third graders moved to the ninth percentile, and fourth graders to the 16th. In math, third graders jumped from the lowest percentile to the 18th, while fourth graders moved from the second percentile to the 30th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The 90 percent of I Promise students who met their goals exceeded the 70 percent of students districtwide, and scored in the 99th growth percentile of the evaluation association’s school norms, which the district said showed that students’ test scores increased at a higher rate than 99 out of 100 schools nationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The students have a long way to go to even join the middle of the pack. And time will tell whether the gains are sustainable and how they stack up against rigorous state standardized tests at the end of the year. To some extent, the excitement surrounding the students’ progress illustrates a somber reality in urban education, where big hopes hinge on small victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It’s encouraging to see growth, but by no means are we out of the woods,” said Keith Liechty, a coordinator in the Akron public school system’s Office of School Improvement. The school district, where achievement and graduation rates have received &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://reportcard.education.ohio.gov/district/overview/043489&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;failing marks on state report cards&lt;/a&gt;, has been trying to turn around its worst-performing schools for years. “The goal is for these students to be at grade level, and we’re not there yet. This just tells us we’re going in the right direction,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Mr. Liechty, who has been with the district for 20 years, said that the students’ leaps would not be expected in an entire school year, let alone half of one. “For the average student,” he said, “your percentile doesn’t move that much unless something extraordinary is happening.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-nvxo42 e73j0it0&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Although LeBron James has been to I Promise only twice since this school year started, his presence is ubiquitous.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Lining the walls of the school’s vast lobby are 114 shoes, including those worn during the 2016 season when Mr. James led the Cleveland Cavaliers to the N.B.A. championship.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;On a tour of the school on Monday, Michele Campbell, the executive director of the LeBron James Family Foundation, pointed out what she called I Promise’s “secret sauce.” In one room, staff members were busy organizing a room filled with bins of clothing and shelves of peanut butter, jelly and Cheerios. At any time, parents can grab a shopping bin and take what they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Down the hallway, parents honed their math skills for their coming G.E.D. exams as their students learned upstairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Dr. Campbell arrived to a classroom where a student and teacher were facing off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“You’re being too aggressive!” the student snapped at Angel Whorton, an intervention specialist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;There was a pause, and the two burst into giggles, breaking character in a role-playing assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Good; that’s how I need you to use your words,” Ms. Whorton said to the boy, who is awaiting a disciplinary hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Dr. Campbell smiled, “There’s magic happening in that room.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Wallace Watson resting on Ms. Whorton during a meditation exercise.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;I Promise students were among those identified by the district as performing in the 10th to 25th percentile on their second-grade assessments. They were then admitted through a lottery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“These were the children where you went and talked with their old teachers, and they said, ‘This will never work,’” Dr. Campbell said. “We said give them to us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;They are called the “Chosen Ones,” &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.si.com/nba/2018/05/30/origin-lebron-james-chosen-1-tattoo&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an ode to the headline that donned Mr. James’s first Sports Illustrated cover&lt;/a&gt; when he was a junior in high school, and which he later had tattooed across his shoulder blades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-nvxo42 e73j0it0&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;I Promise students were among those identified by the district as performing in the 10th to 25th percentile on their second-grade assessments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;According to standardized tests, students at I Promise have vastly improved from their scores the previous year in Akron public schools.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Students here are aware that they are part of something special. “We get to have fun, and have opportunities that other kids don’t have,” said Kamari Dennis, a fourth grader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The school is an extension of Mr. James’s work in his hometown, Akron, where his family’s foundation has been active for seven years. The I Promise program supports about 1,100 other students in third through 10th grade across the Akron public school district, with mentoring, college and career preparation and other resources estimated at $2.6 million for this school year. All of the students in the program and the school who meet certain academic criteria will receive a full college scholarship to the University of Akron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But the I Promise School was a recognition that the foundation’s community services were not enough. They needed to reach students earlier. They secured an old district office building that served as a holding place for schools in transition, poured in $2 million and counting for improvements and reopened it in seven weeks. The school opened in July 2018 and is expected to serve 720 students in third through eighth grade by 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The foundation’s support affords I Promise more resources than the average school, but Ms. Davis, a veteran principal in the district, said the school values things that no money could buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It doesn’t take money to build relationships,” she said. “It doesn’t take money for you to teach students how to love.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;A food pantry inside the school. At any time, parents can grab a shopping bin and take what they need.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The school negotiated with the Akron Education Association for an extra hour a day and an extended year to put into place programs intended to address students’ social and emotional needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Pat Shipe, the president of the association, said the union was proud of the collaboration and “cautiously optimistic” about its outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“While this school is in its infancy, we look forward to an extended review of the many indicators, which will confirm any growth, understanding that one or two tests do not tell the whole story,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;On a recent morning, students spent the first hour getting ready for the day in a gathering that is called an “I Promise Circle.” By the end of the circle, a girl who was upset about a run-in with her bus driver and another girl who had dozed off were squealing happily at the end of the game Down by the Banks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-nvxo42 e73j0it0&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;I Promise’s $2 million budget is funded by the district, roughly the same amount per pupil that it spends in other schools.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;The school negotiated for an extra hour a day and an extended year to carry out programs meant to address students’ social and emotional needs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Everything is strategic to transform the way our day goes,” said Nicole Hassan, a liaison from Akron Public Schools who oversees I Promise’s trauma-informed curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The school’s culture is built on “Habits of Promise” — perseverance, perpetual learning, problem solving, partnering and perspective — that every student commits to memory. The slogan “We Are Family” is emblazoned on walls and T-shirts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Nickole Wyatt, whose son Ti’Jay Wyatt is in fourth grade, said she had felt unsupported ever since she became a teenage mother. “It took me coming here to realize what family even is,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Wyatt, who is taking classes at the school to get her high school equivalency diploma, said I Promise saved not only her son’s education but her own life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I was skeptical even of my own life, wondering, ‘Am I even worth fighting for?’” she said. “When I come here every day, I know it’s going to be O.K.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Vikki McGee, who runs the school’s family resource center, said the center’s existence conveyed that the school was about something much bigger than a basketball star: “This is about fighting for generations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. James has visited twice since the school year started, but he is everywhere — on murals, on wallpaper, on video messages. He comes up often when students reflect on their educational experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;The school’s culture is built on “Habits of Promise” — perseverance, perpetual learning, problem solving, partnering and perspective — that every student commits to memory.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“One time, LeBron wrote us a letter, and I knew it was real because I saw the paper was signed in pen,” said Vikyah Powe, a fourth grader. “That encouraged me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;While Mr. James called the school “the coolest thing that I’ve done in my life thus far,” he said he could take credit for only a small part of what was happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I had the vision of wanting to give back to my community. The people around every day are helping that vision come to life,” he said. “Half the battle is trying to engage them and show that there’s always going to be somebody looking out for them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Lining the walls of the school’s vast lobby are 114 shoes, including those worn during the 2016 season when Mr. James led the Cleveland Cavaliers to the N.B.A. championship, a reminder that he once walked a path similar to these students. Mr. James was also considered at risk; in fourth grade, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KingJames/status/1023601169698938880&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;he missed 83 days of school&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Nataylia Henry, a fourth grader, missed more than 50 days of school last year because she said she would rather sleep than face bullies at school. This year, her overall attendance rate is 80 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“LeBron made this school,” she said. “It’s an important school. It means that you can always depend on someone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Nataylia Henry, a fourth grader at I Promise, missed more than 50 days of school last year.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maddie McGarvey for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 20:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>throwaway5752</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/12/education/lebron-james-school-ohio.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>LeBron James Opened a School That Was Considered an Experiment. It’s Showing Promise.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/12/us/politics/12dc-lebron14/merlin_153293445_79c2c470-02e3-44bc-b932-0caea5aa4470-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The inaugural class of third and fourth graders at the school has posted extraordinary results on its first set of test scores.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/12/education/lebron-james-school-ohio.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>