<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The account of realDonaldTrump will be locked for 12 hours</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1346970431039934464</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1346970431039934464</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1346970431039934464&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1346970431039934464&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25664822&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25664822&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 251&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 215&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edward</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1346970431039934464</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>London will be overwhelmed by Covid in a fortnight says leaked NHS briefing</title>
<link>https://www.hsj.co.uk/acute-care/exclusive-london-will-be-overwhelmed-by-covid-in-a-fortnight-says-leaked-nhs-england-briefing/7029264.article</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.hsj.co.uk/acute-care/exclusive-london-will-be-overwhelmed-by-covid-in-a-fortnight-says-leaked-nhs-england-briefing/7029264.article</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;NHS England London medical director Vin Diwakar set out the stark analysis to the medical directors of London’s hospital trusts on a Zoom call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NHS England presentation, seen by &lt;em&gt;HSJ&lt;/em&gt; (see slides below story), showed that even if the number of covid patients grew at the lowest rate considered likely, and measures to manage demand and increase capacity, including open the capital’s Nightingale hospital, were successful, the NHS in London would be short of nearly 2,000 general and acute and intensive care beds by 19 January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The briefing forecasts demand for both G&amp;amp;A and intensive care beds, for both covid and non-covid patients, against capacity. It accounts for the impact of planned measures to mitigate demand and increase capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both G&amp;amp;A and intensive care, three scenarios are detailed: “Best”, which projects 4 per cent daily growth; “average” which plots 5 per cent daily growth; and “worse” which forecasts 6 per cent daily growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The briefing says that growth on 5 January was 3.5 per cent for G&amp;amp;A beds 4.8 per cent for ICU beds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General and acute&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the “best” case scenario, the number of covid patients in G&amp;amp;A beds is projected to rise to 9,500 by 19 January, while the number of non-covid patients stays the same at 7,460 (as it does under all the scenarios).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some very small demand control measures, total demand is projected as 17,100. The briefing then sets out ways the capacity might be increased. These measures include the NHS finding another 400 beds, and the independent sector 50. These would be complemented by 1,000 “step down beds”, some of the supplied by the opening of the capital’s Nightingale hospital, and 150 freed up by specialist trusts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives total capacity of 15,600 – 1,500 short of forecast demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shortfall in beds – described as a “mitigated deficit” – in the “average” scenario is 2,900 and 4,400 in the “worse” one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The briefing shows that as of 5 January the London NHS had an “unmitigated surplus” of 720 general and acute beds, 5 per cent of its total. Just over 40 per cent of its G&amp;amp;A beds were occupied by covid positive patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intensive care&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intensive care, or “adult critical care”, model follows the same pattern as that for G&amp;amp;A beds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the “best” scenario, the number of covid positive patients rises to 1,600 and “total unmitigated demand” to just over 2,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitigated capacity is projected to be 1,660, giving a “deficit” of just over 400 intensive care beds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The briefing shows that as of 5 January the London NHS had an “unmitigated surplus” of just 46 ICU beds, three per cent of its total. Just over 70 per cent of its ICU beds were occupied by covid positive patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Options to avoid being overwhelmed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement given to &lt;em&gt;HSJ&lt;/em&gt; this evening, Dr Diwakar said: “Hospitals in London are coming under significant pressure from high covid-19 infection rates which is why they have opened hundreds of surge critical care beds and are planning to open more, including opening the London Nightingale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While staff are going the extra mile to care for patients it is crucial that people do everything they can to reduce transmission of the virus.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HSJ&lt;/em&gt; understands that the briefing was part of an attempt to get senior clinical leaders to focus on what they would have to do, if current growth trends were not surpressed by the tighter lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Options that have been floated include very signficantly reducing the number of non-covid patients by cancelling more elective work and/or sending those patients to other regions or private providers, in the capital or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursuing such options may be limited, however, with other regions also seeing rapid growth in covid occupancy caused by the new strain of the virus spreading acoss the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HSJ&lt;/em&gt; understands the medical directors discussed opening up further capacity within the capital over and above that contained in the briefing, but that lack of available staff meant this was unlikely to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first wave, London peaked with about 1,160 covid patients in critical care. It is now just short of this figure, on 1,075. In the spring, total available critical care capacity was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hsj.co.uk/service-design/exclusive-nightingale-largely-empty-as-icus-handle-surge/7027398.article&quot;&gt;put at around 1,550.&lt;/a&gt; At one point &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hsj.co.uk/news/exclusive-frantic-action-to-stop-london-running-out-of-beds-in-four-days/7027222.article&quot;&gt;it was claimed&lt;/a&gt; this could be “super surged” much further – to at least double this – but it is unclear if that was truly possible. It would require radical dilution of staffing and standards of care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline_image image_size_full fullsize zoom&quot; data-attachment=&quot;3049186&quot; data-sequence=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;show-fullscreen&quot; data-url=&quot;/attachment?attype=P&amp;amp;atcode=3049186&amp;amp;storycode=7029264&quot;&gt;#*#*Show Fullscreen*#*#&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;picture&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;icu slide&quot; src=&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAMAAAACCAQAAAA3fa6RAAAADklEQVR42mNkAANGCAUAACMAA2w/AMgAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&quot; data-src=&quot;https://d3e6tmgg461bic.cloudfront.net/Pictures/480xany/1/8/6/3049186_icuslide_552103.jpg&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1023px) 100vw, 780px&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://d3e6tmgg461bic.cloudfront.net/Pictures/480xany/1/8/6/3049186_icuslide_552103.jpg 480w,https://d3e6tmgg461bic.cloudfront.net/Pictures/600xany/1/8/6/3049186_icuslide_552103.jpg 600w,https://d3e6tmgg461bic.cloudfront.net/Pictures/780xany/1/8/6/3049186_icuslide_552103.jpg 780w&quot; class=&quot; lazyload&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;606&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline_image image_size_full fullsize zoom&quot; data-attachment=&quot;3049187&quot; data-sequence=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;show-fullscreen&quot; data-url=&quot;/attachment?attype=P&amp;amp;atcode=3049187&amp;amp;storycode=7029264&quot;&gt;#*#*Show Fullscreen*#*#&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;picture&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;ga slide&quot; src=&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAMAAAACCAQAAAA3fa6RAAAADklEQVR42mNkAANGCAUAACMAA2w/AMgAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&quot; data-src=&quot;https://d3e6tmgg461bic.cloudfront.net/Pictures/480xany/1/8/7/3049187_gaslide_175904.jpg&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1023px) 100vw, 780px&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://d3e6tmgg461bic.cloudfront.net/Pictures/480xany/1/8/7/3049187_gaslide_175904.jpg 480w,https://d3e6tmgg461bic.cloudfront.net/Pictures/600xany/1/8/7/3049187_gaslide_175904.jpg 600w,https://d3e6tmgg461bic.cloudfront.net/Pictures/780xany/1/8/7/3049187_gaslide_175904.jpg 780w&quot; class=&quot; lazyload&quot; width=&quot;929&quot; height=&quot;594&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>biomene</dc:creator>
<og:title>Exclusive: London will be overwhelmed by covid in a fortnight says leaked NHS England briefing</og:title>
<og:type>Article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.hsj.co.uk/acute-care/exclusive-london-will-be-overwhelmed-by-covid-in-a-fortnight-says-leaked-nhs-england-briefing/7029264.article</og:url>
<og:description>London's hospitals are less than two weeks from being overwhelmed by covid even under the &quot;best&quot; case scenario, according to an official briefing given to the capital's most senior doctors this afternoon.</og:description>
<og:image>https://d3e6tmgg461bic.cloudfront.net/Pictures/1024x536/1/8/7/3049187_gaslide_175904.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.hsj.co.uk/acute-care/exclusive-london-will-be-overwhelmed-by-covid-in-a-fortnight-says-leaked-nhs-england-briefing/7029264.article</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WhatsApp gives users an ultimatum: Share data with Facebook or stop using app</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/01/whatsapp-users-must-share-their-data-with-facebook-or-stop-using-the-app/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/01/whatsapp-users-must-share-their-data-with-facebook-or-stop-using-the-app/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/whatsapp-800x534.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In this photo illustration a Whatsapp logo seen displayed on&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; class=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;93 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/01/whatsapp-users-must-share-their-data-with-facebook-or-stop-using-the-app/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;93 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/01/whatsapp-users-must-share-their-data-with-facebook-or-stop-using-the-app/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;118&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 93 posters participating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp, the Facebook-owned messenger that claims to have privacy coded into its DNA, is giving its 2 billion plus users an ultimatum: agree to share their personal data with the social network or delete their accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The requirement is being delivered through an in-app alert directing users to agree to sweeping changes in the WhatsApp terms of service. Those who don’t accept the revamped privacy policy by February 8 will no longer be able to use the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Image-from-iOS.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot; data-height=&quot;2436&quot; data-width=&quot;1125&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Image-from-iOS-640x1386.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1386&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Image-from-iOS.png 2x&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Share and share alike&lt;/h2&gt;

Shortly after Facebook acquired WhatsApp for $19 billion in 2014, its developers &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2014/11/whatsapp-brings-strong-end-to-end-crypto-to-the-masses/&quot;&gt;built state-of-the-art end-to-end encryption&lt;/a&gt; into the messaging app. The move was seen as a victory for privacy advocates because it used the Signal Protocol, an open source encryption scheme whose source code has been reviewed and audited by scores of independent security experts.
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, WhatsApp gave users a one-time ability to opt out of having account data turned over to Facebook. Now, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whatsapp.com/legal/privacy-policy&quot;&gt;updated privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; is changing that. Come next month, users will no longer have that choice. Some of the data that WhatsApp collects includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;User phone numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other people’s phone numbers stored in address books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profile names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profile pictures and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Status message including when a user was last online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diagnostic data collected from app logs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the new terms, Facebook reserves the right to share collected data with its &lt;a href=&quot;https://faq.whatsapp.com/general/security-and-privacy/the-facebook-companies&quot;&gt;family of companies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad_wrapper&quot; aria-label=&quot;In Content advertisement&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad_notice&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;“As part of the Facebook family of companies, WhatsApp receives information from, and shares information with, this family of companies,” the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whatsapp.com/legal/privacy-policy&quot;&gt;new privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; states. “We may use the information we receive from them, and they may use the information we share with them, to help operate, provide, improve, understand, customize, support, and market our Services and their offerings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, such as when someone uses WhatsApp to interact with third-party businesses, Facebook may also share information with those outside entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A lack of transparency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move comes a month after Apple started requiring iOS app makers, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://faq.whatsapp.com/general/unpacking-whatsapps-privacy-label-in-the-apple-app-store&quot;&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt;, to detail the information they collect from users. WhatsApp, &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/whatsapp-messenger/id310633997&quot;&gt;according to the App Store&lt;/a&gt;, reserves the right to collect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Purchases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifiers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usage data and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diagnostics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A WhatsApp spokeswoman declined to speak on the record about the changes and precisely how or if it’s possible for users to opt out of them. She agreed to email additional information on the condition it be kept on background, meaning none of the details can be quoted verbatim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move, the spokeswoman said, is part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.whatsapp.com/shopping-payments-and-customer-service-on-whatsapp&quot;&gt;previously disclosed move&lt;/a&gt; to allow businesses to store and manage WhatsApp chats using Facebook's infrastructure. Users won't have to use WhatsApp to interact with the businesses and have the option of blocking the businesses. She said there will be no change in how WhatsApp shares provides data with Facebook for non-business chats and account data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, the WhatsApp privacy policy and terms of service are more than 8,000 words long and are filled with legal jargon that makes it difficult for non-lawyers to understand. WhatsApp is doing its users a disservice by not agreeing to speak on the record so that reporters can fully understand the changes and explain them to readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who object to the new terms and policy should consider using a different messenger. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal messenger&lt;/a&gt; provides the same robust encryption engine with a much more transparent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.signal.org/legal/&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.signal.org/legal/&quot;&gt;terms of service&lt;/a&gt;. (Those documents are half the length of those from WhatsApp, too.) Besides providing encrypted chats, Signal also offers encrypted audio and video calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post updated to add details in the third-to-last paragraph.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 20:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>erwinmatijsen</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/01/whatsapp-users-must-share-their-data-with-facebook-or-stop-using-the-app/</og:url>
<og:title>WhatsApp gives users an ultimatum: Share data with Facebook or stop using the app</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/whatsapp-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The Facebook-owned messenger with 2 billion users revamps its privacy policy.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/01/whatsapp-users-must-share-their-data-with-facebook-or-stop-using-the-app/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>U.S. Capitol Locked Down Amid Escalating Protests</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/954028436/u-s-capitol-locked-down-amid-escalating-far-right-protests</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/954028436/u-s-capitol-locked-down-amid-escalating-far-right-protests</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res954113431&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/gettyimages-1230455089_custom-44987009c8a8ba07ac0ea912c9fd8bf07a13542d-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/gettyimages-1230455089_custom-44987009c8a8ba07ac0ea912c9fd8bf07a13542d-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrators breached security and entered the Capitol on Wednesday as Congress debated the 2020 electoral vote tally. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Roberto Schmidt/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Roberto Schmidt/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/gettyimages-1230455089_custom-44987009c8a8ba07ac0ea912c9fd8bf07a13542d-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Demonstrators breached security and entered the Capitol on Wednesday as Congress debated the 2020 electoral vote tally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Roberto Schmidt/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated at 7:19 p.m. ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Capitol was the scene of chaos on Wednesday as supporters of President Trump responded to his call to head to the complex and then breached it, leading to unprecedented violence in the seat of America's federal government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A woman was shot and killed during the assault on the Capitol, according to Washington, D.C., police. Her identity was not made public&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A law enforcement official familiar with the investigation told NPR's Carrie Johnson that the alleged shooter of the woman was a senior U.S. Capitol Police officer and that the woman who was killed was unarmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The insurrectionists &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/953443833/congress-electoral-college-tally-promises-more-acrimony-than-ceremony&quot;&gt;interrupted&lt;/a&gt; proceedings in the House and Senate as members of Congress were tallying President-elect Joe Biden's Electoral College victory. The counting of the votes is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2021/01/05/952883116/objecting-to-electoral-votes-in-congress-recalls-bitter-moments-in-history&quot;&gt;normally&lt;/a&gt; a relatively pro forma session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for two months, Trump has falsely and continuously claimed the election was stolen from him, and dozens of fellow Republicans had planned to object to slates of electors from various states they considered contested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res954067003&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap21006717947235-edit_custom-c4abe38dac30495873149de5f92fe131b0b80ad5-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap21006717947235-edit_custom-c4abe38dac30495873149de5f92fe131b0b80ad5-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police with guns drawn face off with protesters trying to break into the House chamber Wednesday at the Capitol. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;J. Scott Applewhite/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;J. Scott Applewhite/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap21006717947235-edit_custom-c4abe38dac30495873149de5f92fe131b0b80ad5-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Police with guns drawn face off with protesters trying to break into the House chamber Wednesday at the Capitol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;J. Scott Applewhite/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers were debating an objection to Arizona's results — a state Trump lost narrowly — when the sessions were recessed as the Capitol Police attempted to put the complex on lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Violent protesters were seen smashing windows and occupying the House and Senate floors and various offices. Police were seen with guns drawn in the House chamber, pointing their firearms at windows that were smashed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People inside the building were told to shelter in place, and congressional leaders were taken off-site. Members of Congress were told that tear gas was being used in the Capitol Rotunda and that they &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PeterWelch/status/1346904269375594505?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1346904269375594505%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.npr.org%2Fsections%2Fcongress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates%2F2021%2F01%2F06%2F954028436%2Fu-s-capitol-locked-down-amid-escalating-far-right-protests&quot;&gt;should get ready to put on masks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trump urges peace but doubles down on election falsehoods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Twitter, Trump asked people to remain peaceful. He then &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1346928882595885058?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1346928882595885058%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Flegacy.npr.org%2Ftemplates%2Fpreview%2FtwitterPreview.php%3FtweetId%3D1346928882595885058hideMedia%3Dtrue&quot;&gt;posted a video&lt;/a&gt; on social media, asking people to go home — but not before reiterating his baseless claims about the election being stolen and saying: &quot;You're very special.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter and Facebook &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/954111914/twitter-restricts-the-reach-of-trumps-video-message-citing-a-risk-of-violence&quot;&gt;acted to remove&lt;/a&gt; the video, and Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1346970431039934464&quot;&gt;said it locked&lt;/a&gt; Trump's account for 12 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His response to the violence came just a few hours after a midday address to supporters outside the White House in which he repeatedly denied the results of the election, claiming without evidence it was rigged against his campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This election was stolen from you, from me, from the country,&quot; he said in the earlier remarks. He also urged his supporters to head to the Capitol, adding: &quot;You'll never take back our country with weakness.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res954048091&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap21006702439804-edit_custom-dfbc66a6b31db68d1e724e9a57194eb401e49a17-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap21006702439804-edit_custom-dfbc66a6b31db68d1e724e9a57194eb401e49a17-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protesters gesture to U.S. Capitol Police in the hallway outside of the Senate chamber on Wednesday. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Manuel Balce Ceneta/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Manuel Balce Ceneta/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap21006702439804-edit_custom-dfbc66a6b31db68d1e724e9a57194eb401e49a17-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Protesters gesture to U.S. Capitol Police in the hallway outside of the Senate chamber on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Manuel Balce Ceneta/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vice President Pence &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Mike_Pence/status/1346918219991420928&quot;&gt;more forcefully condemned the chaos&lt;/a&gt;, saying that the violence was an &quot;attack on our Capitol&quot; and tweeting that people involved must &quot;immediately leave the building&quot; and would be &quot;prosecuted to the fullest extent of the law.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-secondary-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Federal and local authorities &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/954109355/authorities-send-reinforcements-to-help-secure-the-capitol&quot;&gt;scrambled&lt;/a&gt; to send forces to help secure the Capitol after it was overrun by the pro-Trump extremists. Reinforcements were also being deployed from Virginia, Maryland and New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a tweet, White House press secretary Kayleigh McEnany wrote that the National Guard had been called in at Trump's direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res954160983&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage954109355&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/954109355/authorities-send-reinforcements-to-help-secure-the-capitol&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates\/2021\/01\/06\/954109355\/authorities-send-reinforcements-to-help-secure-the-capitol&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap_21006785894247_sq-95000673350ae7d81d44ce295995051ee2115537-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap_21006785894247_sq-95000673350ae7d81d44ce295995051ee2115537-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Authorities Send Reinforcements To Help Secure The Capitol&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We reiterate President Trump's call against violence and to remain peaceful,&quot; she wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Law enforcement eventually gained control of the scene, ushering people out of the Capitol. The House sergeant at arms informed lawmakers and staff after 5 p.m. that the Capitol had been cleared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington, D.C., &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/954052803/d-c-mayor-issues-6-pm-curfew-as-trump-supporters-breach-capitol&quot;&gt;instituted a 12-hour curfew&lt;/a&gt; that went into effect at 6 p.m. ET Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;It's insurrection&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In midafternoon televised remarks, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/954063529/watch-live-joe-biden-speaks-as-protesters-force-u-s-capitol-into-lockdown&quot;&gt;Biden called on Trump&lt;/a&gt; to &quot;go on national television now to fulfill his oath and defend the Constitution and demand an end to this siege&quot; at the Capitol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Let me be very clear,&quot; Biden added, &quot;the scenes of chaos at the Capitol do not reflect a true America, do not reflect who we are,&quot; he said, calling the violent protesters a &quot;small number of extremists dedicated to lawlessness.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res954102942&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage954063529&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/954063529/watch-live-joe-biden-speaks-as-protesters-force-u-s-capitol-into-lockdown&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates\/2021\/01\/06\/954063529\/watch-live-joe-biden-speaks-as-protesters-force-u-s-capitol-into-lockdown&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/gettyimages-1230455130_sq-6de532dbe296135301d604ba8c1b28749581bdf9-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/gettyimages-1230455130_sq-6de532dbe296135301d604ba8c1b28749581bdf9-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Biden: Democracy 'Under Unprecedented Assault' As Pro-Trump Extremists Occupy Capitol&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It borders on sedition and it must end now,&quot; Biden said. &quot;It's not protest; it's insurrection.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;The President bears responsibility&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The events came as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/953616207/diehard-trump-supporters-gather-in-the-nations-capital-to-protest-election-resul&quot;&gt;thousands of pro-Trump and far-right protesters&lt;/a&gt; congregated in downtown Washington to contest the results of the presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Republicans, who spent the summer castigating the mostly peaceful protests against racial police violence, had previously encouraged demonstrations calling to overturn the election results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Republicans and Democrats blasted those who breached the Capitol, with many — including some in Trump's own party — also blaming the president for inciting the mob through his repeated claims of a stolen election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;President Trump incited his followers to violence,&quot; Sen. Dick Durbin, D-Ill., said. &quot;They stormed the Capitol and stopped the House and Senate in session.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res954036293&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap_21006685943540_custom-1b213882c422b09aab1d90c58c62f9288289e18e-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap_21006685943540_custom-1b213882c422b09aab1d90c58c62f9288289e18e-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump supporters try to break through a police barrier during protests Wednesday at the Capitol. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Julio Cortez/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Julio Cortez/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/ap_21006685943540_custom-1b213882c422b09aab1d90c58c62f9288289e18e-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Trump supporters try to break through a police barrier during protests Wednesday at the Capitol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Julio Cortez/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The President bears responsibility for today's events by promoting the unfounded conspiracy theories that have led to this point,&quot; Sen. Richard Burr, R-N.C., said in a statement. &quot;It is past time to accept the will of American voters and to allow our nation to move forward.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Republican Sen. Mitt Romney of Utah, a frequent critic of Trump, described the breach of the U.S. Capitol as &quot;an insurrection, incited by the president of the United States.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Ben Sasse, a Republican from Nebraska, in a statement described the Capitol as being &quot;ransacked while the leader of the free world cowered behind his keyboard.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He continued: &quot;Lies have consequences. This violence was the inevitable and ugly outcome of the President's addiction to constantly stoking division.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is banana republic crap that we're watching happen right now,&quot; Republican Rep. Mike Gallagher of Wisconsin said in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RepGallagher/status/1346912246291603465?s=20&quot;&gt;video message&lt;/a&gt; from lockdown in his congressional office. &quot;This is the cost of countenancing an effort by Congress to overturn the election and telling thousands of people that there is a legitimate shot of overturning the election today, even though you know that is not true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have got to stop this. Mr. President, you have got to stop this,&quot; he said. &quot;The election is over. Call it off.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Finish the work&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the violent breach, congressional leaders were looking to continue the process of officially recognizing the results of the presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Today, a shameful assault was made on our democracy,&quot; House Speaker Nancy Pelosi, D-Calif., wrote in a letter to members. &quot;It was anointed at the highest level of government. It cannot, however, deter us from our responsibility to validate the election of Joe Biden.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A senior Senate aide told NPR the Senate was aiming to reconvene around 8 p.m. ET to continue the electoral vote count and &quot;finish the work.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier Wednesday, Sen. Jeff Merkley, D-Ore., wrote on Twitter that the Electoral College ballots had been &quot;rescued from the Senate floor. If our capable floor staff hadn't grabbed them, they would have been burned by the mob.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res954190063&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap twitter large graphic624&quot; aria-label=&quot;Tweet&quot; readability=&quot;5.7629310344828&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;5.7629310344828&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Electoral college ballots rescued from the Senate floor. If our capable floor staff hadn’t grabbed them, they would have been burned by the mob. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/2JCauUIlvg&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/2JCauUIlvg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Senator Jeff Merkley (@SenJeffMerkley) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SenJeffMerkley/status/1346938705932648451?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPR's Deirdre Walsh and Kelsey Snell contributed to this report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 19:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fortran77</dc:creator>
<og:title>Capitol Reels After Pro-Trump Mob Breaches Building; Woman Is Killed</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/954028436/u-s-capitol-locked-down-amid-escalating-far-right-protests</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The Capitol was the scene of chaos as supporters of President Trump responded to his call to head to the complex and then breached it. A woman was shot and killed during the assault.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2021/01/06/gettyimages-1230455089_wide-894db8d9df5d7ef55a206b08b2b50fdfa5da87e4.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/congress-electoral-college-tally-live-updates/2021/01/06/954028436/u-s-capitol-locked-down-amid-escalating-far-right-protests</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Memory access on the Apple M1 processor</title>
<link>https://lemire.me/blog/2021/01/06/memory-access-on-the-apple-m1-processor/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lemire.me/blog/2021/01/06/memory-access-on-the-apple-m1-processor/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When a program is mostly just accessing memory randomly, a standard cost model is to count the number of distinct random accesses. The general idea is that memory access is much slower than most other computational tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the cost model can be extended to count “nearby” memory accesses as free. That is, if I read a byte at memory address &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and then I read a byte at memory address &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;+1, I can assume that the second byte comes “for free”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This naive memory-access model is often sensible. However, you should always keep in mind that it is merely a model. A model can fail to predict real performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How might it fail? A CPU core can issue multiple memory requests at once. So if I need to access 7 memory locations at once, I can issue 7 memory requests and wait for them. It it is likely that waiting for 7 memory requests is slower than waiting for a single memory request, but is it likely to be 7 times slower?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest Apple laptop processor, the M1, has apparently a lot of memory-level parallelism. It looks like a single core has about &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lemire/testingmlp&quot;&gt;28 levels of memory parallelism&lt;/a&gt;, and possibly more.&lt;a href=&quot;https://lemire.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/results.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19010&quot; src=&quot;https://lemire.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/results.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; srcset=&quot;https://lemire.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/results.png 640w, https://lemire.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/results-300x225.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a high degree of memory-level parallelism makes it less likely that our naive random-memory model applies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test it out, I designed the following benchmark where I compare three functions. The first one just grabs pairs of randomly selected bytes and it computes a bitwise XOR between them before adding them to a counter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  for(size_t i = 0&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i &amp;lt; 2*M&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i+= 2) &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    answer &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; array&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;random&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;^&lt;/span&gt; array&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;random&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We compare against a 3-wise version of this function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  for(size_t i = 0&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i &amp;lt; 3*M&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i+= 3) &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    answer &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; array&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;random&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;^&lt;/span&gt; array&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;random&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; 
              &lt;span&gt;^&lt;/span&gt; array&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;random&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our naive memory-access cost model predicts that the second function should be 50% more expensive. However many other models (such as a simple instruction count) would also predict a 50% overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give our naive memory-access model a run for its money, let us throw in a 2-wise version that also accesses nearby values (with one-byte offset):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  for(size_t i = 0&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i &amp;lt; 2*M&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i+= 2) &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; idx1 &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; random&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; idx2 &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; random&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    
    answer &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; array&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;idx1&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;^&lt;/span&gt; array&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;idx1 &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; 
           &lt;span&gt;^&lt;/span&gt; array&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;idx2&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span&gt;^&lt;/span&gt; array&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;idx2 &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our naive memory-access cost model would predict that first and last function should have about the same running time while the second function should be 50% more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us measure it out. I use a 1GB array and I report the average time spent in nanosecond on each iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2-wise&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8.9 ns&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;3-wise&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13.0 ns&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2-wise +&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12.5 ns&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;At first glance, our naive memory-access model is validated: the 3-wise function is 46% more expensive than the 2-wise function. Yet we should not be surprised because most reasonable models would make such a prediction since in almost every way, the function does 50% more work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is more interesting to compare the two 2-wise function… the last one is 40% more expensive than the first 2-wise function. It contradicts our prediction. And so, at least in this instance, our simple memory-access cost model fails us on the Apple M1 processor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lemire/Code-used-on-Daniel-Lemire-s-blog/tree/master/2021/01/06&quot;&gt;My source code is available&lt;/a&gt;. The run-to-run variability is relatively high on such a test, but the conclusion is robust, on my Apple M1 system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/lemire/1c9e8827b45d057d7546e2743ad34496&quot;&gt;I posted the assembly online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Importantly, I do not predict that other systems will follow the same pattern. Please do not run this benchmark on your non-M1 PC and expect comparable results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 17:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>luigi23</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://lemire.me/blog/2021/01/06/memory-access-on-the-apple-m1-processor/</og:url>
<og:title>Memory access on the Apple M1 processor</og:title>
<og:description>When a program is mostly just accessing memory randomly, a standard cost model is to count the number of distinct random accesses. The general idea is that memory access is much slower than most other computational tasks. Furthermore, the cost model can be extended to count “nearby” memory accesses as free. That is, if I … Continue reading Memory access on the Apple M1 processor</og:description>
<og:image>https://lemire.me/img/portrait2018facebook.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lemire.me/blog/2021/01/06/memory-access-on-the-apple-m1-processor/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The U.S. Is Building a Bike Trail That Runs Coast-to-Coast Across 12 States</title>
<link>https://www.ecowatch.com/great-american-rail-trail-2649733595.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ecowatch.com/great-american-rail-trail-2649733595.html</guid>
<description>Across 50 pages, the atlas — which is collaboratively published by the foundation, Friends of the Earth Germany (BUND) and the international monthly newspaper Le Monde diplomatique — outlines trends and the implications of global meat production on both human and planetary health. It highlights, for example, how the over-use of antibiotics in intensive animal farming is leading to increasingly resistant germs, thereby threatening the effectiveness of drugs used for humans.Similarly, the clearing of forests for animal feed is held up as a threat to human health. As habitat loss brings animals and humans into closer proximity with one another, viruses can be transmitted more easily. This, in turn, can lead to new pandemics. In a survey for the report, young people between the ages of 15 and 29 were asked about their thoughts on meat. The majority said they rejected the meat industry in its current form.
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img lazy-loadable=&quot;true&quot; data-runner-src=&quot;https://assets.rebelmouse.io/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNTI2MTI2My9vcmlnaW4ucG5nIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTY1NDQ2NDg4Mn0.qN_OXydVYlh8UK0xFUW6LY5uEnreJtVEBX9y1AAdCzM/img.png?width=980&quot; id=&quot;49a82&quot; class=&quot;rm-shortcode&quot; data-rm-shortcode-id=&quot;a3dc0e46513e0db25cc4853f1199cc06&quot; data-rm-shortcode-name=&quot;rebelmouse-image&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot; data-height=&quot;1738&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-role=&quot;headline&quot;&gt;Germany Plays Leading Role in the Meat Industry &lt;/h3&gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;​&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;Olaf Bandt, chairman of BUND, says policymakers must take account of society's desire to &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/can-you-be-a-good-christian-and-eat-meat/a-55410685&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&amp;gt;restructure the sector&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;. &quot;This requires far-reaching political realignment of agricultural policy,&quot; he said. &quot;But there can be no agricultural transition without a food transition.&quot;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Bandt describes Germany as a key player in the production of pork and milk, with a 20% share of the EU market. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&quot;Huge amounts of meat are exported,&quot; he said, adding that this reliance on international markets is having a detrimental effect on the environment, livestock and farms. &quot;More and more animals live on ever fewer farms, further exacerbating the pollution of groundwater in those regions.&quot; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-role=&quot;headline&quot;&gt;Meat Devours Rainforest&lt;/h3&gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Global population and economic growth are the drivers behind increasing demand for meat. In 1960, the planet was home to just 3 billion people and, according to the report, meat consumption at that time was around 70 million metric tons. That equated to an annual per capita global average of 23 kilograms.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;By 2018, however, when the population had grown to 7.6 billion people, meat consumption had risen seven-fold to around 350 million metric tons — or a global average of 46 kilograms per person annually.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;A key problem with this trend is that &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/eating-meat-is-no-longer-a-private-matter/a-55515722&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&amp;gt;meat production&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; requires vast areas of land. According to the German Environment Agency (UBA), the country's central environment authority, 71% of global arable land is currently used for livestock feed. That is four times the amount required for direct food growth (18%) or other raw materials such as cotton (7%) and energy crops like corn for biogas (4%). &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img lazy-loadable=&quot;true&quot; data-runner-src=&quot;https://assets.rebelmouse.io/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNTI2MTI4MS9vcmlnaW4ucG5nIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTYzMzY3ODE3M30.bzrJxdzNQIFQ6l70d2InrAMt_IPO68FjvCZuNbvtc5E/img.png?width=980&quot; id=&quot;3601b&quot; class=&quot;rm-shortcode&quot; data-rm-shortcode-id=&quot;5e0bedbcf3921365156f8612ef04429b&quot; data-rm-shortcode-name=&quot;rebelmouse-image&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot; data-height=&quot;2414&quot; /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;As global demand for meat continues to grow, so does the pressure on available arable land. As a result, huge areas of forest in countries such as Brazil are being lost to create land on which to grow animal fodder.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In order to feed the world's population and stop rainforests from being cleared, while simultaneously designating land for reforestation, experts are calling for a dietary rethink: less meat and more &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/will-plant-based-meat-become-the-new-fast-food/a-55578740&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&amp;gt;plant-based foods&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; that require much smaller areas.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In a report on the health of the planet published last year, leading global scientists such as Johan Rockström, director at the Potsdam Institute for Climate Impact Research (PIK) suggested dietary changes that would equate to an average of 16 kilograms of meat and 33 kilograms of dairy products per person per year. Current meat consumption in North and South America as well as in Europe can be as much as seven times that amount.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-role=&quot;headline&quot;&gt;The Problem With Pesticides&lt;/h3&gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Besides revealing the power and global impact of the international meat industry, authors of the &quot;Meat Atlas&quot; also illustrate links to the global chemical industry. They write that dangerous and sometimes banned pesticides are exported by large chemical companies. Among the producers and exporters of such chemicals are European players, Bayer Crop Science, BASF, and Syngenta, as well as U.S. companies Corteva and FMS. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img lazy-loadable=&quot;true&quot; data-runner-src=&quot;https://assets.rebelmouse.io/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNTI2MTI5MC9vcmlnaW4ucG5nIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTY2Njg2NDMxMX0.0aKA3OQjDEKgl9Y088j9WLfsB9H_ilSNhjgSmScpO6o/img.png?width=980&quot; id=&quot;43f23&quot; class=&quot;rm-shortcode&quot; data-rm-shortcode-id=&quot;4fb04eda49e57f1b7c4a6f05c7e56deb&quot; data-rm-shortcode-name=&quot;rebelmouse-image&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot; data-height=&quot;2520&quot; /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;According to Unmüssig, the use of such pesticides threatens thousands of lives, which is why, Bandt says the &quot;German government must do everything it can to ensure that German companies no longer export toxins that have been banned in the EU.&quot;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Unmüssig warns that the planned &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/merkel-amazon-deforestation-threatens-eu-mercosur-deal/a-54651194&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&amp;gt;EU-Mercosur agreement&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; would exacerbate the use of dangerous substances. &quot;Dismantling tariffs would lead to more pesticides being delivered to Latin America and more &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecowatch.com/tag/rainforest&quot;&amp;gt;rainforest&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; would be cleared for soy plantations and meat production.&quot;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The experts conclude that establishing a way to farm animals in a cruelty-free way that doesn't harm the climate or the environment, requires a far-reaching shift in agricultural policy as well a rethink in consumption and production. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&quot;As yet, we have not seen the start of any real meat transition,&quot; Unmüssig said. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;This article was adapted from German.&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Reposted with permission from &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/meat-atlas-its-time-to-rethink-what-we-eat/a-56145352&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&amp;gt;Deutsche Welle&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecowatch.com/r/entryeditor/2649770271#/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;around-the-web&quot; readability=&quot;1.2553191489362&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Your Site Articles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related Articles Around the Web&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 16:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Xplor</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.ecowatch.com/great-american-rail-trail-2649733595.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://assets.rebelmouse.io/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNTE3NTc0Ni9vcmlnaW4uanBnIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTYyNjY1NjMzMX0.ZVvdZCZTVKMMFk7XkrYRvtKxx3X4nqlI7fgCs4301-k/img.jpg?width=1200&amp;coordinates=0%2C40%2C0%2C40&amp;height=600</og:image>
<og:title>The U.S. Is Building a Bike Trail That Runs Coast-to-Coast Across 12 States</og:title>
<og:description>By Natalie MarchantThe Great American Rail-Trail will be almost 6,000km when complete, and will serve 50 million people within 80km of the route.Trails have proved invaluable for recreation and transport during lockdown.Cycling and safe routes are vital for cities planning their post-pandemic recove...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ecowatch.com/great-american-rail-trail-2649733595.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What I’ve Learned in 45 Years in the Software Industry</title>
<link>https://www.bti360.com/what-ive-learned-in-45-years-in-the-software-industry/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bti360.com/what-ive-learned-in-45-years-in-the-software-industry/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;BTI360 teammate Joel Goldberg recently retired after working in the software industry for over four decades. When he left he shared with our team some of the lessons he learned over his career. With his permission, we reshare his wisdom here.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/goldberg-early.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;4299&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/?attachment_id=4299&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/goldberg-early.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;235,341&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;goldberg-early&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/goldberg-early.png&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/goldberg-early.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-4299 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/goldberg-early.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;235&quot; height=&quot;341&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Looking back on four decades in the software industry, I’m struck by how much has changed. I started my career with punch cards and I am ending in the era of cloud computing. Despite all this change, many principles that have helped me throughout my career haven’t changed and continue to be relevant. As I step away from the keyboard, I want to share six ideas I’ve learned from my career as a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Beware of the Curse of Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you know something it is almost impossible to imagine what it is like &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to know that thing. This is the curse of knowledge, and it is the root of countless misunderstandings and inefficiencies. Smart people who are comfortable with complexity can be especially prone to it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t guard against the curse of knowledge it has the potential to obfuscate all forms of communication, including code. The more specialized your work, the greater the risk that you will communicate in ways that are incomprehensible to the uninitiated. Fight the curse of knowledge. Work to understand your audience. Try to imagine what it would be like to learn what you are communicating for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Focus on the Fundamentals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology constantly changes, but some fundamental approaches to software development transcend these trends. Here are six fundamentals that will continue to be relevant for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teamwork&lt;/strong&gt; — Great teams build great software. Don’t take teamwork for granted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust &lt;/strong&gt;— Teams move at the speed of trust. Be the kind of dependable person you would want to work with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication&lt;/strong&gt; — Communicate honestly and proactively. Avoid the curse of knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seek Consensus&lt;/strong&gt; — Take the time to bring your whole team along. Let discussion and disagreement bring you to the best solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Testing&lt;/strong&gt; —  Well-tested code allows your team to move fast with confidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clean, understandable, and navigable code and design&lt;/strong&gt; — Think of the next engineer that will take over your code as your customer.  Build code that your successor won’t have any trouble reading, maintaining, and updating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. Simplicity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fighting complexity is a never-ending cause. Solutions should be as simple as possible. Assume the next person to maintain your code won’t be as smart as you. When you can use fewer technologies, do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A designer knows he has achieved perfection not when there is nothing left to add, but when there is nothing left to take away.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;em&gt;Antoine de Saint-Exupery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Seek First to Understand&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Stephen Covey’s seven habits is, “Seek First To Understand, Then To Be Understood.” This maxim has helped me more than any other advice to become a good listener and teammate. If you want to influence and work effectively with others, you first need to understand them. Actively listen to understand their feelings, ideas, and point of view before you begin trying to make your own thoughts known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/bti360-2019-237.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;4305&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/what-ive-learned-in-45-years-in-the-software-industry/bti360-2019-237-2/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/bti360-2019-237.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;600,388&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;bti360-2019-237&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/bti360-2019-237-400x259.jpg&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/bti360-2019-237.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-4305 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/bti360-2019-237.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;388&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/bti360-2019-237.jpg 600w, https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/bti360-2019-237-400x259.jpg 400w, https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/bti360-2019-237-564x365.jpg 564w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Beware of Lock-In&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will always be the next hot productivity product that will promise to revolutionize how software is built. Computer Assisted Software Engineering (CASE) tools, COTS, Enterprise Resource Planning products like Peoplesoft and SAP and, yes, even Ruby. They claim amazing reductions in cost and time if you buy into their holistic development philosophy. What is not always as obvious is the significant up-front costs or the constraints you may be committing yourself to. Lock-in used to primarily happen with vendors, but now it can happen with frameworks too. Either way, lock-in means significant cost to change. Choose wisely. New is not always better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. Be Honest and Acknowledge When You Don’t Fit the Role&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point in your career you may find yourself in a role that isn’t a good fit. A bad fit isn’t a character flaw, but it’s a problem you shouldn’t ignore. There may be more than one solution to such a dilemma: you can evolve or the role can evolve. The key is to have the self-knowledge to recognize what is happening and get yourself out of an unhealthy spot. Being unhappy is in no-one’s best interests, and BTI360 recognizes this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was at GM, you were a failure if your next move was not &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt;—managing more people or taking on bigger, more complex projects. For many, this made for a miserable career path (see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_principle&quot;&gt;Peter Principle&lt;/a&gt;). At EDS, the culture wasn’t like this. People moved in and out of management roles. There was no stigma associated with moving from roles with greater scope, like strategic planner, to roles with more narrow scope, like PM or project-level developer. I was one of the people who took advantage of this flexibility, moving from a role at the top of the technical pyramid back to being a project-level developer. I never looked back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;4294&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/?attachment_id=4294&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Goldberg_Joel_2_circ-230.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;230,230&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Goldberg_Joel_2_circ-230&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Goldberg_Joel_2_circ-230.png&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Goldberg_Joel_2_circ-230.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-4294 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Goldberg_Joel_2_circ-230.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;230&quot; height=&quot;230&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even before I joined BTI360 I knew enough about the culture to know that it was a place that valued the kinds of principles I’ve described above. I hope each of you will take ownership of maintaining a strong engineering culture that will continue to make BTI360 a great place to build software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;In addition to his varied technical experience, Joel worked with a lot of interesting characters over his career, including W. Edwards Deming and Ross Perot. Next week we will share an interview where he tells more about those encounters and other interesting experiences over 4 decades in the tech industry.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like What You Hear? Work Here!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Are you a software engineer, interested in joining a software company that invests in its teammates and promotes a strong engineering culture? Then you’re in the right place! Check out our current &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bti360.com/careers/#apply-now&quot;&gt;Career Opportunities&lt;/a&gt;. We’re always looking for like-minded engineers to join the BTI360 family.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 14:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>FauxDemure</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bti360.com/what-ive-learned-in-45-years-in-the-software-industry/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook senior software engineer interview</title>
<link>https://daqo.medium.com/facebook-senior-software-engineer-interview-the-only-post-youll-need-to-read-e4604ff2336d</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://daqo.medium.com/facebook-senior-software-engineer-interview-the-only-post-youll-need-to-read-e4604ff2336d</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;dfd3&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;There is no doubt that the technical interviews are stressful, but having a robust process helps the candidate to mitigate and manage their stress level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;8dfb&quot; class=&quot;iw ix fu av iv iy iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj jk jl jm jn jo jp jq jr js dz&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ee25&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs jt ht hu hv ju hw hx hy jv hz ia ib jw ic id ie jx if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;The interview process in big companies is comprised of having one or two phone interviews in the beginning. If everything goes well, they will invite you for the final on-site interview. The on-site interview has multiple components: 1) Behavioral section 2) coding parts 3) system/product design interviews. Getting an offer depends on the cumulative performance of all these interviews. I won’t focus on the behavioral components here in the interest of time, as there are excellent resources on the web explaining that section in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;f3b4&quot; class=&quot;iw ix fu av iv iy iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj jk jl jm jn jo jp jq jr js dz&quot;&gt;Choose a language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;10f6&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs jt ht hu hv ju hw hx hy jv hz ia ib jw ic id ie jx if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;The big tech companies will not get pedantic on the language that you decide to use in your interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;348c&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Before coming to Facebook, I coded primarily in Ruby, Javascript, and Erlang; although, for my interviews, I decided to go with Python as it resembles Ruby. Another reason is that Python and Java are well known in big tech companies. The Python syntax is very terse, which makes it a suitable candidate for whiteboard interviews. To refresh my knowledge of the language, I dedicated a couple of days to go through the Python 3.7 tutorial. This helped me to get myself familiar with Python 3 syntax and idioms. People must avoid using less mainstream languages in their coding interviews as it’s possible that your interviewer might not be familiar with those languages. Anyhow, as a word of advice, don’t shoot yourself in the foot, and stick to a classic interview language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7e24&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;I also spent a couple of hours reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/glossary.html&quot; class=&quot;do jy&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Python Glossary&lt;/a&gt;. That made me familiar with the terminology used in the Python community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1b8e&quot; class=&quot;iw ix fu av iv iy iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj jk jl jm jn jo jp jq jr js dz&quot;&gt;Making a weekly/daily plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1bb8&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs jt ht hu hv ju hw hx hy jv hz ia ib jw ic id ie jx if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Bootstrapping a project is the hardest part. To overcome that, it’s recommended to come up with a weekly plan. The weekly plans are less granular than the daily ones; they let you see the big picture and fail fast. After making my weekly plans, I came up with more detailed daily to-do items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fh fi&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Image for post&quot; class=&quot;kr&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/max/1000/1*Z8kWGSBcRwfu3lKdiziyCQ.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1f13&quot; class=&quot;iw ix fu av iv iy iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj jk jl jm jn jo jp jq jr js dz&quot;&gt;Take notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b2b0&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs jt ht hu hv ju hw hx hy jv hz ia ib jw ic id ie jx if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Do yourself a favor and take notes of the topics you are studying. During this time, you will be covering so many different subjects, and being a human being guarantees that you will forget the majority of them, so take notes and review them once in a while. Your notes are also a valuable resource for the next time that you are preparing for the interviews. The notes belong to you, so feel free to get creative and make them less dull.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;8e3d&quot; class=&quot;iw ix fu av iv iy iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj jk jl jm jn jo jp jq jr js dz&quot;&gt;What and how to study?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;15c8&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs jt ht hu hv ju hw hx hy jv hz ia ib jw ic id ie jx if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;I started studying with having the following items in my reading list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0285&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Introduction to Algorithms serves as an introductory textbook to algorithms. I had read it back in college, but I needed to refresh my memory, so I decided to study it first. Note, that you won’t need to go through CLRS to be succesful in your interview. I just read it because I remember liking it in college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5a1f&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Here is the daily plan that I used to study the CLRS book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4973&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 1 — CLRS (ch 2, 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4ad7&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 2 — CLRS (ch 4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5b28&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 3 — CLRS (ch 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7490&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 4 — CLRS (ch 6, 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0603&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 5 — CLRS (ch 8, 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c80d&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 6 — CLRS (ch 10, 11, 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8f13&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 7 — CLRS (ch 13, 14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1edc&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 8 — CLRS (ch 15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;31f6&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 9 — CLRS (ch 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0187&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 10 — CLRS (ch 17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6db8&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 11 — CLRS (ch 18, 19, 20, 21)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;26f4&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 12 — CLRS (ch 22, 23, 24, 25, 26)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;be56&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 13 — CLRS (ch 27, 28, 29, 30) (Optional)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e39f&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 14 — CLRS (ch 31, 32) (Optional)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c513&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 15 — CLRS (ch 33, 34) (Optional)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4394&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 16 — CLRS (ch 35) (Optional)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6dc2&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;For the most part, I stuck to my plan, but they were days that I fell behind. Don’t feel bad if that happens; just notice it fast and try to adjust your plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a801&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;After studying CLRS, I decided to prepare my mind for solving questions. Based on my previous research, one of the books that help you think algorithmically is classic Programming Pearls. Some people call that book archaic and futile, but I can’t disagree more. There are a lot of valuable insights packed in such a small book. I had Programming Pearls in my reading list for a long time, but I never got a chance to go through it. Preparing for the interviews finally gave me the chance to read it. I studied it based on the following plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;632e&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 17 — PP (columns 1, 2, 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;88b0&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 18 — PP (columns 4, 5, 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c769&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 19 — PP (columns 7, 8, 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d63d&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 20 — PP (columns 10, 11, 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3e99&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 21 — PP (columns 13, 14, 15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9833&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;When studying CLRS or PP, it’s essential to solve the exercises at the end of each chapter. That will help you to solidify what you have learned into your brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ae1f&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;After studying CLRS and PP, you should have a good grasp of the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;3339&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Primitive Types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;4a49&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Arrays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;3e06&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Strings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;7680&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Linked Lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;8524&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Stacks and Queues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;69fd&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Binary Trees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;f6f3&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Heaps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;d63b&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Searching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;bd2c&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Sorting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;253f&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Binary Search Trees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ad23&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Hashing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;2ebb&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Recursion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;8acc&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii ks kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Dynamic Programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;6d98&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;The next book I studied was “Elements of Programming Interviews In Python”. The reason I chose EPIP over CTCI (Cracking the coding interview) is that EPIP uses Python, and in my opinion, it has a better set of questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5a6b&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;My initial plan was to study one chapter per day. That included solving all the questions presented in that chapter. I timeboxed myself to one hour per question. If I weren’t able to solve it, I’d come back to it the next day. If, on the second day, I couldn’t make progress on the question, I’d sneak a peek at the answer. I would make sure that I’m understanding the solution and not just memorizing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1b57&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Besides studying one chapter of EPIP per day, I also started reading Designing Data-Intensive Applications (DDIA). This book provides you with a lot of useful materials that are handy in System Design interviews. I had already studied half of the book and had taken notes; so I just ended up working through the second half and reviewing my notes from the first half:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e45a&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 22 — DDIA (Studying my notes for chapters 1 to 6.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3cab&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 23 — DDIA (ch. 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;04c2&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 24 — DDIA (ch. 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;41bf&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 25 — DDIA (ch. 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a686&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 26 — DDIA (ch. 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b84f&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 27 — DDIA (ch. 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1bbf&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Day 28 — DDIA (ch. 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d248&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Most candidates spend a lot of time preparing for coding interviews, and they neglect the system design preparation. Studying DDIA put me on the right track for my system design interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f187&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Another great source of study for design interviews is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer&quot; class=&quot;do jy&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;“System Design Primer”&lt;/a&gt;. It teaches you the foundation of designing large-scale systems, and it also includes Anki flashcards (Disclaimer: I didn’t use the flashcards, so I’m not sure about the quality).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;652c&quot; class=&quot;iw ix fu av iv iy iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj jk jl jm jn jo jp jq jr js dz&quot;&gt;System Design Interviews&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b613&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs jt ht hu hv ju hw hx hy jv hz ia ib jw ic id ie jx if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;To prepare yourself for system design interviews, take a look at any system and service that you use and ask yourself this question: If I was going to build this system, how would I do it? Try to come up with answers to that question. Later, try to validate your answers to make sure your solution is scalable. You could also use mock interviews to get yourself comfortable with system design questions. I didn’t use any for my preparation, but I know of some companies that offer system design mock interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fe80&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;As a starting point, try to design the following services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;e7ba&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;URL Shortener like bit.ly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;11a1&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;31b4&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cae8&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Twitter Search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;643f&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Facebook News Feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;7725&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Whatsapp/Facebook Messenger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;99c8&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Typeahead Suggestion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;9e48&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;32d1&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Netflix/Youtube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cf3b&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Yelp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;d0cb&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Lyft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;c65d&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs kv ht hu hv kw hw hx hy kx hz ia ib ky ic id ie kz if ig ii la kt ku dz&quot;&gt;Put the name of your favorite service here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;b306&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs iq ht hu hv ir hw hx hy is hz ia ib it ic id ie iu if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;As mentioned before, DDIA and System Design Primer are great resources to study to nail your next system design interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;26ef&quot; class=&quot;iw ix fu av iv iy iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj jk jl jm jn jo jp jq jr js dz&quot;&gt;Coding Interviews&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e40c&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs jt ht hu hv ju hw hx hy jv hz ia ib jw ic id ie jx if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Besides studying EPIP thoroughly, try to solve as many questions as possible. You could use either of HackerRank or LeetCode. Solving more problems will train your mind and will make you prepare for your actual coding interviews. My approach was to start with easy questions, find my way gradually to medium questions, and in the end, work through the hard ones. Some people prefer to start with hard questions, but I don’t recommend that. Starting with easy questions will help you build confidence as you progress. Make sure you are timeboxing each question and are not lingering too much on a single problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;8411&quot; class=&quot;iw ix fu av iv iy iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj jk jl jm jn jo jp jq jr js dz&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;06a0&quot; class=&quot;hp hq fu hr b hs jt ht hu hv ju hw hx hy jv hz ia ib jw ic id ie jx if ig ii di dz&quot;&gt;Applying for senior engineering positions (&amp;gt;E4) in FANG companies is one of the best ways to get into them. Most of these companies have solid internship programs, and almost all E3 (entry-level) positions are offered to returning interns. To have a successful senior engineering interview, define a goal for yourself, and then strive toward that. What I described in this post was my systematic approach to preparing for my Facebook technical interviews. Your journey could be different, so feel free to adjust my plans for your taste.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 14:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hpux</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook senior software engineer interview: the only post you’ll need to read</og:title>
<og:description>I have been working at Facebook as a software engineer for a while now. During this time, I have got different inquiries from friends and…</og:description>
<og:url>https://daqo.medium.com/facebook-senior-software-engineer-interview-the-only-post-youll-need-to-read-e4604ff2336d</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/max/1200/1*Z8kWGSBcRwfu3lKdiziyCQ.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://daqo.medium.com/facebook-senior-software-engineer-interview-the-only-post-youll-need-to-read-e4604ff2336d</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GNU Units</title>
<link>https://www.gnu.org/software/units/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gnu.org/software/units/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;GNU Units&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNU Units converts quantities expressed in various systems of measurement to their equivalents in other systems of measurement. Like many similar programs, it can handle multiplicative scale changes. It can also handle nonlinear conversions such as Fahrenheit to Celsius or wire gauge, and it can convert from and to sums of units, such as converting between meters and feet plus inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond simple unit conversions, GNU Units can be used as a general-purpose scientific calculator that keeps track of units in its calculations. You can form arbitrary complex mathematical expressions of dimensions including sums, products, quotients, powers, and even roots of dimensions. Thus you can ensure accuracy and dimensional consistency when working with long expressions that involve many different units that may combine in complex ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The units are defined in an external data file. You can use the extensive data file that comes with this program, or you can provide your own data file to suit your needs. You can also use your own data file to supplement the standard data file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Examples&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two simple conversion examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;emph-box&quot;&gt;
You have: mile
You want: km
        * 1.609344
        / 0.62137119

You have: furlongs per fortnight
You want: m/s  
        * 0.00016630986
        / 6012.8727
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A calculation involving roots of units:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;emph-box&quot;&gt;
You have: (400 W/m^2 / stefanboltzmann)^(1/4)
You have:
        Definition: 289.80882 K
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temperature &lt;em&gt;differences&lt;/em&gt; are converted using the syntax shown above with unit names like degC and degF. But conversion of absolute temperatures requires a different syntax:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;emph-box&quot;&gt;
You have: tempF(45)
You want: tempC
        7.2222222
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Converting from a sum of units:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;emph-box&quot;&gt;
You have: 17 yards + 2 feet + 5 inches
You want: meter
        * 16.2814
        / 0.06141978
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Converting to a sum of units such as hours plus minutes or feet plus inches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;emph-box&quot;&gt;
You have: 7 meters
You want: ft;in
        22 ft + 11.590551 in
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Converting a sixth of a (US) cup to common US measures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;emph-box&quot;&gt;
You have: 1|6 cup
You want: usvol
        2 tbsp + 2 tsp
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;download&quot;&gt;Downloading Units&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;SourceDistribution&quot;&gt;Source Distribution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Units can be found on the main GNU ftp server: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/units/&quot;&gt;http://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/units/&lt;/a&gt; (via HTTP) and &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/units/&quot;&gt;ftp://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/units/&lt;/a&gt; (via FTP). It can also be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/prep/ftp.html&quot;&gt;GNU mirrors&lt;/a&gt;; please &lt;a href=&quot;http://ftpmirror.gnu.org/units/&quot;&gt;use a mirror&lt;/a&gt; if possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;WindowsBinary&quot;&gt;Windows Binary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A binary distribution for Windows is available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/units/windows/&quot;&gt;http://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/units/windows/&lt;/a&gt; (via HTTP) and &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/units/windows/&quot;&gt;ftp://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/units/windows&lt;/a&gt; (via FTP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;documentation&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/units/manual/&quot;&gt;Documentation for Units&lt;/a&gt; is available online, as is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/manual/&quot;&gt;documentation for most GNU software&lt;/a&gt;. You may also find more information about Units by running &lt;em&gt;info units&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;man units&lt;/em&gt;, or by looking at &lt;em&gt;/usr/share/doc/units/&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;/usr/local/doc/units/&lt;/em&gt;, or similar directories on your system. A brief summary is available by running &lt;em&gt;units --help&lt;/em&gt;. The units definitions can generally be found in &lt;em&gt;/usr/share/units/&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl readability=&quot;-1.5815085158151&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Test releases&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Trying the latest test release (when available) is always appreciated. Test releases of Units can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://alpha.gnu.org/gnu/units/&quot;&gt;http://alpha.gnu.org/gnu/units/&lt;/a&gt; (via HTTP) and &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://alpha.gnu.org/gnu/units/&quot;&gt;ftp://alpha.gnu.org/gnu/units/&lt;/a&gt; (via FTP).&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Maintainer&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd readability=&quot;-0.86631016042781&quot;&gt;Units is currently being maintained by &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:adrianm@gnu.org&quot;&gt;Adrian Mariano&lt;/a&gt; All general bug reports, feature requests or thoughts should go to him.
&lt;p&gt;The Windows binary distribution is maintained by &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jeff_conrad@msn.com&quot;&gt;Jeff Conrad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;license&quot;&gt;Licensing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Units is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.html&quot; rel=&quot;license&quot;&gt;GNU General Public License&lt;/a&gt; as published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 12:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gnu.org/software/units/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: I built the antithesis of Zoom. Add GIFs, stickers, BGs. Talk like IRL</title>
<link>https://reslash.co</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://reslash.co</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;lp-headline text-align-center font-scale-6 line-height-scale-3 subhead&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Akshay Hangloo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-align-center font-scale-5 line-height-scale-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-founder and COO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-align-left font-scale-5 line-height-scale-8&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Akshay knows his way around numbers. As an ex-head of analytics at VWO, he built the analytics team from the ground up - setting up processes, integrating tools like Salesforce and Tableau, building incentive plans, bringing transparency into the customer lifecycle and helping company become data-informed than ever.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Reslash, he's helping us be data-focused right from the get go. And it's not limited to the company. He's working relentlessly to empower our customers with data to understand behaviours and patterns of their interactions on Reslash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outside Reslash, you can catch him building tunes on his Akai MINI keyboard or beatboxing at some off-beat joint in Goa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 12:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>remotelyyours</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>The Virtual Estate Company</og:title>
<og:description>Have many spontaneous conversations within the same space. No need to jump calls or get into breakout rooms. Instead, build real connections virtually.</og:description>
<og:url>https://reslash.co/</og:url>
<og:image>https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/PqDSh8jsRBkIXSVia7c2ApjQe8H-NqMZUH_g-GDw-U4phh5Ce3lSOIiVWMZarby8BItOmiqU1sxKAevJtiRX=s0</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://reslash.co/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>