<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The Octopus Is Smart as Heck, But Why?</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/30/science/animal-intelligence-octopus-cephalopods.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/30/science/animal-intelligence-octopus-cephalopods.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;To demonstrate how smart an octopus can be, Piero Amodio points to a YouTube video. It shows an octopus pulling two halves of a coconut shell together to hide inside. Later the animal stacks the shells together like nesting bowls — and carts them away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“It suggests the octopus is carrying these tools around because it has some understanding they may be useful in the future,” said Mr. Amodio, a graduate student studying animal intelligence at the University of Cambridge in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-45o39g&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube Video&quot; class=&quot;css-uwwqev&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1DoWdHOtlrk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But his amazement is mixed with puzzlement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For decades, researchers have studied how certain animals evolved to be intelligent, among them apes, elephants, dolphins and even some birds, such as crows and parrots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But all the scientific theories fail when it comes to cephalopods, a group that includes octopuses, squid and cuttlefish. Despite feats of creativity, they &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tree.2018.10.010&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lack some hallmarks&lt;/a&gt; of intelligence seen in other species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“It’s an apparent paradox that’s been largely overlooked in the past,” said Mr. Amodio. He and five other experts on animal intelligence explore this paradox in a paper published this month in the journal Trends in Ecology and Evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For scientists who study animal behavior, intelligence is not about acing a calculus test or taking a car apart and putting it back together. Intelligence comprises sophisticated cognitive skills that help an animal thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;That may include the ability to come up with solutions to the problem of finding food, for example, or a knack for planning for some challenge in the future. Intelligent animals don’t rely on fixed responses to survive — they can invent new behaviors on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;To measure animal intelligence, scientists observe creatures in the wild — watching a dolphin &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2011/07/26/science/26obdolphin.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;stick a sponge on its beak to avoid getting cuts&lt;/a&gt; from sharp rocks and coral, for example. Or they bring animals into the lab and offer them puzzles to solve, such as rewarding crows when they &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/28/science/crows-toolmaking.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;learn to rip paper into strips of just the right size&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Only a few species stand out in these studies, and by comparing them, scientists have identified some shared factors. The animals have big brains relative to their body size, they live for a long time, and they can form long-lasting social bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Those similarities have led to some promising explanations for how certain animals evolved to be smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;One is known as the ecological intelligence hypothesis. It holds that intelligence evolves as an adaptation for finding food. While some animals have a reliable food supply, others have to cope with unpredictability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“If you eat fruit, you have to remember where the fruiting trees are and when they’re ripe,” said Mr. Amadio. “It can be much more cognitively challenging than eating leaves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Tools allow animals to get to food that they couldn’t reach otherwise. And if they can make plans for the future, they can store food to survive hard times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Other researchers have argued for what’s known as the social intelligence hypothesis: Smarter animals “cooperate and learn from other members of the same species,” said Mr. Amadio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Together, these forces appear to have encouraged the development of bigger, more powerful brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Smart animals also tend to live for a long time, and it’s possible that bigger brains drove the evolution of longevity. It takes years for juveniles to develop these complex organs, during which time they need help from adults to get enough food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Cephalopods behave in ways that certainly suggest they’re highly intelligent. An octopus named Inky, for example, made a notorious escape recently from the National Aquarium of New Zealand, exiting his enclosure and slithering into a floor drain and, apparently, out to sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Cuttlefish can scare off predators by forming eyespots on their bodies in order to look like giant fish. But they only use this trick against predators that rely on vision to find prey. If a predator that depends on smell shows up, the cuttlefish are smart enough just to flee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Octopuses show the same flexibility when scientists bring them into labs. In one study, researchers at Hebrew University presented octopuses with an L-shaped box with food inside. The animals &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0152048&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;figured out how to push and pull the morsel through a tiny hole&lt;/a&gt; in the wall of their tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Another feature that cephalopods share with other smart animals is a relatively big brain. But that’s where the similarities appear to end. Most of the neurons that do the computing, for example, are in the octopus’s arms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz euv7paa0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;[&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz euv7paa0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://on.fb.me/1paTQ1h&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;Like the Science Times page on Facebook.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;| Sign up for the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz euv7paa0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1MbHaRU&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;Science Times newsletter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz euv7paa0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Most strikingly, cephalopods die young. Some may live as long as two years, while others only last a few months. Nor do cephalopods form social bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;They get together to mate, but males and females don’t stay together for long or care for their young. While chimpanzees and dolphins may live in societies of dozens of other animals, cephalopods seem to be loners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Amodio and his colleagues think the evolutionary history of cephalopods may explain this intelligence paradox. About half a billion years ago, their snaillike ancestors evolved to use their shells as a buoyancy device. They could load chambers in the shell with gas to float up and down in the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A cousin of cephalopods, the nautilus, still lives this way. Like cephalopods, it has tentacles. It also has a somewhat enlarged brain, although it doesn’t seem to be anywhere as intelligent as an octopus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;About 275 million years ago, the ancestor of today’s cephalopods lost the external shell. It’s not clear why, but it must have been liberating. Now the animals could start exploring places that had been off-limits to their shelled ancestors. Octopuses could slip into rocky crevices, for example, to hunt for prey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;On the other hand, losing their shells left cephalopods quite vulnerable to hungry predators. This threat may have driven cephalopods to become masters of disguise and escape. They did so by evolving big brains, the ability to solve new problems, and perhaps look into the future — knowing that coconut or clam shells may come in handy, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 e1vv25i80&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/04/science/04SCI-ZIMMER-02/merlin_147528999_8c2f3373-6d00-4b38-b113-f485f9f3a9a8-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/04/science/04SCI-ZIMMER-02/merlin_147528999_8c2f3373-6d00-4b38-b113-f485f9f3a9a8-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/04/science/04SCI-ZIMMER-02/merlin_147528999_8c2f3373-6d00-4b38-b113-f485f9f3a9a8-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/04/science/04SCI-ZIMMER-02/merlin_147528999_8c2f3373-6d00-4b38-b113-f485f9f3a9a8-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/04/science/04SCI-ZIMMER-02/merlin_147528999_8c2f3373-6d00-4b38-b113-f485f9f3a9a8-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e1olku6u0&quot;&gt;An octopus pulls together two empty shells in order to hide off the coast of Sulawesi, Indonesia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e18m0s9i0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ethan Daniels, via Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Yet intelligence is not the perfect solution for cephalopods, Mr. Amodio suggested. Sooner or later, they get eaten. Natural selection has turned them into a paradox: a short-lived, intelligent animal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Amodio said that scientists still need to learn a lot more about cephalopods before they can know if this hypothesis is sound. But the research may do more than shine a light on octopuses and their cousins: It could give us a deeper understanding of intelligence in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We can’t take for granted that there’s just one way to intelligence,” Mr. Amodio said. “There could be different paths.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1ur45q4 e5d2tgl3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1ukm2ij e5d2tgl0&quot;&gt;More octopus articles you might like&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 21:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dnetesn</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/30/science/animal-intelligence-octopus-cephalopods.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Yes, the Octopus Is Smart as Heck. But Why?</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/04/science/04SCI-ZIMMER/04SCI-ZIMMER-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>It has eight arms, three hearts — and a plan. Scientists aren’t sure how the cephalopods got to be so intelligent.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/30/science/animal-intelligence-octopus-cephalopods.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Programmer&amp;#039;s Introduction to Mathematics</title>
<link>https://jeremykun.com/2018/12/01/a-programmers-introduction-to-mathematics/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jeremykun.com/2018/12/01/a-programmers-introduction-to-mathematics/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For the last four years I’ve been working on a book for programmers who want to learn mathematics. It’s finally done, and you can buy it today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website for the book is &lt;a href=&quot;https://pimbook.org&quot;&gt;pimbook.org&lt;/a&gt;, which has purchase links—paperback and ebook—and a preview of the first pages. You can see more snippets later in the book on &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2KzMT5t&quot;&gt;the Amazon listing’s&lt;/a&gt; “Look Inside” feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a programmer who wants to learn math, this book is written specifically for you! Why? Because programming and math are naturally complementary, and programmers have a leg up in learning math. Many of the underlying modes of thought in mathematics are present in programming, or are otherwise easy to explain by analogies and contrasts to familiar concepts in software. I leverage that in the book so that you can internalize the insights quickly, and appreciate the nuance more deeply than most books can allow. This book is a bridge from the world of programming to the world of math from the mathematician’s perspective. As far as I know, no other book provides this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programs make math more interesting and applicable than otherwise. Typical math writers often hold computation and algorithms at a healthy distance. Not us. We embrace computation as a prize and a principle worth fighting for. Each chapter of the book culminates in an exciting program that applies the mathematical insights from the chapter to an interesting application. The applications include cryptographic schemes, machine learning, drawing hyperbolic tessellations, and a Nobel-prize winning algorithm from economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exercises of the book also push you beyond the book itself. There’s so much math out there that you can’t learn it from a single book. Perspectives and elaborations are spread throughout books, papers, blog posts, wikis, lecture notes, math magazines, and your own scratch paper. This book will prepare you to read a variety of sources by introducing you to the standard language of math, and also push you to engage with those resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, this book includes a healthy dose of culture. Quotes and passages from the writings of famous mathematicians, contextual explanations of cultural attitudes, and a light dose of history will provide a peek into why mathematics is the way it is today, and why at times it can seem so confounding to an outsider. Through all this, I will show what progress means for math, what attitudes and patterns will help you along the way, and how to stay sane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I couldn’t have written the book without the encouragement and support of you, my readers. Thank you for reading, commenting, and supporting me all these years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pimbook.org&quot;&gt;Order the book&lt;/a&gt; today! I can’t wait to hear what you think 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-23934684-82278-5c0401d2ac694&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20180319#blog_id=23934684&amp;amp;post_id=82278&amp;amp;origin=jeremykun.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=23934684-82278-5c0401d2ac694&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-23934684-82278-5c0401d2ac694&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 21:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chocolateboy</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>A Programmer’s Introduction to Mathematics</og:title>
<og:url>https://jeremykun.com/2018/12/01/a-programmers-introduction-to-mathematics/</og:url>
<og:description>For the last four years I’ve been working on a book for programmers who want to learn mathematics. It’s finally done, and you can buy it today. The website for the book is pimbook.org, …</og:description>
<og:image>https://secure.gravatar.com/blavatar/ffc08531463d8605aef9e0b51a9ac71f?s=200&amp;ts=1543766482</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jeremykun.com/2018/12/01/a-programmers-introduction-to-mathematics/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Second Edition of “Refactoring”</title>
<link>https://martinfowler.com/articles/refactoring-2nd-ed.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://martinfowler.com/articles/refactoring-2nd-ed.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to work with Kent Beck on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/C3.html&quot;&gt;C3 project&lt;/a&gt; that birthed Extreme Programming. There was a great deal I learned (and am still learning) from Kent, but one thing that really stood out was the approach he took to continually reworking the code base to keep it healthy, an approach that went under the then-unknown name of &quot;Refactoring&quot;. In my other consulting work I stressed how valuable a technique this is, but couldn't point people to a book to learn about it, so I ended up writing it myself. It was published just before the 20th Century ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's nearly twenty years ago, and the technique is now more widely known, although often not executed as well as it should be. The book has also held up pretty well, and I think you can take this old book and still learn how to refactor pretty much as well as you could all those years ago. But the book shows its age, with wrinkles like the use of &lt;code&gt;java.util.Vector&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So over the years I've been thinking about revising it, but I have also been reluctant. After all it still teaches the technique perfectly well, and second editions have a horrible habit of not improving on the original. But a further force has been tugging at me. At the time I wrote it, it was becoming mainstream to consider classes as the dominant structuring the mechanism for code. These days, however, we see other structures playing a greater role. Classes still are valuable, in my view, but our refactoring needs to be less centered around them, realizing that they can come and go as code is trained into new shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During 2015 and early 2016 I wrote a series of essays exploring various circumstances for refactoring, this helped me get a feel for if I should tackle a rewrite, and if so, how. By mid 2016 I was ready to commence the work in anger. If you've been wondering why I haven't been writing as much for martinfowler.com as I used to, it was because my writing energy has been focused on the book since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;changes&quot; readability=&quot;65.748969889065&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Changes in the Second Edition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changes are both very minor and all-encompassing. They are minor because the basic structure of the book hasn't changed. I begin with an opening example, a chapter of principles, a survey of &quot;code smells&quot;, and an introduction to testing. The bulk of the book is a catalog of refactorings and of those 68 refactorings, all but 10 are still present, and I've added 17 new ones. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/articles/refactoring-2nd-changes.html&quot;&gt;details here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this lack of change in the overall book structure, the changes to the words on pages is huge. Every chapter and refactoring has been rewritten, mostly from near scratch. I rarely had decent opportunities to cut and paste text from the old edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reorientation towards a less class-centered view is a large part of this. Although that may sound as simple as changing the name of &quot;Extract Method&quot; to &quot;Extract Function&quot;, it did entail rethinking all aspects of every refactoring. I needed to reconsider the motivation, often feeling that it needed to be reframed. The mechanics needed at least a detailed review, often a complete rewrite. I wasn't keeping detailed notes on this, but my feel is that for every relatively simple import of an old refactoring, there were two that required a complete rethink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However there is another change, which in a way isn't that important, but is bound to get a lot of attention. The examples are no longer in Java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I choose a language for examples in my writing, I think primarily of the reader. I ask &quot;what language will help the most readers understand the concepts in the book?&quot; &lt;em&gt;Refactoring&lt;/em&gt; isn't a language specific book, its advice may have been explained with the help of examples in Java, but the refactorings apply to most languages. I picked Java because I felt the most people would be able to understand the code examples if they were written in Java. That was the case in 1997, but how about in 2017?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered using multiple languages, which would emphasize the language-neutral intent of the book. But I felt that would be more confusing for the reader, better to use a single language so they can get used to a consistent form of expression. So which one would be the most approachable to readers? Such a language needed to be widely popular, among the top half a dozen in language popularity surveys. It really helps to have a C-based syntax, since most programmers would recognize the basic code structure. Given that, two stood out. One was Java, still widely used and easy to understand. But I went for the alternative: JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing JavaScript was deeply ironic for me, as many readers may know, I'm not a fan of it. It has too many awkward edge cases and clunky idioms. ECMAScript 2015 (ES6) introduced a rather good class model, which makes many object-oriented refactorings much easier to express, but still has annoying holes that are built into the fabric of the language from its earliest days. But the compelling reason for choosing it over Java is that isn't wholly centered on classes. There are top-level functions, and use of first-class functions is common. This makes it much easier to show refactoring out of the context of classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;AWeb-firstBook&quot; readability=&quot;57&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Web-First Book&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world-wide web has made an enourmous impact on our society, particularly affecting how we gather information. When I wrote the first edition, most of the knowledge about software development was transferred through print. Now I gather most of my information online. This has presented a challenge for authors like myself, is there still a role for books, and what should they look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe there still is role for books like this, but they need to change. The value of a book is a large body of knowledge, put together in a cohesive fashion. In writing this book I need to gather together lots of refactorings, and organize them in a consistent and integrated manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that integrated whole is an abstract literary work that, while traditionally represented by a paper book, need not be in the future. Most of the book industry still sees the paper book as the primary representation, and while we've enthusiastically adopted ebooks, these are just electronic representations of an original work based on the notion of a paper book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this book, I'm exploring a different approach. I think of the canonical form of this book as the web site. The paper book is a selection of material from the web site, arranged in a manner that makes sense for print. It doesn't attempt to include all the refactorings in the canonical book, particularly since I may well add more refactorings to the canonical web book in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our intention is that when you buy a copy of Refactoring, 2nd Ed, you might buy it at a bookstore in its physical form, or online in any form. The most essential thing you get for your money is permanent access to the web site. You can read the physical book, and access the web site whenever you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raises a question of what role ebooks (such as epubs and kindle books) should play. There is a strong argument that they should contain all the information on the web site, after all physical size isn't a factor, and ebooks can be updated easily if I add new material. However the book industry doesn't think that way, they expect ebooks to have the same content as the physical books, so the ebook versions of refactoring will follow that principle, at least for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 18:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sz4kerto</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Second Edition of &quot;Refactoring&quot;</og:title>
<og:url>https://martinfowler.com/articles/refactoring-2nd-ed.html</og:url>
<og:description>I'm finishing a new edition of my Refactoring book. Here's details and periodic memos about my work.</og:description>
<og:image>https://martinfowler.com/books/refact2.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://martinfowler.com/articles/refactoring-2nd-ed.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>8K is now being broadcast in Japan</title>
<link>https://www.newsshooter.com/2018/12/01/8k-is-now-being-broadcast-in-japan/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.newsshooter.com/2018/12/01/8k-is-now-being-broadcast-in-japan/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Japanese broadcaster NHK today started broadcasting 8K on a permanent basis. NHK collectively refers to 4K / 8K as “Super Hi-Vision“, and with the 2020 Tokyo Olympic Games and the Paralympic Games not too far away, this is a major step in transitioning viewers to what the broadcaster is calling a “New era of full-scale super high vision”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-75347&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.30.21-PM-600x335.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.30.21-PM-600x335.png 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.30.21-PM-768x429.png 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.30.21-PM.png 775w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;NHK’s 8K (well it’s actually 7680 x 4320) broadcasts are now available on a daily basis on a special channel between the hours of 10 am and 10 pm. The picture quality of the broadcasts will be 16 x greater than that of HD, and audio will be delivered in 22.2 multi-channel.  NHK will be broadcasting in frame rates of 59.94, 60 and 120P.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-75349&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.34.36-PM-600x414.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;414&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.34.36-PM-600x414.png 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.34.36-PM-768x530.png 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.34.36-PM-1024x706.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is the current program schedule for 8K broadcasts by NHK in December (sorry it’s only available in Japanse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-75341&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.20.28-PM-600x192.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;192&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.20.28-PM-600x192.png 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.20.28-PM-768x246.png 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.20.28-PM-1024x328.png 1024w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.20.28-PM.png 1216w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, NHK only has a very limited number of programs in 8K that they are broadcasting. These programs will be shown multiple times during the period of one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-75348&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.33.21-PM-600x303.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;303&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.33.21-PM-600x303.png 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.33.21-PM-768x388.png 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.33.21-PM.png 953w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be able to watch 8K you not only need an 8K capable television but also a dedicated satellite dish to receive the transmissions. NHK also says that viewers may also need to replace receiving equipment such as boosters and distributor boxes. Currently in Japan to watch 4K material you only need a decoder box (these are around $800-$1000 USD). NHK’s 4K and 8K broadcasting is done with BS and 110 ° CS satellite broadcasting. At present, NHK has no concrete plans of 4K / 8K broadcasting by terrestrial digital broadcasting. These means a sizeable investment by the consumer will be required if they want to watch 8K material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-75344&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.22.18-PM-600x335.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.22.18-PM-600x335.png 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.22.18-PM-768x429.png 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.22.18-PM-1024x572.png 1024w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.22.18-PM.png 1045w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only 4 years ago that NHK successfully conducted an 8K image transmission test using the nation’s largest cable TV facility. In that same year, 2014, they showed vision shot using an 8K Super Hi-Vision camera with a frame frequency of 120Hz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-75345&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.22.45-PM-600x449.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.22.45-PM-600x449.png 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.22.45-PM-768x575.png 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.22.45-PM-1024x767.png 1024w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.22.45-PM.png 1059w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my TV here in Japan, I have been seeing more and more ads for NHK’s 8K broadcasting. You would think that most people in Japan would be watching 4K broadcasts or at least own a 4K capable TV, but that couldn’t be further from the truth. Most Japanese are still watching HD broadcasts on HD televisions. It’s somewhat strange that NHK is now pushing 8K, even though you still can only watch very limited content in 4K on their channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-75346&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.23.14-PM-600x366.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;366&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.23.14-PM-600x366.png 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.23.14-PM-768x468.png 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.23.14-PM-1024x624.png 1024w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-29-at-7.23.14-PM.png 1173w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8K TV’s are far and few between and models such as the 70″ SHARP LC-70X500 sell for ￥646,290 ($5705 USD) here in Japan. The cheapest 8K television you can currently buy in Japan is the 60″ SHARP 8T-C60AW1 which retails for ￥498,00 ($4395 USD).  I wouldn’t hold your breath waiting for 8K content to be broadcast in most other places in the world anytime soon. In the US, for example, the whole broadcasting infrastructure isn’t set up for 8K, and streaming services such as Netflix are solely focused on 4K at this point in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8K is being pushed hard&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-74821&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08714-600x401.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08714-600x401.jpg 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08714-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08714-1024x684.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8K technology was on display everywhere at the recent Interbee 2018 show in Japan. From 8K cameras to 8K displays, to 8K being sent over IP via a 5G phone network, everywhere you looked it was 8K. If that wasn’t enough, there were even companies showing 16K 120p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-74820&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1169-450x600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1169-450x600.jpg 450w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1169-768x1024.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With NHK broadcasting the Tokyo Olympics in 8K in 2020 there is a big push here in Japan to not only create 8K content but also make it available for consumers to watch.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-74813&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08696-600x401.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08696-600x401.jpg 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08696-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08696-1024x684.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will make or break 8K is just how easy it will be to watch for the average person. Whether or not the average consumer cares about 8K is largely irrelevant, at least here in Japan. It is coming one way or the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-74814&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08698-600x401.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08698-600x401.jpg 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08698-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08698-1024x684.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japanese government is keen to push 8K and the Interbee show, Astro Design were showcasing live 8K over IP broadcasts using 5G technology. Japanese telecommunications giant Docomo were also showing 8K content over their 5G network that is still in development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-74816&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08703-401x600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;401&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08703-401x600.jpg 401w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08703-768x1150.jpg 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08703-684x1024.jpg 684w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 401px) 100vw, 401px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching 8K material on your smartphone is probably a complete waste of time given how small the pixel density already is on most devices. Maybe we will start to see larger mobile devices such as the foldable Samsung concept phone, or higher resolution screens starting to appear over the next few years. I do, however, think that with the speed and bandwidth available over 5G that a lot of people will be using this technology and getting rid of their fixed internet lines. This means you could be watching 8K material on an 8K screen in your home, all being broadcast or sent over a 5G network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-74818&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08787-600x401.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08787-600x401.jpg 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08787-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08787-1024x684.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8K 120p encoding and playback were also popular at the show. Companies were using very large and very noisy systems to playback 8K 120p material on giant 8K displays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-74819&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08785-600x401.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08785-600x401.jpg 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08785-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08785-1024x684.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above you can see how they were doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-74817&quot; src=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08793-600x401.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08793-600x401.jpg 600w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08793-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08793-1024x684.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If 8K wasn’t enough, there were companies showing 16K 120p uncompressed playback on the showroom floor. Now there isn’t currently any such thing as a 16K display so most companies were either using 4 8K screens or 16 4K screens positioned together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether we like it or not, 8K is coming. Just how long it actually takes before anyone is actually watching 8K content in significant numbers will be interesting to see. I personally think, just like we have seen with 4K, 8K is going to be primarily for acquisition purposes, rather than for actual viewing or broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 17:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kungfudoi</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>8K is now being broadcast in Japan - Newsshooter</og:title>
<og:description>8K is now being broadcast in Japan. Japanese broadcaster NHK today started broadcasting 8K on a permanent basis. NHK collectively refers to 4K / 8K as</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.newsshooter.com/2018/12/01/8k-is-now-being-broadcast-in-japan/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.newsshooter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC08702-1024x684.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.newsshooter.com/2018/12/01/8k-is-now-being-broadcast-in-japan/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Psychology’s Replication Crisis Is Real</title>
<link>https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/11/psychologys-replication-crisis-real/576223/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/11/psychologys-replication-crisis-real/576223/</guid>
<description>&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-0&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, an international team of almost 200 psychologists has been trying to repeat a set of previously published experiments from its field, to see if it can get the same results. Despite its best efforts, the project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/8cd4r/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'0',r'None'&quot;&gt;called Many Labs 2&lt;/a&gt;, has only succeeded in 14 out of 28 cases. Six years ago, that might have been shocking. Now it comes as expected (if still somewhat disturbing) news.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In recent years, it has become painfully clear that psychology is facing a “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/news/replication-studies-bad-copy-1.10634&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'1',r'None'&quot;&gt;reproducibility crisis&lt;/a&gt;,” in which even famous, long-established phenomena—the stuff of textbooks and &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;TED&lt;/span&gt; Talks—might not be real. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/authors?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0029081&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'2',r'None'&quot;&gt;social priming&lt;/a&gt;, where &lt;a href=&quot;http://chronicle.com/article/Power-of-Suggestion/136907/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'3',r'None'&quot;&gt;subliminal exposures&lt;/a&gt; can influence our behavior. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/health_and_science/cover_story/2016/03/ego_depletion_an_influential_theory_in_psychology_may_have_just_been_debunked.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'4',r'None'&quot;&gt;ego depletion&lt;/a&gt;, the idea that we have a limited supply of willpower that can be exhausted. And the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/09/01/no-reason-to-smile-another-modern-psychology-classic-has-failed-to-replicate/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'5',r'None'&quot;&gt;facial-feedback hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;, which simply says that smiling makes us feel happier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One by one, researchers have tried to repeat the classic experiments behind these well-known effects—and failed. And whenever psychologists &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2015/08/psychology-studies-reliability-reproducability-nosek/402466/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'6',r'None'&quot;&gt;undertake large projects&lt;/a&gt;, like Many Labs 2, in which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/08/scientists-can-collectively-sense-which-psychology-studies-are-weak/568630/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'7',r'None'&quot;&gt;they replicate past experiments en masse&lt;/a&gt;, they typically succeed, on average, half of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-0&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2016/09/can-simple-tricks-mobilise-voters-and-help-students/499109/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'8',r'None'&quot;&gt;Read: A worrying trend for psychology’s “simple little tricks”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically enough, it seems that one of the most reliable findings in psychology is that only half of psychological studies can be successfully repeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That failure rate is especially galling, says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simine.com/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'9',r'None'&quot;&gt;Simine Vazire&lt;/a&gt; from the University of California at Davis, because the Many Labs 2 teams tried to replicate studies that had made a big splash and been highly cited. Psychologists “should admit we haven’t been producing results that are as robust as we’d hoped, or as we’d been advertising them to be in the media or to policy makers,” she says. “That might risk undermining our credibility in the short run, but denying this problem in the face of such strong evidence will do more damage in the long run.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many psychologists have blamed these replication failures on sloppy practices. Their peers, they say, are too willing to run small and statistically weak studies that throw up misleading fluke results, to &lt;a href=&quot;http://pss.sagepub.com/content/22/11/1359&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'10',r'None'&quot;&gt;futz around with the data&lt;/a&gt; until they get something interesting, or to only publish positive results while hiding negative ones in their file drawers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/03/psychology-crisis-whether-crisis/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'11',r'None'&quot;&gt;skeptics have argued&lt;/a&gt; that the misleadingly named “crisis” has more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/01/opinion/psychology-is-not-in-crisis.html?&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'12',r'None'&quot;&gt;mundane explanations&lt;/a&gt;. First, the replication attempts themselves might be too small. Second, the researchers involved might be incompetent, or lack the know-how to properly pull off the original experiments. Third, people vary, and two groups of scientists might end up with very different results if they do the same experiment on two different groups of volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Many Labs 2 project was specifically designed to address these criticisms. With 15,305 participants in total, the new experiments had, on average, 60 times as many volunteers as the studies they were attempting to replicate. The researchers involved worked with the scientists behind the original studies to vet and check every detail of the experiments beforehand. And they repeated those experiments many times over, with volunteers from 36 different countries, to see if the studies would replicate in some cultures and contexts but not others. “It’s been the biggest bear of a project,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2015/08/psychology-studies-reliability-reproducability-nosek/402466/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'13',r'None'&quot;&gt;Brian Nosek&lt;/a&gt; from the Center for Open Science, who helped to coordinate it. “It’s 28 papers’ worth of stuff in one.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the large sample sizes and the blessings of the original teams, the team failed to replicate half of the studies it focused on. It couldn’t, for example, show that people subconsciously exposed to the concept of heat were more likely to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hbs.edu/faculty/Pages/item.aspx?num=49507&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'14',r'None'&quot;&gt;believe in global warming&lt;/a&gt;, or that moral transgressions create a need for physical cleanliness &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lady_Macbeth_effect&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'15',r'None'&quot;&gt;in the style of Lady Macbeth&lt;/a&gt;, or that people who &lt;a href=&quot;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/6102/c15ba21e2a6cd1ea8c9af79ff144b8764d28.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'16',r'None'&quot;&gt;grow up with more siblings&lt;/a&gt; are more altruistic. And as in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/08/scientists-can-collectively-sense-which-psychology-studies-are-weak/568630/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'17',r'None'&quot;&gt;previous big projects&lt;/a&gt;, online bettors were surprisingly good at predicting beforehand which studies would ultimately replicate. Somehow, they could intuit which studies were reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/08/scientists-can-collectively-sense-which-psychology-studies-are-weak/568630/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'18',r'None'&quot;&gt;Read: Online bettors can sniff out weak psychology studies.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But other intuitions were less accurate. In 12 cases, the scientists behind the original studies suggested traits that the replicators should account for. They might, for example, only find the same results in women rather than men, or in people with certain personality traits. In almost every case, those suggested traits proved to be irrelevant. The results just weren’t that fickle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, Many Labs 2 “was explicitly designed to examine how much effects varied from place to place, from culture to culture,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gvsu.edu/psychology/katherine-katie-corker-254.htm&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'19',r'None'&quot;&gt;Katie Corker&lt;/a&gt;, the chair of the Society for the Improvement of Psychological Science. “And here’s the surprising result: The results do not show much variability at all.” If one of the participating teams successfully replicated a study, others did, too. If a study failed to replicate, it tended to fail everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth dwelling on this because it’s a serious blow to one of the most frequently cited criticisms of the “reproducibility crisis” rhetoric. Surely, skeptics argue, it’s a fantasy to expect studies to replicate everywhere. “There’s a massive deference to the sample,” Nosek says. “Your replication attempt failed? It must be because you did it in Ohio and I did it in Virginia, and people are different. But these results suggest that we can’t just wave those failures away very easily.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean that cultural differences in behavior are irrelevant. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://psych.wisc.edu/staff/miyamoto-yuri/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'20',r'None'&quot;&gt;Yuri Miyamoto&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Wisconsin at Madison notes in an accompanying commentary, “In the age of globalization, psychology has remained largely European [and] American.” Many researchers have noted that volunteers from Western, educated, industrialized, rich, and democratic countries—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.psych.ubc.ca/~henrich/pdfs/WeirdPeople.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'21',r'None'&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;WEIRD&lt;/span&gt; nations&lt;/a&gt;—are an unusual slice of humanity who think differently than those from other parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the majority of the Many Labs 2 experiments, the team found very few differences between &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;WEIRD&lt;/span&gt; volunteers and those from other countries. But Miyamoto notes that its analysis was a little crude—in considering “non-&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;WEIRD&lt;/span&gt; countries” together, it’s lumping together people from cultures as diverse as Mexico, Japan, and South Africa. “Cross-cultural research,” she writes, “must be informed with thorough analyses of each and all of the cultural contexts involved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2016/02/psychology-studies-replicate/468537/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'22',r'None'&quot;&gt;Read: Psychology’s replication crisis has a silver lining.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nosek agrees. He’d love to see big replication projects that include more volunteers from non-Western societies, or that try to check phenomena that you’d expect to vary considerably outside the &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;WEIRD&lt;/span&gt; bubble. “Do we need to assume that &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;WEirD&lt;/span&gt;ness matters as much as we think it does?” he asks. “We don’t have a good evidence base for that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.uoregon.edu/sanjay/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'23',r'None'&quot;&gt;Sanjay Srivastava&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Oregon says the lack of variation in Many Labs 2 is actually a positive thing. Sure, it suggests that the large number of failed replications really might be due to sloppy science. But it also hints that the fundamental business of psychology—creating careful lab experiments to study the tricky, slippery, complicated world of the human mind—works pretty well. “Outside the lab, real-world phenomena can and probably do vary by context,” he says. “But within our carefully designed studies and experiments, the results are not chaotic or unpredictable. That means we &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do valid social-science research.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alternative would be much worse. If it turned out that people were so variable that even very close replications threw up entirely different results, “it would mean that we could not interpret our experiments, including the positive results, and could not count on them happening again,” Srivastava says. “That might allow us to dismiss failed replications, but it would require us to dismiss original studies, too. In the long run, Many Labs 2 is a much more hopeful and optimistic result.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;* &lt;em&gt;A mention of the marshmallow test was removed from an early paragraph, since the circumstances there differ from those of other failed replications.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;c-letters-cta&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;c-letters-cta__text&quot;&gt;We want to hear what you think about this article. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/contact/letters/&quot; class=&quot;c-letters-cta__link&quot;&gt;Submit a letter&lt;/a&gt; to the editor or write to letters@theatlantic.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;address id=&quot;article-writer-0&quot; class=&quot;c-article-writer lazyload&quot; data-author-id=&quot;7895&quot; data-include=&quot;css:https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/static/a/frontend/dist/theatlantic/css/components/article-writer.38f8b806e515.css&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/Person&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__image&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a class=&quot;o-media__object&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/ed-yong/&quot; title=&quot;Ed Yong's writer page&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-article-writer__img o-media__img&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/None/_R7A6312_1/200.jpg?mod=1522336431&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-article-writer__img o-media__img lazyload&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/None/_R7A6312_1/200.jpg?mod=1522336431&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__bio&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/ed-yong/&quot; class=&quot;author-link&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;Ed Yong&lt;/a&gt; is a staff writer at &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;, where he covers science.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__social&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;c-article-writer__social-link&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/edyong209&quot; itemprop=&quot;sameAs&quot; title=&quot;Ed Yong's Twitter Profile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c-article-writer__social-link-name&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;c-article-writer__social-link&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ed@theatlantic.com&quot; title=&quot;Email Ed Yong&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c-article-writer__social-link-name&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 15:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zwieback</dc:creator>
<og:title>Psychology’s Replication Crisis Is Running Out of Excuses</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/11/psychologys-replication-crisis-real/576223/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2018/11/RTR4FWVF/facebook.jpg?1542662255</og:image>
<og:description>Another big project has found that only half of studies can be repeated. And this time, the usual explanations fall flat.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/11/psychologys-replication-crisis-real/576223/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The EU Copyright Directive: What Redditors in Europe Need to Know</title>
<link>https://redditblog.com/2018/11/28/the-eu-copyright-directive-what-redditors-in-europe-need-to-know/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://redditblog.com/2018/11/28/the-eu-copyright-directive-what-redditors-in-europe-need-to-know/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Defending equal access to the free and open internet is core to Reddit’s ideals, and something that redditors have told us time and again they hold dear too, from the SOPA/PIPA battle to the fight for Net Neutrality. This is why even though we are an American company with a user base primarily in the United States, we’ve nevertheless spent a lot of time this year&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/announcements/comments/9epjue/meme_day_resurgence_the_eu_upload_filter_threat/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;warning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;about how an overbroad EU Copyright Directive could restrict Europeans’ equal access to the open Internet—and to Reddit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Despite these warnings, it seems that EU lawmakers still don’t fully appreciate  the law’s potential impact, especially on small and medium-sized companies like Reddit. So we’re stepping things up to draw attention to the problem. Users in the EU will notice that when they access Reddit via desktop, they are greeted by a modal informing them about the Copyright Directive and referring them to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontwreckthe.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;detailed resources on proposed fixes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The problem with the Directive lies in Articles 11 (link licensing fees) and 13 (copyright filter requirements), which set sweeping, vague requirements that create enormous liability for platforms like ours. These requirements eliminate the previous safe harbors that allowed us the leeway to give users the benefit of the doubt when they shared content. But under the new Directive, activity that is core to Reddit, like sharing links to news articles, or the use of existing content for creative new purposes (r/photoshopbattles, anyone?) would suddenly become questionable under the law, and it is not clear right now that there are feasible mitigating actions that we could take while preserving core site functionality. Even worse, smaller but similar attempts in various countries in Europe in the past have shown that&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontwreckthe.net/#concerns&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;such efforts have actually harmed publishers and creators&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Accordingly, we hope that today’s action will drive the point home that there are grave problems with Articles 11 and 13, and that the current trilogue negotiations will choose to remove both entirely. Barring that, however, we have a number of suggestions for ways to improve both proposals. Engine and the Copia Institute have compiled them&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontwreckthe.net/#fixes&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://dontwreckthe.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;https://dontwreckthe.net/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. We hope you will read them and consider calling your Member of European Parliament (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/meps/en/home&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;look yours up here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;). We also hope that EU lawmakers will listen to those who use and understand the internet the most, and reconsider these problematic articles. Protecting rights holders need not come at the cost of silencing European internet users.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;22425&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://redditblog.com/2018/11/28/the-eu-copyright-directive-what-redditors-in-europe-need-to-know/bgsnoos2x-1/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://redditupvoted.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/bgsnoos2x-1.png?w=720&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;316,152&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;bgSnoos@2x (1)&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://redditupvoted.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/bgsnoos2x-1.png?w=720?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://redditupvoted.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/bgsnoos2x-1.png?w=720?w=316&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-22425&quot; src=&quot;https://redditupvoted.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/bgsnoos2x-1.png?w=720&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://redditupvoted.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/bgsnoos2x-1.png 316w, https://redditupvoted.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/bgsnoos2x-1.png?w=150 150w, https://redditupvoted.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/bgsnoos2x-1.png?w=300 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 316px) 100vw, 316px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Don’t let the EU Copyright Directive silence European redditors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DyslexicAtheist</dc:creator>
<og:title>The EU Copyright Directive</og:title>
<og:description>Defending equal access to the free and open internet is core to Reddit’s ideals, and something that redditors have told us time and again they hold dear too, from the SOPA/PIPA battle to the fight for Net Neutrality. This is why even though we are an American compan</og:description>
<og:image>https://redditupvoted.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/hero-office-snoo.png?w=600&amp;h=315&amp;crop=1</og:image>
<og:url>https://redditblog.com/2018/11/28/the-eu-copyright-directive-what-redditors-in-europe-need-to-know/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://redditblog.com/2018/11/28/the-eu-copyright-directive-what-redditors-in-europe-need-to-know/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Cross-platform open-source 3D modeling software</title>
<link>https://dust3d.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://dust3d.org/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dust3d.org/&quot;&gt;https://dust3d.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18576117&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18576117&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 274&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 83&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 09:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>huxingyi</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://dust3d.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“I didn’t meet my girlfriend until 12 years after our daughter was born”</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/28/style/modern-love-how-i-met-my-children.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/28/style/modern-love-how-i-met-my-children.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;I didn’t meet my girlfriend, Jessica, until 12 years after our daughter, Alice, was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Let me explain. Nearly 25 years ago, I returned from a year of teaching English abroad, moved in with my mother and, lacking prospects, began driving a cab. One day I saw a newspaper ad seeking healthy men, 18 to 35, to participate in a semen donation program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Donors” is the standard industry word, yet virtually all of us are paid. Forty dollars a pop was what I received in 1994.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;I applied to sell my sperm and sold twice weekly for a year. At the time I was in a long-distance relationship, so this seemed like a good outlet. When I told my mother, she presciently wondered aloud if this was the only way she was going to have grandchildren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Today, sperm buyers view detailed profiles for potential vendors, whereas I wasn’t asked to provide much beyond college major, hobbies and family health history. Jessica and her partner at the time chose me primarily because I was a writer and musician.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;After a year of selling my sperm, I went back to giving it away and largely forgot about the whole thing. Occasionally the subject of whether I had children would come up, and I’d make a joke about probably having a bunch. I had signed a nondisclosure waiver and assumed there would never be a way for my progeny and me to find one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Then the internet happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In the early 2000s, I searched online for a way to find my offspring and discovered the Donor Sibling Registry but didn’t see any leads there and never got around to checking back. (I had looked way too early: My progeny began to use the site to find each other when they became teenagers in the 2010s.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A couple of years ago I began seeing ads for 23andMe, a service that analyzes your saliva — you spit in a test tube and mail it off for analysis — and provides you with information about ancestry, health and DNA relatives. The opportunity was obvious, but I assumed the odds of finding my children were low. I procrastinated for months before curiosity and an urge to know them made me order a kit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;I got my results back, and boom: I had a son, Bryce. His full name was unusual enough that I easily Googled him, and the picture resembled me enough that I felt confident this senior geography major was mine (mine?). Guessing he had been notified of my existence by 23andMe, I mulled in agitation for a week before finally putting fingers to keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Dear Bryce,” I wrote. “I recently joined 23andMe and found you listed as my ‘son,’ so I believe myself to be your biological father. I hope my existence isn’t a shock and wonder whether you joined in hopes of connecting with me.” My letter continued awkwardly from there, giving him a brief sketch of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Bryce replied almost instantly: “Dad, I cannot express how excited I am to be hearing from you. I did join 23andMe hoping that you would have already done so and was upset to see you hadn’t. This is amazing though and I’m so happy. I’m one of six of your children that I’m aware of and in contact with. I’m 20 years old and live on Long Island but I’m studying in upstate New York.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Dad?” I was briefly concerned that Bryce might have some fatherly expectations of me and show up on my doorstep, but my worries were unfounded. It’s a brave new world, and we’re all struggling with the terminology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;More important, six children? Yikes! I did some napkin math based on the number of samples I provided and the odds of conception and estimated that I may have as many as 67 children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Bryce connected me with Madalyn, 19. Upon viewing her Facebook page, I had my first parental thought ever: My daughter should put some more clothes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;I may be biased, but I found my children to be ridiculously attractive. I felt a sudden need to share their photos with all the ex-girlfriends who chose not to marry and procreate with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A few months later a new DNA relative appeared on 23andMe: Alice, age 11. Her mother, Jessica, wrote me a note. She and her former partner had each given birth to one daughter conceived with my sperm. They broke up years ago but had been raising both girls together until recently, when the other mother moved away with the daughter she had given birth to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Jess and I began to chat online. She knew a lot about buying sperm and self-impregnating, which was fascinating for me to learn, and, it turns out, more difficult than my role: masturbating into a cup. She also no longer identified as lesbian and was dating a man who, incredibly, had my same first and middle names (Aaron David), with a similar, monosyllabic last name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Had there been a mix-up at the Bureau of Boyfriends? Was I the one who was supposed to be dating her?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;My children and I exchanged written biographies. Bryce’s showed me how little I know of young adult culture and reminded me that one’s 20s are a difficult decade. Madi’s revealed a keen understanding of her upbringing and the parts of it she would like to break from. But it was Alice’s, entitled “A series of awkward events separated by snacks,” that floored me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Hers was a hodgepodge of lists and memories written under duress (“Mom: Write or death!”). Favorite color: “Black. Like my soul.” Favorite holiday: “Halloween (because candy and murder).” She liked Alfred Hitchcock films. “Basically,” she wrote, “I’m an angsty teen in a child’s body.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;This kid’s 11?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A plan developed for Bryce and Madi to come to Seattle for a couple of weeks in the summer. Jess and Alice lived a few hours south and would drive up. I figured meeting my children was going to be the closest thing I’d ever have to a wedding, so I decided to host a party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;I had told my news to a few people, but most learned of it from the “Meet My Kids Party” Facebook invitation, featuring photos of Bryce, Madi and Alice. The shock value was high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Be it genetics, good luck or force of circumstance, I loved my children right away. They have an uncanny aura of me-ness. Bryce is shy but sharp and obsessed with memes in a way I might have been had I grown up Gen Z. Alice has little use for adults, as I still don’t. Madi, especially, has my sense of humor and eyes: Locking gazes with her makes my brain explode, but then we laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At the party, we played a nature-versus-nurture question-and-answer game and discovered we were all quite liberal and that none of us believed in God. None of them, however, sleeps with a pillow between their knees, as I have long done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The first time Jess and I found ourselves alone we hugged at length in a way entirely inappropriate for people who had just met. Jess says I have mannerisms that remind her of both of her daughters and thus felt instantly comfortable with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Whether we were pawns of fate or unwitting participants in a chromosomally arranged marriage, Jess and I quickly bonded. I deployed my Bureau of Boyfriends mix-up line to a grudging but sweet reception. During the vacation, she and I fell easily into the mom-and-dad role for Bryce, Madi and Alice. We soon had in-jokes and teased each other about our foibles, just like any family. I even gave Bryce and Madi a lecture about smoking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1ur45q4 e5d2tgl3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1ukm2ij e5d2tgl0&quot;&gt;Related Modern Love essays&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-15g2oxy e5d2tgl2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-egqive ezm5mny6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme ezm5mny4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1u39xnq ezm5mny2&quot;&gt;I Made Him What He Is, but Who Is He?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1yil5bp eqgapgq0&quot; datetime=&quot;2007-07-29&quot;&gt;July 29, 2007&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr ezm5mny0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2007/07/29/fashion/29loveCA01ready/29loveCA01ready-threeByTwoSmallAt2X-v3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 ezm5mny1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-egqive ezm5mny6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme ezm5mny4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1u39xnq ezm5mny2&quot;&gt;A Wallet-Size Photo, a Father’s Double Life&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1yil5bp eqgapgq0&quot; datetime=&quot;2010-04-02&quot;&gt;April 2, 2010&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr ezm5mny0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2010/04/04/fashion/04love-1/04love-1-threeByTwoSmallAt2X-v3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 ezm5mny1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At the end of the visit, Bryce somehow managed to get Jess and Alice kicked out of the house they were renting by climbing onto the roof to retrieve a toy, so I invited them to stay with me while they figured things out. What Jess soon figured out was that she wanted to keep staying with me. Alice rolled her eyes as if she had been tricked into a traditional family arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;While 23andMe is not generally considered a dating site, Jess and I are grateful to the technology that has made our backward-formed relationship possible. We have a lot of questions about love and genetics and whether we would have felt this connection had we met in a more conventional way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Our bond has survived the “How cool is this?” phase, though we still enjoy cybermonitoring my other progeny and speculating about how many more may emerge. (I’m up to 10 now; I have had some contact with the new ones’ mothers but haven’t made plans to meet yet.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Madi liked the West Coast and us and recently moved into our place. We’re hoping to lure Bryce back, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In the end, the sci-fi trappings of our love story are irrelevant: Jess and I work as a couple because we like spending time together. I suppose it doesn’t hurt that I happen to be the father of her child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;css-11q3cgf ewiwup50&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1psfkbx e1kwarht0&quot;&gt;Aaron Long is a writer in Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1psfkbx e1kwarht0&quot;&gt;Modern Love can be reached at &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;mailto:modernlove@nytimes.com&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;modernlove@nytimes.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1psfkbx e1kwarht0&quot;&gt;To hear Modern Love: The Podcast, subscribe on &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/modern-love/id1065559535?mt=2&amp;amp;version=meter+at+0&amp;amp;module=meter-Links&amp;amp;pgtype=article&amp;amp;contentId=&amp;amp;mediaId=&amp;amp;referrer=&amp;amp;priority=true&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=meter-links-click&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen?u=0#/ps/Iktqjbkz7bychbnofblw32dik64&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;. To read past Modern Love columns, click &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/column/modern-love&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Continue following our fashion and lifestyle coverage on Facebook (&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/nytimesstyles&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Styles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/modernlove&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Modern Love&lt;/a&gt;), Twitter (&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nytstyles&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Styles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nytfashion&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fashion&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nytimesvows&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Weddings&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://instagram.com/nytimesfashion&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 03:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>I-M-S</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/28/style/modern-love-how-i-met-my-children.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>First I Met My Children, Then My Girlfriend. They’re Related.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/09/30/fashion/30MODERNLOVE/30MODERNLOVE-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>A former sperm donor, searching online, finds both offspring and love.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/28/style/modern-love-how-i-met-my-children.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why is 2 * (i * i) faster than 2 * i * i in Java?</title>
<link>https://stackoverflow.com/questions/53452713/why-is-2-i-i-faster-than-2-i-i-in-java</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stackoverflow.com/questions/53452713/why-is-2-i-i-faster-than-2-i-i-in-java</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There is a slight difference in the ordering of the bytecode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;2 * (i * i)&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;     iconst_2
     iload0
     iload0
     imul
     imul
     iadd
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;vs &lt;code&gt;2 * i * i&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;     iconst_2
     iload0
     imul
     iload0
     imul
     iadd
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first sight this should not make a difference; if anything the second version is more optimal since it uses one slot less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we need to dig deeper into the lower level (JIT)&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that JIT tends to unroll small loops very aggressively. Indeed we observe a 16x unrolling for the &lt;code&gt;2 * (i * i)&lt;/code&gt; case:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;030   B2: # B2 B3 &amp;lt;- B1 B2  Loop: B2-B2 inner main of N18 Freq: 1e+006
030     addl    R11, RBP    # int
033     movl    RBP, R13    # spill
036     addl    RBP, #14    # int
039     imull   RBP, RBP    # int
03c     movl    R9, R13 # spill
03f     addl    R9, #13 # int
043     imull   R9, R9  # int
047     sall    RBP, #1
049     sall    R9, #1
04c     movl    R8, R13 # spill
04f     addl    R8, #15 # int
053     movl    R10, R8 # spill
056     movdl   XMM1, R8    # spill
05b     imull   R10, R8 # int
05f     movl    R8, R13 # spill
062     addl    R8, #12 # int
066     imull   R8, R8  # int
06a     sall    R10, #1
06d     movl    [rsp + #32], R10    # spill
072     sall    R8, #1
075     movl    RBX, R13    # spill
078     addl    RBX, #11    # int
07b     imull   RBX, RBX    # int
07e     movl    RCX, R13    # spill
081     addl    RCX, #10    # int
084     imull   RCX, RCX    # int
087     sall    RBX, #1
089     sall    RCX, #1
08b     movl    RDX, R13    # spill
08e     addl    RDX, #8 # int
091     imull   RDX, RDX    # int
094     movl    RDI, R13    # spill
097     addl    RDI, #7 # int
09a     imull   RDI, RDI    # int
09d     sall    RDX, #1
09f     sall    RDI, #1
0a1     movl    RAX, R13    # spill
0a4     addl    RAX, #6 # int
0a7     imull   RAX, RAX    # int
0aa     movl    RSI, R13    # spill
0ad     addl    RSI, #4 # int
0b0     imull   RSI, RSI    # int
0b3     sall    RAX, #1
0b5     sall    RSI, #1
0b7     movl    R10, R13    # spill
0ba     addl    R10, #2 # int
0be     imull   R10, R10    # int
0c2     movl    R14, R13    # spill
0c5     incl    R14 # int
0c8     imull   R14, R14    # int
0cc     sall    R10, #1
0cf     sall    R14, #1
0d2     addl    R14, R11    # int
0d5     addl    R14, R10    # int
0d8     movl    R10, R13    # spill
0db     addl    R10, #3 # int
0df     imull   R10, R10    # int
0e3     movl    R11, R13    # spill
0e6     addl    R11, #5 # int
0ea     imull   R11, R11    # int
0ee     sall    R10, #1
0f1     addl    R10, R14    # int
0f4     addl    R10, RSI    # int
0f7     sall    R11, #1
0fa     addl    R11, R10    # int
0fd     addl    R11, RAX    # int
100     addl    R11, RDI    # int
103     addl    R11, RDX    # int
106     movl    R10, R13    # spill
109     addl    R10, #9 # int
10d     imull   R10, R10    # int
111     sall    R10, #1
114     addl    R10, R11    # int
117     addl    R10, RCX    # int
11a     addl    R10, RBX    # int
11d     addl    R10, R8 # int
120     addl    R9, R10 # int
123     addl    RBP, R9 # int
126     addl    RBP, [RSP + #32 (32-bit)]   # int
12a     addl    R13, #16    # int
12e     movl    R11, R13    # spill
131     imull   R11, R13    # int
135     sall    R11, #1
138     cmpl    R13, #999999985
13f     jl     B2   # loop end  P=1.000000 C=6554623.000000
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see that there is 1 register that is &quot;spilled&quot; onto the stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for the &lt;code&gt;2 * i * i&lt;/code&gt; version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;05a   B3: # B2 B4 &amp;lt;- B1 B2  Loop: B3-B2 inner main of N18 Freq: 1e+006
05a     addl    RBX, R11    # int
05d     movl    [rsp + #32], RBX    # spill
061     movl    R11, R8 # spill
064     addl    R11, #15    # int
068     movl    [rsp + #36], R11    # spill
06d     movl    R11, R8 # spill
070     addl    R11, #14    # int
074     movl    R10, R9 # spill
077     addl    R10, #16    # int
07b     movdl   XMM2, R10   # spill
080     movl    RCX, R9 # spill
083     addl    RCX, #14    # int
086     movdl   XMM1, RCX   # spill
08a     movl    R10, R9 # spill
08d     addl    R10, #12    # int
091     movdl   XMM4, R10   # spill
096     movl    RCX, R9 # spill
099     addl    RCX, #10    # int
09c     movdl   XMM6, RCX   # spill
0a0     movl    RBX, R9 # spill
0a3     addl    RBX, #8 # int
0a6     movl    RCX, R9 # spill
0a9     addl    RCX, #6 # int
0ac     movl    RDX, R9 # spill
0af     addl    RDX, #4 # int
0b2     addl    R9, #2  # int
0b6     movl    R10, R14    # spill
0b9     addl    R10, #22    # int
0bd     movdl   XMM3, R10   # spill
0c2     movl    RDI, R14    # spill
0c5     addl    RDI, #20    # int
0c8     movl    RAX, R14    # spill
0cb     addl    RAX, #32    # int
0ce     movl    RSI, R14    # spill
0d1     addl    RSI, #18    # int
0d4     movl    R13, R14    # spill
0d7     addl    R13, #24    # int
0db     movl    R10, R14    # spill
0de     addl    R10, #26    # int
0e2     movl    [rsp + #40], R10    # spill
0e7     movl    RBP, R14    # spill
0ea     addl    RBP, #28    # int
0ed     imull   RBP, R11    # int
0f1     addl    R14, #30    # int
0f5     imull   R14, [RSP + #36 (32-bit)]   # int
0fb     movl    R10, R8 # spill
0fe     addl    R10, #11    # int
102     movdl   R11, XMM3   # spill
107     imull   R11, R10    # int
10b     movl    [rsp + #44], R11    # spill
110     movl    R10, R8 # spill
113     addl    R10, #10    # int
117     imull   RDI, R10    # int
11b     movl    R11, R8 # spill
11e     addl    R11, #8 # int
122     movdl   R10, XMM2   # spill
127     imull   R10, R11    # int
12b     movl    [rsp + #48], R10    # spill
130     movl    R10, R8 # spill
133     addl    R10, #7 # int
137     movdl   R11, XMM1   # spill
13c     imull   R11, R10    # int
140     movl    [rsp + #52], R11    # spill
145     movl    R11, R8 # spill
148     addl    R11, #6 # int
14c     movdl   R10, XMM4   # spill
151     imull   R10, R11    # int
155     movl    [rsp + #56], R10    # spill
15a     movl    R10, R8 # spill
15d     addl    R10, #5 # int
161     movdl   R11, XMM6   # spill
166     imull   R11, R10    # int
16a     movl    [rsp + #60], R11    # spill
16f     movl    R11, R8 # spill
172     addl    R11, #4 # int
176     imull   RBX, R11    # int
17a     movl    R11, R8 # spill
17d     addl    R11, #3 # int
181     imull   RCX, R11    # int
185     movl    R10, R8 # spill
188     addl    R10, #2 # int
18c     imull   RDX, R10    # int
190     movl    R11, R8 # spill
193     incl    R11 # int
196     imull   R9, R11 # int
19a     addl    R9, [RSP + #32 (32-bit)]    # int
19f     addl    R9, RDX # int
1a2     addl    R9, RCX # int
1a5     addl    R9, RBX # int
1a8     addl    R9, [RSP + #60 (32-bit)]    # int
1ad     addl    R9, [RSP + #56 (32-bit)]    # int
1b2     addl    R9, [RSP + #52 (32-bit)]    # int
1b7     addl    R9, [RSP + #48 (32-bit)]    # int
1bc     movl    R10, R8 # spill
1bf     addl    R10, #9 # int
1c3     imull   R10, RSI    # int
1c7     addl    R10, R9 # int
1ca     addl    R10, RDI    # int
1cd     addl    R10, [RSP + #44 (32-bit)]   # int
1d2     movl    R11, R8 # spill
1d5     addl    R11, #12    # int
1d9     imull   R13, R11    # int
1dd     addl    R13, R10    # int
1e0     movl    R10, R8 # spill
1e3     addl    R10, #13    # int
1e7     imull   R10, [RSP + #40 (32-bit)]   # int
1ed     addl    R10, R13    # int
1f0     addl    RBP, R10    # int
1f3     addl    R14, RBP    # int
1f6     movl    R10, R8 # spill
1f9     addl    R10, #16    # int
1fd     cmpl    R10, #999999985
204     jl     B2   # loop end  P=1.000000 C=7419903.000000
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we observe much more &quot;spilling&quot; and more accesses to the stack &lt;code&gt;[RSP + ...]&lt;/code&gt;, due to more intermediate results that need to be preserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the answer to the question is simple: &lt;code&gt;2 * (i * i)&lt;/code&gt; is faster than &lt;code&gt;2 * i * i&lt;/code&gt; because the JIT generates more optimal assembly code for the first case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;But of course it is obvious that neither the first nor the second version is any good; the loop could really benefit from vectorization, since any x86-64 CPU has at least SSE2 support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it's an issue of the optimizer; as is often the case, it unrolls too aggressively and shoots itself in the foot, all the while missing out on various other opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, modern x86-64 CPUs break down the instructions further into micro-ops (µops) and with features like register renaming, µop caches and loop buffers, loop optimization takes a lot more finesse than a simple unrolling for optimal performance. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.agner.org/optimize/microarchitecture.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;According to Agner Fog's optimization guide&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gain in performance due to the µop cache can be quite considerable if the average instruction length is more than 4 bytes. The following methods of optimizing the use of the µop cache may be considered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make sure that critical loops are small enough to fit into the µop cache.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align the most critical loop entries and function entries by 32.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid unnecessary loop unrolling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid instructions that have extra load time&lt;br/&gt;. . .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding those load times - &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/4087280/approximate-cost-to-access-various-caches-and-main-memory&quot;&gt;even the fastest L1D hit costs 4 cycles&lt;/a&gt;, an extra register and µop, so yes, even a few accesses to memory will hurt performance in tight loops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But back to the vectorization opportunity - to see how fast it can be, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gcc.godbolt.org/z/DdEDny&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;we can compile a similar C application with GCC&lt;/a&gt;, which outright vectorizes it (AVX2 is shown, SSE2 is similar)&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;  vmovdqa ymm0, YMMWORD PTR .LC0[rip]
  vmovdqa ymm3, YMMWORD PTR .LC1[rip]
  xor eax, eax
  vpxor xmm2, xmm2, xmm2
.L2:
  vpmulld ymm1, ymm0, ymm0
  inc eax
  vpaddd ymm0, ymm0, ymm3
  vpslld ymm1, ymm1, 1
  vpaddd ymm2, ymm2, ymm1
  cmp eax, 125000000      ; 8 calculations per iteration
  jne .L2
  vmovdqa xmm0, xmm2
  vextracti128 xmm2, ymm2, 1
  vpaddd xmm2, xmm0, xmm2
  vpsrldq xmm0, xmm2, 8
  vpaddd xmm0, xmm2, xmm0
  vpsrldq xmm1, xmm0, 4
  vpaddd xmm0, xmm0, xmm1
  vmovd eax, xmm0
  vzeroupper
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With run times:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;SSE: 0.24 s, or 2 times faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AVX: 0.15 s, or 3 times faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AVX2: 0.08 s, or 5 times faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;To get JIT generated assembly output, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ojdkbuild/ojdkbuild/releases&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;get a debug JVM&lt;/a&gt; and run with &lt;code&gt;-XX:+PrintOptoAssembly&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;The C version is compiled with the &lt;code&gt;-fwrapv&lt;/code&gt; flag, which enables GCC to treat signed integer overflow as a two's-complement wrap-around.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 22:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>trequartista</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://stackoverflow.com/questions/53452713/why-is-2-i-i-faster-than-2-i-i-in-java</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.sstatic.net/Sites/stackoverflow/img/apple-touch-icon@2.png?v=73d79a89bded</og:image>
<og:title>Why is 2 * (i * i) faster than 2 * i * i in Java?</og:title>
<og:description>The following Java program takes on average between 0.50s and 0.55s to run: public static void main(String[] args) { long startTime = System.nanoTime(); int n = 0; for (int i = 0; i &amp;lt;</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stackoverflow.com/questions/53452713/why-is-2-i-i-faster-than-2-i-i-in-java</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Source: Google Hangouts for consumers will be shutting down sometime in 2020</title>
<link>https://9to5google.com/2018/11/30/google-hangouts-shutting-down/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://9to5google.com/2018/11/30/google-hangouts-shutting-down/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;According to source familiar with the product’s internal roadmap, Google Hangouts for consumers will be shutting down sometime in 2020. That’s not surprising at all since Google essentially ceased development on the app &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2017/03/28/hangouts-18-rolling-out-now-prepares-the-app-to-remove-sms-functionality-apk-teardown/&quot;&gt;more than a year ago&lt;/a&gt;. But just know, going into 2019, this is indeed your last year to keep using the beloved (?) legacy chat app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-259532&quot;/&gt; &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle author_ad&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-1173302821141403&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2047467560&quot;/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nd4ed8a147 nd72fecf67&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nde6824f04&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; class=&quot;nd38258415&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ndf7bd47d5 nd1681a742&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nde6824f04&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; class=&quot;nd38258415&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ndc477742e ndbd5e61e6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nde6824f04&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; class=&quot;nd38258415&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ndcf0bd896 nd841ef940&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nde6824f04&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nd2844116b ndee2bb031&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nde6824f04&quot; data-ndaeba9581=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/y7uehota&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2018/05/51txm4dnyhl.jpg?resize=300%2C250&amp;amp;quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Deal: Get Pixelbook at 25% off: $750!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ndba8a4a5f nd66f46fde&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nde6824f04&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; class=&quot;nd38258415&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ndf1c15e14 nd7485387f&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nde6824f04&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; class=&quot;nd38258415&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last spring, Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2017/03/09/google-hangouts-meet-chat-enterprise/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; its pivot for the Hangouts brand to enterprise use cases with Hangouts Chat and Hangouts Meet, so the writing has been on the wall for quite some time regarding the Hangouts consumer app’s demise. Meanwhile, Google has &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2018/04/19/google-rcs-chat/&quot;&gt;transitioned its consumer-facing messaging efforts to RCS ‘Chat’ and Android Messages&lt;/a&gt; following Allo’s misadventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given Google’s abandonment of the app in terms of development and its presumed eventual death, many have already transitioned away from using it. But Hangouts is still the prominent chat option in Gmail on the web and the app &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.talk&amp;amp;hl=en_US&quot;&gt;remains on the Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt; to this day. Many recent reviews say that the app is showing signs of age, noting bugs and performance issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, Hangouts as a brand will live on with G Suite’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://gsuite.google.com/products/chat/&quot;&gt;Hangouts Chat&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gsuite.google.com/products/meet/&quot;&gt;Hangouts Meet&lt;/a&gt;, the former intended to be a team communication app comparable to Slack, and the latter a video meetings platform. Meanwhile, Google Voice calling, which was at first independent and then long integrated into Hangouts, was &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2018/04/04/google-voice-voip-android-web-beta/&quot;&gt;moved back out&lt;/a&gt; to its &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2017/01/23/new-google-voice-redesign-android-ios-web-app/&quot;&gt;own redesigned app&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, despite its forthcoming axing, Hangouts was &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2018/11/29/android-auto-3-8-media-messaging-gallery/&quot;&gt;one of a few apps&lt;/a&gt; to get early support for Android Auto’s new MMS and &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2018/07/06/google-android-messages-rcs-chat-explained/&quot;&gt;RCS&lt;/a&gt; functionality, alongside Android Messages and WhatsApp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 12/1&lt;/strong&gt;: Google’s Scott Johnston has chimed in and denies that any decisions have been made about the timeline of legacy Hangouts’ shutdown. Confusingly, however, he says that users of consumer Hangouts users will be somehow “upgraded” to Hangouts Chat and Hangouts Meet, both being enterprise-focused products that fill different needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott also explicitly confirms for the first time that Hangouts Classic, the subject of this report, will be shutting down “eventually.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, a second source has since corroborated my initial report, and says decisions have indeed been made for the deprecation of legacy Hangouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/QgYfj03ADn&quot;&gt;https://t.co/QgYfj03ADn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hallstephenj?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@hallstephenj&lt;/a&gt;, I run Hangouts and this is pretty shoddy reporting. No decisions made about when Hangouts will be shut down. Hangouts users will be upgraded to Hangouts Chat and Hangouts Meet. Your source is severely misinformed. You can do better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Scott Johnston (@happyinwater) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/happyinwater/status/1068861340800958466?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 1, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;1/ I can't comment on your sourcing, since I don't have any details. The frustrating part about your reporting is it leaves the reader to jump to dramatic conclusions, because it is only half the story. Hangouts users will be migrated to Chat and Meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Scott Johnston (@happyinwater) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/happyinwater/status/1068871036979109891?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 1, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2/ So while that will result in the eventual shut down of Hangouts classic (as we now call it), it doesn't imply we are ending support for the use case supported by the product: messaging and meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Scott Johnston (@happyinwater) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/happyinwater/status/1068871880814268417?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 1, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;1/ I have immense respect for this team and their products; my report was not meant to disparage Hangouts Chat/Meet, which we have covered extensively since their announcement, nor to suggest that their use cases were going anywhere. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/3JtShmlIb6&quot;&gt;https://t.co/3JtShmlIb6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Stephen Hall (@hallstephenj) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hallstephenj/status/1068906634389479424?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 1, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9to5Google’s Take&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shutting down Hangouts has been a long time coming, so if anything, its retirement still being more than a year away is what’s surprising here. I’d venture to guess that its actual usage numbers are still significant given that Google’s initiative to build a true messaging alternative, Allo, flopped miserably. Meanwhile the ‘Chat’ RCS initiative that Google’s leading up &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2018/11/16/universal-profile-rcs-verizon-launch/&quot;&gt;still isn’t off the ground&lt;/a&gt;, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/9to5google?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out 9to5Google on YouTube for more news:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gqvSzvh_3S8?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 20:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>shaklee3</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>[Update: Google confirms shut down, denies timeline] 2019 is your last year to use Google Hangouts if you haven’t moved on already</og:title>
<og:url>https://9to5google.com/2018/12/01/google-hangouts-shutting-down/</og:url>
<og:description>According to source familiar with the product’s internal roadmap, Google Hangouts for consumers will be shutting down sometime in 2020. That’s not surprising at all since Google essenti…</og:description>
<og:image>https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2016/10/google_hangouts_2.jpg?quality=82&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1600</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://9to5google.com/2018/12/01/google-hangouts-shutting-down/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>