<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Gates foundation program will issue home testing kits for Covid 19 in Seattle</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/08/gates-foundation-backed-program-will-soon-be-issuing-home-testing-kits-for-covid-19-in-seattle/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/08/gates-foundation-backed-program-will-soon-be-issuing-home-testing-kits-for-covid-19-in-seattle/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;A project funded by the Gates Foundation will soon begin issuing at-home testing kits for the novel coronavirus, COVID-19, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/health/gates-funded-program-will-soon-offer-home-testing-kits-for-new-coronavirus/&quot;&gt;according to a report in the Seattle Times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study, based on a nose-swab should be able to return results in up to two days and will be shared with health officials who can then notify people who test positive. Individuals who have been infected will then be encouraged to answer an online questionnaire to give health officials information about their movements so that those officials can identify and notify other people who may need to be tested or quarantined, according to the Seattle Times report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Although there’s a lot to be worked out, this has enormous potential to turn the tide of the epidemic,” Scott Dowell, who leads the coronavirus response effort from the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation told the Seattle Times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no clear timeline for the project’s launch as the Foundation looks to finalize the supporting software and draft a final questionnaire for people who request the tests. The Foundation estimates that it could run up to 400 tests per-day, according to Dowell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gates Foundation isn’t the only entity moving quickly to develop at home test kits. In a Twitter thread on Saturday, serial healthcare entrepreneur Jonathan Rothenberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JMRothberg/status/1236289160253767681?s=20&quot;&gt;outlined a similar approach&lt;/a&gt;, and is apparently &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JMRothberg/status/1236457356529188864?s=20&quot;&gt;now in discussions with a manufacturer&lt;/a&gt; on how to bring it to market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seattle and the surrounding area has been the epicenter for the coronavirus outbreak in the U.S. The state has confirmed 71 cases and 15 deaths from the disease as of Saturday. At least one health expert estimates that Seattle could have as many as 600 cases, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trvrb/status/1235433402045583360&quot;&gt;based on computational modeling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One of the most important things from our perspective, having watched and worked on this in other parts of the world, is the identification of people who are positive for the virus, so they can be safely isolated and cared for, and the identification of their contacts, who can then be quarantined,” Dowell told the Seattle Times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project to do develop at-home testing evolved from a two-year-old research project from the &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/university-of-washington&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;university-of-washington&quot;&gt;University of Washington&lt;/a&gt; that was intended to track the spread of diseases like influenza, according to the Times reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All told, the Gates Foundation has poured about $20 million into the effort. The foundation has also committed $5 million to the local response efforts to combat the disease in the area — including the expansion of testing and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 22:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ajaviaad</dc:creator>
<og:title>Gates Foundation-backed program will soon be issuing home testing kits for COVID-19 in Seattle – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>A project funded by the Gates Foundation will soon begin issuing at-home testing kits for the novel coronavirus, COVID-19, according to a report in the Seattle Times. The study, based on a nose-swab should be able to return results in up to two days and will be shared with health officials who can …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1058017974.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2020/03/08/gates-foundation-backed-program-will-soon-be-issuing-home-testing-kits-for-covid-19-in-seattle/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/08/gates-foundation-backed-program-will-soon-be-issuing-home-testing-kits-for-covid-19-in-seattle/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How I survived being a $220k/year intern</title>
<link>https://matt.sh/commit-this</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://matt.sh/commit-this</guid>
<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;_or-3-years-as-a-senior-developer-who-wasnt-allowed-to-commit-any-code&quot;&gt;or, 3 Years as a Senior Developer Who Wasn’t Allowed To Commit Any Code&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;_or-i-passed-up-a-50000-severance-to-write-this&quot;&gt;or, I Passed Up a $50,000 Severance To Write This&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Previously: &lt;a href=&quot;https://matt.sh/anatomy-of-a-fraud&quot;&gt;Anatomy of Software Frauds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others in this series include, but are not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This page is an overview of Pivotal employment from 2013 to 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever have a job where things just aren’t right? Maybe you think the company is crooked. Maybe you think coworkers are only giving 10% while collecting 200% salaries. Maybe you can’t figure out how the company continues to exist when all you see is failure after failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my account of being employed as a Senior Software Engineer while only having the responsibilities of an intern at Pivotal from October 2013 to October 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked from home for three years with a $220,000 salary, traveled a total of six times, two SF, one Seattle, three to Europe, and contributed thousands of lines of features/fixes/optimizations to high profile projects, all the while never being granted responsibility greater than what you’d give a middle school intern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being treated oddly for a couple years, I tried to clarify with HR what was wrong. HR quickly, after first ignoring my request for six weeks, declared the company investigated itself, the company decided the company did no wrong, and also, just by the way, your position is now discontinued and will you please sign a severance release of non-disparagement. The severance wasn’t tempting enough, and they refused to negotiate beyond a token “how about one extra week.” So, I passed on their $50,000 severance bundle which included the typical “you must never say anything about what is wrong with this company” clause. No dice. hashtag silence breaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;_non-workings&quot;&gt;Non-Workings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did nothing work at this weirdo company? It comes down to three interleaving dysfunctions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;dysfunctional corporate management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dysfunctional processes defined by “management just does whatever they feel like”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dysfunctional egos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company teased self-valuations upwards of a billion dollars. Dozens of employees were taking home over a million dollars a year in sales commissions. At the same time, company stock was worthless for regular employees. At founding, the company allotted about 13% of company stock for employee ownership. The rest was allocated to corporate backers and shady “customers, but also investors, but also customers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s convenient having combo customer/investors. If quarterly numbers look bad, just ask your customers, who are also investors, to buy more services to prop up their own investment. After all, they wouldn’t want their investment decisions to look bad, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managers were trained to double down on rhetoric about how “every employee has ownership in this noble endeavor, so you should feel personally committed to go the extra mile even without pay.” Yeah, great, a percentage of a diluted percentage of a percentage of underwater options. I’ll get right on giving all I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company was in a nosedive from the beginning. It was founded from the dregs of other departments of other companies where nobody could extract value. The products were snake oil and executive goals pushed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/Reviews/Employee-Review-Pivotal-RVW5867976.htm&quot;&gt;sales above product stability&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, sales was such a priority, shady sales people would happily commit frauds of technical ignorance then just laugh all the way to the bank with their million dollar take-home-pay commissions while customers never received functionality they were promised. Don’t worry though, selling imaginary features is a problem addressed by never-ending support or high priced post-purchase pair-programming consulting engagement add-ons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point, sales people pushed imaginary made up “value prop” features (“unlimited scalability!” “zero downtime!” “infinite realtime deploys!” “auto healing mesh!”) when, in reality, the product could do about 4 changes per second without needing a global cluster reboot. This discrepancy caused some customers to refuse to pay recurring invoices on their multi-million dollar 5-year-deployment-schedule architectures from hell. Totally normal, right? Sales fraud leading to customers refusing to pay for contracted services happens every day. Nothing a few friendly panicked CEO-to-CEO calls can’t smooth over. After all, CEOs never lie. We know CEOs have superpowers to fix structurally incompetent software architectures overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While sales people were pulling down million dollar commissions, managers also had it made. Managers had a promotion treadmill they could idly sit on and increase their salary with no extra responsibility. Managers had extra bonus programs, special dispensation towards selling stock directly to The Holy Cult CEO (because they’d be underwater otherwise and daddy manager needs a new house for his irresponsibly growing family), yet employees actually creating the company’s products would get no promotions and inexcusable 1% yearly raises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Executives and PR also loved to brandish sales figures in public based on imagined future bookings instead of actual committed sales (VSOE? Topic 606? Who cares? It’s all marketing!). Executives and PR made sure to never mention &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cmswire.com/information-management/how-will-emcs-once-pivotal-ambitions-play-out/&quot;&gt;one-time consulting revenue versus product revenue&lt;/a&gt; even when the company was essentially a low margin &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5406384&quot;&gt;pair-programming agile body shop scam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire company had been a curious financial failure since the beginning, only propped up by unwarranted crony investments. They were founded to “compete with AWS” even though they had no hardware or hosting of their own, they were founded to “win hadoop,” when everybody was moving away from hadoop to more real time processing architectures, they were founded to “teach the world how to make software,” when they can’t even run their own internal designed-by-22-year-olds-and-run-by-19-year-olds ruby apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out, “win hadoop” resulted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crn.com/news/cloud/300074934/sources-pivotal-laying-off-60-employees-mostly-on-big-data-side-of-business.htm&quot;&gt;layoffs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.channele2e.com/software/big-data/pivotal-kills-hadoop-distribution-embraces-hortonworks/&quot;&gt;completely exiting the hadoop market&lt;/a&gt; even though the company promises it is the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; company capable of writing software in the entire world. If a Cult of Agile can’t even prop up their own lies for three years or score an exit outside of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizjournals.com/boston/blog/mass-high-tech/2012/03/emc-acquires-pivotal-labs-in-an-all-cash-deal.html&quot;&gt;selling bodyshops to senile executives&lt;/a&gt;, how can they possibly provide value to customers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry about the senile executives though. Turns out they are &lt;a href=&quot;http://money.cnn.com/2015/10/13/technology/joe-tucci-emc-pay/index.html&quot;&gt;well taken care of&lt;/a&gt; no matter what happens to the rest of the company. Misaligned incentives much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company was &lt;del&gt;founded&lt;/del&gt; formed in 2013 using failed products already in existence at other companies since 2009, but nobody noticed details like undeliverable vaporware when you’ve got sycophantic NYT coverage of your &lt;a href=&quot;https://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/04/24/pivotals-audacious-plan/&quot;&gt;billion-dollar-out-the-gate company launch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the beginning, executives kept saying the company was “IPO ready from day 1.” The &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2015/11/02/pivotal-ipo/&quot;&gt;huge lie&lt;/a&gt; kept getting &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2015/08/21/whats-next-for-pivotal/&quot;&gt;called on&lt;/a&gt; over the years. Employees started bailing en masse soon after the 8th all hands meeting where executives continued to treat any employee doubt or concern as irrelevant while espousing their own delusions of grandeur. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cmswire.com/information-management/how-will-emcs-once-pivotal-ambitions-play-out/&quot;&gt;The writing was on the wall&lt;/a&gt; and people started to run away as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two years, the CEO of this billion dollar &lt;em&gt;noble endeavor&lt;/em&gt; just up and left. When a CEO leaves two years in because he “reached retirement age,” that’s not a great confidence builder. If you were so close to retirement, why take on an &lt;em&gt;entirely new company?&lt;/em&gt; Maybe because you thought it would be an easy cash out—you didn’t think reality would strike and you’d be discovered for failure and fraud and inability to execute time and time again. That’s okay though, just hand off the company to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://zdnet2.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/2017/10/31/7ce4f8bc-6641-40c7-8d60-39227d4999ba/1ffe2fd79071f5550f8c623c4335d508/penn-mee-telstra-pivotal.jpg&quot;&gt;bloated, slovenly, zero-posture assistant&lt;/a&gt; whose name literally means “I’m going to rip you off.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…and that’s just the start. Where did it go from there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;_corporate-management&quot;&gt;Corporate “Management”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managerial instability is a great way to reduce employee confidence. Make sure each employee has a new manager at least once every 10 months. Make sure each manager has different ideas for how subordinates should behave towards management and towards the company itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 3 years my manager was replaced 5 times, each time in an entirely different department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Manager 1: October 2013 to June 2014
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Manager was from acquired startup, so he left at the end of his vesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since this manager was acquired and not directly hired in, he wasn’t part of the brainwashy personality cult of agile superiority as some of the later managers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manager 2: June 2014 to November 2014
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I was re-parented to manager’s manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manager 3: November 2014 to January 2016
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Manager 2 left, so I was placed in an unrelated department. Manager 3 was fairly hostile to work we were doing because our work was independent from the rest of the company and we didn’t have to interact with the company’s fraudulent goals at large.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manager 3 was also a True Believer in the Holy Mission of Agile Pair Programming and the Infallibility of CEO Directives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manager 3 eventually removed all recurring check-in meetings from my calendar and cut off contact with me for about a year. I literally got Milton’d from Office Space. Forgotten, but direct deposit kept working. My bright red Swingline stapler kept me company in those dark times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manager 4: January 2016 to April 2016
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Received an unexpected email saying “You’re being rotated.” What did that mean? I don’t speak weirdo agile cult language. Turns out they meant “You’re being assigned to a new team for X weeks.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This new team was basically “staff augmentation.” Staff Aug is where one company hires out a second company’s employees for day-to-day tasks. It’s basically extremely low value consulting where you’d place uneducated and unproductive nitwits for daily CRUD maintenance work or server babysitting. Oh, and this department was 80% travel too (Monday-Thursday out of state every week). Nope. Not part of my job description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manager 5: April 2016 to October 2016
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Received another unexpected email saying I was moving back under my under original department where all this started in 2013.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;_process-more-like-recess&quot;&gt;Process? More like Recess&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;_sales-support-software&quot;&gt;Sales, Support, Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My entire raison d’etre for being hired was to create a sales and support offering for an existing open source project the company was paying to develop. They wanted to do a typical licensing/warranty and support offering, but they needed proper sales parameters as well as someone to actually do the support (me!) and the technical presales calls (me!) and the technical sales presentations (me!) and customer architecture reviews (me!) and the bugfixes (me!) and the feature enhancements (me!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrangement was simple enough: company would basically sell “Open Source Support” on the product I worked on, then all support issues going directly back to me. During any support downtime, I’d work on the project itself. Almost makes you wonder why the company was needed here at all—they were basically reselling &lt;em&gt;Matt as a Service&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent my first few months creating training materials for front-line support and sales teams. I made sure our support site was the #1 Google result when searching for “[product X] support”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started getting fruitful inbound sales requests when my support site went live along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://content.pivotal.io/blog/pivotal-offering-redis-support-redis-2-8-0-now-available&quot;&gt;associated promotional pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Digression: All About Sales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“inbound” sales is like a grocery store. You walk in because you &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; something, you see they have pigeon meat for $3.99/kg, you accept their price, then you complete your economic transaction. Easy peasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“outbound” sales is the classic ‘steak-n-strippers’ treatment. outbound sales is cold calling. outbound sales is relationship building. outbound sales is the used car sales of enterprise software. If you’re operating in good faith, you help customers who can benefit from your product, but they just don’t know it yet. If you’re operating in bad faith, you’re running a scam on customers: instill FOMO, play ego games, get your CEO to tell their CEO they should buy your product without consulting any technical staff for feasibility studies (after all, the CEOs are on each other’s boards to do shady insider purchasing sales fluffing), tell them they’re getting in on the ground floor of the next &lt;em&gt;technology revolution&lt;/em&gt; and they must, immediately, begin &lt;em&gt;building software with a silicon valley state of mind&lt;/em&gt;, which of course only you can provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within a few weeks of launching the paid support service, we were getting half a dozen inbound requests every week. The requests were pretty basic because The Company refused to provide any public pricing (your typical sleazy company sales practice—how much does it cost? i dunno, how much you got?) A typical two week long six email exchange would go like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hi, what are your prices?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Thanks, where are you located?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why? I just want your prices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sales is regional, so we have to send you to the right region.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m in X”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“INTERNAL FWD: customer in X requests prices”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;customer is never contacted again&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most sales people didn’t want to engage with customers (and half out would outright refuse) to arrange support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a dozen inquiries just dropped on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sales people were on a major commission incentive to sell the company’s other high-margin, high-fraud, low-utility products, so they didn’t care about our one-off open source support offerings. Time spent closing one $20k to $200k open source deal would distract from their personal commissions on a $5 million cloudgasm deal. Selling $20k of yearly support doesn’t help you reach your goals for that tasty $1 million illegitimate take home commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can lead sales to a customer, but you can’t make them set up a webinar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;_people-dont-exist&quot;&gt;People don’t exist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one end, you have dozens of employees taking home over a million dollars a year in commissions plus executives with negotiated heads-i-win tails-you-lose bonus programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the other end, you have employees who create your products being treated like unwanted interns because development and engineering isn’t given recognition for generating revenue. Obviously only sales and executives are money makers. Developers are just an unneeded, low skilled, interchangeable burden reducing your profits because they have non-commission-based salaries. Why not just fire all your developers then sell what they made without fixing or improving anything—wow, infinite profit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few years I tried to introduce process to unstructured development environments (failed: project owner enjoyed his “i only do what i want and i don’t like communication or teamwork” workflow).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to provide experience from my background running production services to projects run by people with no production experience (failed: project owner enjoyed his “i write everything from first principles and don’t consider ‘servers’ to be a real world problem since everything works on my macbook air”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to introduce better process and repeatable testing into fly-by-the-seat-of-your-pants workflows (failed: project owner said his home server did all the testing he wanted and nobody else’s tests mattered, even though he repeatedly pushed out broken releases with failing tests).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried everything. But in the end, the project owner just said he owned everything and nobody could tell him what to do. He would oddly conflate constructive feedback as “being told what to do.” I tried asking my managers to get involved. My manager asked the project owner to make about 5 software changes to help the company. Project owner just ignored the requests. Managers were powerless to intervene or resolve anything. We just had to wait for things to change on their own. We just had to remain subservient to a laughably stereotypical sheltered ego.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was not tiny software. These were not tiny problems. This was software used by tens of thousands of companies running off a development process resembling 1993 hacker living in their parent’s basement. lol open source! Nobody cares as long as the package deploys, right? It’s not like security or reliability or design or efficiency or growing a sustainable team matters in software these days—just write it, commit it, then ignore all feedback because you are right and the world is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to improve things. I failed. I moved on. Welcome to my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is where we start to slow down. The rest is an outline of where this article would have ended up if I wanted to write a book-length tome/rant of experiences, but the utility of an extra 20,000 words here seems low.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you think any section seems worth fleshing out, let me know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operating constraints:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Work on a project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as a subordinate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as an unwanted subordinate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on a project the company doesn’t actually own&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;project is owned by an individual&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an individual who doesn’t believe in teamwork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;but the individual is employed by your company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;realize your cow-orker gets to personally profit off all work you do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;because he has a “special contract”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;saying the company has no control over his work and he owns everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and proudly brags about his criminal acquaintances in the news&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;saying all work is his, owned by him, and the company has no rights to anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also in consideration: cow-orker is under weirdo foreign employment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;meaning there’s not a huge work/success incentive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;github issues? “oh, i just look at the 3 most recent issues when i fell like it and reply if i feel like it”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it’s cheaper to keep weirdo foreign employees who work 3 months a year rather than fire them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;because company would have to pay 15-24 months severance after firing (see: “weirdo foreign employment”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;_fraud-and-funding-a-startup-story&quot;&gt;Fraud and Funding: A Startup Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;_story-of-pivotal-the-company&quot;&gt;Story of Pivotal The Company&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A story of the company in ten (may not actually be ten) short parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A New Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shares, Owned by Employees; Employees = Owned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going Public, The Soon Exit; The Lie Begins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Executives Come And Go, But Incompetence is Forever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CEO Nopes The Nope Out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Child-of-4chan “CEO” Installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cult Leader CEO declares all Engineer Will Now Operate Like It’s 1995&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 80/20 Rule of Delusional Devotion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cult Leader CEO’s Employee Friends All Get Promotions, Raises, Bonuses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cult Leader CEO’s Employee Friends Get Special Access to Sell Company Stock Even Though Regular Employees Can’t&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product Still Doesn’t Work—Product Has Never Worked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait, So The Only Customers You Talk About Also Invested Hundreds of Millions of Dollars in You?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s Nope Out to Hawaii Yet Stay On The Org Chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did We Mention The Product Doesn’t Work, Yet We Sell it for Millions of Dollars?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s Old White Guys Running Everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire Fighting, Every Day, Because Nothing Works, And That’s Fine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company Freely Emails All Employee Personal Details to Foreign Scammers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lies, Damn Lies, and Sales Tactics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sales is All — Sales Incentivized to Sell At All Costs Including Outright Fraud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dozens of Sales Reach over $1 Million in Take Home Commissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers Told “You Don’t Have The Skills of Sales” When Asked For $1 Million Comp Program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going Public, Never&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begging For Acquisitions, But Nobody Will Bite—Due Diligence Reveals Endless Frauds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trying to Hire CFOs Who Can’t Figure Out How The Company Even Stays Together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And, Scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;_story-of-pivotal-the-employment&quot;&gt;Story of Pivotal The Employment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A story of employment in ten (may not actually sum to ten) short parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All My Work Is Owned by Another Employee? What?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If You’re Weak At Business, You Get Taken Advantage Of By Bastards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Employee Who Owns Everything Won’t Allow Outside Committers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Employee Won’t Submit His Own Code To Code Review Before Commit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait, So I’m A Senior Developer Who Can’t Ever Commit Anything?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s Play Two Years Of “Clean Up The Owner’s Endless Mistakes After They Hit Production!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Six Months In, Finally Granted Access to Do One Thing: Close GitHub Issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close Them I Do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/d/msg/redis-db/PxFeA0fHgO4/zD4IWbXlMOgJ&quot;&gt;Let’s Organize Instead of Being A Hobby Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welp, That Didn’t Take. Let’s Give Up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/antirez/redis/pull/1906&quot;&gt;Two Days of Work to Clear 4 Years of Issues Ignored By The Creator Because Laziness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fine If Nobody Works! Weirdo 18 Month Severance—Cheaper to Keep Around Than Dismiss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matt.sh/files/redisconf.mp4&quot;&gt;Let’s Be A Real Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Singular Selfish Focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr. Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GTFO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, Mr. Manager, Here’s What I Can Do—Oh, You Want Me To Do Nothing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional Criminal Negligence, “lol!!! it’s all open source!!! i can’t be held responsible!!1!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-Directed, Work Continues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Hey, Maybe You Should Do Two Jobs For The Compensation Of One!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Team of Misfit Misfits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Un-Misfitted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-Manager’d Like It’s 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hey, HR, This Company is Some BS—Let’s Clarify My Situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“We, The Company, have investigated. We, the company, have decided the company did no wrong. Also, Your Position No Longer Exists, Please Leave.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Severed Severance, A $50k (pre-tax) Severance With Offensive Behavioral Restrictions. Rejected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even After Leveling Up Out of The Engineering Hierarchy, Company Still Treats You Like A Nobody.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hey, Washington, DC, What Do You Have to Do With Anything?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, here we are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also see &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/captainsafia/status/831671773288607745&quot; class=&quot;uri&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/captainsafia/status/831671773288607745&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;_addendum-the-crooked-severance-agreement&quot;&gt;Addendum: The Crooked Severance Agreement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the company realized they had no productive work remaining for me combined with how they poorly handled my situation across 3 years and 5 managers, they tried to pass off a severance agreement with laughably intolerant terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;_offensive-terms&quot;&gt;Offensive Terms&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Front-and-center: future behavior restrictions
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;restricting what you can say about the company after you leave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this term is standard, but standard doesn’t make it acceptable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OPTIONAL payouts
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Severance payment would be terminated upon new employment or even &lt;em&gt;consulting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yet they wanted behavior restrictions in perpetuity.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;uh, no. If you want to restrict my behavior, you pay for the duration of the behavior restriction. You don’t get to claim your payments are optional and time restricted while my behavior restrictions are in effect until the heat death of the universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oh, and you must notify the old company BEFORE you accept money from any other entity for performing services so they can stop your payments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;double oh, and the company is allowed to randomly quiz you over the next two months about whether you are employed or not. If they don’t like your answers, they can just stop paying your severance, but &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; restrictive terms remain in effect forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I did try my best to meet them half way. Sadly they sent all my negotiation requests to a Dell lawyer in Washington, DC who seemingly had no connection to anything and was just working from a lawyer decision tree play book. Oh well, their loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are relevant excerpts from the unexecuted severance agreement (“Involuntary Separation Plan”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COMMENCE THE NONSENSE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;For good and sufficient consideration, you and Pivotal agree as follows:
1. Employment Status and Termination
(a) Your Active Employment with Pivotal ended on October 28, 2016.

(b) Your “Termination Date” will occur at the earliest of the following events:
    1. January 6, 2017;
    2. the date that you commence “New Employment” as defined below; or
    3. the date you breach any obligation under this Agreement.

(c) For purposes of this Agreement, “New Employment” is defined as part-time
or full-time employment or self-employment (including performing consulting services),
for any person, firm or entity, or becoming a member of a board of any company or
organization. New Employment does not include volunteer services to a charity
or similar organization.

(d) You are required to send notification to Pivotal in writing prior to
commencing New Employment. Please include the following:
    ● name and address of the new employer;
    ● description of the new employer’s business and the position in which
      you will be employed; and
    ● projected start date of new employment;

(e) Please send information via email to AskHR@pivotal.io

(f) You will also be required to complete and return, on a timely basis,
Pivotal’s periodic request for written affirmation that you have not
obtained New Employment as defined in Paragraph 1(c) above;

(g) If you are reinstated or rehired by Pivotal, pay continuation and benefits
under this Agreement shall terminate.&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most fun fun condition: you’re not allowed to say anything negative about the company—even &lt;em&gt;if true&lt;/em&gt;. That’s a huge ask without commensurate compensation for restricting such behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;(b) You agree not to disparage Pivotal, its management, products or strategy.
The obligation of non-disparagement set forth in this section includes
disparagement in any form or forum, including but not limited to any
print or electronic media, social networking site, blog, tweet,
web site statements to or in the press including any trade press.
You are permitted to provide truthful information in response
to a legal subpoena or other legal process.

(c) You agree to cooperate with Pivotal and its legal counsel in
connection with any current or future litigation, investigation or
other legal matters involving Pivotal about which you have knowledge 
or information and to make yourself available at mutually convenient 
times and reasonable locations. Pivotal will reimburse you for reasonable 
travel expenses incurred by you as a result of, and directly related to, 
your cooperation. Your obligation to cooperate shall continue after your 
Termination Date.&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, “Pivotal” apparently includes half the known universe, so you’d never be able to say anything bad about any Dell product (or management—hi shithead michael dell!) or VMware product (or management) or EMC product (or management) or two dozen other companies entwined in their mess of corporate chicanery:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;For purposes of this Release of Claims, “Pivotal” shall be deemed to include 
EMC Corporation, Dell Inc., their predecessors, successors and assigns, their 
parents, affiliates and subsidiaries (including any corporation controlling, 
controlled by or under common control with Dell Inc.), of each of these 
entities, and each of their past, present and future directors, officers, 
stockholders, agents and employees, both individually and in their official 
capacities.&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By signing, you agree the company is always right and you are always wrong:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;(a) In exchange for the pay and benefits under this Agreement,
you hereby release, waive and discharge Pivotal from any and all 
claims, demands, causes of action, legal disputes, liabilities or 
damages of any nature whatsoever, both in law and equity, which you 
have had, now have, or may have in the future, against Pivotal whether 
or not either known to you now or discovered by you hereafter 
(collectively referred to as “Claims”).&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus the typical “screw you out of your equity” clause. Would you really expect anything less from this company? At least the stock was worthless from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;PIVOTAL EQUITY
Unvested stock options granted by Pivotal shall terminate on your 
Termination Date, subject to any earlier expiration date of a stock 
option, pursuant to the terms of the applicable stock plans and grant 
agreements. Vested stock options granted to you by Pivotal may only be 
exercised during a designated 10-business day period, or &quot;open exercise 
window,&quot; that occurs within the ninety (90) days following your Termination 
Date (or that occurs prior to the expiration date of the stock option if earlier).&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They even got bold all caps shouty in one section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;THIS AGREEMENT INCLUDES A RELEASE BY YOU OF CERTAIN RIGHTS,
AND A COMMITMENT NOT TO SUE PIVOTAL. YOU ARE ADVISED TO CONSULT 
WITH AN ATTORNEY PRIOR TO SIGNING THIS AGREEMENT. YOU AGREE THAT 
PIVOTAL ALLOWED YOU SUFFICIENT TIME TO REVIEW THIS AGREEMENT AND TO 
CONSIDER THE CONSEQUENCES OF SIGNING IT. YOU AGREE THAT THE CONSIDERATION 
GIVEN PURSUANT TO THIS AGREEMENT IS IN EXCESS OF ANY AMOUNTS EMC IS OTHERWISE 
LEGALLY OBLIGATED TO PROVIDE TO YOU. YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ 
THIS AGREEMENT, UNDERSTAND ALL OF ITS PROVISIONS, AND ARE ENTERING INTO 
IT VOLUNTARILY.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup, I consulted lawyer and the decision was the ISP consideration was not considerable enough to execute the terms you requested. Sorry (not sorry).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 20:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nodivbyzero</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://matt.sh/commit-this</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy” turns 42</title>
<link>https://www.economist.com/prospero/2020/03/06/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy-turns-42</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.economist.com/prospero/2020/03/06/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy-turns-42</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;29.694736842105&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-test-id=&quot;Lead Image&quot; class=&quot;article__lead-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.economist.com/sites/default/files/20200307_BKP509.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/200/113/85/sites/default/files/20200307_BKP509.jpg 200w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/300/169/85/sites/default/files/20200307_BKP509.jpg 300w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/400/225/85/sites/default/files/20200307_BKP509.jpg 400w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/600/338/85/sites/default/files/20200307_BKP509.jpg 600w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/640/360/85/sites/default/files/20200307_BKP509.jpg 640w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/800/450/85/sites/default/files/20200307_BKP509.jpg 800w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/1000/563/85/sites/default/files/20200307_BKP509.jpg 1000w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/85/sites/default/files/20200307_BKP509.jpg 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 320px) 300px, (max-width: 414px) 400px, (max-width: 600px) 640px, (max-width: 768px) 800px, (max-width: 960px) 1000px, (max-width: 1024px) 1200px&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;article__header&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-test-id=&quot;Article Description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot; class=&quot;article__description&quot;&gt;Douglas Adams’s masterwork is blithely comic in tone but deeply serious in purpose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div data-test-id=&quot;Blog Identity&quot; class=&quot;article__section&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-test-id=&quot;Blog Section Subheadline&quot; class=&quot;article__section-subheadline&quot;&gt;Books, arts and culture&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;blogsiteheadline&quot; class=&quot;article__section-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/prospero/&quot; data-test-id=&quot;Blog Section Headline&quot;&gt;Prospero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;ds-rule layout-article-header__rule&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div itemprop=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;113.25140712946&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;article__aside&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;layout-article-meta&quot;&gt;&lt;time itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/DateTime&quot; datetime=&quot;2020-03-06T14:06:21Z&quot; class=&quot;article__dateline-datetime&quot;&gt;Mar 6th 2020&lt;/time&gt;&lt;p data-test-id=&quot;Article Byline&quot; class=&quot;article__byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;by D.B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;EVERY YEAR the world celebrates the anniversaries of masterworks and maestros. In 2020 there will be a host of events and publications commemorating the lives of Ludwig van Beethoven, Raphael, Charles Dickens, Anne Brontë and William Wordsworth. Such milestones usually come in neat multiples of 50. The 42nd anniversary of anything is rarely observed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;Yet on March 8th fans of “The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy” (“HHGTTG”) will pay tribute to the comedy science-fiction series, which had its radio premiere on that day in 1978 and was subsequently adapted into novels, TV series, video games and a film. To mark the occasion, Pan Macmillan has reprinted the scripts and novels in colourful new editions (“HHGTTG” was the first book published under their “Pan Original” imprint to sell more than 1m copies). The British Library will host a day of “celebrations, conversation and performance”. BBC Radio 4 has aired the original episodes; Radio 4 Extra will put on a “five-hour Hitchhiker’s spectacular” including archival material and specially commissioned programmes. Such is the enduring interest in Douglas Adams’s story that it is due to be adapted into a new television series by Hulu, a streaming service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;The number 42 is the tale’s signature joke. It is the response that Deep Thought, a supercomputer, has taken millions of years to deliver to a race of “hyper-intelligent pan-dimensional beings” who seek “the Answer to the Ultimate Question of Life, the Universe, and Everything”. (In a risqué throwaway gag typical of Adams, the name “Deep Thought” evokes a notorious pornographic film of 1972; later it inspired IBM's chess computers, including the grandmaster-vanquishing Deep Blue.) When the machine unveils its nonsensical answer, the hyper-intelligent beings are livid. What they really want to know, Deep Thought muses, is the wording of the “Ultimate Question” itself. It turns out that the planet Earth is a very complicated simulation designed to reveal that question, with the hyper-intelligent beings secretly keeping tabs on it while disguised as mice. Unfortunately, a tribe of hideous aliens blow the planet up five minutes before the simulation is due to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;The series’ protagonist is Arthur Dent, a denizen of a small West Country town who narrowly escapes the Earth's destruction and is fated to wander the universe, bewildered, in a dressing gown as improbable events take place around him. This droll application of the quotidian to the wonders of the universe is at the heart of Adams’s appeal. He strips away sci-fi’s more portentous attributes without depriving it of either its sweep or its potential profundity. He is often so deliciously funny that readers may find themselves dwelling on the insights he has offered only when they close the books. The Total Perspective Vortex, a notional machine designed to extrapolate the enormity of “Life, the Universe, and Everything” from a single mundane but agreeable object—a slice of fairy cake—serves as a metaphor for his own work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;If Adams’s themes are universal, his reach has proved almost as wide. “HHGTTG” has sold more than 14m copies worldwide and been translated into dozens of languages, including Korean, Hebrew and Japanese—apt for a series which gave Babel Fish, an early online translation site, its name. (Your correspondent was fascinated by the English original as a teenager in Nairobi in the 1980s.) Every year May 25th is observed by Adams fans across the globe as “Towel Day”, named for “the most massively useful thing an interstellar hitchhiker can have”. On Towel Day in 2013, Norway’s Kolumbus public-transport company gave away towels which allowed passengers to ride for free. Two years later Samantha Cristoforetti, an Italian astronaut, delivered a “HHGTTG” reading from the International Space Station. Elon Musk, the boss of Tesla, has described Adams as his “favourite philosopher”. “What Adams was essentially saying,” Mr Musk has said, “is, ‘The universe is the answer; what are the questions?’...A lot of times the question is harder than the answer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;Adams was an imperfect writer. His plotting was lax, partly a result of a notorious procrastination habit which required him to rush at the last moment, but which helped make him an imaginative improviser. (“I love deadlines,” he wrote. “I like the whooshing sound they make as they fly by.”) His female characters are flimsy. But he excelled at bringing a human scale and sensibility to the vastness of the cosmos, and vice-versa, often via a deftly executed one-liner. God, in the world of Arthur Dent, has only one message for his creations: “We apologise for the inconvenience.” This wry approach to serious subjects is now a recognisable idiom in sci-fi. His late rival Terry Pratchett might not have cared to acknowledge it, but “HHGTTG” opened up the door for Pratchett’s “Discworld”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;The success of “HHGTTG” was a wonderfully unintended consequence for a writer who treated unintended consequences as the stuff of both life and literature. “I may not have gone where I intended to go,” Adams wrote, “but I think I have ended up where I needed to be.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;layout-article-links&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s100.copyright.com/AppDispatchServlet?publisherName=economist&amp;amp;publication=economist&amp;amp;title=%E2%80%9CThe%20Hitchhiker%E2%80%99s%20Guide%20To%20The%20Galaxy%E2%80%9D%20turns%2042&amp;amp;publicationDate=2020-03-06&amp;amp;contentID=%2Fcontent%2Fhjcoc4ibncair0fk7jo2j4s2s00pc5qb&amp;amp;type=A&amp;amp;orderBeanReset=TRUE&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ds-actioned-link ds-actioned-link--reuse-this-content&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Reuse this content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/about-the-economist&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;ds-actioned-link ds-actioned-link--the-trust-project&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Trust Project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 18:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pama</dc:creator>
<og:title>“The Hitchhiker’s Guide To The Galaxy” turns 42</og:title>
<og:type>Article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.economist.com/prospero/2020/03/06/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy-turns-42</og:url>
<og:description>Douglas Adams’s masterwork is blithely comic in tone but deeply serious in purpose</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.economist.com/sites/default/files/20200307_BKP509.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.economist.com/prospero/2020/03/06/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy-turns-42</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Exponential Growth and Covid-19 [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kas0tIxDvrg</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kas0tIxDvrg</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;eow-description&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;A good time for a primer on exponential and logistic growth, no?&lt;br/&gt;Home page: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.3blue1brown.com&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.3blue1brown.com&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.3blue1brown.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Brought to you by you: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=http%3A%2F%2F3b1b.co%2Fcovid-thanks&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=http%3A%2F%2F3b1b.co%2Fcovid-thanks&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://3b1b.co/covid-thanks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.worldometers.info%2Fcoronavirus%2Fcoronavirus-cases%2F%23total-cases&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.worldometers.info%2Fcoronavirus%2Fcoronavirus-cases%2F%23total-cases&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.worldometers.info/coronav...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some have (quite rightfully) commented on how you shouldn't look at the R^2 of linear regressions on cumulative data since even for completely random changes each total is not at all independent of the last. Since the derivative of an exponential should also be an exponential, we could instead run the same test on the logarithms of the differences from day to day, which in this case gives R^2 = 0.91.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this video uses COVID-19 (aka the Coronavirus) as a motivating example, the main goal is simply a math lesson on exponentials and logistic curves. If you're looking for a video more focused on COVID-19 itself, I'd recommend taking a look at this one from Osmosis: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cFB_C2ieW5I&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink spf-link&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgg&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/cFB_C2ieW5I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Extrapolation xkcd: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fxkcd.com%2F605%2F&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fxkcd.com%2F605%2F&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://xkcd.com/605/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;------------------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These animations are largely made using manim, a scrappy open source python library: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2F3b1b%2Fmanim&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2F3b1b%2Fmanim&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://github.com/3b1b/manim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to check it out, I feel compelled to warn you that it's not the most well-documented tool, and it has many other quirks you might expect in a library someone wrote with only their own use in mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Music by Vincent Rubinetti.&lt;br/&gt;Download the music on Bandcamp:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fvincerubinetti.bandcamp.com%2Falbum%2Fthe-music-of-3blue1brown&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fvincerubinetti.bandcamp.com%2Falbum%2Fthe-music-of-3blue1brown&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://vincerubinetti.bandcamp.com/a...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stream the music on Spotify:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fopen.spotify.com%2Falbum%2F1dVyjwS8FBqXhRunaG5W5u&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fopen.spotify.com%2Falbum%2F1dVyjwS8FBqXhRunaG5W5u&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://open.spotify.com/album/1dVyjw...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to contribute translated subtitles or to help review those that have already been made by others and need approval, you can click the gear icon in the video and go to subtitles/cc, then &quot;add subtitles/cc&quot;. I really appreciate those who do this, as it helps make the lessons accessible to more people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;------------------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3blue1brown is a channel about animating math, in all senses of the word animate. And you know the drill with YouTube, if you want to stay posted on new videos, subscribe: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=http%3A%2F%2F3b1b.co%2Fsubscribe&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=http%3A%2F%2F3b1b.co%2Fsubscribe&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://3b1b.co/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various social media stuffs:&lt;br/&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.3blue1brown.com&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.3blue1brown.com&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.3blue1brown.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2F3blue1brown&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2F3blue1brown&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/3blue1brown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Reddit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.reddit.com%2Fr%2F3blue1brown&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.reddit.com%2Fr%2F3blue1brown&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/3blue1brown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Instagram: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.instagram.com%2F3blue1brown_animations%2F&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.instagram.com%2F3blue1brown_animations%2F&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.instagram.com/3blue1brown...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Patreon: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fpatreon.com%2F3blue1brown&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fpatreon.com%2F3blue1brown&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://patreon.com/3blue1brown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F3blue1brown&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F3blue1brown&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Kas0tIxDvrg&amp;amp;redir_token=fKTrtyQNj1lTGCFTXs_idUus5YN8MTU4MzgwMjA4NUAxNTgzNzE1Njg1&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CC4Q6TgYACITCLjy9taYjOgCFcOExAodcIQEgki4_Y7iyJbN1Sk&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/3blue1brown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 17:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tomerbd</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kas0tIxDvrg</og:url>
<og:title>Exponential growth and epidemics</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Kas0tIxDvrg/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>A good time for a primer on exponential and logistic growth, no? Home page: https://www.3blue1brown.com Brought to you by you: http://3b1b.co/covid-thanks Da...</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kas0tIxDvrg</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Göttingen researchers identify existing drug with potential to treat Covid-19</title>
<link>https://www.dpz.eu/en/home/single-view/news/die-vermehrung-von-sars-coronavirus-2-im-menschen-verhindern.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.dpz.eu/en/home/single-view/news/die-vermehrung-von-sars-coronavirus-2-im-menschen-verhindern.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;
Schematic representation of a coronavirus with surface proteins on the outer envelope. Illustration: Markus Hoffmann 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;75.197547683924&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Viruses must enter cells of the human body to cause disease. For this, they attach to suitable cells and inject their genetic information into these cells. Infection biologists from the German Primate Center - Leibniz Institute for Primate Research in Göttingen, together with colleagues at Charité – Universitätsmedizin Berlin, have investigated how the novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2 penetrates cells. They have identified a cellular enzyme that is essential for viral entry into lung cells: the protease TMPRSS2. A clinically proven drug known to be active against TMPRSS2 was found to block SARS-CoV-2 infection and might constitute a novel treatment option (Cell).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several coronaviruses circulate worldwide and constantly infect humans, which normally caused only mild respiratory disease. Currently, however, we are witnessing a worldwide spread of a new coronavirus with more than 90,000 confirmed cases and over 3,000 deaths. The new virus has been named SARS coronavirus-2 and has been transmitted from animals to humans. It causes a respiratory disease called COVID-19 that may take a severe course. The SARS coronavirus-2 has been spreading since December 2019 and is closely related to the SARS coronavirus that caused the SARS pandemic in 2002/2003. No vaccines or drugs are currently available to combat these viruses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stopping virus spread&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A team of scientists led by infection biologists from the German Primate Centre and including researchers from Charité, the University of Veterinary Medicine Hannover Foundation, the BG-Unfallklinik Murnau, the LMU Munich, the Robert Koch Institute and the German Center for Infection Research, wanted to find out how the new coronavirus SARS-CoV-2 enters host cells and how this process can be blocked. The researchers identified a cellular protein that is important for the entry of SARS-CoV-2 into lung cells. &quot;Our results show that SARS-CoV-2 requires the protease TMPRSS2, which is present in the human body, to enter cells,&quot; says Stefan Pöhlmann, head of the Infection Biology Unit at the German Primate Center. &quot;This protease is a potential target for therapeutic intervention.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promising drug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Since it is known that the drug camostat mesilate inhibits the protease TMPRSS2, the researchers have investigated whether it can also prevent infection with SARS-CoV-2. &quot;We have tested SARS-CoV-2 isolated from a patient and found that camostat mesilate blocks entry of the virus into lung cells,&quot; says Markus Hoffmann, the lead author of the study. Camostat mesilate is a drug approved in Japan for use in pancreatic inflammation. &quot;Our results suggest that camostat mesilate might also protect against COVID-19,&quot; says Markus Hoffmann. &quot;This should be investigated in clinical trials.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original publication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hoffmann, M et al. (2020). SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically-proven protease inhibitor. Cell, &lt;a href=&quot;https://marlin-prod.literatumonline.com/pb-assets/journals/research/cell/CELL_S0092-8674%2820%2930229-4.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Original Publication in Cell magazine&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOI: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.02.052&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 16:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mpweiher</dc:creator>
<og:title>Preventing spread of SARS coronavirus-2 in humans</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.dpz.eu/en/home/single-view/news/die-vermehrung-von-sars-coronavirus-2-im-menschen-verhindern.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.dpz.eu/fileadmin/_processed_/3/8/csm_Corona_MH_web2_b0c2a8c12a.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Göttingen infection researchers identify potential drug</og:description>
<dc:language>de</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.dpz.eu/en/home/single-view/news/die-vermehrung-von-sars-coronavirus-2-im-menschen-verhindern.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Octo-Bouncer</title>
<link>https://electrondust.com/2020/03/01/the-octo-bouncer/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://electrondust.com/2020/03/01/the-octo-bouncer/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I started thinking about ball juggling machines in the year 2015. I wrote about my first few attempts at creating them in &lt;a href=&quot;https://electrondust.com/2017/10/28/the-quest-to-get-a-machine-to-juggle/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; blog post from the year 2017. In 2018 I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://electrondust.com/2018/07/22/stepper-juggler/&quot;&gt;another&lt;/a&gt; post about my then newest build. We’re now in the year 2020. And finally, the quest to get a machine to juggle a ping pong ball reliably has come to an end (as this current build is able to keep the ball bouncing for hours.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-481&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-embed__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;372&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lYyAMDYzJQM?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This machine requires the following things to work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;1x Teensy 4.0 Microcontroller running &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/T-Kuhn/HighPrecisionStepperJuggler/tree/master/Arduino/HighPrecisionStepperJuggler&quot;&gt;this code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4x StepperOnline DM442S stepper motor drivers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4x Nema 17 Stepper Motors with 5:1 planetary gearbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x 48V 8A power supply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x e-con Systems &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.e-consystems.com/4k-usb-camera.asp&quot;&gt;See3CAM_CU135&lt;/a&gt; camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x Windows Computer with OpenCV installed on it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the parts defined in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/T-Kuhn/HighPrecisionStepperJuggler/tree/master/Autodesk%20Fusion360%20data&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; Fusion360 project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/T-Kuhn/HighPrecisionStepperJuggler/tree/master/Unity/HighPrecisionStepperJuggler/Build&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; custom Windows Application (made with Unity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191015_203210-1920x1440.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-507&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191015_203210-1920x1440.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191015_203210-512x384.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191015_203210-768x576.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191015_203210-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191015_203210-2048x1536.jpg 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why A Teensy 4.0?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because 600 MHz. That’s the clock speed of the Teensy 4.0. Compare that to the 16 MHz you get with most Arduino boards. But why so much emphasis on clock speed anyway? Because we need to generate pulses with a frequency of up to 250 kHz for each of the 4 stepper motors. And since we want the stepper motors to start and stop smoothly, the spacing between the pulses needs to increase/decrease in a sinusoidal pattern. And yes, it doesn’t need to be sinusoidal – you could also go for a sigmoid – but the point is if you want very fast, smooth movements linearly increasing speed-curves probably won’t cut it. And because this is quite a lot of calculations to do on a 16 Mhz microcontroller I went for the Teensy 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191002_224558-1920x1440.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-505&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191002_224558-1920x1440.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191002_224558-512x384.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191002_224558-768x576.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191002_224558-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMG_20191002_224558-2048x1536.jpg 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the way, this microcontroller also comes with a FPU (Floating Point Unit) which both supports 64bit doubles and 32bit floats. As if the crazy 600 MHz clock speed in and itself wasn’t enough, now we also get an FPU!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Do we really need 600 Mhz?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe you’re still not convinced. “Why do we need to generate 250 kHz pulse signals? The motors aren’t really rotating that fast are they? Won’t 10 kHz do it?” Good question. Here’s what I found out while trying to get my steppers to move as fast as possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the more microsteps the better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the higher the voltage the better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So more microsteps is better. I set the microstep setting on my drivers to 25600 steps/rev. That’s a lot of pulses for 1 single revolution. And remember that we’re using stepper motors with a 5:1 gearbox attached. So it’s really 128’000 steps per revolution. We’re getting pretty high up in the numbers already and maybe you can see now why 250 kHz isn’t that unreasonable at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an actual image of the first 9 milliseconds of a 150 milliseconds long pulse signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/IMAG009.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-515&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can clearly see how the pulses are getting narrower towards the right side. The frequency is increasing smoothly. Starting slow but picking up speed as the signal progresses. Keep in mind that we’re only able to see the first 9 milliseconds of this signal. The frequency will go way up and then start to decrease again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What exactly is the microcontroller doing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Teensy 4.0’s job in this project is simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Listen for movement comments on the serial bus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate pulses for the stepper motors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data we’re listening for on the serial bus looks basically like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;0.11941:0.11941:0.11941:0.11941:0.15000&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are 5 values all separated by colons. The first 4 values are absolute motor positions (in radians) and the last one is the move time. So with this instruction, we are telling the machine to move all it’s motors to the absolute position &lt;code&gt;0.11941&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;0.15000&lt;/code&gt; seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also able to string multiple movement commands together. The machine will work through the movement commands one at the time in the order the commands came in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s the desktop Application doing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told you that I’ve built an Application with Unity for this machine. So why did I do that? What about all that talk about that crazy fast 600 Mhz microcontroller?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/OctoBouncerDesktopApplication.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-527&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/OctoBouncerDesktopApplication.png 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/OctoBouncerDesktopApplication-512x288.png 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/OctoBouncerDesktopApplication-768x432.png 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/OctoBouncerDesktopApplication-1536x864.png 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason I ended up writing this application is that I wanted to do 120 FPS real-time image processing of 640×480 image data. So here’s what the computer application ended up doing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Setting up the camera (120 FPS 640×480 data stream, gain, exposure, contrast, ISO, saturation) via OpenCV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execute OpenCVs &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.opencv.org/master/da/d53/tutorial_py_houghcircles.html&quot;&gt;Hough Transform circle recognition algorithm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get 3D position of ping pong ball using the results of above-mentioned circle recognition algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculate ball velocity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use ball position and velocity in PID control code to calculate correction-tilt of plate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execute Inverse Kinematic code to figure out how much each motor needs to rotate in order to get the plate to a certain height with a specific tilt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send result of IK calculation to the microcontroller via serial interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Render machine position and movements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also render image processing data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How did you make all those aluminium parts?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This machine is made of 150+ aluminium parts. And producing all these parts took A LOT of patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I basically ran my &lt;a href=&quot;https://electrondust.com/2019/04/29/the-benbox-cnc-1310/&quot;&gt;Benbox CNC 1310&lt;/a&gt; (almost) nonstop for multiple weeks. “Multiple weeks? You must be kidding.” Well, I’m not. The total machining time for all the parts was about 160 hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Why is your CNC mill so slow?” you might wonder. It’s because the spindle isn’t quite as powerful as I’d like it to be. We’re looking at an 80W spindle here. Updating the spindle is one of the things I’d like to do in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5454.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-531&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5454.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5454-512x341.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5454-768x512.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5454-1536x1024.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made a sound-absorbing box for the CNC mill in order to preserve my sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5456.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-532&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5456.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5456-512x341.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5456-768x512.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5456-1536x1024.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5496.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-533&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5496.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5496-512x341.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5496-768x512.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5496-1536x1024.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used a 1.5mm endmill on 6061 Aluminium with a thickness of 3mm. As you can see in the image above, I fixed my workpiece with 4 screws to ensure that it is both held in place securely and the surface is as plain as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some pics I took while working on the machine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows are some pictures I took while working on this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5470-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-552&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5470-1.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5470-1-512x341.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5470-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5470-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191116_214218.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-539&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191116_214218.jpg 1440w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191116_214218-384x512.jpg 384w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191116_214218-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191116_214218-1152x1536.jpg 1152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5488.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-553&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5488.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5488-512x341.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5488-768x512.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5488-1536x1024.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191207_161816.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-540&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191207_161816.jpg 1440w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191207_161816-384x512.jpg 384w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191207_161816-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191207_161816-1152x1536.jpg 1152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191208_213448.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-541&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191208_213448.jpg 1440w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191208_213448-384x512.jpg 384w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191208_213448-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191208_213448-1152x1536.jpg 1152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191221_181001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-543&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191221_181001.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191221_181001-512x384.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191221_181001-768x576.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_20191221_181001-1536x1152.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing worth mentioning is that I used ball bearings for all the joints. If you look closely at some of the pics above you should be able to see them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The finished Octo-Bouncer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here some more pics of the finished project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_571_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-546&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_571_.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_571_-512x341.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_571_-768x512.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_571_-1536x1024.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5714.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-547&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5714.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5714-512x341.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5714-768x512.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5714-1536x1024.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5717.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-548&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5717.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5717-512x341.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5717-768x512.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5717-1536x1024.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5719.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-549&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5719.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5719-512x341.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5719-768x512.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5719-1536x1024.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5721.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-550&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5721.jpg 1920w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5721-512x341.jpg 512w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5721-768x512.jpg 768w, https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5721-1536x1024.jpg 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 14:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>spchampion2</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Octo-Bouncer - Electron Dust</og:title>
<og:description>I started thinking about ball juggling machines in the year 2015. I wrote about my first few attempts at creating them in this blog post from the year 2017. In 2018 I wrote another post about my then newest build. We’re now in the year 2020. And finally, the quest to get a machine to … Continue reading The Octo-Bouncer</og:description>
<og:url>https://electrondust.com/2020/03/01/the-octo-bouncer/</og:url>
<og:image>https://electrondust.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_5716.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://electrondust.com/2020/03/01/the-octo-bouncer/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pollution from tire wear is worse than exhaust emissions?</title>
<link>https://www.emissionsanalytics.com/news/pollution-tyre-wear-worse-exhaust-emissions</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.emissionsanalytics.com/news/pollution-tyre-wear-worse-exhaust-emissions</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-layout sqs-grid-12 columns-12&quot; data-layout-label=&quot;Post Body&quot; data-type=&quot;item&quot; data-updated-on=&quot;1583507895045&quot; id=&quot;item-5e6266f71bb8ea6763dff341&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row sqs-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col sqs-col-12 span-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-5d63259215d2509e5a63&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-role=&quot;image&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a9400b37e3c3a8c47522029/1583509207439-ZUVZH829SSN2K1PPORMK/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJuO1kdfnkRg5DQ3JsWSgW1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyBtQSaubBtPLj-HkIgWTPMjqjbt-tFQZfVl3f1wuSKMFkPiTakKBdMzO_Nchs4VCU/EMI-Blog-LargeSUV-685x400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EMI-Blog-LargeSUV-685x400.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a9400b37e3c3a8c47522029/1583509207439-ZUVZH829SSN2K1PPORMK/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJuO1kdfnkRg5DQ3JsWSgW1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyBtQSaubBtPLj-HkIgWTPMjqjbt-tFQZfVl3f1wuSKMFkPiTakKBdMzO_Nchs4VCU/EMI-Blog-LargeSUV-685x400.jpg&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a9400b37e3c3a8c47522029/1583509207439-ZUVZH829SSN2K1PPORMK/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJuO1kdfnkRg5DQ3JsWSgW1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyBtQSaubBtPLj-HkIgWTPMjqjbt-tFQZfVl3f1wuSKMFkPiTakKBdMzO_Nchs4VCU/EMI-Blog-LargeSUV-685x400.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;685x400&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;EMI-Blog-LargeSUV-685x400.jpg&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e626ed6a70fa738eec345c7&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-6773fca3f846c85632de&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Tight regulation of exhaust emissions by the EU has meant that new cars emit very little particle pollution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But tyre wear pollution is unregulated and can be 1,000 times worse, finds independent real-world testing experts Emissions Analytics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Increased popularity of SUVs, larger and heavier than standard vehicles, exacerbates this problem – as does growing sales of heavy EVs and widespread use of budget tyres&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Fitting only high-quality tyres and lowering vehicle weight are routes to reducing these ‘non-exhaust emissions’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oxford, 6th March 2020:&lt;/strong&gt; Pollution from tyre wear can be 1,000 times worse than what comes out of a car’s exhaust, Emissions Analytics has found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Harmful particle matter from tyres – and also brakes – is a very serious and growing environmental problem, one that is being exacerbated by the increasing popularity of large, heavy vehicles such as SUVs, and growing demand for electric vehicles, which are heavier than standard cars because of their batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;What’s more, vehicle tyre wear pollution is completely unregulated, unlike exhaust emissions which have been rapidly reduced by car makers thanks to the pressure placed on them by European emissions standards. New cars now emit very little in the way of particulate matter but there is growing concern around ‘non-exhaust emissions’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Non-exhaust emissions (NEE) are particles released into the air from brake wear, tyre wear, road surface wear and resuspension of road dust during on-road vehicle usage. No legislation is in place to limit or reduce NEE, but they cause a great deal of concern for air quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;NEEs are currently believed to constitute the majority of primary particulate matter from road transport, 60 percent of PM2.5 and 73 percent of PM10 – and in its 2019 report ‘Non-Exhaust Emissions from Road Traffic’ by the UK Government’s Air Quality Expert Group (AQEG), it recommended that NEE are immediately recognised as a source of ambient concentrations of airborne particulate matter, even for vehicles with zero exhaust emissions of particles – such as EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;To understand the scale of the problem, Emissions Analytics – the leading independent global testing and data specialist for the scientific measurement of realworld emissions – performed some initial tyre wear testing. Using a popular family hatchback running on brand new, correctly inflated tyres, we found that the car emitted 5.8 grams per kilometer of particles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Compared with regulated exhaust emission limits of 4.5 milligrams per kilometer, the completely unregulated tyre wear emission is higher by a factor of over 1,000. Emissions Analytics notes that this could be even higher if the vehicle had tyres which were underinflated, or the road surfaces used for the test were rougher, or the tyres used were from a budget range – all very recognisable scenarios in ‘real world’ motoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Lofthouse, Senior Researcher at Emissions Analytics said:&lt;/strong&gt; “It’s time to consider not just what comes out of a car’s exhaust pipe but particle pollution from tyre and brake wear. Our initial tests reveal that there can be a shocking amount of particle pollution from tyres – 1,000 times worse than emissions from a car’s exhaust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“What is even more frightening is that while exhaust emissions have been tightly regulated for many years, tyre wear is totally unregulated – and with the increasing growth in sales of heavier SUVs and battery-powered electric cars, non-exhaust emissions (NEE) are a very serious problem.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick Molden, CEO of Emissions Analytics said:&lt;/strong&gt; “The challenge to the industry and regulators is an almost complete black hole of consumer information, undone by frankly out of date regulations still preoccupied with exhaust emissions. In the short term, fitting higher quality tyres is one way to reduce these NEEs and to always have tyres inflated to the correct level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Ultimately, though, the car industry may have to find ways to reduce vehicle weight too. What is without doubt on the horizon is much-needed regulation to combat this problem. Whether that leads to specific types of low emission, harder wearing tyres is not for us to say – but change has to come.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;ENDS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;For all media inquiries please contact Sam Hardy on +44 (0)7815 863968, or via &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:media@emissionsanalytics.com&quot;&gt;media@emissionsanalytics.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Emissions Analytics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Emissions Analytics is the leading independent global testing and data specialist for the scientific measurement of real-world emissions and fuel efficiency for passenger and commercial vehicles and non-road mobile machinery. Emissions Analytics seeks to bring transparency to a confused market sector. It publishes the EQUA Index of real-world driving emissions, and works with clients around the world to establish accurate emissions measurement and data requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 12:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>clouddrover</dc:creator>
<og:title>Press Release: Pollution From Tyre Wear 1,000 Times Worse Than Exhaust Emissions — Emissions Analytics</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.emissionsanalytics.com/news/pollution-tyre-wear-worse-exhaust-emissions</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Pollution from tyre wear can be 1,000 times worse than what comes out of a car’s exhaust, Emissions Analytics has found.</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5a9400b37e3c3a8c47522029/5a9411a2e4966bf0588103a2/5e6266f71bb8ea6763dff341/1583510015294/EMI-Blog-LargeSUV-685x400.jpg?format=1500w</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.emissionsanalytics.com/news/pollution-tyre-wear-worse-exhaust-emissions</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Do whatever you can&amp;#039;t stop thinking about</title>
<link>https://shime.sh/do-whatever-you-can%27t-stop-thinking-about</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://shime.sh/do-whatever-you-can%27t-stop-thinking-about</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;mb-8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 6, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bg-blue-lightest py-1 px-2 text-center text-blue-dark mr-2 rounded text-sm&quot;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the start of the year, I’ve been making mistakes with with my free time. I’ve been spending some of my leisure time on wrong activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wishing to improve in the open-source department, one of my New Year's resolutions was to become more active with Rails contributions. I would learn about Rails internals, help people with their issues and get feedback from Rails core team members. The plan was to work at least 30 minutes on Rails every day and I was using a habit tracker tool in order to ensure that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I've noticed that doing that significantly drains my energy. I'm not excited about doing maintenance work and it doesn't make me jump out of the bed in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t realized how bad it was for my energy, until I decided to work on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://getkuote.com&quot;&gt;side project&lt;/a&gt; last weekend. It made me super excited. The process of turning something from my head into reality will never stop feeling magical. I was eager to wake up and work on it. Working on it didn’t feel like work. Hours passed without me noticing. I wasn’t tired, I was excited afterwards. I've neglected my other habits because of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was such a contrast to pushing myself to maintain Rails. That’s when I remembered having read about managing personal energy from&lt;br /&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shime.sh/summaries/how-to-fail-at-almost-everything-and-still-win-big&quot;&gt;How to Fail at Almost Anything and Still Win Big&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. I’ve read it, but haven’t thought about it much until now. Experiencing such a difference in excitement about something I do in my free time made me remember it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the experts, what looks like hard work from the outside, is play from the inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naval Ravikant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic idea of personal energy management is that you should focus on increasing your personal energy and lifting up your mood in your leisure time, instead of working on things that drain your personal energy. Hobbies should lift your mood, not drain you. This makes you better perform all the other tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the difference in my experience comes from the source of motivation. I am not intrinsically motivated to work on Rails. If money wasn’t the issue, I would probably not start working on maintaining it. The hidden motivation was external and it was rooted in the desire to make it more easy to find the next job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a side project, on the other hand, is something I can imagine myself doing, if money was not the issue. That’s why I should probably spend my leisure time doing that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because every minute spent doing something other than what you love most today is a minute you’re more likely to regret when you’re 80.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julian Shapiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another useful tool, for deciding what to work on is the Regret Minimization Framework: Project yourself being 80 years old and thinking whether you would regret your current decision. That's how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jwG_qR6XmDQ&quot;&gt;Jeff Bezos decided to work on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. It's a useful tool for prioritizing over long-term and rationalizing decisions that make no sense in the short-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never work on anything you would regret looking back on your deathbed and spend as much time you can on doing whatever you can’t stop thinking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;mt-4&quot;&gt;Did you like this article? You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shime_sh&quot;&gt;follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, subscribe to the newsletter or &lt;a href=&quot;https://shime.sh/feed.xml&quot;&gt;subscribe to the RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; if you'd like to follow along.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 11:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>a7b3fa</dc:creator>
<og:title>Do whatever you can't stop thinking about</og:title>
<og:description>Since the start of the year, I’ve been making mistakes with with my free time. I’ve been spending some of my leisure time on wrong activities.</og:description>
<og:url>http://shime.sh/do-whatever-you-can't-stop-thinking-about</og:url>
<og:image>http://shime.sh/public/social.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://shime.sh/do-whatever-you-can%27t-stop-thinking-about</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Word from Wuhan</title>
<link>https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v42/n05/wang-xiuying/the-word-from-wuhan</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v42/n05/wang-xiuying/the-word-from-wuhan</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcaps dropcap--w&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;hen&lt;/span&gt; SARS broke out in 2003, I was in graduate school. Shanghai was not a hot zone, with only eight people infected out of a population of 17 million. The campus was not under quarantine, and there was no social media to spread alarm. Summer came, and the virus waned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new coronavirus – SARS-CoV-2 – has already infected more people than SARS. Besides the lungs and respiratory tract it can also affect the oesophagus, heart, kidneys, ileum and bladder. A definite diagnosis isn’t always easy: blood tests aren’t reliable and the standard nucleic acid test, which uses swabs from the throat or nose, produces a high rate of false negatives – especially in the middle of a public health emergency, when large numbers of people are being tested in a short space of time under conditions that are hard to monitor. The patient may have a cough or a fever, or be short of breath – but there are also many cases of asymptomatic infection, making an outbreak significantly harder to contain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wuhan, the capital of Hubei province, where the virus emerged, was locked down on 23 January. Since then misinformation and disinformation have dominated Chinese lives. Before the lockdown, experts said there was no evidence of human to human transmission and therefore no need to panic. Business carried on as usual. Wuhan hosted the Two Sessions, an annual gathering of the regional branches of the National People’s Congress and the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference. One city district held a mass banquet for forty thousand families, with a world record-beating 13,986 dishes, to bring in the approaching Chinese New Year. No need to disappoint so many good people with inconvenient public health alerts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lockdown was imposed the day before New Year’s Eve, by which point – as revealed by data harvested from Baidu’s maps app, which is installed on nearly every smartphone – five million people had already left the city, going back to see family or heading abroad for the holiday. Hospitals in Wuhan began sending out messages on Weibo in a call for public assistance: this was a situation they could no longer manage. It all came as a shock. Having repeatedly insisted that they had everything under control, the authorities were now putting nearly nine million people under indefinite quarantine – an absurd overreaction, many felt. Soon the whole country was mobilised to collect donations of money and medical supplies – face masks, biohazard suits, safety goggles, sterile gloves, tampons for female medics. Teams of doctors arrived from every province in China to join the effort and an army of engineers was deployed to build two new hospitals in ten days. Millions of people watched the buildings go up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the hospitals – more and more of them – kept on calling out for help. People started to wonder where all the money and supplies were going. The Chinese public is supposed to make donations through the Red Cross, which then directs resources to where they’re needed most. But the Red Cross in China is also known as the Red Lice (the words for ‘cross’ and ‘lice’ share the same sound, &lt;em&gt;shizi&lt;/em&gt;), thanks to a series of scandals and accusations of corruption. A particular bombshell was the Guo Meimei saga of 2011. A pretty young woman who claimed to be a Red Cross manager – her Weibo profile had a blue verification badge confirming it – was seen all over the internet flaunting her Maserati, Hermès bags and generally extravagant lifestyle. There was an uproar on social media: she was doxxed and trolled and called ‘China’s most despised woman’. Guo may not have had an official connection with the Red Cross – her actual association was murkier – but the episode drew attention to the organisation’s many shady commercial affiliates and the money being splashed around. Its reputation has never fully recovered. After the scandal, a new chief was appointed, Zhao Baige, who promised to do everything it took to restore public trust. She failed colossally. When she left the post in 2014, she didn’t say a word to the media. People who knew her say she was broken by the online mobs: no matter what she did, it was never good enough. Sceptics wonder whether she did very much at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wuhan Red Cross, like other local branches, has a tiny staff – no more than a dozen or so people. Under ordinary circumstances a job there is quite the sinecure – you get paid for doing next to nothing. Salaries are on a par with those of civil servants but there is no requirement to sit the challenging civil service exam which Long Ling described so vividly in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v42/n02/long-ling/diary&quot;&gt;a recent issue of the &lt;em&gt;LRB&lt;/em&gt; (13 January)&lt;/a&gt;. The staff’s capacity to deal with an emergency had never previously been tested. They were soon overwhelmed by the flood of donations, and it was clear that they had no idea how to allocate resources efficiently, or at all. Packages arrived from all over the world and were piled up in warehouses without being documented or sorted. Hospital workers are required to produce an official letter before they can collect supplies, and they then have to sieve through mountains of boxes to find what they need. Another state-backed nonprofit, the Wuhan Charity Federation, received around three billion yuan – more than £300 million – in public donations. After endless questions on social media about how it was planning to use the money, it decided simply to hand over 2.7 billion to the municipal government. The message this sent was: ‘This is too much money and responsibility for us. We’ll take 10 per cent, you handle the rest.’ Of course the fact that some of the funds weren’t going to be disbursed at all was only a ‘rumour’, officially denied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are endless ‘rumours’ out there to be dispelled. One day we’re told that children are less likely to be infected, the next day that pregnant women and children are more susceptible. One day they say the virus can’t survive outside the body, the next that it can live on hard surfaces for up to five days. One day we learn that the virus is capable of aerosol transmission via coughing or sneezing, the next day we’re told that’s not something to worry about. According to one piece of advice – perhaps issued on the basis that people can’t live on bad news alone – the chances of infection may be reduced by the moderate consumption of alcohol. In the face of such contradictory and shifting official guidance, a good number of people – young people especially – have been working tirelessly to challenge the rumours spreading online. It’s a thankless task, since attempts at rumour-dispelling are instantly dismissed as rumours themselves. So people meticulously record the timestamps of dubious posts and track down their sources – all in the hope that the false doesn’t drown out the useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The censor machine is working tirelessly too. Public mood is constantly monitored and analysed by AI, with countermeasures devised to match it. Take the case of Li Wenliang. Li, an ophthalmologist in Wuhan, was one of the first to warn people about the new virus. On 30 December he messaged a group of colleagues about a possible outbreak; a few days later he was summoned by police and reprimanded for ‘making false statements that disturbed the public order’. Li continued his work at the hospital and on 10 January started experiencing symptoms of infection. On 6 February, his heart stopped. Several news outlets immediately reported his death, and the country began to mourn. I’ve never seen anything like it on social media: everyone was sharing the story, praising Li’s bravery as a whistleblower. Many said they hoped it was only a rumour, that he was ‘still with us’. And then suddenly new information popped up: apparently Li remained on life support and the hospital was working to revive him. At this announcement the previously united mourners split into several camps: some sincerely prayed for his recovery; others condemned the media’s earlier reports of his death as ‘thriving on human blood’; the rest of us had suspicions about what was going on and were furious. The mock salvation ended in the early hours of the morning of 7 February, which became the official date of his death. When you wake up hearing the same news for a second time, you may still be angry – but perhaps without the same level of shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the Wuhan lockdown began, there have been tensions between local government and the central organs of the state. There is a phrase in China for the way such tensions are manifested: when everyone denies all responsibility and tries to shift the blame back onto the blamer, they are busy ‘throwing woks’. The Wuhan municipal government maintained that it had reported the virus to the central health authority in Beijing as soon as details emerged, and that Beijing’s team of experts had responded by telling them that there was no evidence of human to human transmission and the outbreak was containable. So Wuhan followed the advice it was given and carried on as normal. The experts in Beijing, meanwhile, insist that Wuhan didn’t provide them with reliable data, which made it impossible to respond with an accurate assessment. The woks flew back and forth for so long that Beijing lost patience. People under quarantine were whipping up a storm on social media in the hope of landing a hospital bed; seriously ill patients were being ignored or denied treatment; desperate sufferers were being driven to suicide; senior officials were seen on TV news using high-end N95 respirators while frontline doctors made do with disposable medical masks. The incompetence of local government, as Beijing saw it, could no longer be tolerated. An envoy was dispatched to Wuhan to inspect the mess, with a group of journalists in tow. It took the journalists no time at all to find a bus full of sick people to interview but the driver hadn’t been told where to take them. The bus drove around for hours, until the journalists finally found them a hospital. The next day, the heads of city districts were summoned into the envoy’s presence to receive their reprimand: they were made to apologise and bow to the patients they had overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throwing woks is an art you need to understand if you want to get things done in China. Whether you’re building an airport, applying for a research grant or inviting a foreign national to give a talk, you have to fill in so many forms, and get approval from so many departments with all their competing demands, that you risk getting trapped somewhere in the middle: whichever way you turn you risk causing upset or offence in one quarter or another. In the workplace too, a step in the wrong direction can provoke a superior and ruin a career, so that sometimes it’s wisest to do nothing at all. Until a virus strikes, that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the envoy’s visit, the party secretary of Hubei province was summarily removed from his job and the mayor of Shanghai, Ying Yong (the name rhymes with the word for ‘bravery’), flew in to take over. The next day, the official number of newly confirmed cases in Hubei skyrocketed, from 1638 to 14,840. Surely the virus hadn’t suddenly developed superpowers. The medical explanation was that more capacious diagnostic criteria had been applied; the media explanation was that truth will always out; the political explanation was that a new leader wants to make his mark. Or you could look at it in banking terms: bring off-balance sheet items onto the balance sheet and expose the bad debt, then adjust the accounting rules to make up for the loss in goodwill. People saw significance in the fact that Hubei’s new party secretary has a background in law enforcement and a reputation for cleaning up mess. Like the other new top-level appointees – the party secretary of the city of Wuhan was replaced the same day – he knows inside-out how bureaucracy works and how pervasive it is. Such people send a signal that they are not to be fobbed off with the usual excuses local officials mutter in their own defence. No more flying woks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The citizens of Shanghai agreed to ‘donate’ their mayor, ‘so long as we get to keep Dr Zhang’. Zhang Wenhong, director of the Department of Infectious Diseases at Shanghai’s Huashan Hospital, became a national hero for a press conference speech:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first-aid team put themselves in great danger. They are tired and need to rest. We shouldn’t take advantage of good people. From now on, I’ll replace all the frontline medics with party members from different sectors. Didn’t you all swear to put the people’s interest first when you joined the party, whatever the difficulties? I don’t care what you were actually thinking when you joined the party. Now it’s time to live up to what you promised. I don’t care if you personally agree or not: it’s non-negotiable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;leftranged&quot;&gt;The video went viral and now local citizens wouldn’t trade him for anything. When Dr Zhang told people to stay at home, they listened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcaps dropcap--d&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;espite&lt;/span&gt; the evasions and failures of party bigwigs and moguls, a fierce battle is being fought by the people on the ground. Frontline medics are working under extreme physical and mental pressure. They wear adult nappies so they don’t have to waste time taking their biohazard suits on and off when they go to the loo. Volunteer drivers are delivering medical necessities while normal transport networks remain suspended. Chinese people living overseas have been buying up stocks of face masks in Europe and beyond to send back to their families and friends. A picture of an unfazed young man in a hospital bed reading Francis Fukuyama’s &lt;em&gt;The Origins of Political Order&lt;/em&gt; was suddenly all over the internet. It reminded me of the photograph of three Englishmen choosing books in what remained of Holland House library after the Blitz. The young man received a great many love notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese medicine has played a dubious role in all this. Many believe the virus originated in a wild animal market in Wuhan. Trading and eating wild animals isn’t uncommon in Asia, partly because traditional medicine holds that some animal parts have near-magical properties. Pangolin scales are supposed to help new mothers produce milk; manta ray gills clear the lungs and cure chickenpox; the penises of pandas, tigers and bears can do the same trick as Viagra; a bit of monkey brain can make you smarter. But the market in such delicacies has also been blamed for the transmission of viruses from animals to humans. Traditional Chinese medicine may have contributed to the outbreak of the epidemic but some cling to the hope that it may also come to the rescue. On 31 January the Shanghai Institute of Materia Medica announced that a herbal mixture called &lt;em&gt;shuanghuanglian&lt;/em&gt; might be effective against the coronavirus (the &lt;em&gt;banlangen&lt;/em&gt; root was similarly said to treat SARS). &lt;em&gt;Shuanghuanglian&lt;/em&gt; sold out even more quickly than face masks. People want to believe there’s a cure. It’s true that the concoction may soothe a sore throat – the only problem is that you might catch the virus while queuing to buy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools are suspended until further notice. With many workplaces also shut, notoriously absent Chinese fathers have been forced to stay home and entertain their children. Video clips of life under quarantine are trending on TikTok. Children were presumably glad to be off school – until, that is, an app called DingTalk was introduced. Students are meant to sign in and join their class for online lessons; teachers use the app to set homework. Somehow the little brats worked out that if enough users gave the app a one-star review it would get booted off the App Store. Tens of thousands of reviews flooded in, and DingTalk’s rating plummeted overnight from 4.9 to 1.4. The app has had to beg for mercy on social media: ‘I’m only five years old myself, please don’t kill me.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With couples confined together 24/7, ordinary marital friction soon escalates into all-out war. Domestic servants, often migrants, who went out of town over the Chinese New Year, have been unable to return to work – but someone still has to do the household chores. Men slump on the sofa playing video games or hide behind a laptop pretending to work, while still expecting three meals a day and fresh laundry. A joke went around:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Client: My wife and I have been quarantined together for 14 days and we’ve decided to get back together! I don’t want to go ahead with the divorce. Can you refund the fee?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawyer: 14 days … hmmmm … Let’s not rush it: I think we’re still in business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few are profiting from the situation. Tourism is paralysed – the cruise industry may never recover – and many factories, malls, shops and restaurants are closed. The economy has suffered a huge blow. It’s like a high-speed train slamming on the brakes. Many smaller companies will be bankrupt in two or three months. Yet against all logic, the stock market is going strong. Thank heaven for the ‘invisible hand’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have now been at home for a month. I order food on my smartphone and a courier delivers it to the gate of the compound. In China, internet shopping took off after the SARS outbreak in 2003 gave Jack Ma the inspiration for Taobao, an online shopping platform on which virtually everyone these days relies. Now that the number of confirmed cases of infection is dropping, people are preparing to return to work. A real-time map allows us to monitor whether there are any cases nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of us in quarantine spend most of our time browsing social media, commenting on news stories, rumours and conspiracy theories. People on the left call for a united front against the virus. Liberals are determined to hold the government to account for everything that has gone wrong. In the West, panda-huggers say no other government would be doing better under the circumstances; dragon-slayers are cheerleading for the end of communist rule, as they do every time there is trouble in China. Whatever happens, those arguments won’t change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rightranged&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;21 February&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 07:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yarapavan</dc:creator>
<og:title>Wang Xiuying · The Word from Wuhan · LRB 22 February 2020</og:title>
<og:description>People on the left call for a united front against the virus. Liberals are determined to hold the government to account...</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v42/n05/wang-xiuying/the-word-from-wuhan</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.lrb.co.uk/media/cache/social_image/var/site/storage/images/2/1/7/1/12331712-1-eng-GB/Xiuying-Web%202.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v42/n05/wang-xiuying/the-word-from-wuhan</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dangerzone: Convert potentially dangerous PDFs, documents, or images to safe PDF</title>
<link>https://github.com/firstlookmedia/dangerzone</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/firstlookmedia/dangerzone</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Take potentially dangerous PDFs, office documents, or images and convert them to a safe PDF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/firstlookmedia/dangerzone/blob/master/assets/screenshot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/firstlookmedia/dangerzone/raw/master/assets/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dangerzone works like this: You give it a document that you don't know if you can trust (for example, an email attachment). Inside of a sandbox, dangerzone converts the document to a PDF (if it isn't already one), and then converts the PDF into raw pixel data: a huge list of of RGB color values for each page. Then, in a separate sandbox, dangerzone takes this pixel data and converts it back into a PDF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sandboxes don't have network access, so if a malicious document can compromise one, it can't phone home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dangerzone can optionally OCR the safe PDFs it creates, so it will have a text layer again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dangerzone compresses the safe PDF to reduce file size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After converting, dangerzone lets you open the safe PDF in the PDF viewer of your choice, which allows you to open PDFs and office docs in dangerzone by default so you never accidentally open a dangerous document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dangerzone can convert these types of document into safe PDFs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PDF (&lt;code&gt;.pdf&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft Word (&lt;code&gt;.docx&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.doc&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft Excel (&lt;code&gt;.xlsx&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.xls&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft PowerPoint (&lt;code&gt;.pptx&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.ppt&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ODF Text (&lt;code&gt;.odt&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ODF Spreadsheet (&lt;code&gt;.ods&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ODF Presentation (&lt;code&gt;.odp&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ODF Graphics (&lt;code&gt;.odg&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jpeg (&lt;code&gt;.jpg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.jpeg&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GIF (&lt;code&gt;.gif&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PNG (&lt;code&gt;.png&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TIFF (&lt;code&gt;.tif&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.tiff&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dangerzone was inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.invisiblethings.org/2013/02/21/converting-untrusted-pdfs-into-trusted.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Qubes trusted PDF&lt;/a&gt;, but it works in non-Qubes operating systems. It uses containers as sandboxes instead of virtual machines (using Docker for macOS, Windows, and Debian/Ubuntu, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://podman.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;podman&lt;/a&gt; for Fedora).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up a development environment by following &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/firstlookmedia/dangerzone/blob/master/BUILD.md&quot;&gt;these instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 05:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>panarky</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/16566963?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>firstlookmedia/dangerzone</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/firstlookmedia/dangerzone</og:url>
<og:description>Take potentially dangerous PDFs, office documents, or images and convert them to a safe PDF - firstlookmedia/dangerzone</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/firstlookmedia/dangerzone</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>