<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Mark Zuckerberg&amp;#039;s Facebook hearing was a sham</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/apr/11/mark-zuckerbergs-facebook-hearing-sham</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/apr/11/mark-zuckerbergs-facebook-hearing-sham</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;O&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;n Tuesday, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/apr/10/zuckerberg-facebook-testimony-latest-news-regulation-congress&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/a&gt; was in the hot seat. Cameras surrounded him. The energy in the room – and on Twitter – was electric. At last, the reluctant CEO is made to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/apr/11/mark-zuckerbergs-testimony-to-congress-the-key-moments&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;answer some questions&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except it failed. It was designed to fail. It was a show designed to get Zuckerberg off the hook after only a few hours in Washington DC. It was a show that gave the pretense of a hearing without a real hearing. It was designed to deflect and confuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each senator was given less than five minutes for questions. That meant that there was no room for follow-ups, no chance for big discoveries and many frustratingly half-developed ideas. Compare that to Bill Gates’ hearing on Microsoft, where he faced lawyers and staff for several days, or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.senate.gov/artandhistory/history/common/investigations/Kefauver.htm&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Kefauver hearings,&lt;/a&gt; which were over a year. By design, you can’t do a hearing of this magnitude in just a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;We shouldn’t be begging for Facebook’s endorsement of laws, or for Mark Zuckerberg’s promises of self-regulation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The worst moments of the hearing for us, as citizens, were when senators asked if Zuckerberg would support legislation that would regulate Facebook. I don’t care whether Zuckerberg supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Honest_Ads_Act&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Honest Ads&lt;/a&gt; or privacy laws or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt;. By asking him if he would support legislation, the senators elevated him to a kind of co-equal philosopher king whose view on Facebook regulation carried special weight. It shouldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; is a known behemoth corporate monopoly. It has exposed at least 87 million people’s data, enabled foreign propaganda and perpetuated discrimination. We shouldn’t be begging for Facebook’s endorsement of laws, or for Mark Zuckerberg’s promises of self-regulation. We should treat him as a danger to democracy and demand our senators get a real hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best senators understood this was a show, and used it as such. “Your user agreement sucks,” said John Kennedy. “Are you a monopoly?” asked Lindsey Graham. (Zuckerberg “comically” responded: “It certainly doesn’t feel like that to me.”) Richard Blumenthal said we needed laws, not promises or apologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because each senator was limited to under five minutes, Zuckerberg tried to run the clock by talking about mission, philosophy or what he believed in. There were some good questions, but there was little chance for follow up. You could almost see him, well-trained to count the minutes, playing for time when things got a little hot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senators Mazie Hirono and Cory Booker, for instance, both pointed out the damning reporting by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/people/julia-angwin&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Julia Angwin at ProPublica&lt;/a&gt;, which showed that employers and landlords were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/facebook-advertising-discrimination-housing-race-sex-national-origin&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;using Facebook for discriminatory ads.&lt;/a&gt; Zuckerberg defended the company by saying they were hard to flag, and that they depend on community flagging to stop them.&lt;/p&gt;

Zuckerberg says Facebook is cooperating with 2016 US elections investigation – video
&lt;p&gt;The tools Facebook provides make discrimination easy. Facebook has monopoly profit margins, so it could easily provide real staffing to protect against discrimination, if it wanted to. It doesn’t want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hirono and Booker could have shown that, but, like the rest of the senators, they each had only a few minutes for a line of questioning. Zuckerberg replied with vague answers about how their comments were “important” or “interesting” or “an important conversation to have”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the hearing seemed designed to figure out whether Zuckerberg is a good or bad man, or whether he has a good or bad – or bizarre – political philosophy. Zuckerberg strikes me as reliably self-serving. That doesn’t make him that interesting as the CEO of a corporate monopoly; it makes him a run-of-the-mill robber baron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asking Zuckerberg philosophical questions, such as how he thinks we should deal with questions of hate speech, treats him as a thought leader. Accepting his failures to catch discriminatory housing ads, for instance, treats him as a good-hearted actor with limited resources, instead of someone who is making monopoly margins and billions in profits.&lt;/p&gt;
 Sign up to receive the latest US opinion pieces every weekday
&lt;p&gt;In my view, we need to break up Facebook from Instagram and the other potential competitors that Facebook bought up. We need to – at a minimum – move towards opt-in, we need to hold Facebook responsible for enabling discrimination, and we need to require interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that’s not enough. There is so much we don’t know about Facebook. We know we have a corporate monopoly that has repeated serious violations that are threatening our democracy. We don’t know how their algorithm treats news organizations or content producers, how Facebook uses its own information about Facebook users or how tracking across platforms works, to just give a few examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the initial show trial is done, we need the real deal, one where no senator gets cut off after a few minutes. The real hearing would allow for unlimited questions from each of our senators, who represent millions of people. If it takes two months of sitting in Washington DC, let it take two months. This is our democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zephyr Teachout is an American academic, political activist and former political candidate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 07:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DyslexicAtheist</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/apr/11/mark-zuckerbergs-facebook-hearing-sham</og:url>
<og:description>Now that the initial show trial is done, we need the real deal</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/9f759d93e7371dd0e624fe3a8112c4b1ee97d184/0_169_5055_3033/master/5055.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19vcGluaW9ucy5wbmc&amp;s=562a28ed3fde2fc71f9ab5eb7951a330</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Mark Zuckerberg's Facebook hearing was an utter sham | Zephyr Teachout</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/apr/11/mark-zuckerbergs-facebook-hearing-sham</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Python 2 will be replaced with Python 3 in the next RHEL major release</title>
<link>https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-us/red_hat_enterprise_linux/7/html/7.5_release_notes/chap-red_hat_enterprise_linux-7.5_release_notes-deprecated_functionality</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-us/red_hat_enterprise_linux/7/html/7.5_release_notes/chap-red_hat_enterprise_linux-7.5_release_notes-deprecated_functionality</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This chapter provides an overview of functionality that has been deprecated in all minor releases of Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 up to Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deprecated functionality continues to be supported until the end of life of Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7. Deprecated functionality will likely not be supported in future major releases of this product and is not recommended for new deployments. For the most recent list of deprecated functionality within a particular major release, refer to the latest version of release documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deprecated &lt;span class=&quot;emphasis&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;hardware&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; components are not recommended for new deployments on the current or future major releases. Hardware driver updates are limited to security and critical fixes only. Red Hat recommends replacing this hardware as soon as reasonably feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;span class=&quot;emphasis&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;package&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; can be deprecated and not recommended for further use. Under certain circumstances, a package can be removed from a product. Product documentation then identifies more recent packages that offer functionality similar, identical, or more advanced to the one deprecated, and provides further recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533323016576&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; has been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; will be replaced with &lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in the next Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) major release.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533392987184&quot;&gt;LVM libraries and LVM Python bindings have been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;lvm2app&lt;/code&gt; library and LVM Python bindings, which are provided by the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;lvm2-python-libs&lt;/span&gt; package, have been deprecated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red Hat recommends the following solutions instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LVM D-Bus API in combination with the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;lvm2-dbusd&lt;/code&gt; service. This requires using Python version 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LVM command-line utilities with JSON formatting; this formatting has been available since the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;lvm2&lt;/span&gt; package version 2.02.158.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533381515456&quot;&gt;Mirrored mirror log has been deprecated in LVM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mirrored mirror log feature of mirrored LVM volumes has been deprecated. A future major release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux will no longer support creating or activating LVM volumes with a mirrored mirror log.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommended replacements are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.88558352402746&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0.41666666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;para&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;RAID1 LVM volumes. The main advantage of RAID1 volumes is their ability to work even in degraded mode and to recover after a transient failure. For information on converting mirrored volumes to RAID1, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-us/red_hat_enterprise_linux/7/html/logical_volume_manager_administration/lv#convert-mirror-to-RAID1&quot;&gt;Converting a Mirrored LVM Device to a RAID1 Device&lt;/a&gt; section in the LVM Administration guide.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disk mirror log. To convert a mirrored mirror log to disk mirror log, use the following command: &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;lvconvert --mirrorlog disk &lt;em class=&quot;replaceable&quot;&gt;my_vg/my_lv&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533359628784&quot;&gt;Deprecated packages related to Identity Management and security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following packages have been deprecated and will not be included in a future major release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;informaltable&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;lt-4-cols gt-7-rows&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;25%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;75%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th id=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Deprecated packages&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th id=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Proposed replacement package or product&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;authconfig&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;authselect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;pam_pkcs11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;sssd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;pam_krb5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;sssd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;openldap-servers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot;&gt;Depending on the use case, migrate to Identity Management included in Red Hat Enterprise Linux or to Red Hat Directory Server. &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;mod_auth_kerb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;mod_auth_gssapi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;python-kerberos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;python-krbV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;python-gssapi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;python-requests-kerberos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;python-requests-gssapi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;hesiod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot;&gt;No replacement available.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;mod_nss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;mod_ssl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359625056&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;mod_revocator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533359624576&quot;&gt;No replacement available.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;admonition&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.5, the following packages were added to the table above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533313913424&quot;&gt;Support for earlier IdM servers and for IdM replicas at domain level 0 will be limited&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red Hat does not plan to support using Identity Management (IdM) servers running Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) 7.3 and earlier with IdM clients of the next major release of RHEL. If you plan to introduce client systems running on the next major version of RHEL into a deployment that is currently managed by IdM servers running on RHEL 7.3 or earlier, be aware that you will need to upgrade the servers, moving them to RHEL 7.4 or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next major release of RHEL, only domain level 1 replicas will be supported. Before introducing IdM replicas running on the next major version of RHEL into an existing deployment, be aware that you will need to upgrade all IdM servers to RHEL 7.4 or later, and change the domain level to 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider planning the upgrade in advance if your deployment will be affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533313910656&quot;&gt;Bug-fix only support for the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;nss-pam-ldapd&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NIS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; packages in the next major release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;nss-pam-ldapd&lt;/span&gt; packages and packages related to the &lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NIS server&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; will be released in the future major release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux but will receive a limited scope of support. Red Hat will accept bug reports but no new requests for enhancements. Customers are advised to migrate to the following replacement solutions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;informaltable&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;lt-4-cols lt-7-rows&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;25%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;75%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th id=&quot;idm140533355007680&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Affected packages&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th id=&quot;idm140533355007200&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Proposed replacement package or product&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533355007680&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;nss-pam-ldapd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533355007200&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;sssd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533355007680&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;ypserv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;ypbind&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;portmap&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;yp-tools&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td headers=&quot;idm140533355007200&quot;&gt;Identity Management in Red Hat Enterprise Linux&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533363291632&quot;&gt;Use the &lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go Toolset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; instead of &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;golang&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;golang&lt;/span&gt; package has been updated to version 1.9 with Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;para&quot; readability=&quot;11.78853046595&quot;&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;golang&lt;/span&gt; package, available in the Optional channel, will be removed from a future minor release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7. Developers are encouraged to use the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Go Toolset&lt;/code&gt; instead, which is currently available as a Technology Preview through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.redhat.com/products/clang-llvm-go-rust/hello-world/index.html#fndtn-go&quot;&gt;Red Hat Developer program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533359874784&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;mesa-private-llvm&lt;/span&gt; will be replaced with &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;llvm-private&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;mesa-private-llvm&lt;/span&gt; package, which contains the LLVM-based runtime support for &lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mesa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, will be replaced in a future minor release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 with the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;llvm-private&lt;/span&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533384490496&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;libdbi&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;libdbi-drivers&lt;/span&gt; have been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;libdbi&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;libdbi-drivers&lt;/span&gt; packages will not be included in the next Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) major release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533384486656&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/code&gt; deprecated in the Extras channel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/code&gt; and its dependencies will no longer be updated through the Extras channel. Instead, the Red Hat Ansible Engine product has been made available to Red Hat Enterprise Linux subscriptions and will provide access to the official Ansible Engine channel. Customers who have previously installed &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/code&gt; and its dependencies from the Extras channel are advised to enable and update from the Ansible Engine channel, or uninstall the packages as future errata will not be provided from the Extras channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/code&gt; was previously provided in Extras (for AMD64 and Intel 64 architectures, and IBM POWER, little endian) as a runtime dependency of, and limited in support to, the Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) System Roles. Ansible Engine is available today for AMD64 and Intel 64 architectures, with IBM POWER, little endian availability coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/code&gt; in the Extras channel was not a part of the Red Hat Enterprise Linux FIPS validation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following packages have been deprecated from the Extras channel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;ansible(-doc)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;libtomcrypt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;libtommath(-devel)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;python2-crypto&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;python2-jmespath&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;python-httplib2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;python-paramiko(-doc)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;python-passlib&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;sshpass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that Red Hat Enterprise Linux System Roles, available as a Technology Preview, continue to be distributed though the Extras channel. Although Red Hat Enterprise Linux System Roles no longer depend on the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;ansible&lt;/span&gt; package, installing &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;ansible&lt;/span&gt; from the Ansible Engine repository is still needed to run playbooks which use Red Hat Enterprise Linux System Roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533367198672&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;signtool&lt;/code&gt; has been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;signtool&lt;/code&gt; tool from the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;nss&lt;/span&gt; packages, which uses insecure signature algorithms, has been deprecated and will not be included in a future minor release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533367195136&quot;&gt;TLS compression support has been removed from &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;nss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prevent security risks, such as the CRIME attack, support for TLS compression in the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;NSS&lt;/code&gt; library has been removed for all TLS versions. This change preserves the API compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533390660768&quot;&gt;Public web CAs are no longer trusted for code signing by default&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mozilla CA certificate trust list distributed with Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.5 no longer trusts any public web CAs for code signing. As a consequence, any software that uses the related flags, such as &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;NSS&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;OpenSSL&lt;/code&gt;, no longer trusts these CAs for code signing by default. The software continues to fully support code signing trust. Additionally, it is still possible to configure CA certificates as trusted for code signing using system configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533376557312&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Sendmail&lt;/code&gt; has been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Sendmail&lt;/code&gt; has been deprecated in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7. Customers are advised to use &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Postfix&lt;/code&gt;, which is configured as the default Mail Transfer Agent (MTA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533376553984&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;dmraid&lt;/span&gt; has been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.5, the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;dmraid&lt;/span&gt; packages have been deprecated. It will stay available in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 releases but a future major release will no longer support legacy hybrid combined hardware and software RAID host bus adapter (HBA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533316710512&quot;&gt;Automatic loading of &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;DCCP&lt;/code&gt; modules through socket layer is now disabled by default&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For security reasons, automatic loading of the &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;Datagram Congestion Control Protocol (DCCP)&lt;/code&gt; kernel modules through socket layer is now disabled by default. This ensures that userspace applications can not maliciously load any modules. All &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;DCCP&lt;/code&gt; related modules can still be loaded manually through the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;modprobe&lt;/code&gt; program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;/etc/modprobe.d/dccp-blacklist.conf&lt;/code&gt; configuration file for blacklisting the &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;DCCP&lt;/code&gt; modules is included in the kernel package. Entries included there can be cleared by editing or removing this file to restore the previous behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that any re-installation of the same kernel package or of a different version does not override manual changes. If the file is manually edited or removed, these changes persist across package installations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533362332704&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;rsyslog-libdbi&lt;/span&gt; has been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;rsyslog-libdbi&lt;/span&gt; sub-package, which contains one of the less used &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;rsyslog&lt;/code&gt; module, has been deprecated and will not be included in a future major release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux. Removing unused or rarely used modules helps users to conveniently find a database output to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533377385152&quot;&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;inputname&lt;/code&gt; option of the &lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rsyslog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;imudp&lt;/code&gt; module has been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;inputname&lt;/code&gt; option of the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;imudp&lt;/code&gt; module for the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;rsyslog&lt;/code&gt; service has been deprecated. Use the &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; option instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533368170544&quot;&gt;SMBv1 is no longer installed with Microsoft Windows 10 and 2016 (updates 1709 and later)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft announced that the Server Message Block version 1 (SMBv1) protocol will no longer be installed with the latest versions of Microsoft Windows and Microsoft Windows Server. Microsoft also recommends users to disable SMBv1 on earlier versions of these products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update impacts Red Hat customers who operate their systems in a mixed Linux and Windows environment. Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.1 and earlier support only the SMBv1 version of the protocol. Support for SMBv2 was introduced in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533353486288&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;FedFS&lt;/code&gt; has been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federated File System (FedFS) has been deprecated because the upstream FedFS project is no longer being actively maintained. Red Hat recommends migrating FedFS installations to use &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;autofs&lt;/code&gt;, which provides more flexible functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533353483232&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Btrfs&lt;/code&gt; has been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Btrfs&lt;/code&gt; file system has been in Technology Preview state since the initial release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6. Red Hat will not be moving &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Btrfs&lt;/code&gt; to a fully supported feature and it will be removed in a future major release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;Btrfs&lt;/code&gt; file system did receive numerous updates from the upstream in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.4 and will remain available in the Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 series. However, this is the last planned update to this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533364089184&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;tcp_wrappers&lt;/span&gt; deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;tcp_wrappers&lt;/span&gt; package has been deprecated. &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;tcp_wrappers&lt;/span&gt; provides a library and a small daemon program that can monitor and filter incoming requests for &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;audit&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;cyrus-imap&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;dovecot&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;nfs-utils&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;openssh&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;openldap&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;proftpd&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;sendmail&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;stunnel&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;syslog-ng&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;vsftpd&lt;/span&gt;, and various other network services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533314284688&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;nautilus-open-terminal&lt;/span&gt; replaced with &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;gnome-terminal-nautilus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.3, the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;nautilus-open-terminal&lt;/span&gt; package has been deprecated and replaced with the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;gnome-terminal-nautilus&lt;/span&gt; package. This package provides a Nautilus extension that adds the  option to the right-click context menu in Nautilus. &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;nautilus-open-terminal&lt;/span&gt; is replaced by &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;gnome-terminal-nautilus&lt;/span&gt; during the system upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533351923968&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;sslwrap()&lt;/code&gt; removed from &lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;para&quot; readability=&quot;9.76&quot;&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;sslwrap()&lt;/code&gt; function has been removed from &lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python 2.7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. After the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0466/&quot;&gt;466 Python Enhancement Proposal&lt;/a&gt; was implemented, using this function resulted in a segmentation fault. The removal is consistent with upstream. Red Hat recommends using the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;ssl.wrap_socket()&lt;/code&gt; function instead.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533355099680&quot;&gt;Symbols from libraries linked as dependencies no longer resolved by &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;ld&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;ld&lt;/code&gt; linker resolved any symbols present in any linked library, even if some libraries were linked only implicitly as dependencies of other libraries. This allowed developers to use symbols from the implicitly linked libraries in application code and omit explicitly specifying these libraries for linking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For security reasons, &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;ld&lt;/code&gt; has been changed to not resolve references to symbols in libraries linked implicitly as dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, linking with &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;ld&lt;/code&gt; fails when application code attempts to use symbols from libraries not declared for linking and linked only implicitly as dependencies. To use symbols from libraries linked as dependencies, developers must explicitly link against these libraries as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;para&quot; readability=&quot;8.4&quot;&gt;To restore the previous behavior of &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;ld&lt;/code&gt;, use the &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-copy-dt-needed-entries&lt;/code&gt; command-line option. (BZ#&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1292230&quot;&gt;1292230&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533354820928&quot;&gt;Windows guest virtual machine support limited&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7, Windows guest virtual machines are supported only under specific subscription programs, such as Advanced Mission Critical (AMC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533358329360&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libnetlink&lt;/code&gt; is deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libnetlink&lt;/code&gt; library contained in the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;iproute-devel&lt;/span&gt; package has been deprecated. The user should use the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libnl&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libmnl&lt;/code&gt; libraries instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533360703824&quot;&gt;S3 and S4 power management states for KVM have been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Native KVM support for the S3 (suspend to RAM) and S4 (suspend to disk) power management states has been discontinued. This feature was previously available as a Technology Preview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533360701344&quot;&gt;The Certificate Server plug-in udnPwdDirAuth is discontinued&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;udnPwdDirAuth&lt;/code&gt; authentication plug-in for the Red Hat Certificate Server was removed in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.3. Profiles using the plug-in are no longer supported. Certificates created with a profile using the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;udnPwdDirAuth&lt;/code&gt; plug-in are still valid if they have been approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533366413648&quot;&gt;Red Hat Access plug-in for IdM is discontinued&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red Hat Access plug-in for Identity Management (IdM) was removed in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.3. During the update, the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;redhat-access-plugin-ipa&lt;/span&gt; package is automatically uninstalled. Features previously provided by the plug-in, such as Knowledgebase access and support case engagement, are still available through the Red Hat Customer Portal. Red Hat recommends to explore alternatives, such as the &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;redhat-support-tool&lt;/code&gt; tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533322524096&quot;&gt;The Ipsilon identity provider service for federated single sign-on&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;ipsilon&lt;/span&gt; packages were introduced as Technology Preview in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.2. Ipsilon links authentication providers and applications or utilities to allow for single sign-on (SSO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red Hat does not plan to upgrade Ipsilon from Technology Preview to a fully supported feature. The &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;ipsilon&lt;/span&gt; packages will be removed from Red Hat Enterprise Linux in a future minor release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red Hat has released Red Hat Single Sign-On as a web SSO solution based on the Keycloak community project. Red Hat Single Sign-On provides greater capabilities than Ipsilon and is designated as the standard web SSO solution across the Red Hat product portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533322519312&quot;&gt;Several &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;rsyslog&lt;/code&gt; options deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;rsyslog&lt;/code&gt; utility version in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.4 has deprecated a large number of options. These options no longer have any effect and cause a warning to be displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functionality previously provided by the options &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-c&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-u&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-q&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-x&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-A&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-Q&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-4&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-6&lt;/code&gt; can be achieved using the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;rsyslog&lt;/code&gt; configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no replacement for the functionality previously provided by the options &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-l&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;-s&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533365256432&quot;&gt;Deprecated symbols from the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;memkind&lt;/code&gt; library&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following symbols from the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;memkind&lt;/code&gt; library have been deprecated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;memkind_finalize()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;memkind_get_num_kind()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;memkind_get_kind_by_partition()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;memkind_get_kind_by_name()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;memkind_partition_mmap()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;memkind_get_size()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_MEMALIGN&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_MALLCTL&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_GETCPU&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_PMTT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_TIEDISTANCE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_ALIGNMENT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_MALLOCX&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_REPNAME&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_PTHREAD&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_BADPOLICY&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;MEMKIND_ERROR_REPPOLICY&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533377765872&quot;&gt;Options of Sockets API Extensions for SCTP (RFC 6458) deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The options &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;SCTP_SNDRCV&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;SCTP_EXTRCV&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;SCTP_DEFAULT_SEND_PARAM&lt;/code&gt; of Sockets API Extensions for the Stream Control Transmission Protocol have been deprecated per the RFC 6458 specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New options &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;SCTP_SNDINFO&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;SCTP_NXTINFO&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;SCTP_NXTINFO&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;SCTP_DEFAULT_SNDINFO&lt;/code&gt; have been implemented as a replacement for the deprecated options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533390284640&quot;&gt;Managing NetApp ONTAP using SSLv2 and SSLv3 is no longer supported by &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libstorageMgmt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SSLv2 and SSLv3 connections to the NetApp ONTAP storage array are no longer supported by the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libstorageMgmt&lt;/code&gt; library. Users can contact NetApp support to enable the Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533390281296&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;dconf-dbus-1&lt;/code&gt; has been deprecated and &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;dconf-editor&lt;/code&gt; is now delivered separately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this update, the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;dconf-dbus-1&lt;/code&gt; API has been removed. However, the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;dconf-dbus-1&lt;/code&gt; library has been backported to preserve binary compatibility. Red Hat recommends using the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;GDBus&lt;/code&gt; library instead of &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;dconf-dbus-1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;filename&quot;&gt;dconf-error.h&lt;/code&gt; file has been renamed to &lt;code class=&quot;filename&quot;&gt;dconf-enums.h&lt;/code&gt;. In addition, the &lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dconf Editor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is now delivered in the separate &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;dconf-editor&lt;/span&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533374991936&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;FreeRADIUS&lt;/code&gt; no longer accepts &lt;code class=&quot;option&quot;&gt;Auth-Type := System&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;FreeRADIUS&lt;/code&gt; server no longer accepts the &lt;code class=&quot;option&quot;&gt;Auth-Type := System&lt;/code&gt; option for the &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;rlm_unix&lt;/code&gt; authentication module. This option has been replaced by the use of the &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;unix&lt;/code&gt; module in the &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;authorize&lt;/code&gt; section of the configuration file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533352294560&quot;&gt;Deprecated Device Drivers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following device drivers continue to be supported until the end of life of Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 but will likely not be supported in future major releases of this product and are not recommended for new deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3w-9xxx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3w-sas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;aic79xx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;aoe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;arcmsr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ata drivers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;acard-ahci&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_mv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_nv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_promise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_qstor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_sil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_sil24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_sis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_svw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_sx4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_uli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_via&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sata_vsc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bfa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cxgb3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cxgb3i&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hptiop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;isci&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iw_cxgb3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mptbase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mptctl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mptsas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mptscsih&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mptspi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mtip32xx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mvsas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mvumi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OSD drivers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;osd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libosd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;osst&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata drivers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_acpi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_ali&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_amd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_arasan_cf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_artop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_atiixp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_atp867x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_cmd64x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_cs5536&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_hpt366&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_hpt37x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_hpt3x2n&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_hpt3x3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_it8213&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_it821x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_jmicron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_marvell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_netcell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_ninja32&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_oldpiix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_pdc2027x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_pdc202xx_old&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_piccolo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_rdc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_sch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_serverworks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_sil680&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_sis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pata_via&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pdc_adma&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pm80xx(pm8001)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pmcraid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;qla3xxx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;stex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sx8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ufshcd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533314688816&quot;&gt;Deprecated Adapters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following adapters from the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;aacraid&lt;/code&gt; driver have been deprecated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;93&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERC 2/Si (Iguana/PERC2Si), PCI ID 0x1028:0x0001&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERC 3/Di (Opal/PERC3Di), PCI ID 0x1028:0x0002&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERC 3/Si (SlimFast/PERC3Si), PCI ID 0x1028:0x0003&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERC 3/Di (Iguana FlipChip/PERC3DiF), PCI ID 0x1028:0x0004&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERC 3/Di (Viper/PERC3DiV), PCI ID 0x1028:0x0002&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERC 3/Di (Lexus/PERC3DiL), PCI ID 0x1028:0x0002&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERC 3/Di (Jaguar/PERC3DiJ), PCI ID 0x1028:0x000a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERC 3/Di (Dagger/PERC3DiD), PCI ID 0x1028:0x000a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERC 3/Di (Boxster/PERC3DiB), PCI ID 0x1028:0x000a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;catapult, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0283&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tomcat, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0284&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptec 2120S (Crusader), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptec 2200S (Vulcan), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptec 2200S (Vulcan-2m), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legend S220 (Legend Crusader), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legend S230 (Legend Vulcan), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptec 3230S (Harrier), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptec 3240S (Tornado), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-2020ZCR SCSI PCI-X ZCR (Skyhawk), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-2025ZCR SCSI SO-DIMM PCI-X ZCR (Terminator), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-2230S + ASR-2230SLP PCI-X (Lancer), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-2130S (Lancer), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAR-2820SA (Intruder), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAR-2620SA (Intruder), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAR-2420SA (Intruder), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICP9024RO (Lancer), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICP9014RO (Lancer), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICP9047MA (Lancer), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICP9087MA (Lancer), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICP5445AU (Hurricane44), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICP9085LI (Marauder-X), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICP5085BR (Marauder-E), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICP9067MA (Intruder-6), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themisto Jupiter Platform, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0287&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themisto Jupiter Platform, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0200&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Callisto Jupiter Platform, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-2020SA SATA PCI-X ZCR (Skyhawk), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-2025SA SATA SO-DIMM PCI-X ZCR (Terminator), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAR-2410SA PCI SATA 4ch (Jaguar II), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CERC SATA RAID 2 PCI SATA 6ch (DellCorsair), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAR-2810SA PCI SATA 8ch (Corsair-8), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAR-21610SA PCI SATA 16ch (Corsair-16), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESD SO-DIMM PCI-X SATA ZCR (Prowler), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAR-2610SA PCI SATA 6ch, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-2240S (SabreExpress), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-4005, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM 8i (AvonPark), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM 8i (AvonPark Lite), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM 8k/8k-l8 (Aurora), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM 8k/8k-l4 (Aurora Lite), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-4000 (BlackBird), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-4800SAS (Marauder-X), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-4805SAS (Marauder-E), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASR-3800 (Hurricane44), PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perc 320/DC, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptec 5400S (Mustang), PCI ID 0x1011:0x0046&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptec 5400S (Mustang), PCI ID 0x1011:0x0046&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dell PERC2/QC, PCI ID 0x1011:0x0046&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HP NetRAID-4M, PCI ID 0x1011:0x0046&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dell Catchall, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legend Catchall, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptec Catch All, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0285&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptec Rocket Catch All, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptec NEMER/ARK Catch All, PCI ID 0x9005:0x0288&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following adapters from the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;mpt2sas&lt;/code&gt; driver have been deprecated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS2004, PCI ID 0x1000:0x0070&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS2008, PCI ID 0x1000:0x0072&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS2108_1, PCI ID 0x1000:0x0074&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS2108_2, PCI ID 0x1000:0x0076&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS2108_3, PCI ID 0x1000:0x0077&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS2116_1, PCI ID 0x1000:0x0064&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS2116_2, PCI ID 0x1000:0x0065&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SSS6200, PCI ID 0x1000:0x007E&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following adapters from the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;megaraid_sas&lt;/code&gt; driver have been deprecated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dell PERC5, PCI ID 0x1028:0x15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS1078R, PCI ID 0x1000:0x60&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS1078DE, PCI ID 0x1000:0x7C&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS1064R, PCI ID 0x1000:0x411&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VERDE_ZCR, PCI ID 0x1000:0x413&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS1078GEN2, PCI ID 0x1000:0x78&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS0079GEN2, PCI ID 0x1000:0x79&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS0073SKINNY, PCI ID 0x1000:0x73&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAS0071SKINNY, PCI ID 0x1000:0x71&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following adapters from the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;qla2xxx&lt;/code&gt; driver have been deprecated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ISP24xx, PCI ID 0x1077:0x2422&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ISP24xx, PCI ID 0x1077:0x2432&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ISP2422, PCI ID 0x1077:0x5422&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLE220, PCI ID 0x1077:0x5432&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLE81xx, PCI ID 0x1077:0x8001&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLE10000, PCI ID 0x1077:0xF000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLE84xx, PCI ID 0x1077:0x8044&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLE8000, PCI ID 0x1077:0x8432&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLE82xx, PCI ID 0x1077:0x8021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following adapters from the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;qla4xxx&lt;/code&gt; driver have been deprecated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLOGIC_ISP8022, PCI ID 0x1077:0x8022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLOGIC_ISP8324, PCI ID 0x1077:0x8032&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLOGIC_ISP8042, PCI ID 0x1077:0x8042&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following Ethernet adapter controlled by the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;be2net&lt;/code&gt; driver has been deprecated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following adapters from the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;be2iscsi&lt;/code&gt; driver have been deprecated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;itemizedlist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emulex OneConnect 10Gb iSCSI Initiator (generic), PCI ID 0x212&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCe10101, OCm10101, OCe10102, OCm10102 BE2 adapter family, PCI ID 0x702&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCe10100 BE2 adapter family, PCI ID 0x703&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;listitem&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following adapters from the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;lpfc&lt;/code&gt; driver have been deprecated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check the PCI IDs of the hardware on your system, run the &lt;code class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;lspci -nn&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that other adapters from the mentioned drivers that are not listed here remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533378074512&quot;&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libcxgb3&lt;/code&gt; library and the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;cxgb3&lt;/span&gt; firmware package have been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libcxgb3&lt;/code&gt; library provided by the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;libibverbs&lt;/span&gt; package and the &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;cxgb3&lt;/span&gt; firmware package have been deprecated. They continue to be supported in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 but will likely not be supported in the next major releases of this product. This change corresponds with the deprecation of the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;cxgb3&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;cxgb3i&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;iw_cxgb3&lt;/code&gt; drivers listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533372076176&quot;&gt;SFN4XXX adapters have been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.4, SFN4XXX Solarflare network adapters have been deprecated. Previously, Solarflare had a single driver &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;sfc&lt;/code&gt; for all adapters. Recently, support of SFN4XXX was split from &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;sfc&lt;/code&gt; and moved into a new SFN4XXX-only driver, called &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;sfc-falcon&lt;/code&gt;. Both drivers continue to be supported at this time, but &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;sfc-falcon&lt;/code&gt; and SFN4XXX support is scheduled for removal in a future major release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533385815616&quot;&gt;Software-initiated-only FCoE storage technologies have been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software-initiated-only type of the Fibre Channel over Ethernet (FCoE) storage technology has been deprecated due to limited customer adoption. The software-initiated-only storage technology will remain supported for the life of Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7. The deprecation notice indicates the intention to remove software-initiated-based FCoE support in a future major release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the hardware support and the associated user-space tools (such as drivers, &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libfc&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libfcoe&lt;/code&gt;) are unaffected by this deprecation notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;idm140533362400848&quot;&gt;Containers using the &lt;code class=&quot;systemitem&quot;&gt;libvirt-lxc&lt;/code&gt; tooling have been deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;para&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;The following &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;libvirt-lxc&lt;/span&gt; packages are deprecated since Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.1:

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future development on the Linux containers framework is now based on the &lt;span class=&quot;application&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;docker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; command-line interface. &lt;span class=&quot;package&quot;&gt;libvirt-lxc&lt;/span&gt; tooling may be removed in a future release of Red Hat Enterprise Linux (including Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7) and should not be relied upon for developing custom container management applications.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 06:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alianinfo</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-us/red_hat_enterprise_linux/7/html/7.5_release_notes/chap-red_hat_enterprise_linux-7.5_release_notes-deprecated_functionality</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AV1 beats x264 and libvpx-vp9 in practical use case</title>
<link>https://code.facebook.com/posts/253852078523394/av1-beats-x264-and-libvpx-vp9-in-practical-use-case/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://code.facebook.com/posts/253852078523394/av1-beats-x264-and-libvpx-vp9-in-practical-use-case/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Improved video compression is important for delivering digital video files more quickly and with higher quality, while using less bandwidth and storage. Everything from 4K movie streaming to smartphone video chat to laptop screen sharing can be enhanced by making the video files smaller through better compression codecs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Alliance for Open Media — a consortium founded in 2015 and made up of video-on-demand providers including Amazon, Facebook, Google, Microsoft and Netflix, along with web browser developers and semiconductor firms — has just released AV1 (also known as AOMedia Video 1), a new open, royalty-free video format that promises to be a significant step forward in compression efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tested the new codec under conditions that closely match the most common real-world use cases for Facebook video. Our test examined AV1's performance vs. practical open source video encoders that can be deployed to a practical production system, rather than merely testing efficiency vs. standard reference software encoders (i.e., H.264/AVC Joint Model or JM). By structuring the test this way, we were able to show how the codec will perform in a true production environment compared with current widely used alternatives, such as x264 and libvpx-vp9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our testing shows AV1 surpasses its stated goal of 30% better compression than VP9, and achieves gains of 50.3%, 46.2% and 34.0%, compared to x264 main profile, x264 high profile and libvpx-vp9, respectively. The new codec requires longer encoding times vs. current alternatives, however, due to increased complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our tests were conducted primarily with Standard Definition (SD) and High Definition (HD) video files, because those are currently the most popular video formats on Facebook. But because AV1's performance increased as video resolution increased, we conclude the new compression codec will likely deliver even higher efficiency gains with UHD/4K and 8K content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the official public release of AV1 on March 28, 2018, these results should foster confidence that the technology is capable of significant gains in compression in real-world implementations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specifics of our testing process and results below will help engineers evaluate AV1 compression performance in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Test Methodology and Evaluation Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of using uncompressed test video sequences, such as common test sequences in video standard quality evaluation or public test sequences in &lt;a href=&quot;https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fmedia.xiph.org%2Fvideo%2Fderf%2F&amp;amp;h=ATPvtZ7L9jLtplJvb6Vh5JCf-SK1uGTlesWReSI0FsssTcR6dzqthBslNCiaM7eWa0UYCFCa32ELjl7jGZkB56zo0x3qk2qs7x2bFveSqJzGFqAqpIsXsWcx15fRqz5fqrEM&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-lynx-mode=&quot;hover&quot;&gt;https://media.xiph.org/video/derf/&lt;/a&gt;, our experiment selected 400 top-viewed public videos from Facebook (FB) Pages. Those videos had the following characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Most videos were recorded on smartphones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They were already compressed on the client side before being uploaded to Facebook servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most were SD or HD, instead of UHD/4K or 8K.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;As these criteria make clear, the test content was quite different from that in video standard test conditions, where uncompressed and UHD test sequences are essential for recent video standard quality evaluation. The already-compressed test content was decompressed first and then re-compressed by all tested encoders. Again, this approach allowed us to gauge how AV1 would perform in a real-world production environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To measure the representation of these videos, the content analysis was conducted according to ITU-T P.910 &lt;em&gt;Subjective video quality assessment methods for multimedia applications&lt;/em&gt;. This content analysis is useful to show the relative spatial information and temporal information found in the various videos available, since the compression difficulty is directly related to the spatial and temporal information of a video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to scene change within the video, except for the maximum values of the standard deviation as recommended in ITU-T P.910, the median values of spatial and temporal information are also calculated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/29664631_1622111287843678_5744192774677200896_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=9e12187ba4ee8ac2752264802ab16b8e&amp;amp;oe=5B5ED88D&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 1 shows scatter plots of the spatial and temporal information for all 400 FB top videos (the first 10 seconds). The plots show a wide spread of content coverage, including slow/fast motion and low/high spatial complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/29661926_182397725725321_6175763432315289600_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=62430db9a6f424412d80bd458917e2b2&amp;amp;oe=5B584E63&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Figure 1a. Scatter plots of spatial and temporal information (max) for 400 FB top videos&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/29795722_650772711920429_7325788754575097856_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=47ad1d60fa0639cf46a30cad6e4c7400&amp;amp;oe=5B2C1D21&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Figure 1b. Scatter plots of spatial and temporal information (median) for 400 FB top videos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Encoder Implementations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For AV1 encodings, we used a snapshot version of AOM AV1 reference software. For H.264/AVC and VP9 encodings, we used ffmpeg version 3.3.3, with corresponding libx264 and libvpx-vp9 libraries. Table 1 lists the video codec versions used in our test setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/22538454_1258297544315183_8656247985107107840_n.png?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=c4cc414ee4b623a0e23d710cb3829b2c&amp;amp;oe=5B5A4FB2&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Table 1. Video codec versions used in test setup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are details on the three codecs used in our test:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AV1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This snapshot version was fetched from AOM AV1 repository when the AV1 specification was officially released on March 28, 2018. The coding performance of AV1 should be stable since this snapshot version, and the main focus of current AV1 development is on speed optimization to make it practical for use in production systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;x264&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;x264 is a well-known video encoder for H.264/AVC and provides best-in-class performance, compression, and features with ~24% better encoding than the second place encoder in &lt;a href=&quot;http://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.compression.ru%2Fvideo%2Fcodec_comparison%2Fh264_2010%2F&amp;amp;h=ATNcsZEy0WadWfv-LdkpXd6A-jut8ov_LfYTNY5xBLnX5o_oMuFGgQWJfJj38TBwfjptusz8T85pppRUhzmhirLqzNBOxGAfE4DF1Q_07LsdEDA5PEClfzAVHGPCh_fxAQui&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-lynx-mode=&quot;hover&quot;&gt;MSU Sixth MPEG-4 AVC/H.264 Video Codecs Comparison&lt;/a&gt;. x264 is widely used in the core of many web video services, including Facebook's, and adopted by television broadcasters and ISPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;libvpx-vp9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The free software video codec library libvpx was developed by Google and serves as the reference software implementation for the video coding formats VP8 and VP9. With the release of 1.5 and 1.6, libvpx-vp9 delivered significant speedups for both encoding and decoding, which make it practical for use in production systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Encoder configurations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to determine the bit rates in a content-adaptive way, each video was first encoded using Constant Rate Factor (CRF) or Quantization Parameter (QP) mode with 6 CRF/QP values; then the output bit rates in CRF/QP encoding stage are fed into the 2-pass Adaptive Bit Rate (ABR) encoding. To match the quality/bit rate range across codecs, the following CRF/QP values were used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;x264 CRF = {19, 23, 27, 31, 35, 39}, VP9/AV1 CRF/QP = {27, 33, 39, 45, 51, 57}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CRF/QP and ABR configurations are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/30507605_419145771878905_2825510859206295552_n.png?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=da064fbb9affad2f4aed76d8465bba3c&amp;amp;oe=5B2D0F60&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Table 2. CRF/QP and ABR configurations for codecs
&lt;p&gt;We chose settings that reflect the most common x264 and libvpx-vp9 encoding setting used in Facebook Video On Demand (VOD) applications. Since both x264’s main profile and high profile are used in Facebook video encoding, they are reported separately. AV1 tries to match x264 and libvpx-vp9’s encoding setting. Note: In order to match other codecs’ settings, our test used “--kf-max-dist=60 --kf-min-dist=60” for AV1, instead of the setting originally recommended by Google's WebM team (“--kf-max-dist=150 --kf-min-dist=0”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Experimental Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compression efficiency was measured by the Bjontegaard-Delta rate (BD-rate) metric, which calculates the average bit-rate differences between Rate-Distortion (R-D) curves for the same distortion, e.g., for the same Peak Signal-to-Noise Ratio (PSNR) or Structural Similarity (SSIM). Note that negative BD-rate values indicate actual bit rate savings. As outlined above, the test used 400 FB videos for different resolutions (360p/480p/720p/1080p) with 30fps, 16:9 aspect ratio, 1:1 pixel aspect ratio and 8bit depth. The first 10 seconds were extracted from each video for encoding tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Experimental Results for CRF/QP&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 and Figure 3 show AV1 BD-rate savings for CRF/QP mode against x264 main, x264 high, and libvpx-vp9. In terms of PSNR, the average BD-rate savings of AV1 relative to x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9 are 50.0%, 45.8% and 32.9%, respectively. In terms of SSIM, the average BD-rate savings of AV1 relative to x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9 are 49.8%, 45.7% and 40.5%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the encoding computational complexity (in terms of encoding run time) of AV1 compared with x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9 for CRF/QP mode was increased by factors of 5721.5x, 5869.9x and 658.5x, respectively, as shown in Figure 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize the BD-rate performance of all tested encoders for CRF/QP mode, Table 3 provides an overview of cross-codec comparisons in terms of PSNR and SSIM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/29795685_502817926786736_6379961596499722240_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=8f86b562b5e1e9e6e767c70802e9acf1&amp;amp;oe=5B6C4C65&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Figure 2. AV1 BD-rate saving in terms of PSNR for CRF/QP mode against x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/29661791_2034670206751165_3521651772860923904_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=3ed7f5614a6ecdd525b861c2a4692b3b&amp;amp;oe=5B5D3738&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Figure 3. AV1 BD-rate saving in terms of SSIM for CRF/QP mode against x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/29797421_213340995927039_730735552373981184_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=a57543b605d1b9ffbdf9bbbba7af3e26&amp;amp;oe=5B28F704&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Figure 4. AV1 encoding time increase ratio for CRF/QP mode against x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/29918764_2016330071941268_4860755076047699968_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=66623fde9155bb3cb044a1a988baac9e&amp;amp;oe=5B6BD5AB&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Table 3. Summary of BD-rate performance of all test encoders for CRF/QP mode in terms of PSNR and SSIM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Experimental Results for ABR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 5 and Figure 6 show AV1 BD-rate savings for ABR mode against x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9. In terms of PSNR, the average BD-rate savings of AV1 relative to x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9 were 51.0%, 47.0% and 29.9%, respectively. In terms of SSIM, the average BD-rate savings of AV1 relative to x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9 were 50.3%, 46.3% and 32.5%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, AV1 saw increases in encoding computational complexity compared with x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9 for ABR mode. Encoding run time was 9226.4x, 8139.2x and 667.1x greater, respectively, as shown in Figure 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize the BD-rate performance of all tested encoders for ABR mode, Table 4 provides an overview of cross-codec comparisons in terms of PSNR and SSIM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/30179786_321236495069511_3989848176432513024_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=736cae554369cdc1fb323dfb4e12bd33&amp;amp;oe=5B2C9B84&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Figure 5. AV1 BD-rate saving in terms of PSNR for ABR mode against x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/30515290_1885725448391730_2707405129786589184_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=429652b0c188ee07726b95b4fef468be&amp;amp;oe=5B2C9E4B&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Figure 6. AV1 BD-rate saving in terms of SSIM for ABR mode against x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/30179634_213060259453407_4307818495279628288_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=ad2abbb337b2ad7ba24c0ba31e844531&amp;amp;oe=5B6104C7&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Figure 7. AV1 encoding time increase ratio for ABR mode against x264 main, x264 high and libvpx-vp9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;_253 img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/29918945_584484758580483_6847837256208613376_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=69b7e33fa5436ad866d6a3f78efb4325&amp;amp;oe=5B69E2C4&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Table 4. Summary of BD-rate performance of all test encoders for ABR mode in terms of PSNR and SSIM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results should give engineers confidence in how AV1 performs and speed up the adoption of AV1 in production systems. Based on our findings, software developers can look to add support for AV1 knowing it outperforms its efficiency targets in these real-world conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook will continue to promote the adoption of AV1 in our production systems. We plan to gradually serve AV1 content on web for popular Facebook videos once major web browsers such as Chrome and Firefox implement AV1 support. Users watching AV1 content will enjoy better quality at the same bit rate or see 30% to 50% less buffering at the same quality compared with VP9 or H.264/AVC content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;_4f8k&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More to Read&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:title>AV1 beats x264 and libvpx-vp9 in practical use case</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://code.facebook.com/posts/253852078523394/av1-beats-x264-and-libvpx-vp9-in-practical-use-case/</og:url>
<og:image>https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/29795665_257271491482290_7711797750597156864_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;oh=6b2602ceb27b5611c0be6acd3e48b6e8&amp;oe=5B28E26B</og:image>
<og:description>A performance test of AV1, a new open, royalty-free video format, finds it surpasses its stated goal of 30% better compression in common real-world use cases.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://code.facebook.com/posts/253852078523394/av1-beats-x264-and-libvpx-vp9-in-practical-use-case/?_fb_noscript=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We saved $50k/year with a Go microservice coded in a hackathon</title>
<link>https://movio.co/en/blog/saving-money-with-Hackathon-project/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://movio.co/en/blog/saving-money-with-Hackathon-project/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In the past few weeks we've rolled out a Go microservice called &quot;KIB&quot; to production, which reduced a huge portion of the infrastructure necessary for &lt;a href=&quot;https://movio.co/en/movio-cinema/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Movio Cinema&lt;/a&gt;'s core tools: Group Builder and Campaign Execution. In doing this, we saved considerable AWS bills, after-hours and office-hours support bills, significantly simplified our architecture and made our product 80% faster on average. We wrote KIB on a Hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that the domain-specific components of this post don't apply to every dev team, the success of applying the &lt;a href=&quot;https://go-proverbs.github.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;guiding principles&lt;/a&gt; of simplicity and pragmatism driving our decision-making process felt like a story worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Group Builder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movio Cinema's core functionality is to send targeted marketing campaigns to a cinema chain's loyalty members. If you're a member of a big cinema chain’s loyalty program, wherever you are in the world, chances are the emails you're getting from it come from us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group Builder facilitates the segmentation of loyalty members by the construction of groups of filters of varying complexity over the cinema's loyalty member base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;filer_image&quot; alt=&quot;Group Builder Screenshot.png&quot; src=&quot;https://movio-live-2bb6ef96eabb4f369327a8b01ec1-73a1b1f.aldryn-media.io/filer_public_thumbnails/filer_public/c9/1d/c91d9d22-6e24-4b40-a0ab-8c3eb7d1e089/group_builder_screenshot.png__2020x1500_q90_crop_subsampling-2_upscale.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://movio.co/en/blog/category/case-studies/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Marketing teams around the world&lt;/a&gt;  build the perfect audiences for their marketing campaigns using this tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Group Builder algorithm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using this algorithm, an arbitrarily complex set of filters can be solved with a single SQL query. Note that it's domain-agnostic; you can use this strategy for filtering any set of elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Constraints&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A Group Builder group can have any number of filters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filters can be grouped together in an arbitrary number of sub-groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strictly for UI/UX reasons, sub-groups can be nested only once (i.e. up to sub-sub-groups).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filters and groups operate against each other using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algebra_of_sets&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Algebra of Sets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each filter can either include or exclude set elements, set elements being loyalty members. The UI shows filters as green when they include members, and red when it excludes members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's the SQL strategy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would be the final query for the Group Builder UI image above; note that the 3 filter subqueries represent the 3 filters shown in the image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre id=&quot;highlight-89612&quot; class=&quot;highlight-js&quot;&gt;
        
        &lt;code class=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;SELECT
   t.loyaltyMemberID,
   MAX(CASE WHEN t.filter = 1 THEN 1 ELSE 0 END) AS f1,
   MAX(CASE WHEN t.filter = 2 THEN 1 ELSE 0 END) AS f2,
   MAX(CASE WHEN t.filter = 3 THEN 1 ELSE 0 END) AS f3

FROM (
       (
                       SELECT loyaltyMemberID, 1 AS filter FROM … // Gender
       ) UNION ALL (
                       SELECT loyaltyMemberID, 2 AS filter FROM … // Age
       ) UNION ALL (
                       SELECT loyaltyMemberID, 3 AS filter FROM … // Censor
       )
   ) AS t
GROUP BY t.loyaltyMemberID
HAVING
       f1 = 1 // = 1 means “Include”
   AND (
       f2 != 1 // != 1 means “exclude”
   OR
       f3 = 1
   ) // Parens equate to subgroups in the UI&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each sub-query in the UNION section selects the set of loyalty members after applying each filter in the group. The result set of the UNION (before the GROUP BY) will have one row per member per filter. The GROUP BY together with the AGGREGATE FUNCTIONs in the main SELECT section provide a very simple way to replicate the set algebra specified in the Group Builder UI, which you can see cleanly separated in the HAVING section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The limits of MySQL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Group Builder algorithm worked really well in the beginning, but after some customers reached more than 5 million members (and 100 million sales transactions) the queries simply became way too slow to be able to provide timely feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We needed an option that was fast but didn't require re-architecting our whole product. That option was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InfiniDB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;InfiniDB&lt;/a&gt;. This was 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;InfiniDB: a magic drop-in replacement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;InfiniDB was a MySQL almost-drop-in replacement that stored data in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Column-oriented_DBMS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;columnar format&lt;/a&gt;. As such, and given our queries were rarely involving many fields, our InfiniDB implementation was a big success. We didn't stop using MySQL; instead we replicated data to InfiniDB in near real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;filer_image&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram 1_v2.png&quot; src=&quot;https://movio-live-2bb6ef96eabb4f369327a8b01ec1-73a1b1f.aldryn-media.io/filer_public_thumbnails/filer_public/9c/1f/9c1f5867-45e4-47eb-bbd2-b91884b8de25/diagram_1_v2.png__1667x548_q90_crop_subsampling-2_upscale.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Super-slow groups were fast again! We rolled out our InfiniDB implementation to all big customers and saved the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The cons of our implementation of InfiniDB&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the success of our solution, it wasn't without significant costs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The InfiniDB instances &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/infinidb/infinidb/issues/21&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;required a lot of memory and CPU&lt;/a&gt; to function properly, so we had to put them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/i3/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;i3.2xlarge&lt;/a&gt; EC2 instances. This was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ec2instances.info/?cost_duration=annually&amp;amp;selected=i3.2xlarge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;very expensive&lt;/a&gt; (~$7k per annum), considering we didn't charge extra for InfiniDB-powered Movio Cinema consoles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfiniDB didn't have a master-slave scheme for replication (except for &lt;a href=&quot;https://dba.stackexchange.com/questions/174133/infinidb-replication-and-failover&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;), so we had to build our own custom one. Unfortunately, table name-swapping sometimes got some tables corrupted and we had to re-bootstrap the whole schema to come back up online, a process that could take several hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We had a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/infinidb/infinidb/issues/3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recurring bug&lt;/a&gt; where some complex count queries would just return 0 results on InfiniDB, but the same query on MySQL wouldn't. It was never resolved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even though InfiniDB was much faster than MySQL, we still saw some slow running groups for every big customer every week throughout 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company behind InfiniDB sadly &lt;a href=&quot;http://infinidb.co/forum/important-announcement-infinidb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;had to shutdown&lt;/a&gt; and was eventually &lt;a href=&quot;https://mariadb.com/about-us/newsroom/press-releases/open-source-leader-mariadb-rockets-analytics-market&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;incorporated into MariaDB&lt;/a&gt; (now &lt;a href=&quot;https://mariadb.com/products/technology/columnstore&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MariaDB ColumnStore&lt;/a&gt;); this meant no updates nor bugfixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfiniDB had no substantial community, so it was really hard to troubleshoot any issues. There were only &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/search?q=infinidb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;120 questions&lt;/a&gt; on StackOverflow at the time of this writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Research time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the winter of 2017 we had an upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;https://movio.co/en/blog/Hackathon-August-2017/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hackathon&lt;/a&gt;, so three of us decided to do a little research on how to create an alternative solution for Group Builder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that, even in slow-running groups, most of the filters were relatively simple and fast queries, and retrieving the resulting set of members was incredibly fast as well (~one million per second). The slowness was mostly in the final aggregation step, which could produce billions of intermediate rows on groups with many filters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a few filters were slow no matter what. Even on fully indexed query execution plans they still had to scan over half a billion rows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could we circumvent these two issues with a simple solution achievable in a day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hackathon idea: the KIB project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our solution was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Reviewing all slow filters for quick wins (e.g. adding/changing indexes, reworking queries)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Running every filter as a separate query against MySQL concurrently, and doing the aggregation programmatically using sparse bitsets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Caching filter results for a number of minutes to minimise the time recalculating long-running queries, given the repetitive usage pattern shown by our customers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;filer_image&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram 2_v2.png&quot; src=&quot;https://movio-live-2bb6ef96eabb4f369327a8b01ec1-73a1b1f.aldryn-media.io/filer_public_thumbnails/filer_public/20/52/205238de-6f4c-4509-b527-ca2632c51f7d/diagram_2_v2.png__1667x671_q90_crop_subsampling-2_upscale.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Hackathon, we quickly added two planned features that covered outstanding problematic cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Refreshing caches automatically, to make most frequently used filters and slow-running ones very quick at all times.&lt;br/&gt;2) Pre-caching on startup based on usage history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We packed these features into a tiny Go microservice called KIB and shipped it onto a c4.xlarge EC2 instance (&amp;lt;$3k per annum). While before we had one InfiniDB instance on a i3.2xlarge for each customer, in this case we put all customers on the same single c4.xlarge instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did add a second instance for fault tolerance, and it was a fortunate decision, because that very week our EC2 instance died. Thanks to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://movio.co/en/blog/6-months-kubernetes-production/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kubernetes cluster implementation&lt;/a&gt;, the KIB instance quickly restarted on the second healthy node and no customers were impacted. In contrast, when our InfiniDB nodes died, re-bootstrapping would sometimes take hours. Note, however, that this was not an intrinsic problem of InfiniDB itself, but of our custom replication implementation of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Go?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long answer to that question is described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://movio.co/en/blog/migrate-Scala-to-Go/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this blogpost&lt;/a&gt;. In short, we've been coding in Go for about a year, and it has noticeably reduced our estimations and workload, made our code much simpler, which in turn has indirectly improved our software quality, and in general has made our work more rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the key bits of the KIB Go code with only a few details elided:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An endpoint request represents a Group Builder group to be run, and the group is represented as a tree of SQL queries. It looks somewhat like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre id=&quot;highlight-89613&quot; class=&quot;highlight-js&quot;&gt;
        
        &lt;code class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;type request struct {
    N SQLNode `json:&quot;node&quot;`
}

type SQLNode struct {
    SQL        string    `json:&quot;sql&quot;`
    Operator   string    `json:&quot;operator&quot;`
    Nodes      []SQLNode `json:&quot;nodes&quot;`
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the function that takes the request and resolves every SQL in the tree to a bitset:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre id=&quot;highlight-89614&quot; class=&quot;highlight-js&quot;&gt;
        
        &lt;code class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;func (r request) toBitsets(solver *solver) (*bitsetWr, error) {
    var b = bitsetWr{new(tree)}
    b.root.fill(r.treeRoot, solver) // runs all SQL concurrently
    solver.wait() // waits for all goroutines to finish
    return &amp;amp;b, solver.err
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the inner function that deals with the tree structure; running “solve” on every node:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre id=&quot;highlight-89615&quot; class=&quot;highlight-js&quot;&gt;
        
        &lt;code class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;func (t *tree) fill(n SQLNode, solver *solver) {
    if len(n.Nodes) == 0 { // if leaf
        t.op = n.Operator
        solver.solve(n.SQL, t) // runs SQL; fills bitset
        return
    }
    t.nodes = make([]*tree, len(n.Nodes)) // if group
    for i, nn := range n.Nodes {
        t.nodes[i] = &amp;amp;tree{}
        t.nodes[i].fill(nn, solver)
    }
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is the inner function that runs the SQL (or loads from cache) concurrently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre id=&quot;highlight-89616&quot; class=&quot;highlight-js&quot;&gt;
        
        &lt;code class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;func (r *solver) solve(sql string, b *tree) {
    r.wg.Add(1)
    go func(b *tree) { // returns immediately
        defer r.wg.Done()
        res, err := r.cacheMaybe(sql) // runs SQL or uses cache
        if err != nil {
            r.err = err
            return
        }
        b.bitset = res
    }(b)
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are about 50 more lines for solving the algebra and 25 more for the basic caching, but these three snippets are a representative example of what the KIB code looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snippets show some intermediate concepts: tree traversal, green threads, bitset operations and caching. While not that uncommon, what I've rarely seen in practice is an implementation of all these things solving a real business problem within a day's work. We don't think we would have been able to pull this off in any other language. I'll explain why we think so in the conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of our project were extremely gratifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In financial terms, we saved $31.000 yearly in AWS bills and $4.000 yearly in after-hours support.&lt;br/&gt;In-office support &amp;amp; maintenance probably costed more than the previous ones combined in the last year, but these are not easily quantifiable in dollar value.&lt;br/&gt;Note that our InfiniDB-based solution has undergone yearly rewrites (we've had to rewrite our InfiniDB solution in 2015 and again in 2016 since our original 2014 implementation).&lt;br/&gt;By my calculation, we will save more than $50,000 this year and a similar amount every year going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of speed, here's a week-on-week table of results for 9 of our biggest customers (we've replaced the actual names with their countries of origin):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;filer_image&quot; alt=&quot;Source Table.png&quot; src=&quot;https://movio-live-2bb6ef96eabb4f369327a8b01ec1-73a1b1f.aldryn-media.io/filer_public_thumbnails/filer_public/62/4b/624b3f35-5634-44ab-b948-8608dc0a8b98/source_table.png__1667x981_q90_crop_subsampling-2_upscale.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some customers, this upgrade meant not waiting for Group Builder anymore, as it was the case for this USA customer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;filer_image&quot; alt=&quot;Scatter graph (55d5ac8c-0b78-45b9-93d0-c3cc7a8169c4).png&quot; src=&quot;https://movio-live-2bb6ef96eabb4f369327a8b01ec1-73a1b1f.aldryn-media.io/filer_public_thumbnails/filer_public/14/34/143429b2-2b1f-4886-b04e-a551c3eac6ac/scatter_graph_55d5ac8c-0b78-45b9-93d0-c3cc7a8169c4.png__1667x981_q90_crop_subsampling-2_upscale.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globally, it was an 81% average improvement in group run times; an average constructed from every single Group Builder group ran on those weeks, not from a sample. That really exceeded our own expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us devs, replacing our complex custom replication implementation of InfiniDB that kept us up at night every other week with such a tiny and simple Go microservice we built on a Hackathon is the greatest gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the Hackathon, we spent the day researching, designing and coding, and no more than half an hour debugging. We didn't have dependency issues. We didn't have issues understanding each other's code, because it looked exactly the same and just as simple. We fully understood the tools we were using, because we have been using the same bare bone building blocks for a year. We didn't struggle with debugging, because the only bugs we had were silly mistakes that were either found early by the IDE's linter or clearly explained by the compiler with error messages written for humans. All of this was possible thanks to the Go language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KIB is in production today on all major customers, and it's barely using a few hundred MB of RAM per customer and sharing 4 vCPUs among all of them. Even though we aggressively parallelised SQL query execution and bitset operations, we had no issues at all related to this: no &quot;too many connections&quot; to MySQL, no bugs related to concurrency, etc; not even while writing it. We did have one pointer-related bug and one silly tree traversal edge case; we're human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's the lesson learned here? My lesson learned is the power and value of simplicity. Even within the simplicity of Go, we went with the simplest (not the easiest) possible subset of it: we didn't use channels, interfaces, panics, named returns, iotas, mutexes (we did have one WaitGroup for the one set of goroutines). We only used goroutines and pointers where necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading this blogpost. KISS!&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 22:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>maloga</dc:creator>
<og:title>How A Tiny Go Microservice Coded In Hackathon Is Saving Us Thousands</og:title>
<og:description>In this blog post, we discuss how the implementation of a Go microservice coded during a Hackathon is saving us $50,000 in costs per year.</og:description>
<og:image>https://movio-live-2bb6ef96eabb4f369327a8b01ec1-73a1b1f.aldryn-media.io/filer_public_thumbnails/filer_public/1e/12/1e12dc0f-84bb-459c-b974-2f68ef99e054/feature_1.png__600x378_q90_crop_subsampling-2_upscale.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://movio.co/blog/saving-money-with-Hackathon-project/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://movio.co/en/blog/saving-money-with-Hackathon-project/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple is making a show based on Isaac Asimov’s ‘Foundation’ books</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/10/apple-foundation-series/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/10/apple-foundation-series/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/apple/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;apple&quot;&gt;Apple,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; you’ve got my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not content with landing &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/10/apple-and-steven-spielberg-are-reportedly-rebooting-amazing-stories/&quot;&gt;an &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt; reboot from Steven Spielberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/apple-orders-two-seasons-of-jennifer-aniston-reese-witherspoon-tv-drama/&quot;&gt;multiple series from Reese Witherspoon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/15/apple-picks-up-a-new-space-drama-from-the-creator-of-battlestar-galactica/&quot;&gt;a space opera from Ron Moore&lt;/a&gt; and much more for its upcoming original TV initiative (&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/26/apples-original-shows-may-launch-next-march-report-says/&quot;&gt;which might launch next March&lt;/a&gt;), Apple is also developing a series based on Isaac Asimov’s &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://deadline.com/2018/04/apple-isaac-asimov-foundation-tv-series-david-goyer-josh-friedman-skydance-1202361072/&quot;&gt;Deadline reports&lt;/a&gt; that the project from Skydance Television is “in development for straight-to-series consideration,” with David S. Goyer and Josh Friedman attached as showrunners. Goyer is best-known for comic book adaptations like &lt;em&gt;Blade,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Man of Steel&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Batman v. Superman: Dawn of Justice,&lt;/em&gt; while Friedman was the creator of &lt;em&gt;Terminator: The Sarah Connor Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; stories depict the fall of a massive galactic empire, and the efforts of a small group of scientists to preserve knowledge and restore civilization. They were first published in &lt;em&gt;Astounding Science Fiction&lt;/em&gt; in the 1940s, then collected into three books in the ’50s. (At the 1966 World Science Fiction Convention, the series beat out &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; to win &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehugoawards.org/hugo-history/1966-hugo-awards/&quot;&gt;the Hugo Award for Best All-Time Series&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asimov (a legendary science fiction and science writer, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;http://mentalfloss.com/article/72995/isaac-asimov-radio-shack-pitchman&quot;&gt;an occasional computer pitchman&lt;/a&gt;) returned to the series near the end of his career, and while the later books are not as well-loved by fans, they also won him awards and landed him on The New York Times bestseller list for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to read thousands more words about why the books mean a lot to me, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/anthonyha/the-good-doctors-voice&quot;&gt;be my guest&lt;/a&gt;. But when it comes to a TV adaptation, two points seem salient: One, the books take place over hundreds of years, with a constantly rotating cast of characters, and two, they consist almost entirely of conversation, with just a few brief scenes of action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That may be why previous attempts to adapt &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; — including an effort at HBO by Goyer’s &lt;em&gt;Dark Knight&lt;/em&gt; co-writer Jonathan Nolan — have failed. If this one pans out, I suspect we’ll see some pretty big changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 22:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbanffy</dc:creator>
<og:title>Apple is making a show based on Isaac Asimov’s ‘Foundation’ books</og:title>
<og:description>Okay, Apple, now you’ve got my attention. Not content with landing an Amazing Stories reboot from Steven Spielberg, multiple series from Reese Witherspoon, a space opera from Ron Moore and much more for its upcoming original TV initiative (which might launch next March), Apple is also develop…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/foundation-1024x776.jpg?w=528</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/04/10/apple-foundation-series/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/10/apple-foundation-series/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why SQLite Does Not Use Git</title>
<link>https://sqlite.org/whynotgit.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://sqlite.org/whynotgit.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;nosearch&quot; readability=&quot;0.54770992366412&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why SQLite Does Not Use Git&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SQLite does not use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.org&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; version control system. SQLite uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://fossil-scm.org/&quot;&gt;Fossil&lt;/a&gt; instead, which is a version control system that was specifically designed and written to support SQLite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People sometimes ask why SQLite does not use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.org&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; version control system like everybody else. This article attempts to answer that question. Also, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/whynotgit.html#getthecode&quot;&gt;section 3&lt;/a&gt;, this article provides hints to Git enthusiasts as to how they can easily access the SQLite source code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;revisions_to_this_article&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;1.1.&lt;/span&gt; Revisions To This Article&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less than 24 hours after first publication, the original text of this article was being &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16806114&quot;&gt;hotly debated on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;, and was rebuked for inaccuracies, distortions, and exaggerations. The version you are now reading is a re-write that attempts to correct those problems and to use a softer and less confrontational tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One could summarize the reason why SQLite does not use Git in a single sentence: The lead SQLite developer finds Git to be unpalatable. If you like Git and want to use it, that's great. I do not like Git and would rather use something that I think is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are a few of the reasons why I do not like Git:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;git_makes_it_difficult_to_find_successors_descendents_of_a_check_in&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;2.1.&lt;/span&gt; Git makes it difficult to find successors (descendents) of a check-in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git allows you to go backwards in time easily. Given the latest check-in on a branch, Git lets you see all the ancestors of that check-in. But Git makes it difficult to move in the other direction. Given some historical check-in, it is quite challenging in Git to find out what came next. It can be done, but it is sufficiently difficult and people rarely do it. Common interfaces for Git, such as GitHub, do not support the ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not impossible to find the descendents of a check-in in Git. It is merely difficult. For example, there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/27960605/find-all-the-direct-descendants-of-a-given-commit#27962018&quot;&gt;stackoverflow page&lt;/a&gt; showing the command sequence for finding the descendents of a check-in in unix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codeblock&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
git rev-list --all --parents | grep &quot;.\{40\}.*.*&quot; | awk '{print $1}'

&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command sequence is a lot to memorize and type. (One would want to create a bash alias or short shell script if it were used frequently.) Furthermore, it is not quite the same thing. The command above gives one a list of descendents without showing the branching structure, which is important for understanding what happened. In contrast, Fossil offers displays such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/src/timeline?d=8a439a6dda390d74&amp;amp;n=15&quot;&gt;https://sqlite.org/src/timeline?d=8a439a6dda390d74&amp;amp;n=15&lt;/a&gt;, which is a tremendous help in analyzing the aftermath of historical changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it is not really about just finding the descendents of a check-in from time to time. The fact that descendents are readily available in Fossil means that the information pervades the web pages provided by Fossil. One example: Every Fossil check-in information page (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/src/info/ec7addc87f97bcff&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;) shows a small &quot;Context&quot; graph of the immediate predecessor and successors to that check-in. This helps the user maintain better situational awareness, and it provides useful capabilities, such as the ability click forward to the next check-in in sequence. Another example: Fossil easily shows the context around a specific check-in (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/src/timeline?c=2018-03-16&amp;amp;n=10&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;) which again helps to promote situational awareness and a deeper understanding of what is happening in the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the above is possible with Git, given the right extensions and tools and using the right commands. But it is not easy to do, and so it rarely gets done. Consequently, developers have less awareness of what is happening in the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the_mental_model_for_git_is_needlessly_complex&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;2.2.&lt;/span&gt; The mental model for Git is needlessly complex&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complexity of Git distracts attention from the software under development. A user of Git needs to keep all of the following in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;'a'&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The working directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &quot;index&quot; or staging area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The local head&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The local copy of the remote head&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The actual remote head&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Git contains commands (or options on commands) for moving and comparing content between all of these locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, Fossil users only need to think about their working directory and the check-in they are working on. That is 60% less distraction. Every developer has a finite number of brain-cycles. Fossil requires fewer brain-cycles to operate, thus freeing up intellectual resources to focus on the software under development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One user of both Git and Fossil &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16806955&quot;&gt;writes in HN&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fossil gives me peace of mind that I have everything ... synced to the server with a single command.... I never get this peace of mind with git.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;git_does_not_track_historical_branch_names&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;2.3.&lt;/span&gt; Git does not track historical branch names&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git keeps the complete DAG of the check-in sequence. But branch tags are local information that is not synced and not retained once a branch closes. This makes review of historical branches tedious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, consider display of a single historical branch of SQLite as rendered by GitHub and by Fossil:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fossil view clearly shows that the branch was eventually merged back into trunk. It shows where the branch started, and it shows two occasions where changes on trunk were merged into the branch. GitHub shows none of this. In fact, the GitHub display is mostly useless in trying to figure out what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many readers have recommended various third-party GUIs for Git that might do a better job of showing historical development activity. Maybe some of them do work better than native Git and/or GitHub, though they will all be hampered by the fact that Git does not preserve historical branch names across syncs. And even if those other tools are better, the fact that it is necessary to go to a third-party tool to get the information desired does not speak well of the core system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;git_requires_more_administrative_support&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;2.4.&lt;/span&gt; Git requires more administrative support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git is complex software. One needs an installer of some kind to put Git on a developer workstation, or to upgrade to a newer version of Git. Setting up a Git server is non-trivial. One could use GitHub, but that introduces another third-party dependency and a centralized service, which mitigate the key advantage of Git which is that it is &quot;distributed&quot;. There are various free alternatives to GitHub, such as GitLab, but those too require a lot of dependences and a lot of server setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, Fossil is a single standalone binary which one installs by placing it to $PATH. That one binary contains all the functionality of core Git and also GitHub or GitLab. It manages a community server with wiki and bug tracking, provides packaged downloads for consumers, login managements, and so forth, with no extra software required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less administration means that programmers spend more time working on the software (SQLite in this case) and less time fussing with the version control system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;git_provides_a_poor_user_experience&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;2.5.&lt;/span&gt; Git provides a poor user experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/1579/&quot;&gt;https://xkcd.com/1579/&lt;/a&gt; cartoon is an exaggeration, yet hits close to home:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.fossil-scm.org/fossil/doc/trunk/www/xkcd-git.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's be real. Few people seriously dispute that Git provides a suboptimal user experience. A lot of the underlying implementation shows through into the user interface. The interface is so bad that there is even a parody site that generates &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-man-page-generator.lokaltog.net/&quot;&gt;fake git man pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designing software is hard. It takes a lot of focus. A good version control system should provide the developer with assistance, not frustration. Git has gotten better in this regard over the past decade, but it still has a long way to go. And so, the developers of SQLite plan to continue using a difference version control system for now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a devoted Git user, you can still easily access SQLite. This section gives some hints on how to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;github_mirrors&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;3.1.&lt;/span&gt; GitHub Mirrors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a mirror of the SQLite source tree on GitHub at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mackyle/sqlite&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mackyle/sqlite&lt;/a&gt;. This mirror is maintained by user &quot;mackyle&quot; who is unaffiliated with, and unknown to, the official SQLite development team. We do not know mackyle, but we observe that he does a terrific job of keeping his mirror current, and so if you want to access the SQLite source code on GitHub, his mirror is the recommended source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;web_access&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;3.2.&lt;/span&gt; Web Access&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/src/timeline&quot;&gt;SQLite Fossil Repository&lt;/a&gt; contains links for downloading a Tarball, ZIP Archive, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlite.org/sqlar.html&quot;&gt;SQLite Archive&lt;/a&gt; for any historical version of SQLite. The URLs for these downloads are simple and can be incorporated easily into automated tools. The format is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;tt&gt;https://sqlite.org/src/tarball/&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;em&gt;VERSION&lt;/em&gt;&lt;tt&gt;/sqlite.tar.gz&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply replace &lt;em&gt;VERSION&lt;/em&gt; with some description of the version to be downloaded. The &lt;em&gt;VERSION&lt;/em&gt; can be a prefix of the cryptographic hash name of a specific check-in, or the name of a branch (in which case the most recent version of the branch is fetched) or a tag for a specific check-in like &quot;version-3.23.0&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fossil_access&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;3.3.&lt;/span&gt; Fossil Access&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fossil is really easy to install and use. Here are the steps for unix. (Windows is similar.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download the self-contained Fossil executable from &lt;a href=&quot;https://fossil-scm.org/fossil/uv/download.html&quot;&gt;https://fossil-scm.org/fossil/uv/download.html&lt;/a&gt; and put the executable somewhere on your $PATH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;mkdir ~/fossils&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;fossil clone https://sqlite.org/src ~/fossils/sqlite.fossil&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;mkdir ~/sqlite; cd ~/sqlite&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;fossil open ~/fossils/sqlite.fossil&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, to update your check-out, simply type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;fossil up&lt;/tt&gt; &lt;em&gt;VERSION&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &quot;trunk&quot; for version to get the latest trunk version of SQLite. Or use a prefix of a cryptographic hash name, or the name of some branch or tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the &quot;&lt;tt&gt;fossil ui&lt;/tt&gt;&quot; command from within the ~/sqlite checkout to bring up a local copy of the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other pages that talk about Fossil and Git include:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 22:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>trextrex</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://sqlite.org/whynotgit.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Data Collected by Quiz App Included Private Messages</title>
<link>https://mobile.nytimes.com/2018/04/10/technology/facebook-cambridge-analytica-private-messages.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mobile.nytimes.com/2018/04/10/technology/facebook-cambridge-analytica-private-messages.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;36.437984496124&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;22.139534883721&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO — Facebook has said that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/04/technology/mark-zuckerberg-testify-congress.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1wi90kg-Link-linkClass eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;political data firm Cambridge Analytica improperly harvested&lt;/a&gt; the public profile data of up to 87 million of its users, including their political beliefs, interests and friends’ information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Now the social network has revealed that the extent of the harvesting went even further — it included people’s private messages, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;On Monday, Facebook began informing people whose data may have been compromised by Cambridge Analytica through an app developed by the researcher Aleksandr Kogan. In its notifications, Facebook said that while the information harvested was largely limited to what was on people’s public profiles, “a small number of people” also shared information from their Facebook timeline, posts and messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;31.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Facebook did not specify how many people’s messages were gathered and said it was taking as broad a view as possible when notifying people that their data may have been taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;43.418530351438&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;33.769968051118&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The revelation widens the scope of data that was harvested from people on Facebook and how it went beyond what was publicly available. The development may provide grist to lawmakers on a day when Mark Zuckerberg, Facebook’s chief executive, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/10/us/politics/mark-zuckerberg-testimony.html?hp&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;amp;clickSource=story-heading&amp;amp;module=first-column-region&amp;amp;region=top-news&amp;amp;WT.nav=top-news&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1wi90kg-Link-linkClass eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;is set to be grilled on Capitol Hill&lt;/a&gt; over data privacy and other matters, such as Russian misuse of the social network to influence the 2016 election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;How Mr. Zuckerberg publicly addresses these problems in congressional hearings on Tuesday and Wednesday will be closely scrutinized. Facebook faces possible regulation and other changes amid a backlash over the lack of data privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The Cambridge Analytica outcry was triggered after The New York Times and others &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/17/us/politics/cambridge-analytica-trump-campaign.html?action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=U.S.&amp;amp;module=RelatedCoverage&amp;amp;region=Marginalia&amp;amp;pgtype=article&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1wi90kg-Link-linkClass eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;reported last month&lt;/a&gt; that a quiz app made by Mr. Kogan had collected information on Facebook users. That information was then used by Cambridge Analytica to build psychological profiles of voters in the United States and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;It is not clear whether the direct messages were among the data eventually provided to Cambridge Analytica. In an interview on Tuesday, Mr. Kogan told The Times that the private messages were harvested from a limited number of people, likely “a couple thousand,” as part of a separate academic research project and never provided to Cambridge Analytica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;He said the messages were collected as part of research that he conducted at Cambridge University in 2013 and the first half of 2014, before he began working with Cambridge Analytica. The messages were collected for research into how people use emojis to convey emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;39.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Kogan said the messages were kept securely in his university lab, known as the Cambridge Prosociality and Well-Being Lab, and access was restricted to a small group of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The message data “was obviously sensitive so we tried to be careful about who could access it,” Mr. Kogan said. He stressed that his Facebook app collected messages only from a “couple thousand” people who completed his questionnaire, not from their friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-4za5ic-Paragraph-paragraphClass e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;During Mr. Kogan’s later work for Cambridge Analytica, his Facebook app took data from people who took his questionnaire and from all their friends. But the data did not include private messages — it included only names, birth dates, locations and pages the users had liked, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32.027303754266&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Addendum-addendums--1F9r3 Addendum-news--if0h7&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Addendum-item--3Si_o&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;Addendum-type--uYTDD&quot;&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Because of an editing error, an earlier version of a headline with this article misidentified the entity that improperly harvested the personal information of up to 87 million Facebook users. The information was collected though a quiz app developed by the researcher Aleskandr Kogan, not by the consulting firm Cambridge Analytica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ExtendedInformation-extendedInformation--3og6I ExtendedInformation-news--2QoWo&quot; readability=&quot;11.150627615063&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Sheera Frenkel, Matthew Rosenberg and Nicholas Confessore on Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sheeraf&quot;&gt;@sheeraf&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AllMattNYT&quot;&gt;@AllMattNYT&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nickconfessore&quot;&gt;@nickconfessore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sheera Frenkel reported from San Francisco, Matthew Rosenberg from Washington and Nicholas Confessore from New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 21:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sethbannon</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/10/technology/facebook-cambridge-analytica-private-messages.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook Data Collected by Quiz App Included Private Messages</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/04/11/business/11FACEBOOKMESSAGES/11FACEBOOKMESSAGES-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The social network revealed that the harvesting of people’s Facebook data was not limited to public profile information.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.nytimes.com/2018/04/10/technology/facebook-cambridge-analytica-private-messages.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Form a California LLC in 10 minutes for $70</title>
<link>https://blog.bookandledger.com/topics/business-formation/form-a-california-llc</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.bookandledger.com/topics/business-formation/form-a-california-llc</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.bookandledger.com/topics/business-formation/form-a-california-llc&quot;&gt;https://blog.bookandledger.com/topics/business-formation/form-a-california-llc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16805322&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16805322&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 435&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 238&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;hnrss is a labor of love, but if the project has made your job
or hobby project easier and you want to show some gratitude, &lt;a
href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=ZP9Q7QUNS3QYY&quot;&gt;donations are very much
appreciated&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
        </description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 20:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mmckelvy</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.bookandledger.com/topics/business-formation/form-a-california-llc</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube Face is clickbait, attaining human form</title>
<link>https://openspace.sfmoma.org/2018/04/your-pretty-face-is-going-to-sell/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://openspace.sfmoma.org/2018/04/your-pretty-face-is-going-to-sell/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On YouTube, there’s a long tail of content that pretty much guarantees the inclusion of every potential human interest. There are skate videos, makeup tutorials, and backyard surgical removals of blackheads. And yet the presentation of a lot of this content — especially when it’s trying to attract a large audience — is remarkably similar. Everywhere you look, there’s YouTube Face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Face is hard to miss once you first spot it: an exaggerated expression, an overreaction to a given video’s subject, typically conveying heightened states like disgust, anger, or ecstasy. The assault of a bad smell; a bite of something intensely sour; a faked orgasm; an elbow to the guts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube Face is most prominent in the preview images for videos. It surrounds whatever video you’re watching in a big grid of emotion. Here’s one, attached to an instructional video for driving stick shift:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-74617&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/sfmomaopenspace/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/02110219/youtube-face-car.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And another, for an irate video game nerd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-74615&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/sfmomaopenspace/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/02110209/youtube-face-games.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And another, for a roundup of bad albums:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-74614&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/sfmomaopenspace/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/02110205/youtube-face-music.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet another, a collection of PG-rated body horror:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-74618&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/sfmomaopenspace/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/02110223/youtube-face-body-horror.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken cumulatively, there’s a surreal, Lynchian quality to the images. Few things could ever be exciting enough to elicit these kinds of reactions, and no one could possibly be this expressive. &lt;em&gt;So&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;what’s wrong with these people? Were their brains tenderized?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, worse. YouTube Face is clickbait, attaining human form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; •&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like nearly everything on the contemporary web, YTF is the result of a series of matryoshka-ish financial incentives. The basic economic goal of YouTube, a subsidiary of the holding company Alphabet, Inc. — formerly Google, Inc. — is to get users to stare at videos for as many waking hours  as possible, so that they can be served ads tailored to their supposed interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To minimize overhead costs and ensure that an enormous amount of videos are uploaded, the burden to create content is placed upon the YouTube community. As encouragement, the company offers a small percentage of its ad revenue  back to eligible users, based upon the number of views their videos get. More views, more money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, tropes begin to form. As certain channels gain popularity, others bite their style and techniques, trying to replicate their success. Vloggers begin to incorporate bright colors; large Impact font captions; talk in the same exact weird cadence — “&lt;em&gt;Hey guys! BlackheadDigger420 here, sorry I haven’t posted in a while…”&lt;/em&gt; — aka &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2015/12/the-linguistics-of-youtube-voice/418962/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;YouTube Voice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the video market saturates, various techniques lose their power, and the attention arms race escalates. Video creators seek increasingly extreme tactics, in form as well as content. YouTube stars &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-intersect/wp/2015/12/01/over-100000-people-want-youtube-to-ban-sam-pepper-for-staging-a-prank-murder/?utm_term=.4813058e8960&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;fake murdering their friends for a prank&lt;/a&gt;, for example, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/2018/1/9/16871252/logan-paul-video-suicide-forest-youtube-explained&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;filming dead bodies&lt;/a&gt; for shock value. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, a user discovered that a catchy preview image tended to trigger potential viewers’ curiosity enough that they clicked through more frequently. Most likely this notion was inspired by other forms of clickbait (in style, it seems to be a mix of ~2012 Facebook newsfeed viral garbage with generic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theawl.com/2015/06/a-complete-taxonomy-of-internet-chum/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;chumbox&lt;/a&gt; aesthetics). Then another user discovered that including a facial reaction tended to boost views further (perhaps manipulating some kind of primal feeling of empathy or morbid curiosity in the pain of others?). Over time, view count metrics gradually pushed these facial reactions into more exaggerated expressions, making everyone look like extras in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3mbBbFH9fAg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Soundgarden music video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aesthetic seems to have been largely popularized by the “reaction video” genre. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/TheFineBros/videos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;The Fine Bros&lt;/a&gt;, who make videos of old people reacting to new things, and young people reacting to old things. Their ~1,500 videos have received over six billion views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-74616&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/sfmomaopenspace/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/02110215/YouTube-face-fine-bros.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5vtqDuUM1DmEDlQxKJi9i-j0wLWB-2zK&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;The Try Guys&lt;/a&gt; over on BuzzFeed Video. They are guys who try things, and then react to them. Their videos have received over one billion views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-74610&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/sfmomaopenspace/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/02110143/youtube-face-try-guys-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other popular channels outside of the reaction genre also use the aesthetic. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/PewDiePie/videos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Pewdiepie&lt;/a&gt;, for one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-74612&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/sfmomaopenspace/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/02110154/youtube-face-pewdiepie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/theneedledrop/videos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;theneedledrop&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-74648&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/sfmomaopenspace/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/03111516/youtube-face-needledrop-2_preview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps strangest of all, reaction videos have spawned an odd meta-genre: people reacting to reactions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-74609&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/sfmomaopenspace/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/02110136/youtube-face-try-guys-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And people reacting to reactions of reactions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-74611&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/sfmomaopenspace/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/02110148/youtube-face-reactions-to-reactions-to-reactions.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting attention on social media platforms requires creating content designed to perform well within their ecosystems. Everything must contort to please the almighty Algorithmic Gods. It requires some guesswork, as these algorithms exist at such an ever-increasing scale and complexity that even their creators don’t — &lt;em&gt;can’t&lt;/em&gt; — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/researcher-fooled-a-google-ai-into-thinking-a-rifle-was-a-helicopter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;understand&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://nymag.com/selectall/2017/10/does-even-mark-zuckerberg-know-what-facebook-is.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;them&lt;/a&gt;. The Algorithm Gods work in mysterious ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has odd and often unexpected effects on the physical world. Restaurants attempt &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/20/16000552/instagram-restaurant-interior-design-photo-friendly-media-noche&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;to create Instagram-friendly environments&lt;/a&gt; with nauseatingly kitschy interior designs. Hamburger buns are glazed to make them more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicagotribune.com/bluesky/technology/ct-chilis-burger-buns-with-photo-appeal-20150514-story.html&quot;&gt;aesthetically appealing&lt;/a&gt;. Extremist political campaigns are won partially on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.channel4.com/news/exposed-undercover-secrets-of-donald-trump-data-firm-cambridge-analytica&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;the strength of their shitposting&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps the emergence of YTF hints at one of the many ways these algorithmic forces might begin to shape our physical appearances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also witnessing tactics common to the advertising industry, especially those of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HPC3mLNL3B0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;late-night infomercials&lt;/a&gt;, being utilized autonomously by individuals. People simulate the behavior of corporate brands, while corporate brands simulate people , hiring &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketingland.com/5-questions-guy-behind-dennys-social-success-89636&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;teams of flacks&lt;/a&gt; to help make something like, I don’t know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/2016/8/3/16041690/inside-frackfeed-the-rights-fracking-meme-campaign-8f8a8c9aee6d&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;fracking&lt;/a&gt; seem “authentic” and “cool.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So begins the Great Brand Singularity. Corporations, humans, and machines merging in a banal orgy of commerce. The tech is currently primitive, but it’s easy to imagine scrolling through some future feed and seeing the faces of long-deceased relatives digitally grafted onto advertisements for #FappuccinoHappyHour; close friends suddenly revealed to be replicants working for foam mattress startups; augmented reality Pillsbury Doughboys stalking us on late night walks home, their soft footsteps squishing confidently along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the general trajectory of things, it seems unlikely that humanity will be exterminated by a vengeful AI, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2017/03/elon-musk-billion-dollar-crusade-to-stop-ai-space-x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;as some tech luminaries predict&lt;/a&gt;. No — we’ll all just be rendered into one giant sentient ad for subscription cosmetic boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yikes! But what do you guys think? Let me know in the comments below, and please take a sec to like and share my article 🙂&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 18:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dwighttk</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://openspace.sfmoma.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/youtube-face-car.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://appserver-d062bdda.c.pantheon-dmz.internal/2018/04/your-pretty-face-is-going-to-sell/</og:url>
<og:title>Your Pretty Face is Going to Sell</og:title>
<og:description>On YouTube, there’s a long tail of content that pretty much guarantees the inclusion of every potential human interest. There are skate videos, makeup tutoria</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://openspace.sfmoma.org/2018/04/your-pretty-face-is-going-to-sell/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Does “=” Mean Assignment?</title>
<link>https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/equals-as-assignment/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/equals-as-assignment/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Take the following code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(a)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common FP critique of imperative programming goes like this: “How can &lt;code&gt;a = a + 1&lt;/code&gt;? That’s like saying &lt;code&gt;1 = 2&lt;/code&gt;. Mutable assignment makes no sense.” This is a notation mismatch: “equals” should mean “equality”, when it really means “assign”. I agree with this criticism and think it’s bad notation. But I also know some languages don’t write &lt;code&gt;a = a + 1&lt;/code&gt;, instead writing &lt;code&gt;a := a + 1&lt;/code&gt;. Why isn’t that the norm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The usual answer is “because of C”. But that’s just passing the buck: &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; does C do it that way? Let’s find out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-big-four&quot;&gt;The Big Four&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 1960’s we had four dominant high-level languages: COBOL, FORTRAN II, ALGOL-60, and LISP. At the time, people broke assignment into two classes: &lt;em&gt;Initialization&lt;/em&gt; is when you define a variable for the first time, and &lt;em&gt;reassignment&lt;/em&gt; is when you change the value of an existing variable. So, annotating our python example, we have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;# Init&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;# Reassignment&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(a)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People didn’t use these specific terms, but it captures what everybody was doing. Here’s what the operators were for every language, as well as how you did an equality check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Language&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Initialize&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Reassign&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Equality&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;FORTRAN&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;.EQ.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;COBOL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;INITIALIZE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;MOVE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;EQUAL&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;ALGOL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;:=&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;LISP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;let&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;set&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;equal&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;ALGOL didn’t have a special operator for initialization. Rather, you created the variable with the type, and then later used an operator to assign to it. You could do &lt;code&gt;integer x; x := 5;&lt;/code&gt;, but you couldn’t do &lt;code&gt;integer x := 5;&lt;/code&gt;. This makes FORTRAN the only one that used &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; for any kind of assignment, so would seem the right candidate for modern usage. But we know that C descends from ALGOL, which means somehow the &lt;code&gt;:=&lt;/code&gt; assignment was dropped and &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; was changed from an equality check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;algol-begat-cpl&quot;&gt;ALGOL Begat CPL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALGOL-60 might be the most influential programming language in the history of CS. It might also be one of the most useless. The language, by intention, didn’t have any I/O features in the core spec. You could hardcode inputs and measure outputs, but if you wanted to actually &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; anything with it, you had get a compiler that extended the core language. ALGOL was designed for researching algorithms and broke down if you were doing anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was such a strong language, though, that people wanted to generalize it for business and industry. The first big push came in 1963 from Christopher Strachey and University of Cambridge. Their language, CPL, added a bunch of innovations on top of ALGOL, most of which we would come to regret. One of them was &lt;em&gt;initialized definition&lt;/em&gt;, where a variable could be initialized and assigned in the same statement! Instead of writing &lt;code&gt;integer x; x := 5;&lt;/code&gt; you could write &lt;code&gt;integer x = 5&lt;/code&gt;. Groovy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we switched from &lt;code&gt;:=&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; there. That’s because CPL had &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; kinds of variable initialization:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; meant initialize by value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;≃&lt;/code&gt; meant initialize by reference, so that if &lt;code&gt;x ≃ y&lt;/code&gt;, reassigning to &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; would also mutate &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt;. But if you wrote &lt;code&gt;x ≃ y + 1&lt;/code&gt; and tried reassigning the &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;, the program would crash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;≡&lt;/code&gt; meant initialize by substitution, aka make &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; a niladic function that evaluates the RHS every time it’s used. They never explain what’s supposed to happen if you try reassigning to &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and I’m afraid to find out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A problem: now &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; was used for both initialization and equality. Fortunately CPL was clear-ish enough on this in practice: anywhere you wrote &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; it was unambiguous which one you meant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a year later Ken Iverson invented APL, which uses &lt;code&gt;←&lt;/code&gt; for all assignments. Since most keyboards don’t have that as a key, not even Iverson kept with it, and his followup language, J, uses &lt;code&gt;=:&lt;/code&gt; for assignments. But APL deeply influenced S, which deeply influenced R, which is why &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/code&gt; is the preferred R assignment operator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cpl-begat-bcpl&quot;&gt;CPL Begat BCPL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CPL was a great language with a minor problem: nobody could implement it. A few people managed partial implementations of subsets of the features, but it was too big and complicated for compilers of the era. So Martin Richards stripped out a lot of the extraneous complexity to create BCPL. The first BCPL compiler came out in 1967… and the first CPL compiler in 1970.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among other simplifications, the “three kinds of initialization” rules had to go. Richards believed that substitution expressions were niche and could be replaced by functions, and the same with assignments. So he collapsed them all into just &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;, with the exception of naming global memory addresses, which used &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt;. As with CPL, &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; was also the equality check. For reassignment, he used &lt;code&gt;:=&lt;/code&gt; just as CPL and ALGOL did. A lot of later languages follow this convention: &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; for initialization, &lt;code&gt;:=&lt;/code&gt; for reassignment, and &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; for equality. But it went mainstream when Niklaus Wirth created Pascal, which is why we now call it “Pascal style”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, BCPL was also the first “weakly-typed” language, as the only data-type was the data word. This made the compiler a lot more portable at the expense of leading to more logic errors, but Richards expected/hoped that better process improvements, descriptive naming, would counteract this. BCPL also introduced braces as a means of defining blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bcpl-begat-b&quot;&gt;BCPL Begat B&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken Thompson wanted to convert BCPL to run on the PDP-7. While BCPL had a “small compiler”, it was still four times larger than the minimum working memory of the PDP-7, 16 kb to 4 kb. So Thompson needed to create a new, more minimal language. He also personally, aesthetically, wanted to minimize the number of characters in source code. This ended up being the biggest factor in B’s design. That’s why we have, for example, &lt;code&gt;++&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--&lt;/code&gt; operators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you get rid of named global memory addresses, BCPL always uses &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; for initialization and &lt;code&gt;:=&lt;/code&gt; for reassignment. Thompson decided to merge these into a single token for all forms of assignment, and picked &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; because it’s shorter. However, this makes determining the use ambiguous: if &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; was already declared, is &lt;code&gt;x = y&lt;/code&gt; an assignment or an equality check? And there are some cases where it’s supposed to be both! He added a new token, &lt;code&gt;==&lt;/code&gt;, as the sole form of “equal to”. As Thompson &lt;a href=&quot;https://ia801303.us.archive.org/1/items/TheCProgrammingLanguageFirstEdition/The%20C%20Programming%20Language%20First%20Edition%20%5BUA-07%5D.pdf&quot;&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since assignment is about twice as frequent as equality testing in typical programs, it’s appropriate that the operator be half as long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thompson (joined by Dennis Ritchie) released the first version of B around 1969. In the time between the two Ole Dahl and Kristen Nygaard invented Simula 67, the first OOP language. Simula follows ALGOL conventions of strictly-separate initialization and reassignment steps. Alan Kay also started work on smalltalk around this time, which adds blocks but follows the same syntax. So even up until 1971 or so most new languages were using &lt;code&gt;:=&lt;/code&gt; for assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;b-begat-c&quot;&gt;B Begat C&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, there’s still a bit more to cover. ML came out a year later and AFAICT was the first language to really emphasize pure functions and no mutation. But it still has an escape hatch in reference cells, which can be reassigned to new values with &lt;code&gt;:=&lt;/code&gt;. Starting 1980 we begin seeing correctness-oriented imperative languages, particularly Eiffel and Ada, which both use &lt;code&gt;:=&lt;/code&gt; for assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at this as a whole, &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; was never “the natural choice” the assignment operator. Pretty much everybody in the ALGOL tree used &lt;code&gt;:=&lt;/code&gt; for assignment instead, possibly &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; was so associated with equality. Nowadays most languages use &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; entirely because C uses it, and we can trace C using it to CPL being such a clusterfuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if this adds anything to the conversation. I just like software history.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 18:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>panic</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why Does &quot;=&quot; Mean Assignment? • Hillel Wayne</og:title>
<og:description>Take the following code: a = 1 a = a + 1 print(a) A common FP critique of imperative programming goes like this: “How can a = a + 1? That’s like saying 1 = 2. Mutable assignment makes no sense.” This is a notation mismatch: “equals” should mean “equality”, when it really means “assign”. I agree with this criticism and think it’s bad notation. But I also know some languages don’t write a = a + 1, instead writing a := a + 1.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/equals-as-assignment/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/equals-as-assignment/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>