<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Does anyone remember websites?</title>
<link>http://tttthis.com/rememberwebsites.php/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://tttthis.com/rememberwebsites.php/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;&amp;#x201D;shortcut&quot; href=&quot;%E2%80%9Dhttp://www.tttthis.com/favicon.ico%E2%80%9D&quot; type=&quot;&amp;#x201D;image/icon&amp;#x201D;&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;&amp;#x201D;icon&amp;#x201D;&quot; href=&quot;%E2%80%9Dhttp://www.tttthis.com/favicon.ico%E2%80%9D&quot; type=&quot;&amp;#x201D;image/icon&amp;#x201D;&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;#RememberWebsites&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;47.848421052632&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tttthis.com/images/rememberwebsites.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;47&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does anyone remember websites? These might be unfamiliar to anyone unexposed to the internet before 2005 or so, and may be all-but-forgotten for many others, obscured by the last 10 years of relentless internet development, but before mass social media platforms and amazing business opportunities on the internet, it was largely a collection of websites made by people who were interested in some subject enough to write about it and put it online. Does anyone remember when you stumbled on a new website written by some guy and read his first article, then clicked back to his homepage and saw he had a list of similar articles that looked like they'd be just as interesting. You could spend a whole day reading just the stuff he wrote on that one website. In general, if you found a webpage with something on it you liked, or a writer you liked, you found that everything else he had on there was also interesting to you, and you could generally say you liked the person behind it. Some bigger websites at the time were like mazes with some of the words on each page hyperlinked to other pages on the site that were about each of those separate topics, and you had to open up multiple links from each page otherwise you'd lose them, and you wanted to read every word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing was that there was no dross, because everything had to be written and uploaded by a person. There was no standard format, since there were no real platforms that uniformly stylized anything. There was no sharing or commenting, although later that day you could talk to your friends about the amazing things you read. Most websites were written with html, so they were all unique. They were organic, as everything there had been added because the writer &quot;had to add it&quot; in order to complete the information he had to put out there, and it took a lot of time to make the material and the html page itself, and organize it all so that it worked properly for any guests (in a pretty true sense of the word). And usually the information there was available nowhere else. There were few pictures, mostly words, and almost all of it from the person who created the website himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does anyone remember websites? It seems many or most of them have disappeared, since the WayBack machine only started saving sites for posterity in the mid-2000s and before that time, before platforms, websites were hosted by providers who rented space out to people, and after they stopped paying for them (the cost per month was around the equivalent of 2 or 3 hours of minimum wage, I think, through the same company that provided your home phone line and internet connection - sometimes you got some free hosting as part of your internet plan). Lately I've gone looking for them, and haven't found any trace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article can be discussed on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/TTTThis/comments/72ukag/rememberwebsites/&quot;&gt;r/TTTThis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplehitcounter.com/hit.php?uid=2294221&amp;amp;f=16777215&amp;amp;b=0&quot; /&gt;  &lt;span&gt;pageloads since August 19 2017&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 21:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dfps</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://tttthis.com/rememberwebsites.php/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kremlin Cash Behind Yuri Milner’s Twitter and Facebook Investments</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;386&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2200&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;Facebook, Twitter and other social media sites have become a major focus of federal investigations into Kremlin interference in the 2016 election. Federal prosecutors and congressional investigators are examining how Russians linked to the Kremlin turned the sites into garden hoses of bogus news stories and divisive political ads, and whether they coordinated with the Trump campaign.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;296&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2496&quot;&gt;No one has suggested that Mr. Milner or his companies had any connection to the propaganda operation. For his part, Mr. Milner said in a pair of recent interviews that the Russian government money was no different from the financing he had received from his many other investors around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;&gt;A Russian Billionaire Investor’s Stake in American Technology Companies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;interactive-graphic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-milner-money-chart-box&quot; class=&quot;ai2html&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-milner-money-chart-300&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard g-artboard-v3&quot; data-min-width=&quot;300&quot; readability=&quot;12.5&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;g-ai0-0&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/2017/10/30/milner-money-chart/3518f7aadec4c10234790589d967423e2563cfad/milner-money-chart-300.png&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhCgAKAIAAAB8fHwAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAKAAoAAAIIhI+py+0PYysAOw==&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-1&quot; class=&quot;g-text g-aiAbs&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;The Kremlin controls &lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle0&quot;&gt;Gazprom Investholding&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle1&quot;&gt;VTB Bank&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-2&quot; class=&quot;g-text g-aiAbs&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle0&quot;&gt;Gazprom Investholding&lt;/span&gt; lent hundreds of millions of dollars to Kanton Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-3&quot; class=&quot;g-text g-aiAbs&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kanton Services owned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle2&quot;&gt;DST USA II&lt;/span&gt;, which was used to invest in Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-4&quot; class=&quot;g-text g-aiAbs&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle1&quot;&gt;VTB Bank&lt;/span&gt; gave $191 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle3&quot;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; DST Investments 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;for its stake in Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-5&quot; class=&quot;g-text g-aiAbs&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;The venture capitalist Yuri Milner founded &lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle2&quot;&gt;DST Global&lt;/span&gt;, which managed DST USA II and DST Investments 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;235&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2731&quot;&gt;Even so, his use of the state-directed apparatus employed by so many Russian oligarchs to enrich themselves shows how the Kremlin has extended its long financial arm not only to his company but to some of America’s technology giants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;376&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3107&quot;&gt;“Kremlin-connected institutions make investments with strategic interests in mind — not just commercial interests but state interests as well,” said Michael Carpenter, the Russia director at the National Security Council during the Obama administration, who is now senior director of the Penn Biden Center for Diplomacy and Global Engagement. “They go hand in hand.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;306&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3413&quot;&gt;Mr. Carpenter added, “Oligarchs who receive significant amounts of financial support from Russian banks like VTB or Sberbank or Gazprombank have to pass above a political threshold, meaning such support requires the explicit or tacit approval of those at the top of Russia’s crony capitalist system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;206&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3619&quot;&gt;There is nothing illegal about foreign state-owned institutions investing in American companies. VTB and Gazprom said the transactions were both sound investments, not motivated by political considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;309&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3928&quot;&gt;As Mr. Milner sees it, the story is similarly simple — “nothing more than business,” he said, adding: “We are getting money, and we are putting them in Facebook and Twitter. We are making money for our limited partners, and we are giving money back to them. For me, it’s a commercial arrangement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;81&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4009&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;(A statement from DST Global, Mr. Milner’s venture capital firm, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/dst-global.html&quot;&gt;appears here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;story-subheading story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;26&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4035&quot;&gt;The Path to Silicon Valley&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;246&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4281&quot;&gt;Mr. Milner, 55, studied theoretical physics at Moscow State University before moving to the United States, where he attended the Wharton School at the University of Pennsylvania in the early 1990s and then worked for the World Bank in Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;273&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4554&quot;&gt;He returned to Russia and in the late 1990s and worked as an executive at Bank Menatep, which was founded by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/12/31/business/international/tycoon-is-free-but-his-money-is-still-tied-up.html?rref=collection%2Ftimestopic%2FKhodorkovsky%2C%20Mikhail%20B.&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=timestopics&amp;amp;region=stream&amp;amp;module=stream_unit&amp;amp;version=latest&amp;amp;contentPlacement=14&amp;amp;pgtype=collection&quot; title=&quot;New York Times article&quot;&gt;Mikhail B. Khodorkovsky&lt;/a&gt;, the oil tycoon who was stripped of his company, prosecuted and imprisoned after a televised confrontation with President Vladimir V. Putin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;284&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4838&quot;&gt;Mr. Milner eventually teamed with Alisher Usmanov — an Uzbek-Russian oligarch close to the Russian prime minister, Dmitri A. Medvedev — and a former Goldman Sachs executive to build a large stake in Mail.ru, a Russian internet company that now trades on the London Stock Exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;280&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5118&quot;&gt;Mr. Milner’s initial American investments came as he served on an innovation commission set up in 2009 by Mr. Medvedev, who was Russia’s president at the time and is something of a tech enthusiast, famously touring Apple’s headquarters in Cupertino, Calif., with Steve Jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;318&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5436&quot;&gt;In May 2009, Facebook announced an investment of roughly $200 million by Mr. Milner’s company, Digital Sky Technologies, and said the company planned to spend at least $100 million buying additional stock. Eventually, Mr. Milner’s new venture capital firm, DST Global, also amassed a significant stake in Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri2/merlin_129558428_1e7b047f-01e6-44d5-8f20-d3f66b7a6ebe-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri2/merlin_129558428_1e7b047f-01e6-44d5-8f20-d3f66b7a6ebe-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Mr. Milner, right, with Mark Zuckerberg, the chief executive of Facebook. The company, along with Twitter and other social media sites, has become a major focus of investigations into Russian interference in the 2016 presidential election.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Kimberly White/Getty Images for Breakthrough Prize&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri2/merlin_129558428_1e7b047f-01e6-44d5-8f20-d3f66b7a6ebe-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Mr. Milner, right, with Mark Zuckerberg, the chief executive of Facebook. The company, along with Twitter and other social media sites, has become a major focus of investigations into Russian interference in the 2016 presidential election.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Kimberly White/Getty Images for Breakthrough Prize&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;167&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5603&quot;&gt;“A number of firms approached us, but DST stood out because of the global perspective they bring,” Mark Zuckerberg, Facebook’s chief executive, said at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;160&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5763&quot;&gt;The documents reviewed by The Times reveal that DST brought something else as well: a connection — through a succession of shell companies — to the Kremlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;story-subheading story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;25&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5788&quot;&gt;Ties to the Russian State&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;264&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6052&quot;&gt;In those years, as part of its diplomatic “reset” with Moscow, the Obama administration was encouraging Russia to learn from the American technology industry. Importing tech knowledge, the theory went, would ease Russia’s dependence on exporting oil and gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-3&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html#story-continues-5&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;267&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6319&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-5&quot;&gt;For the Facebook deal, it was Gazprom, the state-controlled natural-gas giant, that became the bridge. The company, a vital component of the Putin government, has employed its financial subsidiary, Gazprom Investholding, to reclaim assets privatized during the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;421&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6740&quot;&gt;Gazprom Investholding is “used for politically important and strategically important deals for the Kremlin,” said Ilya Zaslavskiy, a contributor to the Kleptocracy Initiative, a project of the Hudson Institute, a conservative think tank in Washington. Both VTB and Gazprom Investholding’s parent, Gazprom, are under United States sanctions stemming from Russia’s support of separatists in eastern Ukraine in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;580&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7320&quot;&gt;Over several years, Gazprom Investholding and a subsidiary made hundreds of millions of dollars in loans to a company called Kanton Services, according to records from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/04/05/world/panama-papers-explainer.html&quot; title=&quot;New York Times article&quot;&gt;Panama Papers&lt;/a&gt;, the trove of leaked documents from the law firm Mossack Fonseca. Kanton, in turn, owned one of the DST investment vehicles used to buy shares of Facebook. While it is unclear precisely when Kanton first received its stake in the DST entity, Kanton received $197 million of the Gazprom Investholding loans three months before Facebook announced its first deal with Mr. Milner, the records show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;101&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7421&quot;&gt;Kanton, based in the British Virgin Islands, had numerous ties to Mr. Milner’s backer, Mr. Usmanov.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;400&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7821&quot;&gt;Kanton was owned by a longtime Usmanov business associate, and was controlled by Matthias Bolliger, a director of numerous subsidiaries of Mr. Usmanov’s main holding company, USM Holdings, according to an Appleby memo and the Panama Papers. And an email sent by a trust company on the Isle of Man used by Mr. Usmanov referred to Kanton as a “private investment company, (facebook and twitter).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;430&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8251&quot;&gt;In the interviews, Mr. Milner said his investors’ identities were not generally public information. And he sought to distance his company from Mr. Usmanov. “I had no knowledge of him using state funds to invest with us,” he said. What’s more, he said, Mr. Usmanov had many potential sources of financing, making it impossible to know whether money from Gazprom Investholding was even used to finance his stake in Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri3/merlin_129559067_9d301b77-a51e-483d-81c5-31d1ef88a0cc-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri3/merlin_129559067_9d301b77-a51e-483d-81c5-31d1ef88a0cc-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;President Vladimir V. Putin of Russia, right, with Mr. Milner&amp;#x2019;s backer, the Uzbek-Russian oligarch Alisher Usmanov.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Michael Klimentyev/Sputnik, via Agence France-Presse &amp;#x2014; Getty Images&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri3/merlin_129559067_9d301b77-a51e-483d-81c5-31d1ef88a0cc-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;President Vladimir V. Putin of Russia, right, with Mr. Milner’s backer, the Uzbek-Russian oligarch Alisher Usmanov.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Michael Klimentyev/Sputnik, via Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;419&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8670&quot;&gt;To demonstrate this, Mr. Milner set out a series of clear plastic cups with labels like “Alleged Russian government funds,” “Mr. Usmanov” and “Facebook.” He pulled out a large bag of green M&amp;amp;M’s, filled several cups and proceeded to shift the M&amp;amp;M’s from one cup to another. “Money is fungible,” he explained, adding, “You can’t just say that this specific dollar went all the way to Facebook.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;281&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8951&quot;&gt;A spokesman for Mr. Usmanov, Rollo Head, did not address specific questions. But in a statement, he insisted that there are clear streams of money that do not mingle. Mr. Usmanov, he said, “did not borrow from or use state or quasi-state funds to make investments in Facebook.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;&gt;Got a confidential news tip?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;interactive-leadin&quot;&gt;The New York Times would like to hear from readers who want to share messages and materials with our journalists.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&quot;story-subheading story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;25&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8976&quot;&gt;Lucrative ‘Synergies’&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;249&quot; data-total-count=&quot;9225&quot;&gt;The Facebook deal was a case study in the way Russia’s oligarchs have mixed public and private roles for their own, and their government’s, benefit: Even as he was investing in Facebook, Mr. Usmanov was general director of Gazprom Investholding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-4&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html#story-continues-6&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;222&quot; data-total-count=&quot;9447&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-6&quot;&gt;In fact, Mr. Usmanov had often intertwined his government position with his personal deals, according to a report by the global investigations and security firm Kroll. Kroll described those arrangements as “synergies.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;470&quot; data-total-count=&quot;9917&quot;&gt;The Kroll report — a “reputation audit” — had been commissioned by Mr. Usmanov as he set out to burnish his image a year before his deal with Mr. Milner to invest in Facebook. Kroll investigators, relying on public records and interviews, detailed a long and colorful history: time in prison in Uzbekistan (he was later exonerated) and past associations with alleged Russian organized crime figures, according to a draft copy of the report reviewed by The Times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;303&quot; data-total-count=&quot;10220&quot;&gt;The investigators also recounted a dizzying number of deals — involving mining, media and technology companies, often with the assistance of the Kremlin and Mr. Medvedev. “Usmanov looks set to end the Putin era as the ‘most improved’ oligarch over the past eight years,” one source told Kroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;155&quot; data-total-count=&quot;10375&quot;&gt;Kroll investigators found that, for some investments, Mr. Usmanov turned to Kanton, the company that would be a part of Mr. Milner’s Facebook investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;211&quot; data-total-count=&quot;10586&quot;&gt;A Facebook spokeswoman, Vanessa Chan, declined to answer specific questions about the deal with DST, calling it a “passive investor” and noting that the company had invested and cashed out several years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;341&quot; data-total-count=&quot;10927&quot;&gt;Gazprom Investholding called the loans “prudent,” saying they were “provided for general corporate purposes” at above-market rates. The company did not answer a question about what role, if any, Mr. Usmanov played in the loans, except to say that as its general director, he “operated in accordance” with the company’s charter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;328&quot; data-total-count=&quot;11255&quot;&gt;To complete the Facebook deal, DST used a pair of lawyers based in Cyprus and Britain who have also set up offshore entities for Russian oligarchs close to Mr. Putin, according to the Panama Papers, United States securities filings and records from Appleby. DST did not answer questions about how it came to use the two lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;239&quot; data-total-count=&quot;11494&quot;&gt;After the Facebook deal, Mr. Milner became a fixture in Silicon Valley, spending about $100 million on a 25,000-square-foot house in Los Altos Hills and investing $7 billion in more than 30 companies, including Spotify, Airbnb and Groupon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri4/merlin_128737946_a88e7dd8-8b9c-439b-b6e8-d16a444c7a13-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri4/merlin_128737946_a88e7dd8-8b9c-439b-b6e8-d16a444c7a13-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;A home in Los Altos Hills, Calif., that Mr. Milner bought for $100 million after investing in Facebook.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Paul Sakuma/Associated Press&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri4/merlin_128737946_a88e7dd8-8b9c-439b-b6e8-d16a444c7a13-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;A home in Los Altos Hills, Calif., that Mr. Milner bought for $100 million after investing in Facebook.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Paul Sakuma/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;271&quot; data-total-count=&quot;11765&quot;&gt;In interviews, he has referred to his close relationship to management at the companies in which he invests. Mr. Milner and Mr. Zuckerberg became friends and met monthly. Still, despite his company’s sizable stake, Mr. Milner did not take a board seat or voting rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-5&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html#story-continues-7&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;236&quot; data-total-count=&quot;12001&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-7&quot;&gt;At the 2010 technology conference in San Francisco, Mr. Milner was asked if he provided management with advice along with his cash. “I think it’s actually the opposite,” he replied. “I sometimes get informal advice from them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;story-subheading story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;27&quot; data-total-count=&quot;12028&quot;&gt;Obscure Financial Maneuvers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;154&quot; data-total-count=&quot;12182&quot;&gt;Mr. Milner’s roughly $380 million investment in Twitter was directly backed by another instrument of Kremlin power: Russia’s second-largest bank, VTB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;287&quot; data-total-count=&quot;12469&quot;&gt;Sixty-one percent of the bank is owned by the Russian government. VTB’s president, Andrey L. Kostin, is a former Soviet diplomat; Matthias Warnig, on the bank’s supervisory council, is a former East German spy who served in Dresden while Mr. Putin was stationed there with the K.G.B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;270&quot; data-total-count=&quot;12739&quot;&gt;VTB has operations across the world, including in the United States. In recent years, it has been involved in a number of politically sensitive deals, including a loan that financed the Russian government’s murky privatization of 19.5 percent of the oil giant &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rosneft.com/&quot; title=&quot;company's website&quot;&gt;Rosneft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;320&quot; data-total-count=&quot;13059&quot;&gt;Last year, the Panama Papers revealed that a Cyprus bank owned by VTB was used to transfer hundreds of millions of dollars to accounts connected to Sergei Roldugin, a cellist and close friend of Mr. Putin. It was unknown what the money was for, but some speculated that he was working as a frontman for Kremlin insiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;248&quot; data-total-count=&quot;13307&quot;&gt;Mr. Roldugin did not respond to messages for this article, but said at the time that his wealth came through donations from rich businessmen for the purchase of musical instruments. VTB called the account in the Panama Papers “unsubstantiated.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri6/merlin_129558974_178776f9-04d2-4cfd-ae86-825534c41e19-blog427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri6/merlin_129558974_178776f9-04d2-4cfd-ae86-825534c41e19-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;A company owned by a Russian bank that supported Mr. Milner&amp;#x2019;s Twitter deal transferred hundreds of millions of dollars to accounts linked to Sergei Roldugin, a cellist some speculated was a frontman for Kremlin insiders.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Sergey Guneev/Sputnik, via Associated Press&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri6/merlin_129558974_178776f9-04d2-4cfd-ae86-825534c41e19-blog427.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;A company owned by a Russian bank that supported Mr. Milner’s Twitter deal transferred hundreds of millions of dollars to accounts linked to Sergei Roldugin, a cellist some speculated was a frontman for Kremlin insiders.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Sergey Guneev/Sputnik, via Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;263&quot; data-total-count=&quot;13570&quot;&gt;“VTB is really a slush fund for Putin,” said Anders Aslund, a resident senior fellow at the Atlantic Council in Washington, and an early economic adviser to the post-Soviet Russian government. The bank, he added, is “the black cashier of the Putin crowd.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-6&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html#story-continues-8&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;190&quot; data-total-count=&quot;13760&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-8&quot;&gt;Mr. Milner’s Twitter deal is a complex web of share transfers and offshore financial entities. But its details may offer clues that there was a strategic motive behind VTB’s involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;372&quot; data-total-count=&quot;14132&quot;&gt;In July 2011, VTB invested at least $191 million in exchange for shares of an Isle of Man company called DST Investments 3, corporate records show. That offshore vehicle was used to buy roughly half of DST Global’s stake in Twitter that month. DST Investments 3 also issued shares to Kanton, the company linked to Mr. Usmanov that was at the center of the Facebook deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;280&quot; data-total-count=&quot;14412&quot;&gt;The Twitter deal had a notable feature: VTB put virtually all of the cash into DST Investments 3, filings show. Kanton contributed almost none. It is highly unusual for investors in DST funds to get stakes without contributing cash, according to a person familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;246&quot; data-total-count=&quot;14658&quot;&gt;On May 7, 2014 — six months after Twitter’s initial public offering, when insiders were first permitted to sell their shares — VTB transferred the bulk of its stake in DST Investments 3 to Kanton. DST also cashed out its Twitter investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;248&quot; data-total-count=&quot;14906&quot;&gt;DST had one other investment from VTB, which Mr. Milner compared to a sovereign wealth fund. VTB was an investor in the Chinese internet company JD.com as recently as February 2015, when it transferred its stake to Kanton, Isle of Man records show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;293&quot; data-total-count=&quot;15199&quot;&gt;In a statement, VTB said its involvement with Twitter was “solely a financial investment,” sold for a profit, one of several successful deals in the high-tech industry in that period. The bank added, “VTB is a solely commercial bank, we have never had any politically motivated deals.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;144&quot; data-total-count=&quot;15343&quot;&gt;Twitter declined to answer a series of questions about VTB, but said that as a matter of policy it had done reviews of all pre-I.P.O. investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;419&quot; data-total-count=&quot;15762&quot;&gt;Mr. Milner would not discuss how VTB came to be an investor, other than to say that the bank helped take Mail.ru public in 2010. According to the Kroll report, the Kremlin had previously ordered VTB to finance other ventures of Mr. Usmanov. The report also details the close relationship between Mr. Usmanov and Mr. Medvedev, finding that Mr. Medvedev helped him win a bid for a lucrative copper ore deposit in Siberia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-7&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html#story-continues-9&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;story-subheading story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;19&quot; data-total-count=&quot;15781&quot;&gt;Beyond Social Media&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;409&quot; data-total-count=&quot;16190&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-9&quot;&gt;Mr. Milner has also been active beyond Silicon Valley. He is a founder of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughprize.org/&quot; title=&quot;official website&quot;&gt;Breakthrough Prize&lt;/a&gt;, a series of lucrative scientific awards. And in July 2015, he was one of several high-profile investors in Cadre, a New York-based real estate technology company founded by Mr. Kushner and his brother, Joshua. (Other investors and partners include Goldman Sachs, George Soros and Peter Thiel’s Founders Fund.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;320&quot; data-total-count=&quot;16510&quot;&gt;Mr. Milner said he invested $850,000 in Cadre through a trust, which in turn controls DST Global Advisers, DST Global’s investment management firm. He said he was introduced to the company through an early investor whose name he did not remember. He said he met Jared Kushner only once, at a conference in Aspen, Colo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;42&quot; data-total-count=&quot;16552&quot;&gt;Mr. Kushner and Cadre declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri5/merlin_106710409_d5896170-fe59-48da-979f-edca429f13f1-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri5/merlin_106710409_d5896170-fe59-48da-979f-edca429f13f1-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Mr. Milner, whose technology interests are wide-ranging, appeared with the physicist Stephen Hawking in Manhattan last year to announce a space exploration initiative.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Timothy A. Clary/Agence France-Presse &amp;#x2014; Getty Images&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri5/merlin_106710409_d5896170-fe59-48da-979f-edca429f13f1-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Mr. Milner, whose technology interests are wide-ranging, appeared with the physicist Stephen Hawking in Manhattan last year to announce a space exploration initiative.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Timothy A. Clary/Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;143&quot; data-total-count=&quot;16695&quot;&gt;In his interviews with The Times, Mr. Milner shied away from the controversy now enveloping Facebook and Twitter, his former major investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;177&quot; data-total-count=&quot;16872&quot;&gt;Growing up in the Soviet Union, he said, “if you’re a father and you have a conversation with your son, it’s easy to say, ‘Please don’t get involved in politics.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;155&quot; data-total-count=&quot;17027&quot;&gt;That “was my principle back then and still now,” he said, adding: “I prefer just to focus on business and philanthropy. And this is plenty for me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;addenda&quot; class=&quot;addenda&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-addendum story-content theme-correction&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction: November 5, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;An earlier version of this article misspelled the surname of a Facebook spokeswoman. She is Vanessa Chan, not Chen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 19:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>killjoywashere</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Kremlin Cash Behind Billionaire’s Twitter and Facebook Investments</og:title>
<og:description>Leaked files show that a state-controlled bank in Moscow helped to fuel Yuri Milner’s ascent in Silicon Valley, where the Russia investigation has put tech companies under scrutiny.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/06/world/06Yuri2/06Yuri2-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/05/world/yuri-milner-facebook-twitter-russia.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>28-year-old makes millions buying from Walmart, selling on Amazon</title>
<link>https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/companies/28-year-old-makes-millions-buying-from-walmart-selling-on-amazon/ar-AAupB8i</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/companies/28-year-old-makes-millions-buying-from-walmart-selling-on-amazon/ar-AAupB8i</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;xnetvidplayer&quot; data-aop=&quot;xnet-mod&quot; aria-label=&quot;Video 'This 28-year-old's company makes millions buying from Walmart and selling on Amazon'&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6073968705548&quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;overlay-open&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Click to expand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;player-and-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;player&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wcvideoplayer vxplayer animate&quot; id=&quot;video_player_d58e3c73-2e48-4b4a-8bf9-4b797de680a6&quot; data-adpagegroups=&quot;{&amp;quot;web&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;usamon&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;mobileweb&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mmviv1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;tvweb&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&quot; data-config=&quot;{&amp;quot;AutoPlay&amp;quot;: false,&amp;quot;FlashSource&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;//static-entertainment-wus-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/en-us/money/_h/b00c897a/webcore/flash/player.swf&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;HomePageLink&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;//www.msn.com/en-us&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;HybridPlayerSource&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;//static-entertainment-wus-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/en-us/money/_h/561caba8/webcore/flash/hybridplayer_2.swf&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;IsImmersivePlayer&amp;quot;: true,&amp;quot;InPlayerPageContext&amp;quot;: false,&amp;quot;IsInlinePlayer&amp;quot;: true,&amp;quot;InViewPlay&amp;quot;: true,&amp;quot;InViewWidthFraction&amp;quot;: 0.5,&amp;quot;InViewHeightFraction&amp;quot;: 0.5,&amp;quot;LeadWith&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;html5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Mute&amp;quot;: true,&amp;quot;SwfCacheRefreshTime&amp;quot;: 86400,&amp;quot;ShowTitle&amp;quot;: true,&amp;quot;UseHybridPlayer&amp;quot;: false,&amp;quot;AdConfig&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;AdManagerRequestTimeout&amp;quot;: 25,&amp;quot;FWFlashProfile&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;188286:MSN_US_AS3_LIVE&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;FWHtml5Profile&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;188286:MSN_HTML5_Live&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;FWNetworkId&amp;quot;: 188286,&amp;quot;FWServer&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;http://2df7e.v.fwmrm.net&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;HybridPlayerAdInitTimeout&amp;quot;: 30,&amp;quot;HybridPlayerAdStartTimeout&amp;quot;: 30,&amp;quot;UseTargetingService&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;none&amp;quot;},&amp;quot;EndSlateConfig&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;EndslateContinuousPlayEnabled&amp;quot;: true},&amp;quot;ReportingConfig&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;Category&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;finance-companies&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;ComscoreProviderConfig&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;{\&amp;quot;ca1\&amp;quot;:\&amp;quot;1\&amp;quot;,\&amp;quot;ca2\&amp;quot;:\&amp;quot;1000004\&amp;quot;,\&amp;quot;ca6\&amp;quot;:\&amp;quot;MSNCNBC\&amp;quot;}&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;ComscoreUrl&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;https://sb.scorecardresearch.com/b?&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;DomainId&amp;quot;: 7290,&amp;quot;Fr&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;en-us_finance&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;ImpressionGuid&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;cd8cb05232194accbdf4f608d734bbc1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Market&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;en-us&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;OtfUrl&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;//otf.msn.com/c.gif?&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;SubCategory&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;no-sc&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Subcvs&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;finance&amp;quot;}}&quot; data-metadata=&quot;{&amp;quot;adNetworkId&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;188286&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;csId&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;AAnPvW&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;csIdBase32&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;7G5UV4Q&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;description&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Ryan Grant turned a lucrative side-hustle of flipping Barbies and other purchases into a full-time job.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;durationSecs&amp;quot;:100,&amp;quot;providerId&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;CNBC_CNBCArticleshttp://www.cnbc.com/id/104807027http://pdl.iphone.cnbc.com/VCPS/Y2017/M11D02/3000667968/makeit_100217_Amazon_Reseller3_MBR_4500.mp4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shareUrl&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/companies/this-28-year-olds-company-makes-millions-buying-from-walmart-and-selling-on-amazon/vi-AAumSd4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;sourceFriendly&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;CNBC&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;sourceLogo&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This 28-year-old's company makes millions buying from Walmart and selling on Amazon&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;uuid&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;AAumSd4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;uuidBase32&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;B4PQKGVNS&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;videoFiles&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;formatCode&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1001&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://eus-streaming-video-msn-com.akamaized.net/0ba86fd8-5ef7-44a6-912e-704e764891a9/735b6c92-9182-478a-be9c-b0ac710e032d.mp4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;formatCode&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1004&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://eus-streaming-video-msn-com.akamaized.net/6453ef80-9761-4dd1-adac-f6f10efe6bcd/735b6c92-9182-478a-be9c-b0ac710e032d.ism/manifest&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;formatCode&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1006&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://eus-streaming-video-msn-com.akamaized.net/6453ef80-9761-4dd1-adac-f6f10efe6bcd/735b6c92-9182-478a-be9c-b0ac710e032d.ism/manifest(format=m3u8-aapl)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;formatCode&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1007&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://eus-streaming-video-msn-com.akamaized.net/6453ef80-9761-4dd1-adac-f6f10efe6bcd/735b6c92-9182-478a-be9c-b0ac710e032d.ism/manifest(format=mpd-time-csf)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;formatCode&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;104&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://eus-streaming-video-msn-com.akamaized.net/b09065e1-ef17-4b53-9c7d-7a3eacc474e5/735b6c92-9182-478a-be9c-b0ac710e_1280x720_3874.mp4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1280&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;720&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;formatCode&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;101&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://eus-streaming-video-msn-com.akamaized.net/64eaa480-3126-4187-82b9-1fd6b474dfc2/735b6c92-9182-478a-be9c-b0ac710e_320x180_527.mp4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;320&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;180&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;formatCode&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;102&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://eus-streaming-video-msn-com.akamaized.net/a43bf85d-c1ce-44fe-94f7-dece60a45005/735b6c92-9182-478a-be9c-b0ac710e_640x360_1428.mp4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;640&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;360&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;formatCode&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;103&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://eus-streaming-video-msn-com.akamaized.net/0be52c58-b292-4660-9fc4-68abd810a01d/735b6c92-9182-478a-be9c-b0ac710e_1024x576_2810.mp4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;576&amp;quot;}],&amp;quot;tags&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;ns&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;wlOnboardingId&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;System.Collections.Generic.List`1[System.String]&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;ns&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;partnerCategories&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;System.Collections.Generic.List`1[System.String]&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;ns&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;isInline&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;System.Collections.Generic.List`1[System.String]&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;ns&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;jobEnvironment&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;System.Collections.Generic.List`1[System.String]&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;ns&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;jobInstanceName&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;System.Collections.Generic.List`1[System.String]&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;ns&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;feedUrl&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://search.cnbc.com/main.do?partnerId=10029&amp;quot;}],&amp;quot;files&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;formatCode&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://prod-video-cms-amp-microsoft-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/AAumSd4?blobrefkey=en-us&amp;amp;$blob=1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;culture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;en-us&amp;quot;}],&amp;quot;headlineImage&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/AAumEbF.img&amp;quot;}}&quot; data-playertype=&quot;Html5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hybrid video_player&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video_player_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video_player_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video_play_thumb&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;video_spinner&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image spinner_image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://static-entertainment-wus-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/sc/d3/9f8e92.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;endslate&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;endslateinner&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;act rel&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rp&quot; title=&quot;Replay Video&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replay Video&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rvouter&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rvinner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UP NEXT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rvthumb&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Weary looking Soviet soldiers ride on top of their armored vehicles as they travel along a highway in Kabul heading for the Soviet Union, in 1988. This was the first large scale military withdrawal by the USSR after a decade of military intervention in A&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BBxvZEo.img?h=80&amp;amp;w=100&amp;amp;m=6&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;o=t&amp;amp;l=f&quot; title=&quot;Soviet Withdrawal Afghanistan - Getty Images&quot; width=&quot;100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rvdetails&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One in two millennials would rather live in a socialist or communist country, study says&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American millennials say they would rather live in a socialist or communist country than a capitalist democracy. Veuer's Nick Cardona (@nickcardona93) has that story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;srclog&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Veuer Logo&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; src=&quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BByCPYg.img?h=16&amp;amp;w=16&amp;amp;m=6&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;o=t&amp;amp;l=f&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;srcname&quot;&gt;Veuer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rvthumb&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;a public bathroom with graffiti on the side of a building: Will a $1,000 Phone Soon Make Apple a $1 Trillion Company?&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/AAupgaR.img?h=80&amp;amp;w=100&amp;amp;m=6&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;o=t&amp;amp;l=f&quot; title=&quot;Will a $1,000 Phone Soon Make Apple a $1 Trillion Company? - Provided by Zazoom, LLC&quot; width=&quot;100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rvdetails&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will a $1,000 iPhone soon make Apple a $1 trillion company?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone X went on sale Friday reports and now, the market capitalization of the company is creeping towards a trillion dollars. Elizabeth Keatinge (@elizkeatinge) has more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;srclog&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Veuer Logo&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; src=&quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BByCPYg.img?h=16&amp;amp;w=16&amp;amp;m=6&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;o=t&amp;amp;l=f&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;srcname&quot;&gt;Veuer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-0.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rvthumb&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;a close up of person: Twitter employee deactivates Trump's account on last day&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/AAuo4CP.img?h=80&amp;amp;w=100&amp;amp;m=6&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;o=t&amp;amp;l=f&amp;amp;x=436&amp;amp;y=274&quot; title=&quot;Twitter employee deactivates Trump's account on last day - Provided by Reuters&quot; width=&quot;100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rvdetails&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter employee deactivates Trump's account on last day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An internal investigation by Twitter reveals that a rogue employee took down Donald Trump's official account for about 11 minutes on their last day with the company. Ryan Brooks reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;srclog&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Reuters America Logo&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; src=&quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BBurRAt.img?h=16&amp;amp;w=16&amp;amp;m=6&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;o=t&amp;amp;l=f&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;srcname&quot;&gt;Reuters America&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video_control_container vid_ctrls&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;controls&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption_ctrl&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;close_caption_bar&quot; role=&quot;menu&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cc_box&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SETTINGS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OFF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;qlty_ctrl&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;qltybar&quot; role=&quot;menu&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HQ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;nextvideo-outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nextvideo-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;UP NEXT&quot; class=&quot;vid-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;UP NEXT&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems too easy to be true that you could make millions by raiding the clearance aisle at your local Walmart or Target and then selling your haul on Amazon. But that's exactly what 28-year-old Ryan Grant is doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;recentquotes&quot; class=&quot;rqcontainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rqlist&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiquotebox mqrqtodaypage&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;indexmovers&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quotedataitem&quot; data-item-id=&quot;126.1.AMZN&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon.com Inc&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;changecontainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+17.38&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+1.59%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;indexmovers&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quotedataitem&quot; data-item-id=&quot;126.1.WMT&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wal-Mart Stores Inc&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;changecontainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+0.88&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+0.99%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only four years after quitting his accounting job in Minneapolis, Minn., to flip purchases full-time, his business is making seven-figure profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Pretty early on I realized I wasn't in the career path that I wanted to be on,&quot; he tells &lt;a href=&quot;https://pub.cnbc.com/id/103395579?__source=msn|money|inline|story|&amp;amp;par=msn&amp;amp;doc=104815890&quot;&gt;CNBC Make It&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;That experience really had me looking for other options and I was starting to explore ways that I could basically leave that job and have my own schedule and be on my own time.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that, Grant turned to the side hustle he had used to make ends meet in college.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a student at Winona State University, he organized textbook buyback events on campus twice a year. He listed the books on Amazon and shipped them out to customers around the country for a profit of up to $10,000 a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process worked simply enough: Using the Amazon Seller app he could see exactly how much he could expect to profit on each book and in what time frame. But the hours spent processing and packaging each order himself proved to be a bit much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Going through that process for one semester was enough to know that I didn't want to do it again,&quot; he says. &quot;From there forward I did Fulfillment by Amazon the rest of the way.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline-slideshow nonfullscreen clean&quot; readability=&quot;4.9161290322581&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;26.21935483871&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;a man standing in front of a store: Ryan Grant spent 30 hours a week searching Walmart for products that he could flip on Amazon.&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&quot; height=&quot;373&quot; src=&quot;https://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/AAumIOf.img?h=373&amp;amp;w=624&amp;amp;m=6&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;o=t&amp;amp;l=f&amp;amp;x=1089&amp;amp;y=298&quot; title=&quot;Ryan Grant spent 30 hours a week searching Walmart for products that he could flip on Amazon.&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; - Provided by CNBC&quot; width=&quot;624&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryan Grant spent 30 hours a week searching Walmart for products that he could flip on Amazon.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;© Provided by CNBC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Amazon's fulfillment services meant he could ship all the books in bulk using preferred UPS rates to an Amazon warehouse, where, for a fee, the online retailer handled processing and shipping out each individual order. It made his side hustle more manageable, time-wise. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, when Grant grew more unfulfilled at his accounting job, it sparked the idea of going online to flip more than just textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After work and on the weekends, he scoped out the clearance aisles at Walmart, scanned a few items using Amazon's app and bought up toys, games, and home improvement items he realized he could re-sell for a profit. A receipt from his early days shows a variety of purchases, everything from vacuums to Barbies, LEGO sets to stainless steel flatware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I was putting in about 10 hours per week and I was making in the ballpark of $1,000 per month,&quot; he recalls. Once he was able to make the same kind of money reselling on Amazon as he had made at his accounting job, in September 2013, he quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I was confident that if I had full-time hours to dedicate to selling online that I would be able to more or less scale that up,&quot; Grant says. Just three months later, in December, he notched $9,000 in profit on over $25,000 in total sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Making that amount of money in one month was a big boost in my confidence to be able to scale up further from there,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boxes upon boxes destined for Amazon warehouses started stacking up in Grant's duplex so, in the spring of 2014, he rented out a 725-foot warehouse. He packed his Mazda 626 full of products on runs back and forth from other brand-name retailers like Target and Toys R Us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It was starting to basically take over my life because I'm coming home and there's product all over my house,&quot; he recalls. When the 30 hours of shopping and the 15 hours of preparing shipments each week became too much to handle alone, Grant hired his first employee, a friend who could help scour local stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually it got easier to target the items that had the biggest opportunity for arbitrage. Seasonality, they realized, was a key factor. They could, for example, buy up discounted candy after Halloween and half-priced Christmas decorations around the New Year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Believe it or not, there's actually people buying those items out of season,&quot; Grant laughs. Still, even he was surprised at how quickly the business took off from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I went from just me in this business doing around three-to-five thousand dollars in sales per month and now, four years later, we're a team of 11 and we're doing well over $200,000 in sales per month,&quot; Grant says. The team had to move to a warehouse that's over five times as large as their first this past July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since he started selling on Amazon, Grant says the business is on track to top $8 million in total sales by the end of this year. Profits are heavily reinvested back into the company, though Grant was still able to take a salary of around $150,000 when he was working for the venture full time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team also made mistakes made along the way. They lost $6,000 when a faulty nail filing product for dogs got Grant's Amazon seller account temporarily suspended, for example. They also had to pay the fees Amazon charges for products that failed to sell and sat idly in Amazon's warehouses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the same, Grant believes he has found an easy and effective formula for success. &quot;I think anyone can do it if they're willing to put in the work,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As his business is increasingly run by his team, Grant has reduced his salary down to $60,000 a year and now dedicates much of his time to getting that message out. He consults and teaches e-commerce classes through the same blog he has been using to track his performance. His hope is that he might be able to help a few people who might not be happy at their jobs find the same independence he did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I was just looking to have freedom of schedule and replace the income that I had from that job and now it's turned into a lot more than that,&quot; he says. &quot;I mean, I would be sitting in an office cubicle now or working at a client location as opposed to doing what I want to do effectively when I want to do it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 19:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kolbe</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/companies/28-year-old-makes-millions-buying-from-walmart-selling-on-amazon/ar-AAupB8i</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Paradise Papers: New leak from offshore finance firm</title>
<link>https://www.icij.org/investigations/paradise-papers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.icij.org/investigations/paradise-papers/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icij.org/investigations/paradise-papers/&quot;&gt;https://www.icij.org/investigations/paradise-papers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15630646&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15630646&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 590&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 346&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 18:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>martgnz</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Paradise Papers: Secrets of the Global Elite</og:title>
<og:description>A global investigation that reveals the offshore activities of some of the world’s most powerful people and companies.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.icij.org/investigations/paradise-papers/</og:url>
<og:image>https://s3.amazonaws.com/www-s3-1.icij.org/uploads/2017/11/Paradise-Papers-FB-Share.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.icij.org/investigations/paradise-papers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Earth on AWS – Open geospatial data</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/earth/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/earth/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more, research in the areas of climate change, agricultural resilience and space exploration rely on access to computing resources in the cloud. Because the cloud makes it easy to share massive amounts of data and allows them to only pay for the computing resources they need, they can accelerate their pace of research while reducing costs.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 13:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thecodeboy</dc:creator>
<og:title>Earth on AWS</og:title>
<og:type>company</og:type>
<og:url>//aws.amazon.com/earth/</og:url>
<og:image>https://a0.awsstatic.com/main/images/logos/aws_logo_smile_1200x630.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/earth/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lessons of an MIT Education</title>
<link>http://www.math.tamu.edu/~cyan/Rota/mitless.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.math.tamu.edu/~cyan/Rota/mitless.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Despite the lecturer's best efforts, however, it becomes more difficult to hold the attention of the students as the term wears on, and they start falling asleep in class under those circumstances should be a source of satisfaction for a teacher, since it confirms that they have been doing their jobs. There students have been up half the night-maybe all night-finishing problem sets and preparing for their midterm exams.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Four courses in science and engineering each term is a heavy workload for anyone; very few students fail to learn, first and foremost, the discipline of intensive and constant work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lesson Two:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;You learn what you don't know you are learning.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;The second lesson is demonstrated, among other places, in 18.313, a course I teach in advanced probability theory. It is a difficult course, one that compresses the material typically taught in a year into one term, and it includes weekly problem sets that are hard, even by the standards of professional mathematicians. (How hard is that? Well, every few years a student taking the course discovers a new solution to a probability problem that merits publication as a research paper in a refereed journal.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Students join forces on the problem sets, and some students benefit more than others from these weekly collective efforts. The most brilliant students will invariably work out all the problems and let other students copy, and I pretend to be annoyed when I learn that this has happened. But I know that by making the effort to understand the solution of a truly difficult problem discovered by one of their peers, students learn more than they would by working out some less demanding exercise.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lesson Three:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;By and large, &quot;knowing how&quot; matters more than &quot;knowing what.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Half a century ago, the philosopher Gilbert Ryle discussed the difference between &quot;knowing how&quot; courses are those in mathematics, the exact sciences, engineering, playing a musical instrument, even sports. &quot;Knowing what&quot; courses are those in the social sciences, the creative arts, the humanities, and those aspects of a discipline that are described as having social value.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  At the beginning of each term, students meet with their advisors to decide on the courses each will study, and much of the discussion is likely to resolve around whether a student should lighten a heavy load by substituting one or two &quot;knowing what&quot; courses in place of some stiff &quot;knowing how&quot; courses.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  To be sure, the content of &quot;knowing what&quot; courses if often the most memorable. A serious study of the history of United States Constitution or&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;King Lear&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;may well leave a stronger imprint on a student's character than a course in thermodynamics. Nevertheless, at MIT, &quot;knowing how&quot; is held in higher esteem than &quot;knowing what&quot; by faculty and students alike. Why?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  It is my theory that &quot;knowing how&quot; is revered because it can be tested. One can test whether a student can apply quantum mechanics, communicate in French, or clone a gene. It is much more difficult to asses an interpretation of a poem, the negotiation of a complex technical compromise, or grasp of the social dynamics of a small, diverse working group. Where you can test, you can set a high standard of proficiency on which everyone is agreed; where you cannot test precisely, proficiency becomes something of a judgment call.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  At certain liberal arts colleges, sports appear to be more important than classroom subjects, and with good reason. A sport may be the only training in &quot;knowing how&quot;-in demonstrating certifiable proficiency-that a student undertakes at those colleges. At MIT, sports are a hobby (however passionately pursued) rather than a central focus because we offer a wide range of absorbing &quot;knowing how&quot; activities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lesson Four:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In science and engineering, you can fool very little of the time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Most of the sweeping generalizations one hears about MIT undergraduates are too outrageous to be taken seriously. The claim that MIT students are naive, however, has struck me as being true, at least in a statistical sense.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Last year, for example, one of our mathematics majors, who had accepted a lucrative offer of employment from a Wall Street firm, telephoned to complain that the politics in his office was &quot;like a soap opera.&quot; More than a few MIT graduates are shocked by their first contact with the professional world after graduation. There is a wide gap between the realities of business, medicine, law, or applied   enginering, for example, and the universe of scientific objectivity and theoretical constructs that is MIT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  An education in engineering and science is an education in intellectual honesty. Students cannot avoid learning to acknowledge whether or not they have really learned. Once they have taken their first quiz, all MIT undergraduates know dearly they will pay if they fool themselves into believing they know more than is the case.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  On campus, they have been accustomed to people being blunt to a fault about their own limitations-or skills-and those of others. Unfortunately, this intellectual honesty is sometimes interpreted as naivete.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lesson Five:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don't have to be a genius to do creative work.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;The idea of genius elaborated during the Romantic Age (late 18th and 19th centuries) has done harm to education. It is demoralizing to give a young person role models of Beethoven, Einstein, and Feynman, presented as saintly figures who moved from insight to insight without a misstep. Scientific biographies often fail to give a realistic description of personality, and thereby create a false idea of scientific work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Young people will correct any fantasies they have about genius, however, after they come to MIT. As they start doing research with their professors, as many MIT undergraduates do, they learn another healthy lesson, namely, a professor may well behave like a fumbling idiot.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  The drive for excellence and achievement that one finds everywhere at MIT has the democratic effect of placing teachers and students on the same level, where competence is appreciated irrespective of its provenance, Students learn that some of the best ideas arise in groups of scientists and engineers working together, and the source of these ideas can seldom be pinned on specific individuals. The MIT model of scientific work is closer to the communion of artists that was found in the large shops of the Renaissance than to the image of the lonely Romantic genius.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lesson Six:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You must measure up to a very high level of performance.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;I can imagine a propective student or parent asking, &quot;Why should I (or my child) take calculus at MIT rather than at Oshkosh College? Isn't the material practically identical, no matter where it is taught, while the cost varies a great deal?&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  One answer to this question would be following: One learns a lot more when taking calculus from someone who is doing research in mathematical analysis than from someone who has never published a word on the subject. But this is not the answer; some teachers who is doing research in mathematical analysis than from someone who has never published a word on the subject. But this is not the answer; some teachers who have never done any research are much better at conveying the ideas of calculus than the most brilliant mathematicians.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  What matters most is the ambiance in which the course is taught; a gifted student will thrive in the company of other gifted students. An MIT undergraduate will be challenged by the level of proficiency that is expected of everyone at MIT, students and faculty. The expectation of high standards is unconsciously absorbed and adopted by the students, and they carry it with them for life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lesson seven:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world and your career are unpredictable, so you are better off learning subjects of permanent value.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Some students arrive at MIT with a career plan, many don't, but it actually doesn't matter very much either way. Some of the foremost computer scientists of our day received their doctorates in mathematical logic, a branch of mathematics that was once considered farthest removed from applications but that turned out instead to be the key to the development of present-day software. A number of the leading figures in experimental molecular biology received their doctorates in physics. Dramatic career shifts that only a few years ago were the exception are becoming common.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Our students will have a harder time finding rewarding jobs than I had when I graduated in the fifties. The skills the market demands, both in research and industry, are subject to capricious shifts. New professions will be created, and old professions will become obsolete with the span of a few years. Today's college students have good cause to be apprehensive about future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  The curriculum that most undergraduates at MIT choose to follow focuses less on current occupational skills than on those fundamental areas of science and engineering that at least likely to be affected by technological changes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lesson Eight:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are never going to catch up, and neither is anyone else.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;MIT students often complain of being overworked, and they are right. When I look at the schedules of courses my advisees propose at the beginning of each term, I wonder how they can contemplate that much work. My workload was nothing like that when I was an undergraduate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  The platitudes about the disappearance of leisure are, unfortunately, true, and faculty members at MIT are as heavily burdened as students. There is some satisfaction, however, for a faculty member in encountering a recent graduate who marvels at the light work load they carry in medical school or law school relative to the grueling schedule they had to maintain during their four years at MIT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lesson Nine:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The future belongs to the computer-literate-squared.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Much has been said about computer literacy, and I suspect you would prefer not to hear more on the subject. Instead, I would like to propose the concept computer-literacy-squared, in other words computer literacy to second degree.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  A large fraction of MIT undergraduates major in computer science or at least acquire extensive computer skills that are applicable in other fields. In their second year, they catch on to the fact that their required courses in computer science do not provide the whole story. Not because of deficiencies in the syllabus; quite the opposite. The undergraduate curriculum in computer science at MIT is probably the most progressive and advanced such curriculum anywhere. Rather, the students learn that side by side with required courses there is another, hidden curriculum consisting of new ideas just coming into use, new techniques and that spread like wildfire, opening up unsuspected applications that will eventually be adopted into the official curriculum.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Keeping up with this hidden curriculum is what will enable a computer scientist to stay ahead in the field. Those who do not become computer scientists to the second degree risk turning into programmers who will only implement the ideas of others.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lesson Ten:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mathematics is still the queen of the sciences.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Having tried in lessons one through nine to take an unbiased look at the big MIT picture, I'd like to conclude with a plug for my own field, mathematics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  When an undergraduate asks me whether he or she should major in mathematics rather than in another field that I will simply call X, my answer is the following: &quot;If you major in mathematics, you can switch to X anytime you want to, but not the other way around.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Alumni who return to visit invariably complain of not having taken enough math courses while they were undergraduates. It is a fact, confirmed by the history of science since Galileo and Newton, that the more theoretical and removed from immediate applications a scientific topic appears to be, the more likely it is to eventually find the most striking practical applications. Consider number theory, which only 20 years ago was believed to be the most useless chapter of mathematics and is today the core of computer security. The efficient factorization of integers into prime numbers, a topic of seemingly breathtaking obscurity, is now cultivated with equal passion by software desigers and code breakers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  I am often asked why there are so few applied mathematicians in the department at MIT. The reason is that all of MIT is one huge applied mathematics department; you can find applied mathematicians in practicially every department at MIT &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; mathematics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 10:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>funkylexoo</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.math.tamu.edu/~cyan/Rota/mitless.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Craniopagus Twins Share a Brain and See Out of Each Others Eyes</title>
<link>http://www.cbc.ca/cbcdocspov/m/features/the-hogan-twins-share-a-brain-and-see-out-of-each-others-eyes</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.cbc.ca/cbcdocspov/m/features/the-hogan-twins-share-a-brain-and-see-out-of-each-others-eyes</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;BC's Hogan twins, featured in the documentary &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/cbcdocspov/episodes/inseparable&quot;&gt;Inseparable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, are unique in the world. Joined at the head, their brains are connected by a thalamic bridge which gives them neurological capabilities that researchers are only now beginning to understand.  Still, they are like other Canadian ten-year-olds; they attend school, have a favourite pet and are part of a large, loving family determined to live each day to the fullest. Here are a few highlights:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Hogan twins at 2&quot; src=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/cbcdocspov/content/images/blog/twinswhoshareabrain_title.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Craniopagus twins, joined at the head, are a rarity — one in 2.5 million. The vast majority do not survive 24 hours. Krista and Tatiana Hogan were born October 25, 2006, in Vancouver, B.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Baby Hogan twins&quot; src=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/cbcdocspov/content/images/blog/4.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A CT scan of the twins showed they could never be separated due to the risk of serious injury or death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of the twins’ brains makes them unique in the world. Their brains are connected by a thalamic bridge, connecting the thalamus of one with that of the other. The thalamus acts like a switchboard relaying sensory and motor signals and regulating consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCENE FROM THE FILM: The Hogan twins demonstrate how they can see out of each other's eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krista and Tatiana Hogan share the senses of touch and taste and even control one another’s limbs. Tatiana can see out of both of Krista’s eyes, while Krista can only see out of one of Tatiana’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCENE FROM THE FILM: The Hogan twins demonstrate how they can control each other's limbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tatiana controls three arms and a leg, while Krista controls three legs and an arm. They can also switch to self-control of their limbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Hogan twins have fun with balloons&quot; src=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/cbcdocspov/content/images/blog/hogantwinsblowballoons.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twins say they know one another’s thoughts without having to speak. “Talking in our heads” is how they describe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girls are diabetic and have epilepsy. They take a regimen of pills, blood tests and need daily insulin injections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WEB EXCLUSIVE: The Hogan twins take their dog to school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twins go to a regular school and as of September 2017 have started Grade 6. Though academically delayed, they are learning to read, write and do arithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Hogan family&quot; src=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/cbcdocspov/content/images/blog/hoganfamily.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twins have three siblings: Sisters Rosa and Shaylee and a brother Christopher, also known as Toad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCENE FROM THE FILM: The girls talk about how they feel about each other after ten years together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girls have very different personalities. Tatiana is outgoing, talkative and high strung while Krista is quieter, more relaxed and loves to tell jokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hogan twins in the pool&quot; src=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/cbcdocspov/content/images/blog/swimming.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girls ride a specially-built bicycle, zoom down hills on toboggans, cross country ski and, as part of their physical therapy, are learning to swim.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 09:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Osiris30</dc:creator>
<og:image>http://www.cbc.ca/cbcdocspov/content/images/episodes/twinfacts.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>BC’s Hogan Twins Share A Brain And See Out Of Each Other’s Eyes</og:title>
<og:url>/cbcdocspov/the-hogan-twins-share-a-brain-and-see-out-of-each-others-eyes</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The twins say they know one another’s thoughts without having to speak. “Talking in our heads” is how they describe it.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.cbc.ca/cbcdocspov/m/features/the-hogan-twins-share-a-brain-and-see-out-of-each-others-eyes</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>If you type the letter “i” and it autocorrects to an “A” with a symbol</title>
<link>https://support.apple.com/en-ca/ht208240</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://support.apple.com/en-ca/ht208240</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Try setting up Text Replacement for the letter &quot;i&quot;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what you can do to work around the issue until it’s fixed in a future software update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to Settings &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; Keyboard &amp;gt; Text Replacement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://support.apple.com/library/content/dam/edam/applecare/images/en_US/il/ios10-plus-add-icon.png&quot; width=&quot;17&quot;/&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For Phrase, type an upper-case &quot;I&quot;. For Shortcut, type a lower-case &quot;i.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 01:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doxinho</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://support.apple.com/en-ca/HT208240</og:url>
<og:title>If you type the letter “i” and it autocorrects to an “A” with a symbol</og:title>
<og:description>If you updated your iPhone, iPad, or iPod touch to iOS 11.1 and find that when you type the letter “i” it autocorrects to the letter “A” with a symbol, learn what to do.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://support.apple.com/en-ca/ht208240</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alpha Go Zero: How and Why It Works</title>
<link>http://tim.hibal.org/blog/alpha-zero-how-and-why-it-works/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://tim.hibal.org/blog/alpha-zero-how-and-why-it-works/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;DeepMind's AlphaGo made waves when it became the first AI to beat a top human Go player in March of 2016. This version of AlphaGo - AlphaGo Lee - used a large set of Go games from the best players in the world during its training process. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature24270.epdf?author_access_token=VJXbVjaSHxFoctQQ4p2k4tRgN0jAjWel9jnR3ZoTv0PVW4gB86EEpGqTRDtpIz-2rmo8-KG06gqVobU5NSCFeHILHcVFUeMsbvwS-lxjqQGg98faovwjxeTUgZAUMnRQ&quot;&gt;A new paper&lt;/a&gt; was released a few days ago detailing a new neural net---&lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/blog/alphago-zero-learning-scratch/&quot;&gt;AlphaGo Zero&lt;/a&gt;---that does not need humans to show it how to play Go. Not only does it outperform all previous Go players, human or machine, it does so after only three days of training time. This article will explain how and why it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Monte Carlo Tree Search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The go-to algorithm for writing bots to play discrete, deterministic games with perfect information is Monte Carlo tree search (MCTS). A bot playing a game like Go, chess, or checkers can figure out what move it should make by trying them all, then checking all possible responses by the opponent, all possible moves after that, etc. For a game like Go the number of moves to try grows really fast.&lt;br/&gt;Monte Carlo tree search will selectively try moves based on how good it thinks they are, thereby focusing its effort on moves that are most likely to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_279.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-326&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_279.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero01&quot; width=&quot;1232&quot; height=&quot;223&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More technically, the algorithm works as follows.  The game-in-progress is in an initial state &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_8320d1005489da544f0244dd5ee9af63.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;s_0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and it is the bot's turn to play. The bot can choose from a set of actions&lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_ad70146b431bea9ae74cf8385470c544.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\mathcal{A}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Monte Carlo tree search begins with a tree consisting of a single node for&lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_8320d1005489da544f0244dd5ee9af63.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;s_0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. This node is &lt;em&gt;expanded &lt;/em&gt;by trying every action&lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_eaf8ec4fdaa140ea320fddff77a7ff97.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;a \in \mathcal{A}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and constructing a corresponding child node for each action. Below we show this expansion for a game of tic-tac-toe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_280.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-327&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_280.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero02&quot; width=&quot;908&quot; height=&quot;423&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value of each new child node must then be determined. The game in the child node is &lt;em&gt;rolled out&lt;/em&gt; by randomly taking moves from the child state until a win, loss, or tie is reached. Wins are scored at &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_7015440590904d38e35615ff0672d21c.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;+1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, losses at &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_6bb61e3b7bce0931da574d19d1d82c88.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;-1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and ties at &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_cfcd208495d565ef66e7dff9f98764da.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_281.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-334&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_281.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero03&quot; width=&quot;1073&quot; height=&quot;220&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The random rollout for the first child given above estimates a value of &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_7015440590904d38e35615ff0672d21c.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;+1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. This value may not represent optimal play-it can vary based on how the rollout progresses. One can run rollouts unintelligently, drawing moves uniformly at random. One can often do better by following a better-though still typically random-strategy, or by estimating the value of the state directly. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_282.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-335&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_282.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero04&quot; width=&quot;918&quot; height=&quot;485&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above we show the expanded tree with approximate values for each child node. Note that we store two properties: the accumulated value &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_61e9c06ea9a85a5088a499df6458d276.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;W&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and the number of times rollouts have been run at or below that node, &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_8d9c307cb7f3c4a32822a51922d1ceaa.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;N&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. We have only visited each node once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information from the child nodes is then propagated back up the tree by increasing the parent's value and visit count. Its accumulated value is then set to the total accumulated value of its children:&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_283.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-336&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_283.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero05&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;578&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monte Carlo tree search continues for multiple iterations consisting of selecting a node, expanding it, and propagating back up the new information. Expansion and propagation have already been covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monte Carlo tree search does not expand all leaf nodes, as that would be very expensive. Instead, the selection process chooses nodes that strike a balance between being lucrative-having high estimated values-and being relatively unexplored-having low visit counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A leaf node is selected by traversing down the tree from the root node, always choosing the child &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_865c0c0b4ab0e063e5caa3387c1a8741.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;i&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; with the highest upper confidence tree (UCT) score:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_40ebd778ad825303298c96edbd9a2b2e.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;U_i = \frac{W_i}{N_i} + c\sqrt{\frac{\ln N_p}{N_i}}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;where &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_540bdf656419f2a308d7ad1571c664a0.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;W_i&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is the accumulated value of the &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_865c0c0b4ab0e063e5caa3387c1a8741.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;i&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;th child, &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_173eda91467d59e92b43f2a1d21ee177.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;N_i&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is the visit count for &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_865c0c0b4ab0e063e5caa3387c1a8741.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;i&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;th child, and &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_766b775dcac93fa1cf6f6b365212665f.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;N_p&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is the number of visit counts for the parent node. The parameter &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_b6dbf81b750e9317026b593887c8f097.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;c \geq 0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; controls the tradeoff between choosing lucrative nodes (low &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4a8a08f09d37b73795649038408b5f33.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;c&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) and exploring nodes with low visit counts (high &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4a8a08f09d37b73795649038408b5f33.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;c&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;). It is often set empirically.
&lt;p&gt;The UCT scores (&lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4c614360da93c0a041b22e537de151eb.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;U&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;'s) for the tic-tac-toe tree with &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_27071423b9a403c9ffa1895ef3fefb6e.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;c=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_284.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-337&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_284.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero06&quot; width=&quot;899&quot; height=&quot;613&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case we pick the first node, &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4a1a7a321a00f1e0c682049fec14f8ae.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;s_{0,1}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. (In the event of a tie one can either randomly break the tie or just pick the first of the bet nodes.) That node is expanded and the values are propagated back up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_285.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-338&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_285.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero07&quot; width=&quot;1082&quot; height=&quot;862&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that each accumulated value &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_61e9c06ea9a85a5088a499df6458d276.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;W&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; reflects whether X's won or lost. During selection, we keep track of whether it is X's or O's turn to move, and flip the sign of &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_61e9c06ea9a85a5088a499df6458d276.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;W&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; whenever it is O's turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue to run iterations of Monte Carlo tree search until we run out of time. The tree is gradually expanded and we (hopefully) explore the possible moves, identifying the best move to take. The bot then actually makes a move in the original, real game by picking the first child with the highest number of visits. For example, if the top of our tree looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_286.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-340&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_286.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero08&quot; width=&quot;884&quot; height=&quot;584&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then the bot would choose the first action and proceed to &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4a1a7a321a00f1e0c682049fec14f8ae.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;s_{0,1}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Efficiency Through Expert Policies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games like chess and Go have very large branching factors. In a given game state there are many possible actions to take, making it very difficult to adequately explore the future game states. As a result, there are an estimated &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_b875c645ccc8b5e93084caac0216c444.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;10^{46}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tromp.github.io/chess/chess.html&quot;&gt;board states in chess&lt;/a&gt;, and Go played on a traditional &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_d676449ed5bf5ad19089b753f2bf9324.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;19 \times 19&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; board has around &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_df5777c0d368670abf08782217505ba7.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;10^{170}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Tic-tac-toe only has &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_23712318a400454a2c049f165106d985.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;5478&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; states).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Move evaluation with vanilla Monte Carlo tree search just isn't efficient enough. We need a way to further focus our attention to worthwhile moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose we have an &lt;em&gt;expert policy&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4f08e3dba63dc6d40b22952c7a9dac6d.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\pi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that, for a given state &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_03c7c0ace395d80182db07ae2c30f034.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;s&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, tells us how likely an expert-level player is to make each possible action. For the tic-tac-toe example, this might look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_287.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-341&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_287.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero09&quot; width=&quot;884&quot; height=&quot;539&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where each &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_8cd4d4be01bd8f030b60a1660d20d142.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;P_i = \pi(a_i \mid s_0)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is the probability of choosing the &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_865c0c0b4ab0e063e5caa3387c1a8741.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;i&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;th action &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_2aecb1dc57e87620a373d19b0a889efb.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;a_i&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; given the root state &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_8320d1005489da544f0244dd5ee9af63.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;s_0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the expert policy is really good then we can produce a strong bot by directly drawing our next action according to the probabilities produces by &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4f08e3dba63dc6d40b22952c7a9dac6d.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\pi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, or better yet, by taking the move with the highest probability. Unfortunately, getting an expert policy is difficult, and verifying that one's policy is optimal is difficult as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, one can improve on a policy by using a modified form of Monte Carlo tree search. This version will also store the probability of each node according to the policy, and this probability is used to adjust the node's score during selection. The probabilistic upper confidence tree score used by DeepMind is:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4bfa8a6e66f4d0333e7daf59c6dd3dbb.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;U_i = \frac{W_i}{N_i} + c P_i\sqrt{\frac{\ln N_p}{1 + N_i}}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As before, the score trades off between nodes that consistently produce high scores and nodes that are unexplored. Now, node exploration is guided by the expert policy, biasing exploration towards moves the expert policy considers likely. If the expert policy truly is good, then Monte Carlo tree search efficiently focuses on good evolutions of the game state. If the expert policy is poor, then Monte Carlo tree search may focus on bad evolutions of the game state. Either way, in the limit as the number of samples gets large, the value of a node is dominated by the win/loss ratio &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_8c771be418fd24a81d1d17a071095383.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;W_i/N_i&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, as before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Efficiency Through Value Approximation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second form of efficiency can be achieved by avoiding expensive and potentially inaccurate random rollouts. One option is to use the expert policy from the previous section to guide the random rollout. If the policy is good, then the rollout should reflect more realistic, expert-level game progressions and thus more reliably estimate a state's value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second option is to avoid rollouts altogether, and directly approximate the value of a state with a value approximator function &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_62c5b1b44f9852ea78f1eca562b94387.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\hat{W}(x)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. This function takes a state and directly computes a value in &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_d060b17b29e0dae91a1cac23ea62281a.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;[-1,1]&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, without conducting rollouts. Clearly, if &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_3ef3be39c0ce6db13e25b74b1c003dd1.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\hat{W}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is a good approximation of the true value, but can be executed faster than a rollout, then execution time can be saved without sacrificing performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_288.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-342&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_288.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero10&quot; width=&quot;206&quot; height=&quot;214&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Value approximation can be used in tandem with an expert policy to speed up Monte Carlo tree search. A serious concern remains-how does one obtain an expert policy and a value function? Does an algorithm exist for training the expert policy and value function?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Alpha Zero Neural Net&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Alpha Zero algorithm produces better and better expert policies and value functions over time by playing games against itself with accelerated Monte Carlo tree search. The expert policy &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4f08e3dba63dc6d40b22952c7a9dac6d.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\pi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and the approximate value function &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_3ef3be39c0ce6db13e25b74b1c003dd1.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\hat{W}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; are both represented by deep neural networks. In fact, to increase efficiency, Alpha Zero uses one neural network &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_8fa14cdd754f91cc6554c9e71929cce7.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;f&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that takes in the game state and produces both the probabilities over the next move and the approximate state value. (Technically, it takes in the previous eight game states and an indicator telling it whose turn it is.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_fa6d0507e25db8659672e83f5d2bceee.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;f(s) \rightarrow [\boldsymbol{\mathbf{p}}, W]&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaves in the search tree are expanded by evaluating them with the neural network. Each child is initialized with &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_ea15e6b8b6bc7a151e69645fe1c1095e.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;N = 0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_302b9e6f697eb352475fa548227f04dd.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;W = 0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and with &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_44c29edb103a2872f519ad0c9a0fdaaa.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;P&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; corresponding to the prediction from the network. The value of the expanded node is set to the predicted value and this value is then backed up the tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_289.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-343&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_289.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero11&quot; width=&quot;1091&quot; height=&quot;656&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selection and backup are unchanged. Simply put, during backup a parent's visit counts are incremented and its value is increased according to &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_61e9c06ea9a85a5088a499df6458d276.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;W&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search tree following another selection, expansion, and backup step is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_290.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-344&quot; src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Selection_290.png&quot; alt=&quot;AlphaGoZero12&quot; width=&quot;1042&quot; height=&quot;972&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core idea of the Alpha Zero algorithm is that the predictions of the neural network can be improved, and the play generated by Monte Carlo tree search can be used to provide the training data. The policy portion of the neural network is improved by training the predicted probabilities &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_d9cb06675a8729d9045b594aa1f06d99.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\boldsymbol{\mathbf{p}}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_8320d1005489da544f0244dd5ee9af63.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;s_0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to match the improved probability &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4ca25af2a824eac2ecc195483474c11c.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;{\boldsymbol{\mathbf{\pi}}}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; obtained from running Monte Carlo tree on &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_8320d1005489da544f0244dd5ee9af63.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;s_0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. After running Monte Carlo tree search, the improved policy prediction is:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4119b84ff9bfd4075dc9f6dc81297ab3.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\pi_i = N_i^{1/\tau}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;for a constant &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_a6f317b268ae825d94f832f970af607c.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\tau&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;Values of &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_a6f317b268ae825d94f832f970af607c.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\tau&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; close to zero produce policies that choose the best move according to the Monte Carlo tree search evaluation.
&lt;p&gt;The value portion of the neural network is improved by training the predicted value to match the eventual win/loss/tie result of the game, &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_21c2e59531c8710156d34a3c30ac81d5.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;Z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Their loss function is:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_11a3da921ad07da08d32bf89948e3f5e.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;(W - Z)^2 + {\boldsymbol{\mathbf{\pi}}}^\top \ln\boldsymbol{\mathbf{p}} + \lambda \|\boldsymbol{\mathbf{\theta}}\|_2^2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;where &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_5a7be5bbd5e56478a802b48ef376b9c6.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;(W - Z)^2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is the value loss, &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_c9e01f0acf0156141afab72876c4b9fc.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\pi^\top \ln\boldsymbol{\mathbf{p}}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is the policy loss, and &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_9b77a081393ddce18178cabe3ff2f4fc.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda \|\theta\|_2^2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is an extra regularization term with parameter &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_432b4cfb979f14a140b7205d6bc5dc56.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda \geq 0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_bf1635a14c502e61611a45cd1909b25e.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\boldsymbol{\mathbf{\theta}}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; represents the parameters in the neural network.
&lt;p&gt;Training is done entirely in self-play. One starts with a randomly initialized set of neural network parameters &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_bf1635a14c502e61611a45cd1909b25e.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\boldsymbol{\mathbf{\theta}}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. This neural network is then used in multiple games in which it plays itself. In each of these games, for each move, Monte Carlo tree search is used to calculate &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_4f08e3dba63dc6d40b22952c7a9dac6d.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\pi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. The final outcome of each game determines that game's value for &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_21c2e59531c8710156d34a3c30ac81d5.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;Z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. The parameters &lt;span class=&quot;MathJax_Preview&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tim.hibal.org/blog/wp-content/plugins/latex/cache/tex_bf1635a14c502e61611a45cd1909b25e.gif&quot; class=&quot;tex&quot; alt=&quot;\boldsymbol{\mathbf{\theta}}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; are then improved by using gradient descent (Or any of the more sophisticated accelerated descent methods-Alpha Zero used stochastic gradient descent with momentum and learning rate annealing.) on the loss function for a random selection of states played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Closing Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's it. The folks at DeepMind contributed a clean and stable learning algorithm that trains game-playing agents efficiently using only data from self-play. While the current Zero algorithm only works for discrete games, it will be interesting whether it will be extended to MDPs or their partially observable counterparts in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to see how quickly the field of AI is progressing. Those who claim we will be able to see the robot overlords coming in time should take heed - these AI's will only be human-level for a brief instant before blasting past us into superhuman territories, never to look back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 23:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mageek</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://tim.hibal.org/blog/alpha-zero-how-and-why-it-works/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fake WhatsApp update from “WhatsApp Inc.” with Unicode whitespace: 1M downloads</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/virqdroid/status/926437790140772362</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/virqdroid/status/926437790140772362</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/virqdroid/status/926437790140772362&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/virqdroid/status/926437790140772362&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15626819&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15626819&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 486&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 201&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 20:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jakub_g</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/virqdroid/status/926437790140772362</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>