<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>24-core CPU and I can’t type an email</title>
<link>https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2018/08/16/24-core-cpu-and-i-cant-type-an-email-part-one/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2018/08/16/24-core-cpu-and-i-cant-type-an-email-part-one/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t looking for trouble. I wasn’t trying to build Chrome a &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2017/07/09/24-core-cpu-and-i-cant-move-my-mouse/&quot;&gt;thousand times in a weekend&lt;/a&gt;, I was just engaging in that most mundane of 21st century tasks, writing an email at 10:30 am. And suddenly gmail hung. I kept typing but for several seconds but no characters were appearing on screen. Then, suddenly gmail caught up and I resumed my &lt;em&gt;very important&lt;/em&gt; email. Then it happened again, only this time gmail went unresponsive for even longer. Well &lt;a href=&quot;https://quoteinvestigator.com/2015/03/02/eureka-funny/&quot;&gt;that’s funny&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have trouble resisting a good performance mystery but in this case the draw was particularly strong. I work on Chrome, on Windows, focused on performance. Investigating this hang was actually my &lt;em&gt;job&lt;/em&gt;. And after a lot of false starts and some hard work I figured out how Chrome, gmail, Windows, and our IT department were working together to prevent me from typing an email, and in the process I found a way to save a significant amount of memory for some web pages in Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This investigation had so many rabbit holes that I’m going to save some of the digressions for a follow-on post, but this one will entirely explain the hangs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual I had &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2015/09/01/xperf-basics-recording-a-trace-the-ultimate-easy-way/&quot;&gt;UIforETW&lt;/a&gt; running in the background, tracing to circular buffers, so I just had to type Ctrl+Win+R and the buffers, representing the last thirty seconds or so of system activity, were saved to disk. I loaded it into &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2012/06/19/wpaxperf-trace-analysis-reimagined/&quot;&gt;Windows Performance Analyzer&lt;/a&gt; (WPA), but I couldn’t definitively find the hang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a Windows program stops pumping messages there will be ETW events emitted to indicate &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2012/05/05/xperf-wait-analysisfinding-idle-time/&quot;&gt;exactly where this happened&lt;/a&gt;, so those types of hangs are trivial to find. But apparently Chrome kept on pumping messages. I looked for a time when one of Chrome’s crucial threads either went into a busy loop or went completely idle, but I couldn’t find anything conclusive. There were some spots where Chrome went &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; idle, but even then all of the key threads kept chugging along, so I couldn’t be sure where the hang was – Chrome might have been going idle because nothing was happening:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;image&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image_thumb.png?w=624&amp;amp;h=182&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;182&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;image&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image_thumb1.png?w=163&amp;amp;h=202&quot; width=&quot;163&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; height=&quot;202&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;UIforETW has a built-in key logger which is often useful when identifying key points in a trace. However, for obvious security reasons it defaults to anonymizing the keystrokes, treating every number typed as a ‘1’ and every letter as an ‘A’. This was making it hard to find the exact moment of the hang so I turned the input tracing from “Private” to “Full” and waited for the hang. At around 10:30 the next morning the hang happened again. I saved the trace buffers, and put these notes into UIforETW’s trace information field:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was typing “defer to those with more scuba experience” and gmail hung around the end of “those” and then resumed partway through “experience”. gmail tab was PID 27368.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly just a normal work-related discussion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2017/05/01/commute-challenge-2017/&quot;&gt;commute methods&lt;/a&gt;, but the important thing is that now I had a way of locating the hang in the ETW trace. I loaded the trace, looked at the keyboard data in the Generic Events field (the events are emitted by UIforETW itself, each one is a purple diamond in the screen shot below) and suddenly I could see exactly where the hang was, and clearly the dip in CPU usage was 100% correlated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;image&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image_thumb2.png?w=635&amp;amp;h=460&quot; width=&quot;635&quot; height=&quot;460&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, but why is Chrome stopping? Here’s some foreshadowing: not shown in these screenshots is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/desktop/wmisdk/wmi-start-page&quot;&gt;WmiPrvSE.exe&lt;/a&gt; was consuming an entire CPU hyperthread whenever this happened. But that shouldn’t matter. I have a 24-core/48-thread machine so consuming one hyperthread means my machine is still about 98% idle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then zoomed in to the clearly-significant period where Chrome was idle and looked in particular at CrRendererMain in chrome.exe (27368), the gmail tab process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside: I just want to say thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2015/10/26/thread-naming-in-windows-time-for-something-better/&quot;&gt;2015 me&lt;/a&gt; for asking Microsoft to improve their thread naming mechanisms, and thank you to Microsoft for doing everything I suggested – thread names in WPA are &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem suddenly became clearer. During the 2.81 s hang this thread was scheduled and ran 440 separate times. Normally running every 6 ms is enough to make a program responsive, but for some reason it wasn’t making any progress. I noticed that every time it woke up it was on the same stack. Simplified down it was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;chrome_child.dll (stack base)&lt;br/&gt;KernelBase.dll!VirtualAlloc&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiCommitVadCfgBits&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiPopulateCfgBitMap&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!ExAcquirePushLockExclusiveEx&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!KeWaitForSingleObject (stack leaf)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome is calling VirtualAlloc, which tries to update some “CfgBits” and needs to acquire a lock. At first I assumed that Chrome was calling VirtualAlloc 440 times, which seemed like a weird thing to do, but the reality was perhaps weirder. Chrome called VirtualAlloc once and a lock needed to be acquired. Chrome was signaled when that lock was available but – for 439 times in a row – when Chrome woke up and tried to acquire the lock it was unavailable. The lock had been reacquired by the process that had just released it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is because Windows locks are, by design, &lt;a href=&quot;http://joeduffyblog.com/2006/12/14/anticonvoy-locks-in-windows-server-2003-sp1-and-windows-vista/&quot;&gt;not fair&lt;/a&gt; and if a thread releases a lock and then tries to reacquire it immediately then it can, in cases like this, reacquire it every single time. Starvation. More on this next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Readying Process – the one that signaled Chrome to go grab the lock – in &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; case was WmiPrvSE.exe, releasing the lock on this stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!KiSystemServiceCopyEnd (stack base)&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!NtQueryVirtualMemory&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MmQueryVirtualMemory&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiUnlockAndDereferenceVad&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!ExfTryToWakePushLock (stack leaf)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got distracted by WMI for a while (more on that next time) but eventually I wrote a program to recreate WMI’s behavior. I had CPU sampling data that showed me where WmiPrvSE.exe was spending its time (some edits and simplifications made):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WmiPerfClass.dll!EnumSelectCounterObjects (stack base)&lt;br/&gt;WmiPerfClass.dll!ConvertCounterPath&lt;br/&gt;pdh.dll!PdhiTranslateCounter&lt;br/&gt;pdh.dll!GetSystemPerfData&lt;br/&gt;KernelBase.dll!blah-blah-blah&lt;br/&gt;advapi32.dll!blah-blah-blah&lt;br/&gt;perfproc.dll!blah-blah-blah&lt;br/&gt;perfproc.dll!GetProcessVaData&lt;br/&gt;ntdll.dll!NtQueryVirtualMemory&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!NtQueryVirtualMemory&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MmQueryVirtualMemory&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiQueryAddressSpan&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiQueryAddressState&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiGetNextPageTable (stack leaf)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that reproducing the slow scanning from the sampling data was quite easy. My VirtualScan program just called NtQueryVirtualMemory in the obvious loop to scan the address space of a specified process, the code worked, it took a really long time to scan the gmail process (10-15 seconds), and it triggered the hang. But why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage of writing the scanning loop myself was that I could start generating statistics. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/drivers/ddi/content/ntifs/nf-ntifs-ntqueryvirtualmemory&quot;&gt;NtQueryVirtualMemory&lt;/a&gt; returns data on each contiguous range of address space that has matching attributes. That might mean all reserved, all committed with particular protection settings, etc. The gmail process had about 26,000 of these blocks but I found another process (&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2012/06/19/wpaxperf-trace-analysis-reimagined/&quot;&gt;WPA&lt;/a&gt;, as it turns out) that had 16,000 memory blocks but could be scanned very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point I looked at the gmail process with &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/downloads/vmmap&quot;&gt;vmmap&lt;/a&gt; and noticed that the gmail process had a fair amount of memory (361,836 KiB) and a lot of separate blocks (49,719) coming from a single reservation in the Shareable category – a reservation with a size of 2,147,483,648 KiB, aka 2 TiB. Wot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;image&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image_thumb4.png?w=585&amp;amp;h=225&quot; width=&quot;585&quot; height=&quot;225&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I happened to know that the 2 TiB reservation is used for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alex-ionescu.com/?p=246&quot;&gt;Control Flow Guard&lt;/a&gt; (CFG), and I remembered that “CFG” showed up on the call stacks where the gmail Chrome process was waiting – MiCommitVadCfgBits was on the stack. Maybe the large number of blocks in the CFG region were the problem!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control Flow Guard (CFG) is used to try to stop exploits. Its 2 TiB reservation is a sparse bitmap which indicates which addresses (across 128 TiB of user-mode address space) are valid indirect branch targets. So I modified my virtual memory scanner to count how many blocks were in the CFG region (just look for the 2 TiB reservation) and how many blocks were tagged as executable. Since CFG memory is used to &lt;em&gt;describe&lt;/em&gt; executable memory I expected to see one block of CFG memory for each block of executable memory in the process. Instead I saw 98 blocks of executable memory and &lt;em&gt;24,866&lt;/em&gt; blocks of committed CFG memory. A significant discrepancy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;     Scan time,  Committed, page tables, committed blocks&lt;br/&gt;Total: 41.763s, 1457.7 MiB,    67.7 MiB,  32112, 98 code blocks&lt;br/&gt;  CFG: 41.759s,  353.3 MiB,    59.2 MiB,  24866&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;vmmap shows reservations and commited memory as blocks and my scanning tool only counts committed blocks – that’s why vmmap shows 49,684 blocks where my scanning tool reports 24,866&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight it is obvious, but what if the CFG bitmap never gets cleaned up? What if memory gets allocated in the CFG bitmap when you allocate executable memory, but it doesn’t get freed when you free the executable memory. That would explain this behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;End-to-end repro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step was to write a VAllocStress program that allocates and then frees thousands of blocks of executable memory at random addresses. This executable needs to have CFG enabled and needs to be 64-bit and I hit some road blocks because I didn’t really know what I was trying to do but it worked. After allocating and freeing this many blocks of executable memory this program should sit in a loop where it occasionally try to allocate/free more executable memory, and note when this is slow. Here is my basic algorithm for VAllocStress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Spin in a loop a lot of times:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allocate some executable memory with VirtualAlloc at a random address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free the memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then, spin in an infinite loop:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sleep for 500 ms (don’t want to be a CPU hog)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allocate some executable memory with VirtualAlloc at a fixed location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Print a message if the VirtualAlloc call takes more than ~500 ms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free the memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s it. It’s super simple. And it was so satisfying when it worked. I ran it and then got my VirtualScan program to scan my VAllocStress process. I quickly got confirmation that the CFG block was horribly fragmented, and the scanning took a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; time. And my VAllocStress program hung for the duration of the scan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I had simulated the CFG fragmentation, the long scanning times, and the hang. Huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Root-cause&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that v8 (Chrome’s JavaScript engine) has CodeRange objects for managing code-gen, and each CodeRange object is constrained to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.chromium.org/chromium/src/v8/src/globals.h?q=kMaximalCodeRangeSize&amp;amp;dr=CSs&amp;amp;l=182&quot;&gt;128 MiB address range&lt;/a&gt;. This should be small enough to avoid the rampant CFG allocation I was seeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if you have multiple CodeRange objects, and what if those get allocated at random addresses and then freed? I instrumented the CodeRange constructor, left gmail running, and found the smoking gun. Every couple of minutes another CodeRange object was created (and destroyed). Being in the debugger made it easy to find that WorkerThread::Start was allocating these objects, and suddenly everything makes sense:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;gmail uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/fundamentals/codelabs/offline/&quot;&gt;service workers&lt;/a&gt;, probably for implementing offline mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These appear and disappear every few minutes because that’s how service workers behave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each worker thread gets a temporary CodeRange object which allocates some executable pages for JITted JavaScript code from a random location in the 47-bit process address space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 2 TB CFG memory reservation gets some entries every time new code pages are allocated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CFG allocations are never freed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NtQueryVirtualMemory is &lt;em&gt;painfully&lt;/em&gt; slow when scanning CFG memory (about 1 ms per block) for reasons that I don’t understand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The slow scanning of CFG memory is actually fixed in Windows 10 RS4 (April 2018 Update), which briefly had me wondering if all of this investigation was pointless. But it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Memory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CFG reservation starts out as just an address reservation – no memory is actually committed. As executable pages are allocated however parts of the CFG reservation are turned into committed memory, using real memory pages. And those pages never get freed. If you keep allocating and freeing randomly located blocks of executable memory then the CFG region will grow arbitrarily large! Well, that’s not quite true. The CFG memory block is best thought of a cache with bounded size. However that is little consolation when the bounded size is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BruceDawson0xB/status/1029433717670871040&quot;&gt;2 TiB, per-process&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst I’ve seen so far is when my gmail tab had been running for eight days and had accumulated 353.3 MiB of CFG memory, and 59.2 MiB of page-tables to map that memory, for a total waste of about 400 MiB. For some reason most people see either no symptoms or much milder symptoms than I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The v8 (Chrome’s JavaScript engine) team has updated their code so that it &lt;a href=&quot;https://chromium-review.googlesource.com/c/v8/v8/+/1174837&quot;&gt;reuses addresses for CodeRange objects&lt;/a&gt;, which will squish this bug quite nicely. Microsoft already fixed their CFG memory scanning performance problems. Maybe some day Microsoft will free CFG regions when executable memory is freed, at least in the easy cases where large address ranges are freed. And a vmmap bug was reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my coworkers and our customers never noticed this problem. I only noticed it because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I had gmail’s offline mode enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was running on an old version of Windows 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our IT department was running regular WMI scans of our computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was paying attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got lucky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems highly improbably that, as one of the most qualified people to diagnose this bug, I was the first to notice it. If any of the factors above had not been true then I would not have experienced this hang and the associated memory waste might never have been found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, the reason that the hangs kept happening at 10:30 am is just because that’s when our IT team ran their inventory scans. If you want to trigger a scan manually, you can go to Control Panel | Configuration Manager | Actions | Select ‘Hardware Inventory Cycle’ and then Run Now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/clip_image002.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;clip_image002&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;clip_image002&quot; src=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/clip_image002_thumb.png?w=546&amp;amp;h=331&quot; width=&quot;546&quot; height=&quot;331&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Source code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to play along at home you can grab the source-code to VAllocStress and VirtualScan from github, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/randomascii/blogstuff/tree/master/cfg&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rabbit holes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This investigation included a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of rabbit holes. Some were important (page tables), some were instructive (locks), and some were purely a waste of time (WMI details). I’ll talk more about these, and a vmmap bug, in a follow-up post. If you want more gory details – some of which ended up being wrong or irrelevant – you can follow the whole investigation at &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.chromium.org/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=870054&quot;&gt;crbug.com/870054&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker news discussion is &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17780127&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-18565082-2858-5b7680335b358&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20180319#blog_id=18565082&amp;amp;post_id=2858&amp;amp;origin=randomascii.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=18565082-2858-5b7680335b358&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-18565082-2858-5b7680335b358&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ghuntley</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>24-core CPU and I can’t type an email (part one)</og:title>
<og:url>https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2018/08/16/24-core-cpu-and-i-cant-type-an-email-part-one/</og:url>
<og:description>I wasn’t looking for trouble. I wasn’t trying to build Chrome a thousand times in a weekend, I was just engaging in that most mundane of 21st century tasks, writing an email at 10:30 am. And sudden…</og:description>
<og:image>https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/clip_image002_thumb.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2018/08/16/24-core-cpu-and-i-cant-type-an-email-part-one/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Traveling the World on a Third World Passport</title>
<link>https://www.bucketlistly.blog/posts/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bucketlistly.blog/posts/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai</guid>
<description>&lt;div itemprop=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;281.07475150725&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many things in life that we can choose to be but one thing we can't choose is where we are born. The location of our birth can determine the opportunity we will get, the privilege we will receive, and it can predefine how our lives will play out. I truly believe that traveling the world is a rite of passage every human being in this world should take, but unfortunately, the access to this privilege is predetermined by which country we are born in and the passport we were given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been traveling the world since 2012 and every time I mentioned to the first-world passport holders, the things I have to go through in order to go to a place like Europe, they were shocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a Thai citizen through and through and my Thai passport is ranked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.passportindex.org/byRank.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external&quot;&gt;54 on the Passport Index&lt;/a&gt; with 39 countries visa-free, 41 visa-on-arrival and 116 countries visa required. In comparison to European passports which ranked 2 - 10 on the Passport Index with over 119 visa-free, 36 visa-on-arrival and only 43 countries visa required, you can see the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I hear first-world passport holders complain about doing a visa run or having to apply for an electronic visa online, I cringe a little. For us third-world passport holders, we have to go through much worst to get to places they can simply hop on a plane and be there in no time. How much worst? Well, let me explain the things we have to go through just to get to Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is it like?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox-full&quot; href=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5b155bed5711a8176e9f9783/5b1650f2d584e80016b7efde/files/166738817516-original-image.jpg?1529633552&quot; rel=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5b155bed5711a8176e9f9783/5b1650f2d584e80016b7efde/files/166738817516-original-image.jpg?1529633552&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5b155bed5711a8176e9f9783/5b1650f2d584e80016b7efde/files/166738817516-original-image.jpg?1529633552 500w, https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5b155bed5711a8176e9f9783/5b1650f2d584e80016b7efde/files/166738817516-original-image.jpg?1529633552 1200w&quot; data-original=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5b155bed5711a8176e9f9783/5b1650f2d584e80016b7efde/files/166738817516-original-image.jpg?1529633552&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 1200px&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; class=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe does not make it easy for us to travel to their continent, in contrary to them coming to us. The entire process takes at least 2 weeks to a month from us calling to book for a time slot which can be fully booked up to 2 weeks, to us picking the passport up which can be 3 days to a month from the day we apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Planning a Trip&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planning for a trip for people with a first world passport can simply be just buying a plane ticket and show up on time, but for us, it requires extensive planning weeks in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Europe, first we would have to find the embassy to apply, read up their document requirements and followed the list to a tee. Documents involved are usually a valid return flight ticket, all the accommodation booking details for the entire stay, an itinerary of the entire trip, a 3 months bank statement with cash movement (to prove that it is your money), a letter from work proving that you have something to return to, non-refundable fee from 50 - 200 USD and many more. If anything is missing from the documents, we would get rejected outright and we would have to make an appointment again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, going somewhere with a third world passport requires extensive research and careful planning that hinder us from exploring the world as freely as other types of passport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Traveling on a Whim&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often wonder why we, third-world passport holders, don't travel on a whim. The answer is simple, we can't. Our passport just doesn't allow the type of backpacking trip that goes on for months and months around the world without a return ticket. Even with countries that are visa-free to us, we sometimes get rejected if we do not have a return or onward ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the countries we are going, we are also forced to be bound to our home country because some visa applications require us to be in our home country to be able to apply. For example, I can not go traveling in Turkey for a few months and apply for a European visa in Istanbul to continue my journey to Europe. I have to come back to Thailand to get the visa and fly back to Europe which doubled the cost for us, and since we are not from a very rich country, we can only afford to do this so many time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What do we get?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most first-world passport holders, when you get a visa or exempted from one, you are often given a maximum fixed period of time you can stay in a country, say 90 days in Europe, or Thailand together with multi-entries. For us, on the other hand, is not as simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a third-world passport, often times, the duration we get is considerably less than our first-world counterpart. Europe is the worst at this because they will only give us the duration and the entry that is shown on our submitted itinerary. If we apply for a Schengen visa with a 10 days itinerary involving countries in the Schengen zone, instead of getting the 90 days maximum period like other passport holders, they would only give us 11 days single entry visa, which leave us no room for flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if we want to backpack through Europe for 3 months, we would have to book 90 days of accommodation, printed them all out and submitted to the embassy every time. Even with that, we wouldn't be able to go out of the Schengen zone, say for a small spontaneous trip to Croatia and get back into the Schengen area, because that will be considered multi-entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it is not all flowers and sunshine even after we got the visa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How I Travel the World With a Third World Passport&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox-full&quot; href=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e90f58d39907e58893d4/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-2.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91258d39907e58893d5/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-2-placeholder.jpg&quot; data-size=&quot;1280x859&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91458d39907e58893d6/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-2-500.jpg 500w, https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e90f58d39907e58893d4/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-2.jpg 1200w&quot; data-original=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e90f58d39907e58893d4/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-2.jpg&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 1200px&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; class=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though that sounds grim, I can confidently say that it is not impossible for us to travel the world like a first-world passport holder if we know our way around our passport weaknesses. There are many world travelers out there with a third world passport (&lt;a href=&quot;https://iamaileen.com/how-to-travel-the-world-third-world-passport/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Aileen from IAmAileen.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lovedandwanderlust.com/third-world-passport/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Melai from LovedandWanderlust.com&lt;/a&gt;) that are constantly pushing the limit of what is possible for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Research and Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all comes down to doing your homework before a trip. First I would see which countries have my passport exempted and I would try to stick to that area first and if I came across a country that requires me to get a visa prior to the trip, then I would go into their website and look at the visa application requirement one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is to do enough research that you have an itinerary you can base your trip on. You don't have to follow the itinerary to a tee but it is good to know which country you can go and cannot go without a visa in order to prevent disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, when I first planned my trip to the middle east, I wanted to go to Egypt, Jordan, and Turkey for 3 months. I found out early on that I would need a visa for Egypt prior to traveling and none needed for the other 2 so I went and got my Egypt visa beforehand. I was also looking at neighboring countries like Georgia and Armenia in case I have spare time which I did and I was prepared for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, you can travel the world with a third world passport with the flexibility like a first world passport if you do enough research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Paperwork for Visa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox-full&quot; href=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91758d39907e58893d7/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-3.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91d58d39907e58893d8/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-3-placeholder.jpg&quot; data-size=&quot;1280x853&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91f58d39907e58893d9/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-3-500.jpg 500w, https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91758d39907e58893d7/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-3.jpg 1200w&quot; data-original=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91758d39907e58893d7/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-3.jpg&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 1200px&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; class=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have done your homework, it's time to do the boring part, the paperwork. The key here is to prove to the embassy that you have the mean to come back to your home country. They put this rule in the first place to prevent us from going to their countries and work illegally and we will have to prove that that is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More often than not, the embassy will require you to provide several documents about your itineraries such as flights, accommodation, and day-to-day itinerary. Here is a list of things you are often asked to prepare:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Filled-in Application Form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Copy of Passport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 x photos with specific requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A confirmed return flight ticket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proof of booked accommodation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel Health Insurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A day-to-day itinerary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 months bank statement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proof of employment or a letter explaning what you do and how you earn money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;application form&lt;/strong&gt; is often found on the embassy website where you can fill in online, print it out and attach with a copy of your passport, 2 photos and all the other documents listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often &lt;strong&gt;book a flight&lt;/strong&gt; in advanced that would give me enough time for the visa process (a month prior) and often time I'd buy at full price so that I could get a full refund if need be. Be sure to look at the airline's refund policy so that you can choose the right type of ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a &lt;strong&gt;day-to-day itinerary&lt;/strong&gt;, I would often come up with a plan that I would stick to loosely and write them in the format shown below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Arrival Date] – [Departure Date]: Travel to [City], [Country] via [Bus or Train or Airline] and [a brief activity]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of the itinerary I wrote for my Europe trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan 22, 2018: Flight from Bangkok to Warsaw, Poland via Qatar Airline&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jan 22, 2018 – Feb 12, 2018: Warsaw, Poland and travel around the city..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;strong&gt;accommodation&lt;/strong&gt;, I often go on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/index.html?aid=905356&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Booking.com&lt;/a&gt; to book the accommodation for the entire time I planned to be traveling based on the day-to-day itinerary I came up with, printed the email confirmation, and make sure that the date on the booking confirmation emails add up to the exact amount of time I want to be there for. Booking.com is great for this because they allow you to cancel the booking for free if need be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;strong&gt;travel insurance&lt;/strong&gt;, I often buy mine from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldnomads.com/Turnstile/AffiliateLink?partnerCode=blbe9200&amp;amp;utm_source=blbe9200&amp;amp;source=link&amp;amp;utm_content=link&amp;amp;path=https://www.worldnomads.com/travel-insurance/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;World Nomads&lt;/a&gt; which has all the tools I need to get the right travel insurance for the right country I am going to and covers the entire time I would be there for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;strong&gt;proof of employment&lt;/strong&gt;, you can ask your employer to provide an employment letter with your job title, the date you started and a signature of an authorized personnel in your company. If you are like me who do not have an employer, you will have to write your own letter explaining in detail what you do, who is your client, and how much money you are making per month. If you have any business website to show, capture a screenshot and print them out too. The good thing is once you have written one freelance letter for an application, you can reuse that forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, the &lt;strong&gt;bank statement&lt;/strong&gt;. This is by far one of the most important documents you will have to carefully prepare. One of the criteria they used to approve or reject people is the amount of money you have. You must have enough money in your bank account to cover the entire trip and the bank statement will have to show an active bank account with money coming in and out regularly in the last 3 months which is to prevent people from asking others to temporary transfer the money to the account just for the visa process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my experience, if you have around 2,000 USD in your account for a 3 months trip in Europe, that should be enough to prove that you can cover all the cost but the value varies considerably depending on your duration, the embassy you are applying to and how expensive that country is, so prepare accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Apply Process&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox-full&quot; href=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e92058d39907e58893da/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-4.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e92358d39907e58893db/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-4-placeholder.jpg&quot; data-size=&quot;1280x853&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e92558d39907e58893dc/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-4-500.jpg 500w, https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e92058d39907e58893da/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-4.jpg 1200w&quot; data-original=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e92058d39907e58893da/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-4.jpg&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 1200px&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; class=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of applying for a visa varies depending on the embassy but for the most part, you will have to make an appointment with the embassy in your home country, prepare all your documents according to their requirements on their website, and organized them in the order they recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is no embassy in your home country, then you can apply it in any country that has it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once all the documents are ready, you will have to go to the embassy at the time slot you were assigned to and give them all your documents. They may ask you a few questions about your trip, so answer them truthfully and the process should go smoothly. They will usually tell you when you will get the result so all you have to do now is wait until they call you and they will tell you when you can come and pick up the result. You won't know the result until you pick it up so don't bother asking the person who called you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Getting Rejected&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting rejected is a common occurrence for us. I was lucky enough to only got rejected once, but many people often do and all we can do is observe what went wrong and try again. There are many factors that could affect the outcome of a visa process and more often than not, it boils down to either we did not give enough proof of our return or the bank statement did not pass their requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is to never give up and keep trying. You just need to know what the embassy is looking for in your application and try to prepare enough documents to reinforce it. When it comes to applying for a visa, &lt;strong&gt;it is always better to be over prepared than under prepared&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this guide helps shed light on how lucky it is to be a first-world passport holder, the situation us, third-world passport holders have to deal with and how we can overcome the limits of our passport and travel the world freely. If you have any question, please do not hesitate to ask me in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking for more inspirational articles? Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bucketlistly.blog/inspiration&quot;&gt;The Solo Traveler’s Inspiration&lt;/a&gt; section where we will discuss topics related to the nomadic and traveling lifestyle and shower-thoughts that will invoke wanderlust in all of us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bucketlistly.blog/resources&quot;&gt;The Solo Traveler’s Resources&lt;/a&gt; is a series of posts by Bucketlistly where we will explore the ways of life of nomads including how we work, travel, and what we carry in our backpack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 20:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cirrus-clouds</dc:creator>
<og:title>Traveling the World on a Third World Passport - What is it like and how to overcome it</og:title>
<og:description>There are many things in life that we can choose to be but one thing we can't choose is where we are born. The location of our birth can determine the opportunity we will get, the privilege we will receive, and it can predefine how our lives will play out....</og:description>
<og:image>https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5adf77af6eabcc00190b75b6/5b39e92c58d39907e58893de/files/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-main-image-op.jpg?1533014686</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bucketlistly.blog/posts/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bucketlistly.blog/posts/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Hire</title>
<link>https://hbr.org/2018/01/how-to-hire</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hbr.org/2018/01/how-to-hire</guid>
<description>&lt;h4 class=&quot;ideainbrief-title&quot;&gt;In Brief&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ideainbrief-contents&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;The Problem&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most companies approach hiring with faulty assumptions and poor practices. They believe talent is fixed rather than contextual. They fail to create real partnerships between recruiters and hiring managers. And they rely too much on salary surveys and rigid compensation formulas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;The Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dig beneath the résumé. Ensure that recruiters deeply understand the business and are not viewed as support staff. Don’t obsess over “culture fit”; assess whether candidates can drive growth and address pressing challenges. Calculate the real value they can bring to the company and the comp package required to get them to sign on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really dislike the term “A player.” It implies a grading system that can determine who will be best for a position. HR people always ask how Netflix, where I served as chief talent officer from 1998 to 2012, managed to hire only A players. I say, “There’s an island populated exclusively by A players, but only some of us know where it is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth, one company’s A player may be a B player for another firm. There is no formula for what makes people successful. Many of the people we let go from Netflix because they were not excelling at what we were doing went on to excel in other jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the right people is also not a matter of “culture fit.” What most people really mean when they say someone is a good fit culturally is that he or she is someone they’d like to have a beer with. But people with all sorts of personalities can be great at the job you need done. This misguided hiring strategy can also contribute to a company’s lack of diversity, since very often the people we enjoy hanging out with have backgrounds much like our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making great hires is about recognizing great matches—and often they’re not what you’d expect. Take Anthony Park. On paper he wasn’t a slam dunk for a Silicon Valley company. He was working at an Arizona bank, where he was a “programmer,” not a “software developer.” And he was a pretty buttoned up guy. We called Anthony because in his spare time he’d created a Netflix-enhancing app, which he had posted on his website. He came in for a day of interviews, and everyone loved him. When he got to me, late in the day, I told him he would be getting an offer. He seemed overwhelmed, so I asked if he was all right. He said, “You’re going to pay me a lot of money to do what I love!” I did wonder how he’d fit in with the high-powered team he was joining; I hoped it wouldn’t burn him out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months later I sat in on a meeting of his team. Everyone was arguing until Anthony suddenly said, “Can I speak now?” The room went silent, because Anthony didn’t say much, but when he did speak, it was something really smart—something that would make us all wonder, &lt;em&gt;Damn it, why didn’t I think of that?&lt;/em&gt; Now Anthony is a vice president. He’s proof that organizations can adapt to many people’s styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article I’ll describe what I’ve learned about making great hires during my 14 years at Netflix and in subsequent consulting on culture and leadership. The process requires probing beneath the surface of people and their résumés; engaging managers in every aspect of hiring; treating your in-house recruiters as true business partners; adopting a mindset in which you’re always recruiting; and coming up with compensation that suits the performance you need and the future you aspire to. My observations may be especially relevant to fast-growing tech-based firms, whose rapid innovation means a continual need for new talent. But organizations of all types can benefit from taking a fresh look at their hiring and compensation practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Probe Beneath the Surface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Netflix we had to be creative about where we searched for talent, because we often needed people with rarefied technical skills. When we began looking for big data experts, for example, no one even really knew what “big” meant. We couldn’t just search résumés and do keyword matching. We had to think about all the different kinds of companies—many were insurance or credit card companies—that handled masses of data. What’s more, our recruiting team lacked the in-depth knowledge to assess people’s technical skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our best recruiter of technical people was Bethany Brodsky. She knew virtually nothing about technology before coming to Netflix, but she was great at understanding our business and the root problems we had to solve. She also understood that a candidate’s approach to problem solving was more important than previous experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Bethany’s best interviews was with someone working at Lawrence Livermore—a government research center focused on nuclear science. This was when Netflix was beginning to stream on Xbox, Roku, and TiVo. When interviewing candidates, Bethany would tell them we had signed up a million subscribers in just 30 days on one of those devices and ask which one they thought it was. TiVo was taking off then, so most people said, “TiVo, for sure.” But this candidate asked whether any conditions were attached to getting a Netflix subscription on any of the devices. She told him that Xbox subscribers needed a gold membership. He reasoned that it must be Xbox, because its users were already willing to pay a premium. He was right, and she knew he was our guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-callout&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout-contents&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;Making great hires is about recognizing great matches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a similar “aha” moment when I interviewed Christian Kaiser, who was managing a group of 25 programmers at AOL. I had tried to hire quite a few people from his group, because they were doing the kind of technical work we needed. But they all wanted to stay at AOL. Netflix was a much sexier place to work, so I was perplexed. When I asked them about it, they would say, “I have the most amazing boss! He’s the best communicator I’ve ever known. I can’t bear the thought of leaving him.” I told my recruiters, “Go get that guy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christian wasn’t what I’d expected. He had a thick German accent, and he stuttered. This was the great communicator? On top of that, he was clearly nervous. Our conversation was painful for him and for me. But when I asked him to explain, in simple terms, the technical work he was doing, he was transformed. He still stuttered, but he gave me a riveting explanation, and I realized, &lt;em&gt;That’s it! He’s great at making really complicated things understandable.&lt;/em&gt; We hired him, and he’s been an amazing team builder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always tried to be creative about probing people and their résumés. Bethany once decided to analyze the résumés of our best data-science people for common features. She found that those people shared an avid interest in music. From then on she and her team looked for that quality. She recalls, “We’d get really excited and call out, ‘Hey, I found a guy who plays piano!’” She concluded that such people can easily toggle between their left and right brains—a great skill for data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Engage Managers Fully&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many companies rely on outside recruiters. Netflix was growing so quickly that we opted for a different strategy: We formed an internal team of experienced recruiters. The sad truth is that most companies treat recruitment as a separate, nonbusiness, even non-HR function, and many young companies outsource it. Building a talented team of internal recruiters was a substantial investment, but I could make an irrefutable business case for doing so: I could clearly show what the return would be from eliminating headhunter fees. We saved bundles of money over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical nature of our business meant that managers needed to be highly engaged in the hiring process. But that should be required at all companies. Every hiring manager should understand the company’s approach to hiring and how to execute on it, down to the smallest detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-callout&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout-contents&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;Your HR chief should understand the details of your business.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our recruiters’ job involved coaching our hiring managers. The recruiters created a slide deck to use with each manager, one-on-one. They would ask, “What does your interview process look like? What does your interview team look like? What is your process for having candidates come in?” People don’t have to approach interviewing or recruiting in the same way, but we insisted that they have a plan and not just improvise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the manager would make the hiring decision. Team members provided input, and my team and I also weighed in. But the ultimate responsibility was the manager’s, as was the performance of the team he or she was building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this should be modeled from the top. Bethany once worked with our CEO, Reed Hastings, to fill a director-level position. They met on a Thursday morning to discuss what type of candidate they needed. Friday afternoon Reed e-mailed her to say he had sent messages to 20 prospects he’d found on LinkedIn and had gotten three responses. He’d interviewed one via Skype, really liked him, and wanted him to come in on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When hiring managers are as engaged as Reed was, recruiters up their game even more. After getting Reed’s e-mail, Bethany was determined to find someone even better. (We ended up hiring Reed’s guy, and Reed gloated about it for years.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Treat Recruiters as Business Partners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the approach I’m describing to work, recruiters must be considered vital contributors to building the business. They need to deeply understand the needs of the business, and hiring managers need to treat them as business partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the two groups to work together optimally may require holding hiring managers’ feet to the fire. One day I heard one of my best recruiters complain about a new executive: “He doesn’t return my calls or e-mails. I send him résumés, but he doesn’t respond. I’m frustrated, because we really need to build him a great team.” I walked up to her and said, “I think you need to work with someone else. I’ll take care of this.” Then I sent him an e-mail saying I had reassigned his recruiter: “I’ve put her on another project, because you appear to have a methodology for hiring and don’t seem to need her help. Let us know when we can step in and assist. Love, Patty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within minutes he was at my desk, fuming. “What the hell?” he demanded. I asked him, “Is it true that she set up two meetings with you and you canceled?” He snapped, “I’m a busy guy. I’m doing the work of 10 people.” I asked, “Is it true that she sent you a number of qualified candidates and you didn’t respond? It’s your job to build the team, not hers. By the way, there are three people who are delighted that she’s not spending time on you. She’s a great partner; she could really make this work for you. But if you don’t need her, that’s cool.” Realizing that he did need the recruiter to help grow his team, he changed his tune and began treating her with respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It infuriates me when hiring managers dismiss the value of good HR people. Usually when I asked managers why they weren’t engaging more with recruiters, they’d say, “Well, they’re not that smart, and they don’t really understand what’s going on in my business or how the technology works.” My response would be “Then start expecting—and demanding—that they do!” If you hire smart people; insist that they be businesspeople; and include them in running the business, they’ll act like businesspeople.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On occasion I even advise companies to hire a businessperson, not an HR specialist, to run HR. Just like any other department or division head, your HR chief should understand the details of your business, how you earn your revenue, who your customers are, and your strategy for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Always Be Recruiting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Netflix we had a saying: “Always be recruiting!” Candidates came from everywhere—from professional conferences, from the sidelines of a kids’ soccer game, from conversations on airplanes. But certain fundamentals were strictly enforced. The interview and hiring process gives a powerful first impression about how your company operates, for good or bad. So I had an ironclad rule that if people saw a stranger sitting alone at headquarters waiting for an interview, they should stop and say, “Hi, I’m ____. Are you here for an interview? Let’s look at your schedule, and I’ll help you find the next person.” If I was late coming to meet with a candidate and said, “Sorry—I hope someone talked to you,” he or she would say, “Six people talked to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruiting was so important that interviews trumped any meeting a hiring manager was scheduled for, and they were the only reason people could miss our executive staff meetings. Candidates are evaluating you, just as you’re evaluating them. People forget that. Our goal was to have every person who came for an interview walk away wanting the job. Even if we hated candidates, we wanted them to think, &lt;em&gt;Wow, that was an incredible experience. It was efficient, it was effective, it was on time, the questions were relevant, everyone was smart, and I was treated with dignity.&lt;/em&gt; I would tell people, “Even if this person isn’t the right fit, we might love his next-door neighbor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We acted as quickly as possible once the decision was made: no running the hire by two levels of management, the compensation department, and HR. My team worked directly with hiring managers to determine compensation, title, and other details. Recruiters laid the groundwork; managers made the offers. Speed and efficiency often meant we could land candidates who were interviewing with other great companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Set Compensation That Makes Sense For You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitive salaries are obviously needed to lure top talent. Every business would like to mark its salaries to the market, but that can be challenging. There are amazingly sophisticated resources to tap for salary information; industry surveys cover every domain and give elaborate breakdowns by level. But jobs are not widgets, and neither are people. Roles are specialized in ways that survey descriptions cannot account for, and a candidate may have skills, such as good judgment and collaborative prowess, that can’t be measured by surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say you need a software engineer. Do you want a senior programmer fluent in the best new techniques in search engine development? And this person will be managing a staff of five? Oh, and this person also needs to understand online advertising systems well enough to work with marketing on an online advertising strategy? A survey is not going to tell you how much such a person is paid currently—or should be paid &lt;em&gt;by you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compensation departments spend gobs of time comparing descriptions and adjusting for other factors. However, that process gives you only a baseline understanding of the market landscape. How many people with those qualifications are available? To get the person you want, you often need to throw your calculations away and respond to actual market demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But market demand may not in itself be an adequate guide, because it reflects the present moment, and hiring should be about the future. The prevailing compensation system is often behind the times; it’s based on the historical value of what employees have produced rather than on their potential to add value in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that your recruiter manages to find a software engineer with all the credentials you need, and your team loves her, but she has an offer from your main competitor that’s $35,000 more than what you were prepared to pay. In determining what to offer, consider the difference it might make to the future of your business if you bring her in rather than settle for your second choice—who may be a distant second, and whom it will take three months to hire because you’ll keep looking for someone with the skills and talent of your first choice. How much added revenue might that great first choice produce? Might she ensure that you beat your competitor on the launch of a fabulous new search system—especially if she gets started now rather than three months down the road? How much ad revenue might she bring in by improving your targeting? What about the value of her management experience—might a key member of her team who gets an offer from another firm decide to stay because she’s a great leader? And what about the value to you of her not working for your competitor, particularly if your domain is undergoing rapid innovation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current market demand and salary surveys can’t help you calculate these future gains. I’m not saying there’s &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; value to benchmarking, but I advise forgoing elaborate calculations based on what other companies are paying right now; that’s comparing apples and oranges. It’s better to focus on what you can afford to pay for the performance you want and the future you’re heading toward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-callout&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout-contents&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;A candidate may have skills that can’t be measured by salary surveys.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve made an offer and hired someone, you need to keep assessing compensation. I learned this during a period when Netflix was losing people because of exorbitant offers from our competitors. One day I heard that Google had offered one of our folks almost twice his current pay, and I hit the roof. He was a really important guy, so his manager wanted to counter. I got into a heated e-mail exchange with his manager and a couple of VPs. I wrote, “Google shouldn’t decide the salaries for everybody just because they have more money than God!” We bickered for days. They kept telling me, “You don’t understand how good he is!” I was having none of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I woke up one morning and thought, &lt;em&gt;Oh, of course! No wonder Google wants him. They’re right!&lt;/em&gt; He had been working on some incredibly valuable personalization technology, and very few people in the world had his expertise. I realized that his work with us had given him a whole new market value. I fired off another e-mail: “I was wrong, and by the way, I went through the P&amp;amp;L, and we can double the salaries of everybody on this team.” That experience changed how we thought about compensation. We realized that for some jobs we were creating expertise and scarcity, and rigidly adhering to internal salary ranges could harm our best contributors, who could make more elsewhere. We decided we didn’t want a system in which people had to leave to be paid what they were worth. We also encouraged our employees to interview elsewhere regularly. That was the most reliable and efficient way to learn how competitive our pay was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often tell me, “We can’t pay top dollar. That was great for Netflix, because the company was booming. But we’re not growing that way, and we don’t have the margin.” Fair enough. Maybe it’s not possible to pay top of market for every position. In that case I suggest identifying the positions with the greatest potential to boost your performance and paying top dollar to fill them with the very best people you can get. Think about it this way: What if by paying top of market you could bring in one supremely talented person who could do the job of two people or add even more value than that? Consider the 80/20 rule about sales teams: that 20% of your salespeople will generate 80% of your revenue. It may apply to other employees. I’ve seen a similar effect on team after team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another objection I often hear to hiring star performers at top pay is that their salaries will be much higher than those of their teammates. Managers at Netflix used to complain about that. Say we wanted to bring in someone whose salary would be twice that of everybody else on the team. Department heads would sometimes ask, “Does that mean I’m paying people half of what they’re worth?” I’d say, “Well, is this new person going to be able to move us faster, maybe even twice as fast? And when we hire him, who on your team could take his place at his former company?” The answers were usually “Yeah, we’ll be able to move much faster” and “None of them could replace him, because they don’t have his experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This focus on the value-add of an individual star is especially important when a company is scaling up. I recently got a call from a CEO whose company employs 150 people. He said it would be growing to 300 and asked my advice on getting there. I said, “That’s a precise number of people. What’s it based on?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said his company would need to do twice as much work. I asked would the new people be doing the same kinds of work as the current staff, or would there be new things? Would the company be launching a product line? And if teams were getting bigger, might he need more-experienced managers? Did twice as much work mean reaching twice as many customers? If so, he would have to ramp up customer service. But that might not mean hiring twice as many reps; maybe outsourcing would be better. Then I asked the question I’ve found to be the most thought-provoking in these consultations: “Instead of 150 new people, are you sure you don’t want 75 people whom you pay twice as much because they have twice as much experience and can be higher performers?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that if you focus intently on hiring the best people you can find and pay them top dollar, chances are your business growth will more than make up for what you spend on compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mvm description-text hbrgray, line-height-tight&quot; readability=&quot;25.428571428571&quot;&gt;A version of this article appeared in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/archive-toc/BR1801&quot;&gt;January–February 2018&lt;/a&gt; issue (pp.90–97) of &lt;em&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 19:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>devy</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2017/12/R1801F_AFONSO.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://hbr.org/2018/01/how-to-hire</og:url>
<og:description>And other things you’re doing wrong, according to Patty McCord.</og:description>
<og:title>Stop Hiring for Culture Fit</og:title>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hbr.org/2018/01/how-to-hire</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Hacker News Habit</title>
<link>https://hackernewslater.com/posts/the-hacker-news-habit/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hackernewslater.com/posts/the-hacker-news-habit/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;mt4 w-100&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;f6 b helvetica tracked&quot;&gt;POSTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;time class=&quot;f6 mv4 dib tracked&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-08-13T23:25:01-07:00&quot;&gt;August 13, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have an addiction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More accurately it’s a pesky bad habit I uncovered during a period of self-examination while on sabbatical – I love, excessively, the consumption of bite-sized posts, which I justify reading as it relates to my profession; I rationalize the act as a productive use of my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I call the Hacker News habit, and if you’re here, you may have it as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those without any semblance of this affliction, &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; is a no-frills news aggregator with a submission guideline for items that can be distilled to a single sentence, “anything that gratifies one’s intellectual curiosity.” The site is a de facto blog of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Y-Combinator&lt;/a&gt;, an American seed accelerator that provides startups a bit of funding for a bit of stake. Although I will not list them here, you may recognize some of the startups they’ve nurtured since 2005 if I rattled them off in conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News has been described by some as a platform that funnels talent into their network by connecting people on projects and encouraging people to apply to the accelerator. On the top of the website is a link to the jobs post, and on the bottom is a link to apply to YC. The site is without traditional ads and loads faster than 90% of the pages on the internet. It really is a special place on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hackernewslater.com/images/hn.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Screenshot of Hacker News&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/303/&quot;&gt;Gradle builds&lt;/a&gt;, or when I finally discover a root of a bug, my routine with Hacker News involves refreshing it, queuing stories I’m interested in by opening tabs and working my way down the front page. Some titles are provocative, while others can do the contents more justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subject matter of the articles range and they’re often exciting. Though software topics and startup news often dominate the site, it’s not uncommon to read about computer science, philosophy, music, art, literature, and sociology, or, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/how-an-ex-cop-rigged-mcdonalds-monopoly-game-and-stole-millions&quot;&gt;Jeff Maysh longform about elaborate stings and long cons&lt;/a&gt;. Anyone who loves knowledge would think this is amazing, but there is something wrong about the way I’m reading the items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While on the site, within a span of five minutes, I typically attempt to skim everything I’ve marked with interest. Afterward, I return to my work not feeling like I’ve read anything substantive, and by the end of the day, I forget about the links I’ve opened up, including the ones I meant to revisit. In other words, I’ve attempted to binge on texts that was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; meant to be consumed in seconds, unlike Twitter tweets. (As an aside, the only way I was able to kick the Twitter habit was to forget my password, and remain much too lazy to reset it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unfocused Reading is a Terrible Thing to Do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I began doing on my sabbatical is set aside about an hour a day to study and read, under the assumption that understanding and proficiency of a topic takes consistency and focus, with the expectation that progress will be slow and not necessarily incremental. I did this with Spanish, and topics in Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I could not report leaps and bounds on fluency, I improved overall and felt less stressed about not reading or studying enough. Any novels I read were physical books - no screens. This worked well, but I kept opening tabs on sites like Hacker News throughout the day, committing the act of &lt;em&gt;unfocused reading&lt;/em&gt;. This was when I surrendered to the fact that I had an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Solutions Can I Devise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many other Hacker News readers, I threw code at the problem. I decided to write an Android app that queues the Hacker News items I marked with interest, then have it send an email to me with my saved links at a time I specify. As a result, I can schedule what I want to read in advance, integrating the items with whatever else I want to read. This was a good opportunity to work on a personal project for Android and work on a platform I know nothing about, &lt;a href=&quot;https://spring.io/&quot;&gt;Spring&lt;/a&gt;, for the backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/AndroidFirst?src=hash&quot;&gt;#AndroidFirst&lt;/a&gt; because I wanted to try something new, and move further away from working on iOS. I chose Java on Spring, because in the world of fast and loose JavaScript, it’s easy to forget that Java is the OG high-level language that still powers many of the web applications today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote the Android app in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kotlin_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Kotlin&lt;/a&gt; - a statically typed language that runs on the JVM. There were no real surprises here, as I was around iOS when Swift was introduced to transition away from Objective-C: Kotlin and Swift are surprisingly similar; here is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://nilhcem.com/swift-is-like-kotlin/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; that compares the two. A big improvement over using Java is the null safety; being able to treat objects as potentially null thereby greatly reducing the odds of contributing to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tony_Hoare#Apologies_and_retractions&quot;&gt;Billion Dollar Mistake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To note, I did use &lt;a href=&quot;https://kotlinlang.org/docs/reference/coroutines.html&quot;&gt;coroutines&lt;/a&gt;, which as of Kotlin 1.1 is still an experimental feature. Coroutines allow you to run tasks on a different thread to prevent lockups on the UI for example. As a result, there is not a single AsyncTask on this app. It was as simple as the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-kotlin&quot;&gt;launch(CommonPool) {
  superLongRunningUIBlockingFunction() { data -&amp;gt;
    launch(UI) {
        updateUIWithData(data)
    }
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I experimented with using &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/topic/libraries/architecture/&quot;&gt;Android Architecture Components&lt;/a&gt;. With it, it is now easier to handle lifecycles, as the components are self -aware of the cycle. LiveData allows the UI to update pursuant to database changes, and Room makes writing boilerplate code to work with SQLite a thing of the past. I did not fumble around with Cursors when accessing the database - whether this is a curse or a godsend, you can decide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Midway through development, while wondering if this is an app that anyone would use, I found this &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17637835&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on one of my many HN breaks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hackernewslater.com/images/email_later_hn_post.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Oh Hacker News, you did it again!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that other people experience the same issue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Result&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of my work above is &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=hackernewslater.williamha.com.hackernewslater&quot;&gt;Hacker News Later&lt;/a&gt;, currently live on the Google Play store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hackernewslater.com/images/hacker_news_later_screen_shot.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Hacker News Later&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user can save the items they want based on the title, to be emailed to him or her later. At the moment, a user can’t read the items on the app unless they penalize themselves by buying credits (processing through Stripe). Although the app is about breaking the bad habit of reading the items immediately, I’m still reconsidering this feature, and perhaps replacing it with a snippet preview and option to read immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’m going to shift all Hacker News focused reading through this app sent via email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see below, I was curious about &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17763011&quot;&gt;Katie’s New Face&lt;/a&gt;, and the legitimacy of the claim that &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17767789&quot;&gt;Indian food can be made in five minutes&lt;/a&gt; via a subscription box service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hackernewslater.com/images/inbox_screen_shot.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;The Email&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacker News Later, The Digest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In making this app, the thought of doing a digest of Hacker News may be a worthwhile pursuit, so this is what I hope the blog may become – a place for me to curate and write about news items I find interesting on a weekly basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! If you’ve enjoyed this post, or even downloaded the app, I’m certainly open for comments and suggestions. If something does not work, I intend to fix it, so please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, my sabbatical is loosely coming to an end and I will be looking for interesting projects to work on. If you know of anything, please feel free to message me &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/burritofanatic&quot;&gt;@burritofanatic&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter; my direct messages are open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&quot;w-30-l mt6-l&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 18:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>burritofanatic</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Hacker News Habit</og:title>
<og:description>I have an addiction. More accurately it’s a pesky bad habit I uncovered during a period of self-examination while on sabbatical – I love, excessively, the consumption of bite-sized posts, which I justify reading as it relates to my profession; I rationalize the act as a productive use of my time. This is what I call the Hacker News habit, and if you’re here, you may have it as well.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>/posts/the-hacker-news-habit/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackernewslater.com/posts/the-hacker-news-habit/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who Left Open The Cookie Jar?</title>
<link>https://wholeftopenthecookiejar.eu</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://wholeftopenthecookiejar.eu</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Cookies have become an important aspect of the modern-day web. By default, browsers automatically attach cookies to all HTTP requests. This allows users to keep track which items they have added to their online shopping basket, or simply to log in to their favorite websites. However, cookies may also be exploited for more nefarious goals: users' online activies are tracked at large-scale by various advertising companies, or so-called cross-site attacks can be used to take over the account of an unwitting user. As a response to this increasing threat surface, a variety of defense mechanisms have been developed: either as anti-tracking or ad-blocking browser extensions, or as built-in browser features such as the Tracking Protection in Firefox, or SameSite cookies, which can be highly effective at thwarting cross-site attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important prerequisite for these privacy- and security-enhancing features to function properly, is that &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; requests need to comply with the imposed cookie policies. As browsers have become enormously complex, certain edge-cases may have been overlooked or the interplay of specific features may have unwanted side-effects. In our research, we created a framework to verify whether all imposed cookie- and request-policies are correctly applied (will be made available soon). Worryingly, we found that most mechanisms could be circumvented: for instance for all ad-blocking and anti-tracking browser extensions we discovered at least one technique that could bypass the policies. For the technical details of these findings, we invite you to read our &lt;a href=&quot;https://wholeftopenthecookiejar.eu/static/tpc-paper.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;, which was presented at USENIX Security ’18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been working with browser vendors and extension developers to mitigate the discovered issues. To verify whether you are affected by our detected bypasses, feel free to explore the data on this website (please note that we are still working to have the most up-to-date information available).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 17:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pmoriarty</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://wholeftopenthecookiejar.eu/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FDA approves first generic version of EpiPen</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp/2018/08/16/fda-approves-first-generic-version-of-epipen/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp/2018/08/16/fda-approves-first-generic-version-of-epipen/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-byline multiple&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Carolyn Y. Johnson&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-role&quot;&gt;, Reporter&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Laurie McGinley&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-role&quot;&gt;, Reporter&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;author-timestamp&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2018-08-16T01:05-500&quot;&gt;August 16 at 1:05 PM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-left&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/UXtAKwpFb5wIkPEtEJBr4lEVRPA=/311x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YRIAE4WEBM7PVIJJALOXALOYPA.jpg&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/1DM1nZTe6HJ79n9xaYAG-cihl30=/960x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YRIAE4WEBM7PVIJJALOXALOYPA.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/UXtAKwpFb5wIkPEtEJBr4lEVRPA=/311x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YRIAE4WEBM7PVIJJALOXALOYPA.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YRIAE4WEBM7PVIJJALOXALOYPA.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;311&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;A generic version of EpiPen was just approved by federal regulators. (REUTERS/Jim Bourg/File Photo)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The Food and Drug Administration approved the first generic version of EpiPen on Thursday, a move that will bring new competition for the lifesaving allergy injection that helped spark &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2016/09/21/watch-live-lawmakers-to-grill-executive-who-hiked-the-price-of-lifesaving-drug-epipen/?utm_term=.479068f70d3c&quot;&gt;public furor&lt;/a&gt; over high drug prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The new drug, from Teva Pharmaceuticals USA,&lt;/span&gt; is the first to be deemed a therapeutic equivalent of the EpiPen, which means that it can be automatically substituted at the pharmacy counter for prescriptions for EpiPen or EpiPen Jr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;3&quot;&gt;The approval comes right before the back-to-school season, when sales of EpiPen typically spike as parents stock up on injectors for school or replace expired ones, and people have reported difficulty filling EpiPen prescriptions. There has been “limited availability of EpiPen in certain areas in the U.S., including both pharmacy-level supply disruptions and a manufacturer issue,” according to FDA spokeswoman Theresa Eisenman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;4&quot;&gt;Teva spokeswoman Doris Saltkill said the price of the drug and the exact launch date were not yet available, but the company's statement suggested it would not be in time for many parents who are scrambling to find EpiPen in their pharmacies now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&quot;We're applying our full resources to this important launch in the coming months and [are] eager to begin supplying the market,&quot; the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;6&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/the-generic-drug-industry-has-brought-huge-cost-savings-that-may-be-changing/2017/08/01/ee128d0a-68cf-11e7-8eb5-cbccc2e7bfbf_story.html?utm_term=.10a5c5ea471d&quot;&gt;The generic drug industry has brought huge cost savings. That may be changing.&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;7&quot;&gt;The EpiPen, made by Mylan, is used to inject the hormone epinephrine into the thigh to quell potentially fatal reactions to bee stings, peanuts and other allergens. Although the key ingredient is cheap and the EpiPen itself was first approved in 1987, Mylan began increasing the price of the product, from less than $100 in 2007 for a pack of two injectors to $608 today. In response to criticism over the price of its drug, EpiPen introduced its own half-priced generic in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;9&quot;&gt;Other epinephrine injectors have been approved before, but they struggled to gain market share against a brand that used lobbying and marketing to establish a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/2016/08/25/7f83728a-6aee-11e6-ba32-5a4bf5aad4fa_story.html&quot;&gt;virtual monopoly&lt;/a&gt; on the market. Last year, the drug company Sanofi accused Mylan in a lawsuit of using illegal tactics to squash competition by its injector, called the Auvi-Q, which was discontinued and then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/01/19/epipen-competitor-to-launch-in-february/?utm_term=.394385043895&quot;&gt;relaunched by a different company, Kaléo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;10&quot;&gt;Mylan ultimately paid &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2016/10/07/mylan-to-pay-465-million-epipen-settlement/?utm_term=.30eb11ed97dc&quot;&gt;$465 million&lt;/a&gt; in a settlement with the Justice Department over questions about whether the Medicaid program overpaid for the drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;11&quot;&gt;The Teva product had a hard road to approval, in part because it is a complex generic, meaning the medicine includes both an injector device and a drug. Mylan actively fought the approval of the drug, sending a citizen petition to the FDA in 2015 arguing that the drug was not truly equivalent. The FDA rejected Teva's initial application in 2016, citing “major deficiencies.” Under FDA Commissioner Scott Gottlieb, the agency has &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.fda.gov/fdavoice/index.php/2017/10/reducing-the-hurdles-for-complex-generic-drug-development/&quot;&gt;made it a priority&lt;/a&gt; to smooth the regulatory pathway for such “complex generics” that are difficult to copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;12&quot;&gt;Teva's generic will compete against Mylan's own authorized generic, which already has steeply eroded its brand-name sales. Roughly &lt;a href=&quot;http://investor.mylan.com/node/20216/html&quot;&gt;$1 billion in sales of the brand-name version&lt;/a&gt; of brand name EpiPen in 2016 dropped by more than &lt;a href=&quot;http://investor.mylan.com/node/27081/html&quot;&gt;half in 2017.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;13&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/2016/08/25/7f83728a-6aee-11e6-ba32-5a4bf5aad4fa_story.html?utm_term=.2c88437b82fd&quot;&gt;How Mylan, the maker of EpiPen, became a virtual monopoly&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;14&quot;&gt;In September, the FDA said that Meridian Medical Technologies, a Pfizer company that manufactures the EpiPen, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/09/07/epipen-maker-failed-to-investigate-product-failures-associated-with-patient-deaths-fda-says/?utm_term=.d1366f4c1d0a&quot;&gt;failed to properly investigate&lt;/a&gt; more than 100 complaints that the device malfunctioned during life-threatening emergencies — including situations in which patients died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot;&gt;The approval is a victory for the FDA as the Trump administration seeks to deliver on its promise to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2018/06/08/two-weeks-after-trump-unveiled-plan-to-lower-drug-prices-two-cancer-drugs-got-a-1000-per-month-price-hike/&quot;&gt;lower drug prices&lt;/a&gt;. “This approval means patients living with severe allergies who require constant access to lifesaving epinephrine should have a lower-cost option, as well as another approved product to help protect against potential &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp/2017/10/09/hospitals-scramble-to-avert-saline-shortage-in-wake-of-puerto-rico-disaster/&quot;&gt;drug shortages&lt;/a&gt;,” Gottlieb said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;17&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/09/07/epipen-maker-failed-to-investigate-product-failures-associated-with-patient-deaths-fda-says/?utm_term=.16b53b9c0980&quot;&gt;EpiPen maker failed to investigate product flaws associated with patient deaths, FDA says&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;18&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/what-the-cvs-aetna-deal-means-for-the-future-of-health-care/2017/12/05/e14a8d18-d907-11e7-a841-2066faf731ef_story.html?utm_term=.ee16329c5d5a&quot;&gt;What the CVS-Aetna deal means for the future of health care&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 17:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MBCook</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp/2018/08/16/fda-approves-first-generic-version-of-epipen/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/r0hfV3W2zV_OZZQy2cXile_FH6E=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YRIAE4WEBM7PVIJJALOXALOYPA.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>FDA approves first generic version of EpiPen</og:title>
<og:description>The new drug could be substituted at the pharmacy counter for EpiPen.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp/2018/08/16/fda-approves-first-generic-version-of-epipen/?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introduction to A* (1997)</title>
<link>http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/AStarComparison.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/AStarComparison.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Introduction to A*&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;shortcut icon&quot; href=&quot;/~amitp/favicon.ico&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/~amitp/red_blob.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;preload&quot; as=&quot;image&quot; href=&quot;/~amitp/transparent-blob.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/AStarComparison.html&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;application/atom+xml&quot; title=&quot;Blobs in Games - Atom&quot; href=&quot;https://simblob.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:creator&quot; content=&quot;@redblobgames&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;verify-v1&quot; content=&quot;82b+h1+tgwLrcTqTiJrqquMvoFVBwMwY11dx63m01zk=&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;gameprog widthflex&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;86.706992374305&quot;&gt;
&lt;header&gt;

&lt;nav&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;29&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Movement for a single object seems easy. Pathfinding is complex. Why bother with pathfinding? Consider the following situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;318&quot; src=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/concave1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unit is initially at the bottom of the map and wants to get to the top. There is nothing in the area it scans (shown in pink) to indicate that the unit should not move up, so it continues on its way. Near the top, it detects an obstacle and changes direction. It then finds its way around the “U”-shaped obstacle, following the red path. In contrast, a pathfinder would have scanned a larger area (shown in light blue), but found a shorter path (blue), never sending the unit into the concave shaped obstacle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can however extend a movement algorithm to work around traps like the one shown above. Either avoid creating concave obstacles, or mark their convex hulls as dangerous (to be entered only if the goal is inside):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;318&quot; src=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/concave2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pathfinders let you plan ahead rather than waiting until the last moment to discover there’s a problem. There’s a tradeoff between planning with pathfinders and reacting with movement algorithms. Planning generally is slower but gives better results; movement is generally faster but can get stuck. If the game world is changing often, planning ahead is less valuable. I recommend using both: pathfinding for big picture, slow changing obstacles, and long paths; and movement for local area, fast changing, and short paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;24.702127659574&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;algorithms&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/AStarComparison.html#algorithms&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;Algorithms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have written a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redblobgames.com/pathfinding/a-star/introduction.html&quot;&gt;newer version of this one page&lt;/a&gt;, but not the rest of the pages. It has interactive diagrams and sample code.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pathfinding algorithms from computer science textbooks work on &lt;em&gt;graphs&lt;/em&gt; in the mathematical sense―a set of vertices with edges connecting them. A tiled game map can be considered a graph with each tile being a vertex and edges drawn between tiles that are adjacent to each other:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;246&quot; height=&quot;246&quot; src=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/game-programming/a-star/map-as-graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I will assume that we’re using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-cs-students.stanford.edu/~amitp/game-programming/grids/&quot;&gt;two-dimensional grids&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven’t worked with graphs before, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redblobgames.com/pathfinding/grids/graphs.html&quot;&gt;see this primer&lt;/a&gt;. Later on, I’ll discuss &lt;a href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/MapRepresentations.html#polygonal-maps&quot;&gt;how to build other kinds of graphs out of your game world&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most pathfinding algorithms from AI or Algorithms research are designed for arbitrary graphs rather than grid-based games. We’d like to find something that can take advantage of the nature of a game map. There are some things we consider common sense, but that algorithms don’t understand. We know something about distances: in general, as two things get farther apart, it will take longer to move from one to the other, assuming there are no wormholes. We know something about directions: if your destination is to the east, the best path is more likely to be found by walking to the east than by walking to the west. On grids, we know something about symmetry: most of the time, moving north then east is the same as moving east then north. This additional information can help us make pathfinding algorithms run faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;42.985482781904&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;dijkstras-algorithm-and-best-first-search&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/AStarComparison.html#dijkstras-algorithm-and-best-first-search&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;Dijkstra’s Algorithm and Best-First-Search&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;S2&quot;/&gt; Dijkstra’s Algorithm works by visiting vertices in the graph starting with the object’s starting point. It then repeatedly examines the closest not-yet-examined vertex, adding its vertices to the set of vertices to be examined. It expands outwards from the starting point until it reaches the goal. Dijkstra’s Algorithm is guaranteed to find a shortest path from the starting point to the goal, as long as none of the edges have a negative cost. (I write “a shortest path” because there are often multiple equivalently-short paths.) In the following diagram, the pink square is the starting point, the blue square is the goal, and the teal areas show what areas Dijkstra’s Algorithm scanned. The lightest teal areas are those farthest from the starting point, and thus form the “frontier” of exploration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;526&quot; height=&quot;376&quot; src=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/game-programming/a-star/dijkstra.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Greedy Best-First-Search algorithm works in a similar way, except that it has some estimate (called a &lt;em&gt;heuristic&lt;/em&gt;) of how far from the goal any vertex is. Instead of selecting the vertex closest to the starting point, it selects the vertex closest to the goal. Greedy Best-First-Search is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; guaranteed to find a shortest path. However, it runs much quicker than Dijkstra’s Algorithm because it uses the heuristic function to guide its way towards the goal very quickly. For example, if the goal is to the south of the starting position, Greedy Best-First-Search will tend to focus on paths that lead southwards. In the following diagram, yellow represents those nodes with a high heuristic value (high cost to get to the goal) and black represents nodes with a low heuristic value (low cost to get to the goal). It shows that Greedy Best-First-Search can find paths very quickly compared to Dijkstra’s Algorithm:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;526&quot; height=&quot;376&quot; src=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/game-programming/a-star/best-first-search.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, both of these examples illustrate the simplest case―when the map has no obstacles, and the shortest path really is a straight line. Let’s consider the concave obstacle as described in the previous section. Dijkstra’s Algorithm works harder but is guaranteed to find a shortest path:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;526&quot; height=&quot;376&quot; src=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/game-programming/a-star/dijkstra-trap.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greedy Best-First-Search on the other hand does less work but its path is clearly not as good:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;526&quot; height=&quot;376&quot; src=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/game-programming/a-star/best-first-search-trap.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble is that Greedy Best-First-Search is “greedy” and tries to move towards the goal even if it’s not the right path. Since it only considers the cost to get to the goal and ignores the cost of the path so far, it keeps going even if the path it’s on has become really long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be nice to combine the best of both? A* was developed in 1968 to combine heuristic approaches like Greedy Best-First-Search and formal approaches like Dijsktra’s Algorithm. It’s a little unusual in that heuristic approaches usually give you an approximate way to solve problems without guaranteeing that you get the best answer. However, A* is built on top of the heuristic, and although the heuristic itself does not give you a guarantee, A* &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; guarantee a shortest path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;27.840760157274&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-a-star-algorithm&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/AStarComparison.html#the-a-star-algorithm&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;The A* Algorithm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;S3&quot;/&gt; I will be focusing on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A-star_search_algorithm&quot;&gt;A* Algorithm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. A* is the most popular choice for pathfinding, because it’s fairly flexible and can be used in a wide range of contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A* is like Dijkstra’s Algorithm in that it can be used to find a shortest path. A* is like Greedy Best-First-Search in that it can use a heuristic to guide itself. In the simple case, it is as fast as Greedy Best-First-Search:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;526&quot; height=&quot;376&quot; src=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/game-programming/a-star/a-star.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the example with a concave obstacle, A* finds a path as good as what Dijkstra’s Algorithm found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;526&quot; height=&quot;376&quot; src=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/game-programming/a-star/a-star-trap.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret to its success is that it combines the pieces of information that Dijkstra’s Algorithm uses (favoring vertices that are close to the starting point) &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; information that Greedy Best-First-Search uses (favoring vertices that are close to the goal). In the standard terminology used when talking about A*, &lt;code&gt;g(n)&lt;/code&gt; represents the &lt;em&gt;exact cost&lt;/em&gt; of the path from the starting point to any vertex &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;h(n)&lt;/code&gt; represents the heuristic &lt;em&gt;estimated cost&lt;/em&gt; from vertex &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; to the goal. In the above diagrams, the yellow (&lt;code&gt;h&lt;/code&gt;) represents vertices far from the goal and teal (&lt;code&gt;g&lt;/code&gt;) represents vertices far from the starting point. A* balances the two as it moves from the starting point to the goal. Each time through the main loop, it examines the vertex &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; that has the lowest &lt;code&gt;f(n) = g(n) + h(n)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of this article will explore &lt;a href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/Heuristics.html&quot;&gt;heuristic design&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/ImplementationNotes.html&quot;&gt;implementation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/MapRepresentations.html&quot;&gt;map representation&lt;/a&gt;, and a variety of other topics related to the use of pathfinding in games. Some sections are well-developed and others are rather incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;nav class=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;This is page 1 of 13 of &lt;a href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/index.html&quot;&gt;Amit’s Thoughts on Pathfinding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;←Back: &lt;a rel=&quot;prev&quot; href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/index.html&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Up: &lt;a href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/index.html&quot;&gt;Table of contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Next: &lt;a rel=&quot;next&quot; href=&quot;http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/Heuristics.html&quot;&gt;Heuristics&lt;/a&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;statcounter&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;statcounter&quot; href=&quot;http://statcounter.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;statcounter&quot; src=&quot;http://c.statcounter.com/417499/0//1/&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 17:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://theory.stanford.edu/~amitp/GameProgramming/AStarComparison.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Employees Protest Work on Censored Search Engine for China</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/16/technology/google-employees-protest-search-censored-china.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/16/technology/google-employees-protest-search-censored-china.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;42.279534109817&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;31.709650582363&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Hundreds of Google employees, upset at the company’s decision to secretly build a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/01/technology/china-google-censored-search-engine.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;censored version of its search engine for China&lt;/a&gt;, have signed a letter demanding more transparency to understand the ethical consequences of their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In the letter, which was obtained by The New York Times, employees wrote that the project and Google’s apparent willingness to abide by China’s censorship requirements “raise urgent moral and ethical issues.” They added, “Currently we do not have the information required to make ethically-informed decisions about our work, our projects, and our employment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The letter is circulating on Google’s internal communication systems and is signed by about 1,400 employees, according to three people familiar with the document, who were not authorized to speak publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The internal activism presents another obstacle for Google’s potential return to China eight years after the company publicly withdrew from the country in protest of censorship and government hacking. China has the world’s largest internet audience but has frustrated American tech giants with content restrictions or outright blockages of services including Facebook and Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;42.022271714922&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;32.106904231626&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;It is also the latest example of how Google’s outspoken work force has agitated for changes to strategy. In April, the internet company’s employees spoke out against its &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/04/technology/google-letter-ceo-pentagon-project.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;involvement in a Pentagon program&lt;/a&gt; that uses artificial intelligence to improve weaponry. By June, Google had said it &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/01/technology/google-pentagon-project-maven.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;would not renew a contract&lt;/a&gt; with the Pentagon for A.I. work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Google’s interest in bringing search back to China came to the forefront earlier this month, when &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/08/01/google-china-search-engine-censorship/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reports surfaced&lt;/a&gt; that the company was working on a search app that restricts content banned by Beijing. The project, known internally as Dragonfly, was developed largely in secret, prompting outrage among employees who worried they had been unwittingly working on technology that would help China withhold information from its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We urgently need more transparency, a seat at the table, and a commitment to clear and open processes: Google employees need to know what we’re building,” the letter said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The letter also called on Google to allow employees to participate in ethical reviews of the company’s products, to appoint external representatives to ensure transparency and to publish an ethical assessment of controversial projects. The document referred to the situation as a code yellow, a process used in engineering to address critical problems that impact several teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;44.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Google declined to comment on the letter. It has said in the past that it will not comment on Dragonfly or “speculation about future plans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Late on Thursday, employees pressed Google’s chief executive, Sundar Pichai, and other management about Dragonfly at a weekly staff meeting. As of late Wednesday, one of the top questions on an internal software system called Dory, which lets employees vote for the queries that executives should answer at the meeting, asked whether Google had lost its ethical compass, said people who had reviewed the questions. Other questions on Dory asked directly about the Dragonfly project and specific information that may be censored by the Chinese government, such as air pollution data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“If we were to do our mission well, we are to think seriously about how to do more in China,” Mr. Pichai said in the staff meeting, audio of which was obtained by The Times. “That said, we are not close to launching a search product in China.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Pichai and Sergey Brin, a co-founder of Google, stopped answering questions about Dragonfly after seeing their answers posted on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;36.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;This week’s staff meeting was the first opportunity for Google’s work force to ask executives about Dragonfly, because the meeting was not held last week. The absence of a gathering — the result of a regularly scheduled break in the summer, according to a company spokesman, Rob Shilkin — led to fears among employees that leadership was becoming less transparent following several controversies over Google’s government work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Google has traditionally been more responsive to employee concerns and more transparent about future projects and inner workings than other major technology companies, inviting questions from workers at its staff meetings and encouraging internal debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;41.30801987225&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;30.38750887154&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The internal dissent over Dragonfly comes on the heels of the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/30/technology/google-project-maven-pentagon.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;employee protests over Google’s involvement&lt;/a&gt; in the Pentagon project to use artificial intelligence. After Google &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/google-plans-not-to-renew-its-contract-for-project-mave-1826488620&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; it would not renew its contract with the Pentagon, it unveiled a series of ethical principles governing its use of A.I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In those principles, Google publicly committed to use A.I. only in “socially beneficial” ways that would not cause harm and promised to develop its capabilities in accordance with human rights law. Some employees have raised concerns that helping China suppress the free flow of information would violate these new principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In 2010, Google said it had discovered that Chinese hackers had attacked the company’s corporate infrastructure in an attempt to access to the Gmail accounts of human rights activists. The attack, combined with government censorship, propelled Google to pull its search engine from the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The exit from China was a seminal moment for the company — a symbol of its uncompromising idealism captured by Google’s unofficial motto of “Don’t Be Evil.” At the time, Chinese internet users marked the loss of Google’s search engine by laying flowers at the company’s Beijing offices in what became known as an “&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/evan-osnos/china-and-google-illegal-flower-tribute&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;illegal flower tribute&lt;/a&gt;.” A possible re-entry to China, according to current and former employees, is a sign of a more mature and pragmatic company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;34.07341576507&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;15.357032457496&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Google has maintained a significant presence in China even though its flagship services are not accessible in the country. Last year, Google announced plans for &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/13/business/google-ai-china.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;a research center in China&lt;/a&gt; focused on artificial intelligence. And it has introduced translation and file management apps for the Chinese market. Google now has more than 700 employees in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Google’s work on Dragonfly is not a guarantee that its search engine will be welcomed back to China. The government would have to approve its return and it has kept American technology firms like Facebook at arm’s length, opting instead to work closely with homegrown internet behemoths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;42.26409366869&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;33.43972246314&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Some employees are in favor of re-entering China, arguing that exiting the country in protest of censorship has done little to pressure Beijing to change its position while it has &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/06/technology/china-generation-blocked-internet.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;made Google nonessential&lt;/a&gt; among the world’s largest base of internet users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;When Google pulled out of China in 2010, Mr. Brin said &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/03/22/interview-sergey-brin-on-googles-china-gambit/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;it objected to the country’s “totalitarian” policies&lt;/a&gt; when it came to censorship, political speech and internet communications. If anything, China has only tightened its controls in the last eight years — leaving the company in a bind for how to justify its return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“You can never satisfy a censor, particularly the ones in China,” said Charles Mok, member of the Hong Kong Legislative Council who advocates and represents the information technology sector and who is affiliated with the territory’s democratic camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Google is probably facing intense pressure to introduce more of its products in China, Mr. Mok said, but added that the company would lend legitimacy to government censorship if it debuted a censored search product in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Then the Chinese government can say, ‘Google is O.K. with it, too,’” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;26.184782608696&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;css-3glrhn&quot; readability=&quot;7.2461538461538&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page A1 of the New York edition with the headline: Google Workers Protest Secrecy In China Project&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 16:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/16/technology/google-employees-protest-search-censored-china.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google Employees Protest Secret Work on Censored Search Engine for China</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/08/16/business/16DRAGONFLY/16DRAGONFLY-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>About 1,400 of the internet company’s employees have signed a letter demanding transparency, saying censored search results raise “urgent moral and ethical issues.”</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/16/technology/google-employees-protest-search-censored-china.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>NYU Makes Tuition Free for All Medical Students</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/nyu-offers-full-tuition-scholarships-for-all-medical-students-1534433082</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/nyu-offers-full-tuition-scholarships-for-all-medical-students-1534433082</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;


    

        
    &lt;div class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;
    
    
        &lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
    
              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Melissa Korn&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/7426&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://twitter.com/melissakorn&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@melissakorn&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;facebook&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://facebook.com/melissashirakorn&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;melissashirakorn&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;google&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://plus.google.com/u/0/101257706797480545216/about&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Google+&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:Melissa.Korn@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Melissa.Korn@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Melissa Korn&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;time class=&quot;timestamp&quot;&gt;
      Updated Aug. 16, 2018 12:10 p.m. ET
    &lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  



       &lt;p&gt;New York University said Thursday that it will cover tuition for all its medical students regardless of their financial situation, a first among the nation’s major medical schools and an attempt to expand career options for graduates who won’t be saddled with six-figure debt.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;School officials worry that rising tuition and soaring loan balances are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/in-search-of-more-doctors-new-training-efforts-grow-1497021686?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;pushing new doctors into high-paying fields&lt;/a&gt; and contributing to a shortage of researchers and primary care physicians. Medical schools nationwide have been conducting aggressive fundraising campaigns to compete for top prospects, alleviate the debt burden and give graduates more career choices.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;




       &lt;p&gt;NYU raised more than $450 million of the roughly $600 million it estimates it will need to fund the tuition package in perpetuity, including $100 million from 






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/HD&quot;&gt;Home Depot&lt;/a&gt;
            


       founder Kenneth Langone and his wife, Elaine. The school will provide full-tuition scholarships for 93 first-year students—another nine are already covered through M.D./PhD programs—as well as 350 students already partway through the M.D.-only degree program.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;“This is going to be a huge game-changer for us, for our students and for our patients,” said Dr. Rafael Rivera, associate dean for admission and financial aid. The school will refund out-of-pocket tuition payments already made for the current year, and return loans students may have taken out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The move dwarfs efforts by other schools, including Columbia University and the University of California, Los Angeles, to alleviate the financial strain of a medical education. Earlier this year Columbia’s Vagelos College of Physicians and Surgeons announced it would eliminate loans for all students who qualify for financial aid, while UCLA’s David Geffen School of Medicine expects to provide more than 300 full scholarships between 2012 and 2022, based on merit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Cleveland Clinic Lerner College of Medicine of Case Western Reserve University, with just 32 students a year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB121081981994794319?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;has paid full tuition and fees since 2008&lt;/a&gt; in an effort to encourage graduates to pursue academic and research careers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Nationally, 72% of graduates from the class of 2018 had debt from medical school, with a median of $195,000 in loans, according to student surveys by the Association of American Medical Colleges. More than one-third of medical students also have student loans from prior academic programs.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;Sixty-two percent of NYU medical school’s most recent graduating class had student loans, averaging $171,908 for medical school and $184,000 overall. Most medical students will still need to pay for about $29,000 in annual room, board and other living expenses; tuition had been set at $55,018 for the coming year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“There’s really a moral imperative to reduce the amount of debt people have,” Dr. Rivera said, citing concerns that loan burdens are shaping career choices and might even be scaring some prospects away from going to medical school at all.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Schools are also seeking to better reflect the population of U.S. patients in terms of race, ethnicity, gender and socioeconomic backgrounds. Asians make up a disproportionate share of medical-school classes, but other minorities are vastly underrepresented.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The median parental income for new medical-school students is $125,000, according to the AAMC.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Most medical students who want to go into lower paying practices like family medicine and endocrinology can take advantage of federal programs in which their monthly loan payments are tied to discretionary income; their loan balances are then forgiven after 10 or 25 years, depending on where they work. With compounding interest, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/mike-meru-has-1-million-in-student-loans-how-did-that-happen-1527252975?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;they often don’t make much dent on the principal balance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The salary disparity for doctors can be stark. The four lowest-paying specialties, all in pediatrics, had average annual compensation of $221,900 or below, according to a survey of more than 65,000 doctors by Doximity, a medical social network for clinicians. Doctors specializing in internal medicine had average annual compensation of $260,000.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, neurosurgery was the top-paying specialty last year, with average compensation of $662,755. Thoracic surgery and orthopaedic surgery rounded out the top three, at $602,745 and $537,568, respectively.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There’s no guarantee that schools’ new scholarships will push more students into less lucrative specialties or underserved communities, as the tuition payments aren’t tied to any career commitment after graduation. But school officials are hopeful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“If you’re faced with debts that you’re likely to have into your 50s, it’s got to have an influence on what you choose to do,” said 




      Dr. Lee Goldman, 




       dean of Columbia’s Faculties of Health Sciences and Medicine. Published tuition for that school is $61,146 this year; including living expenses, students can expect to shell out between $92,311 and $100,665, the school says.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;Former 






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/MRK&quot;&gt;Merck&lt;/a&gt;
            


       &amp;amp; Co. chairman Dr. P. Roy Vagelos and his wife, Diana, gave Columbia’s medical school $250 million last winter, with $150 million earmarked for the endowment that funds the new no-loan financial aid package. About half the class receives need-based aid.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Generous aid packages are a powerful recruiting tool.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Columbia’s yield, or the share of admitted students who actually enrolled, increased by 1% this year in the wake of the financial aid announcement, and the school anticipates an even higher yield in the future.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;UCLA boasts on its website that students have turned down offers from the University of California, San Francisco, Harvard University and Stanford University to attend its medical school, thanks to merit scholarships covering all costs for up to 20% of students. Those are funded by a $100 million gift made in 2012 by entertainment mogul David Geffen.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“I don’t know of any schools that would not want their students to graduate debt-free,” said Dr. Roy Ziegelstein, vice dean for education at the top-ranked Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine. “All schools are aiming for that end result.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Median debt for Hopkins medical students who borrow is around $110,000, well below the national median.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dr. Ziegelstein commended Columbia and other schools for their financial aid initiatives. “I love it. And I’m trying to do the same thing,” he said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Write to &lt;/strong&gt;Melissa Korn at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melissa.korn@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;melissa.korn@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Corrections &amp;amp; Amplifications &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br/&gt;NYU will provide full-tuition scholarships for 93 first-year students—another nine are already covered through M.D./PhD programs. An earlier version of this article incorrectly gave the numbers as 92 and 10.&lt;/p&gt; 






      &lt;/div&gt;






    &lt;p class=&quot;printheadline&quot;&gt;
      Appeared in the August 17, 2018, print edition as 'NYU Medical School Makes Tuition Free.'
    &lt;/p&gt;




</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 16:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mudil</dc:creator>
<og:title>NYU Makes Tuition Free for All Medical Students</og:title>
<og:description>NYU said it will cover tuition for all its medical students, a first among the nation’s major medical schools and an attempt to expand career options for graduates who won’t be saddled with six-figure debt.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/nyu-offers-full-tuition-scholarships-for-all-medical-students-1534433082</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-22505/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/nyu-offers-full-tuition-scholarships-for-all-medical-students-1534433082</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OpenPGPjs has passed an independent security audit</title>
<link>https://protonmail.com/blog/openpgpjs-protonmail-security-audit/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://protonmail.com/blog/openpgpjs-protonmail-security-audit/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;As part of our commitment to open source, we maintain the OpenPGPjs encryption library. After some recent code enhancements, OpenPGPjs underwent an independent security audit, the results of which are discussed below.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At ProtonMail, our goal is to make encryption as widespread and accessible as possible. We believe a key step toward that is having well-maintained, robust, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/protonmail-open-source/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;secure open source encryption libraries&lt;/a&gt;. This is the goal of our efforts on the OpenPGPjs &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/what-is-end-to-end-encryption/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;encryption&lt;/a&gt; library, which is today used by hundreds of applications (including ProtonMail) serving millions around the world. As the maintainer of OpenPGPjs, we are responsible for making sure the library is up to date and secure, as well as offering basic support to developers who wish to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2018, we released &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/openpgpjs-3-release/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Version 3.0 of OpenPGPjs&lt;/a&gt;. With this major update, OpenPGPjs is even more powerful, secure, and efficient. As part of this update, the OpenPGPjs developer community commissioned an independent security audit from the well-respected security firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://cure53.de&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Cure53&lt;/a&gt;. Independent security audits are an important way to ensure there are no vulnerabilities that could be exploited by attackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Summer 2018 Security Audit Coverage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The version 3.0 release brought many new features and improvements, such as support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elliptic-curve_cryptography&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;elliptic curve cryptography&lt;/a&gt; (ECC), which uses smaller signing and encryption keys compared with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSA_(cryptosystem)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;RSA cryptography&lt;/a&gt; (what ProtonMail uses now), making it a faster and more efficient alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new version also adds compression, which reduces the size of data before encryption to save space (and time) during encryption and transmission. OpenPGPjs now also offers support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Authenticated_encryption&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;AEAD&lt;/a&gt; (Authenticated Encryption with Associated Data). This protocol provides confidentiality, integrity, and authenticity guarantees on encrypted data, so that you when you decrypt data, you can be sure this was the exact same data encrypted by your sender, and you can be sure that it was indeed encrypted by that sender. For those who are interested, you can find the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openpgpjs/openpgpjs/pull/691&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;full technical details of OpenPGPjs Version 3.0 here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cure53 team focused on a couple of these new features while also taking a closer look at some key aspects of OpenPGPjs’ crypto implementations. In particular, the audit focused on the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;AEAD encrypted packets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EAX, GCM, OCB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CMAC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All cryptographic primitive implementations: AES, AES-EAX, AES-GCM, AES-CBC, ED25519, C25519, ECDSA, HMAC, P256, P384, P521, SECP256K1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prime number handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date support in signatures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cryptographic API exposure via different providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;OpenPGPjs Audit Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to receive a highly positive result from the audit. No major issues were discovered. In their summary, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openpgpjs/openpgpjs/issues/719&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Cure53 provided the following feedback&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tested cryptographic implementations were top notch and excellent quality given the platform. The only limitations come from the platform itself (JavaScript/web), which do not allow for side channel resistance or reliable constant time operations. Overall however this is an exceptional library for JavaScript cryptography.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As OpenPGPjs forms the foundation of ProtonMail’s encryption, this result provides extra certainty that ProtonMail’s cryptography is properly protecting users as intended. Working with the open source community is an important part of what we do at ProtonMail, and we will continue to build out the OpenPGPjs library. We are grateful to the ProtonMail community for supporting us in these efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Regards,&lt;br/&gt;The ProtonMail Team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can get a &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/signup&quot;&gt;free secure email account from ProtonMail here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We also provide a &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonvpn.com/&quot;&gt;free VPN service&lt;/a&gt; to protect your privacy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ProtonMail and ProtonVPN are funded by the community. If you would like to support our efforts, you can upgrade to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/support/knowledge-base/paid-plans/&quot;&gt;paid plan&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/donate&quot;&gt;donate&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Your support allows us to continue to develop ProtonMail as free and &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/protonmail-open-source/&quot;&gt;open source software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 14:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>testloop</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>ProtonMail’s open source encryption library, OpenPGPjs, has passed an independent security audit - ProtonMail Blog</og:title>
<og:description>As part of our commitment to open source, we maintain the OpenPGPjs encryption library. After some recent code enhancements, OpenPGPjs underwent an independent security audit, the results of which are discussed below. At ProtonMail, our goal is to make encryption as widespread and accessible as possible. We believe a key step toward that is having …</og:description>
<og:url>https://protonmail.com/blog/openpgpjs-protonmail-security-audit/</og:url>
<og:image>https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/protonmail-openpgpjs-protonmail-security-audit.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://protonmail.com/blog/openpgpjs-protonmail-security-audit/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>