<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>You don&amp;#039;t need ML/AI, you need SQL</title>
<link>https://cyberomin.github.io/startup/2018/07/01/sql-ml-ai.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cyberomin.github.io/startup/2018/07/01/sql-ml-ai.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;read&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I did a Twitter thread about the need to use traditional and existing tools to solve everyday business problems other than jumping on new buzzwords, sexy and often times complicated technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thread did pretty well, eventually making it to the number one spot on Hackernews. The aftermath of its mini popularity was that it sparked some interesting conversation. With a camp agreeing with what I said and another not agreeing entirely with what I said to those who called me stupid and delusional. Well, the internet can be a wild wild west.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My attempt with this article isn’t to convince you to use my approach, rather, I intend to unpack what exactly I was saying in my initial Twitter thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, as the years go by, some interesting technologies and concept spring forth — machine learning, the blockchain, artificial intelligence, virtual reality, augmented reality, etc — while some existing ones take the back seat. It’s not uncommon to hear these days about people building fantastic products today backed by blockchain. I have seen blockchain backed e-commerce services, social networks and properties. The list goes on. I hear these days for you to close that funding round quickly and early enough, you must throw in “Blockchain” even if it has no relevance in the grand scheme of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while ago, it was Machine learning and Artificial Intelligence. Everybody and their mother that had a landing page with a “join the waitlist” field had ML/AI on that page. Heaven forbids you put up that initial page and there was no mention of AI. Seriously, are you really in business? But honestly, this doesn’t have to be the case. One technology I am still bullish about to this day is the SQL (Structured Query Language). This over 40 years old technology is as relevant today as it was when it first appeared in 1974. While it has gone through some refining over the years, it’s still as powerful as ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have spent all of my career in technology and I spent a good part of it working in e-commerce and I saw first hand how this technology allowed us to grow and scale the business. We used this technology to our advantage, as it allowed us to explore some interesting information from the data we gathered. These data included but not limited to consumer behaviours, shopping pattern and habits. It even allowed us to predict what stock keeping unit(SKU) we should be holding and what we shouldn’t. It even allowed us to delight our customers and re-engage with those that fell along the way. Let me tell you how we did it and how you too can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s always fun when I speak to founders and potential founders and they are quick to tell me how they want to use AI/ML to improve customer retention and improve lifetime value(LTV). The truth is, they don’t even need machine learning or any of those fancy stuff. A properly written SQL is what they need. In a former life, I used to write SQL queries to extract valuable information and insights from the data we generated. One time, we needed to know who the customer of the week was, the idea was to 1) recognize them and 2) reward them. This simple and unexpected gesture the company displayed toward its customers always left people super delighted and it turned them into an evangelist. It wasn’t uncommon to see messages on social media like “Wow, Konga just rewarded me with N2,000 voucher for being the customer of the week. I didn’t expect this. Thanks, guys, you are the best.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do this proved more effective than spending that money on advertisement, don’t get me wrong, traditional advertising still has its place, but nothing beats word of mouth from a trusted friend. Surprisingly, getting this information wasn’t that difficult. No fancy technology was needed other than the good old SQL. To get the customer of the week, we basically wrote an SQL that selects from orders table where basket size is the biggest for that week. When we get this information, we will email a nice thank you note to the customer and attach a small coupon/voucher. Guess what? 99% of these people became repeat customers. We never needed ML. We just wrote a simple SQL and got this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One time we needed to reconnect with customers that hadn’t shopped in a while. Since I was responsible for this, I wrote a SQL query that gathered all the customers whose last shopped date was 3 months or more. The query, yet again, was surprisingly simple. I will write a query like select from order table where last shop date is 3 or more months. When we get this information, we will send a nice “we miss you, come back and here’s X Naira voucher” email. The conversation rate for this one was always greater than 50%. And there was always a flurry of messages on social media too. In my opinion, these two strategies were and still is a lot more effective than spending on Google and Facebook ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We applied this same thinking to newsletters. I mean, why send a generic newsletter to everyone when you could attempt to personalize it? Solution? I wrote SQL queries to check basket content and extract individual items. From these items, we could build a newsletter off it and target relevant content. For instance, say a person bought a pair of shoe, sunglasses and a book. For their newsletter, we will show include shoes, sunglasses and books. This was a lot more relevant than sending random stuff. I mean, why send a letter with breast pumps to a man that just bought a pair of sneakers? It doesn’t even make sense. The typical open rate for most marketing emails is anywhere between 7 - 10%. But when we did our work well, we saw close to 25 - 30%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is three times more than the industry standard. Another nice touch for those emails was that we addressed people by their names. No Dear Customer. It was always Dear Celestine, Dear Omin, etc. It brought a human touch to the whole game. It showed we cared. All of these happened courtesy of the good old SQL, not some fancy machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those customers who couldn’t complete their orders for one reason or another, we didn’t let them drop off too. For as long as they added an item to their cart, that suggests that they had intentions of buying. To get them to check out, I wrote a nice SQL script, paired it with a CRON job and this combination fired an email to customers whose carts had a last updated period of 48 hours or more. Guess what? It worked. Because we could track these emails, we could tell people came back to complete their orders based on those emails. Yet again, the SQL for this was super simple. It selected from the cart where the state is not empty and last update period was more than or equal to 48hrs. We set the CRON to run at 2 AM every day, this was period with less activity and traffic. Customers will then wake up to emails reminding them about their abandoned carts. Talk about reengagement. Nothing fancy here, just SQL, Bash and CRON in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since payment on delivery(POD) was big and still is a thing, SQL yet again came in handy. Customers that will cancel orders three consecutive times, we placed them under a high alert bucket. Next time they made an order, we called and made sure they actually needed the order. This way, we saved time and unnecessary stress. Altogether, POD can be disabled for these customers and the only payment method will be a card or a wallet. In e-commerce, logistics is expensive, so it made sense to focus on serious customers. We didn’t need ML or some fancy AI for this problem. Again, well-written SQL was all we needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For orders that weren’t delivered during our SLA window, we used SQL queries to manage customer expectations too. We selected from orders where status is not delivered and order date &amp;gt;= 7 days. As this is the standard delivery period. We paired this with a CRON job that fires email and SMS to customers. While customers didn’t immediately jump and clapped for us. At the very least, it reassured them that we actually cared and were working to solve the problem. Nothing is as annoying as delayed orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular solution also had a dramatic effect on our NPS. Again, good old SQL + Bash saving the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus: Sift Science is doing an amazing job with fraud prevention. But SQL can come in handy too. If a person tries to checkout with 3 different cards at the same time and these cards bounced, something funny is happening. The first and obvious thing to do here is to block their account temporary for a while. You will be saving the potential card owners a lot of headaches. You don’t need to store card details, just store card checkout attempt for a particular order number and you will be fine. These are low hanging fruits that need no ML but a well-written SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am knocking on ML/AI. These technologies have their place, if anything, Amazon has proven their effectiveness. But if you’re running a small online store with between 1,000 - 10,000 customers, then you can still very much live on SQL. Besides, the ML/AI talents aren’t a dime a dozen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You run an e-commerce store and you need help on any of these? Reach out, I am always happy to listen to your problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll love to hear from you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you want to say hello? &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:celestineomin@gmail.com&quot;&gt;Email me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - celestineomin@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I tweet at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cyberomin&quot;&gt;@cyberomin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If you enjoyed this post, please consider sharing it.&lt;/em&gt;



&lt;noscript readability=&quot;1.15625&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com&quot; class=&quot;dsq-brlink&quot;&gt;comments powered by &lt;/a&gt; </description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 02:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cyberomin</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cyberomin.github.io/startup/2018/07/01/sql-ml-ai.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Patreon Is Suspending Adult Content Creators Because of Its Payment Partners</title>
<link>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbqwwj/patreon-suspension-of-adult-content-creators</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbqwwj/patreon-suspension-of-adult-content-creators</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Adult content creators on crowdfunding site Patreon are facing a sudden spate of suspensions, with many reporting “implied nudity” as the reason their pages are shut down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday, Vex Ashley, a founder of the independent erotic film production collective Four Chambers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vextape/status/1012101945211879424&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that their Patreon page was effectively shut down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is bigger than us &amp;amp; Patreon. It’s a world wide crack down on freedom of expression, on women, on marginalised people, on sex and sex work, on non conventional forms of labour that counter the status quo: the domination of corporations and patriarchy. On dissent,” Ashley wrote. “Just to be clear what is at stake, this is my whole income, my livelihood.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Four Chambers Patreon page is now effectively a tip jar, with a simple “Thank you” message in place of an about section or description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have been ramping up the proactive review of content on Patreon due to requirements from our payment partners,” a Patreon spokesperson told me in an email. “Our community guidelines have not changed, and when we discover a page that is not in compliance with our guidelines we place that page in a state of suspension and work directly with the creator to bring them back within our guidelines. We have also doubled the size of our support team to ensure we get back to creators and give them 1-1 guidance as fast as humanly possible.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://patreon.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/204606125-How-do-you-calculate-fees-&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;According to a Patreon blog about creator fees&lt;/a&gt;, these partners include Stripe and PayPal (which has a history of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/4w74jg/how-the-financial-sector-is-making-life-miserable-for-sex-workers-714&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;refusing to serve sex workers&lt;/a&gt;), but the pressure to turn sex workers away comes from major banking networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/9kqye3/patreon-porn-adult-content-guidelines-open-letter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In late 2017,&lt;/a&gt; Patreon expanded its adult content guidelines, to include stricter guidelines for &quot;bestiality, incest, sexual depiction of minors, and suggestive sexual violence.&quot; At the time, it resulted in suspensions and bans of many adult content creators whose work Patreon previously permitted, but no longer fell in line with new guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/kz3x5z/heres-how-patreon-politely-makes-it-impossible-for-adult-content-creators&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Here's How Patreon Politely Makes It Impossible for Adult Content Creators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, many more adult content creators are reporting that they’re experiencing a renewed wave of suspensions on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/katevictoriaa/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kate Victoria&lt;/a&gt;, a photographer and adult content creator, told me that Patreon also suspended her account on Wednesday. She told me in an email that the reason Patreon cited was “public nudity,” but she said “there wasn’t a single nude body part showing that I would consider to be adult-orientated.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one image that she suspects did trigger the suspension was in a tier-reward image, which was nude but censored by text. “I didn’t get any warnings, just an email and notification that my account was suspended,” Victoria said. “I would be more understanding if I’d uploaded a fully nude image in a public post but that wasn’t the case.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also said that it’s frustrating to have this happen so close to payout at the end of the month—she relies on Patreon for at least 60 percent of her monthly income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sex workers, porn producers and anyone working in the erotic labor trade have always faced &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/nz7b4k/how-sex-workers-get-paid'&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;discrimination from payment processors and banks&lt;/a&gt;—many institutions refuse to give accounts to people working in the sex trade. Patreon set itself up as an alternative home for creators of all kinds to make money doing what they love, but in the last year or so, even they have experienced pushback from payment processors on what is and isn’t allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/guidelines#adult-content&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Patreon’s guidelines for adult content&lt;/a&gt; state that “all public content on your page be appropriate for all audiences,” and “content with mature themes must be marked as a patron-only post.” For several of these reports, Patreon warned that “implied nudity” was the reason for the suspension, where it appeared in public areas or publicly-visible patron tiers and banners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t use Patreon to raise funds in order to produce pornographic material such as maintaining a website, funding the production of movies, or providing a private webcam session,” the guidelines state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/43nw53/patreon-porn-crackdown-response&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adult Content Creators: Patreon Is Doing ‘the Exact Opposite of What We Asked For’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicole Vaunt, an adult content creator, told me in an email that Patreon reached out to her a few months ago, and told her to remove any nudity or implied nudity from her Patreon public page and public posts. She did, and hasn’t had problems since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But I'm honestly scared of losing my livelihood at any minute,” Vaunt said. “Once Four Chambers was deleted it felt like the canary in the coal mine for all of us. This recent influx of suspensions and removals is a slippery slope.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 9:05 p.m. EST: A previous version of this article misstated the 2017 changes to the Patreon community guidelines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 21:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cribbles</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Patreon Is Suspending Adult Content Creators Because of Its Payment Partners</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5b354672bfc85a00078042d5/lede/1530219465681-shutterstock_672695869.jpeg?crop=1xw:0.8548632218844985xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbqwwj/patreon-suspension-of-adult-content-creators</og:url>
<og:description>The subscription crowdfunding platform Patreon confirmed that they are increasing efforts to review content, due to payment processor pressure.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbqwwj/patreon-suspension-of-adult-content-creators</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Grow the Puzzle Around You</title>
<link>http://foundersatwork.posthaven.com/grow-the-puzzle-around-you</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://foundersatwork.posthaven.com/grow-the-puzzle-around-you</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery&quot; id=&quot;posthaven_gallery[1309360]&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-car&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;posthaven-file posthaven-file-image posthaven-file-state-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-image&quot; src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2098206/eMJGWNr6e0eG0_vZ3pi595WDpUQ/medium_nutgrimace.jpeg&quot; data-posthaven-state=&quot;processed&quot; data-medium-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2098206/eMJGWNr6e0eG0_vZ3pi595WDpUQ/medium_nutgrimace.jpeg&quot; data-medium-width=&quot;800&quot; data-medium-height=&quot;600&quot; data-large-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2098206/eMJGWNr6e0eG0_vZ3pi595WDpUQ/large_nutgrimace.jpeg&quot; data-large-width=&quot;1200&quot; data-large-height=&quot;900&quot; data-thumb-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2098206/eMJGWNr6e0eG0_vZ3pi595WDpUQ/thumb_nutgrimace.jpeg&quot; data-thumb-width=&quot;200&quot; data-thumb-height=&quot;200&quot; data-xlarge-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2098206/eMJGWNr6e0eG0_vZ3pi595WDpUQ/xlarge_nutgrimace.jpeg&quot; data-xlarge-width=&quot;2048&quot; data-xlarge-height=&quot;1536&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2098206/eMJGWNr6e0eG0_vZ3pi595WDpUQ/nutgrimace.jpeg&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;2048&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;1536&quot; data-posthaven-id=&quot;2098206&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2005, I cofounded Y Combinator, the first &quot;accelerator.&quot; Today there are hundreds of them all over the world, but in 2005 what we were doing was so unusual that most people in Silicon Valley regarded us as irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Y Combinator began the same way as most other startups: with a hypothesis about something we thought people wanted. It turned out they did want it, and we grew and grew. Now we've funded 1867 startups with a total value of over $100 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So having myself been through the type of startup journey that many of you are hoping to, I wanted to tell you my own story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you only know about me through the media, you might get the impression that my contribution to Y Combinator is that I’m Paul Graham’s wife. And while I love being his wife, there's a bit more to the story than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born in Minneapolis in 1971. Later that year, my mother left home, leaving my father alone with a small baby. So he took me back to Boston, where my grandmother lived.  I lived with her during the week while my dad worked, and with my dad on weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery&quot; id=&quot;posthaven_gallery[1310080]&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-car&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;posthaven-file posthaven-file-image posthaven-file-state-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-image&quot; src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099193/lMuRkleRtNK-9FDedEp6otjAZlo/medium_PICT0138.JPG&quot; data-posthaven-state=&quot;processed&quot; data-medium-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099193/lMuRkleRtNK-9FDedEp6otjAZlo/medium_PICT0138.JPG&quot; data-medium-width=&quot;800&quot; data-medium-height=&quot;533&quot; data-large-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099193/lMuRkleRtNK-9FDedEp6otjAZlo/large_PICT0138.JPG&quot; data-large-width=&quot;1200&quot; data-large-height=&quot;800&quot; data-thumb-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099193/lMuRkleRtNK-9FDedEp6otjAZlo/thumb_PICT0138.JPG&quot; data-thumb-width=&quot;200&quot; data-thumb-height=&quot;200&quot; data-xlarge-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099193/lMuRkleRtNK-9FDedEp6otjAZlo/xlarge_PICT0138.JPG&quot; data-xlarge-width=&quot;2400&quot; data-xlarge-height=&quot;1600&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099193/lMuRkleRtNK-9FDedEp6otjAZlo/PICT0138.JPG&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;4416&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;2944&quot; data-posthaven-id=&quot;2099193&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandmother was the most important female role model in my life. She was a very independent person. The term anyone who knew her would use to describe her was &quot;free-spirited.&quot; For example, in the wintertime, after putting me to bed, she'd go out and work till late at night on giant ice sculptures she built in the front yard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery&quot; id=&quot;posthaven_gallery[1310081]&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-car&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;posthaven-file posthaven-file-image posthaven-file-state-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-image&quot; src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099194/KgHuJNXebGH2McNz4oH9r2gvJlk/medium_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.08.27_PM.png&quot; data-posthaven-state=&quot;processed&quot; data-medium-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099194/KgHuJNXebGH2McNz4oH9r2gvJlk/medium_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.08.27_PM.png&quot; data-medium-width=&quot;800&quot; data-medium-height=&quot;635&quot; data-large-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099194/KgHuJNXebGH2McNz4oH9r2gvJlk/large_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.08.27_PM.png&quot; data-large-width=&quot;1028&quot; data-large-height=&quot;816&quot; data-thumb-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099194/KgHuJNXebGH2McNz4oH9r2gvJlk/thumb_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.08.27_PM.png&quot; data-thumb-width=&quot;200&quot; data-thumb-height=&quot;200&quot; data-xlarge-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099194/KgHuJNXebGH2McNz4oH9r2gvJlk/xlarge_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.08.27_PM.png&quot; data-xlarge-width=&quot;1028&quot; data-xlarge-height=&quot;816&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099194/KgHuJNXebGH2McNz4oH9r2gvJlk/Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.08.27_PM.png&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;1028&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;816&quot; data-posthaven-id=&quot;2099194&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She did what she wanted, and she didn't care if people thought she was unconventional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite growing up without a mother, my childhood was pretty happy. My dad made a lot of sacrifices so I could get a great education, and he constantly encouraged me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played soccer when I was younger, and when I was in 9th grade we played an away game against a school called Phillips Academy, in Andover, MA.  The place seemed so unbelievably fabulous that I decided on the spot that I was going to go to school there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery&quot; id=&quot;posthaven_gallery[1310082]&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-car&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;posthaven-file posthaven-file-image posthaven-file-state-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-image&quot; src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099195/SozOWavphkz_JPssb6kzpaJd61M/medium_JL_goalie.jpg&quot; data-posthaven-state=&quot;processed&quot; data-medium-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099195/SozOWavphkz_JPssb6kzpaJd61M/medium_JL_goalie.jpg&quot; data-medium-width=&quot;800&quot; data-medium-height=&quot;1176&quot; data-large-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099195/SozOWavphkz_JPssb6kzpaJd61M/large_JL_goalie.jpg&quot; data-large-width=&quot;1200&quot; data-large-height=&quot;1765&quot; data-thumb-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099195/SozOWavphkz_JPssb6kzpaJd61M/thumb_JL_goalie.jpg&quot; data-thumb-width=&quot;200&quot; data-thumb-height=&quot;200&quot; data-xlarge-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099195/SozOWavphkz_JPssb6kzpaJd61M/xlarge_JL_goalie.jpg&quot; data-xlarge-width=&quot;1360&quot; data-xlarge-height=&quot;2000&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099195/SozOWavphkz_JPssb6kzpaJd61M/JL_goalie.jpg&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;1360&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;2000&quot; data-posthaven-id=&quot;2099195&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little did I know that this decision would have bittersweet consequences. In my old school I'd been a big fish in a small pond. I was a straight A student and good at sports.  But when I got to Andover in the fall of 1986, it seemed like everyone was a straight A student and good at sports. I got really discouraged and basically gave up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I defaulted to being a mediocre student, and did nothing impressive or noteworthy for the next decade. They were like my own personal Dark Ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a bit embarrassing to reflect on, but I think it’s important to mention, because when journalists and biographers write about successful founders, they often focus on early predictors of success in their formative years. In my case there certainly weren't a lot of the conventional kind. No one would have voted me &quot;most likely to succeed.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But while I had no &quot;achievements,&quot; I did have three defining characteristics when I was younger that were critical in making Y Combinator work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first was the quality that caused my YC cofounders to nickname me &quot;The Social Radar.&quot; I was one of those kids that you just couldn’t get anything past. If something seemed off or out of character, I noticed and made inquiries. I was always trying to figure things out based on subtle social cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second was that I never liked being at the mercy of anyone else. I hated anyone telling me what to do or not do: parents, teachers, bosses, people I was forced to collaborate with but disagreed with—anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the third distinctive thing about me is that I've always pretty much been a &quot;straight shooter.&quot; My grandmother and my father were both like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I’ll come back to these in a minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after I graduated from college, my beloved grandmother died of cancer. It was a really sad and lonely time in my life. And now I was supposed to find a job, with a degree in English and absolutely no clue what I wanted to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wound up getting a job at Fidelity Investments in their customer service group, answering calls from 3:30 til midnight each day. Basically talking to retail investors about why their Magellan account went down that day. Ugh. I didn’t love the job but I did love having a job. Working hard and getting paid for it and not having homework hanging over my head. It was great. After Fidelity I worked in investor relations in NYC, then at &lt;em&gt;Food &amp;amp; Wine&lt;/em&gt; magazine and at an automotive consulting firm. I even briefly worked for a wedding planner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, I was working in the marketing department at an investment bank in Boston when I first met Paul Graham, at a party at his house one night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery&quot; id=&quot;posthaven_gallery[1310083]&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-car&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;posthaven-file posthaven-file-image posthaven-file-state-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-image&quot; src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099196/3f-pXrbBKyd7qaLNqHzs_NOfFQQ/medium_Jess.jpg&quot; data-posthaven-state=&quot;processed&quot; data-medium-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099196/3f-pXrbBKyd7qaLNqHzs_NOfFQQ/medium_Jess.jpg&quot; data-medium-width=&quot;800&quot; data-medium-height=&quot;533&quot; data-large-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099196/3f-pXrbBKyd7qaLNqHzs_NOfFQQ/large_Jess.jpg&quot; data-large-width=&quot;1036&quot; data-large-height=&quot;690&quot; data-thumb-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099196/3f-pXrbBKyd7qaLNqHzs_NOfFQQ/thumb_Jess.jpg&quot; data-thumb-width=&quot;200&quot; data-thumb-height=&quot;200&quot; data-xlarge-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099196/3f-pXrbBKyd7qaLNqHzs_NOfFQQ/xlarge_Jess.jpg&quot; data-xlarge-width=&quot;1036&quot; data-xlarge-height=&quot;690&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099196/3f-pXrbBKyd7qaLNqHzs_NOfFQQ/Jess.jpg&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;1036&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;690&quot; data-posthaven-id=&quot;2099196&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started dating and I felt like I’d finally met Mr. Right. Despite having quite different backgrounds, we were remarkably similar.  If I thought I never wanted to be at the mercy of someone else, Paul was that dialed up to 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’d moved back to Cambridge after selling his startup, Viaweb, to Yahoo and was at the time writing essays, working on programming languages, publishing a book, and curing his debilitating fear of flying by learning to hang glide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul is the best problem solver I've ever met. He’s also a genius at expanding ideas and making radical improvements to things. One of his defining characteristics is telling people &quot;You know what you should do...&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul and his circle of friends exposed me to this new world of startups. It felt much more exciting than the later stage of publicly-traded tech companies that I was involved with at the investment bank. I read the book &lt;em&gt;Startup&lt;/em&gt; by Jerry Kaplan, about his pen computing company called GO, and I was immediately hooked. It was like some light shining down from the heavens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery&quot; id=&quot;posthaven_gallery[1310084]&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-car&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;posthaven-file posthaven-file-image posthaven-file-state-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-image&quot; src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099197/0th8uUUTv9_pJzKIkh0vWAui0ss/medium_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.14.12_PM.png&quot; data-posthaven-state=&quot;processed&quot; data-medium-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099197/0th8uUUTv9_pJzKIkh0vWAui0ss/medium_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.14.12_PM.png&quot; data-medium-width=&quot;800&quot; data-medium-height=&quot;548&quot; data-large-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099197/0th8uUUTv9_pJzKIkh0vWAui0ss/large_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.14.12_PM.png&quot; data-large-width=&quot;1200&quot; data-large-height=&quot;822&quot; data-thumb-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099197/0th8uUUTv9_pJzKIkh0vWAui0ss/thumb_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.14.12_PM.png&quot; data-thumb-width=&quot;200&quot; data-thumb-height=&quot;200&quot; data-xlarge-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099197/0th8uUUTv9_pJzKIkh0vWAui0ss/xlarge_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.14.12_PM.png&quot; data-xlarge-width=&quot;1322&quot; data-xlarge-height=&quot;906&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099197/0th8uUUTv9_pJzKIkh0vWAui0ss/Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.14.12_PM.png&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;1322&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;906&quot; data-posthaven-id=&quot;2099197&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to hear more stories about the early days of startups, so I started working on a book of interviews with startup founders. The book was called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Founders-Work-Stories-Startups-Early/dp/1430210788&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Founders at Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and was published in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time I was becoming more interested in startups, I was becoming less interested in my job. The Bubble had burst a few years back and the investment bank was making drastic cutbacks. Working there had become boring and unpleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I applied for a job doing marketing at a venture capital firm, where I felt I might be one step closer to the more exciting world of startups. While I was interviewing with the VC firm, Paul would “you-know-what-you-should-do” me each night at dinner, telling me how I  should change the VC business once I got into it.  We’d talk for hours about how broken early-stage startup funding was, and most importantly, how more people would start startups if it could be made easier for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the VC firm took longer and longer to decide to hire me, the ideas grew more and more compelling until one night Paul said, &quot;Let's just start our own.&quot; The next day we convinced Paul's cofounders from Viaweb, Robert and Trevor, to join us part-time. The initial plan was that they would pick and advise the startups and I’d do everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of giving large amounts of money to small numbers of established startups, like traditional VCs did, we'd give small amounts of money to large numbers of earlier stage startups, and then give them a lot of help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our initial target audience was programmers, who we felt could handle the technical aspects of a startup but were clueless about everything else, just like Paul, Robert and Trevor had been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had more faith in young founders than most investors did back then.  This was back in the days when Google’s VCs had insisted the founders hire an outside CEO as a condition of their series A round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of us had any experience at angel investing, and that's where the idea of funding startups in batches came from. We decided to fund a bunch of startups at once, during the summer, so that we could learn how to be investors.  In March 2005 we launched Y Combinator’s website, inviting people to apply for what we called &quot;The Summer Founders Program.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We funded 8 startups that summer and recognized almost immediately the power of investing in batches. It was so much better for the founders. They had colleagues to help them during what had previously been a very lonely process. But it was also a much more efficient way for us to help the startups, because we could do things for them all at once. Every Tuesday Paul cooked dinner for all the founders, and at each dinner we brought in a speaker to teach them about startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery&quot; id=&quot;posthaven_gallery[1310085]&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-car&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;posthaven-file posthaven-file-image posthaven-file-state-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-image&quot; src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099198/DUrX_NAb6X8LJx4sJ7078isPVJw/medium_Table_2.jpg&quot; data-posthaven-state=&quot;processed&quot; data-medium-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099198/DUrX_NAb6X8LJx4sJ7078isPVJw/medium_Table_2.jpg&quot; data-medium-width=&quot;800&quot; data-medium-height=&quot;883&quot; data-large-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099198/DUrX_NAb6X8LJx4sJ7078isPVJw/large_Table_2.jpg&quot; data-large-width=&quot;1200&quot; data-large-height=&quot;1324&quot; data-thumb-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099198/DUrX_NAb6X8LJx4sJ7078isPVJw/thumb_Table_2.jpg&quot; data-thumb-width=&quot;200&quot; data-thumb-height=&quot;200&quot; data-xlarge-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099198/DUrX_NAb6X8LJx4sJ7078isPVJw/xlarge_Table_2.jpg&quot; data-xlarge-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-xlarge-height=&quot;2207&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099198/DUrX_NAb6X8LJx4sJ7078isPVJw/Table_2.jpg&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;2207&quot; data-posthaven-id=&quot;2099198&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul talked to all the startups about what they were building, and I helped them all get incorporated as C corporations.  This was a big deal in those days, because back then to become a C corp you had to pay a lawyer $15,000 to do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first summer, we gave the startups $6k per founder, which was based on the stipend that MIT gave grad students during the summer. At the end of the summer, we hosted the first Demo Day, for an audience of about 15 investors.  Reddit was in that first batch, and the founders of Twitch, though they were working on another idea, and Sam Altman’s geolocation startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though we'd only tried funding a batch of startups as a way to learn how to be investors, we realized within a couple weeks that we were onto something promising. So we decided to do all our investing in batches. And we also decided that we'd fund the next batch in Silicon Valley.  We knew that a lot of people would copy us, and we didn't want someone else to be &quot;the Y Combinator of Silicon Valley.&quot; We wanted to be that ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that we’ve grown significantly and have expanded in many ways, YC’s core program is remarkably similar to what it was 13 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question I always used to get from people over the years was, &quot;So, what's your role at YC?&quot; It used to really bug me because no one ever asked Paul, Robert, or Trevor that question.  But now I think it’s kind of an interesting question to think about.  What was my role as the only non-technical founder of Y Combinator?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery&quot; id=&quot;posthaven_gallery[1310086]&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-car&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;posthaven-file posthaven-file-image posthaven-file-state-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-image&quot; src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099199/IOwDe8BN3uzJyJJ97249gCt-oes/medium_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.17.12_PM.png&quot; data-posthaven-state=&quot;processed&quot; data-medium-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099199/IOwDe8BN3uzJyJJ97249gCt-oes/medium_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.17.12_PM.png&quot; data-medium-width=&quot;800&quot; data-medium-height=&quot;834&quot; data-large-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099199/IOwDe8BN3uzJyJJ97249gCt-oes/large_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.17.12_PM.png&quot; data-large-width=&quot;854&quot; data-large-height=&quot;890&quot; data-thumb-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099199/IOwDe8BN3uzJyJJ97249gCt-oes/thumb_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.17.12_PM.png&quot; data-thumb-width=&quot;200&quot; data-thumb-height=&quot;200&quot; data-xlarge-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099199/IOwDe8BN3uzJyJJ97249gCt-oes/xlarge_Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.17.12_PM.png&quot; data-xlarge-width=&quot;854&quot; data-xlarge-height=&quot;890&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099199/IOwDe8BN3uzJyJJ97249gCt-oes/Screen_Shot_2018-06-29_at_5.17.12_PM.png&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;854&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;890&quot; data-posthaven-id=&quot;2099199&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning there were tons of errands, like with any startup, that just had to get done and there was no one else to do them. Paul and I divided up responsibilities perfectly, which I think is critical when you start a startup with your partner or spouse. He made our website and the application form, and I got other stuff set up for that first summer: I worked with the lawyers to set up Y Combinator the entity and to create all kinds of template legal paperwork for our standard investments and everything founders would need to set up their company and assign stock properly (which is a lot if you’ve ever done it!).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had to learn quickly about how to advise them on filling everything out, so they wouldn’t have to pay any legal fees. I had to set up Paul’s small office building in Cambridge to be our weekly dinner gathering space for 25 people. I set up our bank account and contacted people to speak each week at our dinners. I bought the groceries that Paul cooked for the dinners. I even delivered air conditioners that I’d bought at Home Depot to the founders. I was the only one of us organized enough to make all that stuff happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to investing, I had something that my cofounders didn’t have: I was the Social Radar. I couldn’t judge our applicants’ technical ability, or even most of the ideas. My cofounders were experts at those things.  I looked at qualities of the applicants my cofounders couldn't see.  Did they seem earnest? Were they determined? Were they flexible-minded?  And most importantly, what was the relationship between the cofounders like? While my partners discussed the idea with the applicants, I usually sat observing silently. Afterward, they would turn to me and ask, &quot;Should we fund them?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the beginning I was careful about only funding earnest people. Back then, I never envisioned the people we funded growing into a community of thousands of YC alumni, but I always tried to create an asshole-free culture. If I could tell someone was a conceited asshole, we didn’t fund them. I’m sure we’ve since funded some conceited assholes, but early on I was pretty rigid about this. And I think it’s the basis of the culture of our alumni community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far this stuff might sound a bit different than you’d expect in a successful investor. But when you get to an extreme in something, things get qualitatively different. Y Combinator was a new extreme in the venture funding business, so what made someone a good investor was different. VCs relied on growth figures and estimates of market sizes, but those didn't exist at the stage we were investing. What YC needed was deeply technical people to understand the potential of an idea, and someone like me to understand the founders' characters and the relationship between them.  And to do that well you needed abilities no one had previously considered important in an investor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was doubly hard because some of the applicants were so young. We had to judge the founders not by what they were, but what they could turn into. Imagine Mark Zuckerberg back in his dorm room in 2004, with a website that let college students see what other students at their school were doing. Not super impressive-seeming to traditional investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another secret weapon of mine that was strangely well-suited to Y Combinator was that I was a very experienced event planner.  Events are a critical part of what YC does. When you fund startups in batches, everything’s an event. Interviews are an event, each dinner is an event, Demo Day is an event.  As the alumni network grew we started doing events for alumni too, and from the very first year we did big events like Startup School.  I’d been doing events for years in my marketing jobs, so I could run all these practically with one hand behind my back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the thing that was most different about YC as an investment firm was that it felt like a family.  And I was its mom; I was soft and sensitive at a time when investors tended to be hardened and aggressive (and I’ll throw in ruthless too for a few of them). I cared about how the founders were feeling, if they were overwhelmed, if they were eating properly. I’d counsel them on relationships that were under strain due to the pressure of the startup. I’d listen at length and help them with their cofounder disputes and breakups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery&quot; id=&quot;posthaven_gallery[1310087]&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-car&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;posthaven-file posthaven-file-image posthaven-file-state-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;posthaven-gallery-image&quot; src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099200/sx4FPV-RDcK8qlgj_F92PimG7n8/medium_1400-2007-02-27.jpeg&quot; data-posthaven-state=&quot;processed&quot; data-medium-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099200/sx4FPV-RDcK8qlgj_F92PimG7n8/medium_1400-2007-02-27.jpeg&quot; data-medium-width=&quot;800&quot; data-medium-height=&quot;600&quot; data-large-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099200/sx4FPV-RDcK8qlgj_F92PimG7n8/large_1400-2007-02-27.jpeg&quot; data-large-width=&quot;1200&quot; data-large-height=&quot;900&quot; data-thumb-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099200/sx4FPV-RDcK8qlgj_F92PimG7n8/thumb_1400-2007-02-27.jpeg&quot; data-thumb-width=&quot;200&quot; data-thumb-height=&quot;200&quot; data-xlarge-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099200/sx4FPV-RDcK8qlgj_F92PimG7n8/xlarge_1400-2007-02-27.jpeg&quot; data-xlarge-width=&quot;1600&quot; data-xlarge-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099200/sx4FPV-RDcK8qlgj_F92PimG7n8/1400-2007-02-27.jpeg&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;1600&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-posthaven-id=&quot;2099200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a startup is emotionally draining for founders, especially in the beginning.  Sometimes they just needed someone to listen. Luckily, my entire college career had trained me to be a good listener to people’s social problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I tried to always be a straight shooter with my advice. In fact, we all were. Paul is the straightest shooter I know, which is why his advice is so valuable. He doesn’t bury it in euphemisms.  Or worse, withhold the truth in order to preserve people's feelings. And as tough as they might have found his advice at the time, founders always wind up thanking him for his candor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other thing Paul and I had in common was that we weren't driven by money. We were interested in startups and we wanted to help people start more of them. This was the basis for everything we did at YC. It was what allowed us to do something as weird as YC in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because YC didn't have any LPs early on, we weren’t even constrained by a vague fiduciary responsibility to anyone. This allowed us to take more risks with which startups we chose to fund and also allowed us to be benevolent to failing startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That often brought us into conflict with other investors who had different priorities.  Early on, we funded a husband and wife team who had a baby. They worked hard on the startup but it was clearly failing. One of their investors tried to get them acquihired by a big company in the Valley, who ultimately passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul talked to the founders and learned they just wanted the security of jobs, so they could take a break from the constant stress of a startup. So he talked to the big company and got one of them hired there.  The founders were delighted. The investor, on the other hand, was livid. He ripped into Paul harder than almost anyone I’ve ever witnessed (well, before Twitter) saying that Paul had blown any chance of an acquihire. I still don't get why investors squeeze founders even over small outcomes like this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also never cared much about fame. Or my personal &quot;brand&quot;. I just wanted Y Combinator to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing we've learned from Y Combinator is that the most successful startups tend to grow organically out of the founders' lives. This was true in my case too. I was almost uncannily well suited for the kind of work it took to make YC successful. But the things that made me well-suited for it were so far from the qualities most people associate with startup founders. I'll list them so you can see for yourself. I was the social radar, a good event planner, maternal, empathetic, a straight shooter, and not driven by money or fame.  Think how far that is from the profile of the typical startup founder you read about in the press. Maternal? Since when was that an important quality in a startup founder? Let alone the founder of an investment firm. And yet it was critical to making YC what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why I wanted to tell you my story. It's not true that every person can start every startup. But a lot more people have what it takes to start some startup than realize it. A lot of people, perhaps all people, have some distinctive combination of abilities and interests. And a lot of those combinations match some startup idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you want to start a startup, I recommend you try asking yourself what's distinctive about you. What unique combination of abilities and interests do you have?  And don't edit your answers, because as my example shows, the most unlikely ingredients could be the key to the recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, it may even be that the strangest combinations of qualities are the most valuable.  I had a weird combination of qualities, but they matched YC because it was such a weird company. And the most successful startups do tend to be weird. They're usually such outliers that the idea sounds preposterous at first. To everyone except the founders, because the company has grown out of their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what can you learn from my story? Here are 9 things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;strong&gt;There is no one mold for a successful founder&lt;/strong&gt;.  Just because you might only see a certain type in the news, that doesn’t mean you need to turn yourself into that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;strong&gt;Do what you’re genuinely interested in and try to play to your natural strengths&lt;/strong&gt;. A startup is so much work that you'll give up if you're not genuinely interested in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;strong&gt;Don’t pay attention to the mainstream’s opinion of what you're doing—whether it’s your skills, your idea or whatever&lt;/strong&gt;.  Unless they’re your users, their opinion does not matter. (Pay a lot of attention to your users' opinions though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;strong&gt;Find a cofounder with complementary skills, but the same &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moral compass as you&lt;/strong&gt;. Paul and I had the perfect combination of skills to start something like YC. We agreed on all the big questions, and we each deferred to the other's expertise on the small ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;strong&gt;Focus on making something people want&lt;/strong&gt;. Everything follows from that. In 2005, people needed a way to get a small amount of funding easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6) &lt;strong&gt;Don’t let rejection distract you or hold you back&lt;/strong&gt;. You’ll get rejected in so many different ways, but you must keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7) &lt;strong&gt;Start small so you can be nimble and open to change&lt;/strong&gt;. We never could have pulled off moving our operations to Silicon Valley in a matter of months if we'd hired a bunch of people in Cambridge.  To this day, YC has a tradition of trying things on a small scale before expanding them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8) &lt;strong&gt;It’s ok not to have gone to an elite college&lt;/strong&gt;. I grew up thinking that that was the be-all and end-all. You’ve been trained to believe that you’ll be judged by your credentials. But in a startup it's the users who judge you, and they care about your product, not your credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9) &lt;strong&gt;Be intrepid&lt;/strong&gt;. There's room for lots of different kinds of people to be startup founders, but you do need a certain amount of boldness—to work on ideas that most people would consider stupid, and to keep going when you're ridiculed or ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are a jigsaw puzzle piece of a certain shape. You could change your shape to fit an existing hole in the world. That was the traditional plan. But there's another way that can often be better for you and for the world: to grow a new puzzle around you.  That's what I did, and I was a pretty weird-shaped piece. So if I can do it, there’s more hope for you than you probably realize.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 19:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>katm</dc:creator>
<og:title>Grow the Puzzle Around You</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://foundersatwork.posthaven.com/grow-the-puzzle-around-you</og:url>
<og:description>In 2005, I cofounded Y Combinator, the first &quot;accelerator.&quot; Today there are hundreds of them all over the world, but in 2005 what we were doing was so unusual that most people in Silicon Valley...</og:description>
<og:image>https://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/image_part/asset/2099198/DUrX_NAb6X8LJx4sJ7078isPVJw/large_Table_2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://foundersatwork.posthaven.com/grow-the-puzzle-around-you</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why you should not use Google Cloud</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@serverpunch/why-you-should-not-use-google-cloud-75ea2aec00de</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@serverpunch/why-you-should-not-use-google-cloud-75ea2aec00de</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote name=&quot;f0b4&quot; id=&quot;f0b4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--h3&quot; readability=&quot;1.492385786802&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;Follow discussions here. &lt;br/&gt;HACKERNEWS: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17431609&quot; data-href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17431609&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--blockquote-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17431609&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;REDDIT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/8v4wrh/why_you_should_not_use_google_cloud_this_is_about/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/8v4wrh/why_you_should_not_use_google_cloud_this_is_about/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--blockquote-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/8v4wrh/why_you_should_not_use_google_cloud_this_is_about/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;df31&quot; id=&quot;df31&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: This post is not about the quality of Google Cloud products. They are excellent, on par with AWS. This is about the “no-warnings-given, abrupt way” they pull the plug on your entire systems if they (or the machines) believe something is wrong. This is the second time this has happened to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;888a&quot; id=&quot;888a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;Background.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;64c7&quot; id=&quot;64c7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;We have a project running in production on Google Cloud (GCP) that is used to monitor hundreds of wind turbines and scores of solar plants scattered across 8 countries. We have control centers with wall-to-wall screens with dashboards full of metrics that are monitored 24/7. Asset Managers use this system to monitor the health of individual wind turbines and solar strings in real time and take immediate corrective maintenance. Development and Forecasting teams use the system to run algorithms on data in BigQuery. All these actions translate directly to revenue. We deal in a ‘wind/solar energy’ — a perishable commodity. If we over produce, we cannot store and sell later. If we under produce, there are penalties to be paid. For this reason assets need to be monitored 24/7 to keep up/down with the needs of the power grid and the power purchase agreements made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;d1af&quot; id=&quot;d1af&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;What happened.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e92c&quot; id=&quot;e92c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;Early today morning (28 June 2018) i receive an alert from Uptime Robot telling me my entire site is down. I receive a barrage of emails from Google saying there is some ‘potential suspicious activity’ and all my systems have been turned off. EVERYTHING IS OFF. THE MACHINE HAS PULLED THE PLUG WITH NO WARNING. The site is down, app engine, databases are unreachable, multiple Firebases say i’ve been downgraded and therefore exceeded limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*aBCPcQO-e2IfSUPA3ZQiWA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1682&quot; data-height=&quot;862&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*aBCPcQO-e2IfSUPA3ZQiWA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*aBCPcQO-e2IfSUPA3ZQiWA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*dGDuYYi8BAeWKdPwAkR44A.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2123&quot; data-height=&quot;553&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*dGDuYYi8BAeWKdPwAkR44A.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*dGDuYYi8BAeWKdPwAkR44A.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*aQ-RYB9yiw0botwJl64-aQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2548&quot; data-height=&quot;984&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*aQ-RYB9yiw0botwJl64-aQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*aQ-RYB9yiw0botwJl64-aQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;cb8d&quot; id=&quot;cb8d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;It’s a lonely cloud.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c89d&quot; id=&quot;c89d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;Customer service chat is off. There’s no phone to call. I have an email asking me to fill in a form and upload a picture of the credit card and a government issued photo id of the card holder. Great, let’s wake up the CFO who happens to be the card holder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*dWS7JQ4BWaJmfWFZEARcEg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2540&quot; data-height=&quot;1280&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*dWS7JQ4BWaJmfWFZEARcEg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*dWS7JQ4BWaJmfWFZEARcEg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;6bef&quot; id=&quot;6bef&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;We will delete project within 3 business days.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;70b0&quot; id=&quot;70b0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--h4&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We will delete your project unless the billing owner corrects the violation by filling out the Account Verification Form within three business days. This form verifies your identity and ownership of the payment instrument. Failure to provide the requested documents may result in permanent account closure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e9f1&quot; id=&quot;e9f1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What if the card holder is on leave and is unreachable for three days? We would have lost everything — years of work — millions of dollars in lost revenue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f099&quot; id=&quot;f099&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I fill in the form with the details and thankfully within 20 minutes all the services started coming alive. The first time this happened, we were down for a few hours. In all we lost everything for about an hour. An automated email arrives apologizing for ‘&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;inconvenience&lt;/em&gt;’ caused. Unfortunately The Machine has no understanding of the ‘&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;quantum of inconvenience&lt;/em&gt;’ caused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*Tg5ucbPfZk8GGhfD3P1b7Q.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1636&quot; data-height=&quot;626&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*Tg5ucbPfZk8GGhfD3P1b7Q.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*Tg5ucbPfZk8GGhfD3P1b7Q.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;a09c&quot; id=&quot;a09c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;You just can’t turn things off and then ask for an explanation.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9051&quot; id=&quot;9051&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;I understand Google’s need to monitor and prevent suspicious activity. But how you handle things after some suspicious activity is detected matters &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt;. You need a human element here — one that cannot be replaced by any amount of code/AI. You just can’t turn things off and then ask for an explanation. Do it the other way round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;578a&quot; id=&quot;578a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is the first project we built entirely on the Google Cloud. All our previous works were built on AWS. In our experience AWS handles billing issues in a much more humane way. They warn you about suspicious activity and give you time to explain and sort things out. They don’t kick you down the stairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c4d9&quot; id=&quot;c4d9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;I hope GCP team is listening and changes things for better. Until then i’m never building any project on GCP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 17:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>samdung</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why you should not use Google Cloud. – Punch a Server – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@serverpunch/why-you-should-not-use-google-cloud-75ea2aec00de</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*aBCPcQO-e2IfSUPA3ZQiWA.png</og:image>
<og:description>Follow discussions here. HACKERNEWS: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17431609 REDDIT…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@serverpunch/why-you-should-not-use-google-cloud-75ea2aec00de</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Old CS lecturer looking for advice from current and recent students</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17431577</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17431577</guid>
<description>&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;I am 61, with an academic background in computer science, and many years in industry, mostly startups. I taught many years ago, and have resumed teaching, a database course: data modeling, relational algebra, SQL, application programming and architecture (e.g. 2-tier vs. 3-tier, web &amp;amp; mobile), database internals.
&lt;p&gt;Student evaluations were pretty good for the most part, but quite a few students found the presentation a bit dry: I prepared every lecture as HTML ahead of time, made it available online, and presented it in class. A couple of times, I would do interactive things, e.g. tuning queries using EXPLAIN and playing with indexes. That proved pretty popular, but of course, it's difficult to capture this material, (I recorded a log of the session, but extemperaneous discussion was not captured).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for advice on how to balance prepared material and more spontaneous things. Also, any other advice on how to make material of this sort (theory + practice) easier to absorb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>geophile</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17431577</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust pointers for C programmers</title>
<link>http://blahg.josefsipek.net/?p=580</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blahg.josefsipek.net/?p=580</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been eyeing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; for about a year now. Here and there, I tried to use it to make a silly little program, or to implement some simple function in it to see for myself how ergonomic it really was, and what sort of machine code &lt;tt&gt;rustc&lt;/tt&gt; spit out. But last weekend I found a need for a tool to clean up some preprocessor mess, and so instead of hacking together some combination of shell and Python, I decided to write it in Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my earlier attempts, I knew that there are a lot of different “pointers” but I found all the descriptions of them lacking or confusing. Specifically, Rust calls itself a systems programming language, yet I found no clear description of how the different pointers map to C—&lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; systems programming language. Eventually, I stumbled across &lt;a href=&quot;http://cosmic.mearie.org/2014/01/periodic-table-of-rust-types/&quot;&gt;The Periodic Table of Rust Types&lt;/a&gt;, which made things a bit clearer, but I still didn’t feel like I truly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my weekend expedition to Rust land, I think I’ve grokked things enough to write this explanation of how Rust does things. As always, feedback is welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll describe what happens in terms of C. To keep things simple, I will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;assume that you are well-versed in C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assume that you can read Rust (any intro will teach you enough)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; bother with &lt;tt&gt;const&lt;/tt&gt; for the C snippets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; talk about mutability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the following text, I assume that we have some &lt;tt&gt;struct T&lt;/tt&gt;. The actual contents don’t matter. In other words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct T {
        /* some members */
};
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, let’s dive in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;tt&gt;*const T&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;*mut T&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are raw pointers. In general, you shouldn’t use them since only &lt;em&gt;unsafe&lt;/em&gt; code can dereference them, and the whole point of Rust is to write as much &lt;em&gt;safe&lt;/em&gt; code as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raw pointers are just like what you have in C. If you make a pointer, you end up using &lt;tt&gt;sizeof(struct T *)&lt;/tt&gt; bytes for the pointer. In other words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct T *ptr;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&amp;amp;T&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;&amp;amp;mut T&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are borrowed references. They use the same amount of space as raw pointers and behave same exact way in the generated machine code. Consider this trivial example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
#[no_mangle]
pub fn raw(p: *mut usize) {
    unsafe {
        *p = 5;
    }

}

#[no_mangle]
pub fn safe(p: &amp;amp;mut usize) {
    *p = 5;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;tt&gt;rustc&lt;/tt&gt; invocation later, we have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
raw()
    raw:     55                 pushq  %rbp
    raw+0x1: 48 89 e5           movq   %rsp,%rbp
    raw+0x4: 48 c7 07 05 00 00  movq   $0x5,(%rdi)
             00 
    raw+0xb: 5d                 popq   %rbp
    raw+0xc: c3                 ret    

safe()
    safe:     55                 pushq  %rbp
    safe+0x1: 48 89 e5           movq   %rsp,%rbp
    safe+0x4: 48 c7 07 05 00 00  movq   $0x5,(%rdi)
              00 
    safe+0xb: 5d                 popq   %rbp
    safe+0xc: c3                 ret    
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the two functions are bit-for-bit identical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only differences between borrowed references and raw pointers are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;references will never point at bogus addresses (i.e., they are never &lt;tt&gt;NULL&lt;/tt&gt; or uninitialized),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the compiler doesn’t let you do arbitrary pointer arithmetic on references,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the borrow checker will make you question your life choices for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;(#3 gets better over time.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;tt&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are owned “pointers”. If you are a C++ programmer, you are already familiar with them. Never having &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; worked with C++, I had to think about this a bit until it clicked, but it is really easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what all the documentation and tutorials out there say, &lt;tt&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; is &lt;em&gt;not a pointer&lt;/em&gt; but rather a structure containing a pointer to heap allocated memory just big enough to hold &lt;tt&gt;T&lt;/tt&gt;. The heap allocation and freeing is handled automatically. (Allocation is done in the &lt;tt&gt;Box::new&lt;/tt&gt; function, while freeing is done via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/ops/trait.Drop.html&quot;&gt;&lt;tt&gt;Drop&lt;/tt&gt; trait&lt;/a&gt;, but that’s not relevant as far as the memory layout is concerned.) In other words, &lt;tt&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; is something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct box_of_T {
        struct T *heap_ptr;
};
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, when you make a new box you end up putting only what amounts to &lt;tt&gt;sizeof(struct T *)&lt;/tt&gt; on the stack and it magically starts pointing to somewhere on the heap. In other words, the Rust code like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
let x = Box::new(T { ... });
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is roughly equivalent to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct box_of_t x;

x.heap_ptr = malloc(sizeof(struct T));
if (!x.heap_ptr)
        oom();

*x.heap_ptr = ...;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&amp;amp;[T]&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;&amp;amp;mut [T]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are borrowed slices. This is where things get interesting. Even though it looks like they are just references (which, as stated earlier, translates into a simple C-style pointer), they are much more. These types of references use &lt;em&gt;fat pointers&lt;/em&gt;—that is, a combination of a pointer and a length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct fat_pointer_to_T {
        struct T *ptr;
        size_t nelem;
};
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is incredibly powerful, since it allows bounds checking at runtime &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; getting a subset of a slice is essentially free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&amp;amp;[T; n]&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;&amp;amp;mut [T; n]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are borrowed references to arrays. &lt;em&gt;They are different from borrowed slices.&lt;/em&gt; Since the length of an array is a compile-time constant (the compiler will yell at you if &lt;tt&gt;n&lt;/tt&gt; is not a constant), all the bounds checking can be performed statically. And therefore there is no need to pass around the length in a fat pointer. So, they are passed around as plain ol’ pointers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct T *ptr;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;tt&gt;T&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;[T; n]&lt;/tt&gt;, and &lt;tt&gt;[T]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these aren’t pointers, I thought I’d include them here for completeness’s sake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;tt&gt;T&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like in C, a struct uses as much space as its type requires (i.e., sum of the sizes of its members plus padding).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;tt&gt;[T; n]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like in C, an array of structs uses &lt;tt&gt;n&lt;/tt&gt; times the size of the struct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;tt&gt;[T]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simple answer here is that you cannot make a &lt;tt&gt;[T]&lt;/tt&gt;. That actually makes perfect sense when you consider what that type means. It is saying that we have some &lt;em&gt;variable sized&lt;/em&gt; slice of memory that we want to access as elements of type &lt;tt&gt;T&lt;/tt&gt;. Since this is variable sized, the compiler cannot possibly reserve space for it at compile time and so we get a compiler error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more complicated answer involves the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/marker/trait.Sized.html&quot;&gt;&lt;tt&gt;Sized&lt;/tt&gt; trait&lt;/a&gt;, which I’ve skillfully managed to avoid thus far and so you are on your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a lot of text, so I decided to compact it and make the following table. In the table, I assume that our &lt;tt&gt;T&lt;/tt&gt; struct is 100 bytes in size. In other words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
/* Rust */
struct T {
    stuff: [u8; 100],
}

/* C */
struct T {
        uint8_t stuff[100];
};
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the table in its full glory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Rust&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;C&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Size on&lt;br /&gt;ILP32/LP64&lt;br /&gt;(bytes)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Value&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
let x: T;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct T x;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100/100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;th&gt;Raw pointer&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
let x: *const T;
let x: *mut T;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct T *x;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;th&gt;Reference&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
let x: &amp;amp;T;
let x: &amp;amp;mut T;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct T *x;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;th&gt;Box&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
let x: Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct box_of_T {
        struct T *heap_ptr;
};

struct box_of_T x;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Array of 2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
let x: [T; 2];
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct T x[2];
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200/200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Reference to&lt;br /&gt;an array of 2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
let x: &amp;amp;[T; 2];
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct T *x;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;A slice&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
let x: [T];
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct T x[];
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;unknown at&lt;br /&gt;compile time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;th&gt;A reference&lt;br /&gt;to a slice&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
let x: &amp;amp;[T];
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct fat_ptr_to_T {
        struct T *ptr;
        size_t nelem;
};

struct fat_ptr_to_T x;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;A word of caution: I assume that the sizes of the various pointers are actually implementation details and shouldn’t be relied on to be that way. (Well, with the exception of raw pointers - without those being fixed &lt;abbr title=&quot;Foreign Function Interface&quot;&gt;FFI&lt;/abbr&gt; would be unnecessarily complicated.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t cover &lt;tt&gt;str&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;&amp;amp;str&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;String&lt;/tt&gt;, and &lt;tt&gt;Vec&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; since I don’t consider them fundamental types, but rather convenience types built on top of slices, structs, references, and boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I hope you found this useful. If you have any feedback (good or bad), let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 14:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>eatonphil</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blahg.josefsipek.net/?p=580</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The independent researcher</title>
<link>https://nadiaeghbal.com/independent-research</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nadiaeghbal.com/independent-research</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/adarshp&quot;&gt;Adarsh Pandit&lt;/a&gt; recently introduced me to the concept of the “gentleman scientist”: a researcher who funds their work independently. After digging around a bit, I was fascinated to learn that independent researchers were fairly common in the 18th and 19th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many researchers were personally wealthy or had access to deep pockets. Charles Darwin pursued scientific collection as a hobby, and his first voyage on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Darwin#Survey_voyage_on_HMS_Beagle&quot;&gt;HMS &lt;em&gt;Beagle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was funded by his family. James Prescott Joule, after whom the joule is named, was “scientifically self-taught”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=i0XbtpXmcUsC&amp;amp;lpg=PA144&amp;amp;ots=bf4yeXsp0f&amp;amp;d&amp;amp;pg=PA144#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;doing research in his off-hours at the family brewery&lt;/a&gt;. And in the 1930s, Alfred Lee Loomis used his Wall Street wealth to start a laboratory &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfred_Lee_Loomis#Laboratory_at_Tuxedo_Park&quot;&gt;in his mansion&lt;/a&gt;, nicknamed “The Palace of Science”, where physicists like Albert Einstein, Niels Bohr, and Enrico Fermi collaborated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, if you say you work in research, most people assume you work in academia. But it’s sort of odd that we assume you need someone’s permission to do research. There’s no reason that universities need to be the gatekeepers of exploring and developing new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a lack of training can produce even more interesting results. I was reminded of this recently after hearing a talk by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CharlesCMann&quot;&gt;Charles Mann&lt;/a&gt;, author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Wizard-Prophet-Remarkable-Scientists-Tomorrows/dp/0307961699&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wizard and the Prophet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. He told the story of Norman Borlaug, an agronomist who developed disease-resistant wheat varieties that are estimated to have prevented over half a billion deaths worldwide. Because Borlaug lacked formal training, he made the mistake of engaging in “shuttle breeding”: transporting wheat to multiple climates to speed up their breeding season. Researchers at the time widely believed this was wrong. But Borlaug, in his naïvete, ended up not only disproving the theory, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norman_Borlaug#Double_wheat_season&quot;&gt;accidentally producing wheat varieties&lt;/a&gt; that adapted to environments with varying amounts of sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-validation&quot;&gt;Finding validation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading about independent researchers, I found a 1998 &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; article (&lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/279/5348/178.summary&quot;&gt;paywalled here&lt;/a&gt;), called “Scientists Who Fund Themselves”, profiling several contemporary researchers who fund their own work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, many of them asked to remain anonymous, partly because they didn’t want people to know they were wealthy, and partly, it seems, because it carried a hint of embarrassment. It’s better to say you’re funded by a big institutional grant than to admit it’s coming out of your savings account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the dark side of independent research. Without external validation - &lt;em&gt;“I teach at Stanford”&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;“I got a grant from NASA”&lt;/em&gt;, it’s hard to convince people that you’re any good at what you do. The same goes for your output: you want peers to acknowledge and review your work, or the signoff of a well-respected journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand, then, why researchers flock to the safety of institutions. Imagine studying something that nobody else is studying, for reasons you can’t really articulate, without knowing what the outcome of your work will be. For the truly obsessed person, the need for validation isn’t about ego; it’s about sanity. You want to know there’s some &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; behind the dizzying mental labyrinth that you simultaneously can’t escape and also never want to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, independence seems to afford a level of risk and intellectual freedom that every researcher dreams of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifteen years ago, this researcher, then in his late 40s, considered dropping out of science. “I was always well funded,” says the researcher, who asked that his name not be used. “I just disliked the process very much. It finally reached the point, sort of my midlife crisis, where &lt;strong&gt;I realized I was spending 60 hours a week in the lab, and spending less than 15 doing what I wanted to do.”&lt;/strong&gt; Then he slyly grins as he tells the story of how he escaped from the grind that has become modern science: He decided to use his modest savings to play stock markets around the world. Now, he runs a sprawling lab at a major research university, and he funds most of the work himself….&lt;strong&gt;“I do science because I enjoy doing science … I don’t want to be forced to justify what I’m doing because it makes better air in submarines, or whatever,” he says.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;research-doesnt-have-to-be-expensive&quot;&gt;Research doesn’t have to be expensive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While historic examples of “gentleman scientists” seem to refer to people who were wealthy, independent research doesn’t have to be expensive (depending, of course, on your field). &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; interviewed Duke University’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steven_Vogel&quot;&gt;Steven Vogel&lt;/a&gt;, who studied biological fluid mechanics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If I had $1000 a year to spend on research, I’d be in clover,” says Vogel. “I ask questions like, How do leaves on trees respond to wind? My expenses can be two rolls of film.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking from my own experience, funding opportunities are often hiding in plain sight, or can be cobbled together from a number of places. I funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://nadiaeghbal.com/oss&quot;&gt;my initial research&lt;/a&gt; with a grant from the Ford Foundation, without any prior connections or RFPs. We found each other through someone I’d cold emailed. The grants weren’t big, but they were enough, carrying me through the following year until I joined GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Institutions can also help enable more independent research. I’m lucky to have found an organization, Protocol Labs, that funds research &lt;a href=&quot;https://protocol.ai/blog/ann-research-rfp/&quot;&gt;in all sorts of unusual ways&lt;/a&gt;. Having tried this both ways, I can say that having a steady salary (and health insurance!) allows me to do much better work than when I was worried about my next source of funding. Likewise, Harvard generously provided me with tools that an independent researcher wouldn’t otherwise get, such as access to their library and resources. Organizations can still provide this type of support, and the benefit of collaborating with likeminded peers, without requiring a formal entry into academia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;independent-research-as-public-service&quot;&gt;Independent research as public service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first go at independent research wasn’t necessarily easy. I didn’t know independent research was a viable path, and especially not in Silicon Valley, land of builders and shippers. I didn’t know whether I was doing something useful with my time, or whether I was just a crazy person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years later, I’ve realized that the answer to that question doesn’t really matter. Life is short. Do whatever you can’t stop thinking about. Documenting your findings in public (regardless of outcomes!) is a worthy contribution to society, full stop. If you’re doing something new, and you care about understanding the problem, people will pay attention. What’s more, they’ll take your ideas and make them better than you’d ever imagined. And that style of research - living in service to the public - starts to look very different from the bloated, ivory tower models we’ve been accustomed to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we develop new ways of funding creative work, via Patreon or actual patrons, I would love to see more people consider independent research. You don’t need a PhD to study something you care about. You don’t need to publish papers in academic journals to become widely respected. You just need a curious mind, a bankroll, and a commitment to learning in public. Producing work that makes other people think, and perhaps change their behavior, is the validation, and it’s enormously satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope more people are inspired to take a leap of faith and pursue the lines of inquiry that consume them. And I hope we’ll see other patrons and organizations stepping up to fund them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 13:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hardmaru</dc:creator>
<og:title>The independent researcher</og:title>
<og:description>Adarsh Pandit recently introduced me to the concept of the “gentleman scientist”: a researcher who funds their work independently. After digging around a bit, I was fascinated to learn that independent researchers were fairly common in the 18th and 19th centuries.</og:description>
<og:url>https://nadiaeghbal.com/independent-research</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nadiaeghbal.com/independent-research</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>React from zero: a simple tutorial for React</title>
<link>https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple (99% ES2015 less) tutorial for React&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything runs in the browser without a manual pre-compilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Translations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/00-object-elements.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 0 - Object Elements&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/00-object-elements.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/01-element-factory.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 1 - Element Factory&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/01-element-factory.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/02-jsx.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 2 - JSX&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/02-jsx.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/03-nested-elements.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 3 - Nested Elements&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/03-nested-elements.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/04-components.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 4 - Components&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/04-components.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/05-properties.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 5 - Properties&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/62dc2789/05-properties.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/06-property-types.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 6 - Property Types&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/06-property-types.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/07-property-example.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 7 - Property Example&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/07-property-example.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/08-nested-components.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 8 - Nested Components&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/08-nested-components.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/09-component-classes.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 9 - Component Classes&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/09-component-classes.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/10-example-app.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 10 - Example App&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/10-example-app.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/11-lifecycle-methods.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 11 - Lifecycle Methods&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/11-lifecycle-methods.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/12-component-refactor.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 12 - Component refactor&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/12-component-refactor.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/13-element-refactor.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 13 - Element Refactor&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/13-element-refactor.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/14-references.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 14 - References&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/14-references.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/15-simple-integration.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 15 - Simple Integration&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/15-simple-integration.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/blob/master/16-advanced-integration.html&quot;&gt;Lesson 16 - Advanced Integration&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/kay-is/react-from-zero/b31878c2/16-advanced-integration.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 08:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>galfarragem</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/6407677?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>kay-is/react-from-zero</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero</og:url>
<og:description>react-from-zero - A simple (99% ES2015 less) tutorial for React</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/kay-is/react-from-zero</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Opinion: Elsevier are corrupting open science in Europe</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/political-science/2018/jun/29/elsevier-are-corrupting-open-science-in-europe</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/science/political-science/2018/jun/29/elsevier-are-corrupting-open-science-in-europe</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;O&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;pen Science is all about making science work better so that it can address the world’s challenges. It has been at the top of the EU’s agenda for some time. The European Commission has the ambitious target of achieving Open Access to all scientific publications by 2020. The development of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/political-science/2015/jul/09/the-metric-tide-responsible-indicators-research&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;European Open Science Cloud&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/research/openscience/index.cfm?pg=open-science-policy-platform&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Open Science Policy Platform&lt;/a&gt; indicate that Open Science has entered the mainstream, shifting the process and governance of scholarly communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the European Commission have launched an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/info/research-and-innovation/strategy/goals-research-and-innovation-policy/open-science/open-science-monitor/about-open-science-monitor_en&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Open Science Monitor&lt;/a&gt; to help provide data on the development of Open Science in Europe. To their credit, the Commission have been relatively transparent about &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/info/sites/info/files/open_science_monitor_methodological_note_v2.pdf&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;the methods and data sources&lt;/a&gt; used for this and who is involved. They are also inviting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makingspeechestalk.com/ch/Open_Science_Monitor/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt; to improve the indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a cursory glance at the methodological note reveals something rather odd. The subcontractor for the monitor is Elsevier, the publisher and data analytics provider. Within scholarly communications, Elsevier has perhaps the single worst reputation. With profit margins around 37%, larger than Apple and big oil companies, Elsevier dominate the publishing landscape by selling research back to the same institutes that carried out the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It gets worse too. Throughout the methods, you can see that there is an overwhelming bias towards Elsevier products and services, such as Scopus, Mendeley, and Plum Analytics. These services provide metrics for researchers such as citation counts and social media shares, as well as data-sharing and networking platforms. There are now dozens of comments in the note pointing out the clear bias towards Elsevier and the overlooking of alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth highlighting some of the key issues here that the Commission seems to have ignored in subcontracting to Elsevier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, Elsevier has a notorious history of campaigning against openness in order to protect its paywall-based business. In 2004, they submitted &lt;a href=&quot;https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200304/cmselect/cmsctech/399/399we57.htm&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;evidence&lt;/a&gt; to the UK House of Commons Science and Technology Select Committee on what they saw as the risks associated with Open Access such as threats to scientific integrity and research quality. In 2007, they were &lt;a href=&quot;http://legacy.earlham.edu/~peters/fos/2007/08/publishers-launch-anti-oa-lobbying.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;part of a PR campaign&lt;/a&gt; that connected Open Access to government censorship while lobbying the US Congress. In the USA, Elsevier supported a range of anti-open bills, including the Research Works Act (RWA), for which they made &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/gnxp/2012/01/elsevier-funded-ny-congresswoman-carolyn-maloney-wants-to-deny-americans-access-to-taxpayer-funded-research/#.WyevD4jRBPY&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;numerous financial contributions&lt;/a&gt; to members of the House of Representatives . All of this has stifled the growth of public access to knowledge and slowed the advance of Open Science, benefiting nobody except Elsevier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, many EU member states are currently turning against Elsevier due to its anti-open business practices, high and ever-increasing prices, and dangerously powerful size as a commercial publisher. Research institutes are typically prevented from disclosing details of their ‘big deal’ subscriptions with Elsevier, as this would place downward pressure on journal prices. This profoundly anti-competitive practice has created a dysfunctional scholarly publishing market, and a budget crisis for university libraries. We are seeing national boycotts of Elsevier and rejection of Elsevier journal bundles. Just recently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.timeshighereducation.com/news/sweden-cancels-elsevier-contract-open-access-dispute-spreads#survey-answer&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Swedish&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.timeshighereducation.com/news/will-other-countries-follow-germany-battle-elsevier&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;German&lt;/a&gt; research institutes announced that they were cancelling all Elsevier subscriptions due to concerns about sustainability, unfair pricing arrangements and a general lack of value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this wasn’t bad enough, the conflict of interest of having an organisation that stands to benefit from the monitor by using its own services is so blindingly apparent that you have to wonder why Elsevier were subcontracted in the first place. How is it reasonable for a multi-billion dollar publishing corporation to not only produce metrics that evaluate publishing impact, but also to use them to monitor Open Science and help to define its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180402/09131239544/hated-science-publisher-elsevier-to-help-eu-monitor-open-science-including-open-access.shtml&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;future direction&lt;/a&gt;? Elsevier will be providing data through the monitor that will be used to help facilitate future policy making in the EU that it inevitably will benefit from. That’s like having McDonald’s monitor the eating habits of a nation and then using that to guide policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider Elsevier’s CiteScore metric, a measure of the apparent impact of journals that competes with the impact factor based on citation data from Scopus. An &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insidehighered.com/news/2016/12/14/exploring-citescore-elseviers-new-journal-impact-metrics&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;independent analysis&lt;/a&gt; showed that titles owned by Springer Nature, perhaps Elsevier’s biggest competitor, scored 40% lower and Elsevier titles 25% higher when using CiteScore rather than previous journal impact factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bianca Kramer, a librarian at Utrecht University, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makingspeechestalk.com/ch/Open_Science_Monitor/comm/1215&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;commented&lt;/a&gt; that the monitor should “only include indicators that are themselves open, so data can be reused and results can be reproduced.” This is a fundamental part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/political-science/2015/jul/09/the-metric-tide-responsible-indicators-research&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;responsible metrics&lt;/a&gt; and begs the question of why closed databases like Scopus feature so prominently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so many glaring issues, we should ask why the European Commission allowed this. It seems like a profoundly undemocratic practice to have a company with such an anti-open history now with such a powerful position in the future of Open Science in Europe. The risk here is that by using Elsevier services for such a crucial task, it creates a perverse incentive for researchers to use those services, and thus become dependent on them. This very real issue became apparent last week when Mendeley &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/support/kb/mendeley_import&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;encrypted its databases&lt;/a&gt;, making it more difficult for users to access even their own data. Researchers could become trapped in a relationship with Elsevier in which they are the service and content providers, the product and the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a cruel irony that Elsevier are to be paid to monitor the very system that they have historically fought against. The European Commission should remove Elsevier as sub-contractor and look into better options such as an independent group with no conflicts of interest. It is time to stand up to these ruthless mega-corporations before they corrupt Open Science.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 06:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>slbenfica</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/science/political-science/2018/jun/29/elsevier-are-corrupting-open-science-in-europe</og:url>
<og:description>Elsevier - one of the largest and most notorious scholarly publishers - are monitoring Open Science in the EU on behalf of the European Commission. Jon Tennant argues that they cannot be trusted.</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/63c06e86eb0698a7ef41a3a0db9f2c7822c8392a/1181_416_1678_1007/master/1678.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19vcGluaW9ucy5wbmc&amp;s=618514163c57b2954959a8d853b0904e</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Elsevier are corrupting open science in Europe</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/science/political-science/2018/jun/29/elsevier-are-corrupting-open-science-in-europe</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Downranks 65,000 Pirate Sites in Search Results</title>
<link>https://torrentfreak.com/google-downranks-65000-pirate-sites-in-search-results-180629/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://torrentfreak.com/google-downranks-65000-pirate-sites-in-search-results-180629/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/googlefightspiracy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;172&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-124812&quot;/&gt;The entertainment industries have repeatedly accused Google of not doing enough to limit piracy while demanding tougher action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, groups including the MPAA and RIAA want search engines to remove clearly infringing websites from their search results entirely, especially if courts have previously found them to be acting illegally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/google-opposes-whole-site-removal-of-pirate-domains-151021/&quot;&gt;doesn’t want to&lt;/a&gt; remove whole sites, the critique did prompt the company to make changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in 2014 it &lt;a href=&quot;http://torrentfreak.com/google-will-downrank-pirate-sites-starting-next-week-141018/&quot;&gt;updated its core algorithms&lt;/a&gt; aimed at lowering the visibility of “pirate” sites. Using the number of accurate DMCA requests as an indicator, these sites are demoted in search results for certain key phrases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sites with high numbers of removal notices may appear lower in search results. This ranking change helps users find legitimate, quality sources of content more easily,” Google explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the effects were felt immediately, it’s been unclear how many sites were affected by the algorithmic change. This week, the search engine is filling in some of these blanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a comment to Australian media, Google states that it has demoted 65,000 sites in search results, a list that’s still growing every week. In total, the company received DMCA takedown requests for over 1.8 million domain names, so a little under 4% of these are downranked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of the measures is that people are less likely to see a pirate site when they type “watch movie X” or “download song Y.” This means that these sites see a drop in visitors from Google and a quite significant one too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Demotion results in sites losing around 90 percent of their visitors from Google Search,” a Google spokesperson &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theage.com.au/business/companies/empty-desks-everywhere-film-industry-reeling-from-online-piracy-20180627-p4zo37.html&quot;&gt;told The Age&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, soon after the demotion signal was implemented, pirate sites were &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/googles-new-downranking-hits-pirate-sites-hard-141023/&quot;&gt;hit hard&lt;/a&gt;. However, pirates wouldn’t be pirates if they didn’t respond with their own countermeasures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, many infringing sites have hopped from domain to domain, in part &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/google-anti-piracy-agreement-will-target-domain-hopping-share-search-data-170307/&quot;&gt;to circumvent&lt;/a&gt; the downranking efforts. In addition, Google’s measures also created an opportunity for smaller, less reputable, sites to catch search traffic that would otherwise go to the main players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, however, it’s probably safe to argue that Google’s demotion efforts lowered the search engine’s referrals to pirate sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, demands to do more won’t subside. In Australia, Village Roadshow co-chief Graham Burke has been especially vocal. He has accused Google of profiting from piracy-related traffic and wants the search engine to permanently &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/google-should-begin-delisting-pirate-sites-aussie-rightsholders-say-180322/&quot;&gt;remove infringing sites&lt;/a&gt; from search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaming piracy for declining revenues, Burke noted this week that there are “empty desks everywhere … we can’t compete with stolen goods being sold for free.” And he is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theage.com.au/business/companies/empty-desks-everywhere-film-industry-reeling-from-online-piracy-20180627-p4zo37.html&quot;&gt;not alone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google sees things differently of course. The company has repeatedly highlighted that it has taken several measures to address the piracy concerns, while noting that the entertainment industries have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/google-piracy-availability-pricing-problem-140310/&quot;&gt;responsibility of their own&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 04:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jerry2</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google Downranks 65,000 Pirate Sites in Search Results - TorrentFreak</og:title>
<og:description>With the aim to protect the interests of copyright holders, Google is making ‘pirate’ sites more difficult for its users to find. This week the search engine revealed more information about the scope of this effort. Thus far, Google has downranked 65,000 sites, a measure that led to a 90% reduction in referrals from search results.</og:description>
<og:url>https://torrentfreak.com/google-downranks-65000-pirate-sites-in-search-results-180629/</og:url>
<og:image>https://torrentfreak.com/images/computerkeyboardfeat.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://torrentfreak.com/google-downranks-65000-pirate-sites-in-search-results-180629/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>