<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Slack Is Down</title>
<link>https://status.slack.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://status.slack.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://status.slack.com/&quot;&gt;https://status.slack.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23161623&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23161623&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 223&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 97&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wgjordan</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Slack System Status</og:title>
<og:image>https://status.slack.com/img/v2_rebrand/slack_hash_256.png</og:image>
<og:description>Resources for real-time and historical information about the Slack service.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://status.slack.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>React Native for Windows and Mac</title>
<link>https://microsoft.github.io/react-native-windows/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://microsoft.github.io/react-native-windows/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;Heading&quot;&gt;Bringing React Native to Windows &amp;amp; Mac devices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;21.07541322314&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reactnative.dev/&quot;&gt;React Native&lt;/a&gt; enables you to build world-class native application experiences on multiple platforms using a consistent developer experience based on Javascript and &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;React Native for Windows &amp;amp; Mac brings React Native support for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/downloads&quot;&gt;Windows 10 SDK&lt;/a&gt; as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/macos_release_notes/macos_catalina_10_15_release_notes&quot;&gt;MacOS 10.12 SDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. With this, you can use Javascript to build native Windows apps for &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/get-started-windows-10&quot;&gt;all devices supported by Windows 10&lt;/a&gt; including PCs, tablets, 2-in-1s, Xbox, Mixed reality devices, etc., as well as the MacOS desktop and laptop ecosystems.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://microsoft.github.io/react-native-windows/img/homepage/native-and-js.png&quot; alt=&quot;Written in Javascript, Running Native&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;You can use React Native for Windows &amp;amp; Mac in any way you need, including things like:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Add Windows &amp;amp; Mac support to your existing React Native projects for iOS and/or Android&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Create full Windows 10 &amp;amp; MacOS 10.12 apps using React Native for Windows &amp;amp; Mac from scratch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Add React Native for Windows &amp;amp; Mac components to your existing native Windows 10 or MacOS 10.12 projects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Add React Native for Windows components to your existing Win32 projects using XamlIslands&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 21:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ed</dc:creator>
<og:title>React Native for Windows &amp; Mac · Build native Windows apps with Javascript and React</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://microsoft.github.io/react-native-windows/</og:url>
<og:description>Build native Windows apps with Javascript and React</og:description>
<og:image>https://microsoft.github.io/react-native-windows/img/undraw_online.svg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://microsoft.github.io/react-native-windows/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Update to L.A.&amp;#039;s stay-at-home orders</title>
<link>https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-05-12/coronavirus-beaches-reopen-los-angeles-county-move-toward-new-normal</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-05-12/coronavirus-beaches-reopen-los-angeles-county-move-toward-new-normal</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Los Angeles County’s stay-at-home orders will “with all certainty” be extended for the next three months, county Public Health Director Barbara Ferrer acknowledged during a Board of Supervisors meeting Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferrer later added that even if the orders remain in place through the summer, restrictions will be “gradually relaxed” under a five-step plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are being guided by science and data that will safely move us forward along the road to recovery in a measured way—one that allows us to ensure that effective distancing and infection control measures are in place,” Ferrer said, adding that the county is counting on the public’s compliance with the orders to be able to relax restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testifying before the Board of Superviros, Ferrer stressed further progress will be guided by efforts to contain the virus. Los Angeles County is now the Calfornia epicenter of the coronavirus, with more than 1,300 deaths so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our hope is that by using the data, we’d be able to slowly lift restrictions over the next three months,” she said. But without widely available testing for the coronavirus or rapid home kits that would allow people to test themselves daily, it seems unlikely that the social distancing directives and stay-at-home orders would be completely eased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday afternoon, Los Angeles County Supervisor Kathryn Barger also expressed hope there could be more easing in coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am eager to reopen more of L.A. County as soon as it’s safe to do so, in collaboration with our health experts, community leaders, businesses and residents, with best practices in place to ensure our overall health and well-being. These decisions will be guided by the latest science and data collected,” she said in a statement.&quot;I’m confident that the more our communities continue to comply, the sooner we can resume normalcy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferrer’s comments came shortly before Gov. Gavin Newsom announced that he was modifying the state’s stay-at-home orders to allow individual counties to approve the reopening of malls for curbside pickup service only. The order also allows for the reopening of some offices if teleworking is not feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We aren’t out of the woods yet,” Newsom reminded residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In L.A. County, confirmed cases and deaths have continued to rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When beaches reopen this week, how people can use the sand will look different. Face coverings will be required when not in the water, and sunbathing won’t be allowed. Only active recreation — surfing, running, walking and swimming — will be permitted. Coolers, chairs, umbrellas and any of the other accessories that typically dot the shoreline should be left at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The update to L.A.'s stay-at-home orders comes as officials try to meet two needs: restarting the economy under a new normal while also ensuring that the resurgence in activity doesn’t upend progress in the fight against the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a big push in recent weeks to reopen the state’s economy, which has been hurt by the stay-at-home orders. Newsom last week announced new protocols for retail stores and some workplaces to reopen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the plan, some in-restaurant dining, car washes and shopping malls could also be allowed to reopen in coming weeks if public health officials in a county are able to demonstrate that the spread of the virus has stabilized and that they have adequate testing and hospital capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some rural counties that have seen relatively few cases are likely to be able to meet those benchmarks more quickly than urban counties such as Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-05-08/most-large-california-counties-not-close-to-wider-reopening-times-data-anaylsis-finds&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Times data analysis last week&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; found most big California counties are not close to meeting Newsom’s standards. The analysis looked at which counties could pass just the first two &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gov.ca.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/5.7.20-Presentation.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;criteria&lt;/a&gt; — whether deaths have stopped in the last 14 days, and whether there is no more than one case per 10,000 residents in that same time period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of California failed that test. In fact, 95% of Californians live in counties that don’t meet that standard, the Times analysis found. Not a single county in Southern California nor the San Francisco Bay Area met the criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsom suggested Friday that the guidelines would be later modified on a statewide basis, allowing larger counties hit hardest by the outbreak to also reopen more broadly. “Over the next few weeks, we’ll be making subsequent announcements for the entire state, not just those that meet those more restrictive criteria,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, he also explained &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;%20https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-dine-in-restaurants.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the guidelines&lt;/a&gt; for restaurants in some counties to open for dine-in service, including disposable menus and an emphasis on outdoor seating. He also suggested that customers be screened for symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also on Tuesday, Dr. Anthony Fauci, the nation’s top infectious disease expert, warned members of the U.S. Senate that states that push too quickly to ease orders could undo progress that would trigger an outbreak. Fauci said a 14-day decline in cases is the major benchmark that states should meet before reopening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As other California regions have seen a decline in the number of reported infections and COVID-19-related deaths, L.A. County, the state’s most populous, continues to see growth on both fronts. The county reported Tuesday an additional 961 people who tested positive for the virus, and an additional 45 deaths, bringing the death toll to 1,613. L.A. County’s COVID-19 deaths account for more than half of the state’s total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officials have noted that the numbers reported at the start of the week are typically lower, largely because testing is not at full capacity on weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly 253,000 individuals of L.A. County’s 10 million residents have been checked for the virus and roughly 11% — more than 32,000 — have been infected. Officials have been encouraging all residents, even those without symptoms, to get tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officials have said that social distancing has helped slow the spread of the virus, but also have warned that it remains contagious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s safer to stay at home. COVID-19 &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-05-11/economy-reopening-coronavirus-cases-keep-rising-la-county&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has not changed&lt;/a&gt;,” Ferrer reminded residents Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some neighboring counties that are easing restrictions also continue to see increases in cases and deaths. Riverside County, where &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-05-11/face-masks-rebellion-inland-empire&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;officials voted Friday&lt;/a&gt; to lift requirements for face coverings, reported 150 new cases Monday and 12 additional deaths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Orange County, 45 more cases and one death were reported Tuesday as the number of hospitalizations — a count that fluctuates by the day depending on how many of the county’s eligible 25 hospitals report statistics — rose to 230.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile in Santa Clara County, which was once the hottest spot for infections in the state, the number of cases has declined. Officials reported two additional cases Monday and zero deaths. Santa Clara is one of &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-04-27/6-bay-area-counties-extend-stay-at-home-orders-through-may&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;six Bay Area counties&lt;/a&gt; that have extended shelter-in-place orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also Tuesday, the L.A. County Board of Supervisors debated whether to extend the county’s eviction moratorium to help renters who may be struggling financially because of the pandemic. Supervisors Sheila Kuehl and Hilda Solis proposed extending it until Aug. 31.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kuehl said she based her proposed date off the Department of Public Health’s guidance that at least some of the stay-at-home restrictions would be extended for the next three months. She added that the board’s need to vote on the moratorium every month would create “amazing anxiety” for renters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Obviously our tenants are suffering extreme pain right now,” Solis said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supervisors Kathryn Barger and Janice Hahn submitted an amendment to extend the rent eviction moratorium until only the end of June. The board passed that amendment, 3-2, with Kuehl and Supervisor Mark Ridley-Thomas voting against it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Times staff writer Jaclyn Cosgrove contributed to this report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 20:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CPLX</dc:creator>
<og:title>L.A. County could keep stay-at-home orders in place well into summer, depending on conditions</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-05-12/coronavirus-beaches-reopen-los-angeles-county-move-toward-new-normal</og:url>
<og:image>https://ca-times.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/c187b38/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1575+0+213/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcalifornia-times-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fc5%2Fcb%2F667495f84449babe5e17e54776be%2Fla-me-coronavirus-air-quality.09.JPG</og:image>
<og:description>Los Angeles County's stay-at-home orders will 'with all certainty' be extended for the next three months, Public Health Director Barbara Ferrer said.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-05-12/coronavirus-beaches-reopen-los-angeles-county-move-toward-new-normal</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Make Your PDF Look Scanned</title>
<link>http://www.scanyourpdf.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.scanyourpdf.com</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Tired of being asked to print and scan your signed PDF? Just use a digital signature, upload your document and we will make it look like it was scanned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Document will be available for 1 hour. Maximum of 100 pages PDF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;file-upload&quot; id=&quot;file-upload&quot;&gt;
&lt;form method=&quot;post&quot; enctype=&quot;multipart/form-data&quot; id=&quot;form&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;csrfmiddlewaretoken&quot; value=&quot;aeTRDQ05bpowp3cYuXxeOBZhvzAqwPC5fhhwrXKmRQ6zMi2BVW2eA9sSv3skClbT&quot;/&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;file-upload-btn&quot; type=&quot;button&quot; onclick=&quot;$('.file-upload-input').trigger( 'click' )&quot;&gt;Add File&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-upload-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;file-upload-input&quot; type=&quot;file&quot; onchange=&quot;readURL(this);&quot; accept=&quot;application/pdf&quot; name=&quot;document&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Drop File here or select Add File&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;file-upload-content&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; onclick=&quot;removeUpload()&quot; class=&quot;remove-image&quot;&gt;Remove&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button type=&quot;submit&quot; id=&quot;btn_upload&quot; class=&quot;file-upload-btn&quot;&gt;Submit&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;4.0697674418605&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Questions? Contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scanyourpdf.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection&quot; class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;adc5c8c1c1c2eddececcc3d4c2d8dfddc9cb83cec2c0&quot;&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 18:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>baicunko</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.scanyourpdf.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Backblaze Hard Drive Stats Q1 2020</title>
<link>https://www.backblaze.com/blog/backblaze-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.backblaze.com/blog/backblaze-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-95506 size-full&quot; title=&quot;Backblaze Hard Drive Stats Q1 2020&quot; src=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bb-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Backblaze Drive Stats Q1 2020&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;820&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bb-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020.jpg 1440w, https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bb-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020-300x171.jpg 300w, https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bb-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020-1024x583.jpg 1024w, https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bb-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020-768x437.jpg 768w, https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bb-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020-560x319.jpg 560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;bzdropcap&quot;&gt;As of March 31, 2020, Backblaze had 132,339 spinning hard drives in our cloud storage ecosystem spread across four data centers. Of that number, there were 2,380 boot drives and 129,959 data drives. This review looks at the Q1 2020 and lifetime hard drive failure rates of the data drive models currently in operation in our data centers and provides a handful of insights and observations along the way. In addition, near the end of the post, we review a few 2019 predictions we posed a year ago. As always, we look forward to your comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hard Drive Failure Stats for Q1 2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of Q1 2020, Backblaze was using 129,959 hard drives to store customer data. For our evaluation we remove from consideration those drives that were used for testing purposes and those drive models for which we did not have at least 60 drives (see why below). This leaves us with 129,764 hard drives. The table below covers what happened in Q1 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-95507 size-full&quot; title=&quot;Jan 1- Mar 31 2020 Hard Drive Failure Rates by Manufacturer and Model &quot; src=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Backblaze Q1 2020 Annualized Hard Drive Failure Rates&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;620&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image1.jpg 660w, https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image1-300x282.jpg 300w, https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image1-560x526.jpg 560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes and Observations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Annualized Failure Rate (AFR) for Q1 2020 was 1.07%. That is the lowest AFR for any quarter since we started keeping track in 2013. In addition, the Q1 2020 AFR is significantly lower than the Q1 2019 AFR which was 1.56%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this quarter 4 (four) drive models, from 3 (three) manufacturers, had 0 (zero) drive failures. None of the Toshiba 4TB and Seagate 16TB drives failed in Q1, but both drives had less than 10,000 drive days during the quarter. As a consequence, the AFR can range widely from a small change in drive failures. For example, if just one Seagate 16TB drive had failed, the AFR would be 7.25% for the quarter. Similarly, the Toshiba 4TB drive AFR would be 4.05% with just one failure in the quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, both of the HGST drives with 0 (zero) failures in the quarter have a reasonable number of drive days, so the AFR is less volatile. If the 8TB model had 1 (one) failure in the quarter, the AFR would only be 0.40% and the 12TB model would have an AFR of just 0.26% with 1 (one) failure for the quarter. In both cases, the 0% AFR for the quarter is impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were 195 drives (129,959 minus 129,764) that were not included in the list above because they were used as testing drives or we did not have at least 60 drives of a given model. For example, we have: 20 Toshiba 16TB drives (model: MG08ACA16TA), 20 HGST 10TB drives (model: HUH721010ALE600), and 20 Toshiba 8TB drives (model: HDWF180). When we report quarterly, yearly, or lifetime drive statistics, those models with less than 60 drives are not included in the calculations or graphs. We use 60 drives as a minimum as there are 60 drives in all newly deployed Storage Pods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, all the data from all of the drive models, including boot drives, is included in the files which can be accessed and downloaded on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/hard-drive-test-data.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Hard Drive Test Data&lt;/a&gt; webpage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computing the Annualized Failure Rate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout our reports we use the term Annualized Failure Rate (AFR). The word “annualized” here means that regardless of the period of observation (month, quarter, etc.) the failure rate will be transformed into being an annual measurement. For a given group of drives (i.e. model, manufacturer, etc.) we compute the AFR for a period of observation as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFR = (Drive Failures / (Drive Days / 366) * 100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Drive Failures is the number of drives that failed during the period of observation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive Days is the number of days all of the drives being observed were operational during the period of observation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 366 days in 2020, obviously in non-leap years we use 365.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Compute the AFR for the Drive Model BB007 for the last six months given;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;There were 28 drive failures during the period of observation (six months).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were 6,000 hard drives at the end of the period of observation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The total number of days all of the drives of drive model BB007 were in operation during the period of observation (6 months) totaled 878,400 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;AFR = (28 / (878,400 / 366)) * 100 = (28 / 2,400) * 100 = 1.17%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the six month period, drive model BB007 had an annualized failure rate of 1.17%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;But What About Drive Count?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of you may be wondering where “drive count” fits into this formula? It doesn’t, and that bothers some folks. After all, wouldn’t it be easier to calculate the AFR as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFR = (Drive Failures / Drive Count) * (366 / days in period of observation) * 100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back to our example in the previous paragraph. There were 6,000 hard drives in operation at the end of the period of observation; doing the math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFR = (28 / 6000) * (366 / 183) * 100 = (0.00467) * (2) * 100 = 0.93%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the drive count method, model BB007 had a failure rate of 0.93%. The reason for the difference is that Backblaze is constantly adding and subtracting drives. New &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/vault-cloud-storage-architecture/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Backblaze Vaults&lt;/a&gt; come online every month; new features like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/backblaze-b2-s3-compatible-api/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;S3 compatibility&lt;/a&gt; rapidly increase demand; migration replaces old, low capacity drives with new, higher capacity drives; and sometimes there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/life-and-times-of-a-backblaze-hard-drive&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;cloned and temp drives&lt;/a&gt; in the mix. The environment is very dynamic. The drive count on any given day over the period of observation will vary. When using the drive count method, the failure rate is based on the day the drives were counted. In this case, the last day of the period of observation. Using the drive days method, the failure rate is based on the entire period of observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our example, the following table shows the drive count as we added drives over the six month period of observation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/blog-q1-2020-example-table.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;575&quot; height=&quot;236&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-95532&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/blog-q1-2020-example-table.png 575w, https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/blog-q1-2020-example-table-300x123.png 300w, https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/blog-q1-2020-example-table-560x230.png 560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 575px) 100vw, 575px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you total up the number of drive days, you get 878,400, but the drive count at the end of the period of observation is 6,000. The drive days formula responds to the change in the number of drives over the period of observation, while the drive count formula responds only to the count at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The failure rate of 0.93% from the drive count formula is significantly lower, which is nice if you are a drive manufacturer, but not correct for how drives are actually integrated and used in our environment. That’s why Backblaze chooses to use the drive days method as it better fits the reality of how our business operates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Predictions from Q1 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/backblaze-hard-drive-stats-q1-2019/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Q1 2019 Hard Drive Stats&lt;/a&gt; review we made a few hard drive-related predictions of things that would happen by the end of 2019. Let’s see how we did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction:&lt;/strong&gt; Backblaze will continue to migrate out 4TB drives and will have fewer than 15,000 by the end of 2019: we currently have about 35,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reality: 4TB drive count as of December 31, 2019: 34,908.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review: We were too busy adding drives to migrate any.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction:&lt;/strong&gt; We will have installed at least twenty 20TB drives for testing purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reality: We have zero 20TB drives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review: We have not been offered any 20TB drives to test or otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction:&lt;/strong&gt; Backblaze will go over one exabyte (1,000 petabytes) of available cloud storage. We are currently at about 850 petabytes of available storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction:&lt;/strong&gt; We will have installed, for testing purposes, at least 1 HAMR based drive from Seagate and/or 1 MAMR drive from Western Digital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reality: Not a sniff of HAMR or MAMR drives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review: Hopefully by the end of 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In summary, I think I’ll go back to my hard drive statistics and leave the prognosticating to soothsayers and divining rods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lifetime Hard Drive Stats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table below shows the lifetime failure rates for the hard drive models we had in service as of March 31, 2020. The reporting period is from April 2013 through December 31, 2019. All of the drives listed were installed during this timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-95511 size-full&quot; title=&quot;Lifetime Hard Drive Failure Rates by Make and Model&quot; src=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Backblaze Lifetime Hard Drive Failure Rates&quot; width=&quot;670&quot; height=&quot;630&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image2.png 670w, https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image2-300x282.png 300w, https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image2-560x527.png 560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Hard Drive Stats Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete data set used to create the information used in this review is available on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/hard-drive-test-data.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Hard Drive Test Data webpage&lt;/a&gt;. You can download and use this data for free for your own purpose. All we ask are three things: 1) You cite Backblaze as the source if you use the data, 2) You accept that you are solely responsible for how you use the data, and 3) You do not sell this data to anyone—it is free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you just want the summarized data used to create the tables and charts in this blog post you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://f001.backblazeb2.com/file/Backblaze_Blog/Q1_2020_Drive_Stats_Charts_Data.zip&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;download the ZIP file&lt;/a&gt; containing the MS Excel spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck and let us know if you find anything interesting.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 17:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gnabgib</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Hard Drive Failure Rates: A Look at Drive Reliability</og:title>
<og:description>We take a look at the Q1 2020 and lifetime performance of 129,764 hard drives used in the Backblaze data centers.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.backblaze.com/blog/backblaze-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.backblaze.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bb-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.backblaze.com/blog/backblaze-hard-drive-stats-q1-2020/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Was TON And Why It Is Over</title>
<link>https://telegra.ph/What-Was-TON-And-Why-It-Is-Over-05-12</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://telegra.ph/What-Was-TON-And-Why-It-Is-Over-05-12</guid>
<description>&lt;address&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/durov&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pavel Durov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://telegra.ph/file/c6f281b62b5909d0c5bad.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the last 2,5 years some of our best engineers have been working on a next-generation blockchain platform called TON and a cryptocurrency we were going to name Gram. TON was designed to share the principles of decentralization pioneered by Bitcoin and Ethereum, but to be vastly superior to them in speed and scalability. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were very proud with the result – the technology we created allowed for an open, free, decentralized exchange of value and ideas. When integrated with Telegram, TON had the potential to revolutionize how people store and transfer funds and information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, a US court stopped TON from happening. How? Imagine that several people put their money together to build a gold mine – and to later split the gold that comes out of it. Then a judge comes and tells the mine builders: &lt;em&gt;&quot;Many people invested in the gold mine because they were looking for profits. And they didn't want that gold for themselves, they wanted to sell it to other people. Because of this, you are not allowed to give them the gold.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this doesn't make sense to you, you are not alone – but this is exactly what happened with TON (the mine), its investors, and Grams (the gold). A judge used this reasoning to rule that people should not be allowed to buy or sell Grams like they can buy or sell Bitcoins. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps even more paradoxically, the US court declared that Grams couldn't be distributed not only in the United States, but globally. Why? Because, it said, a US citizen might find some way of accessing the TON platform after it launched. So, to prevent this, Grams shouldn’t be allowed to be distributed anywhere in the world – even if every other country on the planet seemed to be perfectly fine with TON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This court decision implies that other countries don’t have the sovereignty to decide what is good and what is bad for their own citizens. If the US suddenly decided to ban coffee and demanded coffee shops in Italy be closed because some American might go there – we doubt anyone would agree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, despite that, we have made the difficult decision not to proceed with TON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the US judge is right about one thing: we, the people outside the US, can vote for our presidents and elect our parliaments, but we are still dependent on the United States when it comes to finance and technology (luckily not coffee). The US can use its control over the dollar and the global financial system to shut down any bank or bank account in the world. It can use its control over Apple and Google to remove apps from the App Store and Google Play. So yes, it is true that other countries do not have full sovereignty over what to allow on their territory. Unfortunately, we – the 96% of the world’s population living elsewhere – are dependent on decision makers elected by the 4% living in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may change in the future. But today, we are in a vicious circle: you can’t bring more balance to an overly centralized world exactly because it’s so centralized. We did try though. We're leaving it to the the next generations of entrepreneurs and developers to pick up the banner and learn from our mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing this post to officially announce that Telegram’s active involvement with TON is over. You may see – or may have already seen – sites using my name or the Telegram brand or the &quot;TON&quot; abbreviation to promote their projects. Don’t trust them with your money or data. No present or past member of our team is involved with any of these projects. While networks based on the technology we built for TON may appear, we won’t have any affiliation with them and are unlikely to ever support them in any way. So be careful, and don’t let anyone mislead you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to conclude this post by wishing luck to all those striving for decentralization, balance and equality in the world. You are fighting the right battle. This battle may well be the most important battle of our generation. We hope that you succeed where we have failed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amaccuish</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>What Was TON And Why It Is Over</og:title>
<og:description>For the last 2,5 years some of our best engineers have been working on a next-generation blockchain platform called TON and a cryptocurrency we were going to name Gram. TON was designed to share the principles of decentralization pioneered by Bitcoin and Ethereum, but to be vastly superior to them in speed and scalability.  We were very proud with the result – the technology we created allowed for an open, free, decentralized exchange of value and ideas. When integrated with Telegram, TON had the potential…</og:description>
<og:image>https://telegra.ph/file/c6f281b62b5909d0c5bad.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://telegra.ph/What-Was-TON-And-Why-It-Is-Over-05-12</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Linux is Most Used OS in Microsoft Azure – over 50 percent of VM cores</title>
<link>https://build5nines.com/linux-is-most-used-os-in-microsoft-azure-over-50-percent-fo-vm-cores/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://build5nines.com/linux-is-most-used-os-in-microsoft-azure-over-50-percent-fo-vm-cores/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For the last few years, Microsoft has stated during event keynotes and in other places that Linux is a rapidly growing operating system (OS) being used within Microsoft Azure. They had proudly stated that 50% of new VMs running in Azure were running Linux. (This is the latest stat I remember Microsoft saying publicly a while back already.) Well, I came across an interesting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/adirron_linuxonazure-progress-activity-6665502370795003905-DY1G&quot; class=&quot;rank-math-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;infographic recently (thanks to Adir Ron)&lt;/a&gt; that gives some statistics and other information regarding the percentage and overall usage of the Linux OS in Microsoft Azure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-28288&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the past growth of Linux adoption in Microsoft Azure, I’ve long suspected that Microsoft Azure hosts more Linux VMs than Windows VMs. This infographic looks to shed some light on this most likely being true, as it states “More than 50% of VM cores runs Linux on Azure”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you look at the infographic itself, here are a few stats listed in it that I’d like to point out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;More than 50% of VM cores runs Linux on Azure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux-based images comprise 60% of Azure Marketplace images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top 100 Microsoft customers deploy Linux workloads on Azure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azure Tuned Kernels provide 25% faster network throughput&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft supports all major Linux distros, like: Red Hat, SUSE, Ubuntu, Oracle Linux, Debian, CentOS, CoreOS, and OpenSUSE &lt;em&gt;(Related: Azure also supports FreeBSD)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azure offers two natively supported managed Kubernetes orchestration services: Azure Kubernetes Service, and Azure Red Hat OpenShift&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the “Did you know? Linux is the fastest growing platform on Azure” &lt;a href=&quot;https://build5nines.com/tag/infographic/&quot; class=&quot;rank-math-link&quot;&gt;infographic&lt;/a&gt; below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?ssl=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;28289&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://build5nines.com/linux-is-most-used-os-in-microsoft-azure-over-50-percent-fo-vm-cores/linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?fit=1200%2C4464&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1200,4464&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?fit=81%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?fit=275%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?fit=275%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;Linux is Most Used OS in Microsoft Azure - over 50 percent of VM cores 1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-28289&quot; width=&quot;275&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?w=1200&amp;amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?resize=275%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1 275w, https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?resize=768%2C2857&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?resize=413%2C1536&amp;amp;ssl=1 413w, https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?resize=1080%2C4018&amp;amp;ssl=1 1080w, https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?resize=980%2C3646&amp;amp;ssl=1 980w, https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-microsoft-azure-2020-05-11.jpg?resize=480%2C1786&amp;amp;ssl=1 480w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 275px) 100vw, 275px&quot; title=&quot;Linux is Most Used OS in Microsoft Azure - over 50 percent of VM cores 1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy running Linux in Azure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. If you’re looking to save money hosting VMs in Microsoft Azure (both Windows and Linux), you should read my article showing you how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://build5nines.com/properly-shutdown-azure-vm-to-save-money/&quot; class=&quot;rank-math-link&quot;&gt;properly shutdown Azure VMs to save money&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-relatedposts&quot; class=&quot;jp-relatedposts&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;build-article-h3s&quot; id=&quot;build-15633644&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;build-1127545375&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-layout=&quot;in-article&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;fluid&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-2908331720107711&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;8431898565&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;build-article-after&quot; id=&quot;build-1837083926&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-2908331720107711&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;9337818916&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot; data-full-width-responsive=&quot;true&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;articleauthor-headline&quot;&gt;Article Author&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;


&lt;p id=&quot;author-desc&quot;&gt;Chris is a &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft MVP&lt;/strong&gt; and has nearly 20 years of experience designing and building Cloud &amp;amp; Enterprise systems. He is also a &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Certified Azure Solutions Architect&lt;/strong&gt; and developer, a &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Certified Trainer&lt;/strong&gt; (MCT), and Cloud Advocate. He has a passion for technology and sharing what he learns with others to help enable them to learn faster and be more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>crpietschmann</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Linux Is Most Used OS In Microsoft Azure - Over 50 Percent Of VM Cores | Build5Nines</og:title>
<og:description>For the last few years, Microsoft has stated during event keynotes and in other places that Linux is a rapidly growing operating system (OS) being used within M</og:description>
<og:url>https://build5nines.com/linux-is-most-used-os-in-microsoft-azure-over-50-percent-fo-vm-cores/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i1.wp.com/build5nines.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/microsoft-did-you-know-linux-fastest-growing-platform-on-azure.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://build5nines.com/linux-is-most-used-os-in-microsoft-azure-over-50-percent-fo-vm-cores/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Waymo has raised $3B in the last two months</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/waymo-adds-750-million-to-war-chest-as-driverless-cars-prove-tough-to-deploy-11589299200</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/waymo-adds-750-million-to-war-chest-as-driverless-cars-prove-tough-to-deploy-11589299200</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In the world of driverless cars, the big keep getting bigger.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Waymo LLC has raised a further $750 million, pushing the total outside investment the company has announced in the past two months to $3 billion and bolstering its financial war chest at a time when the coronavirus pandemic has created new uncertainty in the race to develop self-driving vehicles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The...
  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Rutledge</dc:creator>
<og:title>Waymo Adds $750 Million to War Chest as Driverless Cars Prove Tough to Deploy</og:title>
<og:description>Waymo has raised another $750 million, pushing the total outside investment the driverless-car company has announced in the past two months to $3 billion as the coronavirus creates new uncertainty in the race to develop self-driving vehicles.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/waymo-adds-750-million-to-war-chest-as-driverless-cars-prove-tough-to-deploy-11589299200</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-186096/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/waymo-adds-750-million-to-war-chest-as-driverless-cars-prove-tough-to-deploy-11589299200</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>In Praise of AutoHotKey</title>
<link>https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/ahk/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/ahk/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;People think it’s weird that I do all my development on a Windows machine. It’s definitely a second-class citizen experience in the wider development world, and Windows has a lot of really frustrating issues, but it’s still my favorite operating system. This is for exactly one reason: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.autohotkey.com/&quot;&gt;AutoHotKey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AHK is an engine for mapping keystrokes to scripts. I wouldn’t call it particularly elegant, and it’s filled with tons of redundancy and quirks. Even its fans admit how nasty the language can be. But it hooks into the whole Windows system and makes it easy to augment my workflow. It’s given me a far greater degree of control over my computer than I ever managed to achieve with another OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a short list of some of the scripts I’ve written, in &lt;em&gt;roughly&lt;/em&gt; ascending order of complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mouse-shortcuts&quot;&gt;Mouse shortcuts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a simple one. I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nuance.com/dragon.html&quot;&gt;Dragon&lt;/a&gt; voice to text for writing as I can speak prose a lot faster than I can type. My microphone is very sensitive and often picks up the sounds of the keyboard, so I need a way to toggle dictation on and off. I wanted to map the toggle button to tapping my mouse wheel left, but Dragon only supports keyboard shortcuts. So I glued the two together with AutoHotKey:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-ahk&quot; data-lang=&quot;ahk&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;WheelLeft::Send,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{NumpadAdd}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;WheelLeft&lt;/code&gt; is the shortcut itself. On the right of the &lt;code&gt;::&lt;/code&gt; is the actual command. In this case all it does is send a Numpad &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; keystroke, which happens to be the “toggle dictation” hotkey in Dragon. It’s a small thing that only took me about a minute to write and makes using Dragon more pleasant. Most my AutoHotKey uses are like this: tacking on a crude API on to something that doesn’t have one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hotstrings-for-math&quot;&gt;Hotstrings for math&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write a lot of mathematical notation, such as &lt;code&gt;∀x ∈ S: P(x) ⇒ Q(x)&lt;/code&gt;, for work. Historically people wrote these characters by using a rendering engine like LaTeX or Mathjax, which are cumbersome and not portable. I can’t put arbitrary LaTeX into an email. The alternative to those is writing Unicode. But Unicode symbols are not on standard keyboards and there are &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of characters to write. Most of the time I’ve seen people just copy and paste the characters they want, one character at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AutoHotKey lets you define &lt;strong&gt;hotstrings&lt;/strong&gt;, which trigger when certain strings are typed. While this can be any kind of command, it’s most often used to replace a short string with a much longer one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;::;shrug::¯\_(ツ)_/¯ 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can also use it to map strings to complex Unicode characters. Here’s a sample of my current hotstrings list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;:O:;e::∃
::;in::∈
::;cup::∪
:O:;diamond::◇
; etc
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if I type &lt;code&gt;;a x ;in S: ;diamond(f[x] ;geq 0)&lt;/code&gt;, I get &lt;code&gt;∀x ∈ S: ◇(f[x] ≥ 0)&lt;/code&gt;. This is a hell of a lot more convenient than copy and paste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;markdown-links&quot;&gt;Markdown links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is in Markdown. The syntax for a markdown link is &lt;code&gt;[title](url)&lt;/code&gt;. It’s really annoying if I have to copy both the title and the URL from somewhere else. Then I need to do two trips between the source and the markdown text, one to copy each part. Enter AutoHotKey:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-ahk&quot; data-lang=&quot;ahk&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#!c::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; ; win+alt+c&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;ctmp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;clipboard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; ; what's currently on the clipboard&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;clipboard&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Send&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; ; copy to clipboard&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;ClipWait,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; ; wait for the clipboard to change&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;clipboard&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;[&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;clipboard&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;](&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;ctmp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;)&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; ; ends a multiline command&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &lt;code&gt;url&lt;/code&gt; is on the clipboard and I press &lt;code&gt;win+alt+c&lt;/code&gt; while &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; is the selected text, then the clipboard is replaced with &lt;code&gt;[title](url)&lt;/code&gt;. This might seem like a small affordances but it makes adding links so, &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much nicer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;fast-window-switching&quot;&gt;Fast Window Switching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;alt+tab&lt;/code&gt; is annoying because you have to visually confirm you’re on the right app. You can’t use muscle memory here because the stack depends on your recent windows. As a hard-core Vim user, anything that gets in the way of muscle memory is bad and should be avoided. Let’s write a better window switcher in AutoHotKey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AHK lets you create &lt;strong&gt;window groups&lt;/strong&gt; based on window titles, &lt;code&gt;.exe&lt;/code&gt; name, or process ID. I can create a separate window group for each app, and then make a hotkey that specifically cycles through that window group:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-ahk&quot; data-lang=&quot;ahk&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;GroupAdd,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;firefox,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;ahk_exe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;firefox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span&gt;; right alt + 1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;::&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;GroupActivate,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;firefox,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;R&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now no matter where I am, pressing &lt;code&gt;rightalt+1&lt;/code&gt; will immediately switch to Firefox. If I’m already in Firefox, it cycles through the active windows. A window can belong to multiple groups, so I can have a special “workshops” key to cycle between lecture notes, slides, and the IDE. I have a separate window group for each of my most commonly used apps, including Neovim, the TLA+ toolbox, and the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of commonly used apps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;remapping-the-calculator-button&quot;&gt;Remapping the calculator button&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nobody likes the default Windows calculator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you press the calculator button when the calculator is already open, it just opens a 2nd calculator. Why would anyone want that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;So instead I have it open up &lt;a href=&quot;https://frinklang.org/&quot;&gt;Frink&lt;/a&gt;. If Frink is already open, it activates it. If it’s already active, it minimizes it. Much better UX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-ahk&quot; data-lang=&quot;ahk&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;toggle_app(app,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;location)&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;if &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;WinExist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(app)&lt;/span&gt;   
    &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;WinActive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(app)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span&gt;WinActivate&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span&gt;WinMinimize&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;location&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;Run,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;%location%&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span&gt;Launch_App2::toggle_app(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Frink&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;\Path\to\frink.jar&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the same thing set up for Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;scihubize&quot;&gt;Scihubize&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sci-hub.tw/&quot;&gt;sci-hub&lt;/a&gt; is a service that lets you access research papers for free. It’s not quuiiiiiiiiite legal, but buying papers is super expensive, like fifty dollars per paper. Not something I can afford, and I think the entire industry is evil anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally to use sci-hub you have to copy the blocked paper url, go to sci-hub, paste the link into a form on the website, and click go. It’s a lot more convenient than paying 50 bucks for a paper, but it’s still pretty annoying. If I’m trying to skim a dozen papers, doing that every single time breaks my flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately sci-hub uses a standard format for its links, so I can automate the entire process. This script reopens the current paper in sci-hub:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-ahk&quot; data-lang=&quot;ahk&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;; Only enable hotkey in Firefox&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;#IfWinActive&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;ahk_exe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;firefox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span&gt;; right alt + right ctrl + s&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;!^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;; wait for both control keys to be lifted&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Keywait,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;RControl&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Keywait,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;RAlt&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;; go to url bar&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;SendEvent,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span&gt;; add prefix, go&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;SendInput,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{left}sci&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;hub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;tw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{enter}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that after adding this I’ve read a lot more science papers. There’s something about the difference between “a single hotkey” and “four steps” that makes me more likely to bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have something set up similar for the Internet Archive, where I can just press a hotkey to reload the current page in the archive. This is handy for doing any kind of historical research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t think AutoHotKey or Windows is special in this regard. I could have gotten something similar working on Mac or Linux. But when I tried, I found it much harder. I had to dive into about how the OS worked. I remember trying for two days to get the &lt;code&gt;∈&lt;/code&gt; sign thing working on Linux and eventually had to read up on how the scan codes worked. In the end I decided that the added convenience was just not worth the extra effort. And that was just one system. If I wanted to add my window switcher, I’d have to learn how the window management works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real draw is that AutoHotKey makes it all convenient. Each of these scripts takes me just a few minutes to write, no deep dives into Windows internals needed. When adding affordances to my computer is easy, I’m more likely to add them. Using AutoHotKey makes me feel like I can customize my machine. My scripts bring the computer closer to what I need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside is that it’s pretty fragile. I have to tweak delays and sometimes reorganize my computer just to keep my scripts from breaking. I disabled every animation I can to minimize nondeterminism. I wish it was easier to use AutoHotKey if you weren’t a technical expert, so I could give scripts to my friends to help them too. But even with these issues it’s still one of my favorite programs, and still the reason I prefer working on Windows to any other operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Lito Nicolai for feedback.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>todsacerdoti</dc:creator>
<og:title>In Praise of AutoHotKey • Hillel Wayne</og:title>
<og:description>People think it’s weird that I do all my development on a Windows machine. It’s definitely a second-class citizen experience in the wider development world, and Windows has a lot of really frustrating issues, but it’s still my favorite operating system. This is for exactly one reason: AutoHotKey. AHK is an engine for mapping keystrokes to scripts. I wouldn’t call it particularly elegant, and it’s filled with tons of redundancy and quirks.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/ahk/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/ahk/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twitter Will Allow Employees to Work at Home Forever</title>
<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/twitter-will-allow-employees-to-work-at-home-forever</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/twitter-will-allow-employees-to-work-at-home-forever</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;31.098591549296&quot;&gt;
  
  




&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;BuzzFeed News has reporters across five continents bringing you trustworthy stories about the impact of the coronavirus. To help keep this news free,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://support.buzzfeednews.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;become a member&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;and sign up for our newsletter,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/newsletters/coronavirus?utm_source=newsletter&quot;&gt;Outbreak Today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-retailers=&quot;Amazon&quot; data-keywords=&quot;cleaning,fast fashion&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;71.531962201223&quot;&gt;
  
  




&lt;p&gt;Some Twitter employees will never return to their office.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey emailed employees on Tuesday telling them that they’d be allowed to work from home permanently, even after the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/collection/coronavirus&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;coronavirus&lt;/a&gt; pandemic lockdown passes. Some jobs that require physical presence, such as maintaining servers, will still require employees to come in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We've been very thoughtful in how we've approached this from the time we were one of the first companies to move to a work-from-home model,” a Twitter spokesperson told BuzzFeed News. “We'll continue to be, and we'll continue to put the safety of our people and communities first.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2020/keeping-our-employees-and-partners-safe-during-coronavirus.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;encouraged its employees&lt;/a&gt; to start working from home in early March as the coronavirus began to spread across the US. Several other &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/the-coronavirus-is-forcing-techies-to-work-from-home-some&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tech companies&lt;/a&gt; did the same, including Microsoft, Google, and Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That month, Twitter human resources head Jennifer Christie told BuzzFeed News the company would “never probably be the same” in the structure of its work. “People who were reticent to work remotely will find that they really thrive that way,” Christie said. “Managers who didn’t think they could manage teams that were remote will have a different perspective. I do think we won’t go back.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dorsey had announced the company's intent to work in a “&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/twitter-got-a-big-tax-break-to-stay-in-san-francisco-jack&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;distributed&lt;/a&gt;” way before the virus, but the pandemic forced the company to move the timeline up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his email, Dorsey said it’s unlikely Twitter would open its offices before September, and that business travel would be canceled until then as well, with very few exceptions. The company will also cancel all in-person events for the rest of the year, and reassess its plan for 2021 later this year. Finally, Twitter upped its allowance for work from home supplies to $1,000 for all employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/twitter-will-allow-employees-to-work-at-home-forever</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2020-05/12/21/campaign_images/1cb332cf13f9/twitter-will-allow-employees-to-work-at-home-fore-2-340-1589320570-0_dblbig.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Twitter Will Allow Employees To Work At Home Forever</og:title>
<og:description>Two months into working from home, Twitter makes it permanent for some.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/twitter-will-allow-employees-to-work-at-home-forever</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>