<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Uber and Lyft ordered by California judge to classify drivers as employees</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/10/21362460/uber-lyft-drivers-employees-california-court-ruling</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/10/21362460/uber-lyft-drivers-employees-california-court-ruling</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;JPKKJ5&quot;&gt;A California judge ruled that Uber and Lyft must classify their drivers as employees in a stunning preliminary injunction issued &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fdocument%2F472020392%2FOrder-on-People-s-Motion-for-Preliminary-Injunction-and-Related-Motions&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F8%2F10%2F21362460%2Fuber-lyft-drivers-employees-california-court-ruling&quot; rel=&quot;sponsored nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Monday afternoon&lt;/a&gt;. The injunction is stayed for 10 days, however, giving Uber and Lyft an opportunity to appeal the decision. Uber said it planned to file an immediate emergency appeal to block the ruling from going into effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;T7O63Y&quot;&gt;Uber and Lyft are under increasing pressure to fundamentally alter their business models in California, the state where both companies were founded and ultimately prospered. At issue is the classification of ride-hailing drivers as independent contractors. Uber and Lyft say drivers prefer the flexibility of working as freelancers, while labor unions and elected officials contend this deprives them of traditional benefits like health insurance and workers’ compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;KC5ZSl&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Uber said it planned to file an immediate emergency appeal&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;IZqL8M&quot;&gt;In May, California Attorney General Xavier Becerra, along with city attorneys of Los Angeles, San Francisco, and San Diego, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/5/21248347/california-uber-lyft-attorney-general-independent-employees&quot;&gt;sued the companies&lt;/a&gt;, arguing that their drivers were misclassified as independent contractors when they should be employees under the state’s AB5 law that went into effect on January 1st. Becerra later &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21302140/california-ag-uber-lyft-drivers-classify-employees-preliminary-injunction&quot;&gt;filed a motion for a preliminary injunction&lt;/a&gt; that could compel the ride-hailing companies to classify drivers as employees immediately. AB5, which was signed into law last September, enshrines the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.californiaemploymentlawreport.com/2019/03/understanding-the-abc-test-for-independent-contractors-in-california/&quot;&gt;so-called “ABC test”&lt;/a&gt; to determine if someone is a contractor or an employee.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p id=&quot;W8Y9OF&quot;&gt;“It’s this simple,” California Superior Court Judge Ethan Schulman wrote in his ruling, “Defendants’ drivers do not perform work that is ‘outside the usual course’ of their business. Defendants’ insistence that their businesses are ‘multi-sided platforms’ rather than transportation companies is flatly inconsistent with the statutory provisions that govern their businesses as transportation network companies, which are defined as companies that ‘engage in the transportation of persons by motor vehicle for compensation.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5nd17a&quot;&gt;He added, “It also flies in the face of economic reality and common sense... To state the obvious, drivers are central, not tangential, to Uber and Lyft’s entire ride-hailing business.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;xBH5TB&quot;&gt;In a statement hailing the ruling, Becerra said California and its workers “shouldn’t have to foot the bill when big businesses try to skip out on their responsibilities. We’re going to keep working to make sure Uber and Lyft play by the rules.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;N48SbI&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It also flies in the face of economic reality and common sense”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;sjAx08&quot;&gt;This was just the latest legal blow against Uber and Lyft in California. Last week, the state’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/5/21356096/uber-lyft-california-labor-commissioner-lawsuit-driver-classification&quot;&gt;labor commissioner alleged&lt;/a&gt; in a pair of lawsuits that the companies were stealing wages from drivers by refusing to classify them as employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;knT9Eq&quot;&gt;Drivers’ groups that have been pressuring the companies to reclassify their drivers celebrated the decision as forward progress. “Today’s ruling affirms what California drivers have long known to be true,” Mike Robinson, a Lyft driver and member of the Mobile Workers Alliance, a group of Southern California drivers, said in a statement, “workers like me have rights and Uber and Lyft must respect those rights.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Am3hdr&quot;&gt;But Uber and Lyft maintain this ruling conflicts with the desires of the majority of drivers and will result in fewer jobs during a global pandemic that is putting strain on workers’ finances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;OfLhpg&quot;&gt;“The vast majority of drivers want to work independently, and we’ve already made significant changes to our app to ensure that remains the case under California law,” an Uber spokesperson said. “When over 3 million Californians are without a job, our elected leaders should be focused on creating work, not trying to shut down an entire industry during an economic depression.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;iY6kOc&quot;&gt;A Lyft spokesperson agreed. “Drivers do not want to be employees, full stop,” the spokesperson said. “We’ll immediately appeal this ruling and continue to fight for their independence. Ultimately, we believe this issue will be decided by California voters and that they will side with drivers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;PU6FPH&quot;&gt;If drivers were classified as employees, Uber and Lyft would be responsible for paying them minimum wage, overtime compensation, paid rest periods, and reimbursements for the cost of driving for the companies, including personal vehicle mileage. But as independent contractors, drivers receive none of these benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;hoqcY5&quot;&gt;The flurry of lawsuits and court rulings in California comes ahead of the November election, when the state’s voters will decide on an Uber-and-Lyft-backed ballot measure that would override AB5 by classifying ride-hail drivers and other gig economy workers as independent contractors.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 21:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:description>A judge ordered the companies to classify their drivers, but Uber and Lyft are appealing.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JSKtCJ3wxGb0dTqiEQbJwQW1p20=/0x553:5568x3468/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21714537/1227939563.jpg.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Uber and Lyft ordered by California judge to classify drivers as employees</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/10/21362460/uber-lyft-drivers-employees-california-court-ruling</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/10/21362460/uber-lyft-drivers-employees-california-court-ruling</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Clean Network – United States Department of State</title>
<link>https://www.state.gov/5g-clean-network/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.state.gov/5g-clean-network/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-172688 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanNetwork_NewCleans-300x169.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanNetwork_NewCleans-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanNetwork_NewCleans-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanNetwork_NewCleans-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanNetwork_NewCleans-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanNetwork_NewCleans-85x48.jpg 85w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanNetwork_NewCleans-1698x956.jpg 1698w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanNetwork_NewCleans-1642x924.jpg 1642w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanNetwork_NewCleans.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We call on all freedom-loving nations and companies to join the Clean Network.&lt;cite&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael R. Pompeo&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Secretary of State&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clean Network program is the Trump Administration’s comprehensive approach to safeguarding the nation’s assets including citizens’ privacy and companies’ most sensitive information from aggressive intrusions by malign actors, such as the Chinese Communist Party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clean Network addresses the long-term threat to data privacy, security, human rights and principled collaboration posed to the free world from authoritarian malign actors. The Clean Network is rooted in internationally accepted digital trust standards. It represents the execution of a multi-year, all-of-government, enduring strategy, built on a coalition of trusted partners, and based on rapidly changing technology and economics of global markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Digital Trust Standards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 2020, at the request of the Department of State, the Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) assembled a group of 25 experts from Asian, European, and U.S. companies and research centers to develop criteria to assess the trustworthiness of telecommunications equipment suppliers. These &lt;a href=&quot;https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/publication/200511_Lewis_5G_v3.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-sk=&quot;tooltip_parent&quot; aria-describedby=&quot;sk-tooltip-11869&quot;&gt;Criteria for Security and Trust in Telecommunications Networks and Services&lt;/a&gt; complement the work of the Prague Proposals and the European Union’s 5G Toolbox. They offer governments and network owners or operators an additional tool to use to determine trustworthiness and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prague Proposals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 2019, government officials from more than 30 countries across the globe, alongside representatives from the European Union, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, and industry, participated in discussions regarding the important national security, economic, and commercial considerations that must be part of each country’s evaluation of 5G vendors. The resulting &lt;a class=&quot;c-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nukib.cz/download/5G%20site/Prague-Proposals-5G-Sec-190503.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-sk=&quot;tooltip_parent&quot; aria-describedby=&quot;sk-tooltip-11547&quot;&gt;Prague Proposals&lt;/a&gt; on 5G security published by the Czech conference chair serve as a set of recommendations and principles for nations to consider as they design, construct, and administer their 5G infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Clean Network Lines of Effort&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 5, 2020, Secretary Pompeo &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/secretary-michael-r-pompeo-at-a-press-availability-10/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-auth=&quot;NotApplicable&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the expansion of the Clean Network program:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clean Carrier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure that People’s Republic of China (PRC) carriers are not connected with U.S. telecommunications networks. Such companies pose a danger to U.S. national security and should not provide international telecommunications services to and from the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clean Store&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remove untrusted applications from U.S. mobile app stores. PRC apps threaten our privacy, proliferate viruses, censor content, and spread propaganda and disinformation. Americans’ most sensitive personal and business information must be protected on their mobile phones from exploitation and theft for the CCP’s benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clean Apps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prevent untrusted PRC smartphone manufacturers from pre-installing—or otherwise making available for download—trusted apps on their apps store. Huawei, an arm of the PRC surveillance state, is trading on the innovations and reputations of leading U.S. and foreign companies. These companies should remove their apps from Huawei’s app store to ensure they are not partnering with a human rights abuser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clean Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prevent U.S. citizens’ most sensitive personal information and our businesses’ most valuable intellectual property, including COVID-19 vaccine research, from being stored and processed on cloud-based systems accessible to our foreign adversaries through companies such as Alibaba, Baidu, China Mobile, China Telecom, and Tencent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clean Cable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure the undersea cables connecting our country to the global internet are not subverted for intelligence gathering by the PRC at hyper scale. We will also work with foreign partners to ensure that undersea cables around the world aren’t similarly subject to compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Clean Path&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-162027&quot; src=&quot;https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Secretary Michael R. Pompeo in the State Department Press Briefing Room on April 29, 2020, in front of a screen reading &amp;quot;Clean Path&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-2048x1152.jpg 2048w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-85x48.jpg 85w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-1698x956.jpg 1698w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-1642x924.jpg 1642w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 29, 2020, Secretary Pompeo &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/secretary-michael-r-pompeo-at-a-press-availability-4/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that the U.S. Department of State will begin requiring a Clean Path for all 5G network traffic entering and exiting U.S. diplomatic facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 5G Clean Path is an end-to-end communication path that does not use any transmission, control, computing, or storage equipment from untrusted IT vendors, such as Huawei and ZTE, which are required to comply with directives of the Chinese Communist Party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 5G Clean Path embodies the highest standards of security against untrusted, high-risk vendors’ ability to disrupt, manipulate or deny services to private citizens, financial institutions, or critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Untrusted IT vendors will have no access to U.S. State Department systems. We will follow the letter of the law to ensure that we have a clean path for all 5G network traffic coming into all of our facilities. Period. We will keep doing all we can to keep our critical data and our networks safe from the Chinese Communist Party.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael R. Pompeo&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Secretary of State&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5G Clean Countries and Clean Telcos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/the-tide-is-turning-toward-trusted-5g-vendors/&quot;&gt;Many countries are choosing to allow only trusted vendors in their 5G networks&lt;/a&gt;. Examples include the United Kingdom, Czech Republic, Poland, Sweden, Estonia, Romania, Denmark, and Latvia. Greece has agreed to use Ericsson, rather than Huawei, to develop its 5G infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister of Poland Mateusz Morawiecki stated, “Poland believes the construction of our 5G Clean Path network is a prerequisite for EU strategic technological sovereignty. That is why we must keep it secure at all costs and we are a 5G Clean Country. To protect our 5G network from potential wrongdoers it is necessary that all European entrepreneurs maintain clean production lines and a 5G Clean Path, free from potential industrial espionage. Demanding that 5G Clean Standards are observed with regard to 5G technology is a step towards building a fairer globalized world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European Commissioner Thierry Breton remarked on the clean EU 5G toolbox, “The European Union with all member states developed a 5G cybersecurity toolbox defining the criteria and clear measures to avoid the use of ‘high-risk suppliers.’ The toolbox adds that member states have identified certain non-EU countries with state-backed actors as a serious cyber threat to their national interest. The European 5G suppliers are likely to meet these criteria. It will serve as a reference for the telco operators’ board of directors who have to make the decision on 5G suppliers. If they choose a ‘high-risk 5G supplier,’ the board members may be liable if something happens.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the largest telecom companies around the globe are also becoming “Clean Telcos.” Orange in France, Jio in India, Telstra in Australia, SK and KT in South Korea, NTT in Japan, and O2 in the United Kingdom are rejecting doing business with tools of the Chinese Communist Party’s surveillance state, like Huawei. The big three telecommunications companies in Canada have decided to partner with Ericsson, Nokia, and Samsung, because public opinion was overwhelmingly against allowing Huawei to build Canada’s 5G networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telefónica states in its Digital Manifesto that “security is paramount,” and its CEO and Chairman José María Álvarez-Pallete López recently declared, “Telefónica is proud to be a 5G Clean Path company. Telefónica Spain and O2 (UK) are fully clean networks, and Telefónica Deutschland (Germany) and Vivo (Brazil) will be in the near future without equipment from any untrusted vendors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEO Jun Sawada of Japan’s NTT &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ntt.co.jp/topics_e/safety/index.html#:~:text=Safety%20and%20security%20of%20telecommunication%20services%20NTT%20is,products%20of%20trusted%20vendors%20in%20its%20own%20network&quot;&gt;states&lt;/a&gt;, “The safety and security of our customers and their personal information is our top priority. In this context, the statement by US government regarding 5G Clean Network is consistent with our position. That is why we are glad to be appreciated as a 5G Clean Telecommunications company and are committed to only using trusted vendors in our 5G networks in Japan and as we expand our business around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oracle CEO Safra Catz said, “Oracle shares the vision of secure, trusted and resilient 5G applications and networks.  Grounded in our commitment to develop the most secure telecommunications and infrastructure products and services for our customers, we are proud to support the Clean Path initiative and provide Clean Path solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VMware CEO Pat Gelsinger said, “VMware is pleased to provide support for Clean Path and its intent to create end-to-end 5G infrastructure that is open, secure, programmable, reliable, and software-driven.  Safety and security should be the goal of everybody globally who is serious about building the best and safest possible telecommunications infrastructure for 5G, 6G, and beyond.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tele2 Eesti CEO Christopher Alan Robbins said, “Tele2 Estonia supports open, free-market, global competition while recognizing governments must protect the personal and professional data of their citizens, and Tele2 is committed to do our part. That’s why we’re proud to be a 5G Clean Path partner company and will ensure our telecommunication network is, and will be, free from any hardware or software deemed by the government of Estonia to be a threat to the security of the country and people.”&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-171796&quot; src=&quot;https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanTelcos_v7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanTelcos_v7.jpg 1920w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanTelcos_v7-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanTelcos_v7-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanTelcos_v7-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanTelcos_v7-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanTelcos_v7-85x48.jpg 85w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanTelcos_v7-1698x956.jpg 1698w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/CleanTelcos_v7-1642x924.jpg 1642w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://policy.state.gov/5g/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;LEARN MORE ABOUT 5G SECURITY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sysoleg</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Clean Network - United States Department of State</og:title>
<og:description>Clean Networks is a comprehensive effort by a coalition of like-minded countries and companies to secure their critical telecommunications, Internet, cloud computing, data analytics, and 5G technologies from malign actors by relying on only trusted vendors who are not subject to unjust or extra-judicial control by authoritarian governments, such as the Chinese Communist Party.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.state.gov/5g-clean-network/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/S_5GCleanPath-scaled.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.state.gov/5g-clean-network/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Over 400 vulnerabilities on Qualcomm’s Snapdragon chip</title>
<link>https://blog.checkpoint.com/2020/08/06/achilles-small-chip-big-peril/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.checkpoint.com/2020/08/06/achilles-small-chip-big-peril/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Over 400 vulnerabilities on Qualcomm’s Snapdragon chip threaten mobile phones’ usability worldwide&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/330695/number-of-smartphone-users-worldwide/&quot;&gt;3 billion users globally&lt;/a&gt;, smartphones are an integral, almost inseparable part of our day-to-day lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the mobile market continues to grow, vendors race to provide new features, new capabilities and better technological innovations in their latest devices. To support this relentless drive for innovation, vendors often rely on third parties to provide the required hardware and software for phones. One of the most common third-party solutions is the Digital Signal Processor unit, commonly known as DSP chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this research dubbed “&lt;strong&gt;Achilles&lt;/strong&gt;” we performed an extensive security review of a DSP chip from one of the leading manufacturers: &lt;strong&gt;Qualcomm Technologies.&lt;/strong&gt; Qualcomm provides a wide variety of chips that are embedded into devices that make up over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20200416005583/en/2019-Smartphone-Apps-Processor-Market-Share-Shipments&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;40%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;of the mobile phone market&lt;/strong&gt;, including high-end phones from &lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Samsung&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;LG&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;OnePlus&lt;/strong&gt; and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More &lt;strong&gt;than 400 vulnerable pieces of code were found&lt;/strong&gt; within the DSP chip we tested, and these vulnerabilities could have the following impact on users of phones with the affected chip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attackers can turn the phone into a perfect spying tool, without any user interaction required&lt;/strong&gt; – The information that can be exfiltrated from the phone include photos, videos, call-recording, real-time microphone data, GPS and location data, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attackers may be able to render the mobile phone constantly unresponsive –&lt;/strong&gt; Making all the information stored on this phone permanently unavailable – including photos, videos, contact details, etc – in other words, a targeted denial-of-service attack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malware and other malicious code can completely hide their activities and become un-removable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We disclosed these findings with Qualcomm, who acknowledged them, notified the relevant device vendors and assigned them with the following CVE’s : &lt;strong&gt;CVE-2020-11201, CVE-2020-11202, CVE-2020-11206, CVE-2020-11207, CVE-2020-11208 and CVE-2020-11209.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To learn more about the Achilles vulnerability, how it impacts your organization, and how you can defend against it, we invite you to join our webinar on August 13: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/16731/431234&quot;&gt;AMERICA session&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/16731/431231&quot;&gt;EMEA session&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important note&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check Point Research decided not to publish the full technical details of these vulnerabilities until mobile vendors have a comprehensive solution to mitigate the possible risks described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we decided to publish this blog to raise the awareness to these issues. We have also updated relevant government officials, and relevant mobile vendors we have collaborated with on this research to assist them in making their handsets safer. The full research details were revealed to these stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check Point Research is committed to making technology and products around the world safer and will cooperate with any security vendor that requests for a collaboration. In a proactive move, we have also offered organizations that could have been affected by these risks 20 free SandBlast Mobile licenses for their management mobile devices to protect and prevent any potential damage in the upcoming 6 months from the publication of this research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/16731/431234&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-25781 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/QualcommChip_WEBINAR_blog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is a DSP anyway?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A DSP (Digital Signal Processor) is a system on a chip that has hardware and software designed to optimize and enable each area of use on the device itself, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charging abilities (such as “quick charge” features)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multimedia experiences e.g. video, HD Capture, advanced AR abilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various Audio features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, a DSP is a complete computer on a single chip – and almost any modern phone includes at least one of these chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single SoC (Software on Chip) may include features to enable daily mobile usage such as image processing, computer vision, neural network-related calculations, camera streaming, audio and voice data. Additionally vendors can optionally use these “mini computers” to insert their own functionality that will run as dedicated applications on top of the existing framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A new attack vector&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While DSP chips provide a relatively economical solution that allows mobile phones to provide end users with more functionality and enable innovative features– they do come with a cost. These chips introduce new attack surface and weak points to these mobile devices. DSP chips are much more vulnerable to risks as they are being managed as “Black Boxes” since it can be very complex for anyone other than their manufacturer to review their design, functionality or code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What did we do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check Point Research believes such an ecosystem may be a fertile ground for critical vulnerabilities that might have severe impact on millions of people around the world, and that fixing them requires a long chain of communication between many vendors, manufacturers and resellers. For this reason, we decided to review and perform a deep dive on the security posture of one of the most common chips available today – Qualcomm’s Snapdragon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the “Black Box” nature of the DSP chips it is very challenging for the mobile vendors to fix these issues, as they need to be first addressed by the chip manufacturer. Using our research methodologies and state-of-the-art fuzz testing technologies, we were able to overcome these issues – gaining us with a rare insight into the internals of the tested DSP chip. This allowed us to effectively review the chip’s security controls and identify its weak points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this research will help build a better and more secure environments for the DSP chip ecosystem, as well as provide the necessary knowledge and tools for the security community to preform regular security reviews for these chips in order to strengthen the security of mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about this research watch our presentation at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-safemode/dc-safemode-speakers.html#Makkaveev&quot;&gt;DEFCON&lt;/a&gt; virtual conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly recommend organizations protect their corporate data on their mobile devices by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.checkpoint.com/products/mobile-security/&quot;&gt;mobile security solutions&lt;/a&gt;. SandBlast Mobile provides real-time threat intelligence and visibility into the mobile threats that could affect businesses, and provides complete protection against the risks detailed in this blog, associated with the Quallcomm vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To learn more about the Achilles vulnerability, how it impacts your organization, and how you can defend against it, we invite you to join our webinar on August 13: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/16731/431234&quot;&gt;AMERICA session&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/16731/431231&quot;&gt;EMEA session&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 14:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Flenser</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Achilles: Small chip, big peril. - Check Point Software</og:title>
<og:description>Over 400 vulnerabilities on Qualcomm’s Snapdragon chip threaten mobile phones’ usability worldwide With over 3 billion users globally, smartphones are an</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.checkpoint.com/2020/08/06/achilles-small-chip-big-peril/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/QualcommChip_WEBINAR_blog.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.checkpoint.com/2020/08/06/achilles-small-chip-big-peril/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>G Suite Doesn&amp;#039;t Let You Contact Support Until Logged In. Locked Out = Stuck</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24109809</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24109809</guid>
<description>I know my password for google suite admin (paid), but they have locked me out due to a suspicious login.
&lt;p&gt;Google have locked me out with the following message:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We detected an unusual sign-in attempt. To make sure that someone else isn't trying to access your account, your organization needs you to sign in using your corporate mobile device (the phone or tablet you normally use to access your corporate account).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have your corporate mobile device with you right now, try again later when you have your corporate mobile device with you. If you continue to have problems signing in, contact your administrator. Learn more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go back &amp;amp; use your corporate mobile device&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am unable to get back in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Google support doesn't work if you are logged out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* I have no primary mobile or corporate device to complete the above step on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does Google expect customers to do here?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 14:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>HelloThur</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24109809</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What&amp;#039;s it like to be an Octopus? (2017)</title>
<link>https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v39/n17/amia-srinivasan/the-sucker-the-sucker</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v39/n17/amia-srinivasan/the-sucker-the-sucker</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcaps dropcap--i&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;smallcapslede smallcapslede-spaced&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;​ 1815, 15 years before he made his most famous print, &lt;em class=&quot;emphasisClass&quot;&gt;The Great Wave&lt;/em&gt;, Hokusai published three volumes of erotic art. In one of them there is a woodcut print known in English as ‘The Dream of the Fisherman’s Wife’ and in Japanese as ‘&lt;em class=&quot;emphasisClass&quot;&gt;Tako to ama’&lt;/em&gt;, ‘Octopus and Shell Diver’. It depicts a naked woman lying on her back, legs spread and eyes closed, while a huge red octopus performs cunnilingus on her. The octopus’s slit eyes bulge between the woman’s legs and its suckered limbs wrap around her writhing body. A second, smaller octopus inserts its beak into the woman’s mouth while curling the thin tip of an arm around her left nipple. In Europe, the print was interpreted as a scene of rape, but the critics didn’t read Japanese. In the text arranged in the space around the three entwined bodies, the shell diver exclaims: ‘You hateful octopus! Your sucking at the mouth of my womb makes me gasp for breath! Ah! Yes … it’s … there! With the sucker, the sucker! … There, there! … Until now it was I that men called an octopus! An octopus! … How are you able? … Oh! Boundaries and borders gone! I’ve vanished!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; ez-embed-type-o,age&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embedded_image_wrapper embedded_image_wrapper--captioned original-size&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lrb-imageHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v39/n17/amia-srinivasan/the-sucker-the-sucker&quot; data-appsrc=&quot;/var/site/storage/images/2/0/8/8/5778802-1-eng-GB/srin01_3917_01.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://www.lrb.co.uk/media/cache/tiniest_filter/var/site/storage/images/2/0/8/8/5778802-1-eng-GB/srin01_3917_01.jpg 220w, https://www.lrb.co.uk/media/cache/tiny_filter/var/site/storage/images/2/0/8/8/5778802-1-eng-GB/srin01_3917_01.jpg 400w, https://www.lrb.co.uk/media/cache/small_filter/var/site/storage/images/2/0/8/8/5778802-1-eng-GB/srin01_3917_01.jpg 800w, https://www.lrb.co.uk/media/cache/medium_filter/var/site/storage/images/2/0/8/8/5778802-1-eng-GB/srin01_3917_01.jpg 1200w, https://www.lrb.co.uk/media/cache/largest_filter/var/site/storage/images/2/0/8/8/5778802-1-eng-GB/srin01_3917_01.jpg 2000w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; class=&quot;lazyload lazypreload embedded-image&quot; alt=&quot;A Giant Pacific octopus&quot; draggable=&quot;false&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embedded-image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ezrichtext-field&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Giant Pacific octopus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The octopus threatens boundaries. Its body, a boneless mass of soft tissue, has no fixed shape. Even large octopuses – the largest species, the Giant Pacific, has an arm span of more than six metres and weighs a hundred pounds – can fit through an opening an inch wide, or about the size of its eye. This, combined with their considerable strength – a mature male Giant Pacific can lift thirty pounds with each of its 1600 suckers – means that octopuses are difficult to keep in captivity. Many octopuses have escaped their aquarium tanks through small holes; some have been known to lift the lid of their tank, making their way, sometimes across stretches of dry floor, to a neighbouring tank for a snack, or to the nearest drain, and maybe from there back home to the sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Octopuses do not have any stable colour or texture, changing at will to match their surroundings: a camouflaged octopus can be invisible from just a few feet away. Like humans, they have centralised nervous systems, but in their case there is no clear distinction between brain and body. An octopus’s neurons are dispersed throughout its body, and two-thirds of them are in its arms: each arm can act intelligently on its own, grasping, manipulating and hunting. (Octopuses have arms, not tentacles: tentacles have suckers only at their tips. Squid and cuttlefish have a combination of arms and tentacles.) In evolutionary terms, the intelligence of octopuses is an anomaly. The last common ancestor between octopuses on the one hand, and humans and other intelligent animals (monkeys, dolphins, dogs, crows) on the other, was probably a primitive, blind worm-like creature that existed six hundred million years ago. Other creatures that are so evolutionarily distant from humans – lobsters, snails, slugs, clams – rate pretty low on the cognitive scale. But octopuses – and to some extent their cephalopod cousins, cuttlefish and squid – frustrate the neat evolutionary division between clever vertebrates and simple-minded invertebrates. They are sophisticated problem solvers; they learn, and can use tools; and they show a capacity for mimicry, deception and, some think, humour. Just how refined their abilities are is a matter of scientific debate: their very strangeness makes octopuses hard to study. Their intelligence is like ours, and utterly unlike ours. Octopuses are the closest we can come, on earth, to knowing what it might be like to encounter intelligent aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Godfrey-Smith is a philosopher and diver who has been studying octopuses and other cephalopods in the wild, mostly off the coast of his native Sydney, for years. The alienness of octopuses, in his view, provides an opportunity to reflect on the nature of cognition and consciousness without simply projecting from the human example. Because of their evolutionary distance from us, octopuses are an ‘independent experiment in the evolution of large brains and complex behaviour’. Insofar as we are able to make intelligent contact with them – to understand octopuses and have them understand us – it is ‘not because of a shared history, not because of kinship, but because evolution built minds twice over’. The potential worry is that the evolutionary chasm between us and the octopus is too great to make mutual intelligibility possible. In that case the octopus will have something to teach us about the limits of our own understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An octopus is an eight-armed, soft-bodied mollusc. Its arms are covered in suckers and arranged radially around a sharp-beaked mouth. It eats by catching prey with one of its arms and moving it through a conveyer belt of undulating suckers to its mouth – in that sense an octopus’s arms can also be thought of as its lips. On top of its arms rests its head, which contains its brain and features two large eyes with horizontal, dash-shaped pupils, like a cat’s eyes turned on their side. Behind the head is the octopus’s mantle, a large bulbous structure that contains its vital organs, including three hearts which pump blue-green blood. A tubular siphon is attached to the mantle, which the octopus uses variously for jet propulsion, respiration, excretion and inking predators. A full-grown octopus can range in size from the Giant Pacific, with its six-metre arm span, to the 2.5 centimetre-long &lt;em class=&quot;emphasisClass&quot;&gt;Octopus wolfi&lt;/em&gt;, which weighs less than a gram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linnaeus called the octopus &lt;em class=&quot;emphasisClass&quot;&gt;singulare monstrum&lt;/em&gt;, ‘a unique monster’. Erik Pontoppidan, bishop of Bergen, in his &lt;em class=&quot;emphasisClass&quot;&gt;Natural History of Norway&lt;/em&gt; (1752), wrote about the Kraken, a giant octopus-like sea monster capable of dragging down ‘the largest man of war’ in its arms, or sucking it down in the whirlpool of its wake. A similar creature, the Akkorokamui, with huge eyes and the ability to amputate and regenerate its limbs, features in Ainu folklore, and is worshipped in Shinto shrines throughout Japan. Victor Hugo’s &lt;em class=&quot;emphasisClass&quot;&gt;Toilers of the Sea&lt;/em&gt; includes a long description of the octopus or ‘devil-fish’:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;leftranged&quot;&gt;If terror were the object of … creation, nothing could be imagined more perfect than the devil-fish … This irregular mass advances slowly towards you. Suddenly it opens, and eight radii issue abruptly from around a face with two eyes. These radii are alive: their undulation is like lambent flames … A terrible expansion! … Its folds strangle, its contact paralyses. It has an aspect like gangrened or scabrous flesh. It is a monstrous embodiment of disease … Underneath each of [its] feelers range two rows of pustules, decreasing in size … They are cartilaginous substances, cylindrical, horny and livid … A glutinous mass, endowed with a malignant will, what can be more horrible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Octopuses are indeed glutinous; according to Sy Montgomery, author of the splendid &lt;em class=&quot;emphasisClass&quot;&gt;Soul of an Octopus&lt;/em&gt;, the slime on an octopus’s skin feels like a cross between drool and snot. But the octopus’s will is far from malignant, at least when it comes to humans. Octopuses do occasionally attack people, giving a venomous nip or stealing an underwater camera when threatened or annoyed, but in general they are gentle, inquisitive creatures. (Fishermen, by contrast, often kill octopuses by biting out their brains, and in many countries they are eaten alive.) Octopuses encountering divers in the wild will frequently meet them with a probing arm or two, and sometimes lead them by the hand on a tour of the neighbourhood. Aristotle, mistaking curiosity for a lack of intelligence, called the octopus a ‘stupid creature’ because of its willingness to approach an extended human hand. Octopuses can recognise individual humans, and will respond differently to different people, greeting some with a caress of the arms, spraying others with their siphons. This is striking behaviour in an animal whose natural life cycle is deeply antisocial. Octopuses live solitary lives in single dens and die soon after their young hatch. Many male octopuses, to avoid being eaten during mating, will keep their bodies as far removed from the female as possible, extending a single arm with a sperm packet towards her siphon, a manoeuvre known as ‘the reach’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just how clever are octopuses? An octopus has half a billion neurons, about as many as a dog. (A human has a hundred billion neurons.) Octopuses also have a high ratio of brain to body size, a sign of the ‘investment’ the animal makes in its own cognition. But these metrics are only a very rough guide to animal intelligence; the number and complexity of synaptic connections between neurons are also a factor. (Crows and parrots have small brains, but have recently been shown to be highly intelligent.) And the brain-to-body ratio does not take into account the majority of the octopus’s neurons that exist outside its brain. What’s more, the octopus’s brain has a structure completely distinct from that of our own. Even birds and fish have brains which exhibit a one-to-one correspondence with parts of the human brain. But the octopus’s brain is built on a different model entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since a comparison with the human brain tells us so little, scientists turn to the octopus’s behaviour as the best indicator of its cognitive power. But here researchers are often frustrated by what Godfrey-Smith describes as a ‘mismatch’ between anecdotal reports and experimental studies. In the lab, octopuses do fairly well: they can navigate mazes, use memory to solve simple puzzles and unscrew jars and child-proof bottles to get food (octopuses have also been filmed opening jam jars from the inside). Yet it can take octopuses a surprisingly long time to be trained in new behaviours, which some researchers have taken as a sign of their cognitive limitations. Much of the early work on octopus intelligence was done at the Naples Zoological Station. In 1959, Peter Dews, a Harvard scientist, trained three octopuses there to pull a lever to obtain a chunk of sardine. Two of the octopuses, Albert and Bertram, pulled the lever in a ‘reasonably consistent’ manner. But the third, Charles, would anchor his arms on the side of the tank and apply great force to the lever, eventually breaking it and bringing the experiment to a premature end. Dews also reported that Charles repeatedly pulled a lamp into his tank, and that he ‘had a high tendency to direct jets of water out of the tank; specifically … in the direction of the experimenter’. ‘This behaviour,’ Dews wrote, ‘interfered materially with the smooth conduct of the experiments, and is … clearly incompatible with lever-pulling.’ He concluded that his experiment was a partial failure. Godfrey-Smith says this ‘encapsulates much of the story with octopus behaviour’. Octopuses have a high curiosity drive, and a knack for repurposing things around them for their own ends. Perhaps there are tasks that octopuses find it hard to learn. Or perhaps they just have better things to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captive octopuses appear to be aware of their captivity; they adapt to it but also resist it. When they try to escape, which is often, they tend to wait for a moment they aren’t being watched. Octopuses have flooded laboratories by deliberately plugging valves in their tanks with their arms. At the University of Otago, an octopus short-circuited the electricity supply – by shooting jets of water at the aquarium lightbulbs – so often that it had to be released back into the wild. Jean Boal, a cephalopod researcher at Millersville University in Pennsylvania, reported feeding octopuses in a row of tanks with thawed squid, not an octopus’s favourite food. Returning to the first tank, Boal found that the octopus in it hadn’t eaten the squid, but was instead holding it out in its arm; watching Boal, it slowly made its way across the tank and shoved the squid down the drain. (The third-century Roman rhetorician Claudius Aelianus, a more sympathetic observer than Aristotle, identified the octopus’s main characteristic as ‘mischief and craft’.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it feel like to be an octopus? Does it feel like anything at all? Or are octopuses, as Godfrey-Smith puts it, ‘just biochemical machines for which all is dark inside’? This form of question – ‘what is it like to be a bat?’ Thomas Nagel asked in a hugely influential paper in 1974 – is philosophical shorthand for asking whether a creature is conscious. Many philosophers think consciousness is an all or nothing phenomenon: you either have it or you don’t. Humans have it, as do perhaps chimps and dolphins. Mice, ants and amoebas presumably do not. Part of the motivation for the all or nothing view is that it is difficult to imagine consciousness being possessed in degrees. Other cognitive attributes – like memory, linguistic capacity and problem-solving ability – are the sorts of thing that can and do vary in degree from creature to creature, and species to species. But it is harder to see how consciousness can vary in that way. As Godfrey-Smith puts it, ‘how can an animal be halfway to having it feel like something to be that animal?’ Yet, if consciousness is a natural thing, something that evolved over time, it seems unlikely that it just popped up at some point in evolutionary history, fully formed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godfrey-Smith starts with the conviction that consciousness is an evolved thing, and accepts the conclusion that it has more primitive precursors: that it comes in degrees after all. Consciousness – the possession of an ‘inner’ model of the ‘outer’ world, or the sense of having an integrated, subjective perspective on the world – is, on his view, just a highly evolved form of what he calls ‘subjective experience’. Many animals, Godfrey-Smith thinks, have some degree of subjective experience, even if it falls short of full-blown consciousness. He points to what the physiologist Derek Denton called the ‘primordial emotions’: thirst, lack of air, physical pain. These sensations intrude on our more complex mental processes, refusing to be dismissed. They hark back to a more rudimentary form of experiencing the world – a form, Godfrey-Smith thinks, that does not require a sophisticated inner model of the world. ‘Do you think,’ he asks, that pain, thirst or shortness of breath ‘&lt;em class=&quot;emphasisClass&quot;&gt;only feel like something&lt;/em&gt; because of sophisticated cognitive processing in mammals that has arisen late in evolution? I doubt it.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of animal pain underscores Godfrey-Smith’s point. Simple animals respond to physical harm with what appears to be distress, and there is experimental evidence that suggests that they feel pain, that physical harm feels bad for them. Zebrafish, injected with what is assumed to be a painful chemical, will prefer an otherwise less desirable environment if a painkiller is dissolved in the water. Similarly, chickens with leg injuries will choose a feed they don’t normally favour if it is laced with a painkiller. Insects do not appear to feel pain, carrying on as usual even after major injuries. But shrimp and crabs groom their injured parts, and do so less when they are given an anaesthetic. None of this is dispositive evidence that animals feel pain – but then it isn’t clear what would be. As Godfrey-Smith puts it, ‘you can still doubt that these animals feel anything, yes. But you can doubt that about your next-door neighbour.’ If even simple animals have rudimentary forms of consciousness or subjective experience, what might that feel like? What does it feel like to be an injured crab? Here Godfrey-Smith reaches for a metaphor proposed by the evolutionary theorists Simona Ginsburg and Eva Jablonka: white noise. Primitive consciousness, he writes, might be like ‘a crackle of metabolic electricity’, an ‘inchoate buzz’ that grows, with evolutionary time, in complexity and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If consciousness comes in degrees, then where on the spectrum is the octopus? Octopuses almost certainly feel pain. They nurse and protect injured body parts, and don’t like to be touched near wounds. (Until recently, researchers operated on octopuses without anaesthetic, and much early work on them involved electric shocks. A 2010 EU directive on animal testing classifies cephalopods together with vertebrates because of their ‘ability to experience pain, suffering, distress and lasting harm’.) As well as feeling pain, octopuses have sophisticated sensory capacities: excellent eyesight, and acute senses of taste and smell. This, together with their large nervous systems and complex behaviour, makes it all but certain, in Godfrey-Smith’s view, that octopuses have rich subjective experience. But they may have even more than this. According to some theorists, notably Stanislas Dehaene, a particular kind of mental processing, the sort that involves completing novel tasks extended over time, not only goes hand in hand with human consciousness, but helps explain why humans are conscious. The octopus’s curiosity and adaptability to novel circumstances are, Godfrey-Smith suggests, ‘reminiscent’ of these paradigmatically human forms of cognition. If so, then being an octopus might be more like being a human than we have tended to think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of what subjective experience might be like for an octopus is complicated by the odd relationship between its brain and its body. An octopus’s arms have more neurons than its brain, about ten thousand neurons per sucker; the arms can taste and smell, and exhibit short-term memory. Each arm acts with considerable independence from the brain; even a surgically detached arm can reach and grasp, avoid painful stimuli, and change colour. (In &lt;em class=&quot;emphasisClass&quot;&gt;The Soul of an Octopus&lt;/em&gt;, Montgomery imagines an octopus testing human intelligence by seeing how many colour patterns our severed arms can produce in one second.) Yet an octopus’s brain can exert executive control, ‘pulling itself together’ when it needs to, for example when an octopus puts out only a single inquisitive arm to inspect a stranger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godfrey-Smith suggests that the octopus is, phenomenologically speaking, in a hybrid situation: its arms are partly self, and partly other. Because of this, the octopus is sometimes held up as a mascot for the ‘embodied cognition’ movement in psychology, according to which the physical body, by constraining and making possible certain actions, is itself ‘intelligent’. The human ability to walk, for example, is not simply a matter of top-down brain control, but also a function of the angles of our joints; in this sense, our bodies encode information vital for intelligent action. There can be little doubt that an octopus’s embodiment is radically different from our own, and that understanding an octopus’s mind requires us to grasp its particular form of embodiment. But thinking about the octopus in terms of embodied cognition may undersell its strangeness. While it makes sense to think of our own bodies in terms of the constraints and opportunities they afford, the octopus’s body, as Godfrey-Smith says, is ‘protean, all possibility’. Even asking how much the body contributes to intelligent action presupposes a division between brain and body that seems not to apply to the octopus. The octopus’s body is pervaded by nervousness: it is not a thing controlled by the animal’s thinking part, but itself a thinking thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A further oddity in thinking about octopus experience has to do with the creature’s relationship to colour. An octopus’s skin is a layered screen of pixel-like sacs of colour called chromatophores, which make it possible for an octopus to change its colour at will to match its surroundings or threaten an aggressor. The so-called mimic octopus can impersonate more than 15 different animals, including flounder, lionfish and sea snakes, by changing its colour and shape. An octopus’s colour also seems to indicate its mood – some octopuses turn white after being caressed for a long time by humans, as well as after mating. The chromatic displays produced by octopuses can include elaborate patterns of stripes and spots, flashing rings and waves of rippling colour. Yet octopuses – like most cephalopods – appear to be colour-blind. Their eyes lack the variety of photoreceptors required to see colour, and octopuses are unable to distinguish between differently coloured objects in experimental tests. Researchers have recently discovered that octopuses have photoreceptors not only in their eyes but also in their skin, which suggests that the skin can see (as well as taste and smell), either by sending the visual information it receives to the octopus’s brain, or by processing the information itself. Both options are weird: either the skin as a whole becomes an eye, or the octopus’s body sees independently of the octopus’s brain. Even this isn’t the whole story, since the photoreceptors found in an octopus’s skin are, like those in its eyes, insufficient to detect colour. The best working hypothesis is that some complex interaction between the skin’s photoreceptors and chromatophores allows the octopus to adopt colours it cannot see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Octopuses use their colour displays mainly for camouflage and signalling. But sometimes they produce elaborate colour displays for no apparent reason, in the absence of predators or other octopuses. Godfrey-Smith calls such purposeless displays ‘chromatic chatter’, suggesting they may just be an involuntary, metabolic effect. Could they be more intentionally expressive? Do octopuses talk to themselves? The problem with this thought is that octopuses appear not to have any language at all, and so presumably can no more talk to themselves than to others. (Wittgenstein famously argued for the conceptual impossibility of a ‘purely private language’, meaningful only to one person. Whether or not a private language is conceptually possible, it is evolutionarily unlikely, since the ability to talk to oneself appears to be a later internalisation of the ability to talk to others.) The megapixel screen of the octopus’s body means that theoretically it could telegraph information of almost infinite complexity – the sort of expressive bandwidth of which a chimp or baboon can only dream. Yet most of the chromatic signals produced by an octopus appear not to have any consistent effect on other octopuses, suggesting that they are signs without meaning, words with no sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most species of octopus live for only a year or two; the Giant Pacific, the species that lives longest, dies after four years at most. Both female and male octopuses mate only once, and enter a swift and sudden decline into senescence soon after, developing white lesions on their skin, losing interest in food, and becoming unco-ordinated and confused. The females die from starvation while they tend their eggs, and the males are typically preyed on as they wander the ocean aimlessly. Most highly intelligent animals live significantly longer than octopuses, as do some other molluscs. Why is the octopus’s life so short? Ageing in general is explained by evolutionary theorists in terms of what is known as the Medawar effect: natural selection tends to weed out mutations whose harmful effects appear early in an animal’s life, but it is less likely to weed out mutations whose harmful effects manifest later on. This is because most animals succumb to death by predation, disease or accident before they reach the age where late-acting mutations could take effect. Late-acting mutations therefore accumulate in animal populations, eventually producing the appearance of a preprogrammed lifespan. In the octopus, the Medawar effect, coupled with an unusual body plan, has resulted in its uncommonly short lifespan. In its early evolutionary history, the octopus gave up its protective, molluscan shell in order to embrace a life of unboundaried potential. But the cost was an increased vulnerability to toothy and bony predators. An animal with a soft body and no shell cannot expect to live long, and so harmful mutations that take effect only once it has been alive for a couple of years will soon spread through the population. The result is a life that is experientially rich but conspicuously brief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcaps dropcap--e&quot;&gt;E&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;smallcapslede smallcapslede-spaced&quot;&gt;arlier&lt;/span&gt;​ this summer, on a drive from San Francisco to Los Angeles, I went to see the octopuses at Monterey Bay Aquarium. At the time Monterey’s permanent octopus exhibit housed two Giant Pacifics, though there were more octopuses in its temporary show &lt;em class=&quot;emphasisClass&quot;&gt;Tentacles&lt;/em&gt;, the largest ever exhibition of cephalopods. This was my second encounter with a live octopus. (I have had more encounters with dead octopuses at the dinner table than I care to recall. They make excellent carpaccio. Never again.) The first was off a beach in Mykonos, where I was snorkelling. There wasn’t much on the sea floor, just small crustaceans and darting silver fish, until I saw a red mass a few feet away, about the size of a cat, watching me with a single eye. I stayed still, watching it back. The octopus made small, unhurried movements, curling and uncurling its arms, snuffling along the floor. Eventually it crawled to a sunken rope some feet away and wrapped itself around it. Its body became a brown, barnacled coil, and then there was only a single white eye with a black dash of pupil. The eye closed, and the octopus vanished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Monterey the two Giant Pacifics were in adjacent tanks, each a few metres wide. The first octopus was energetic, unfurling its huge body and then compressing it, uncoiling its arms and pushing its suckers against the tank walls, boiling and jetting its way back and forth through the water. Tourists took flash photographs despite the sign warning that octopuses dislike bright lights. Children expressed admiration and disgust. When you’re looking at an octopus, your attention is naturally drawn to its rows of suckers, coiling arms and bulging body. Its eyes look sleepy, half-closed. You have to know what you’re looking for to see that they are open, and staring straight at you. I looked the octopus in the eyes and found it looking back at me, fixedly, as its body ballooned and hollowed behind it. The second octopus was quieter, bundled up at the top of her tank. A few thin strands of translucent, pearl-shaped eggs – laid and then painstakingly braided together with the thin tips of her arms – hung nearby, remnants of the clutch that had been removed by the aquarium keepers. Her skin was dull and white. She was dying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logic of aquariums, as with zoos, is the logic of conservation: individual animals must sacrifice their freedom so that the species as a whole can be protected. (As the philosopher Robert Nozick put it, ‘utilitarianism for animals, Kantianism for humans.’) The conservationist logic is at its most compelling at an aquarium like Monterey, with its state of the art research centre, environmental policy unit, and public education programmes. Plenty of its creatures seem delighted to be there, as far as one can tell, and others seem perfectly unaware of where they are. No doubt many of these animals live longer and healthier lives than they would in the ocean. Yet ethical questions remain, raised by creatures, like the octopus, which so clearly yearn for freedom. Perhaps from our perspective the life of a wild octopus is already a tragic thing: sociality without society, speaking without being heard, a life-world without longevity. An alien. If only the octopus were more like us, we might be better at leaving it alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 14:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>samgilb</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amia Srinivasan · The Sucker, the Sucker! What’s it like to be an octopus? · LRB 6 September 2017</og:title>
<og:description>Their intelligence is like ours, and utterly unlike ours. Octopuses are the closest we can come, on earth, to knowing...</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v39/n17/amia-srinivasan/the-sucker-the-sucker</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.lrb.co.uk/media/cache/social_image_on_bg/var/site/storage/images/3/3/8/8/6158833-1-eng-GB/LRB-3917-01.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v39/n17/amia-srinivasan/the-sucker-the-sucker</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>C will never stop you from making mistakes</title>
<link>https://thephd.github.io/your-c-compiler-and-standard-library-will-not-help-you</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thephd.github.io/your-c-compiler-and-standard-library-will-not-help-you</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Short answer: because we said so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;:)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, fine, that’s too short to make it an article, dear reader, and my inflammatory words demand an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The C Committee meeting – originally scheduled for Freiburg, Germany but not happening there because &lt;em&gt;(* vague gesturing towards outside *)&lt;/em&gt; – concluded Friday, August 7th. It went pretty well, with us making good progress on all fronts. Yes, we make real progress; I promise we do, and this is not a dead language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side note I’ve also become the Project Editor for C so before you take this as an uninformed rant of a person too lazy to “make things better”, let me assure that I am, indeed, incredibly invested in making sure C can begin to meet the needs of developers without needing 50 vendor-specific extensions to build remotely nice/usable libraries and applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I made a claim (the C Language will never stop you from making mistakes), and therefore I need to substantiate it. We could look at the thousands of CVEs and the inherent issues with tons of C Code, or the need for MISRA to vigorously police every last little potential C feature to prevent misuse (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thephantomderp/status/1290824683399663616&quot;&gt;hello, K&amp;amp;R prototype declarations&lt;/a&gt;…), or other more intricate and fun bugs related to portability and undefined behavior. But instead, we are just going to take the words from the horse’s mouth: the Committee itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, dear reader, put the popcorn away. As with all ISO proceedings, I am not allowed to quote anyone verbatim, and this is not a name-and-shame article. It will, however, explain why things that we can easily diagnose and identify as bad behavior in standards-conforming ISO C will never go away. And we will start with a paper by Dr. Philipp Klaus Krause:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg14/www/docs/n2526.htm&quot;&gt;N2526, use const for data from the library that shall not be modified&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N2526 is a very simple paper. “Some data returned by the library is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;const&lt;/code&gt; morally, spiritually, and in fact even by its implementation. It’s undefined behavior and wrong to write into it, so let’s stop teasing each other about it and put a ring on that finger bad boy!” … Okay, that’s not exactly what it says, but I’m sure the idea makes sense to you, dear reader. Originally, when the vote for this paper was taken, there was almost no votes against the paper. Then, a few people voiced their &lt;em&gt;strong&lt;/em&gt; objections to the paper because it breaks old code. And, well, of course that’s bad: even my breath caught and I strained to think about this – adding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;const&lt;/code&gt;? C has no ABI that could be affected by this, C (their implementations) doesn’t even respect qualifiers, how are we breaking things?! So, let’s talk about why this would be a breaking change in the eyes of certain folk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, as I like to call it, “The Type Safety Is For Losers Language”. Of course, that’s a mouthful, so “C” will have to do. You may be wondering why I would call a language like C as having no type safety. After all,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-c highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Meow&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Bark&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;double&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[])&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Meow&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Bark&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dog&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// error: initializing 'struct Bark' with an expression of incompatible type 'struct Meow'&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, let’s be honest: that looks like strong type safety to me, Jim! Of course, it only gets spicier from here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-c highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;#include &amp;lt;stdlib.h&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Meow&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Bark&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;double&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[])&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Meow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p_cat&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Meow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;malloc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;sizeof&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Meow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Bark&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p_dog&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p_cat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// :3&lt;/span&gt;
        
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f̵̞͟͞o̷r̰͇͎̞ ̡̝͍͍̥̗̖͖̲̮i͕͔̭̹̪̳͙͍̩ͅ ̷͖̙͈̗̯̙͓̲̻̩̱͖̺a̧̪̳̠̰̱͎̖̙̳̱͎̯̦̟͟m̶͓͔͉̺̩̙̖̞̼͈̖͇͇͇ ͇̘̬͕̯̕͢d͚o̢̳̱̙͠ͅg̴̨̦̬̥͓̯̩͞,̷̬͕͖͎̺͈̰̳̮͓̞ ͚d͎̀̕͢es̵̱͙̪͓͖͇̩̳̻͉͉̹̣͈͜͝t͖͈͉̩̭̙̺̬r̤̟̫͔̩̰̗̤͔̭̰̞̦̺ͅo̝̹̻ͅy̸͎͎͚̖̤̣̥̭̼̳͎e̘̟̰̣̫̹͇͍̦͓ͅr̙̙̳̠͔̙̖̯̺ͅ ̸̜̫̫̩̫̝͎̩̠̦̭̠̟o҉̛͢f̫̝͇ ҉̣̞̟a̪̲͎͇̣̠͖͖̮̥ͅl̷̛͈̦̰̜͍̲̟̬̘̝͕̰̮͠l̮̯̘͉̦͔̘̲̰̤͔̬̲͔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, two entirely unrelated pointer types can be set to one another in standards-conforming C. Most compilers warn, but it is standards-conforming to accept this code unless you crank up the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-Werror&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-Wall&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-Wpedantic&lt;/code&gt; etc. etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, other pointer-related things the compiler can accept without an explicit cast are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;volatile&lt;/code&gt; (who needs those semantics anyways?!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;const&lt;/code&gt; (write into all the read-only data you like!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_Atomic&lt;/code&gt; (thread safety, shred shmafety!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, note I am not arguing that you should not be able to do these things at all. But when you’re working in C – wherein it is very easy to get yourself a 500, 1000-line function alongside variable names that do not describe WTF they are for – the Hard Facts™ is that you work primarily with pointers, and you lack any amount of safety at all insofar as the Core Language cares. (NOTE: It &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; a constraint violation, but there’s so much legacy code that every implementation ignores qualifiers anyhow, so your code won’t ever &lt;em&gt;stop&lt;/em&gt; compiling because of this (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fanf/status/1292826424345337868&quot;&gt;thanks, @fanf!&lt;/a&gt;)!) Every potential failure here is diagnosable – easily so – with a compiler, and they all warn, but they will never require you to cast to communicate to the compiler that you Seriously, Really Meant It. It also means – much more importantly – that the human beings who come after you will have no bloody idea if you meant to do this, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All someone has to do is strip the build of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-Werror&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-Wall&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-Wpedantic&lt;/code&gt; and you’ll be off to the races in committing multithreading, read-only, and hardware register crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this is fair, right? If someone strips off all of these warning/error flags, they obviously do not care about whatever faux pas or silly gaffe you’ve committed. Which means that, at the end of the day, these warnings are ultimately irrelevant and harmless as far as standards-conforming, ISO C is concerned. And yet…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a special kind of hell that C developers have grown comfortable with, and to a lesser extent C++ developers. Warnings are seen as annoyances; and, as is shown by ever turning on &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-Weverything&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/W4&lt;/code&gt;, they very well are. Shadowing warnings from variables in the global namespace (thanks, every header and C library ever is now a problem), using “reserved” names (as the kids say, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://wg14.link/n2493&quot;&gt;lol nice one xd!!&lt;/a&gt;”), and “this struct has padding because you used &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;alignof&lt;/code&gt;” (… yes, yes I know it has padding, I explicitly asked it to increase my padding BECAUSE I USED &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;alignof&lt;/code&gt; MR. COMPILER) are all incredibly time-wasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But they are warnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if they are annoying, they prevent problems. The fact that I can blithely &lt;a href=&quot;https://godbolt.org/z/rEbPvd&quot;&gt;ignore all qualifiers and dumpster all forms of read, write, thread, and read-only safety&lt;/a&gt; is a serious issue when it comes to communicating intent and preventing bugs. Even the old K&amp;amp;R syntax produced bugs in industrial and government codebases because users did the wrong thing. This is not because they are shit programmers: it’s because they are straddling codebases sometimes older than they are and gearing up to ride on a multi-million line technical liability. You cannot keep the entirety of the codebase in your head: this is what conventions, static analysis, high warning levels, and everything are supposed to combat. Unfortunately,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;everyone likes to have Warning Free code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that the moment a GCC developer makes a warning more sensitive to potential problematic cases, maintainers (not the original developers) will suddenly get hefty several-gigabyte logs containing all the newest vomit of warnings and other things from their old code. “This is stupid”, they say, “the code has been running for Y E A R S, why is GCC complaining now?”. This means that even doing something like adding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;const&lt;/code&gt; to a function signature, even if it is morally, spiritually, and factually the right thing to do, is avoided. “Breaking” people is “they now have to look at code which has questionable intentions”. This is code that would – on pain of Undefined Behavior – crash your chip or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MalwareMinigun/status/1260061878614556684&quot;&gt;corrupt your memory&lt;/a&gt;. But that’s the other problem with being a C developer in today’s ecosystem, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;age-as-a-measure-of-quality&quot;&gt;Age as a Measure of Quality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many people would have ever guessed &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; had a vulnerability as jaw-droppingly simple as “-1 or integer overflow gives you access to everything”? How many people thought Heartbleed would be a real problem? How many game developers are shipping stb’s “tiny” libraries without ever having run a fuzzer on them and realizing they contain more significant exploitable input vulnerabilities than they could imagine? This is not a dig at any of these pieces of code or the programmers behind them: they are providing a vital service that the world has depended on for decades, often with little to no support from anyone until a big problem exploded. But, the people worshipping and deploying these pieces of code end up fermenting a toxic adage under the auspice of survivorship bias:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This code is so old and used by so many, how could it possibly have problems?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By holding backwards compatibility and “not being a bother” as the highest ideals for C code, people who survive long enough in the industry begin to equate age with quality, as if codebases were barrels of wine in a cellar. The older and longer the code is used, the finer and more delectable the wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality is, unfortunately, far less romantic and cute: crawling with more bugs than you can shake a stick at, security vulnerabilities by the basketful, these technical liabilities only grow more risky with each passing day. Each system evolves into a half-alive, unaddressed, and partially-unmaintained rotting husk. They are gussied up and given the veneer of nobility and greatness when it is in fact an embalmed corpse, just waiting to be poked the wrong way before its festering, antediluvian pustules burst and fill your application with its finely aged botulism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;okay-gross-but-like-what-about-the-c-standard&quot;&gt;Okay… Gross, but like what about the C Standard?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem I have noticed in my (incredibly short) tenure as a member is that we prefer backwards compatibility over all else, attributing old applications and their use cases over any chance at improving the safety, security, or craftsmanship of the C code for those who are moving to C, even today. Dr. Krause’s paper is so small as to be almost inconsequentially uncontroversial: if someone does not like the warnings, they can shut them off. They are warnings, not errors, for a reason: no diagnostic is &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt; by the C abstract machine, ISO C allows that this code is accepted under the strictest build modes, and it would help the rest of the world to wean themselves off of APIs that clearly state “modifying the contents of what we hand back to you is undefined behavior”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, we turned our opinion for the paper over anyways after “we cannot introduce new warnings” was brought up as a reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The argument against was essentially “there is so much code that will break if we change these signatures”. This, again, frames a change in warnings as a break in behavior (remember, implicit conversions that remove qualifiers – even &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_Atomic&lt;/code&gt; – are perfectly valid ISO C even if it is a constraint violation). Were this the case, every compiler developer would have to introduce something similar to Rust’s Epochs, But Just For Warnings to give people a “stable” set to always test against. This is not exactly a new sentiment: I have read papers from some of Coverity’s own engineers about their handling of producing new warnings and the customer response to them. Managing “developer confidence” in new warnings and other things is tough work. It takes a long time to bootstrap developers on its usefulness. Even John Carmack took some time to get a proper set of warnings and errors suitable for his development out of his static analysis tools, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/128836/InDepth_Static_Code_Analysis.php&quot;&gt;before concluding that “&lt;strong&gt;it is irresponsible to not use it&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, as a Committee, we struggle with adding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;const&lt;/code&gt; to 4 function return values because it would add warnings to potentially dangerous code. We raised objections to deprecating the old K&amp;amp;R syntax despite tangible evidence of both innocent screw ups and also tangible vulnerabilities from developers passing in the wrong types. We &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; added undefined behavior to the preprocessor, just to bend over backwards and make a bespoke C implementation “do the right thing”. We are always teetering on the edge of doing the objectively wrong thing for backwards compatibility reasons. And this, dear reader, is what scares me the most about the future of C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake: no matter what programmers tell you or what people whisper in your ear, the behavior of C’s governing body is very clear. We will not introduce warnings into your old code, even if that old code could be doing something dangerous. We will not steer you away from mistakes, because that could shake the veneer that what your old code does is, in fact, wrong. We will not make it easier for new programmers to write better C code. We will not demand that your old code is held to any Standard. Every new feature we add we will make optional, because we cannot possibly imagine holding compiler writers to a higher standard nor expect more out of our Standard Library vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will let the compiler lie to you. We will lie to your code. And when things do go bad – a mistake, an “oopsie kapoopsie”, a leak of data – we will shake our heads solemnly. We will offer our thoughts and prayers and say “well, that’s a shame”. A shame, indeed…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe we’ll fix it another day, dear reader. 💚&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 11:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why the C Language Will Never Stop You from Making Mistakes</og:title>
<og:description>Short answer: because we said so.</og:description>
<og:url>https://thephd.github.io/your-c-compiler-and-standard-library-will-not-help-you</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thephd.github.io/your-c-compiler-and-standard-library-will-not-help-you</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Software Should Be Free (2002)</title>
<link>https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/shouldbefree.en.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/shouldbefree.en.html</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Why Software Should Be Free&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stallman.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Stallman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The existence of software inevitably raises the question of how decisions about its use should be made. For example, suppose one individual who has a copy of a program meets another who would like a copy. It is possible for them to copy the program; who should decide whether this is done? The individuals involved? Or another party, called the “owner”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software developers typically consider these questions on the assumption that the criterion for the answer is to maximize developers' profits. The political power of business has led to the government adoption of both this criterion and the answer proposed by the developers: that the program has an owner, typically a corporation associated with its development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to consider the same question using a different criterion: the prosperity and freedom of the public in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This answer cannot be decided by current law—the law should conform to ethics, not the other way around. Nor does current practice decide this question, although it may suggest possible answers. The only way to judge is to see who is helped and who is hurt by recognizing owners of software, why, and how much. In other words, we should perform a cost-benefit analysis on behalf of society as a whole, taking account of individual freedom as well as production of material goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this essay, I will describe the effects of having owners, and show that the results are detrimental. My conclusion is that programmers have the duty to encourage others to share, redistribute, study, and improve the software we write: in other words, to write &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html&quot;&gt;“free” software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/shouldbefree.en.html#f1&quot;&gt;(1)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;owner-justification&quot;&gt;How Owners Justify Their Power&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who benefit from the current system where programs are property offer two arguments in support of their claims to own programs: the emotional argument and the economic argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emotional argument goes like this: “I put my sweat, my heart, my soul into this program. It comes from &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;, it's &lt;em&gt;mine&lt;/em&gt;!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This argument does not require serious refutation. The feeling of attachment is one that programmers can cultivate when it suits them; it is not inevitable. Consider, for example, how willingly the same programmers usually sign over all rights to a large corporation for a salary; the emotional attachment mysteriously vanishes. By contrast, consider the great artists and artisans of medieval times, who didn't even sign their names to their work. To them, the name of the artist was not important. What mattered was that the work was done—and the purpose it would serve. This view prevailed for hundreds of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The economic argument goes like this: “I want to get rich (usually described inaccurately as ‘making a living’), and if you don't allow me to get rich by programming, then I won't program. Everyone else is like me, so nobody will ever program. And then you'll be stuck with no programs at all!” This threat is usually veiled as friendly advice from the wise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll explain later why this threat is a bluff. First I want to address an implicit assumption that is more visible in another formulation of the argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This formulation starts by comparing the social utility of a proprietary program with that of no program, and then concludes that proprietary software development is, on the whole, beneficial, and should be encouraged. The fallacy here is in comparing only two outcomes—proprietary software versus no software—and assuming there are no other possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given a system of software copyright, software development is usually linked with the existence of an owner who controls the software's use. As long as this linkage exists, we are often faced with the choice of proprietary software or none. However, this linkage is not inherent or inevitable; it is a consequence of the specific social/legal policy decision that we are questioning: the decision to have owners. To formulate the choice as between proprietary software versus no software is begging the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;against-having-owners&quot;&gt;The Argument against Having Owners&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question at hand is, “Should development of software be linked with having owners to restrict the use of it?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to decide this, we have to judge the effect on society of each of those two activities &lt;em&gt;independently&lt;/em&gt;: the effect of developing the software (regardless of its terms of distribution), and the effect of restricting its use (assuming the software has been developed). If one of these activities is helpful and the other is harmful, we would be better off dropping the linkage and doing only the helpful one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it another way, if restricting the distribution of a program already developed is harmful to society overall, then an ethical software developer will reject the option of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine the effect of restricting sharing, we need to compare the value to society of a restricted (i.e., proprietary) program with that of the same program, available to everyone. This means comparing two possible worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis also addresses the simple counterargument sometimes made that “the benefit to the neighbor of giving him or her a copy of a program is cancelled by the harm done to the owner.” This counterargument assumes that the harm and the benefit are equal in magnitude. The analysis involves comparing these magnitudes, and shows that the benefit is much greater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elucidate this argument, let's apply it in another area: road construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be possible to fund the construction of all roads with tolls. This would entail having toll booths at all street corners. Such a system would provide a great incentive to improve roads. It would also have the virtue of causing the users of any given road to pay for that road. However, a toll booth is an artificial obstruction to smooth driving—artificial, because it is not a consequence of how roads or cars work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing free roads and toll roads by their usefulness, we find that (all else being equal) roads without toll booths are cheaper to construct, cheaper to run, safer, and more efficient to use.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/shouldbefree.en.html#f2&quot;&gt;(2)&lt;/a&gt; In a poor country, tolls may make the roads unavailable to many citizens. The roads without toll booths thus offer more benefit to society at less cost; they are preferable for society. Therefore, society should choose to fund roads in another way, not by means of toll booths. Use of roads, once built, should be free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the advocates of toll booths propose them as &lt;em&gt;merely&lt;/em&gt; a way of raising funds, they distort the choice that is available. Toll booths do raise funds, but they do something else as well: in effect, they degrade the road. The toll road is not as good as the free road; giving us more or technically superior roads may not be an improvement if this means substituting toll roads for free roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the construction of a free road does cost money, which the public must somehow pay. However, this does not imply the inevitability of toll booths. We who must in either case pay will get more value for our money by buying a free road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not saying that a toll road is worse than no road at all. That would be true if the toll were so great that hardly anyone used the road—but this is an unlikely policy for a toll collector. However, as long as the toll booths cause significant waste and inconvenience, it is better to raise the funds in a less obstructive fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply the same argument to software development, I will now show that having “toll booths” for useful software programs costs society dearly: it makes the programs more expensive to construct, more expensive to distribute, and less satisfying and efficient to use. It will follow that program construction should be encouraged in some other way. Then I will go on to explain other methods of encouraging and (to the extent actually necessary) funding software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;harm-done&quot;&gt;The Harm Done by Obstructing Software&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider for a moment that a program has been developed, and any necessary payments for its development have been made; now society must choose either to make it proprietary or allow free sharing and use. Assume that the existence of the program and its availability is a desirable thing.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/shouldbefree.en.html#f3&quot;&gt;(3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restrictions on the distribution and modification of the program cannot facilitate its use. They can only interfere. So the effect can only be negative. But how much? And what kind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three different levels of material harm come from such obstruction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fewer people use the program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None of the users can adapt or fix the program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other developers cannot learn from the program, or base new work on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each level of material harm has a concomitant form of psychosocial harm. This refers to the effect that people's decisions have on their subsequent feelings, attitudes, and predispositions. These changes in people's ways of thinking will then have a further effect on their relationships with their fellow citizens, and can have material consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three levels of material harm waste part of the value that the program could contribute, but they cannot reduce it to zero. If they waste nearly all the value of the program, then writing the program harms society by at most the effort that went into writing the program. Arguably a program that is profitable to sell must provide some net direct material benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, taking account of the concomitant psychosocial harm, there is no limit to the harm that proprietary software development can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;obstructing-use&quot;&gt;Obstructing Use of Programs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first level of harm impedes the simple use of a program. A copy of a program has nearly zero marginal cost (and you can pay this cost by doing the work yourself), so in a free market, it would have nearly zero price. A license fee is a significant disincentive to use the program. If a widely useful program is proprietary, far fewer people will use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy to show that the total contribution of a program to society is reduced by assigning an owner to it. Each potential user of the program, faced with the need to pay to use it, may choose to pay, or may forego use of the program. When a user chooses to pay, this is a zero-sum transfer of wealth between two parties. But each time someone chooses to forego use of the program, this harms that person without benefiting anyone. The sum of negative numbers and zeros must be negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this does not reduce the amount of work it takes to &lt;em&gt;develop&lt;/em&gt; the program. As a result, the efficiency of the whole process, in delivered user satisfaction per hour of work, is reduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reflects a crucial difference between copies of programs and cars, chairs, or sandwiches. There is no copying machine for material objects outside of science fiction. But programs are easy to copy; anyone can produce as many copies as are wanted, with very little effort. This isn't true for material objects because matter is conserved: each new copy has to be built from raw materials in the same way that the first copy was built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With material objects, a disincentive to use them makes sense, because fewer objects bought means less raw material and work needed to make them. It's true that there is usually also a startup cost, a development cost, which is spread over the production run. But as long as the marginal cost of production is significant, adding a share of the development cost does not make a qualitative difference. And it does not require restrictions on the freedom of ordinary users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, imposing a price on something that would otherwise be free is a qualitative change. A centrally imposed fee for software distribution becomes a powerful disincentive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's more, central production as now practiced is inefficient even as a means of delivering copies of software. This system involves enclosing physical disks or tapes in superfluous packaging, shipping large numbers of them around the world, and storing them for sale. This cost is presented as an expense of doing business; in truth, it is part of the waste caused by having owners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;damaging-social-cohesion&quot;&gt;Damaging Social Cohesion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose that both you and your neighbor would find it useful to run a certain program. In ethical concern for your neighbor, you should feel that proper handling of the situation will enable both of you to use it. A proposal to permit only one of you to use the program, while restraining the other, is divisive; neither you nor your neighbor should find it acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing a typical software license agreement means betraying your neighbor: “I promise to deprive my neighbor of this program so that I can have a copy for myself.” People who make such choices feel internal psychological pressure to justify them, by downgrading the importance of helping one's neighbors—thus public spirit suffers. This is psychosocial harm associated with the material harm of discouraging use of the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many users unconsciously recognize the wrong of refusing to share, so they decide to ignore the licenses and laws, and share programs anyway. But they often feel guilty about doing so. They know that they must break the laws in order to be good neighbors, but they still consider the laws authoritative, and they conclude that being a good neighbor (which they are) is naughty or shameful. That is also a kind of psychosocial harm, but one can escape it by deciding that these licenses and laws have no moral force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmers also suffer psychosocial harm knowing that many users will not be allowed to use their work. This leads to an attitude of cynicism or denial. A programmer may describe enthusiastically the work that he finds technically exciting; then when asked, “Will I be permitted to use it?”, his face falls, and he admits the answer is no. To avoid feeling discouraged, he either ignores this fact most of the time or adopts a cynical stance designed to minimize the importance of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the age of Reagan, the greatest scarcity in the United States is not technical innovation, but rather the willingness to work together for the public good. It makes no sense to encourage the former at the expense of the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;custom-adaptation&quot;&gt;Obstructing Custom Adaptation of Programs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second level of material harm is the inability to adapt programs. The ease of modification of software is one of its great advantages over older technology. But most commercially available software isn't available for modification, even after you buy it. It's available for you to take it or leave it, as a black box—that is all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A program that you can run consists of a series of numbers whose meaning is obscure. No one, not even a good programmer, can easily change the numbers to make the program do something different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmers normally work with the “source code” for a program, which is written in a programming language such as Fortran or C. It uses names to designate the data being used and the parts of the program, and it represents operations with symbols such as ‘+’ for addition and ‘-’ for subtraction. It is designed to help programmers read and change programs. Here is an example; a program to calculate the distance between two points in a plane:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
     float
     distance (p0, p1)
          struct point p0, p1;
     {
       float xdist = p1.x - p0.x;
       float ydist = p1.y - p0.y;
       return sqrt (xdist * xdist + ydist * ydist);
     }
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precisely what that source code means is not the point; the point is that it looks like algebra, and a person who knows this programming language will find it meaningful and clear. By contrast, here is same program in executable form, on the computer I normally used when I wrote this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
     1314258944      -232267772      -231844864      1634862
     1411907592      -231844736      2159150         1420296208
     -234880989      -234879837      -234879966      -232295424
     1644167167      -3214848        1090581031      1962942495
     572518958       -803143692      1314803317
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source code is useful (at least potentially) to every user of a program. But most users are not allowed to have copies of the source code. Usually the source code for a proprietary program is kept secret by the owner, lest anybody else learn something from it. Users receive only the files of incomprehensible numbers that the computer will execute. This means that only the program's owner can change the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend once told me of working as a programmer in a bank for about six months, writing a program similar to something that was commercially available. She believed that if she could have gotten source code for that commercially available program, it could easily have been adapted to their needs. The bank was willing to pay for this, but was not permitted to—the source code was a secret. So she had to do six months of make-work, work that counts in the GNP but was actually waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;abbr title=&quot;Massachusetts Institute of Technology&quot;&gt;MIT&lt;/abbr&gt; Artificial Intelligence Lab (AI Lab) received a graphics printer as a gift from Xerox around 1977. It was run by free software to which we added many convenient features. For example, the software would notify a user immediately on completion of a print job. Whenever the printer had trouble, such as a paper jam or running out of paper, the software would immediately notify all users who had print jobs queued. These features facilitated smooth operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later Xerox gave the AI Lab a newer, faster printer, one of the first laser printers. It was driven by proprietary software that ran in a separate dedicated computer, so we couldn't add any of our favorite features. We could arrange to send a notification when a print job was sent to the dedicated computer, but not when the job was actually printed (and the delay was usually considerable). There was no way to find out when the job was actually printed; you could only guess. And no one was informed when there was a paper jam, so the printer often went for an hour without being fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system programmers at the AI Lab were capable of fixing such problems, probably as capable as the original authors of the program. Xerox was uninterested in fixing them, and chose to prevent us, so we were forced to accept the problems. They were never fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most good programmers have experienced this frustration. The bank could afford to solve the problem by writing a new program from scratch, but a typical user, no matter how skilled, can only give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving up causes psychosocial harm—to the spirit of self-reliance. It is demoralizing to live in a house that you cannot rearrange to suit your needs. It leads to resignation and discouragement, which can spread to affect other aspects of one's life. People who feel this way are unhappy and do not do good work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine what it would be like if recipes were hoarded in the same fashion as software. You might say, “How do I change this recipe to take out the salt?” and the great chef would respond, “How dare you insult my recipe, the child of my brain and my palate, by trying to tamper with it? You don't have the judgment to change my recipe and make it work right!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But my doctor says I'm not supposed to eat salt! What can I do? Will you take out the salt for me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I would be glad to do that; my fee is only $50,000.” Since the owner has a monopoly on changes, the fee tends to be large. “However, right now I don't have time. I am busy with a commission to design a new recipe for ship's biscuit for the Navy Department. I might get around to you in about two years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;software-development&quot;&gt;Obstructing Software Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third level of material harm affects software development. Software development used to be an evolutionary process, where a person would take an existing program and rewrite parts of it for one new feature, and then another person would rewrite parts to add another feature; in some cases, this continued over a period of twenty years. Meanwhile, parts of the program would be “cannibalized” to form the beginnings of other programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The existence of owners prevents this kind of evolution, making it necessary to start from scratch when developing a program. It also prevents new practitioners from studying existing programs to learn useful techniques or even how large programs can be structured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owners also obstruct education. I have met bright students in computer science who have never seen the source code of a large program. They may be good at writing small programs, but they can't begin to learn the different skills of writing large ones if they can't see how others have done it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any intellectual field, one can reach greater heights by standing on the shoulders of others. But that is no longer generally allowed in the software field—you can only stand on the shoulders of the other people &lt;em&gt;in your own company&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The associated psychosocial harm affects the spirit of scientific cooperation, which used to be so strong that scientists would cooperate even when their countries were at war. In this spirit, Japanese oceanographers abandoning their lab on an island in the Pacific carefully preserved their work for the invading U.S. Marines, and left a note asking them to take good care of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conflict for profit has destroyed what international conflict spared. Nowadays scientists in many fields don't publish enough in their papers to enable others to replicate the experiment. They publish only enough to let readers marvel at how much they were able to do. This is certainly true in computer science, where the source code for the programs reported on is usually secret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;does-not-matter-how&quot;&gt;It Does Not Matter How Sharing Is Restricted&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been discussing the effects of preventing people from copying, changing, and building on a program. I have not specified how this obstruction is carried out, because that doesn't affect the conclusion. Whether it is done by copy protection, or copyright, or licenses, or encryption, or &lt;abbr title=&quot;Read-only Memory&quot;&gt;ROM&lt;/abbr&gt; cards, or hardware serial numbers, if it &lt;em&gt;succeeds&lt;/em&gt; in preventing use, it does harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users do consider some of these methods more obnoxious than others. I suggest that the methods most hated are those that accomplish their objective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;should-be-free&quot;&gt;Software Should be Free&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have shown how ownership of a program—the power to restrict changing or copying it—is obstructive. Its negative effects are widespread and important. It follows that society shouldn't have owners for programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to understand this is that what society needs is free software, and proprietary software is a poor substitute. Encouraging the substitute is not a rational way to get what we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaclav Havel has advised us to “Work for something because it is good, not just because it stands a chance to succeed.” A business making proprietary software stands a chance of success in its own narrow terms, but it is not what is good for society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-develop&quot;&gt;Why People Will Develop Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we eliminate copyright as a means of encouraging people to develop software, at first less software will be developed, but that software will be more useful. It is not clear whether the overall delivered user satisfaction will be less; but if it is, or if we wish to increase it anyway, there are other ways to encourage development, just as there are ways besides toll booths to raise money for streets. Before I talk about how that can be done, first I want to question how much artificial encouragement is truly necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;fun&quot;&gt;Programming is Fun&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some lines of work that few will enter except for money; road construction, for example. There are other fields of study and art in which there is little chance to become rich, which people enter for their fascination or their perceived value to society. Examples include mathematical logic, classical music, and archaeology; and political organizing among working people. People compete, more sadly than bitterly, for the few funded positions available, none of which is funded very well. They may even pay for the chance to work in the field, if they can afford to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a field can transform itself overnight if it begins to offer the possibility of getting rich. When one worker gets rich, others demand the same opportunity. Soon all may demand large sums of money for doing what they used to do for pleasure. When another couple of years go by, everyone connected with the field will deride the idea that work would be done in the field without large financial returns. They will advise social planners to ensure that these returns are possible, prescribing special privileges, powers, and monopolies as necessary to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change happened in the field of computer programming in the 1980s. In the 1970s, there were articles on “computer addiction”: users were “onlining” and had hundred-dollar-a-week habits. It was generally understood that people frequently loved programming enough to break up their marriages. Today, it is generally understood that no one would program except for a high rate of pay. People have forgotten what they knew back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it is true at a given time that most people will work in a certain field only for high pay, it need not remain true. The dynamic of change can run in reverse, if society provides an impetus. If we take away the possibility of great wealth, then after a while, when the people have readjusted their attitudes, they will once again be eager to work in the field for the joy of accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question “How can we pay programmers?” becomes an easier question when we realize that it's not a matter of paying them a fortune. A mere living is easier to raise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;funding&quot;&gt;Funding Free Software&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Institutions that pay programmers do not have to be software houses. Many other institutions already exist that can do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardware manufacturers find it essential to support software development even if they cannot control the use of the software. In 1970, much of their software was free because they did not consider restricting it. Today, their increasing willingness to join consortiums shows their realization that owning the software is not what is really important for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universities conduct many programming projects. Today they often sell the results, but in the 1970s they did not. Is there any doubt that universities would develop free software if they were not allowed to sell software? These projects could be supported by the same government contracts and grants that now support proprietary software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is common today for university researchers to get grants to develop a system, develop it nearly to the point of completion and call that “finished”, and then start companies where they really finish the project and make it usable. Sometimes they declare the unfinished version “free”; if they are thoroughly corrupt, they instead get an exclusive license from the university. This is not a secret; it is openly admitted by everyone concerned. Yet if the researchers were not exposed to the temptation to do these things, they would still do their research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmers writing free software can make their living by selling services related to the software. I have been hired to port the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/gcc/&quot;&gt;GNU C compiler&lt;/a&gt; to new hardware, and to make user-interface extensions to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;GNU Emacs&lt;/a&gt;. (I offer these improvements to the public once they are done.) I also teach classes for which I am paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not alone in working this way; there is now a successful, growing corporation which does no other kind of work. Several other companies also provide commercial support for the free software of the GNU system. This is the beginning of the independent software support industry—an industry that could become quite large if free software becomes prevalent. It provides users with an option generally unavailable for proprietary software, except to the very wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New institutions such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/fsf/fsf.html&quot;&gt;Free Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt; can also fund programmers. Most of the Foundation's funds come from users buying tapes through the mail. The software on the tapes is free, which means that every user has the freedom to copy it and change it, but many nonetheless pay to get copies. (Recall that “free software” refers to freedom, not to price.) Some users who already have a copy order tapes as a way of making a contribution they feel we deserve. The Foundation also receives sizable donations from computer manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Free Software Foundation is a charity, and its income is spent on hiring as many programmers as possible. If it had been set up as a business, distributing the same free software to the public for the same fee, it would now provide a very good living for its founder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the Foundation is a charity, programmers often work for the Foundation for half of what they could make elsewhere. They do this because we are free of bureaucracy, and because they feel satisfaction in knowing that their work will not be obstructed from use. Most of all, they do it because programming is fun. In addition, volunteers have written many useful programs for us. (Even technical writers have begun to volunteer.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This confirms that programming is among the most fascinating of all fields, along with music and art. We don't have to fear that no one will want to program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;owe&quot;&gt;What Do Users Owe to Developers?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a good reason for users of software to feel a moral obligation to contribute to its support. Developers of free software are contributing to the users' activities, and it is both fair and in the long-term interest of the users to give them funds to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this does not apply to proprietary software developers, since obstructionism deserves a punishment rather than a reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thus have a paradox: the developer of useful software is entitled to the support of the users, but any attempt to turn this moral obligation into a requirement destroys the basis for the obligation. A developer can either deserve a reward or demand it, but not both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that an ethical developer faced with this paradox must act so as to deserve the reward, but should also entreat the users for voluntary donations. Eventually the users will learn to support developers without coercion, just as they have learned to support public radio and television stations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;productivity&quot;&gt;What Is Software Productivity?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If software were free, there would still be programmers, but perhaps fewer of them. Would this be bad for society?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily. Today the advanced nations have fewer farmers than in 1900, but we do not think this is bad for society, because the few deliver more food to the consumers than the many used to do. We call this improved productivity. Free software would require far fewer programmers to satisfy the demand, because of increased software productivity at all levels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wider use of each program that is developed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to adapt existing programs for customization instead of starting from scratch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better education of programmers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The elimination of duplicate development effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who object to cooperation claiming it would result in the employment of fewer programmers are actually objecting to increased productivity. Yet these people usually accept the widely held belief that the software industry needs increased productivity. How is this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Software productivity” can mean two different things: the overall productivity of all software development, or the productivity of individual projects. Overall productivity is what society would like to improve, and the most straightforward way to do this is to eliminate the artificial obstacles to cooperation which reduce it. But researchers who study the field of “software productivity” focus only on the second, limited, sense of the term, where improvement requires difficult technological advances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;competition&quot;&gt;Is Competition Inevitable?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it inevitable that people will try to compete, to surpass their rivals in society? Perhaps it is. But competition itself is not harmful; the harmful thing is &lt;em&gt;combat&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to compete. Competition can consist of trying to achieve ever more, to outdo what others have done. For example, in the old days, there was competition among programming wizards—competition for who could make the computer do the most amazing thing, or for who could make the shortest or fastest program for a given task. This kind of competition can benefit everyone, &lt;em&gt;as long as&lt;/em&gt; the spirit of good sportsmanship is maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constructive competition is enough competition to motivate people to great efforts. A number of people are competing to be the first to have visited all the countries on Earth; some even spend fortunes trying to do this. But they do not bribe ship captains to strand their rivals on desert islands. They are content to let the best person win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competition becomes combat when the competitors begin trying to impede each other instead of advancing themselves—when “Let the best person win” gives way to “Let me win, best or not.” Proprietary software is harmful, not because it is a form of competition, but because it is a form of combat among the citizens of our society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competition in business is not necessarily combat. For example, when two grocery stores compete, their entire effort is to improve their own operations, not to sabotage the rival. But this does not demonstrate a special commitment to business ethics; rather, there is little scope for combat in this line of business short of physical violence. Not all areas of business share this characteristic. Withholding information that could help everyone advance is a form of combat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business ideology does not prepare people to resist the temptation to combat the competition. Some forms of combat have been banned with antitrust laws, truth in advertising laws, and so on, but rather than generalizing this to a principled rejection of combat in general, executives invent other forms of combat which are not specifically prohibited. Society's resources are squandered on the economic equivalent of factional civil war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;communism&quot;&gt;“Why Don't You Move to Russia?”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the United States, any advocate of other than the most extreme form of laissez-faire selfishness has often heard this accusation. For example, it is leveled against the supporters of a national health care system, such as is found in all the other industrialized nations of the free world. It is leveled against the advocates of public support for the arts, also universal in advanced nations. The idea that citizens have any obligation to the public good is identified in America with Communism. But how similar are these ideas?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communism as was practiced in the Soviet Union was a system of central control where all activity was regimented, supposedly for the common good, but actually for the sake of the members of the Communist party. And where copying equipment was closely guarded to prevent illegal copying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The American system of software copyright exercises central control over distribution of a program, and guards copying equipment with automatic copying-protection schemes to prevent illegal copying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, I am working to build a system where people are free to decide their own actions; in particular, free to help their neighbors, and free to alter and improve the tools which they use in their daily lives. A system based on voluntary cooperation and on decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, if we are to judge views by their resemblance to Russian Communism, it is the software owners who are the Communists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;premises&quot;&gt;The Question of Premises&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make the assumption in this paper that a user of software is no less important than an author, or even an author's employer. In other words, their interests and needs have equal weight, when we decide which course of action is best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This premise is not universally accepted. Many maintain that an author's employer is fundamentally more important than anyone else. They say, for example, that the purpose of having owners of software is to give the author's employer the advantage he deserves—regardless of how this may affect the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is no use trying to prove or disprove these premises. Proof requires shared premises. So most of what I have to say is addressed only to those who share the premises I use, or at least are interested in what their consequences are. For those who believe that the owners are more important than everyone else, this paper is simply irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why would a large number of Americans accept a premise that elevates certain people in importance above everyone else? Partly because of the belief that this premise is part of the legal traditions of American society. Some people feel that doubting the premise means challenging the basis of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important for these people to know that this premise is not part of our legal tradition. It never has been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the Constitution says that the purpose of copyright is to “promote the Progress of Science and the useful Arts.” The Supreme Court has elaborated on this, stating in &lt;em&gt;Fox Film v. Doyal&lt;/em&gt; that “The sole interest of the United States and the primary object in conferring the [copyright] monopoly lie in the general benefits derived by the public from the labors of authors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not required to agree with the Constitution or the Supreme Court. (At one time, they both condoned slavery.) So their positions do not disprove the owner supremacy premise. But I hope that the awareness that this is a radical right-wing assumption rather than a traditionally recognized one will weaken its appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like to think that our society encourages helping your neighbor; but each time we reward someone for obstructionism, or admire them for the wealth they have gained in this way, we are sending the opposite message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software hoarding is one form of our general willingness to disregard the welfare of society for personal gain. We can trace this disregard from Ronald Reagan to Dick Cheney, from Exxon to Enron, from failing banks to failing schools. We can measure it with the size of the homeless population and the prison population. The antisocial spirit feeds on itself, because the more we see that other people will not help us, the more it seems futile to help them. Thus society decays into a jungle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we don't want to live in a jungle, we must change our attitudes. We must start sending the message that a good citizen is one who cooperates when appropriate, not one who is successful at taking from others. I hope that the free software movement will contribute to this: at least in one area, we will replace the jungle with a more efficient system which encourages and runs on voluntary cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;f1&quot;&gt;The word “free” in “free software” refers to freedom, not to price; the price paid for a copy of a free program may be zero, or small, or (rarely) quite large.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;f2&quot;&gt;The issues of pollution and traffic congestion do not alter this conclusion. If we wish to make driving more expensive to discourage driving in general, it is disadvantageous to do this using toll booths, which contribute to both pollution and congestion. A tax on gasoline is much better. Likewise, a desire to enhance safety by limiting maximum speed is not relevant; a free-access road enhances the average speed by avoiding stops and delays, for any given speed limit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;f3&quot;&gt;One might regard a particular computer program as a harmful thing that should not be available at all, like the Lotus Marketplace database of personal information, which was withdrawn from sale due to public disapproval. Most of what I say does not apply to this case, but it makes little sense to argue for having an owner on the grounds that the owner will make the program less available. The owner will not make it &lt;em&gt;completely&lt;/em&gt; unavailable, as one would wish in the case of a program whose use is considered destructive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;blockquote id=&quot;fsfs&quot; readability=&quot;1.6969696969697&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;big&quot;&gt;This essay is published in &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.fsf.org/product/free-software-free-society/&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Free Software, Free Society: The Selected Essays of Richard M. Stallman&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 10:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>finolex1</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/shouldbefree.en.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>CEO of Uber: Gig Workers Deserve Better</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/10/opinion/uber-ceo-dara-khosrowshahi-gig-workers-deserve-better.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/10/opinion/uber-ceo-dara-khosrowshahi-gig-workers-deserve-better.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Since the first Uber trip 10 years ago, one existential question has shadowed us: Do we treat drivers well?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Many of our critics, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/27/opinion/uber-covid-gig-economy.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;including The New York Times editorial board&lt;/a&gt;, believe that Uber and our gig economy peers have failed drivers by treating them as contractors, and that we will do anything to avoid the cost of employee benefits like health insurance. Given our company’s history, I can understand why they think that. But it’s not true, and it’s not what I believe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Our current employment system is outdated and unfair. It forces every worker to choose between being an employee with more benefits but less flexibility, or an independent contractor with more flexibility but almost no safety net. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/newsroom/working-together-priorities/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Uber is ready, right now, to pay more to give drivers new benefits and protections&lt;/a&gt;. But America needs to change the status quo to protect all workers, not just one type of work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Why not just treat drivers as employees? Some of our critics argue that doing so would make drivers’ problems vanish overnight. It may seem like a reasonable assumption, but it’s one that I think ignores a stark reality: Uber would only have full-time jobs for &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/uber-under-the-hood/analysis-on-impacts-of-driver-reclassification-2f2639a7f902&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a small fraction of our current drivers and only be able to operate in many fewer cities&lt;/a&gt; than today. Rides would be more expensive, which would significantly reduce the number of rides people could take and, in turn, the number of drivers needed to provide those trips. Uber would not be as widely available to riders, and drivers would lose the flexibility they have today if they became employees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;More important than what I think is what drivers think: In public surveys over the last decade, the vast majority of drivers have said they &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/16/opinion/uber-ab5-california.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;don’t want to be employees&lt;/a&gt; because of how much they value flexibility. A recent &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cadriversurvey.com/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt; commissioned by Uber and other companies found that two out of three app drivers would stop driving if their flexibility was compromised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This is because they understand the trade-offs between traditional employment and app work. Unlike traditional jobs, drivers have total freedom to choose when and how they drive, so they can fit their work around their life, not the other way around. Anyone who’s been fired after having to miss a shift, or who’s been forced to choose between school and work, will tell you that this type of freedom has real value and simply does not exist with most traditional jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;While I disagree with our critics about the solution, I do think they are right about many of the problems. The freedom to work whenever you want comes with a serious drawback: When the worst happens, too often you are on your own. There has historically been little to no paid support for independent workers if they couldn’t work — if they wanted to take a vacation or, more important, if they got sick.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;There has to be a “third way” for gig workers, but we need to get specific, because we need more than new ideas — we need new laws. Our current system is binary, meaning that each time a company provides additional benefits to independent workers, the less independent they become. That creates more uncertainty and risk for the company, which is a main reason why we need new laws and can’t act entirely on our own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It’s time to move beyond this false choice. As a start, all gig economy companies need to pay for benefits, should be more honest about the reality of the work and must strengthen the rights and voice of workers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;I’m proposing that gig economy companies be required to establish benefits funds which give workers cash that they can use for the benefits they want, like health insurance or paid time off. Independent workers in any state that passes this law could take money out for every hour of work they put in. All gig companies would be required to participate, so that workers can build up benefits even if they switch between apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Had this been the law in all 50 states, Uber would have contributed $655 million to benefits funds last year alone. Taking one example, we estimate that a driver in Colorado averaging over 35 hours per week would have accrued approximately $1,350 in benefits funds in 2019. That’s enough to cover two weeks of paid time off, or the median annual premium payment for subsidized health insurance available through an existing Uber partnership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Why just give drivers money and let them decide what to do with it, rather than requiring companies to provide specific benefits to everyone? Once again, it comes down to what drivers want. When you ask many policymakers which benefit they think is most important to drivers, the answer is almost always health care. Yet when we ask drivers which benefits they most want, health care doesn’t crack the top five. That’s most likely because &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://therideshareguy.com/uber-drivers-can-survive-the-coronavirus/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;most drivers already have some form of health insurance&lt;/a&gt;, whether through another job, the Affordable Care Act or a family member.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Driving passengers or delivering food on a bike comes with real risks. States should require all gig companies to provide medical and disability coverage for injuries incurred on the job, creating a baseline safety net that we cannot give to drivers today without risking their independent status under the law. We also need new laws that prevent companies from denying independent workers opportunities based on their race, religion, gender, sexual orientation or any other protected characteristic. Shockingly, that fundamental measure of equality is not fully enshrined into law for all American workers today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;There are changes we should make on our own. Uber will start, and I hope others will follow. To begin with, we have to be more transparent about what drivers make and the realities of the work. That’s why we’ve launched a new earnings estimator, using historical data to give drivers a clearer view of what they can expect to earn in their area, before they even sign up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;We also need to do a better job acting on driver concerns. That starts with holding ourselves accountable: We commit to surveying every single active driver in the country about what’s working and what’s not and to publicly releasing the results, no matter what they say. With the upcoming election, we commit to helping every driver register to vote, so that independent workers have a stronger voice in our democracy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For many people, nothing short of us reclassifying all drivers as employees will be enough. That is the thrust of several lawsuits against Uber in the wake of a new California law, known as Assembly Bill 5. (We’re backing a November ballot initiative in California that would keep drivers as independent contractors, while requiring us to provide new benefits.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Some have argued that we should scrap independent work altogether because of its shortcomings. But if we eliminate this work, how do we expect the millions of Americans who have been doing gig work to stay afloat when few companies are hiring? If gig workers want to keep their current flexibility and get new benefits, shouldn’t we give them the best of both worlds, instead of asking them to choose the lesser of two evils?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;During this moment of crisis, I fundamentally believe platforms like Uber can fuel an economic recovery by quickly giving people flexible work to get back on their feet. But this opportunity will be lost if we ignore the obvious lessons of the pandemic and fail to ensure independent workers have a stronger safety net. This is the time for Uber to come together with government to raise the standard of work for all. The opportunity is now, and the responsibility is ours. The world has changed, and we must change with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-pncxxs etfikam0&quot;&gt;Mr. Khosrowshahi is the chief executive officer of Uber. From May 2015 until September 2017, he was on The New York Times board.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-pncxxs etfikam0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;The Times is committed to publishing &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/31/opinion/letters/letters-to-editor-new-york-times-women.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;a diversity of letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt; to the editor. We’d like to hear what you think about this or any of our articles. Here are some &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://help.nytimes.com/hc/en-us/articles/115014925288-How-to-submit-a-letter-to-the-editor&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;tips&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;. And here’s our email: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;mailto:letters@nytimes.com&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;letters@nytimes.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-pncxxs etfikam0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Follow The New York Times Opinion section on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/nytopinion&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://twitter.com/NYTOpinion&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Twitter (@NYTopinion)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/nytopinion/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 10:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mitchbob</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/10/opinion/uber-ceo-dara-khosrowshahi-gig-workers-deserve-better.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Opinion | I Am the C.E.O. of Uber. Gig Workers Deserve Better.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/08/11/opinion/10khosrowshahi-sub/10khosrowshahi-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Gig workers want both flexibility and benefits — we support laws that could make that possible.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/10/opinion/uber-ceo-dara-khosrowshahi-gig-workers-deserve-better.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I tried starting a manufacturing unit in India</title>
<link>https://superr.in/economy/i-tried-starting-a-manufacturing-unit-in-india/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://superr.in/economy/i-tried-starting-a-manufacturing-unit-in-india/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is the story of me trying to start a manufacturing unit in India…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Quick facts:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Land Size: 3 Acres OR 1,20,000 sq.ft.&lt;br/&gt;Factory Shed / Warehouse Building.&lt;br/&gt;State: &lt;strong&gt;Maharashtra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;District: &lt;strong&gt;Sangli&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do note that, Maharashtra state is considered to be one of the most liberal and best states in terms of “ease of doing business” in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started the process around November 2019. It’s been more than 9 months and I am still at least 4 months away from getting the permission that allows me to construct anything on my agricultural land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The NA Permission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you need to obtain “permission” before you build any manufacturing structure on your own land with your own money. This permission is called the NA or &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;on-&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;gricultural Certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s get this certificate! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get that, I went to the Sangli District Administration Office. The building looks quite good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/District-Office-1024x295.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of Sangli District Collector Office&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-50&quot; srcset=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/District-Office-1024x295.jpg 1024w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/District-Office-300x86.jpg 300w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/District-Office-768x221.jpg 768w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/District-Office.jpg 1050w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;Collector Office, Sangli
&lt;p&gt;After asking around a bit, I was told that I could get the NA permission from the “Revenue Department” office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I went there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There I was told to get a list of documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Level 1 – The Application:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documents Required:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;7/12 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affidavit (Self)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application Form (Self)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Land Records Since 1950 (Tahshildar Office)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Official Plot Map (Gat Nakasha)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9/3 – 9/4 (Document showing ownership of land and other details as on 1950)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first two documents are available online and easy to get. The 3rd and 4th documents were also easy as the format was already available, I just had to fill them up and sign on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last three documents were not easy to get. It took me more than 3 months and 2000 Rs in legal fees and more than 20 visits to different offices more than 10 kms apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I finally got them. I thought this was it. I was now going to get the prestigious NA certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I bought a file and filed all these papers in it and went to the “Revenue Department” Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I submitted the file. And was told that the application will be reviewed, discussed in a meeting and then if the application is approved, the procedure for NA-ing the land could be started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After about a month, I got a call from the Revenue Department asking to visit them for further procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There I was handed a letter, addressing 11 different departments and asking those departments to give me a NOC (No Objection Certificate). I was told to get all the 11 NOC’s by showing this letter to each department and any other additional documents they might ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Level 2 – The 11 NOCs:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, there are more than 13 NOC’s required to be obtained but this letter only mentions 11 of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After applying to each of these places, they give their own list of documents which require one or two more NOC’s each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Collector--768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The letter from the Collector Office addressing 11 departments to grant me No Objection Certificates to start a manufacturing unit.&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-36&quot; srcset=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Collector--768x1024.jpg 768w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Collector--225x300.jpg 225w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Collector--1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Collector--1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Collector--1200x1600.jpg 1200w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Collector--1980x2640.jpg 1980w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Collector--scaled.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px&quot;/&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Public Works Department&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MahaVitaran
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gram Panchayat NOC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear Land of Any Transmission Lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MahaTransco&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Irrigation Department
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gram Panchayat NOC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay the Irrigation Tax – 1,89,000 Per Hectare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map showing distance from nearest River&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legal Form showing the Agreement by Adjoining Farm Land Holders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health Department, Zilla Parishad
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gram Panchayat NOC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Primary Health Center NOC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forest Department&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Center&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maharashtra Pollution Control Board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tehshildar (Taluka)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Town Planning Department
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gram Panchayat NOC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MSEB NOC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building Plan – Layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mojni Nakasha (90 days)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legal Form showing the Agreement by Adjoining Farm Land Holders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Okay cool. I said to myself. After 4 months, all I had to do was to take this letter to each of these offices (after finding their address, located somewhere in the district) and then get their letter. Easy peasy, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But no! Once I reached the first “PWD” office, they gave me a list of documents required by them to grant me NOC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so did MahaVitaran. And Mahatransco. And the Irrigation Department…!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. The PWD NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand the reasoning behind the need for a PWD NOC. What if they’re planning to build a road through the land on which we intend to do our construction. It’s certainly worth notifying the public works department before we do any construction activity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the PWD NOC was easy to get. It took more than 4 months but no one asked for any bribe nor did anyone ask for any extravagant documents or signatures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no problem with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Mahavitaran NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, Mahavitaran is the Maharashtra state owned company. It owns the low-tension electricity transmission lines which provides electricity to houses, commercial spaces and farms. (Not industries). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The requirement for the Mahavitaran NOC is that “if” there are any lines going through the farm land, then the land owner must get them removed. I also agree with this idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though removing these lines cost a lot, it is an important step for safety. So again, not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. MahaTransco NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Mahatransco-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-41&quot; srcset=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Mahatransco-1.jpg 623w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Mahatransco-1-221x300.jpg 221w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again Mahatransco is the same as Mahavitaran except that it provides high-tension electricity transmission for industrial use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s a problem here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are no high-tension lines, as is the case in our land, a self-declaration by the farm owner that there is no Mahatransco line should be sufficient. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem I face: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I applied for NOC. They came and checked. Their person signed and wrote that there is no Mahatransco line. And then they gave me that paper and asked me to get signatures from two village authorities. The Talathi and The Circle Officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And both of them denied it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mahatransco would not accept it without the signatures. And these two people would not sign it at any cost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What should a mere mortal with no government or political connections do about this?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s it. Stuck there forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Irrigation NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Irrigation-784x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Documents required by irrigation department to grant a No Objection Certificate&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-37&quot; srcset=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Irrigation-784x1024.jpg 784w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Irrigation-230x300.jpg 230w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Irrigation-768x1003.jpg 768w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Irrigation-1176x1536.jpg 1176w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Irrigation-1569x2048.jpg 1569w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Irrigation-1200x1567.jpg 1200w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Irrigation-1980x2585.jpg 1980w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Irrigation-scaled.jpg 1961w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 784px) 100vw, 784px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only do they need 11 documents, each of which requires almost a month to obtain, they also want us to pay Rupees 2,89,000 (That is more than twice the Average Per Capita National Income of India ~1,35,000) “because” our land falls within the area served by a canal from the Irrigation Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, to begin with, Indian farmers don’t pay for electricity and water. So they just keep the Switch for the water pump turned ON always. Whenever electricity is available, the water keeps getting pumped into the farm, flooding the farm with unnecessary water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let’s assume that I don’t care at all about the water and electricity being wasted by the farmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I care about is that I should get a water and an electricity connection and I should be billed at whatever price that prevails and I will pay the bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But no. Someone is taking the pain to setup a manufacturing unit. Someone is taking the pain to provide employment. “So let’s just milk out as much as we can from this person so that we can continue giving free things to these “majority” farmers and keep getting elected.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Irrigation-Fee-Tax-Highlights-716x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-59&quot; srcset=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Irrigation-Fee-Tax-Highlights-716x1024.jpg 716w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Irrigation-Fee-Tax-Highlights-210x300.jpg 210w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Irrigation-Fee-Tax-Highlights-768x1098.jpg 768w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Irrigation-Fee-Tax-Highlights-1074x1536.jpg 1074w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Irrigation-Fee-Tax-Highlights-1432x2048.jpg 1432w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Irrigation-Fee-Tax-Highlights-1200x1716.jpg 1200w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Irrigation-Fee-Tax-Highlights-1980x2831.jpg 1980w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Irrigation-Fee-Tax-Highlights-scaled.jpg 1790w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 716px) 100vw, 716px&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;5. Health Department, Zilla Parishad  NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Health-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-39&quot; srcset=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Health-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Health-225x300.jpg 225w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Health-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Health-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Health-1200x1600.jpg 1200w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Health-1980x2639.jpg 1980w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Edited-Health-scaled.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do you need the health department’s “permission” to start a manufacturing unit on your land? Well maybe because the government is interested in creating as many hurdles as possible so that these “public servants” can milk as much money as possible from the fool who wants to start a business and create employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, they gave me a list of documents. These documents were to be uploaded on to a website. And as always, the website doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s stuck because the website isn’t working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Forest Department NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7. MIDC NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIDC NOC is understandable. They procure land and offer it for cheap prices for manufacturing purposes. Therefore it is necessary to confirm that the land on which you are building is not a part of any upcoming MIDC project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the process was fast here. No one asked for any bribes. So I have no problem with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8. Udhyog Kendra NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This office was created to facilitate the creation of business capacity in the district. But now it just adds to the burden by being in the list of barriers to be completed before you can start a business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But fortunately I got it with one application and within one week, so it should just be removed anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;9. MPCB NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got it within a few days without the need of any documents. And it’s the Pollution Control Board, which is necessary to save the environment. So I am fine with it. As long as it’s fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;10. Tahsildar NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applied for this NOC in the Tahshildar Office at Miraj. No response. No letter. No communication. And no person is willing to talk about what one should do next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been more than 4 months. Just total silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, they are playing “hard to get” to get me to pay some bribe and initiate the process. But after going through all this, I am not going to pay any bribe to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it’s just stuck there. Been more than 4 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;11. Town Planning Department NOC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/town-planning-noc-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-44&quot; srcset=&quot;https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/town-planning-noc-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/town-planning-noc-225x300.jpg 225w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/town-planning-noc-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/town-planning-noc-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/town-planning-noc-1200x1600.jpg 1200w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/town-planning-noc-1980x2640.jpg 1980w, https://superr.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/town-planning-noc-scaled.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most important NOC according to many experienced “agents” who have been in this N.A. game. A lot of money needs to be sprinkled for this NOC or they can delay your project infinitely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They require the following documents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gram Panchayat NOC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MSEB (Mahavitaran NOC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Land Counting Map (Mojani Nakasha) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Land Co-holders Affidavit &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4&gt;12. Gram Panchayat.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as this is a requirement in almost all the NOC’s mentioned above, I went and applied for the Gram Panchayat NOC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they openly demanded bribes after waiting for four months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Gram Panchayat NOC is stuck because of non payment of bribe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And many other NOC’s depend on the Gram Panchayat NOC, so they are stuck too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is how, ladies and gentlemen, brother and sisters, India will treat you if you try starting a small manufacturing unit to create jobs, useful products and prosperity for yourself and a few others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been more than 9 months, I went from one office to another. From one Taluka to another, most of the times to find out that the concerned person has decided to stay at home that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The office in the village, the “chavdi” as it is called in Marathi runs on the whims of one person and this one person could appear at the office any day and disappear any day. All you can do is sit and wait till the evening and “hope” that this person arrives before 6 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So what next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I have found out that the law governing these rules is based in the “Maharastra State Land Revenue Code”. I will try to challenge this process in the court as well as protest for change so any one could start or construct anything of their choice on their land without much delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My request to you is join me in this mission to really make India a place where Businesses come up like weeds grow on fertile land. Currently even though there is a lot of aspiration in the people and lot of people want to start something, laws like these act as a concrete layer on fertile land to completely halt any entrepreneurial willpower in the rural and the poor people of India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow me on Twitter for future updates. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mrohanshah&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Rohan Shah Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] I tried starting a manufacturing unit in India (superr.in) […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least you got a piece of land. Getting a land is it self a problem. MIDC lands are for rich and influential only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MH is NOT the most friendly Govt. particularly when you go to smaller town like Sangali. ‘Norm’ in India is to treat everyone as they doing something ‘bad, illegal, fraud, outrageous profit’ etc. So either a delay or a ‘cut’ … I know facilities that are lying idle due to such issues. Also converting Agree Land in to commercial is big attention catcher of bureaucrats so either pay up or suffer 🙁 Many do buy AL cheap and make huge profilt by converting it in to CL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kudos. Good Luck. How would you like us to help or join in this movement ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] Read More […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] &lt;a href=&quot;https://superr.in/economy/i-tried-starting-a-manufacturing-unit-in-india/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow ugc&quot;&gt;https://superr.in/economy/i-tried-starting-a-manufacturing-unit-in-india/&lt;/a&gt; […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your follow through is really commendable.&lt;br/&gt;How can I help?&lt;br/&gt;Have you tried to Send this ordeal to PMO office?&lt;br/&gt;I would try that ask them “was this supped to be the goal of Make In India”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also share your blog post with news media to gain traction…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the reality of Atmanirbhar Bharat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be great if you could convert this blog in local languages, probably hindi and marathi. Please let me know if you need help. We could forward it to district magistrates and newspapers for better awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have just started this process and I do understand your frustration. If I can be of any help please let me know&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superpower by 2030?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a manufacturing unit owner I had to go through similar stuff tooo, it’s really had to start something and after all this hurdle they come and take away the taxes without giving us any benefits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is good insight. There should be one nodal agency that can manage all departments.Start petition in change.org. Can get a large number of people behind this and get policians to take note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading this makes me squirm. I wonder where is the Ease of Doing Business drive? Just because we have had a disruption due to the virus, do we forget our long term priorities?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will gain tremendous support. Name and shame all the person involved. Let them rot in hell. We will support you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haw people invest in maharashtra for any projects. Very difficult to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the best, more power to you 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for sharing this. Maharashtra is a screwed place. Can empathise with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respect for your fight. Would like to support and want to be part of this. Am a journalist and I write for Indian Manufacturing. People like you are our assets. All the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Rohan,&lt;br/&gt;I’m a podcast producer for BillionTwenty Media an upstart podcasting company working on a story about the ease of doing business in India. I would love to interview you about your experience.Can you please email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:adi@billiontwenty.com&quot;&gt;adi@billiontwenty.com&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should not be such an ordeal experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good. Noc is required but do not give bribe to anyone. Fight agianst corruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well done. But is this in notice of the PM? How can I be of any help in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How come there is no mention of bribe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not many people will be surprised by this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people especially those who never started a business or work in government (government employees), are completely unaware of such harassment or they totally support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the best for your fight!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you tried reaching to PMO? Also, if you get a solution, please do let everyone know. Also, o feel modiji when says, make in India, he should also specify “how” in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] Read More […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheif you aren’t alone in this fight, we would all like to come to your help together just shout out, we would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really shocking but….&lt;br/&gt;Givt should seriously look into this and create Real Time Single Window System for industries… that will&lt;br/&gt;Be real ease of doing business…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respect..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with some others here. All states and Central govt. should constitute a single nodal agency for all operations and strict service level timelines should be adhered to. And all applications and processing should be transparent and made online for anyone to check. That way, we can keep both the government officials and the businessman honest, so that genuine laws/rules and their underlying intent is not compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep fighting boss. Send this entire story to pmo and state chief minister office. Try to make a video of it and get pmo tweet on this. Get media attention on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though not advisable from an ethical viewpoint, in reality, don’t ppl just start a unit without bothering about all these clearances? And then keep ‘managing’ the relevant depts as they visit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow !!! Absolute wow… The craziness and heights of nonsense..this country never ceases to amaze. What patience man you have? Shame on the system and the people who run it.. we deserve to be the third world country that we are..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great effort. Why not take this to Modi’s attention. We are with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is devised to serve the interests of bureaucrats only. They don’t care about business growth, economic development or employment generation. They have job security for their life and have no responsibility or accountability. The only way to avoid this hassel is to use so called consultants, who are effectively working as their agents to channel bribes to these corrupt officials to perform their normal duties. PMO can’t do anything here unless the grassroot level officials are made accountable and jailed enmass and their properties are confiscated…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There needs to be some regulation. You can’t just build whatever you want on an agricultural land even if you own it. How can a government make sure that people wont take advantage and build whatever they want once they get permission to build a factory on an agricultural land? If I have to pick one concern then that would be pollution which would affect your neighboring land directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree that there should be regulation. But there shouldn’t be loot, bribery, corruption, time wasting like people currently experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 07:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rohan_shah</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://superr.in/economy/i-tried-starting-a-manufacturing-unit-in-india/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Linux Backdoor Attempt of 2003 (2013)</title>
<link>https://freedom-to-tinker.com/2013/10/09/the-linux-backdoor-attempt-of-2003/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://freedom-to-tinker.com/2013/10/09/the-linux-backdoor-attempt-of-2003/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Josh &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedom-to-tinker.com/blog/kroll/software-transparency-debian-openssl-bug/&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; recently about a serious security bug that appeared in Debian Linux back in 2006, and whether it was really a backdoor inserted by the NSA. (He concluded that it probably was not.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I want to write about another &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/57135/&quot;&gt;incident&lt;/a&gt;, in 2003, in which someone tried to backdoor the Linux kernel. This one was definitely an attempt to insert a backdoor. But we don’t know who it was that made the attempt—and we probably never will.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-8995&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Back in 2003 Linux used a system called BitKeeper to store the master copy of the Linux source code. If a developer wanted to propose a modification to the Linux code, they would submit their proposed change, and it would go through an organized approval process to decide whether the change would be accepted into the master code. Every change to the master code would come with a short explanation, which always included a pointer to the record of its approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But some people didn’t like BitKeeper, so a second copy of the source code was kept so that developers could get the code via another code system called CVS. The CVS copy of the code was a direct clone of the primary BitKeeper copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But on Nov. 5, 2003, Larry McVoy &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/57137/&quot;&gt;noticed&lt;/a&gt; that there was a code change in the CVS copy that did not have a pointer to a record of approval. Investigation showed that the change had never been approved and, stranger yet, that this change did not appear in the primary BitKeeper repository at all. Further investigation determined that someone had apparently broken in (electronically) to the CVS server and inserted this change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did the change do? This is where it gets really interesting. The change modified the code of a Linux function called wait4, which a program could use to wait for something to happen. Specifically, it added these two lines of code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
if ((options == (__WCLONE|__WALL)) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; (current-&amp;gt;uid = 0))
        retval = -EINVAL;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Exercise for readers who know the C programming language: What is unusual about this code? Answer appears below.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A casual reading by an expert would interpret this as innocuous error-checking code to make wait4 return an error code when wait4 was called in a certain way that was forbidden by the documentation. But a really careful expert reader would notice that, near the end of the first line, it said “= 0” rather than “== 0”. The normal thing to write in code like this is “== 0”, which tests whether the user ID of the currently running code (current-&amp;gt;uid) is equal to zero, without modifying the user ID. But what actually appears is “= 0”, which has the effect of setting the user ID to zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting the user ID to zero is a problem because user ID number zero is the “root” user, which is allowed to do absolutely anything it wants—to access all data, change the behavior of all code, and to compromise entirely the security of all parts of the system. So the effect of this code is to give root privileges to any piece of software that called wait4 in a particular way that is supposed to be invalid. In other words … it’s a classic backdoor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very clever piece of work. It looks like innocuous error checking, but it’s really a back door. And it was slipped into the code outside the normal approval process, to avoid any possibility that the approval process would notice what was up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the attempt didn’t work, because the Linux team was careful enough to notice that that this code was in the CVS repository without having gone through the normal approval process. Score one for Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could this have been an NSA attack? Maybe. But there were many others who had the skill and motivation to carry out this attack. Unless somebody confesses, or a smoking-gun document turns up, we’ll never know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Post edited (2013-10-09) to correct the spelling of Larry McVoy’s name.]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 06:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>t4h4</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://freedom-to-tinker.com/2013/10/09/the-linux-backdoor-attempt-of-2003/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>