<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Old box, dumb code, few thousand connections, no big deal</title>
<link>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2020/05/07/serv/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2020/05/07/serv/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I think some of us who have been doing this a while have been doing a terrible job of showing what's possible to those folks who are somewhat newer. I get the impression that a lot of us (myself included) hit a certain point, get tired of this crap, and just want to be free of it. Sometimes I wonder what it would be like if I could just forget I knew anything about systems stuff and just disappear into the world to... I don't know, raise goldfish, or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as long as I'm here writing about this stuff, I might as well share some of what's been learned over the years. Not all of it is good, and some of it is probably just flat-out wrong or outdated, but there are other things people need to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, it does not take &quot;that much machine&quot; to serve a fair number of clients. Ever since I &lt;a href=&quot;https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2020/03/07/costly/&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about the whole Python/Gunicorn/Gevent mess a couple of months back, people have been asking me &quot;if not that, then what&quot;. It got me thinking about alternatives, and finally I just started writing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is something kind of unusual for me: a server without a real purpose just yet. It's more of a demonstrative thing at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I have is a server which starts up and kicks off a &quot;listener&quot; thread to do nothing but watch for incoming traffic. When it gets a new connection, it kicks off a &quot;serviceworker&quot; thread to handle it. The &quot;listener&quot; thread owns all of the file descriptors (listeners and clients both), and manages a single epoll set to watch over them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a client fd goes active, it pokes that serviceworker thread with a condvar, and it wakes up and does a read from the network. If there's a complete and usable message, it dispatches it to my wacky little RPC situation which is sitting behind it. Then it pushes the result out to the network again and goes back to waiting for another wakeup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're keeping score, this means I spawn a whole OS-level thread every time I get a connection. I designed this thing around the notion of &quot;what if we weren't afraid to create threads&quot;, and this is the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote up a load testing tool, too. It will create any number of worker threads, each of which opens a TCP connection back to the server. Each one of those will fire a request down the pipe, wait for the response, sleep a configurable period, and then go again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's say I stand up the server and a loadgen instance on the same machine. In this case it's my nine-year-old workstation box running Slackware64. I tell the load generator to hit the server (on localhost), run 2000 workers, and wait 200 milliseconds between queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing the math, every worker should run about 5 queries per second. It's not exactly 5 because the request itself takes some amount of time to complete. That means I should see about 10000 per second overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I start it up. What do you suppose happens to the server? It now has 2000 client connections and 10000 QPS to worry about. Does it eat the whole machine? No, far from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server process has about 90 MB of RSS -- that is, physical memory. That's not bad for something with a hair over 2000 threads! Now, sure, the virtual size (VSZ) of the process is something like 20 GB, but who cares? That's all of the overhead of having that many threads around, but they aren't actually using it in physical terms, so it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the latency look like? Since this is all running over loopback, it looks stellar. Most of the time, all of the requests finish in under a millisecond. Every now and then, a handful slop over into &quot;more than 1, less than 2&quot; territory. That's pretty cool, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, all right, that's not realistic. Queries don't come from localhost, they come from other machines on the same network. Fine. So what happens when I keep those 2000 clients running, then add 4000 more over the local gig Ethernet from my Mac laptop?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, first of all, the latency spreads out. Those requests going over loopback aren't all now happening in under a millisecond. Now some of them are actually making it up to 40 ms. Gasp!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mac, meanwhile, is seeing a nice spread of latencies, too. I have it doing some really terrible analysis to yield percentiles. If I haven't screwed this up too badly, the numbers look like this for one five-second period grabbed from the scrolling console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p50: 24ms, p75: 31ms, p90: 42ms, p95: 49ms, p99: 68ms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're not familiar, this means that half (50%) of the requests finished in 24 milliseconds or less. 75% finished in 31 milliseconds or less, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to be lagging my laptop a lot worse than the Linux box which is doing all of the serving. I'm ON the Linux box running X, in an X terminal, sshed into the Mac, typing this post... and it's now lagging. It's not the Linux box, either, since I can do more interactive things on it, and it's ho-hum, boring, same old same old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server, meanwhile, is up around 256 MB of physical memory, and is juggling just over 6000 threads. The load average on the whole machine (which is running the server, a load generator, and some other unrelated things) is about 4.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what happens if I throw more load at it? I have one more vaguely-Unixy box here on my local network: a 2011 Mac Mini. How about another 4000 clients from that thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server is now up to about 422 MB of physical memory and just over 10000 threads. The load average on the whole machine is about 7.8 now. The whole server is running about 32000 QPS now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did this do to the timing? Back on my laptop, things have slowed down a little bit. Here's another five-second snapshot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p50: 25ms, p75: 38ms, p90: 57ms, p95: 75ms, p99: 127ms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be quite honest, the numbers from the laptop are all over the place. It also has Firefox and at least one stupid chat client that's actually a giant piggy web browser running, plus whatever else Apple decides to kick off in the background. Still, the p99 stays under 250ms. In theory, I could run this a lot longer and get some error bars out of this whole business. I could also use sensible systems to do this testing which don't have tons of other crap running on them which add noise to my results. But hey, I'm using what I have on hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, to be clear, this all hinges on exactly what kind of work the server is doing. It's not doing TLS. It IS dealing with my own little goofy wire protocol, deserializing that into a protobuf, figuring out what it means, deserializing the inside of *that* thing into another (request-dependent) protobuf, and then dispatching it to the handler. The handler does a little work (more on that in a bit), and then the server has to serialize the response, jam it into the outer message, serialize that, wrap it up in my goofy wire protocol, and fire it down the socket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What, then, is the workload? Well, for this test, I wrote something truly stupid called LavaLamp. It's an homage to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lavarand&quot;&gt;SGI Lavarand&lt;/a&gt; project which used cameras pointing at lava lamps to generate random numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mine does not use lava lamps. The name is meant to be ironic. It DOES generate &lt;em&gt;pseudo&lt;/em&gt;-random numbers, though. The idea is to do just a little work on the CPU without being anything too interesting. It's deliberately not optimized. Every time it runs, it creates a random device, a random engine, and a uniform int distribution which is constrained between 'A' and 'Z'. Yep, that's right, this thing only spits out capital letters in ASCII.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It runs this 16 times and sends you the result. There's no caching, so every client gets their little blob fresh off the grill, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's kind of funny since it does actually open /dev/urandom every time through. In fact, if you don't give this thing a high enough file descriptor limit, it might just blow up when it gets that far. After all, being connected to 10000 clients each consumes a fd, the listening sockets eat a few, epoll has one, there's stdin/out/err, and now you want to open /dev/urandom every time you get a request? That's a lot of cruft!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: it doesn't crash when this happens. I catch the random device failure and just kill the request. Why bring down the whole server when one request failed? That's just asking for trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just wanted something that would present a little churn to the box instead of being something truly stupid like an &quot;echo&quot; endpoint. This does a teeny tiny amount of work and makes it that much more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my dumb little box from 2011 can handle 10000 persistent connections each firing a request down the pipe 5 times a second to do something truly stupid with random numbers. It does this with maybe half a gig of physical memory used, and about 75% of the CPU power available. I haven't done anything special in terms of balancing IRQs from the NIC, splitting up the accept/epoll/dispatch load, or pipelining requests. It's about as stupid as you can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that should be even mildly interesting is that I built it with a deliberate decision to not be afraid of threads. I figure, I'll stand 'em up, and let the kernel figure out when to schedule them. So far, it's been working pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just one example of what can be done. It's not magic. It's just engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 20:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2020/05/07/serv/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cross-signing and end-to-end encryption by default</title>
<link>https://matrix.org/blog/2020/05/06/cross-signing-and-end-to-end-encryption-by-default-is-here</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://matrix.org/blog/2020/05/06/cross-signing-and-end-to-end-encryption-by-default-is-here</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, Matrix is end-to-end encrypted &lt;strong&gt;by default&lt;/strong&gt; for private conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years have passed since we &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/2016/11/21/matrixs-olm-end-to-end-encryption-security-assessment-released-and-implemented-cross-platform-on-riot-at-last&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;first announced End-to-end Encryption in Matrix&lt;/a&gt; and started to beta test it in Riot - and after an enormous amount of polishing and refinement on its user experience, we are finally declaring it out of beta and enabling it by default for all new private conversations in Riot. As Riot is currently the most common Matrix client, this means that Matrix as a whole should now be considered end-to-end encrypted by default for DMs and invite-only rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work on E2EE in Matrix has progressed in waves since we first shipped it - including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;adding keysharing (letting you share encryption keys between your devices to improve reliability)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making Riot Web's encryption resilient to running concurrently in multiple tabs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding online key backup (so you don't lose all your history if you lose all your devices)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making encryption resilient to restoring the app from a backup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding interactive key verification via emoji to make the verification process easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, our goal was always to enable E2EE by default for all private rooms, which means having feature parity between unencrypted and E2EE Matrix so that we can enable encryption without &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; negative impact on usability. The high-level remaining items were significant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cross-signing: verifying your own logins so others don’t have to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding QR codes for even better verification UX, to make cross-signing as painless as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replacing the old prototype UI for E2EE with final polished UI/UX.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to support non-E2EE clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to search encrypted rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to view file indexes in encrypted rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixing the remaining “Unable to decrypt” errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months the Riot team has been almost entirely focused on implementing solutions to these items - and we're finally at the point where the switch can be flipped and as of Riot Web/Desktop 1.6, Riot iOS 0.11.1 and RiotX Android 0.19, all new private rooms will be encrypted by default; completing the transition we began at &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2020/schedule/event/matrix/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;FOSDEM 2020&lt;/a&gt; when we landed cross-signing E2E-by-default in the development branches of Riot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For full details, please go check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.riot.im/e2e-encryption-by-default-cross-signing-is-here/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;massive deep dive over at the Riot blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - also featuring all the other recent progress in Riot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heads up that encrypted traffic is slightly more heavier on the server than unencrypted (due to exchanging keys, verification traffic, and keybackup traffic), and so there is a risk that the already-over-popular Matrix.org server instance may feel a little hugged to death. However, unprecedented Synapse performance breakthroughs are on the horizon in the coming weeks which will fix this - and, of course, you can (and should!) be using your own instance anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks everyone for helping us test encryption over the years and getting us to this point: cross-signing provides a more secure way of tracking device trust than almost any other comms system out there, and we hope that you'll agree the improved UX has been worth the wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop: Synapse performance, and rebuilding Riot's first time user experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;thanks,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew, Amandine &amp;amp; the Matrix Team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 20:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thanksforfish</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://matrix.org/blog/2020/05/06/cross-signing-and-end-to-end-encryption-by-default-is-here</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Cross-signing and End-to-end Encryption by Default is HERE!!! | Matrix.org</og:title>
<og:image>https://blog.riot.im/content/images/2020/05/Frame-29-1.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://matrix.org/blog/2020/05/06/cross-signing-and-end-to-end-encryption-by-default-is-here/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Making Emacs Popular Again</title>
<link>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/819452/1480c3a59d3d9093/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/819452/1480c3a59d3d9093/</guid>
<description>&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;90%&quot; cellspacing=&quot;5&quot; readability=&quot;4.1829745596869&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.154598825832&quot;&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Welcome to LWN.net&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following subscription-only content has been made available to you by an LWN subscriber. Thousands of subscribers depend on LWN for the best news from the Linux and free software communities. If you enjoy this article, please consider accepting the trial offer on the right. Thank you for visiting LWN.net!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;Form&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; readability=&quot;1.2016574585635&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6049723756906&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;4.8066298342541&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Free trial subscription&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try LWN for free for 1 month: no payment or credit card required. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Promo/slink-trial2-3/claim&quot;&gt;Activate your trial subscription now&lt;/a&gt; and see why thousands of readers subscribe to LWN.net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Jake Edge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;May 6, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;Emacs editor&lt;/a&gt; predates Linux, and was once far more popular, but it has fallen into relative obscurity over the years. In a mega-thread on the emacs-devel mailing list, participants discussed various ideas for making Emacs more &quot;attractive&quot;, in both aesthetic and in &quot;appealing to more users&quot; senses of that term. Any improvements to Emacs in that regard have numerous hurdles to overcome, however. There are technical questions and, naturally, licensing considerations, but there is also the philosophical question of what it is, exactly, that stops the venerable text editor from being more popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;So square&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussion started with &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/8wXYP4GY9hwW-9mYv6_LGMETZ8Vz3Ob1Bec6yh6kPT7yxjTkxA3V6dXY4ELra9tYiJUxJmgXKSIEX4w8HFiPRoeGVSQHDSoBVy1voj1e3Qo=@protonmail.com/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; from &quot;ndame&quot; asking why Emacs is &quot;&lt;span&gt;so square&lt;/span&gt;&quot;; the appearance of things like buttons could be improved with rounded corners, they said. Richard Stallman, one of the original authors of Emacs, seemed somewhat dismissive in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/E1jOYIC-000709-3J@fencepost.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;reply&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;&lt;span&gt;Perhaps we should implement a mode that puts cosmetics on Emacs so it will appeal to those who judge by the surface of things.&lt;/span&gt;&quot; But Stefan Kangas &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/CADwFkmnyYPjLd8=N7K955v5+34+wgDAUrC6C6KGG0xvT3OJr9g@mail.gmail.com/&quot;&gt;thought&lt;/a&gt; there was more to it than that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BigQuote&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;I think it's unfortunate if we assume that this is all bells and whistles. Graphical design elements can also improve usability.
&lt;p&gt;I also don't know that it's helpful to assume that the rest of the world will take the enlightened stance. For example, I've always assumed that many people use Sublime Text not due to any serious feature comparison with Emacs, but because they like its &quot;sleek look&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wondered if there was &quot;&lt;span&gt;any reason not to improve the default look&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. Stallman &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/E1jOuIG-0004CF-OB@fencepost.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; that there are some technical barriers in finding someone interested in and capable of doing the work needed, but there is an overarching problem that needs to be addressed first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code to interface Emacs to X-based GUIs needs rewriting by an expert, and has needed it for decades. Until it gets that rewrite, changes in it are likely to break something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stallman did agree that the graphical design could improve usability, &quot;&lt;span&gt;but I have a feeling that the changes that would help are deeper issues than the shape of corners&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. The GUI interface only matters if Emacs users are leaving those features (e.g. the menu bar and tool bar) enabled, Eli Zaretskii &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/83y2qwdmnd.fsf@gnu.org/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;, but much of the advice out there on configuring Emacs suggests disabling those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to be enthusiastic about making these features more modern when the community seems to be divided on whether they should at all be present. IMO, we should first get our act together and decide whether these features are important, and then speak up according to those decisions when we see advice to the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, though, there are bigger problems with Emacs as a whole, Joseph Garvin &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/CAH=MJ4Yu0_ZLzm-W1-+i4JNh0PLSdNUGOxrzCkPjwtZ55EDEyg@mail.gmail.com/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. The Emacs user interface &quot;&lt;span&gt;doesn't look or behave like any other application&lt;/span&gt;&quot;, the keyboard shortcuts are different than other programs, and the terminology used in the Emacs world does not match with what users expect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BigQuote&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;[...] no Microsoft word user has ever considered themselves to have opened a &quot;buffer&quot;. They open &quot;files&quot;. They move &quot;windows&quot; around, not &quot;frames.&quot; They cut and paste not kill and yank, etc.
&lt;p&gt;You are basically making a commitment to being or becoming a power user. I certainly would not have put up with it if I didn't think it was going to save me a lot of time as a software developer (and it does, everyday). I doubt anyone invests the mental effort to deal with learning emacs nowadays unless this is their goal. If you just want to do &quot;casual&quot; text editing emacs is a very weird choice in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &quot;modernizing&quot; Emacs (however defined) is likely to be a waste of the project's time, since its look is not what's holding it back, Ahmed Khanzada &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/863691n4xl.wl-me@enzu.ru/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. For example: &quot;&lt;span&gt;Terminal-based Vim is not like a modern application, yet is more popular than Emacs.&lt;/span&gt;&quot; The appeal of an editor that can be extended using the Lisp language is somewhat limited, he said. Spending a bunch of time and energy to give it a modern look would not change that and, by the time the work was done, the definition of &quot;modern&quot; will have changed again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Popularity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kangas &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/CADwFkm=Vashc18sr=+h8XEdLAKa38U94jsnzc+TgABWFx0uQ9g@mail.gmail.com/&quot;&gt;wondered&lt;/a&gt; about the assertion of Vim's popularity; Khanzada &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/86blno9yle.wl-me@enzu.ru/&quot;&gt;pointed&lt;/a&gt; to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2019#development-environments-and-tools&quot;&gt;2019 survey&lt;/a&gt; that showed Vim with a substantial lead over Emacs (20% to 3% is what he reported, though it shows 25% to 4% as of this writing). That survey showed that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_Studio_Code&quot;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; (VSC) is the clear winner, however, with 50+% of respondents using that tool. You could perhaps quibble with the survey's methodology, but the broad-brush numbers do not seem wildly out of line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That set off some discussion of why users prefer the experience with VSC. &quot;&lt;span&gt;We need to figure out why VSC is so popular, and then fill in the areas that Emacs is missing&lt;/span&gt;&quot;, Po Lu &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/875zdv9jf3.fsf@yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. Bob Newell &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/CADoYgq-tj61Pfgm=zVJ50ZLjG+nTcLt_p0W0pZa4sFzsb59Tfg@mail.gmail.com/&quot;&gt;thought&lt;/a&gt; that &quot;&lt;span&gt;the goal of making Emacs more accessible and more appealing is laudable and ambitious&lt;/span&gt;&quot;; it is something that the project could accomplish, he said. He is worried, though, that today's software is aimed at &quot;instant gratification&quot; rather than long-term usability—and power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, make Emacs appealing and user friendly. But don't forget that a masterful tool in the end requires mastery, which can't come for free. I certainly draw the line at saying Emacs is for everyone. I'm not saying it's only for some sort of snooty &quot;elite&quot; but I am saying that it's for those who are willing to learn, seeing some extra work as the aforementioned long-term investment, and who have the patience reach a worthy goal a little later rather than right this very minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stallman &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/E1jQi0V-000320-Sf@fencepost.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;agreed&lt;/a&gt; with that sentiment. But he would also &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/E1jQM1d-0007n9-BV@fencepost.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;like to see&lt;/a&gt; Emacs return to popularity &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/E1jQi44-0003eV-0u@fencepost.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;as an editor of text for publication&lt;/a&gt;. Several noted that &lt;a href=&quot;https://orgmode.org/&quot;&gt;Org mode&lt;/a&gt; is already being used successfully for text-publication purposes. That mode is &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/E1jR5ss-0001xM-L9@fencepost.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;not familiar&lt;/a&gt; to Stallman and he was unable to learn much about using it for word processing by reading the documentation. Zaretskii &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/83v9lregx0.fsf@gnu.org/&quot;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt; that there is a high barrier to learning Org mode from its documentation, at least for the word-processing use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, though, it seems quite unlikely that some putative, well-documented word-processing Emacs mode is likely to have users flocking to the editor. But Stallman &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/E1jPzXg-0003tH-MT@fencepost.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; that the user profile for Emacs was much broader 30 years ago; he would like to see it be that way again. He personally does not see rounded corners as part of that, though he is not opposed to efforts in that direction; &quot;&lt;span&gt;[...] if you want to attract more users to Emacs, I think there are more important areas for improvement.&lt;/span&gt;&quot; Lu &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/87imhw431x.fsf@yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;had some ideas&lt;/a&gt; along those lines, for example using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/StarterKits&quot;&gt;starter kits&lt;/a&gt; (or packs) to help make the editor &quot;&lt;span&gt;more friendly to newcomers&lt;/span&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a difference of opinion about making changes to the defaults, though, in order to help newcomers. If changes need to be made for the sake of newcomers, ndame &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/nBz61t2TEA4FJbun5KtDMQlnaI3Y8jE1loAcCJPTgilcVDC5ns7QyUh6WUfGEFn0Bnw5od3SX-iZRZ08Sfj26GUO64h91QPuc2HeOzWyPVU=@protonmail.com/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;, established users can just turn them off. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/CuaMode&quot;&gt;Cua Mode&lt;/a&gt;, which adds the &quot;standard&quot; keybindings for things like cut and paste (i.e. ctrl-c, ctrl-x, ctrl-v) to Emacs, should be on by default; &quot;&lt;span&gt;it could make the life of new users easier if they didn't have to turn it on explicitly and they could use their copy/paste keys from the start like they are used it to in other tools&lt;/span&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Lu &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/87k12bdgx7.fsf@yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; adding a button for newcomers to turn on those features from the splash screen instead. Better still might be for Emacs to recognize a possible newcomer, ndame &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/RtuoskwUPgcjfttdVWYUzFKTAPGRcbaMR_zTV1bZGTDbo_07pkyfq6avexjdhEWZDNZmI3WCFZjgIhiIOEwODgZZTqN_QjYFa7S70kRZ4zU=@protonmail.com/&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BigQuote&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;A button can work too. Or if emacs is started with no config file then it can ask &quot;Are you using Emacs for the first time?&quot; If the user says yes then it can offer to set some convenience features like CUA mode.
&lt;p&gt;And if the user says no then everything is as usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was some discussion of gathering feedback before deciding to change defaults and such, but Dmitry Gutov &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/45098d13-2770-4a19-6f82-b22276eb51c8@yandex.ru/&quot;&gt;wondered&lt;/a&gt; if existing users are even relevant. If expanding the reach of Emacs is the goal, it may make sense to look at the problem differently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BigQuote&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;So for all questions about changing defaults, we should ask ourselves, do we prioritize the existing 5% (or 3%, as SO poll says) userbase that will naturally continue shrinking over the years, or whether we prefer to make life easier and more productive for the users that should come later.
&lt;p&gt;And it's not like existing, long-time users can't grow to like the new defaults (even after a certain amount of grumbling).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lu &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/877dy91mb0.fsf@yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;disagreed&lt;/a&gt;; &quot;&lt;span&gt;We should prioritize existing users over hypothetical users that don't even exist yet.&lt;/span&gt;&quot; But Gutov &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/0ce06d95-0593-bc55-983f-6b6601503a1a@yandex.ru/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; that might be shortsighted; &quot;&lt;span&gt;I don't want Emacs to die out, and it will if we don't do the work of attracting new users.&lt;/span&gt;&quot; No real conclusion was reached; everyone would like to see the number of Emacs users (developers, testers, documentation writers, ...) grow, but how to do so is unclear at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Licensing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to rounded corners, Zaretskii &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/83lfmxgt6c.fsf@gnu.org/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; that the only thing standing in the way of that was code to implement it; &quot;&lt;span&gt;[...] patches to add such capabilities to Emacs are most welcome&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. But Emacs is multi-platform, Gutov &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/ce35ba27-622e-4f78-fc00-7f17ef6d7dcb@yandex.ru/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;, which means that buttons look different on each. Even on the same platform, different graphics toolkits give different looks—and the looks change between toolkit releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Bennée &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/87r1wng2ki.fsf@linaro.org/&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that &quot;&lt;span&gt;unifying under a single cross-platform toolkit like GTK+&lt;/span&gt;&quot; would avoid some parts of the problem, but he also noted that a longstanding &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=85715&quot;&gt;bug&lt;/a&gt; in GTK+ had caused him to use Emacs with the Lucid toolkit instead. He also worried about the next generation: &quot;&lt;span&gt;I've been thinking about text editors for my children to use as they graduate from point and click programming to proper text and even I'm not sure I want their first experience to be Emacs.&lt;/span&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zaretskii &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/83o8rrenn1.fsf@gnu.org/&quot;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt; that GTK+ is not really cross-platform. In addition, the bug in question is not considered to be one by the GNOME developers, which led Ulrich Mueller to &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/u8sivv1lb_-_@gentoo.org/&quot;&gt;muse&lt;/a&gt; about a switch to Qt. But Stallman was quick to &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/E1jPGhC-0003i1-W4@fencepost.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;put the kibosh&lt;/a&gt; on that; Qt is only available for GPL 2 and 3, using it would mean that if there is a GPL 4 someday, Emacs could not switch to it. &quot;&lt;span&gt;So we must avoid using Qt.&lt;/span&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electron was also &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/CAO2hHWZGk0iq0ROoLoeLGwDYRmu-sQeMJuVQ-rziFd+O5Z=8ng@mail.gmail.com/&quot;&gt;raised&lt;/a&gt; as a possibility, but it turns out to have &quot;&lt;span&gt;freedom issues&lt;/span&gt;&quot;, Lu &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/878siptegk.fsf@yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. It is not clear how serious any of these ideas were; switching graphics toolkits is a decidedly non-trivial undertaking. It does seem like an indication that some in the Emacs development community are getting frustrated with the GUI version(s) of the editor. Beyond that, many of the Emacs developers do not even use the GTK+ version because of the bug, which leads to less interest in improving that version of Emacs; it all seems to be something of a mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The icons used by Emacs were also questioned in the thread, with licensing rearing its head there as well. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/&quot;&gt;Emacs subreddit&lt;/a&gt; is apparently fertile ground for thoughts and suggestions as it came up a few times in the thread. For example, ndame &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/qcx9gTVkYn55kqfq16drSfrURpHlTlC3JVCnh8v0MWHsJCFHzg-CPbHgaAw4SP6otQ_Q1VED_2Wrx5XrzNvWtAlZeryp7ssZc8ANKNL7Xv8=@protonmail.com/&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; &quot;&lt;span&gt;that a user posted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/6sIHOGt.png&quot;&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt; of an emacs toolbar with really sad looking icons at the end&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. There are icon sets available under the GPL that could be used instead, they asserted. But Zaretskii &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/83y2qvcjv6.fsf@gnu.org/&quot;&gt;cautioned&lt;/a&gt; that things may not be that clear-cut:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to point us to GPLed icons that can be incorporated in Emacs. At the time, the situation was nowhere as easy as you imply, but maybe things have changed since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several icon sets were suggested, including GNOME icons, some from Wikimedia, and those from KDE, all of which are available under various free licenses (GPL, Creative Commons, LGPL). But there is more work to do than just identifying candidates, Zaretskii &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/83k12ed20s.fsf@gnu.org/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BigQuote&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;Someone™ needs to invest the time and effort to figure out the legal issues, find the icons that we want out of those which are legally fit, and post the resulting information. We did that process at the time (AFAIR, quite a few of our icons come from Gnome/GTK), and it wasn't easy.
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, someone could create our own icons, in which case they could be even prettier than the ones pointed out here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, this is a non-trivial job, and volunteers are most welcome to do it. I don't think anyone is happy about the icons shown on the tool bar by Message mode; the only reason we use them is that we couldn't find better ones that are free and suitable for inclusion in Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, ndame &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/9GxTqx0raB6NkyAQ4gjUHfoCFK4rgmvRKZaUUxM-p6WOuO_3oJOBYiXI4L8pGz-VtHtgYKJ14Z1nU9UmZ68nJLO18nLYnaBaqBxLEaNN9mg=@protonmail.com/&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt;, shouldn't icons that come from GNOME, a longstanding free-software project, be perfectly acceptable to use in Emacs? Sadly, it is not so easy as that, Zaretskii &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/83d086cu05.fsf@gnu.org/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;&lt;span&gt;IANAL, but I think it has to be GPL v2+ at least. And perhaps we would also need the copyright assigned to the FSF.&lt;/span&gt;&quot; For example, the Wikimedia icons are available under the the LGPLv3 and Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike (CC BY-SA) 3.0 licenses, but neither of those would work for pieces that are part of the Emacs program, Stallman &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/E1jPzZX-0004DO-HS@fencepost.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. Without the &quot;or later&quot; on the LGPL grant, the Qt problem would exist; CC BY-SA 3.0 &quot;&lt;span&gt;is incompatible with every version of the GPL&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. But that may not matter in the end:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BigQuote&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;If the icons would NOT be part of the program, Emacs, then there is no conflict.
&lt;p&gt;The Emacs distribution contains many works, including textual, art, and small programs, which are distinct from the program, Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zaretskii and Stallman were able to determine that icons for Emacs fall into that category, so they simply need to be available under any free license, which should simplify things—if someone gets the time and energy to work on the problem. Like most projects, Emacs suffers from a shortage of human power; a project to improve the GUI that may not be widely used by those developers could go wanting. And that, in a lot of ways, sums up the situation with the editor project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Moving forward&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emacs is quite useful for its adherents; many of them see it is their main interface to their computers. Others use it regularly but less universally. There are even longtime Vim users (who may have started on vi, in truth) that need Emacs for certain tasks—me for example. It serves all of these users well, but does it really still have a role in ten, twenty, or forty years? It is not an easy question to answer, of course; certainly it will still be with us in both ten and twenty years, but how many users will it have in forty?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the problem is that the dedicated following for Emacs is also pretty resistant to change to any major degree. That's not meant as a knock of any sort, simply an observation. There are plenty of examples in that huge thread of ideas that were seemingly shot down because they represent change that might upset existing users. But it would seem that some changes of some sort are needed to bring in new blood. If few or no new users are coming in and nothing is done to attract more, it can only lead to eventual extinction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that is not the path that Emacs is on—or if it is, that it changes direction before (too) long. It is one of the earliest free-software programs in existence; pre-dating the term &quot;free software&quot; by nearly a decade, in fact. Of course, the code itself need never disappear entirely, but a vibrant—growing—Emacs community would be wonderful to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth, we have barely scratched the surface of that mega-thread. There are plenty of sub-threads that went completely unmentioned here; those interested in Emacs development—warts and all—will find plenty to read and digest there. Whether Emacs ends up with rounded corners or not seems like simply the tip of the iceberg of things that might need to be addressed to make Emacs more newcomer-friendly. How that can happen within that community remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;Form&quot; readability=&quot;1.2534246575342&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5068493150685&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you like this article?&lt;/strong&gt; Please accept our &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Promo/slink-trial2-3/claim&quot;&gt;trial subscription offer&lt;/a&gt; to be able to see more content like it and to participate in the discussion.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr width=&quot;60%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Login/?target=/Articles/819452/&quot;&gt;Log in&lt;/a&gt; to post comments)</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 19:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>todsacerdoti</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/819452/1480c3a59d3d9093/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Lenovo ThinkPad Range with Ryzen 4000 and 4000 Pro Mobile</title>
<link>https://www.anandtech.com/show/15772/new-lenovo-thinkpad-range-with-ryzen-4000-4000-pro-mobile</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.anandtech.com/show/15772/new-lenovo-thinkpad-range-with-ryzen-4000-4000-pro-mobile</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Small to medium business owners generally want a something in a compact design, to lug it around to a business meeting to take essential notes, but ultimately can be managed from a central administration system across hundreds or thousands of employees. Catering for this market is Lenovo, and it has announced a pair of new models designed for its SMB customers. The Lenovo ThinkPad E14 and E15 series of notebooks have been improved in design and are now available with up to an including an AMD Ryzen 7 4700U APU. Also announced are AMD's ThinkPad T14, T14s, L14, L15, and smaller X13 models all featuring the latest AMD Ryzen 4000 PRO series processors with extra security features designed for professional and business users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding to its portfolio, including its Intel 10th gen mobile refresh ThinkPad E14 and E15 series, SMB users looking now have an AMD Ryzen based option. Similar in design to the previous E14 and E15 series, the new Lenovo ThinkPad E series will be available with Ryzen 4000 Mobile. Lenovo has stated that it has an improved screen to body ratio of 85%, although it doesn't provide the metric which this is measured against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/15772/Lenovo%20ThinkPad%20E15%202.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/15772/Lenovo%20ThinkPad%20E15%202_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lenovo ThinkPad E15 with Ryzen 4000 Mobile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lenovo ThinkPad series is is available with an eight-core AMD Ryzen 7 4700U APU without SMT and has seven Radeon graphics cores to power the display. While Lenovo hasn't detailed the display or the other vital specifications at this time, it has added a touch fingerprint reader and an optional IR camera powered by Mirametrix. They are quoted as specialists in security and privacy with its gaze tracking technology. This combined with its Glance software which is integrated within adds an extra element of security which respond to a users presence and can automatically lock the laptop when users step away. The touch fingerprint reader is built into the power button and allows users the ability to turn the system on with one touch, which is more secure than conventional power buttons and is suited to business environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/15772/Lenovo%20X13.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/15772/Lenovo%20X13_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lenovo ThinkPad X13 is the most portable from its range&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lenovo has also announced new ThinkPad T, X, and L series models powered by AMD Ryzen PRO 4000 series processors. The Lenovo ThinkPad 14 Gen 1 is advertised to include a projected 16-hour battery life and a thin lightweight frame of 17.9 mm and 1.46 Kg, with an even bigger 20-hour battery life on its uprated T14s model. The ThinkPad T14s has a slimmer profile at 16.1 mm thick, with a weight starting at 1.27 Kg. The smaller ThinkPad X13 model has a claimed battery life of up to 17.5 hours, with a thickness of 16.9 mm and a weight on an upward curve starting at just 1.28 Kg. This makes the ThinkPad X13 the lightest from its announced stack.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/15772/Lenovo%20ThinkPad%20L15.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/15772/Lenovo%20ThinkPad%20L15_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Lenovo ThinkPad L15 powered by Ryzen 4000 PRO Mobile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving down the new Lenovo ThinkPad stack are the L14 and L15 models which are the largest in size with a thickness of 20.4 mm on the L14, whereas the L15 is slightly chunkier with a thickness of 21 mm. The ThinkPad L14 will have a weight starting at 1.61 Kg, while the L15 will weigh upwards of 1.98 Kg. Both include a projected battery life of up to 14-hours, which Lenovo claims it has used the MobileMark14 benchmark to get this data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the Lenovo ThinkPad T, X, and L series models will feature AMD's newest Ryzen 4000 PRO mobile series processors, with extra layers of built-in security features, and feature Lenovo's Self-Healing BIOS, and Lenovo ThinkShield. &lt;span&gt;These new models will be available from June, with prices starting at $849 for the T14, $1029 for the T14s, and $849 for the X13 series. Also available from June will be the L14 and L15 series of ThinkPad models which will both start at $649.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As for the Lenovo ThinkPad E14 and E15 series, both will be available from June and come with a price tag starting at $639.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Related Reading&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 17:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>awiesenhofer</dc:creator>
<og:title>New Lenovo ThinkPad Range with Ryzen 4000 &amp; 4000 PRO Mobile</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.anandtech.com/show/15772/new-lenovo-thinkpad-range-with-ryzen-4000-4000-pro-mobile</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.anandtech.com/doci/15772/Lenovo%20ThinkPad%20E15_678x452.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.anandtech.com/show/15772/new-lenovo-thinkpad-range-with-ryzen-4000-4000-pro-mobile</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google ends plans for smart city in Toronto</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52572362</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52572362</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Aerial shot of Toronto with the waterfront land in front&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/13F01/production/_106856618_waterfronttoronto.gif&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Waterfront Toronto&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The former dockland and industrial area of Toronto that Sidewalk Labs planned to develop sits on the edge of Lake Ontario
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Google's sister firm Sidewalk Labs has scrapped a plan to build a smart city in Canada, citing complications caused by the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For several years it had pursued ambitions to build a digital-first city in Toronto &quot;from the internet up&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chief executive Dan Doctoroff blamed &quot;unprecedented economic uncertainty&quot; for abandoning the plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The project had proved controversial and Sidewalk Labs had already been forced to scale back its ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/sidewalk-talk/why-were-no-longer-pursuing-the-quayside-project-and-what-s-next-for-sidewalk-labs-9a61de3fee3a&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;In a blog post&lt;/a&gt;, Mr Doctoroff said: &quot;As unprecedented economic uncertainty has set in around the world, and in the Toronto real estate market, it has become too difficult to make the 12-acre project financially viable without sacrificing core parts of the plan we had developed together with Waterfront Toronto to build a truly inclusive, sustainable community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I believe the ideas we have developed over the last two-and-a-half years will represent a meaningful contribution to the work of tackling big urban problems, particularly in the areas of affordability and sustainability.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vision was to have a city full of technology, from autonomous cars to innovative ways of collecting rubbish, and hundreds of sensors collecting data on air quality and the movements of people. Buildings would be sustainable and built in radical new ways, and cycle lanes would be heated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But some questioned how Sidewalk Labs had won the contract. When it emerged that it planned to develop a much larger site than originally stated, a lobby group of citizens opposing the plans emerged, asking why they would want to be &quot;lab rats&quot; in a digital experiment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An independent panel was set up to scrutinise its plans and released a report suggesting some of its ideas were &quot;tech for tech's sake&quot;, and potentially unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sidewalk Labs was eventually given a tentative green light to continue its plan, but it was heavily scaled back from the 190-acre site it wanted to work with to a 12-acre piece of land. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was also told that any data it collected from its sensors would have to become a public asset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stephen Diamond is chairman of Waterfront Toronto, the body set up to oversee development of the site. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reacting to Sidewalk's announcement, he said: &quot;While this is not the outcome we had hoped for, Waterfront Toronto offers thanks and appreciation to Sidewalk Labs for its vision, effort and the many commitments that both the company and its employees have made to the future of Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Quayside remains an excellent opportunity to explore innovative solutions to affordable housing, improved mobility, climate change and several other urban challenges that Toronto - and cities around the world - must address in order to continue to grow and succeed.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his blog, Dan Doctoroff said the firm continued to invest in start-ups &quot;working on everything from robotic furniture to digital electricity&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We continue to work internally on factory-made mass timber construction that can improve housing affordability&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>colinprince</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google ends plans for smart city in Toronto</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Sister firm Sidewalk Labs cites Covid-19 as the reason for stepping back from its ambitious plan.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52572362</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13F01/production/_106856618_waterfronttoronto.gif</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52572362</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Cost of Free Doughnuts: 70 Years of Regret</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/money/2012/07/13/156737801/the-cost-of-free-doughnuts-70-years-of-regret</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/money/2012/07/13/156737801/the-cost-of-free-doughnuts-70-years-of-regret</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res156740239&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2012/07/13/8e02281v1-a4643e6defc77b420d078b8ccab425a868aae477-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2012/07/13/8e02281v1-a4643e6defc77b420d078b8ccab425a868aae477-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7.3183856502242&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;9.9951923076923&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. soldiers receive refreshments, including doughnuts, from an American Red Cross clubmobile in London. Soldiers today still resent a Red Cross move to charge for doughnuts. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lcweb2.loc.gov/service/pnp/fsa/8e02000/8e02200/8e02281v.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Library of Congress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lcweb2.loc.gov/service/pnp/fsa/8e02000/8e02200/8e02281v.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Library of Congress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the online services you probably use are free. Gmail is free. Facebook is free. Yahoo News and NPR are free (though we certainly &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/stations/donate/index.php?ps=st273&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;solicit contributions&lt;/a&gt;!). But increasingly, online companies are trying to figure out how to start charging, at least for some services, some of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But today, we have a cautionary tale about charging for things that were once free. It's the story of how one small mistake moving away from free can cause trouble that's impossible to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story starts when Russ Roberts, a George Mason University economist, started hearing about how veterans don't like the Red Cross. That struck him as odd, and when he asked about it, he always got the same answer: the doughnuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;And I thought, the doughnuts?&quot; Roberts says. &quot;What could that be?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to any VFW hall, even today, and you'll get the same story: During World War II, the Red Cross had comfort stations for soldiers overseas, with free coffee and free doughnuts. Then, in 1942, the Red Cross started charging for the doughnuts. Soldiers have held a grudge ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turns out it's true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It keeps coming up, that they were charged for coffee and doughnuts,&quot; says Susan Watson, archivist for the Red Cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organization started charging only because the U.S. Secretary of War asked it to. British soldiers had to pay for their snacks, and the free doughnuts for Americans were causing tensions. So the Red Cross complied, after protesting to no avail. It didn't last long — for most of the last 70 years, Red Cross doughnuts have remained free — but veterans haven't forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chalk it up to something called categorical change, says Uri Simonsohn, a University of Pennsylvania business professor. Price changes, people can adjust to. But this was different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Imagine, for Thanksgiving, you go to your parents' for dinner and after a nice dinner they say, 'That's going to be $10 per person,' &quot; Simonsohn says. &quot;You would be upset.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem isn't the price — $10 for a good turkey dinner might not be such a bad deal — but that you're being charged in the first place. It changes the relationship. For the veterans, the Red Cross went from being a little like Mom, to being the corner store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for all the Internet companies out there looking to charge for your service — take heed. Changing categories is really difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>leoh</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Cost Of Free Doughnuts: 70 Years Of Regret</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/money/2012/07/13/156737801/the-cost-of-free-doughnuts-70-years-of-regret</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>When the Red Cross began charging soldiers for snacks during World War II, it learned a painful lesson in the economics of free stuff.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2012/07/13/8e02281v1_wide-661637be7b88a6c9cdebb385a02d056485e9c25b.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/money/2012/07/13/156737801/the-cost-of-free-doughnuts-70-years-of-regret</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Driving engineers to an arbitrary date is a value destroying mistake</title>
<link>https://iism.org/article/driving-engineers-to-an-arbitrary-date-is-a-value-destroying-mistake-49</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://iism.org/article/driving-engineers-to-an-arbitrary-date-is-a-value-destroying-mistake-49</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://iism.org/article/driving-engineers-to-an-arbitrary-date-is-a-value-destroying-mistake-49&quot;&gt;https://iism.org/article/driving-engineers-to-an-arbitrary-date-is-a-value-destroying-mistake-49&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23103582&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23103582&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 223&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 96&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 14:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>signa11</dc:creator>
<og:description>Executive Mandates shutdown the value discovery efforts of software teams</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://iism.org/article/driving-engineers-to-an-arbitrary-date-is-a-value-destroying-mistake-49</og:url>
<og:title>Driving engineers to an arbitrary date is a value destroying mistake</og:title>
<og:image>https://iism.org/material-assets/software-management-essentials-product-execution/driving-to-a-date-is-a-value-destroying-journey-small-r1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://iism.org/article/driving-engineers-to-an-arbitrary-date-is-a-value-destroying-mistake-49</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GCC 10.1 Released</title>
<link>https://gcc.gnu.org/pipermail/gcc-announce/2020/000163.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gcc.gnu.org/pipermail/gcc-announce/2020/000163.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;GCC 10.1 Released&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Index&quot; href=&quot;index.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;made&quot; href=&quot;mailto:jakub%40redhat.com?Subject=Re:%20Re%3A%20GCC%2010.1%20Released&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3C20200507125959.GO8462%40tucnak%3E&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;index,nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Previous&quot; href=&quot;000000.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;33.674157303371&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jakub Jelinek&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jakub%40redhat.com?Subject=Re:%20Re%3A%20GCC%2010.1%20Released&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3C20200507125959.GO8462%40tucnak%3E&quot; title=&quot;GCC 10.1 Released&quot;&gt;jakub@redhat.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thu May 7 12:59:59 GMT 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
A year has lapsed away since the release of last major
GCC release, more than 33 years passed since the first
public GCC release and the GCC developers survived
repository conversion from SVN to GIT earlier this year.

Today, we are glad to announce another major GCC release, 10.1.

This release makes great progress in the C++20 language support,
both on the compiler and library sides [1], some C2X enhancements,
various optimization enhancements and bug fixes, several new
hardware enablement changes and enhancements to the compiler back-ends
and many other changes.  There is even a new experimental static
analysis pass [2].

Some code that compiled successfully with older GCC versions might require
source changes, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://gcc.gnu.org/gcc-10/porting_to.html&quot;&gt;http://gcc.gnu.org/gcc-10/porting_to.html&lt;/a&gt; for
details.

See

  &lt;a href=&quot;https://gcc.gnu.org/gcc-10/changes.html&quot;&gt;https://gcc.gnu.org/gcc-10/changes.html&lt;/a&gt;

for more information about changes in GCC 10.1.

This release is available from the FTP servers listed here:

 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/order/ftp.html&quot;&gt;http://www.gnu.org/order/ftp.html&lt;/a&gt;

The release is in gcc/gcc-10.1.0/ subdirectory.

If you encounter difficulties using GCC 10.1, please do not contact me
directly.  Instead, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://gcc.gnu.org&quot;&gt;http://gcc.gnu.org&lt;/a&gt; for information about
getting help.

Driving a leading free software project such as GNU Compiler Collection
would not be possible without support from its many contributors.
Not to only mention its developers but especially its regular testers
and users which contribute to its high quality.  The list of individuals
is too large to thank individually!

Please consider a donation to the GNU Toolchain Fund to support the
continued development of GCC! [3]

----

[1] See &lt;a href=&quot;https://gcc.gnu.org/projects/cxx-status.html,&quot;&gt;https://gcc.gnu.org/projects/cxx-status.html,&lt;/a&gt;
    and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gcc.gnu.org/onlinedocs/libstdc++/manual/status.html#status.iso.2020&quot;&gt;https://gcc.gnu.org/onlinedocs/libstdc++/manual/status.html#status.iso.2020&lt;/a&gt;

[2] See &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/03/26/static-analysis-in-gcc-10&quot;&gt;https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/03/26/static-analysis-in-gcc-10&lt;/a&gt;

[3] See &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.fsf.org/civicrm/contribute/transact?reset=1&amp;amp;id=57&quot;&gt;https://my.fsf.org/civicrm/contribute/transact?reset=1&amp;amp;id=57&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gcc.gnu.org/mailman/listinfo/gcc-announce&quot;&gt;More information about the gcc-announce mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 14:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nayefc</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gcc.gnu.org/pipermail/gcc-announce/2020/000163.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Keybase Alternatives?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23103386</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23103386</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Ask HN: Keybase Alternatives?&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.0843537414966&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.1938775510204&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;23103386&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23103386&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Keybase Alternatives?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_23103386&quot;&gt;632 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=capableweb&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;capableweb&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23103386&quot;&gt;10 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_23103386&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=23103386&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D23103386&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Keybase%20Alternatives%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Keybase%20Alternatives%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=23103386&amp;amp;auth=ce70aa5baee075da94c8cbd53117623e3d9f0ad8&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23103386&quot;&gt;161 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16.229838709677&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;14.838709677419&quot;&gt;Since Keybase is being acquired by Zoom (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23102430&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23102430&lt;/a&gt;), it would be lazy to not start looking at alternatives already
&lt;p&gt;I myself mostly use the following features from Keybase: Chat, KBFS, Git repositories and encrypting messages sent out-of-band via PGP in Keybase (and the various cryptographic tools [signing, validation etc])&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What alternatives have the features outlined above, but are ideally either FOSS or at least not run by a for-profit company? I mainly used Keybase to make using those features easier, so please don't suggest the cli of gnupgp (or similar) as alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 14:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>capableweb</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23103386</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft&amp;#039;s GitHub account allegedly hacked, 500GB stolen</title>
<link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsofts-github-account-allegedly-hacked-500gb-stolen/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsofts-github-account-allegedly-hacked-500gb-stolen/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Microsoft GitHub&quot; height=&quot;455&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/content/hl-images/2020/05/06/MSFT_open_source.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hacker claims to have stolen over 500GB of data from Microsoft's private GitHub repositories, BleepingComputer has learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This evening, a hacker going by the name Shiny Hunters contacted BleepingComputer to tell us they had hacked into the Microsoft GitHub account, gaining full access to the software giant's 'Private' repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Actor's proof of access to Microsoft's private GitHub repos&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/Microsoft/g/github-repo-breach/private-repo.png&quot; width=&quot;942&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actor's proof of access to Microsoft's private GitHub repos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The individual told us that they then downloaded 500GB of private projects and initially planned on selling it, but has now decided to leak it for free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the file stamps in the leaked files, the breach may have occurred on March 28th, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Leaked data listing showing the breach date​​​​​​​&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/Microsoft/g/github-repo-breach/timestamps.jpg&quot; width=&quot;712&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leaked data listing showing the breach date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shiny Hunters told BleepingComputer he no longer has access to the account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Private repositories leaked&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a teaser, the hacker offered 1GB of files on a hacker forum for registered members to use site 'credits' to gain access to the leaked data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As some of the leaked files contain Chinese text or references to latelee.org, other threat actors on the forum do not feel that the data is real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a directory listing and samples of other private repositories sent to BleepingComputer, the stolen data appears to be mostly code samples, test projects, an eBook, and other generic items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some private repositories look a bit more interesting such as ones named some 'wssd cloud agent', a The Rust/WinRT language projection', and a 'PowerSweep' PowerShell project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, from what was shared, there does not appear to be anything significant for Microsoft to worry about, such as Windows or Office source code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber intelligence firm Under the Breach, who saw the leak on the hacker forum, also does not think there is much to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They did express concern that private API keys or passwords could have accidentally been left behind in some of the private repositories like other developers have done in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/underthebreach/status/1258168260492701702&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tweet&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; width=&quot;488&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/Microsoft/g/github-repo-breach/ub-tweet.jpg&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft employee Sam Smith &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/samsmithnz/status/1258174191834222594&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;replied&lt;/a&gt; to Under the Breach's tweet stating that he thought the leak was fake as &quot;Msft has a “rule” that GitHub repos must be public within 30 days.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BleepingComputer has contacted Microsoft to confirm if these are indeed legitimate files but have not received a reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a developing story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 13:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>badRNG</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsofts-github-account-allegedly-hacked-500gb-stolen/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Microsoft's GitHub account allegedly hacked, 500GB stolen</og:title>
<og:description>A hacker has claimed to have hacked into Microsoft's GitHub account and downloaded over 500GB of 'Private' repositories, BleepingComputer has learned.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.bleepstatic.com/content/hl-images/2020/05/06/MSFT_open_source.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsofts-github-account-allegedly-hacked-500gb-stolen/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>