<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Container technologies at Coinbase: Why Kubernetes is not part of our stack</title>
<link>https://blog.coinbase.com/container-technologies-at-coinbase-d4ae118dcb6c</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.coinbase.com/container-technologies-at-coinbase-d4ae118dcb6c</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;3d05&quot; class=&quot;es dz aw as ar ct et eu fe ev ew ff ex ey fg ez fa fh fb fc fi fd&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;be&quot;&gt;Why Kubernetes is not part of our stack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fj&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;n fk fl fm fn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o n&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/@coinbaseblog?source=post_page-----d4ae118dcb6c----------------------&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Coinbase&quot; class=&quot;r fo fp fq&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/96/96/2*aPYWIFK3sVKT1KK9NwNOAQ.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;48&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6953&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;By Drew Rothstein, Director of Engineering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;c92f&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;TLDR: Container orchestration platforms are complex and amazing technologies, helping some businesses and teams solve a whole suite of problems. What’s commonly overlooked however, is that container technologies also create a large set of challenges that must be overcome to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hjacobs/kubernetes-failure-stories&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;prevent failures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ff9c&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;iw&quot;&gt;This post is adapted from an internal blog post as I haven’t seen many write-ups like this externally available. Minimal redaction has been done and images have been added to provide more flare. If you are interested in working on some of what we discuss below — we are actively hiring on our&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/careers/positions?department=Engineering%2520-%2520Infrastructure&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;iw&quot;&gt;Infrastructure team&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;iw&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;49ec&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;a6b0&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Before jumping into the current day, it is important to understand the technologies that led us here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;98f3&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;There is a more detailed history in Chapter 7 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/enterprise-docker/9781491994986/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Enterprise Docker&lt;/a&gt; if interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3f6c&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Without containers as we know them today, let’s go back ~10yrs. At this time we did not have/use docker, rkt, or any other mainstream containerized wrapper/service. Most large-scale companies built in-house systems to bundle their applications to go from source code to deployment in production. What engineers ran on their machine was usually not what was running in production or if it was, it was lovingly one-off built/packaged in a manner that was likely very custom and complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c0bf&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;In this world of an in-house system to bundle and deploy applications there was a large operations team, usually in a platform or infrastructure organization that would manage the bundle/building processes, deployment, and post-deployment. These roles were generally highly operational involving troubleshooting bad hosts, diagnosing specific dependency issues on OS patches/upgrades, etc. Post-deployment had minimal to no automated orchestration and involved capacity planning, ordering more servers, getting them racked/installed, and somehow getting software updated on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c481&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;If you were lucky, there was some regular process to build a “golden image” (think: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.packer.io/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Packer&lt;/a&gt; by Hashicorp) that was well documented, potentially even codified, and run by a Continuous Integration system such as Hudson (previous to Jenkins {&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hudson_(software)&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ref&lt;/a&gt;}). These images were somehow distributed to your systems either manually or automatically through some sort-of configuration management utilities and then started in some ordering, likely with parallel SSH or similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dcab&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;This past decade everything has changed. We went from gigantic monolithic applications to breaking down services into more discrete and less coupled parts. We went from having to build/own your own compute to having a managed or Public Cloud offering with a couple clicks and a credit card. We went from scaling applications vertically to re-architecting them to scale horizontally. All of this was happening at the same time that societal changes were also occurring: cell phones in every pocket, network speeds improving, network latencies dropping across the world, to doing everything online from booking your dog walker to commoditized video conferencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c7a2&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;AWS’s offering in 2009 was quite limited. For perspective, it wasn’t until 2008 when AWS’s EC2 offering exited beta and began offering an SLA (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_Amazon_Web_Services&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ref&lt;/a&gt;). For reference, GCP didn’t launch a compute offering in GA until 2013 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Cloud_Platform&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ref&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;d5a8&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;Why do companies choose to containerize their applications?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b5f0&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Companies choose to containerize their applications to increase engineering output/developer productivity in a quick, safe, and reliable manner. Containerizing is a choice made vs. building images, although containers can sometimes be built into images, but that is out of scope (&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenewstack.io/bakery-foundation-container-images-microservices/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ref&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;930d&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Containers enable engineers to develop, test, and run their applications locally in the same or similar manner that they will run in other environments (staging and production). Containers enable bundling of dependencies to be articulated and explicit vs. implied (the OS will always contain package $foo that my service depends on). Containers allow for more discreet service encapsulation and resource definition (using X CPUs and Y GB of Memory). Containers inherently enable you to think about scaling your application horizontally vs. vertically, resulting in more robust architectural decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d074&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Some of these points could be argued in great detail. These are purposely bold and a bit over-extended to move the conversation forward as this isn’t a discussion of the pros/cons of containerization or &lt;em class=&quot;iw&quot;&gt;service-ification&lt;/em&gt; (i.e. the breakdown of monolithic applications to a proliferation of more discreet services that run separately).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a0d4&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;What about virtualization?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6e68&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Virtualization is the concept of being able to run multiple containers on an OS virtualized system (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OS-level_virtualization&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ref&lt;/a&gt;). Containers can only see the devices/resources granted to it. On a managed compute platform such as AWS you are actually running below a Hypervisor (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypervisor&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ref&lt;/a&gt;) which manages the VMs that your OS and resulting containers run within.&lt;/p&gt;

Simplified diagram
&lt;p id=&quot;23f2&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Virtualization enables the world of containers today. Without the ability to virtualize, hardware resources running multiple applications in containers wouldn’t be possible today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;892f&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;What problem does a container orchestration platform (Mesos, Kubernetes, Docker Swarm) solve?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2e17&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;A container orchestration platform solves the following types of problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;6e91&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;Managed/Standardized deployment tooling (deployment).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;c219&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;Scaling of applications based-on some defined heuristic (horizontal scaling).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;9f69&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;Re-scheduling/Moving containers when failures occur (self-healing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;4693&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;While some platforms may state that they have other features such as storage orchestration, secret/config. management, and automatic bin packing to name a few: the reality is that these &lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;generally do not work for larger scale installations without intense investments either in forking / customization or through integrations and separation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;198a&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;For example, most folks that run large-scale container orchestration platforms cannot utilize their built-in secret or configuration management. These primitives are generally not meant, designed, or built for hundreds of engineers on tens of teams and generally do not include the necessary controls to be able to sanely manage, own, and operate their applications. It is extremely common for folks to separate their secret and config. management to a system that has stronger guarantees and controls (not to mention scaling).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;64a4&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Similarly for service discovery and load balancing it is quite common to separate this out and run an overlay or abstract control plane. It is quite common to deploy &lt;a href=&quot;https://istio.io/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Istio&lt;/a&gt; to handle this for Kubernetes. Managing and running Istio is not a trivial task and many modern-day cluster outages are due to misconfiguration of this control plane/service mesh and a lack of understanding of the minute details of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;8f92&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;What do we use as our container orchestration platform?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;07cc&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Our container orchestration platform is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coinbase/odin&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Odin&lt;/a&gt; + AWS ASGs (auto-scaling groups). When you click Deploy from Codeflow (our &lt;a class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/scaling-developer-productivity-d23ce491f869&quot;&gt;internal UI&lt;/a&gt; for deployments), Odin is invoked with an API call from Codeflow. Odin kicks off a step function and begins to deploy your application. New VMs are stood up in AWS and loaded into a new ASG, your software is fetched from various internal locations, a load balancer starts health-checking these new instances, and eventually traffic is cut over in a Blue/Green manner to the new hosts in the new ASG behind the load balancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1cff&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Our container orchestration platform is &lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;extremely simple&lt;/strong&gt; (on purpose). We enable the same key features of Kubernetes: A single Deploy + Rollback button in Codeflow, Scaling based-on some defined heuristic (we support custom AWS metrics or standard CPU metrics), and re-scheduling/moving of your containers if your VM dies/becomes unhealthy in your ASG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;62f4&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;To handle secrets and configuration management we have built a dynamic configuration service that provides libraries to all internal customers with a p95 of 6ms. It is backed by DynamoDB and serves 100s of thousands of requests per minute of synchronous and asynchronous methods types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;db35&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;To handle service discovery and load balancing we utilize Route53 (DNS), ALBs (Application Load Balancers), and client-side load balancing for gRPC either natively or through Envoy. We expect to invest more here later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;6939&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;Why do we not run Kubernetes?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b53d&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;Running Kubernetes does not solve any customer (engineering) problems. Running Kubernetes would actually create a whole new set of problems.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;9aaf&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ke jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;We would need to build/staff a full-time Compute team&lt;/strong&gt;. While we may do this anyway as we grow, this would be required immediately so that they could focus on building out tens of clusters (likely separate for each team/org), starting to scope/build the wrapping/glue tooling, starting to build out the abstract control plane/service mesh, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fc99&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq ke jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;Securing Kubernetes is not a trivial, easy, or well understood operation&lt;/strong&gt;. To enable us to own/operate Kubernetes we would need the same tooling and controls that we have today with our entire platform (Odin, ASGs, Step Deployers — and everything they enforce). To build these same primitives providing the same level of safety that these provide today would be a substantial investment both by a (future) Compute team and our Security team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;611a&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq ke jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;Managed Kubernetes (EKS on AWS, GKE on Google) is very much in its infancy and doesn’t solve most of the challenges with owning/operating Kubernetes (if anything it makes them more difficult at this time)&lt;/strong&gt;. At AWS they are scaling their support/operations teams to run EKS and at Google it isn’t uncommon for them to have multi-hour outages with GKE (&lt;a href=&quot;https://status.cloud.google.com/incident/container-engine/19012&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ref&lt;/a&gt;). You are trading off some operations issues and challenges to another operations team (and removing a lot of visibility).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;e96a&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq ke jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;Cluster upgrades and management require a much more operationally heavy focus than we have today&lt;/strong&gt;. The only way to sanely run Kubernetes is by giving teams/orgs their own clusters (similar to giving them their own AWS accounts or GCP projects). Upgrading clusters and patching vulnerabilities is not a quick/easy task even with Istio and associated tooling. Generally you have to build/run a secondary cluster, failover all applications, and then fail back after an upgrade. This primitive is not built into any abstracts at this point in time. While this may exist for managed clusters (GKE) it doesn’t always work as you might expect and rolling back once started is generally not well handled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;16f4&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq ke jn jo&quot;&gt;Today, &lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;we do not carry this burden&lt;/strong&gt;. We run on a hardened OS with minimal &amp;gt; no dependencies. Our AMI rollout is managed starting with development and then moving forward after weeks of testing. If we need to rollback we have the ability to do so with a trivial one-line change. On average we spend &amp;lt; 5hrs/month on anything even closely related to this area of concern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;20e7&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;iw&quot;&gt;Additional references on the complexities of owning/operating Kubernetes &amp;amp; Istio:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;a554&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.openstack.org/developer/performance-docs/issues/scale_testing_issues.html&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt; (Kubernetes Issues At Scale 900 Minions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;b81a&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/scaling-kubernetes-to-2500-nodes/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;OpenAI&lt;/a&gt; (Scaling Kubernetes to 2,500 Nodes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;f0f8&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/civis-analytics/https-medium-com-civis-analytics-breaking-kubernetes-how-we-broke-and-fixed-our-k8s-cluster-adfa6fbade61&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Civis&lt;/a&gt; (Breaking Kubernetes: How We Broke and Fixed our K8s Cluster)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;270d&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://k8s.af/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;k8s.af&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;bd91&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Let’s discuss some of the complexity of securing and running Kubernetes as a business that &lt;a class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/our-focus-on-the-institutional-space-5c8e87332268&quot;&gt;stores more than $8 billion in crypto assets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;06cb&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;Components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e786&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;The basics of securing a Kubernetes cluster (&lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/administer-cluster/securing-a-cluster/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ref&lt;/a&gt;) are well known/understood but once you dig into each of them the complexities start to unravel. Securing all of the system components (etcd, kubelet), the API server, and any abstracts/overlays (Istio) opens up a lot of surface to understand, test, and secure. Going deep into namespaces, seccomp, SELinux, cgroups, etc. is all required given the increased attack surface. Kubernetes is so large that it has its own CIS &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cisecurity.org/benchmark/kubernetes/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;benchmark&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; InSpec &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dev-sec/cis-kubernetes-benchmark&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;suite&lt;/a&gt; (thankfully).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;437d&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;Vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3c3c&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;A small list of references that provide a good starting point for researching:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;f1fd&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2019-5736&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;CVE-2019–5736&lt;/a&gt; (8.6 High): Allows attackers to overwrite the host runc binary (and consequently obtain host root access).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;a25c&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2019-11246&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;CVE-2019–11246&lt;/a&gt; (6.5 Medium): If the tar binary in the container is malicious, it could run any code and output unexpected, malicious results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;99d6&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2019-11253&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;CVE-2019–11253&lt;/a&gt; (7.5 High): Allows authorized users to send malicious YAML or JSON payloads, causing the API server to consume excessive CPU or memory, potentially crashing and becoming unavailable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;62bc&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;888f&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Kubernetes is a powerful PaaS as a kit with &lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;lots&lt;/strong&gt; of security-relevant options to support the variety of deployment scenarios that it can be used in. It’s incredibly valuable from a security perspective when it is the universal consensus choice for PaaS, because most of those options can be abstracted away, and secondary systems must be put into place to support its use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4e9c&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Kubernetes is fundamentally designed for workload orchestration — Trust is not the differentiator or purpose behind the encapsulation or pieces in Kubernetes; The multi-tenancy purpose is for bin packing and not in support of furthering permission boundaries. It provides several layers at which you can choose to place mild boundaries of varying enforceability. Some of these boundaries are built-in, while others are simply integration points for other tools to help manage. Here are some of the primitives Kube provides (and doesn’t provide) to isolate workloads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3130&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;Control Plane (AWS Account / GCP Project)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dbcd&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Kubernetes clusters operate within the services and networks that are provided to them, and naturally have some interaction with the AWS/GCP control plane such as provisioning load balancers for ingress, accessing secrets stored in KMS, etc. Teams grow and expand to have separate accounts, projects, and further isolation over time. A separate AWS account or GCP project is the primary primitive by which you can achieve total IAM segmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0b68&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;A Kubernetes cluster, on the other hand, needs to operate within one AWS account (even if federated with other clusters elsewhere). This limits segmentation options and flexibility. We could provision a cluster per team or service, but this takes away many of the efficiency gains that Kubernetes brings, and brings on new management problems, like meta-orchestrating all of those clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;4d85&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;Clusters &amp;amp; Nodes &amp;amp; Pods &amp;amp; Containers (Oh my!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1306&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;be&quot;&gt;Clusters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f139&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Cluster master (API) servers are a secondary control plane (besides the AWS one) that we need to secure as well. Service accounts and access scopes, which containers can assume to access resources both within and outside the cluster, are just as complex as AWS’ IAM is, and need to be mapped against one another strictly so that a breakout does not affect the, e.g., AWS control plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;b8e6&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;be&quot;&gt;Nodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;68cc&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;The operating system of the underlying nodes must be maintained much as we do today. In fact, our OS is very similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/container-optimized-os/docs&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;base OS&lt;/a&gt; Google uses for GKE. While we wouldn’t necessarily have to change anything to move our OS to Kubernetes, we wouldn’t gain anything either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;6cfc&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;be&quot;&gt;Pods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;512d&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Creation of pods in the cluster, and the rules about what standards they have to meet to be created, are accomplished through PodSecurityPolicy, which operates similarly to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coinbase/salus&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Salus&lt;/a&gt; and our consensus management tooling today. We would have to invest in significant integration work, and additional open source dependencies, to cleanly integrate them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1382&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Pods are segmented from each other through networking policies, much as we do today with Security Groups and/or our internal service framework. But in the world of Kubernetes, identity, authentication, and authorization of pods to communicate with each other involve a number of supporting technologies, such as SPIFFE and SPIRE for identity format and attestation below the node level, Envoy for authorization gating, Istio for authN and Z orchestration, and OPA for authorization policy. Each of these is a significant effort to standardize and adopt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;363f&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;be&quot;&gt;Containers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7844&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Containers are not security boundaries, they’re resource boundaries. In order to define security boundaries around containers, you need to delve into custom kernel namespaces, syscall filtering, mandatory access control frameworks, and/or vm-based isolation technologies designed for containers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/gvisor&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;gVisor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;29e1&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Currently, we have not invested much in this area because we do not operate in a multi-tenant fashion. If we moved to a multi-tenant model, we would have to make significant investments here almost immediately so that we could trust that pods/containers are only running on the same nodes as similarly classified pods, and that they are not interfering with one another with host/vm isolation technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;77c4&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;When will we run Kubernetes and is Kubernetes in our future?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7e6f&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;If/when there are significant use cases for a more advanced container orchestration platform we will likely &lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;first visit the problem statement&lt;/strong&gt;. If this is something that can easily be added to our existing platform: we will likely visit that first and explore/scope from there. If we deem it unreasonable to extend/add to our platform then we would visit all potential options — not just Kubernetes. It is much more likely that we would visit AWS’s managed offerings first such as Fargate and ECS before diving in to Kubernetes based on the above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a541&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;If/when there are significant gains to be had by our engineers by offering Kubernetes (or any other container orchestration platform) we will explore offering them. At this time there is not a significant gain to be had by offering Kubernetes. This may change if/when Kubernetes offers enough new features that we haven’t kept up, they have paid down their technical debt (or we have not), or our customers require new functionality that they are able to offer and we are not in the foreseeable future. If the barrier to entry of our current platform were to significantly change and that were now a clear differentiator, then we would also explore offering a different platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;098e&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;If/when we hit the limits of our existing platform, are too deeply burdened or foresee being too deeply burdened in our platform due to missing features that our customers need, extending our platform is becoming too onerous, or we are having too many outages that are violating our SLA, than we would likely revisit a different container orchestration platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9127&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;If/when we lose support of a major upstream dependency such as AWS or ASGs, we would then look into other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6e1c&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;These are a few of the reasons we might choose to look into another container orchestration platform. &lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;At this time we have no plans to build/own/operate Kubernetes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;882e&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;Doesn’t Kubernetes solve various problems such as re-balancing/auto-healing, auto-scaling, and service discovery? How do we solve these today?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;212d&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Kubernetes at a smaller scale solves most of these problems without a lot of fuss. At a larger scale it requires a lot more thought, glue code, and putting wrappers / safe guards on pretty much everything to make it work safely and reliably. Generally, as mentioned above, folks tend to add a Service Mesh such as Istio to enable more advanced features / requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0cb2&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Today we solve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;f3b3&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;Re-balancing/auto-healing with Odin and ASGs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;0970&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et jp hs ev jq ht hk jr fg hm js fh ho jt fi hq jm jn jo&quot;&gt;Service discovery with DNS and Envoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;3378&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;Kubernetes has Storage Orchestration and we don’t have that today, should we?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4c6b&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;We have two major stateful applications at Coinbase today- &lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;blockchain nodes&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong class=&quot;hh kd&quot;&gt;trading engines&lt;/strong&gt; that could be potential customers of a feature such as storage orchestration. For the former (blockchain nodes) the usage of storage is fairly custom and we have built a custom deployer that gives them the features that they need. For the latter (trading engines), we embedded from the Reliability (SRE) team and provided support to a number of their specific challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d341&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;While having Storage Orchestration built-in to Kubernetes might have been a nice starting point for both blockchain nodes and the trading engines- a lot of the same issues we have with the underlying technology would still exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bbfd&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;What is the future of a Container Orchestration Platform if not Kubernetes?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e771&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;We will explore and migrate to a higher-level abstracted service for some applications. We will explore Fargate and ECS as contenders for this purpose. The current initial reasons would be utilization and cost improvements — both of which are not very customer focused. We may choose to wait until we have more customer focused reasons to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f5a1&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Potential customer focused asks would be around deployment times, deployment patterns (beyond canaries), more complex service mesh needs than exist today, or specific improvements/ features that may be added to Fargate or ECS that building onto existing tooling is not possible/not reasonable. These are some of the potential customer focused asks that are possible but not known or realized at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1c81&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et hi hs ev hj ht hk hl fg hm hn fh ho hp fi hq ds&quot;&gt;Ideally the move to a different underlying container technology would be fairly invisible as the tools to interact with them wouldn’t fundamentally change. The reality of moving to a different platform would likely uncover hidden or unknown expectations about the existing system. How you deploy and debug services in staging and production would still be abstracted, but there may be different features offered that do not exist today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6769&quot; class=&quot;ix iy ea as ar bu iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj&quot;&gt;Do I/we hate Kubernetes? Does Kubernetes fail as a container platform?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a634&quot; class=&quot;hf hr ea as hh b et ju hs ev jv ht hk jw fg hm jx fh ho jy fi hq ds&quot;&gt;No. It is a great tool despite its challenges. Kubernetes has moved our industry forward in an increasingly positive direction. With Kubernetes well into a v1, the development of &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/knative/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Knative&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/fargate/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Fargate&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/run/&quot; class=&quot;cy gr is it iu iv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Cloud Run&lt;/a&gt; are increasingly raising the level of abstraction and solving the underlying challenges with managing Kubernetes. The future is bright. As these underlying challenges are solved, many existing concerns will likely be alleviated in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 19:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>arkadiyt</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Container technologies at Coinbase</og:title>
<og:description>Why Kubernetes is not part of our stack</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.coinbase.com/container-technologies-at-coinbase-d4ae118dcb6c</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/max/1200/0*ekgXkPjYTRoCnx10</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.coinbase.com/container-technologies-at-coinbase-d4ae118dcb6c?gi=61e597c147b9</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Potential organized fraud in ACM/IEEE computer architecture conferences</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@tnvijayk/potential-organized-fraud-in-acm-ieee-computer-architecture-conferences-ccd61169370d</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@tnvijayk/potential-organized-fraud-in-acm-ieee-computer-architecture-conferences-ccd61169370d</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;e441&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;fa fs&quot;&gt;Potential Organized Fraud in ACM/IEEE Computer Architecture Conferences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;213b&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;Many of you are likely to have seen the &lt;a class=&quot;bx eh ft fu fv fw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@huixiangvoice/evidence-put-doubts-on-the-ieee-acms-investigation-991a6d50802a&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; by Huixiang’s Voice on Medium showing that Huixiang Chen’s laptop contained downloads of most, if not all, submissions to more than one conference along with the de-anonymized reviews and PC discussions. These revelations have been troubling to say the least. A Joint ACM-IEEE Investigative Committee has been launched to look into this matter further. Independently, I have come across some disturbing indications of potential large-scale collusion which I discuss next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e4cb&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;Before I get into the details, I want to point out two principles I have followed: (1) This post is not to point a finger at the ACM SIGARCH and IEEE TCCA officers, who are volunteers and, above all, one of us. Far from it. We should not be shooting inwards. We should be focused on the culprits and their acts, whoever they may be. (2) If any of us notices something odd but does not discuss it with the relevant officers, then the culprits win. Similarly, if ACM/IEEE officers conduct investigations or have proof of misconduct (not allegations) then they owe it to the community to make public everything they know of the investigations or misconduct, in addition to notifying higher-up officers — a responsibility that comes with the official capacity. Full transparency is a must for (1) the community members to have confidence in our conferences which have a heavy influence on who gets interviewed, hired, promoted, awarded, and respected, and (2) the culprits to have a low chance of repeatedly getting away with it (e.g., else the culprits may repeat the fraud in multiple conferences over multiple years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c3ab&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;fa fs&quot;&gt;Another ACM SIG:&lt;/strong&gt; Let me start with the details confirmed directly to me by a SIG officer who conducted the investigation but wishes to remain anonymous: Another SIG community has had a collusion problem where the investigators found that a group of PC members and authors colluded to bid and push for each other’s papers violating the usual conflict-of-interest rules. The investigators manually analyzed bids and scores going back a few years. At least five papers were affected. I am disallowed from naming the SIG community. I could not get a confirmation on how many years and conferences were analyzed, nor was I told any other details. I have informed the Joint Committee about this issue but you all should know too (principle #2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ee6e&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;Here is what I heard from an award-winning professor about what happened. The professor has first-hand knowledge of the investigations and has communicated directly with the investigators, but wishes to remain anonymous: There is a chat group of a few dozen authors who in subsets work on common topics and carefully ensure not to co-author any papers with each other so as to keep out of each other’s conflict lists (to the extent that even if there is collaboration they voluntarily give up authorship on one paper to prevent conflicts on many future papers). They exchange papers before submissions and then either bid or get assigned to review each other’s papers by virtue of having expertise on the topic of the papers. They give high scores to the papers. If a review raises any technical issues in PC discussions, the usual response is something to the effect that despite the issues they still remain positive; or if a review questions the novelty claims, they point to some minor detail deep in the paper and say that they find that detail to be novel even though the paper itself does not elevate that detail to claim novelty. Our process is not set up to combat such collusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6886&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;fa fs&quot;&gt;Relevance to SIGARCH:&lt;/strong&gt; This case is relevant to us because (1) there is overlap between the SIG community and SIGARCH and (2) collusion is a common thread in this case and ours. This overlap, of course, does not mean that everyone in the intersection of the communities is suspect. Huixiang’s Voice revelations of misconduct in multiple conferences strongly point to collusion between PC members and authors. HotCRP does not show you your own submission even if you are a PC member, so how did the de-anonymized reviews and PC comments for Huixiang’s paper end up in his laptop? An insider help seems likely. Given that the other SIG’s incident has not been made public, I have two options: (1) not make the incident public, potentially letting the culprits continue their fraud in SIGARCH conferences, or (2) warn everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f58f&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;In the presence of such potential collusion, imagine what would happen to online accepts, where only a small subset of reviewers who read a paper (often just three) decide to accept the paper without any vetting from the rest of the PC (online accepts are bulk-accepted without reading out even the titles to the whole PC). The so-called split PC, as discussed in this recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sigarch.org/time-to-eliminate-in-person-pc-meetings/&quot; class=&quot;bx eh ft fu fv fw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, would make all accepts inherit the online accepts’ problems (which exist even without any collusion).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9b10&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;The lack of power of subpoena and warrant on the part of the Joint Committee, the ACM or IEEE officers has come up. If the suspects are funded by taxpayer money (e.g., NSF), then the fraud falls in the jurisdiction of the police and FBI, who do have those powers. Our community should consider this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;20a4&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;fa fs&quot;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; 99.99% of us are honest but the dishonest 0.01% can cause serious, repeated damage. Huixiang’s laptop did have prohibited contents. So misconduct has occurred for sure. There have been confirmed cases of collusion in another, overlapping SIG community. Put together, these revelations point to organized fraud. We can either believe that nothing is amiss and allow potential fraud to continue, or take steps to prevent and to detect collusion. Like you, I would rather be discussing new ideas with my graduate students and collaborators than chasing collusion, but the stakes are too high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4c8f&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;fa fs&quot;&gt;PS:&lt;/strong&gt; The SIGARCH blog declined to publish this post. There is a difference between rumors (Webster: “talk or opinion widely disseminated with no discernible source”) and bona fide sources who wish to remain anonymous. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Source_(journalism)&quot; class=&quot;bx eh ft fu fv fw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Wikipedia on journalistic standards&lt;/a&gt; for sources that wish to remain anonymous. As for concerns about the conferences’ reputation, the &lt;a class=&quot;bx eh ft fu fv fw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@huixiangvoice/evidence-put-doubts-on-the-ieee-acms-investigation-991a6d50802a&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; by Huixiang’s Voice has already raised serious questions about the integrity of our process. Curtailing open discussions on the extent of the problem will neither make the problem go away nor help with the conferences’ reputation. Doing so will only help the culprits. If the problem gets worse, our conferences’ reputation will only get worse. Until the culprits are caught (which may take some time), a key step in handling potential fraud is to warn everyone. Therefore, I think that it is important to make this post public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3a36&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;fa fs&quot;&gt;About the Author:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;fx&quot;&gt;T. N. Vijaykumar is Professor of Electrical and Computer Engineering at Purdue University and works on computer architecture.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;029c&quot; class=&quot;ey fm ap ce fa b fb fc fn fd fe fo ff fg fp fh fi fq fj fk fr fl et&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;fa fs&quot;&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; The opinions expressed in this post are the author’s and not of Purdue University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 19:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bmc7505</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Potential Organized Fraud in ACM/IEEE Computer Architecture Conferences</og:title>
<og:description>Many of you are likely to have seen the post by Huixiang’s Voice on Medium showing that Huixiang Chen’s laptop contained downloads of most…</og:description>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@tnvijayk/potential-organized-fraud-in-acm-ieee-computer-architecture-conferences-ccd61169370d</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@tnvijayk/potential-organized-fraud-in-acm-ieee-computer-architecture-conferences-ccd61169370d</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wuhan hospital traffic, search engine data indicate virus activity in Fall 2019</title>
<link>https://dash.harvard.edu/handle/1/42669767</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://dash.harvard.edu/handle/1/42669767</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Citation&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Nsoesie, Elaine Okanyene, Benjamin Rader, Yiyao L. Barnoon, Lauren Goodwin, and John S. Brownstein. Analysis of hospital traffic and search engine data in Wuhan China indicates early disease activity in the Fall of 2019 (2020).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Abstract&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;span&gt;The global COVID-19 pandemic was originally linked to a zoonotic spillover event in Wuhan’s Huanan Seafood Market in November or December of 2019. However, recent evidence suggests that the virus may have already been circulating at the time of the outbreak. Here we use previously validated data streams - satellite imagery of hospital parking lots and Baidu search queries of disease related terms - to investigate this possibility. We observe an upward trend in hospital traffic and search volume beginning in late Summer and early Fall 2019. While queries of the respiratory symptom “cough” show seasonal fluctuations coinciding with yearly influenza seasons, “diarrhea” is a more COVID-19 specific symptom and only shows an association with the current epidemic. The increase of both signals precede the documented start of the COVID-19 pandemic in December, highlighting the value of novel digital sources for surveillance of emerging pathogens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;simple-item-view-abstract item-page-field-wrapper table&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Terms of Use&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;span&gt;This article is made available under the terms and conditions applicable to Open Access Policy Articles, as set forth at &lt;a href=&quot;http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HUL.InstRepos:dash.current.terms-of-use#OAP&quot;&gt;http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HUL.InstRepos:dash.current.terms-of-use#OAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;simple-item-view-abstract item-page-field-wrapper table&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Citable link to this page&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HUL.InstRepos:42669767&quot;&gt;http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HUL.InstRepos:42669767&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 19:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>abc-xyz</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://dash.harvard.edu/handle/1/42669767</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon’s New Competitive Advantage: Putting Its Own Products First</title>
<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/amazons-new-competitive-advantage-putting-its-own-products-first</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.propublica.org/article/amazons-new-competitive-advantage-putting-its-own-products-first</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;
An Amazon distribution center in North Las Vegas, Nevada, on April 25. Amazon has started to reserve the best position in search results for its private-label products. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;392.98134767266&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-notes&quot; readability=&quot;5.6178571428571&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; id=&quot;newsletter-txt-note&quot; readability=&quot;6.9142857142857&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProPublica is a nonprofit newsroom that investigates abuses of power. Sign up to receive &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.propublica.org/big-story-2019&quot;&gt;our biggest stories&lt;/a&gt; as soon as they’re published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.0&quot;&gt;Until recently, when Amazon customers typed “melatonin” into the site’s search bar, a variety of sleep supplements would appear in the most coveted real estate on the listings results — top left on the first page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.1&quot;&gt;One of consultant Jason Boyce’s clients, a seller of natural supplements, often sought to outbid competitors for the best spots by promising Amazon about $6 each time someone clicked on the product. While the brand never attained the top left slot, it regularly landed in the top row. But in late March, Boyce noticed that Amazon’s own brand, Solimo, had taken over the top left, while his client’s product had been bumped to a lower row. Then Boyce typed “ground coffee” in the search bar, only to find AmazonFresh Colombia ground coffee in the top left, pushing down another client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.2&quot;&gt;“This is madness,” Boyce said. “They’re putting their own product right in the front of the line.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.3&quot;&gt;He said the clients, whom he declined to name because they feared retaliation from Amazon, were outraged. “They were thinking, ‘What is Amazon going to do next?’” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;newsletter newsletter-big-story small left&quot; readability=&quot;22.317919075145&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;newsletter-head&quot;&gt;Get Our Top Investigations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to the Big Story newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.0&quot;&gt;Although customers don’t necessarily realize it, brands have for years been able to bid on search terms to secure the most visible listing positions at the top of Amazon’s product search results pages, where their products carry a “sponsored” tag above the description. Now, they still bid for top-row placements, but the best spot — the top left on the first page — is unavailable across dozens of product search terms, according to consultants and ProPublica’s own review. During the pandemic, Amazon has begun to use that position for its own private-label products, without bidding, under the heading “featured from our brands.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.1&quot;&gt;The domino effect of Amazon’s new strategy has demoted competitors’ listings for products including diapers, copy paper, kids’ pajamas, mattresses, trail mix and lightbulbs. By putting its own private brands in some of the most valuable slots, Amazon is sacrificing short-term ad revenue to build up sales of its private brands over time, consultants said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.2&quot;&gt;The new approach violates Amazon’s mantra that every decision must put the customer first, said Tim Hughes, a consultant who used to work in product management at Amazon. “Why would their brand be a better option for consumers?” said Hughes, chief operating officer of a firm that helps brands manage Amazon accounts. “It doesn’t necessarily have to be cheaper, or better, or anything. So then what’s their justification to say, ‘We’re just going to put this up in front of everybody else’? This is just another example of Amazon being able to manipulate the platform for its own good use.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.3&quot;&gt;While Amazon has promoted its own private-label products in various prominent spots on its site over the years, consultants and legal experts said this latest iteration takes advantage of the surge in online buying during the pandemic and may accentuate antitrust concerns for a company already juggling domestic and global probes. Amazon’s share price has increased more than 30% this year, although the company missed earnings estimates for the most recent quarter because of higher costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-300&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.0&quot;&gt;Amazon’s dedicating of prime positions to its own brands could be viewed under U.S. law as “exclusionary conduct” — which, along with proving a company has substantial market power, is a key element of antitrust cases, said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.antitrustinstitute.org/people/christopher-sagers/&quot;&gt;Christopher Sagers&lt;/a&gt;, a professor of antitrust law at Cleveland State University in Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.1&quot;&gt;“If I were their lawyer, this would definitely make me nervous,” Sagers said. “It’s hard to explain the search results finagling as anything besides a nasty, anticompetitive move.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.2&quot;&gt;Amazon acknowledged that it recently introduced this “featured from our brands” strategy, which the company described as “merchandising placement” rather than advertising. “Like all retailers, Amazon regularly makes decisions about how to use the space in our stores based on a variety of factors, centered on what customers will find most helpful,” a spokesperson said. “That’s a normal part of retail that’s happened for decades.” There is no real estate reserved for Amazon brands, and they may be placed anywhere, Amazon said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.3&quot;&gt;The spokesperson said that Amazon did not adopt this strategy to take advantage of the pandemic. &quot;The change in labeling of this merchandising feature had been planned for many months,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.4&quot;&gt;Amazon highlights its private-label brands because customers prefer them, the spokesperson added. “Amazon’s private brand products have on average higher customer review ratings, lower return rates and higher repeat purchase rates than other comparable brands in the Amazon store,” he said. “As a result, like other retailers, Amazon highlights its private brands in promotions and marketing.” Most private-label sales are for staples such as paper towels, baby wipes and batteries, Amazon said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;Absent favored treatment by Amazon, though, its private-label brands sometimes don’t have enough sales under the algorithm’s criteria to justify a listing on the first page of search results, said consultant James Thomson, the former business head of an Amazon team that recruits third-party sellers. Amazon Essentials regular and slim-fit short-sleeve pocket Oxford shirts, both listed on the first page of results for “men’s shirts,” had about $4,400 and $1,600, respectively, in sales over a recent 30-day period, far less than the surrounding unpaid listings. Their sales should have put the Oxford shirts at best at the bottom of the second page, according to Thomson and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.junglescout.com/&quot;&gt;Jungle Scout&lt;/a&gt;, a service that analyzes Amazon sales rank data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.6&quot;&gt;Amazon “confuses consumers into thinking these products are more popular than they really are,” Thomson said. Amazon said its shopping results don’t favor private brands, and sales is only one of many factors considered by its algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20200606-ground-coffee-redacted-cropped.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20200606-ground-coffee-redacted-cropped.jpg 400w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo800w/20200606-ground-coffee-redacted-cropped.jpg 800w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo1600w/20200606-ground-coffee-redacted-cropped.jpg 1600w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo2000w/20200606-ground-coffee-redacted-cropped.jpg 2000w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1720px) 826px, (min-width: 780px) calc(46.09vw + 43px), (min-width: 600px) 59.38vw, 93.21vw&quot;/&gt; A screenshot of a search for ground coffee on Amazon’s site shows the company’s private-label product in the top left slot below a headline ad.
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.0&quot;&gt;Amazon has 45 private-label brands with a total of 243,000 products available, accounting for about 1% of retail sales, the company said. “Private labels are playing an increasingly important role in Amazon’s overall strategy,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://coresight.com/research/inside-the-world-of-amazons-private-label-offering-select-findings/&quot;&gt;Coresight Research&lt;/a&gt; said in a report last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.1&quot;&gt;Since people read from left to right, the top left is the most desirable spot in the search results. When we searched for “almonds,” Amazon’s Happy Belly brand whole raw almonds occupied that spot. In the “bra” results, it was Amazon’s Iris &amp;amp; Lilly brand. A search for “envelopes” revealed AmazonBasics security tinted version in the top left, ahead of three paid listings. A search for “shaving cream” featured Amazon’s Made For You shaving cream, to the left of two paid listings from The Art of Shaving brand. A spokesman for The Art of Shaving said “there aren’t any issues at the moment” with sales or how its products appear on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.2&quot;&gt;The prominent positioning for its own products enables Amazon to boost prices, Boyce said. When Boyce, who used to own a home recreation equipment company and remains interested in the category, happened to type “bocce” into Amazon’s search bar in April, he saw an Amazon brand bocce ball set featured at the top, before all the other listings, he said. When he checked again weeks later, the price of Amazon’s product — still top left — had gone up several dollars, he said. “We’re always looking to deliver consistently low prices to customers on all products we offer,” the spokesperson said, adding, “No amount of advertising will fool customers into paying more than they want if there are competitive offers for competitive products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.3&quot;&gt;Amazon has an advantage over competitors because it doesn’t have to pay itself for the best placement, Boyce said. Brands pay between 10% and 30% of sales for a sponsored slot, he said. “The deck is hugely stacked in favor of Amazon,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-pp-id=&quot;8&quot; data-pp-blocktype=&quot;promo&quot; class=&quot;promo small left&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;aside-head&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-entry section-articles&quot; readability=&quot;20.436585365854&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lead-art&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;aspect-3-2&quot; href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/amazon-says-it-puts-customers-first-but-its-pricing-algorithm-doesnt&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/legacy/images/_threeTwo400w/20160920-amazon-630x420.gif&quot; height=&quot;267&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.0&quot;&gt;Amazon is facing at least one &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/IP_19_4291&quot;&gt;European&lt;/a&gt; antitrust investigation and two in the U.S. The House Judiciary Committee last &lt;a href=&quot;https://judiciary.house.gov/news/documentsingle.aspx?DocumentID=2051&quot;&gt;June&lt;/a&gt; announced an investigation into possible anti-competitive conduct by large tech companies including Amazon. The House investigation is ongoing, according to a spokesman for Rep. David Cicilline of Rhode Island, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cicilline.house.gov/about-me/committees-and-caucuses&quot;&gt;chairman&lt;/a&gt; of the committee’s antitrust subcommittee. Cicilline last month &lt;a href=&quot;https://mobile.twitter.com/davidcicilline/status/1261432733982773251?s=21&quot;&gt;threatened&lt;/a&gt; to subpoena Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos if he ignores a request to testify. The demand followed a Wall Street Journal report that Amazon used data about third-party sellers on its site to develop competing products under its private-label brands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.1&quot;&gt;In addition, the Federal Trade Commission has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-11/amazon-antitrust-probe-ftc-investigators-interview-merchants&quot;&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; been looking into possible anti-competitive practices at Amazon for nearly a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mlexmarketinsight.com/insights-center/editors-picks/area-of-expertise/antitrust/amazon-third-party-sales-data-sought-by-ftc&quot;&gt;year&lt;/a&gt;. The FTC declined to comment. Other big tech companies also have been under scrutiny. Media outlets &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/justice-department-state-attorneys-general-likely-to-bring-antitrust-lawsuits-against-google-11589573622&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; last month that the Justice Department and a group of state attorneys general are likely to file antitrust lawsuits against Google, focusing in part on its online advertising business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.2&quot;&gt;Amazon declined to comment specifically on the investigations. It said that it faces “intense competition in every segment” in which it operates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.3&quot;&gt;Amazon represents less than 4% of the U.S. retail market but nearly 40% of U.S. online &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emarketer.com/content/us-ecommerce-2019&quot;&gt;sales&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the third-biggest player in the U.S. digital advertising market, behind Google and Facebook, with about $10 billion in U.S. digital ad revenues in 2019, according to market research firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emarketer.com/content/amazon-advertising-2019&quot;&gt;eMarketer&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon’s share of that space is about 8% and growing, eMarketer said. Three-fourths of Amazon’s digital ad revenues come from keyword-targeted, cost-per-click search ads, including the “sponsored product” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emarketer.com/content/amazon-advertisers-still-focus-spending-on-sponsored-products&quot;&gt;listings&lt;/a&gt;, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emarketer.com/content/amazon-approaches-10-billion-in-us-net-digital-ad-revenues-this-year&quot;&gt;eMarketer&lt;/a&gt; estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.4&quot;&gt;A desktop search on Amazon generally yields multiple pages of results. Each page may show a dozen or more rows of products, typically with three or four listings per row. The top row may feature between one and four paid listings, known as sponsored products. For example, a recent search for “curtains” showed AmazonBasics curtains in the top left spot, followed by two sponsored and one “organic” — or unpaid — listing across the row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-300&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.0&quot;&gt;Under what Boyce calls a “pay-to-play” system, brands compete for sponsored product placement on Amazon’s website, bidding on a specific search term such as “curtains.” Brands pay nothing upfront for these listings. Rather, they bid on what they’re willing to pay Amazon per click — amounts typically ranging from about a nickel to $20 per click, depending on the search term, consultants said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.1&quot;&gt;Many brands may be competing for the same limited ad space, and they can learn estimated winning bids before placing theirs. Having the highest bid doesn’t guarantee placement. When determining which brands will get the coveted spots, Amazon’s algorithm takes into account a brand’s sales and inventory availability, and the product’s relevance to the desired search term. Placement for individual brands is constantly changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.2&quot;&gt;Amazon offers sponsored product ads at the bottom of the first search results page as well as on subsequent pages, but those are less expensive since they generally lead to fewer sales, consultants said. If products — like the sleep supplement sold by Boyce’s client — lose their sponsored position, they no longer have to pay for placement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.3&quot;&gt;Amazon began offering pay-per-click ads on its site in 2012, said Mike Ziegler, a former senior product manager for Amazon’s advertising program. Since then, it has gradually increased both the number of paid listings on product search results pages as well as the amount of space that features Amazon-brand products, said Thomson, who advises brands working with Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.4&quot;&gt;In recent years, Amazon has sometimes featured its own products in headline ads that run across the top of the results page, just below the search bar. This area is now known as “sponsored brand” space and is available to brands willing to bid on it. In addition, Amazon has featured its brands in the middle of the results page in a section called “top rated from our brands.” It still sometimes promotes its products in this way. But, prior to the pandemic, Amazon’s private-label brands only entered the top row of listings through competitive bidding, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;By giving itself the top placement, Amazon is guaranteeing the success of its brands, Hughes said. Since customers are more likely to buy products listed at the top of the search results, Amazon is boosting sales for its products — and increasing, by the same token, their rating in the eyes of the algorithm. So even if Amazon ultimately cedes the top left, its products will end up in a better position relative to competitors than before, Hughes said. Amazon said this isn’t part of its strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-pp-id=&quot;12&quot; data-pp-blocktype=&quot;promo&quot; class=&quot;promo small left&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;aside-head&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-entry section-articles&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lead-art&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;aspect-3-2&quot; href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/amazon-defends-its-pricing-algorithm-but-leaves-out-billions-in-sales&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/legacy/images/_threeTwo400w/20160923-amazon-630x420.jpg&quot; height=&quot;267&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.0&quot;&gt;When Hughes worked for Amazon between 2012 and 2015, his job was to maximize advertising revenue on the Amazon-owned website IMDb, a database of movies and TV shows that then had annual ad revenue of about $50 million, he said. For unpopular or unused advertising space, Hughes built relationships with so-called “remnant providers” that would fill the space with last-minute ads for a discounted rate. Although his job was to get the most revenue out of the available ad space, Hughes said his boss eventually told him to drop the remnant ad suppliers in favor of running unpaid ads for Amazon services including Prime Video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.1&quot;&gt;“I was told flat out we’re not doing remnant providers anymore, we’re just showing Amazon house ads,” he said. “There was no rationale. It came from senior leadership. You have to do it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.2&quot;&gt;Amazon said it only shows house ads in the program described by Hughes when it doesn’t have a relevant paid ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.3&quot;&gt;Hughes said that Amazon’s efforts to promote its own brands have become more aggressive over the years, first with the headline and middle-of-page placements and now with the top-left slot. “They don’t have to fight like everybody else to get positioning” for their private-label brands on the product search pages, Hughes said. “They just put ‘our brands’ there, and boom, instant sales. The difference between being in slot one versus slot 10, even on the first page, is going to be an order of magnitude different in terms of sales. It is an exponentially decreasing curve. It is a huge drop off.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.4&quot;&gt;Dan Brownsher, CEO of an agency that advises sellers on Amazon, said brands compete to be in the top row of search results because the “further down you go on a page, the less likely you are” to click on a listing and buy a product, he said. “If you’re on Page 2, you’re basically dead,” he said. “If Amazon is taking up key real estate, then that’s pushing everybody else down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-300&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;15.0&quot;&gt;As a result, Amazon’s private-label sales are likely to increase, even on products that currently aren’t popular, Brownsher said. So while the company may forgo advertising revenue in the short term, as its own brand displaces a paid advertising slot, it’s “going to win in the long term,” he said. Brownsher also said Amazon may promote products that are overstocked and need to be sold quickly. The Amazon spokesperson said this isn’t its strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;15.1&quot;&gt;Not all sellers are upset. Ziegler, the former senior product manager who now advises brands who advertise on Amazon, said his clients — which include Unilever Food Solutions — accept that Amazon has in the past promoted its own brands alongside competitors and that it will continue to do so. “It’s a fact of life,” Ziegler said. Unilever did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;15.2&quot;&gt;Randall Fields, CEO of retail advisory firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://parkcitygroup.com/about-the-company/meet-our-ceo/&quot;&gt;Park City Group&lt;/a&gt;, said grocery and discount chains have long created private-label products. Amazon putting its brands in the most lucrative web space is akin to a grocery store featuring its own brand of trail mix in the most prominent shelf space, he said. Like Amazon, brick-and-mortar stores also charge fees for premier display space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;15.3&quot;&gt;“They’re not doing anything that any other supermarket chain is not doing,” said Fields, co-founder of cookie maker Mrs. Fields. (He’s no longer involved with the company.) “It’s just the scale of it is so immense at Amazon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;15.4&quot;&gt;There is an important difference, Thomson and Sagers said. Because of Amazon’s dominance over online retail, many sellers and suppliers rely on it as their primary or only source of sales revenue, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;15.5&quot;&gt;“An open marketplace means anybody can show up, anybody can sell their products, anybody’s got an opportunity,” Thomson said. “But what happens when prime real estate gets created and only Amazon can have access to it? It only pushes you further and further away from the marketplace actually being so-called ‘open.’ It’s not like somebody else can say, ‘I’m prepared to pay to have that real estate.’ Nope. That real estate is not available.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-notes&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note story-update&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, June 6, 2020:&lt;/strong&gt; This article was updated to include additional comment from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;topics-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filed under:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 19:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.propublica.org/article/amazons-new-competitive-advantage-putting-its-own-products-first</og:url>
<og:title>Amazon’s New Competitive Advantage: Putting Its Own Products First</og:title>
<og:description>Brands have long been able to bid for the premier slot at the top left of Amazon’s listings, but during the pandemic the online retailer has begun using this position for its private-label items, raising antitrust concerns.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_1200x630_crop_center-center_82_none/20200606-Amazon-features-own-OG.jpg?mtime=1591309366</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.propublica.org/article/amazons-new-competitive-advantage-putting-its-own-products-first</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We can no longer ignore the potential of psychedelic drugs to treat depression</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/jun/08/psychedelic-drugs-treat-depression</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/jun/08/psychedelic-drugs-treat-depression</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;he world is experiencing a devastating physical health emergency. But the coronavirus pandemic has also seen a renewed focus on our psychological wellbeing. Loneliness, uncertainty and grief may be intensifying an already acute mental health crisis, and in the US there has been a &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/changing-america/well-being/mental-health/493125-increase-in-anti-anxiety-medication-antidepressants&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;20% spike&lt;/a&gt; in the number of prescriptions for antidepressant and anti-anxiety drugs during lockdown. Demand for key antidepressants is threatening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://inews.co.uk/news/health/mental-health-coronavirus-antidepressants-medication-supplies-uk-lockdown-rise-demand-2842273&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;exceed supply&lt;/a&gt; in the UK – where prescriptions have already &lt;a href=&quot;https://digital.nhs.uk/news-and-events/news-archive/2017-news-archive/antidepressants-were-the-area-with-largest-increase-in-prescription-items-in-2016&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;more than doubled&lt;/a&gt; over the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I head the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imperial.ac.uk/psychedelic-research-centre&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Centre for Psychedelic Research&lt;/a&gt; at Imperial College London, the first of its kind, supported by about £3m in philanthropic donations. For 15 years, my research has focused on how drugs such as LSD, psilocybin, DMT and MDMA work in the brain, and how they may be useful in treating disorders such as depression. Like the present pandemic, a psychedelic drug experiences can be transformative – of the individual – and of society. Both illuminate the extent to which the condition of the world we inhabit is dependent on our own behaviours. And these, in turn, are a consequence of how we feel, think and perceive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Centre was founded in April 2019. A few months later, Johns Hopkins University in the US &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2019/09/05/us/johns-hopkins-psychedelic-research-center-trnd/index.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; a supersized version, floated by $17m. If you have read Michael Pollan’s book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2018/may/22/how-to-change-mind-new-science-psychedelics-michael-pollan-review&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;How to Change Your Mind&lt;/a&gt; or seen the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goop.com/psychedelics-and-healing/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;first episode&lt;/a&gt; of Gwyneth Paltrow’s Netflix series, The Goop Lab (titled The Healing Trip), you may be aware that such developments reflect a rising interest, and investment, in the mental health application of psychedelic drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason for this is that a decades-long struggle to resurrect medical research in the area is beginning to bear fruit. In London, we have spearheaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanpsy/article/PIIS2215-0366(16)30065-7/fulltext&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; showing how psilocybin ( or “magic mushrooms”) can be used to assist psychotherapy for difficult-to-treat depression, making a significant difference when conventional antidepressants and talking therapy have not. Right now, we are crunching data from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03429075&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;much larger&lt;/a&gt; depression trial that compares psilocybin-assisted therapy with a six-week course of a conventional antidepressant drug, a “Prozac-like” selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor (SSRI). Preliminary analyses indicate game-changing results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There hasn’t been a breakthrough in mental healthcare for some time, and psychedelic therapy works very differently to current treatments. Conventional drug treatments have dominated psychiatry for decades, and although many people prefer psychotherapy, it is more expensive, harder to access and arguably no more effective than the drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These drugs haven’t changed much since their discovery, and come with side effects that put people off taking them. Where SSRIs are concerned, their antidepressant action seems to rely on a moderation of the stress response – but it is a palliative rather than curative action, which requires having the chemical in the body for several months or longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychedelic therapy is a much more comprehensive treatment package. It entails a small number of psychologically supported dosing sessions, flanked by assessment, preparation, and integration (talking through one’s experience afterwards). Psychedelics appear to increase brain “plasticity”, which, broadly speaking, implies an accelerated ability to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One view is that a psychedelic experience is a consequence of an especially intense surge of plasticity that opens a window of opportunity for lasting therapeutic change. The same windows may open up during other extreme states, such as experiencing trauma, stress-induced breakdown, a spontaneous spiritual experience or coming close to death. The difference with psychedelic therapy, however, is that the experience is carefully prepared for, contained and mediated. If not done this way, the use of psychedelics can be dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of successful psychedelic therapy is often one of revelation or epiphany. People speak of witnessing “the bigger picture”, placing things in perspective, accessing deep insight about themselves and the world, releasing pent-up mental pain, feeling emotionally and physically recalibrated, clear-sighted and equanimous. This is very different from people’s descriptions of the effects of SSRIs, where a contrasting feeling of being emotionally muted is not uncommon. It would be premature to disclose the findings of our head-to-head trial prior to proper scientific review, but on top of impressive tolerability and antidepressant effects with psilocybin-assisted therapy, we are seeing remarkable changes in patient-relevant outcomes. These include increased quality of life, “flourishing” (feeling well rather than just “not depressed”), the ability to feel pleasure again and normal sexual functioning. The value of something new and different is often hard to gauge until it is placed alongside something more familiar, and our new study does this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those driving efforts to get psilocybin therapy licensed hope to be able to market it across North America and Europe within the next five years. As was the case with medicinal cannabis, however, it is quite possible that use could begin to scale up prior to formal licensing. Before Covid-19, a small but buoyant market existed for plant-based psychedelic retreats or ceremonies in pockets of Europe, as well as Central and South America. There have been a number of initiatives to liberalise policies on psychedelic use in the US, and the most ambitious is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oregonlive.com/politics/2020/05/dr-bronners-soap-company-donates-1-million-to-oregon-effort-to-legalize-psychedelic-mushrooms.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;psilocybin service initiative&lt;/a&gt; in Oregon, which aims to phase in legal, regulated psilocybin therapy through Oregon’s health system, from this year. Whatever one’s view on these developments, allying them with research is imperative if we are to advance scientific understanding, and ultimately inform and safeguard the individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this progress, the idea of “psychedelics for mental health” will be petrol on flames for some. Stigma is attached to both mental illness and psychedelics, and so full entry into the mainstream won’t go unchallenged (and rightly so). If the 1960s is anything to go by, there may be passions to temper at both ends of the spectrum, as psychedelics evangelisers could stoke as much trouble as opponents – which is why a dispassionate, scientific approach is so important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all tourism, the psychedelic variety will have taken a big hit in the pandemic, but it is unclear whether home use has been affected, either in prevalence or quality. “Hardly the best time for a trip,” one might think – but psychedelics are sensitive to the slippery subtleties of context. Many of the insights these compounds awaken are of a Buddhist sort, and although timelessly relevant, they feel particularly so today: the self as illusory, suffering as inevitable, attachment as a common cause of suffering, impermanence as fundamental, and slowing down, contemplation, breath, and community as potent resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sars-Cov-2 is a virus that attacks the respiratory system and can kill. We all breathe, and we will all die, but our instinct is to forget and escape these truths. Two of this pandemic’s silver linings are that it has invited an expanded consciousness – and that people have slowed down. Many will have noticed their breath, contemplated their own and other’s impermanence, and felt grateful for care, love and life. If psychedelic therapy does fulfil its potential, it will be providing the same essential lessons. The extent to which we listen will be up to us.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 17:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>throwaway888abc</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/jun/08/psychedelic-drugs-treat-depression</og:url>
<og:description>At Imperial College we’ve been comparing psilocybin to conventional antidepressants – and the results are likely to be game-changing, says Robin Carhart-Harris</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a4b479a6a868bf0f36804ea8f72a355818db5a97/0_0_2560_1536/master/2560.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctb3BpbmlvbnMucG5n&amp;enable=upscale&amp;s=e910f616128a5890345b4a3306b28811</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>We can no longer ignore the potential of psychedelic drugs to treat depression | Robin Carhart-Harris</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/jun/08/psychedelic-drugs-treat-depression</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>DuckDuckGo, Google, and Android choice screens</title>
<link>https://www.wired.co.uk/article/duckduckgo-android-choice-screen-search</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.co.uk/article/duckduckgo-android-choice-screen-search</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bb-dropcap bb-dropcap--letter&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt;rom this summer, when you set up a new Android phone or tablet in Europe, you will be presented with an extra step: a choice screen to select your default search engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;The screen is simple. Under a search icon and a short blurb are four options. One is always Google; the others vary depending on which country you’re in. Pick one of Google’s rivals, and its results – not Google’s – will appear in a home screen search widget and in the Chrome web browser. Its app will also be downloaded to the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;The change is so subtle that many people may not notice it. But across the continent, it marks a fundamental shift. The choice screen appears in the wake of the European Commission fining Google €4.34 billion (£3.81bn) for breaching EU antitrust rules. On July 18, 2018, competition commissioner Margarethe Vestager hit Google with the fine – the largest of three she has issued against the company – for abusing the dominance of its Android operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad__main is-hidden ad--article ad--article-rail ad--article-rail-top stick-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad__block stick-element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;ad__title&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Being big isn’t illegal, but the European Commission says dominant companies have a &quot;special responsibility&quot; not to abuse their powerful market position by restricting competition. At the end of an investigation spanning more than three years, the Commission concluded that Google had acted illegally in using Android to ensure that traffic went to Google Search instead of its competitors. The Commission accused Google of three unfair tactics. Google, it said, had required manufacturers to pre-install the Google Search and Chrome apps if they wanted to license the Google Play app store; had paid mobile network operators and phone manufacturers to exclusively pre-install Google Search; and had prevented manufacturers from creating alternative versions of Android without its approval if they wanted to pre-install any Google apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Google’s actions, the Commission said, helped it to cement its dominance in the mobile search industry. In Europe, more than 95 per cent of all searches on mobile are made through Google. The market is mostly Android devices, but Google also pays billions to Apple to be the default search engine in the Safari browser on iOS. According to Vestager, its Android practices “denied rivals the chance to innovate and compete on the merits.” Google is appealing the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;The way many European antitrust fines work puts the onus of fixing a problem on the guilty party. Google has re-written the contracts it holds with phone makers and relaxed limits on how Android can be developed by others. On new phones and tablets shipped into the European Economic Area, it has introduced the search engine choice screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;The choice screen gives Google’s rivals an unprecedented presence on Android devices. Smaller players have never had such an opportunity to directly reach users on the world’s biggest mobile operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad__main is-hidden ad--article ad--article-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad__block&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;ad__title&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Chief among those set to benefit is DuckDuckGo, a US-based search engine founded in 2008 by CEO Gabriel Weinberg. DuckDuckGo will appear on all 31 choice screens across Europe when it is first implemented, a number matched only by Info.com. The company has been competing with Google for more than a decade, offering a search engine that emphasises privacy and doesn’t collect user data, but it is still tiny compared to Larry Page and Sergey Brin’s creation. “We're not trying to topple Google,” Weinberg, 40, says. “Our goal is for consumers who want to choose a private option, they should be able to do so easily.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bb-figure__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/static/img/tiny.gif&quot; data-src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KDavxo8kvvY/crop/405/f/1.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KDavxo8kvvY/crop/405/f/1.jpg 405w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KDavxo8kvvY/crop/810/f/1.jpg 810w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KDavxo8kvvY/crop/1020/f/1.jpg 1020w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KDavxo8kvvY/crop/1440/f/1.jpg 1440w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KDavxo8kvvY/crop/1620/f/1.jpg 1620w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; class=&quot;c-image c-image--lazyload&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KDavxo8kvvY/crop/405/f/1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bb-figure__content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Rohlfs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bb-dropcap bb-dropcap--letter&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he idea for DuckDuckGo came partly from a stained glass class. In 2007, a couple of years after completing his masters in technology policy at MIT, and having already sold a social networking startup, Opobox, for $10 million, Weinberg decided to try his hand at a new hobby. The class teacher handed out a print-out of the best websites to learn more about creating stained glass. When Weinberg tried to search for information on Google, none of the recommended sites appeared in the top results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;The sheet of paper led to the creation of I’ve Got a Fang, a crowd-sourced site where people could contribute authoritative URLs on particular subjects. Weinberg, who lives in Philadelphia, believed the knowledge from people’s heads could be better than Google’s algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad__main is-hidden ad--article ad--article-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad__block&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;ad__title&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;I’ve Got a Fang was a flop: few people added links to the site and it failed to get any traction. But the idea of human curation stuck, and Weinberg combined this notion with the remnants of another failed side gig – one that had already run into trouble with Google. Tldscan was a series of websites that crawled structured information and published it to the web – think sports statistics available in one place. In a now-archived 2010 blog post, “My history of (mostly failed) side projects and startups”, Weinberg wrote that he was getting 50,000 visitors and $500 revenue per day from Tldscan. “Then Google blacklisted all of my sites,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;The combination of I’ve Got a Fang’s human expertise and Tldscan’s efforts to surface useful information became key pillars of DuckDuckGo, which launched a year later in September 2008. “My original spark was: could there be a better user experience in search?” says a bespectacled, clean-shaven Weinberg, speaking via a Zoom call in March. (While many companies had to radically adapt their way of working as the Covid-19 outbreak spread across the world, little changed for DuckDuckGo; its 89 staff work remotely all the time, and there is no main office.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Initially, Weinberg started building the technology needed to crawl, index and rank the web himself, but he stopped when Yahoo! introduced a service called Build Your Own Search Service (BOSS). Using this, he focused on refining Yahoo!’s results and adding extra services on top. Today, DuckDuckGo combines data from more than 400 sources into its search results: Microsoft’s Bing is predominantly used to surface relevant pages, but Wikipedia, Apple Maps, TripAdvisor and DuckDuckGo’s own web crawler also contribute. There are more than 1,000 different sources for the “Instant Answer” snippets DuckDuckGo shows alongside its results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;It wasn’t until 2010 that the search company set out its unique selling point: it wasn’t going to track users. The company committed to throwing away IP address information and not storing details of what people searched for. “At the beginning, privacy wasn't the main draw,” Weinberg says. “It wasn't as known as an issue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Initial growth was slow; in April 2010 the site was getting around 30,000 to 40,000 search queries a day, barely appearing as a blip on the search radar. Weinberg didn’t hire his first full-time employee until 2011, and up until then he was primarily focused on being a stay-at-home dad for his first child, born the year after DuckDuckGo launched. During some early investor meetings, he says, he was rocking his second child out of his webcam’s field of vision. The company raised $3 million in a Series A round in 2011, led by Union Square Ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo’s real breakthrough came thanks to Edward Snowden. The former NSA contractor’s explosive government surveillance revelations in 2013 prominently included Google among the data sources used by British and US spy agencies. People were newly interested in seeking out privacy-first alternatives, and DuckDuckGo’s daily search queries swelled from 1.5 million a day to 4.1 million a day in the space of a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;At the time, many people switching from Google wouldn’t have been happy with the experience their new search engine offered, and it’s likely that plenty quickly switched back. Weinberg says that it wasn’t until 2014 that DuckDuckGo could really compete with its Silicon Valley rival. It was a crucial year for the company: it hit its tenth employee; incorporated news, video and image verticals in a big site redesign; and was included as an alternative search engine option in Apple’s Safari browser on iOS. “Apple is effectively a mainstream endorsement,” Weinberg says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;It was in 2014 that DuckDuckGo also made its first profit; it’s been profitable ever since, and the company forecasts it will pass the $100 million revenue barrier for the first time in 2020 (thought this may be affected by the Covid-19 pandemic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;It makes its money in the same way as Google: through advertisements. Each time a user clicks on an ad that is shown alongside search results, the company takes home a small amount of money. But where the two differ is that DuckDuckGo uses contextual advertising over the data-heavy behavioural advertising that helps Google earn billions each quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Contextual adverts are shown to users based on the searches they make: if you DuckDuckGo “Mercedes”, you’ll be served adverts for cars on that page. Google “Mercedes”, however, and adverts for cars will follow you off the page and around the web, because Google adds that data to the other information it knows about you. Behavioural advertising is much more lucrative, as each time an ad is clicked on there’s a higher likelihood the person will buy. Google’s expertise in knowing what users will be most likely to click on is rivalled only by that of Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;People’s increased awareness of privacy issues has continued to fuel DuckDuckGo’s growth. As with Snowden’s revelations, the 2018 Cambridge Analytica scandal propelled Weinberg and DuckDuckGo into the mainstream. Around the same time, the company launched desktop browser extensions that stop web tracking, as well as its own mobile web browser for Android and iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;The cumulative effect was significant. On March 17, 2018, the day &lt;em class=&quot;bb-em&quot;&gt;The Observer&lt;/em&gt; first reported on Cambridge Analytica, 17 million DuckDuckGo searches were made; exactly two years later, 57 million searches were completed. Weinberg says DuckDuckGo’s key users are people who both care about their privacy and are willing to act upon it. “The caring really went up after Snowden,” he says. “After Cambridge Analytica the acting percentage has really skyrocketed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Google’s new Android choice screen could give another boost to DuckDuckGo, finally propelling it into the mainstream as millions of people replace their old phones over the coming years. “It's really a levelling, if it's done right, for competition,” Weinberg says. But he, and other search engines, have issues with Google’s implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bb-figure__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/static/img/tiny.gif&quot; data-src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/e8RwVjd2o2R/crop/405/f/5.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/e8RwVjd2o2R/crop/405/f/5.jpg 405w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/e8RwVjd2o2R/crop/810/f/5.jpg 810w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/e8RwVjd2o2R/crop/1020/f/5.jpg 1020w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/e8RwVjd2o2R/crop/1440/f/5.jpg 1440w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/e8RwVjd2o2R/crop/1620/f/5.jpg 1620w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; class=&quot;c-image c-image--lazyload&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/e8RwVjd2o2R/crop/405/f/5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bb-figure__content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Rohlfs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bb-dropcap bb-dropcap--letter&quot;&gt;M&lt;/span&gt;ultiple European search startups say they are in favour of a choice screen. They argue that users should be allowed to pick which search tool they use – even if they end up choosing Google (in most cases they will). But Google’s execution of the choice screen has angered its rivals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;To appear, companies have to pay Google, via an auction that is held every three months. Bid enough, and you win a coveted slot as one of three options alongside Google. A similar auction approach was introduced as a fix to a 2017 EU antitrust case around Google Shopping. In search, companies say they don't think an auction is a fair way of encouraging competition or innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Google argues that an auction is a “fair and objective” way of smaller companies being able to compete, and that it allows them to decide “what value they place on appearing in the choice screen”. Every time an Android user picks a search engine to use – even if they switch back to Google minutes later – that search engine is charged. Google issues the companies an invoice each month, and the money goes back into the development of Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Ahead of the first round of bidding towards the end of 2019, Google set a minimum bid. Multiple sources, who are not able to speak publicly, say it set prices of above $20 per user for some European countries. This amount would be unrealistic for small companies, the sources say. “I actually think they saw this as a price we would easily be able to pay,” one person familiar with the bidding says, adding that it was “ridiculous”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Ultimately, the minimum bid was scrapped in favour of a system where all the winners pay the price set by the first losing bidder. Google says it changed the format after receiving feedback and to make it easier for rivals to participate. One source says companies will now be paying the “lowest number to zero that you can do besides being zero.” Another company says the only reason it bid in the process was because it was cheaper than advertising on Facebook. “We will get our name out more than I think we will directly get users from the choice screen,” the company CEO says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo is one of the auction’s big winners, appearing as an option in all 31 countries. But it isn’t happy about it. “You're incentivised to bid your profit,” Weinberg says. He predicts the auction prices will keep rising until it’s harder for search engines to make any money. “Google is taking away all the profit of these search engines and profiting from it themselves,” he says. “They're effectively running other people's search and taking other people's profit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;“It plays the competitors against each other,” says Christian Kroll, the CEO of Ecosia, a German search engine that plants trees when searches are made on its platform. “So instead of collaboration, we have now kind of a toxic environment between smaller search engines as well.” Ecosia decided to boycott the auction. Kroll says in the long term he doesn’t believe the company can win, because 80 per cent of its profits are spent on tree planting. “I think this was very well thought out by Google,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo has loudly criticised Google’s efforts. Weinberg and DuckDuckGo general counsel Megan Gray, who previously worked at the US Federal Trade Commission in consumer protection, argue that Google’s process is flawed. They say there should be more than four options shown to users, and that people should be given more information about the choice they’re making. If there was one fix? “Getting rid of the damn auction,” Gray says. “It should be a genuine choice – it shouldn't be pay to play. That would be the best outcome here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Paul Gennai, a product management director at Google, says that Android has “created more choice for everyone, not less” and that the operating system's openness has meant “developers of apps that compete against Google have precisely the same ability to reach users”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;“From day one, Google developed Android to be open: both to the manufacturers who build devices, as well as to the people who buy them – we think both should have the flexibility to set them up just as they want,” Gennai says. “This has taken billions of dollars of investment over more than ten years.” He adds that Google also invests in its Play app store, which includes safety features such as scanning apps for malware. “With the changes required in Europe, we implemented an auction to ensure that it would continue to be viable for Google to continue its investments in the open Android ecosystem,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;A spokesperson for the European Commission says it is closely monitoring how the choice screen is being introduced and the mechanisms behind it. &quot;We have been discussing the choice screen mechanism with Google, following relevant feedback from the market, in particular in relation to the presentation and mechanics of the choice screen and to the selection mechanism of rival search providers,&quot; the spokesperson says. (Since this story went to press, the results of the second Android choice screen auction have been published. Fewer companies are included as winners and Microsoft's Bing has no presence. DuckDuckGo says prices have increased, too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Aside from controversies around the auction, there are questions over how much difference the choice screen will make. A 2010 EU antitrust investigation saw Microsoft launch a choice screen for web browsers – the Commission had said that Microsoft used the dominance of the Windows operating system to direct people to its Internet Explorer browser, which was included as the default on Windows. Its choice screen ran for four years, but at the end of this time smaller browsers had not gained any significant market share. (The biggest market shift was the rise of Google's Chrome browser, which had only recently launched and was rising in popularity anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;And in search, Google nearly always wins. One major exception – aside from in China, where Google search is banned – is in Russia. There, Yandex is king. Launched in 1997, a year before Google, Yandex acts as the country’s homegrown Uber, Spotify, Amazon and favoured search engine all rolled into one. At the start of 2015, Russians searching the web on their desktop machines were overwhelmingly likely to be using the company – 63 per cent of all searches were made using Yandex. But on mobile it was a different story. In an Android-dominant country, the tables were turned, with 62 per cent of all mobile searches being made via Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Staff at Yandex were aghast when they discovered Google had struck deals with phone makers that prohibited them from accepting payments to pre-install other search engines if they wanted to use the Android operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;As in the EU, regulators in Russia were scrutinising the power Android gives Google search. In March 2017, the Federal Antimonopoly Service (FAS) fined Google 438,067,400 roubles (£4.4 million) and then reached a settlement with the company that said Android would offer a choice screen for search engines, in this case on both new and existing devices (Google says technical changes mean the EU choice screen can only apply to new phones).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Smartphone users in Russia started to see choice screens from August 2017. That month, search on Android was 60 per cent Google. The gap closed and a year later it was split 50/50 with Yandex. At the start of March 2020, Yandex had 56 per cent of all Android searches, with Google’s share dropping to 42 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;But while Yandex was also one of the bigger winners in the EU Android auction, appearing on device screens in 16 countries, Preston Carey, a senior vice president at Yandex, says he doesn’t expect to see any large market shifts. “Putting a choice screen up in the UK or Germany is not going to have the same result as putting one up in Russia,” he says. He argues that no other search company has the brand recognition that Yandex does in Russia in any other country – meaning people will be less likely to switch away from Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;In its own tests, DuckDuckGo created a choice screen with 18 different options and placed Google at the end of the list. It found people still scrolled all the way to the bottom to find the one they were most familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bb-figure__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/static/img/tiny.gif&quot; data-src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/6j8r9L2Aqjb/crop/405/f/0720ftduckduckgo_4.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/6j8r9L2Aqjb/crop/405/f/0720ftduckduckgo_4.jpg 405w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/6j8r9L2Aqjb/crop/810/f/0720ftduckduckgo_4.jpg 810w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/6j8r9L2Aqjb/crop/1020/f/0720ftduckduckgo_4.jpg 1020w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/6j8r9L2Aqjb/crop/1440/f/0720ftduckduckgo_4.jpg 1440w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/6j8r9L2Aqjb/crop/1620/f/0720ftduckduckgo_4.jpg 1620w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; class=&quot;c-image c-image--lazyload&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/6j8r9L2Aqjb/crop/405/f/0720ftduckduckgo_4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bb-figure__content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Rohlfs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bb-dropcap bb-dropcap--letter&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;hile Android’s new choice screen is unlikely to end Google’s dominance in search, even a one per cent shift in market share over a period of several years would be colossal growth for firms such as DuckDuckGo. Weinberg predicts his firm could one day have a market share of ten per cent (it currently sits at 0.32 per cent of global market share). This would still pale in comparison to Google but be a big boost to the 1.5 billion monthly DuckDuckGos already taking place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;And to DuckDuckGo, the battle for search represents just a small part of a bigger struggle over how advertising on the web works, and what this means for personal data and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;The vast ad networks of Facebook and Google are fed with personal data collected across the web. Trackers from both companies gather information about online activity from almost all of the web’s most popular sites. By collecting billions of data points, the companies are able to build revenues in excess of $20 billion every three months. The vast majority of this money comes from advertising – in particular behavioural advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Trackers and cookies are present across almost all websites; they monitor and track people’s activities online and log them under unique identifiers connected to individuals (Wired.co.uk uses trackers to collect and share reader data as part of business practices). But at the start of April this year, the data protection regulator for Ireland, which oversees all the big US tech companies headquartered in the country, released a report saying many websites fail to give “basic information” to people that visit them and that “most ordinary users will not be aware of the extent to which they may be tracked”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;This tracking allows companies to collect data on people’s interests and activities, which they can feed into advertising models and use to serve people behavioural adverts linked to their interests; Facebook’s Pixel, for example, is on more than eight million websites. “Strategically, Google and Facebook have all the user data,” Weinberg says. DuckDuckGo’s web browser, like its search engine, does not store personal data. In addition, it blocks the invisible trackers hidden on web pages. The company wants to see less tracking elsewhere, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;In 2009, security researchers proposed a Do Not Track setting for browsers. In theory this is a checkbox, or an option in a browser’s settings menu, that allows a user to opt out of being tracked as they move around the web. Firefox, Internet Explorer, Opera and Chrome all use it, but it's largely ineffective. (Apple's Safari stopped using it in 2019). Websites across the web don’t have to honour the setting; Medium and Pinterest are two of the most prominent that do. Twitter originally supported it but doesn’t anymore, and efforts from web standards bodies have failed to make it more effective. Despite having the feature in Chrome, Google’s support pages say the company’s own websites “don't change their behavior” when Do Not Track is turned on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;In 2018, consulting firm Forrester found that around a quarter of Americans had the largely-ineffective setting switched on. A year later, lawyers for DuckDuckGo proposed “The Do-Not-Track Act of 2019”, a draft piece of legislation designed to make the Do Not Track setting be backed by law: websites would have to respect a user’s wishes to not have their behaviour online recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;The idea has not been put into practice anywhere in the US but a similar concept is marginally closer to reality in Europe. For the last three years, European legislators have been debating the ePrivacy Regulation, a complimentary law to GDPR which could include Do Not Track provisions. The regulation has been subject to intense lobbying and is currently in a state of stagnation. But it’s the closest anywhere has got to limiting how people are tracked online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Weinberg believes its enactment would open up the online advertising market and thus potentially reduce the dominance of Facebook and Google in the space. If a quarter of the web was suddenly using a setting that meant it was harder to serve them adverts targeted at their interests, traditional contextual advertising would rise again. This would be good for privacy, but it could also help open up competition, Weinberg says; if Google and Facebook didn’t have such a data advantage, perhaps smaller companies could compete on a more even footing. “If everyone competes on contextual advertising, now all of a sudden they actually have to compete with a lot of other players,” he says. Google has already been experimenting further with contextual advertising, which one of its product managers wrote in a blog post was to help preserve user privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Competition regulators are also shifting their focus to how data is used by big tech companies. On both sides of the Atlantic, examinations are underway into how Alphabet, Amazon, Apple, Facebook and Microsoft have acquired smaller companies. The EU is also looking more broadly at how Google and Facebook collect data and the implications for competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Ultimately, Weinberg wants people to understand that they don’t need to give away their personal information to make the most of technology. “We really want to combat people's learned helplessness in privacy,” he says. “Everyone's concerned, but a large percentage of people just think there's nothing you can really do about it. We want to prove that you can do something.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bb-em&quot;&gt;Updated: This article first appeared in print. Prior to online publication Megan Gray's role at the FTC has been updated and Gabriel Weinberg was rocking his second child while talking to investors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bb-em&quot;&gt;Matt Burgess is WIRED's deputy digital editor. He tweets from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattburgess1&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;@mattburgess1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;bb-h4&quot; id=&quot;more-great-stories-from-wired&quot;&gt;More great stories from WIRED&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;bb-strong&quot;&gt;🤑 Inside the 'bullshit' &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/dropshipping-instagram-ads&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;get-rich-quick world of dropshipping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;bb-strong&quot;&gt;🎵 The secret behind the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/apple-airpods-success&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;success of Apple's AirPods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;bb-strong&quot;&gt;📖 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/how-coronavirus-kills&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;How coronavirus kills&lt;/a&gt;, one organ at a time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad__main is-hidden ad--article ad--article-rail stick-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad__block stick-element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;ad__title&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;bb-strong&quot;&gt;🎲 The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/best-board-games-2020&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;best board games&lt;/a&gt; for adults and families&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;bb-strong&quot;&gt;🔒 The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/uk-lockdown&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;UK's lockdown rules&lt;/a&gt;, explained&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;bb-strong&quot;&gt;👉 Follow WIRED on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WiredUK&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/wireduk/&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/WiredUK/&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/wired-uk/&quot; class=&quot;bb-a noskim&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 16:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>x32n23nr</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google got rich from your data. DuckDuckGo is fighting back</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.wired.co.uk/article/duckduckgo-android-choice-screen-search</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>In July 2018, Google was fined €4.34 billion for limiting search on Android phones. Almost two years later, its rivals claim little has changed and the company is as dominant as ever</og:description>
<og:image>https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/1v6jd6DZrVK/crop/1440/0.5235602094240838/f/1-hero.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.co.uk/article/duckduckgo-android-choice-screen-search</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Al Jaffee / Mad Magazine Fold-In Effect in CSS</title>
<link>https://thomaspark.co/2020/06/the-mad-magazine-fold-in-effect-in-css/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thomaspark.co/2020/06/the-mad-magazine-fold-in-effect-in-css/</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://thomaspark.co/2020/06/the-mad-magazine-fold-in-effect-in-css/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://thomaspark.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mad-fold-in-300x300.gif&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 65 years at Mad Magazine, comic artist Al Jaffee &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/arts-entertainment/2020/06/06/al-jaffee-mad-magazine-retires/&quot;&gt;announced his retirement&lt;/a&gt;. Jaffee was best known for his Mad Fold-Ins, where folding the page would reveal a hidden message in the artwork. Plenty of examples can be found on the web. The problem is, they all show the before and after statically, side by side, which diminishes the magic (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mad_Fold-in&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://13thdimension.com/13-mad-fold-ins-an-al-jaffee-celebration/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). There’s a whole generation who may have only seen the fold-ins in this format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I had to create the paper folding effect for the web. There’s many different ways to achieve this, but this approach is nice because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It’s CSS only, relying on no JavaScript.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses a single image instead of requiring the image to be sliced up in Photoshop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be configured with just HTML by setting CSS variables in a style attribute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a demo of it in action, using artwork by Johnny Sampson &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.madmagazine.com/blog/2019/03/13/a-special-98th-birthday-fold-in-for-al-jaffee&quot;&gt;in an issue that celebrated Jaffee’s 98th birthday&lt;/a&gt;. Hover or tap to fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;jaffee-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jaffee&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomaspark.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/jaffee.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And another by Jaffee himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;jaffee-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jaffee&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomaspark.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/MAD-Magazine-520-Fold-in.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HTML for the effect is fairly straightforward. You might be wondering about the standalone image element — it’s hidden but used to set the size and aspect ratio of the component. The image path is specified there and once again as a CSS variable to set the background image of the other elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markup&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-markup&quot;&gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&quot;jaffee&quot; style=&quot;--bg: url('path/to/image.png');&quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;span class=&quot;a&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;span class=&quot;bc&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;span class=&quot;b&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;img src=&quot;path/to/image.png&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is the CSS used to set the positioning, 3D transforms, and transitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;
.jaffee {
  position: relative;
  display: inline-flex;
  justify-content: center;
  transform: rotateX(10deg); 
  transform-style: preserve-3d;
  cursor: grab;
}

.jaffee img {
  width: auto;
  height: auto;
  max-width: 100%;
  max-height: 60vh;
  opacity: 0;
}

.jaffee .a,
.jaffee .b,
.jaffee .c {
  top: 0;
  display: inline-block;
  height: 100%;
  background-image: var(--bg);
  background-size: cover;
  background-repeat: no-repeat;
}

.jaffee .a {
  position: absolute;
  left: 0;
  width: 50%;
  background-position: 0 0;
}

.jaffee .bc {
  position: absolute;
  display: inline-flex;
  width: 50%;
  height: 100%;
  left: 50%;
  transform-origin: left;
  transition: transform 3s;
  transform-style: preserve-3d;
}

.jaffee .b,
.jaffee .c {
  position: relative;
  width: 50%;
}

.jaffee .b {
  background-position: 66.666667% 0;
}

.jaffee .c {
  background-position: 100% 0;
  transform-origin: left;
  transition: transform 2s;
  backface-visibility: hidden;
}

.jaffee:hover .bc,
.jaffee:active .bc {
  transform: rotateY(-180deg) translateZ(-1px);
  transition: transform 2s;
}

.jaffee:hover .c,
.jaffee:active .c {
  transform: rotateY(180deg) translateZ(1px);
  transition: transform 3s;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;related-posts&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;related-posts-MRP_all&quot; class=&quot;related-posts-type&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 16:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thomaspark</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Mad Magazine Fold-In Effect in CSS</og:title>
<og:url>https://thomaspark.co/2020/06/the-mad-magazine-fold-in-effect-in-css/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>After 65 years at Mad Magazine, comic artist Al Jaffee announced his retirement. Jaffee was best known for his Mad Fold-Ins, where folding the page would reveal a hidden message in the artwork. Plenty of examples can be found on the web. The problem is, they all show the before and after statically,</og:description>
<og:image>https://thomaspark.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mad-fold-in.gif</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thomaspark.co/2020/06/the-mad-magazine-fold-in-effect-in-css/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Britain gave Palantir access to sensitive COVID-19 patient records in £1 deal</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/08/palantir-nhs-covid-19-data.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/08/palantir-nhs-covid-19-data.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;InlineImage-imageEmbed hasBkg&quot; id=&quot;ArticleBody-InlineImage-104257517&quot; data-test=&quot;InlineImage&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineImage-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Thiel, co-founder of PayPal Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VCG | Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; readability=&quot;70.203511572227&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britain's National Health Service has given secretive U.S. tech firm Palantir access to private personal data of millions of British citizens, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn-prod.opendemocracy.net/media/documents/Palantir_Agreements.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a contract published online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data includes personal contact details, gender, race, occupation, physical and mental health conditions, past criminal offenses, as well as religious and political affiliation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contract, known as a data-sharing agreement, was published Friday by politics website OpenDemocracy and law firm Foxglove alongside similar contracts with Google, Microsoft, and U.K. AI start-up Faculty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The contracts show that the companies involved, including Faculty and Palantir, were originally granted intellectual property rights (including the creation of databases), and were allowed to train their models and profit off their unprecedented access to NHS data,&quot; openDemocracy editor-in-chief Mary Fitzgerald and Foxglove founding director and U.S. lawyer Cori Crider wrote in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opendemocracy.net/en/under-pressure-uk-government-releases-nhs-covid-data-deals-big-tech/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is a highly valuable commodity to tech giants, and personal patient data is among the most highly sought after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contracts show Palantir charged only £1 ($1.27) for use of its Foundry data management software while Google offered &quot;technical, advisory and other support&quot; for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the tech firms were enlisted by the British government to set up a national platform that would allow health officials to understand how the coronavirus is spreading across the U.K. and help them allocate resources appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details of the data platform were first &lt;a href=&quot;https://healthtech.blog.gov.uk/2020/03/28/the-power-of-data-in-a-pandemic/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;made public in March&lt;/a&gt; but the U.K. government refused to publish the all-important data-sharing agreements following a number of freedom of information requests, including one by CNBC. The contracts were finally published last week after OpenDemocracy and Foxglove threatened legal action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-founded by billionaire Peter Thiel, an ally of President Donald Trump, Palantir has developed data trawling technology that intelligence agencies and governments use for surveillance and to spot suspicious patterns in public and private databases. Customers include the CIA, FBI, and the U.S. Army.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palantir sees a huge opportunity in Europe and now has more staff in its London office than it does at its headquarters in Palo Alto, California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last September, Palantir was looking to raise new funding at a $26 billion plus valuation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/09/20/palantir-to-seek-at-least-26-billion-valuation-in-fundraising-push.html&quot;&gt;according to Reuters&lt;/a&gt;. It is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2020/04/09/palantir-expects-revenue-to-top-1-billion-this-year.html&quot;&gt;expecting to reach&lt;/a&gt; $1 billion in revenue this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palantir did not immediately respond to CNBC's request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AndrewBissell</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Britain gave Palantir access to sensitive medical records of Covid-19 patients in £1 deal</og:title>
<og:description>Peter Thiel's Palantir was given access to NHS patient records that contain citizen's contact details, gender, race, religion, occupation, physical and mental health condition, as well as past criminal offenses.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/08/palantir-nhs-covid-19-data.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/104257517-GettyImages-464620606.jpg?v=1532563922</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/08/palantir-nhs-covid-19-data.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Impending Doom of Expiring Root CAs and Legacy Clients</title>
<link>https://scotthelme.co.uk/impending-doom-root-ca-expiring-legacy-clients/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://scotthelme.co.uk/impending-doom-root-ca-expiring-legacy-clients/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Regular readers will know that I'm very active in the CA / PKI space and even deliver a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feistyduck.com/training/the-best-ssl-and-tls-training-in-the-world&quot;&gt;2-day advanced training course&lt;/a&gt; on the topic. Over the last year or so I've been watching as a potentially big problem has been rolling in over the horizon and just the other day I saw the first signs of the storm hitting the shore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;terminology&quot;&gt;Terminology&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just before we dig in I want to clear up some terminology so we're all on the same page. A CA is a Certificate Authority, the organisations that issue certificates so you can have HTTPS on your website. I speak a lot about &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/&quot;&gt;Let's Encrypt&lt;/a&gt; who are one of the biggest CAs out there but you may also recognise names like Comodo, Sectigo, DigiCert et al. The PKI, or Public Key Infrastructure, is used to authenticate users and devices online. Today I'm going to be talking about a subset of that which we call the Internet PKI, which refers to the collection of public CAs used to issue certificates to websites so we can authenticate them in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-cas-work&quot;&gt;How CAs Work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that the browser can authenticate a website, it must be presented with a valid certificate chain by the server it's connecting to. A typical chain would look something like this, but note that there can be more than 1 intermediate certificate in a chain. The minimum number of certificates you can expect to see in a valid chain is 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-5.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Root CA Certificate is the heart of a CA and is quite literally embedded in your OS or your browser of choice, it's physically present on your device. The Root CA issues the Intermediate CA, which in-turn issues the End-Entity Certificate (also known as the leaf certificate or server certificate) to your website. The Leaf and Intermediate certificates are delivered to the client from the server, and the client already has the Root certificate, so with this collection of certificates the chain can be built and the identity of the website authenticated. That is an &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; brief overview of how this works and for more details you should seriously check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feistyduck.com/training/the-best-ssl-and-tls-training-in-the-world&quot;&gt;Training Course&lt;/a&gt; on the subject, but for now that should be enough to get us going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;so-what-s-the-problem&quot;&gt;So what's the problem?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is something that we all deal with on a regular basis without too much issue: Certificates have an expiry date and need replacing. I recently wrote about the new lifetime limit of 1 year that will be imposed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/certificate-lifetime-capped-to-1-year-from-sep-2020/&quot;&gt;September 2020&lt;/a&gt; which means we will all have to replace our Server Certificates every 12 months at least. That limit only applies to Server Certificates though, the certificates that we obtain to install on our website, it does not apply to CA Certificates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CA Certificates are governed by a different set of rules to our certificates and as such they have different lifetime restrictions. It's very common to see Intermediate Certificates with a lifetime of 5 years and Root Certificates with a lifetime of 25 years! This means that Intermediate Certificates expire on a somewhat regular schedule but this generally isn't a problem. Because the intermediate is delivered by the website it's fairly dynamic and as the website is renewing their certificate on a regular schedule, changing out the intermediate isn't really much of an extra burden. It can be changed quite easily alongside the Server Certificate, unlike the Root CA Certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said a moment ago, the Root CA is embedded into the client device itself, usually in the OS but also possibly in the browser or other software. Changing the Root CA isn't something the website can control, it's something that requires an update to be installed on the client, either an OS update or software update. I wonder what our track record of keeping OS/software updated is in the wider world?...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;legacy-cas&quot;&gt;Legacy CAs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some CAs have now been around for a very long time, we're talking 20-25 years! That also just so happens to mean that some of the original Root CAs out there are also coming towards the end of their natural life, their time is almost up. For most of us this won't be a problem at all because CAs have created new root certificates and those have been distributed across the World in OS and browser updates for years. For some of us though, those who haven't installed OS or browser updates for years, well there's kind of a problem...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This problem was perfectly demonstrated recently, at May 30 10:48:38 2020 GMT to be exact. That exact time was then the &lt;a href=&quot;https://crt.sh/?id=1&quot;&gt;AddTrust External CA Root&lt;/a&gt; expired and brought with it the first signs of trouble that I've been expecting for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roku, who are a pretty popular streaming device, had an &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.roku.com/en-gb/article/360049417393&quot;&gt;incident&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-6.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stripe, the payment processor, also had &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stripestatus/status/1266764992520441856&quot;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; readability=&quot;6.4649681528662&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;As of 10:48 UTC, webhook delivery is failing for some users. We’re investigating and will post updates here.&lt;/p&gt;
— Stripe Status (@stripestatus) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stripestatus/status/1266764992520441856?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 30, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spreedly, another big payment processor, also had an &lt;a href=&quot;https://status.spreedly.com/incidents/h39zkpygxcpk&quot;&gt;incident&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-7.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a whole load of stuff that broke because of this Root CA expiring and Andy Ayer has a good list tracking quite a few more &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/__agwa/timelines/1266777818811322368&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The point is, the affected clients only have the old (now expired) AddTrust Root CA Certificate installed and because they've not been updated they haven't received the new version that replaces it. Without that new version, things simply don't work and Server Certificates that should be valid, that are valid, will rightly be seen as invalid and rejected by the client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-long-time-coming&quot;&gt;A Long Time Coming&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular issue does not come as a surprise to many that operate in this specific area, I've been talking about this impending problem for probably 2 years in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feistyduck.com/training/the-best-ssl-and-tls-training-in-the-world&quot;&gt;TLS training course&lt;/a&gt;, but for many, this will come as a surprise, proven by all of the incidents I linked to above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-9.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another good example is the upcoming Root CA transition that's Let's Encrypt will be performing. I wrote about this back in &lt;a href=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/lets-encrypt-to-transition-to-isrg-root/&quot;&gt;April 2019&lt;/a&gt; when Let's Encrypt were planning to transition from their Identrust cross-signed chain to their own ISRG Root chain in July 2019, but it didn't happen...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, May 20 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Due to concerns about insufficient ISRG root propagation on Android devices we have decided to move the date on which we will start serving a chain to our own root from July 8, 2019, to July 8, 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's Encrypt had to push back the transition because of an issue we call root propagation, or more specifically, a lack of root propagation, where a Root CA is not widely distributed onto all clients out there. Let's Encrypt are currently using a cross-signed intermediate and chain down to the IdenTrust DST Root CA X3 certificate. That root certificate expires on 30th Sep 2021 and was issued way back in Sep 2000, so it's widely distributed, or propagated, as most devices have done an update in the last 20 years and as a result they have the IdenTrust Root Certificate installed. That said, Let's Encrypt need to move away from it before it expires and the plan was to migrate to their Root CA, the ISRG Root X1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-8.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ISRG Root was issued on 4th Jun 2015 and began the approval process to become a CA, a process it completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/2018/08/06/trusted-by-all-major-root-programs.html&quot;&gt;6th Aug 2018&lt;/a&gt;. At that point the Root CA will be available to all clients via an OS or software update, all they need to do is install the update. &quot;All they need to do&quot;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the core of the problem. The new Let's Encrypt Root CA was created in 2015 and fully approved for distribution in 2018. Now, ~2 years later, if a device has not been updated since Aug 2018, how does it know about this new Root CA? The answer: it doesn't. This is why Let's Encrypt delayed their switch to their own ISRG Root CA and are still serving the intermediate that chains down to the IdenTrust root, but that solution will only last until the expiry of the IdenTrust Root. They bought themselves some time, but not much. To test if your current client has the ISRG Root X1 installed, try and load this test site: &lt;a href=&quot;https://valid-isrgrootx1.letsencrypt.org/&quot;&gt;https://valid-isrgrootx1.letsencrypt.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can connect without warnings then it probably means you're OK, but just because it does connect it doesn't mean you're definitely OK. I'm not going to go into the complexities of chain building and the client doing what it wants, or the possibility you're behind a device terminating TLS on a corporate network, because there are a heap of other things to consider here that require hundreds more words. All I can say is that you're probably OK and if you want to spend hours talking about this, well, I have a training course for that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-not-let-s-encrypt-specific&quot;&gt;This is not Let's Encrypt specific&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not by a long shot, and that's the problem. We're coming to a point in time now where there are lots of CA Root Certificates expiring in the next few years simply because it's been 20+ years since the encrypted Web really started up and that's the lifetime of a Root CA certificate. This will catch some organisations off guard in a big way, as we've already seen, but there are also some organisations that have seen the problem on the horizon and are taking whatever steps they can to resolve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the TLS Training I deliver and various bits of consultancy work I do, I've worked with some organisations that have already actually hit this problem and worked through a solution where they can. There's only one organisation I'm fortunate enough to have been given permission to talk about and that's the BBC, our national broadcaster here in the UK. They had a really interesting problem because they do a lot of online streaming to a lot of different devices. Now, mobile apps and browsers aren't &lt;em&gt;generally&lt;/em&gt; too much of a problem, but Smart TVs, well, they're a whole different game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-10.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm sure many of you here know that Smart TVs aren't often as 'smart' as we'd like. Generally speaking the only time my TV gets an update now it's to &lt;em&gt;remove&lt;/em&gt; a feature, not add one... But this lack of updates does present another rather interesting problem. A Smart TV is basically a cut-down Linux computer, a computer that does TLS comms, that has a Root CA store and that has the exact same problems I've just talked through. The clock is ticking on the Root Certificates installed on the TV and with no updates, they never get replaced...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-11.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;A very awesome friend of mine, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tdp_org&quot;&gt;Neil Craig&lt;/a&gt;, is Lead Technical Architect at the BBC and he got me some specific details of an incident over there and allowed me to share it with you. On a recent server certificate update they got a new certificate issued by the GlobalSign &lt;a href=&quot;https://valid.r5.roots.globalsign.com/&quot;&gt;R5 Root&lt;/a&gt;, the root is valid from 13th Nov 2012 to 19th Jan 2038. The problem was, some TVs are so out of date that they don't have that R5 Root CA installed on them that was issued in 2012! This means that those TVs will reject certificates that chain to that Root CA and as a result, the streaming app stops working on the TV! Here we are in 2019/2020 with a problem that an 8 year old Root CA still hasn't managed to make its way onto a significant portion of 'Smart' TVs. The BBC were smart though and there was a workaround they could deploy which meant serving additional intermediate certificates that chain down to a different GlobalSign Root CA. The GlobalSign &lt;a href=&quot;https://valid.r3.roots.globalsign.com/&quot;&gt;R3 Root&lt;/a&gt; is valid 18th Mar 2009 to 18th Mar 2029 and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://valid.r1.roots.globalsign.com/&quot;&gt;R1 Root&lt;/a&gt; is valid 1st Sep 1998 to 28th Jan 2028.  With the R1 Root going back so far, and there being an alternate trust path available to build to it, the BBC was able to fix the problem and those outdated TVs were fixed because they had the old R1 Root installed. Here's a trimmed output from &lt;code&gt;openssl s_client -connect www.bbc.co.uk:443 -showcerts&lt;/code&gt; and what that looks like in Chrome on Windows at present. They use the same workaround on their &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; so it's easier for us to inspect the chain there than it is on the iPlayer API endpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Certificate chain
 0 s:C = GB, ST = London, L = London, O = British Broadcasting Corporation, CN = www.bbc.co.uk
   i:C = BE, O = GlobalSign nv-sa, CN = GlobalSign ECC OV SSL CA 2018
 1 s:C = BE, O = GlobalSign nv-sa, CN = GlobalSign ECC OV SSL CA 2018
   i:OU = GlobalSign ECC Root CA - R5, O = GlobalSign, CN = GlobalSign
 2 s:OU = GlobalSign ECC Root CA - R5, O = GlobalSign, CN = GlobalSign
   i:OU = GlobalSign Root CA - R3, O = GlobalSign, CN = GlobalSign
 3 s:OU = GlobalSign Root CA - R3, O = GlobalSign, CN = GlobalSign
   i:C = BE, O = GlobalSign nv-sa, OU = Root CA, CN = GlobalSign Root CA&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-17.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;What we can see here is the &lt;code&gt;www.bbc.co.uk&lt;/code&gt; certificate issued by the &lt;code&gt;GlobalSign ECC OV SSL CA 2018&lt;/code&gt; intermediate. That Intermediate has an Authority Key ID of &lt;code&gt;3de629489bea07ca21444a26de6eded283d09f59&lt;/code&gt; which means it can chain to any one of following three certificates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://censys.io/certificates/179fbc148a3dd00fd24ea13458cc43bfa7f59c8182d783a513f6ebec100c8924&quot;&gt;GlobalSign ECC Root CA - R5&lt;/a&gt; (Root) Validity 13 Nov 2012 to 19 Jan 2038&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://censys.io/certificates/f349954e8fb6d44011bcb789d97d9a2cb2032bd5f0b598d1fb8a099f5848d523&quot;&gt;GlobalSign ECC Root CA - R5&lt;/a&gt; (Intermediate) Validity 19 Jun 2019 to 28 Jan 2028&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://censys.io/certificates/3f319b2afed4a0f75127be59925550d0428e68763a09e273eb6a9ff8d18dbb5b&quot;&gt;GlobalSign ECC Root CA - R5&lt;/a&gt; (Intermediate) Validity 21 Nov 2018 to 18 Mar 2029&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem here is the first one in the list, the R5 Root. This is the newer one issued in 2012 that the older Smart TVs did not have installed, so the BBC couldn't just return the &lt;code&gt;www.bbc.co.uk&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;GlobalSign ECC OV SSL CA 2018&lt;/code&gt; certificates, they had to provide more intermediates so the client can build an alternate chain. By providing the 3rd certificate in the above list, the R5 Intermediate, the client can build a chain 'around' the R5 Root that is missing, so the chain continues. That R5 Intermediate certificate has an Authority Key ID of &lt;code&gt;8ff04b7fa82e4524ae4d50fa639a8bdee2dd1bbc&lt;/code&gt; meaning it could chain to one of the following three certificates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://censys.io/certificates/cbb522d7b7f127ad6a0113865bdf1cd4102e7d0759af635a7cf4720dc963c53b&quot;&gt;GlobalSign Root CA - R3&lt;/a&gt; (Root) Validity 18 Mar 2009 to 18 Mar 2029&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://censys.io/certificates/c94fedda4e8608908580bc7f87b434e03bb262e42f64c63820a8f50fb17c1cec&quot;&gt;GlobalSign Root CA - R3&lt;/a&gt; (Intermediate) Validity 18 Mar 2009 to 28 Jan 2028&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://censys.io/certificates/445eec78bc61215044a0379656aa2d5db5e42f76cb70b8d14c2077aa943d4ebb&quot;&gt;GlobalSign Root CA - R3&lt;/a&gt; (Intermediate) Validity 19 Sep 2018 to 28 Jan 2028&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point the BBC could end the chain and serve the &lt;code&gt;www.bbc.co.uk&lt;/code&gt; , &lt;code&gt;GlobalSign ECC OV SSL CA 2018&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;GlobalSign Root CA - R5&lt;/code&gt; (Intermediate) to the client for it to anchor on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://censys.io/certificates/cbb522d7b7f127ad6a0113865bdf1cd4102e7d0759af635a7cf4720dc963c53b&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;GlobalSign Root CA - R3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Root) but again, with an issue date of 2009 and a few years for approval and distribution, that might still not solve the problem as the R3 Root might not be present. So, in goes another intermediate to work around that! Again they served the 3rd certificate in the list above, the &lt;code&gt;GlobalSign Root CA - R3&lt;/code&gt; (Intermediate), which has an Authority Key ID of &lt;code&gt;607b661a450d97ca89502f7d04cd34a8fffcfd4b&lt;/code&gt;. That means it could chain to one of the following two certificates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://censys.io/certificates/ebd41040e4bb3ec742c9e381d31ef2a41a48b6685c96e7cef3c1df6cd4331c99&quot;&gt;GlobalSign Root CA&lt;/a&gt; (Root) Validity 01 Sep 1998 to 28 Jan 2028&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://censys.io/certificates/a8cc00deef9e19f74cceae192b86fe2e3d1a01391bbb01dd62a0438dd07501a7&quot;&gt;GlobalSign Root CA&lt;/a&gt; (Intermediate) Validity 20 Feb 2014 to 15 Dec 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we're &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; getting somewhere. That first certificate has a Friendly Name of &lt;code&gt;GlobalSign Root CA - R1&lt;/code&gt; and is a Root CA that is old enough to be installed on ancient devices that haven't been updated in years and the 'Smart' TVs can successfully build a chain to anchor on. This means instead of serving a 'normal' chain of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;www.bbc.co.uk (Leaf)
GlobalSign ECC OV SSL CA 2018 (Intermediate)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BBC instead have to serve a chain of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;www.bbc.co.uk (Leaf)
GlobalSign ECC OV SSL CA 2018 (Intermediate)
GlobalSign Root CA - R5 (Intermediate)
GlobalSign Root CA - R3 (Intermediate)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: when I started this blog I had no idea how deep down the rabbit hole we were going to end up, but here we are. Anyway, onward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At best, all the BBC have done here is delay the problem until 2028 when the R1 Root expires. At that point, they could shorten the chain and try to anchor on the R3 Root instead, which expires in 2029, and hope that Smart TVs have updated enough to have that Root CA installed by the time we get there...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BBC could also look at switching to another CA with a Root CA that has a slightly longer expiry, maybe 2030 or 2031, but it's the same problem over and over again. The solution here, the real solution, is that the client needs to be updated. Smart TV manufacturers might release updates for a couple of years, but we're talking a decade or more if you want to resolve this particular problem. I've quite comfortably had a TV for 10 years and I'm sure as hell not contributing a heap of e-waste just to update the Root CAs installed on my television!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-affects-all-devices&quot;&gt;This affects all devices&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a device that's connected to the Internet or has the word 'Smart' somewhere in the marketing material then this Root CA expiry problem is probably a consideration, there's no way to avoid it. If the device is not updated then the Root CA store will become stale over time and eventually, the problem will surface. How soon it will be a problem, and how big of a problem it will be, will depend on when the Root CA store was last updated, but just because a device was built in 2018, it doesn't mean the software wasn't already 6+ years out of date either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the problems that the BBC have had they now require these things to be taken into consideration if Smart TV manufacturers want to get the BBC seal of approval for the iPlayer on the box. Microsoft have also taken steps to remedy this problem in Windows and your OS can now get Root CA Store updates when it needs them. Going forwards, it does look like this problem is starting to be solved for the future, but it isn't being solved for the past and the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back earlier in the thread I mentioned that the Let's Encrypt root transition was delayed, their reason was a lack of root propagation and they specifically called out Android devices. I did some digging and found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xda-developers.com/android-version-distribution-statistics-android-studio/&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; on what the Android ecosystem looks like in terms of installed OS versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-12.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This shows there is a &lt;em&gt;significant&lt;/em&gt; portion of devices that are either lagging seriously behind on updates or simply aren't being updated either by the vendor or by the user (hint: it's the vendor). If we take a look at similar &lt;a href=&quot;https://gs.statcounter.com/ios-version-market-share/mobile-tablet/worldwide/#monthly-201905-202005-bar&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; for iOS, it's a very different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-13.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't be too concerned about this problem if I was an iOS user (I am) but it looks like Android users might have some concerns in the not too distant future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;no-modern-cas-for-you&quot;&gt;No modern CAs for you&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing the intermediates you serve to chain back to an old Root CA to keep devices alive is one thing, and even switching CA to choose a CA with the longest lived 'legacy' root is another, but this also means you can't use a modern CA if you want to. Let me quote something that Neil said to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we literally can't use a CA like LE [Let's Encrypt] with TVs because it's in very few root stores&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An enormous media and streaming platform can't use a wicked-awesome, fully automated and free CA because the devices that connect to their service aren't modern enough. Yep, that's right, your cutting edge 50&quot; 4K Smart TV isn't modern enough.  Sounds crazy, right? But that's the problem!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you operate a service, or want to build one, that will have legacy client considerations, you can't just go out and hit up the coolest, newest and free CA, you need to be careful about your choice. You need to know which platform your clients are on, which version of their trust store they're using and when they were last updated, all in the hope you can figure out which root certificates are in there and which CA to use to issue your certificates. It sounds easy, but it can be a real pain to figure out. Some vendors like Apple provide data on the contents of their current Root Store, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT210770&quot;&gt;iOS 13 here&lt;/a&gt;, and you can go back some time but it's not straightforward or easy. Cloudflare have &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cloudflare/cfssl_trust&quot;&gt;cfssl_trust&lt;/a&gt; which can get you back to ~2017 and covers various platforms but that could easily not be far enough back for your needs either. In truth, is this is a concern for you then you have a little bit of work to do to figure this out, there's no easy way. Given the prominence of legacy 'stuff' on the Internet, I think we'd better get to fixing this sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;detecting-the-issue&quot;&gt;Detecting the issue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing if you have an issue like this could be quite useful indeed and there was a surprising story about how to detect the problem. Of course you can have an advanced and intimate knowledge of all of your clients and their Root Stores, which is difficult, or you can use NEL. I wrote an introductory blog post about &lt;a href=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/introducing-the-reporting-api-nel-other-major-changes-to-report-uri/&quot;&gt;Network Error Logging&lt;/a&gt; and followed that up with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/network-error-logging-deep-dive/&quot;&gt;Network Error Logging: Deep Dive&lt;/a&gt; too. The TLDR; for this blog though is that you can have a client send you feedback when they have connectivity issues to your site, including issues caused by certificates. Here's is a very small subset of the errors a client can report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;tls.version_or_cipher_mismatch
    The TLS connection was aborted due to version or cipher mismatch
tls.bad_client_auth_cert
    The TLS connection was aborted due to invalid client certificate
tls.cert.name_invalid
    The TLS connection was aborted due to invalid name
tls.cert.date_invalid
    The TLS connection was aborted due to invalid certificate date
tls.cert.authority_invalid
    The TLS connection was aborted due to invalid issuing authority
tls.cert.invalid
    The TLS connection was aborted due to invalid certificate
tls.cert.revoked
    The TLS connection was aborted due to revoked server certificate
tls.cert.pinned_key_not_in_cert_chain
    The TLS connection was aborted due to a key pinning error
tls.protocol.error
    The TLS connection was aborted due to a TLS protocol error
tls.failed
    The TLS connection failed due to reasons not covered by previous errors&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error of interest there of course is the &lt;code&gt;tls.cert.authority_invalid&lt;/code&gt; error and when the client starts to report those, you can quickly take steps to investigate. It may seem surprising that we're talking about NEL, which is a very modern feature, and talking about legacy clients that don't have updates installed at the same time. The scenario here though turned out to be old Android devices running modern version of Chrome browser which got us to the scenario of an outdated OS and Root Store but a modern client that supported NEL reports! If you don't currently use NEL you should check out my blogs linked above and our support for NEL Reports over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://report-uri.com/products/network_error_logging&quot;&gt;Report URI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/image-18.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updates. One way or another there needs to be an update somewhere. If you're building devices or software that depend on the Internet PKI for secure comms then you're going to have to consider the impact that not updating a Root Store will have on your product or service. If you run a service with legacy clients you need to consider how your choice of CA can affect them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cynic in me tells me that TV manufacturers might not care that streaming services stop working because the solution is to buy a new TV, but planned obsolescence isn't a new idea and there's probably no hidden agenda here according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanlon%27s_razor&quot;&gt;Hanlon's Razor&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occam%27s_razor&quot;&gt;Occam's Razor&lt;/a&gt; if you prefer a more gentle message).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're bundling a library or building on an OS, you need to consider how you're going to update the Root Store in the years to come. You don't need to release a software update with new features, simply replacing the Root Store with the latest version might give a device years more useful life or prevent your service being negatively impacted when the next Root CA expiry comes around. The recent AddTrust Root CA expiry showed us that some big organisations did not see this coming and weren't prepared, but this is the first such incident of its kind, certainly not the last.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 10:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fabian2k</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Impending Doom of Expiring Root CAs and Legacy Clients</og:title>
<og:description>Regular readers will know that I'm very active in the CA / PKI space and even deliver a 2-day advanced training course on the topic. Over the last year or so I've been watching as a potentially big problem has been rolling in over the horizon and just the other day</og:description>
<og:url>https://scotthelme.co.uk/impending-doom-root-ca-expiring-legacy-clients/</og:url>
<og:image>https://scotthelme.co.uk/content/images/2020/06/storm-918589_1920-2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://scotthelme.co.uk/impending-doom-root-ca-expiring-legacy-clients/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>With only free software, a Mali G31 chip can now run GNOME</title>
<link>https://www.collabora.com/news-and-blog/blog/2020/06/05/bifrost-meets-gnome-onward-upward-zero-graphics-blobs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.collabora.com/news-and-blog/blog/2020/06/05/bifrost-meets-gnome-onward-upward-zero-graphics-blobs/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.collabora.com/news-and-blog/blog/2020/04/23/from-bifrost-to-panfrost-deep-dive-into-the-first-render/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;our last blog update for Panfrost&lt;/a&gt;, the free and open-source graphics driver for modern Mali GPUs, we announced initial support for the Bifrost architecture. We have since extended this support to all major features of OpenGL ES 2.0 and even some features of desktop OpenGL 2.1. With only free software, a Mali G31 chip can now run &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.freedesktop.org/wayland/weston&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wayland&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/swaywm/sway&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;compositors&lt;/a&gt; with zero-copy graphics, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnome.org/gnome-3/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;GNOME 3&lt;/a&gt;. We can run every scene in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/glmark2/glmark2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;glmark2-es2&lt;/a&gt;, and 3D games like &lt;a href=&quot;https://neverball.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Neverball&lt;/a&gt; can be played. In addition, we can support hardware-accelerated video players &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mpv-player/mpv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;mpv&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://kodi.tv/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Kodi&lt;/a&gt;. Screenshots above are from a Mali G31 board running Panfrost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the above is included in upstream &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Mesa&lt;/a&gt; with no out-of-tree patches required, with the upcoming Bifrost support enabled via the &lt;code&gt;PAN_MESA_DEBUG=bifrost&lt;/code&gt; environmental variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Collabora - GNOME Shell&quot; src=&quot;https://www.collabora.com/assets/images/blog/Bifrost-GNOME_Preview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Collabora - GNOME Shell&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;GNOME Shell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
  
&lt;table class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Collabora - Neverball&quot; src=&quot;https://www.collabora.com/assets/images/blog/Bifrost-NB2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Collabora - Neverball&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neverball&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New opcodes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bringing up these new applications required implementing many new floating-point arithmetic opcodes, including comparisons, selections, and additional type conversions. Further, I’ve added initial support for integer arithmetic and bitwise operations, used to implement integer types directly as well as booleans. While there are a number of arithmetic logic unit (ALU) opcodes required, this is not an obstacle on architectures with regular instruction encodings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Bifrost is not a regular architecture and has dozens of distinct instruction encodings in order to conserve space. Adding opcodes to the compiler is still routine, but requires adding quite a bit more code. Plus, the duplication can be error-prone, so as soon as I add a new opcode, I add comprehensive tests against the real hardware iterating through different combinations of operand size and modifiers to exercise all the packing special cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upshot is that the testing coverage eliminates entire classes of compiler bugs which tend to plague new drivers, allowing our open source Bifrost driver to flourish despite such a quirky architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond new ALU opcodes, I extended the texture support to enable simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa/commit/?id=87ca1c1eeae&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;texture operations from vertex shaders&lt;/a&gt;, a pattern occurring in &lt;code&gt;glmark2&lt;/code&gt;’s terrain scene. Mali GPUs use slightly different encodings for fragment and vertex texture operations, since fragment shaders can automatically compute the level-of-detail parameter based on neighboring fragments, whereas there is no notion of neighboring fragments in vertex shaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I added &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa/commit/?id=9c329567508836b5b40cfbacf29a840e1e6d4c41&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;initial control flow support (branching) support&lt;/a&gt; for if/else statements and loops. As Bifrost is a Single Instruction, Multiple Thread (SIMT) architecture in which multiple threads run the same shader in lockstep, branching is a complicated affair if threads diverge. Most of the complexity is handled in hardware, but just enough seeps through that the branching implementation ends up a hair more complicated than that of Midgard. Still, it’s enough for glmark2’s &lt;code&gt;loop&lt;/code&gt; scene, and there’s always room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A simpler IR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of couse, Bifrost progress is no obstacle to improving our Midgard support. Inspired by the lessons learned designing the Bifrost Intermediate Representation as previously blogged, I revisited our Midgard Intermediate Representation as well. The focus was two fold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simplify to enable faster, more effective optimizations in fewer lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generalize the IR to support non-32-bit operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To do so, I implemented &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa/commit/?id=aeb55180ff34c50006dc3ba49097e9834bf32171&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;generic helpers&lt;/a&gt; for inferring instruction modifiers like saturation. Consider a shader that squares a variable and saturates it to the range &lt;span class=&quot;math inline&quot;&gt;[0, 1]&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;X = clamp(X * X, 0.0, 1.0);&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In NIR, Mesa’s common intermediate representation used across drivers, this line might look like the following, using NIR’s &lt;code&gt;fsat&lt;/code&gt; opcode to clamp to &lt;span class=&quot;math inline&quot;&gt;[0, 1]&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;ssa_10 = fmul ssa_9, ssa_9
ssa_11 = fsat ssa_10&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our hardware has native support for saturating the results of floating-point instructions. There are a few approaches to take advantage of this. One is to use NIR’s builtin saturation handling, as Midgard’s compiler used to. A NIR pass can fuse the &lt;code&gt;fsat&lt;/code&gt; instruction into the multiply, producing the NIR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;ssa_10 = fmul.sat ssa_9, ssa_9&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then our backend compiler can use the &lt;code&gt;.sat&lt;/code&gt; flag directly. While this is an easy approach, it is inflexible, since the hardware might be able to use modifiers that NIR does not express. For instance, Mali GPUs have a &lt;code&gt;.clamp_positive&lt;/code&gt; operation which does &lt;span class=&quot;math inline&quot;&gt;max(&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;, 0.0)&lt;/span&gt; on the result for free. If we wrote &lt;code&gt;X = max(X * X, 0.0)&lt;/code&gt;, NIR could give us code using a dedicated &lt;code&gt;fclamp_positive&lt;/code&gt; instruction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;ssa_10 = fmul ssa_9, ssa_9
ssa_11 = fclamp_positive ssa_10&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it could not fuse the modifier in without substantial changes affecting common code. The second approach would be to compile this to two instructions in the IR, and use a second propagation pass on our backend IR to fuse it together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;10 = fmul 9, 9                        10 = fmul.pos 9, 9
11 = fclamp_positive ssa_10&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there’s a third option unifying both cases and simplifying the compiler: inferring the modifiers generically while translating NIR into our backend IR. This enables us to use architecture-specific modifiers, like &lt;code&gt;.pos&lt;/code&gt;, while still having the original NIR available for efficient handling. This approach enabled us to replace hundreds of lines of optimizations for floating-point modifiers and bitwise inverses, while optimizing new patterns that the original design could not, promising savings in code complexity and performance improvements. Since it’s generic, it allows us to optimize not just Midgard programs, but soon Bifrost modifiers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Midgard FP16&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a simpler compiler, I was able to add 16-bit support to the Midgard compiler to reduce register pressure and improve thread count (occupancy) due to the architecture’s register sharing mechanism. As previously blogged, our Bifrost compiler is built to support this from day 1, and through the lessons learned there, I was able to backport the improvements to Midgard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prepare, I added types into the IR to avoid compiler passes requiring type inference, a complex and error prone pursuit. Once type sizes were preserved cleanly, I added additional support to the Midgard compiler’s packing routines to handle some outstanding details of 16-bit instructions. Midgard is significantly simpler to pack than Bifrost; whereas 16-bit and 32-bit instructions on Bifrost involve separate instructions with dramatically differing opcodes and formats, Midgard has a one-size-fits-most approach which – despite its inherent limitations – is refreshing. Miscellaneous fixes were needed across the compiler; nevertheless, the simplified IR lived up to its design and is now able to support 16-bit operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bulk of the code required for FP16 has now landed in upstream Mesa but is disabled by default pending further testing. Nevertheless, for the adventurous among you, you can set &lt;code&gt;PAN_MESA_DEBUG=fp16&lt;/code&gt; on a recent build of master. Beware: &lt;em&gt;here be dragons&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Colour masks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping away from the compiler, an interesting improvement is the new handling of draws with colour masked out. A typical draw in OpenGL that does not use blending or colour masks might look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;glColorMask(true, true, true, true);
glDepthMask(true);
glDrawArrays(GL_TRIANGLES, 0, 15);&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since blending is disabled and all colour channels (RGBA) are written simultaneously, this draw does not need to read from the colour buffer (tilebuffer). But what if the draw does not write to &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; colour channels?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;glColorMask(false, false, false, false);
glDepthMask(true);
glDrawArrays(GL_TRIANGLES, 0, 15);&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naively, the GPU would need to read the previous colour and write it back immediately - but that’s wasteful. Instead, we can detect the case where no colour is written, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa/commit/?id=3e4e849e6a9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;elide all access to the colour buffer&lt;/a&gt;, skipping both the read &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could we skip the draw entirely? If there are no side effects, we can, but applications typically mask out colour while also unmasking the depth buffer, which is independent of the colour computation. Midgard has a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if depth/stencil updates are required, as long as the shader only computes colour with no side effects, there’s no reason to run the shader. While Bifrost does not appear to, Midgard allows the driver &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa/commit/?id=1085f74239f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;to specify a draw with no shader&lt;/a&gt;, saving not only colour buffer read/write but also shader execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Community contributions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to our work on Midgard performance, community Panfrost hacker &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.freedesktop.org/icecream95/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Icecream95&lt;/a&gt; has been improving the Midgard stack nonstop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our last blog post, they contributed a major bug fix for handling &lt;code&gt;discard&lt;/code&gt; instructions. For background, OpenGL conceptually first runs the fragment shader for each pixel on the screen and then performs depth testing. In practice, modern hardware attempts to perform depth tests &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; running the shader, known as “early-z” testing, in order to avoid needlessly executing the shader for occluded pixels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, games use &lt;code&gt;discard&lt;/code&gt;, an OpenGL directive allowing shaders to eliminate fragments, which can interfere with optimizations like early-z. The driver is responsible for detecting these situations, disabling these optimizations, and enabling standards-compliant fallback paths including “late-z” testing. After Icecream95 investigated issues with Panfrost’s handling of depth testing in the presence of &lt;code&gt;discard&lt;/code&gt; instructions, they were able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa/commit/?id=0dd24b381c52e0b20fe70041e95611aad6b0d258&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;fix rendering bugs in many games&lt;/a&gt; including SuperTuxKart, OpenMW, and RVGL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the performance front, in the past they have significantly optimized Panfrost’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa/commit/?id=7b9f1b6ef755a07abcd396b42948ae6bf0a569a6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;tiling routines&lt;/a&gt; and Mesa’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa/commit/?id=80aca96803a37a7436ff96c0cec4a2643f11ed05&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;min/max index calculation&lt;/a&gt;, and added support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa/commit/?id=31bd3b52795faa02717d5cca3179965b0d207bea&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;ASTC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.freedesktop.org/mesa/mesa/commit/?id=960fe9daea77e80b0dc72271bb6b8e10acf851be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;ETC&lt;/a&gt; compressed textures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Panfrost (Mali T760) screenshots of games improved by Icecream95’s patches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Collabora - ExtremeTuxRacer screenshot&quot; href=&quot;https://www.collabora.com/assets/images/blog/Bifrost-etr-2.png&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Collabora - ExtremeTuxRacer screenshot&quot; src=&quot;https://www.collabora.com/assets/images/blog/Bifrost-etr-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Collabora - Xonotic&quot; href=&quot;https://www.collabora.com/assets/images/blog/Bifrost-xonotic-2.png&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Collabora - Xonotic&quot; src=&quot;https://www.collabora.com/assets/images/blog/Bifrost-xonotic-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hats off to a great community contributor!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Performance counters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One final area that we’ve been working on is exposing Mali’s performance counters to userspace in Panfrost, allowing us to identify bottlenecks in the driver and other developers to identify bottlenecks in their application running on Panfrost. For about a year, we have had &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git/commit/?id=7786fd1087774c6090775932290f33ac73044f41&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;experimental support&lt;/a&gt; for passing the raw counters from kernelspace. Collaborans Antonio Caggiano and Rohan Garg, in conjunction with Icecream95 and other contributors, have been working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.freedesktop.org/Fahien/gfx-pps/-/blob/master/src/gpu/panfrost/gpu_ds.cc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;integrating these counters&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://perfetto.dev/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Perfetto&lt;/a&gt; to enable high-level analysis with an elegant, free software user&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Perfetto with Panfrost on Mali T760&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Collabora - Perfetto with Panfrost on Mali T760&quot; href=&quot;https://www.collabora.com/assets/images/blog/Bifrost-p.png&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Collabora - Perfetto with Panfrost on Mali T760&quot; src=&quot;https://www.collabora.com/assets/images/blog/Bifrost-p.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Looking ahead&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past 3 months since we began work on Bifrost, fellow Collaboran Tomeu Vizoso and I have progressed from stubbing out the new compiler and command stream in March to running real programs by May. Driven by a reverse-engineering effort in tandem with the free software community, we are confident that against proprietary blobs and downstream hacks, open-source software will prevail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to the future, we plan to improve Bifrost’s coverage of OpenGL ES 2.0 to support more 3D games, now that the basic accelerated desktop is working. We also plan to improve Bifrost compiler performance, in order to approach the proprietary stack’s performance as we did for Midgard. Most of all, we’d like to build a community around the driver, with software freedom and an open first approach as core values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It worked for Freedreno, Etnaviv, and Lima. It worked for Panfrost on Midgard. And I’m confident it will work again on Bifrost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 10:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mfilion</dc:creator>
<og:title>Bifrost meets GNOME: Onward &amp; upward to zero graphics blobs</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.collabora.com/news-and-blog/blog/2020/06/05/bifrost-meets-gnome-onward-upward-zero-graphics-blobs/</og:url>
<og:description>With only free software, a Mali G31 chip can now run Wayland compositors with zero-copy graphics, including GNOME 3.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.collabora.com/assets/images/blog/Bifrost-GNOME-device_SM.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.collabora.com/news-and-blog/blog/2020/06/05/bifrost-meets-gnome-onward-upward-zero-graphics-blobs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>