<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Stack Overflow lets Facebook track users across their sites</title>
<link>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/384864/stack-overflow-lets-facebook-track-us-across-their-sites?cb=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/384864/stack-overflow-lets-facebook-track-us-across-their-sites?cb=1</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Seeing as there's no official answer by the Network, I thought I'd pipe up and write a general answer on how users can protect themselves from this type of tracking and basically what I regard as privacy invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've done some study/research on this and there's nothing private about the internet. Google and other sites also do this. Many companies have been forced to clean up their ways to an &quot;extent&quot;. Most end users are ignorant of what is being done with their data and the risk associated with what these sites view as non-PII (personal identifiable information) and how, in fact, the data can be matched (too long to get into) to reveal specific user details (including PII) without the user being aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I manually select which cookies I'll accept on each site I visit. I have third-party cookies blocked and my browser set to remove cookies (with my selected exceptions) when I quit. I go through my cookies whenever I quit my browser and have been on new sites, or sites where I know the cookies are not removed when I quit, and I manually remove them. I can do this many times a day. I also closed all my social media accounts. Beyond this site having my real name, I'm entitled to my privacy and take it seriously. I prefer to have console errors or a page not to render properly than be tracked and harvested for money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also use an ad blocker and have for a long time. Some sites won't allow you to view pages with this active. If I'm desperate to see something I'll allow ads on that page. Websites are entitled to raise revenue, but I don't have to visit there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: Google was trying to patent the collection of user data few years back. Seriously! I use Google products, but with full awareness of what they do and regularly clear my usage histories. And as for Twitter et al, they're not better. All these sites are data mined for non-PII and put together and this data is utilised and sold. Sometimes information ends up on the Dark Web for sale. It's one of those things. Live your life so there's nothing you do that you will not be concerned about becoming public. Or do not use the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun Fact Two: I live in Australia and not only is our internet appalling, but our government shows a flagrant disrespect for basic human rights, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/science/2018-10-02/proposed-surveillance-laws-draw-international-criticism/10300170&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;right to privacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 17:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Thorondor</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/384864/stack-overflow-lets-facebook-track-us-across-their-sites?cb=1</og:url>
<og:image>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/content/Sites/stackoverflowmeta/img/apple-touch-icon@2.png?v=6de7587d1583</og:image>
<og:title>Stack Overflow lets Facebook track us across their sites</og:title>
<og:description>By now, everyone who is semi-literate regarding technology should be aware of the scandals around Facebook's ethics and data privacy. Stack Overflow directly links to profile pictures from Facebook,</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/384864/stack-overflow-lets-facebook-track-us-across-their-sites?cb=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: What overlooked class of tools should a self-taught programmer look into</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19900955</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19900955</guid>
<description>15 years ago I learned Python by studying some O'Reilly books and I have been a hobbyist programmer ever since.
&lt;p&gt;The books went into detail and since reading them I've felt confident writing scripts I needed to scratch an itch. Over time, I grew comfortable believing I had a strong grasp of the practical details and anything I hadn't seen was likely either minor quibble, domain specific, or impractically theoretic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was until last year when I started working on a trading bot. I felt there should be two distinct parts to the bot, one script getting data then passing that data along to the other script for action. This seemed correct as later I might want multiple scripts serving both roles and passing data all around. Realizing the scripts would need to communicate over a network with minimal latency, I considered named pipes, Unix domain sockets, even writing files to /dev/shm but none of these solutions really fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Googling, I encountered something I hadn't heard of called a message queue. More specifically, the ZMQ messaging library. Seeing some examples I realized this was important. The step of then plowing through the docs was nothing short of revelatory. Every next chapter introduced another brilliant pattern. While grokking Pub/Sub, Req/Res, Push/Pull and the rest I couldn't help breaking away, staring in space, struck by how this new thing I had just read could have deftly solved some fiendish memorable problem I'd previously struggled against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I pondered the meaning of only now stumbling on something so powerful, so fundamental, so hidden in plain sight, as messaging middleware? What other great tools remain invisible to me for lack of even knowing what to look for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My question: In the spirit of generally yet ridiculously useful things like messaging middleware, what non-obvious tools and classes of tools would you suggest a hobbyist investigate that they otherwise may never encounter?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 16:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nathanasmith</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19900955</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>U.S. Farmers Are Being Bled by the Tractor Monopoly</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-23/u-s-farmers-need-a-better-way-to-fix-their-tractors</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-23/u-s-farmers-need-a-better-way-to-fix-their-tractors</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-23/u-s-farmers-need-a-better-way-to-fix-their-tractors&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-23/u-s-farmers-need-a-better-way-to-fix-their-tractors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19900022&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19900022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 382&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 275&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 15:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jelliclesfarm</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=6b67c080-75db-11e9-9a94-393b1edfa559&amp;url=L29waW5pb24vYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wNC0yMy91LXMtZmFybWVycy1uZWVkLWEtYmV0dGVyLXdheS10by1maXgtdGhlaXItdHJhY3RvcnM=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Audit suggests Google favors a small number of major news outlets</title>
<link>https://www.cjr.org/tow_center/google-news-algorithm.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cjr.org/tow_center/google-news-algorithm.php</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;caption-top hidden-print&quot;&gt;Photo | Adobe Stock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the last week of April,&lt;/strong&gt; nearly 23 percent of all &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parse.ly/resources/data-studies/referrer-dashboard/&quot;&gt;traffic to news sites tracked by web analytics firm Parse.ly&lt;/a&gt; came from search engines. Google alone accounts for nearly half of external referral traffic—traffic, that is, that comes from platforms, apps, and other outside sources— to news sites. Together with the fact that Facebook referral traffic is &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2018/06/facebooks-retreat-from-the-news-has-painful-for-publishers-including-slate.html&quot;&gt;on the wane&lt;/a&gt;, this means that Google’s search algorithm is now perhaps the most powerful mediator of online attention to news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for all the influence Google has in directing attention, we know painfully little about how its algorithm selects and curates news. Which sites does it direct traffic toward? And how does Google’s news curation impact the diversity of information found?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICYMI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/watchdog/lottery-winners-foia-reporting.php&quot;&gt;A reporter asked for 20 years of lottery winner data. After analyzing the records, he noticed something unusual.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out, the Computational Journalism Lab at Northwestern, including Daniel Trielli and I, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3300683&quot;&gt;undertook an audit study&lt;/a&gt; of the “Top Stories” box on Google search. Top Stories often shows up in the prime real-estate at the top of search results, presenting a carousel of news articles relevant to the query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-79459&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;830&quot; height=&quot;465&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image3.jpg 830w, https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image3-800x448.jpg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 830px) 100vw, 830px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To audit Top Stories, we scraped Google results for more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1LfYqz2xcWOno8Ve991amZj2uFLhNqg31UaSt_Drasgk/edit#gid=0&quot;&gt;200 queries&lt;/a&gt; related to news events in November, 2017. We selected the queries to test by looking at Google Trends every day and manually choosing terms related to hard news events. These included names of people in the news such as “colin kaepernick,” breaking news events such as “earthquake,” and issue-specific queries such as “tax reform” or “healthcare gov.” We set up our scraper to minimize the potential for result personalization (the process by which Google tailors its search results to an account or IP address based on past use), and ran each query once per minute for a full 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup&quot; class=&quot;hidden-print&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;form-title-embed&quot;&gt;Sign up for &lt;span class=&quot;cjr-bold&quot;&gt;CJR&lt;/span&gt;'s &lt;nobr&gt;daily email&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, we collected 6,302 unique links to news articles shown in the Top Stories box. For each of those links we count an article &lt;em&gt;impression&lt;/em&gt; each time one of those links appears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data shows that just 20 news sources account for more than half of article impressions. The top 20 percent of sources (136 of 678) accounted for 86 percent of article impressions. And the top three accounted for 23 percent: CNN, &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;. These statistics underscore the degree of concentration of attention to a relatively narrow slice of news sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-79458&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;614&quot; height=&quot;673&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image2.jpg 614w, https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image2-547x600.jpg 547w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 614px) 100vw, 614px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the concentration of sources also varies depending on the query. On average there were 19 sources per query, but 30 percent of queries had 10 or fewer sources. And sometimes, even if there were more sources, most of the impressions could go to just a handful. For instance, the query “rex tillerson” had 38 sources, but just two of those sources—the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; and CNN—were responsible for 75 percent of the article impressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior research has shown that search engines can affect users’ attitudes, shape opinions, alter perceptions and reinforce stereotypes, as well as affect &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickdiakopoulos.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/i-vote-for-open-access.pdf&quot;&gt;how voters come to be informed during elections&lt;/a&gt;. As such, media diversity is an important aspect to the way that Google—or any news aggregator—curates sources and perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get at this issue in our audit, we looked at the diversity of sources surfaced in Google Top Stories in terms of their ideological lean. More specifically, we used ratings data &lt;a href=&quot;https://science.sciencemag.org/content/348/6239/1130&quot;&gt;published in an earlier study&lt;/a&gt; which identifies the ideological alignment of the top 500 most-shared news sites on Facebook. The ratings don’t measure the slant of the media outlet per se, but rather reflect the self-reported political affiliation of Facebook users sharing content from those sources. The criteria were published in the peer-reviewed journal &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; in June, 2015 by Eytan Bakshy, Solomon Messing, and Lada Adamic from Facebook’s Core Data Science team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-2015&quot;&gt;Organizations that can generate fresh copy may be more apt to have that material selected by the curation algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data shows that 62.4 percent of article impressions were from sources rated by that research as left-leaning, whereas 11.3 percent were from sources rated as right-leaning. 26.3 percent of impressions were from news sources that didn’t have ratings. But even if that last set of unknown impressions happened to be right-leaning, the trend would still be clear: A higher proportion of left-leaning sources appear in Top Stories. (Again, this means news sources shared on Facebook more often by people with a left-leaning political affiliation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there simply more news produced on the left? It appears so. We confirmed this by searching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gdeltproject.org/&quot;&gt;GDELT&lt;/a&gt; database of news articles for the same queries we used to audit Google. In GDELT there were 2.2 times as many articles from left-leaning sources as right-leaning sources. But in Google Top Stories that ratio was 3.2, indicating that the curation algorithm was slightly magnifying the left-leaning skew in comparison to the GDELT baseline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of Google’s news curation is the timeliness of articles selected. Just how quickly does Google churn through news content? Since the Top Stories box provides the approximate age of each article (e.g. “2 hours ago”), we were able to tabulate the recency of articles. What we found is that 83.5 percent of articles were less than 24 hours old and 13.1 percent were less than an hour old. What this means is that organizations that can generate fresh copy may be more apt to have that material selected by the curation algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-79457&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;986&quot; height=&quot;476&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image1.jpg 986w, https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image1-800x386.jpg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 986px) 100vw, 986px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last part of our analysis, we looked at how much traffic an appearance in Top Stories actually generates. To do this, we combined our scraped data with referral data provided by Chartbeat. Across queries, there is a lot of variation in the number of people searching who could therefore be referred. As an example, in our data, “Matt Lauer” generated 3,961 referrals for each article impression we observed, far more than the average. But a majority of search terms (58 percent) averaged less than 100 referrals per impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICYMI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/first_person/tinazzi-motorcycle-mont-blanc-tunnel-fire-rescue.php&quot;&gt;I wrote a story that became a legend. Then I discovered it wasn’t true.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to account for the variability between terms, we built a statistical model that predicts an article’s referrals from Google based on how many impressions it has in the Top Stories Box or in organic search results. The model predicts that an article receiving 60 impressions in the middle position of Top Stories over the course of an hour (we measure one impression each minute) would lead to a 15.5 percent lift in referrals. That’s a boost of almost 1/6 more referrals for an article. And that’s if it’s visible for just an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impressions generated organically by Google’s search algorithm, rather than in the Top Stories box, accounted for slightly fewer referrals. Sixty organic impressions in an hour would boost referrals by 9.4 percent. Keep in mind, though, that an article could be visible in Top Stories or in organic results for many different queries. Our model offers a lower bound on what the actual boost may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the proportion of impressions in our data, and using our predictive model, a very rough estimate would be that CNN received a 24 percent increase in referral traffic from Google from its article’s placements in Top Stories. NPR, on the other hand, perhaps got an increase of about 3.7 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as our results help better describe Google’s curation of news, what our study decidedly cannot say is &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; some sources dominate on Google. Perhaps some outlets have cracked the SEO code for Top Stories. Or there may be a number of other factors taken into account by Google’s algorithm that end up prioritizing certain outlets over others. We just don’t know unless Google is more transparent with the editorial design and goals of news curation in the Top Stories box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we do know is that Google’s algorithmic curation of news in search converts to real and substantial amounts of user attention and traffic. News source concentration on Google implies an unequal capture of attention and its benefits, including any advertising or potential subscription revenue that might result. If they are serious about supporting digital-first newsrooms, algorithmic news curators, including Google and others, might be more explicit in articulating the inherent design tradeoffs between the relevance desirable for individuals, the diversity desirable for society or democracy, and the fair competition desirable for news organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICYMI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/sandra-bland-video.php&quot;&gt;Reporter says TV boss passed on Sandra Bland video, “didn’t think it was newsworthy”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;post-survey-box&quot; class=&quot;hidden-print&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Has America ever needed a media watchdog more than now? Help us by &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssl.palmcoastd.com/18801/apps/MEMBER1?ikey=5**M02&quot; onclick=&quot;ga('send', 'event', 'MemberSignUp', 'ArticleBoxLink', '');&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;joining CJR today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;small class=&quot;bio-overline&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicholas Diakopoulos is an assistant professor at Northwestern University School of Communication, author of the forthcoming book &quot;Automating the News: How Algorithms are Rewriting the Media&quot; on automation and algorithms in news media, and regular contributor to CJR on these topics.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hhs</dc:creator>
<og:title>Audit suggests Google favors a small number of major outlets</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cjr.org/tow_center/google-news-algorithm.php</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/AdobeStock_139324113-800x419.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>&lt;p&gt;In the last week of April, nearly 23 percent of all traffic to news sites tracked by web analytics firm Parse.ly came from search engines. Google alone accounts for nearly half of external referral traffic—traffic, that is, that comes from platforms, apps, and other outside sources— to news sites. Together with the fact that Facebook […]&lt;/p&gt;</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cjr.org/tow_center/google-news-algorithm.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Supreme Court rules antitrust lawsuit against Apple can proceed</title>
<link>https://www.wired.com/story/supreme-court-apple-decision-antitrust/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.com/story/supreme-court-apple-decision-antitrust/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;On Monday, the&lt;/span&gt; Supreme Court of the United States voted to allow a years-long antitrust case against &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/tag/apple/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; to move forward, despite Apple's objections. The case, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/pepper-v-apple-supreme-court-app-store-antitrust/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Inc. v. Pepper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, concerns a group of iPhone users who accuse Apple of driving up the price of apps by charging third-party app developers a 30 percent commission. Apple argued that App Store customers technically buy apps from third-party developers and have no direct purchasing relationship with Apple, and therefore no standing to seek damages from the company. But in a 5–4 decision, written by conservative Justice Brett Kavanaugh, the court voted against Apple, allowing the case to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The sole question presented at this early stage of the case is whether these consumers are proper plaintiffs for this kind of antitrust suit—in particular, our precedents ask whether the consumers were 'direct purchasers' from Apple,&quot; the decision reads. &quot;It is undisputed that the iPhone owners bought the apps directly from Apple.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The lawsuit, which was first filed in 2011 by lead plaintiff Robert Pepper and three other iPhone users, had been struck down in a district court, only to be revived in the Ninth Circuit, which found that the plaintiffs did, in fact, have standing to sue. Now the case will head back to the district court, where the question of whether Apple violated antitrust law will be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The decision was hailed by consumer advocates like the Center for Democracy &amp;amp; Technology. &quot;Today, more and more of consumers’ purchases go through platforms, where sellers and buyers meet virtually via technology, instead of in brick-and-mortar stores,&quot; Avery Gardiner, CDT’s senior fellow for competition, data and power, said in a statement. &quot;These technologies are evolving fast, and today’s decision shows that antitrust law is—as it should be—flexible enough to address allegations that companies may misuse their market strength in novel ways.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The Supreme Court's decision to allow the case to proceed at all could also have an impact on other companies, like Amazon, that prefer to frame themselves as neutral marketplaces, not direct sellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&quot;I would anticipate that plaintiffs lawyers will be looking at this closely and looking at tech companies and internet platforms and thinking about who they might be able to sue now that this uncertainty is gone,&quot; says Valarie Williams, a partner at the Atlanta-based law firm Alston &amp;amp; Bird, who specializes in antitrust law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;inset-left-component paywall&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 name=&quot;inset-left&quot; class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/author/issie-lapowsky/?itm_campaign=AuthorCarveLeft&quot;&gt;Issie Lapowsky&lt;/a&gt; covers the intersection of tech, politics, and national affairs for WIRED.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The Supreme Court's decision hinges on another 1977 case, &lt;em&gt;Illinois Brick Co. v. Illinois&lt;/em&gt;, in which the state of Illinois sued a number of brick manufacturers, accusing them of price fixing. The manufacturers argued that because their direct customers were contractors, not the government, the government couldn't sue them, and the case should be dismissed. The Supreme Court sided with the brick manufacturers, finding that indirect purchasers cannot seek antitrust damages, a principle now known as the Illinois Brick doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Apple used this same doctrine to argue that the plaintiffs in this case also lacked standing. In oral arguments last fall, a lawyer for Apple argued that because app developers set their own prices, App Store customers are really buying from the developers, not Apple itself. In other words, Apple positioned itself as merely the retail space where app developers pay to set up shop and sell their products. But in their decision the Supreme Court justices rejected this framing, writing that Apple was arguing &quot;strenuously&quot; against a &quot;simple conclusion.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&quot;There is no intermediary in the distribution chain between Apple and the consumer,&quot; the decision reads. &quot;The iPhone owners purchase apps directly from the retailer Apple, who is the alleged antitrust violator.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Tech companies and consumer advocates have been watching this case closely, bracing themselves for a ripple effect across the industry. But Williams says the court's decision in this case largely avoids drastic reinterpretation of the law. It does not, for instance, overturn the Illinois Brick doctrine by finding that indirect purchasers of a product have standing to sue for antitrust violations.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&quot;If they had overturned &lt;em&gt;Illinois Brick&lt;/em&gt; and allowed indirect purchasers to sue for federal antitrust claims, that would be a huge change,&quot; Williams says. Instead, the court merely found that under the law as written, App Store customers do have a direct purchasing relationship with Apple. That's largely because Apple prohibits people from buying iPhone apps anywhere other than its own App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Just because the plaintiffs have proven they have the standing to sue, doesn't mean they'll be able to prove that Apple did, in fact, violate antitrust law. This is its own complex question, and one that Williams says is likely to end in a settlement. It's also a question that European regulators are grappling with, after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/spotify-apple-complaint-warren-antitrust-issue/&quot;&gt;Spotify made a complaint&lt;/a&gt; against Apple to the European Commission earlier this year. Spotify similarly argued that by charging a 30 percent commission on in-app purchases, Apple is abusing its market dominance and requiring app developers to pass those costs on to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Apple didn't respond to WIRED's request for comment regarding the Supreme Court decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;paywall&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;More Great WIRED Stories&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CWSZ</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Supreme Court Deals Blow to Apple in Antitrust Case</og:title>
<og:description>In Apple v. Pepper, the Supreme Court ruled in a 5–4 decision that Apple's App Store customers have standing to sue the company for antitrust violations.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.wired.com/photos/5cd9b00d8e3893122fe4234b/191:100/pass/TimCook-social-1055500764.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.wired.com/story/supreme-court-apple-decision-antitrust/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.com/story/supreme-court-apple-decision-antitrust/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon rolls out machines that pack orders and replace jobs</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-automation-exclusive-idUSKCN1SJ0X1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-automation-exclusive-idUSKCN1SJ0X1</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;SAN FRANCISCO (Reuters) - Amazon.com Inc is rolling out machines to automate a job held by thousands of its workers: boxing up customer orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company started adding technology to a handful of warehouses in recent years, which scans goods coming down a conveyor belt and envelops them seconds later in boxes custom-built for each item, two people who worked on the project told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon has considered installing two machines at dozens more warehouses, removing at least 24 roles at each one, these people said. These facilities typically employ more than 2,000 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would amount to more than 1,300 cuts across 55 U.S. fulfillment centers for standard-sized inventory. Amazon would expect to recover the costs in under two years, at $1 million per machine plus operational expenses, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan, previously unreported, shows how Amazon is pushing to reduce labor and boost profits as automation of the most common warehouse task – picking up an item – is still beyond its reach. The changes are not finalized because vetting technology before a major deployment can take a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is famous for its drive to automate as many parts of its business as possible, whether pricing goods or transporting items in its warehouses. But the company is in a precarious position as it considers replacing jobs that have won it subsidies and public goodwill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are piloting this new technology with the goal of increasing safety, speeding up delivery times and adding efficiency across our network,” an Amazon spokeswoman said in a statement. “We expect the efficiency savings will be re-invested in new services for customers, where new jobs will continue to be created.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dave Clark is Amazon’s senior vice president of worldwide operations)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon last month downplayed its automation efforts to press visiting its Baltimore fulfillment center, saying a fully robotic future was far off. Its employee base has grown to become one of the largest in the United States, as the company opened new warehouses and raised wages to attract staff in a tight labor market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key to its goal of a leaner workforce is attrition, one of the sources said. Rather than lay off workers, the person said, the world’s largest online retailer will one day refrain from refilling packing roles. Those have high turnover because boxing multiple orders per minute over 10 hours is taxing work. At the same time, employees that stay with the company can be trained to take up more technical roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new machines, known as the CartonWrap from Italian firm CMC Srl, pack much faster than humans. They crank out 600 to 700 boxes per hour, or four to five times the rate of a human packer, the sources said. The machines require one person to load customer orders, another to stock cardboard and glue and a technician to fix jams on occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CMC declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Amazon has announced it intends to speed up shipping across its Prime loyalty program, this latest round of automation is not focused on speed. “It’s truly about efficiency and savings,” one of the people said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20190513&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1386618778&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEF4C0H7&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: A worker assembles a box for delivery at the Amazon fulfillment center in Baltimore, Maryland, U.S., April 30, 2019. REUTERS/Clodagh Kilcoyne/File Photo&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: A worker assembles a box for delivery at the Amazon fulfillment center in Baltimore, Maryland, U.S., April 30, 2019. REUTERS/Clodagh Kilcoyne/File Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Including other machines known as the “SmartPac,” which the company rolled out recently to mail items in patented envelopes, Amazon’s technology suite will be able to automate a majority of its human packers. Five rows of workers at a facility can turn into two, supplemented by two CMC machines and one SmartPac, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company describes this as an effort to “re-purpose” workers, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could not be learned where roles might disappear first and what incentives, if any, are tied to those specific jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the hiring deals that Amazon has with governments are often generous. For the 1,500 jobs Amazon announced last year in Alabama, for instance, the state promised the company $48.7 million over 10 years, its department of commerce said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PICKING CHALLENGE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is not alone in testing CMC’s packing technology. JD.com Inc and Shutterfly Inc have used the machines as well, the companies said, as has Walmart Inc, according to a person familiar with its pilot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walmart started 3.5 years ago and has since installed the machines in several U.S. locations, the person said. The company declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interest in boxing technology sheds light on how the e-commerce behemoths are approaching one of the major problems in the logistics industry today: finding a robotic hand that can grasp diverse items without breaking them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon employs countless workers at each fulfillment center who do variations of this same task. Some stow inventory, while others pick customer orders and still others grab those orders, placing them in the right size box and taping them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many venture-backed companies and university researchers are racing to automate this work. While advances in artificial intelligence are improving machines’ accuracy, there is still no guarantee that robotic hands can prevent a marmalade jar from slipping and breaking, or switch seamlessly from picking up an eraser to grabbing a vacuum cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon has tested different vendors’ technology that it may one day use for picking, including from Soft Robotics, a Boston-area startup that drew inspiration from octopus tentacles to make grippers more versatile, one person familiar with Amazon’s experimentation said. Soft Robotics declined to comment on its work with Amazon but said it has handled a wide and ever-changing variety of products for multiple large retailers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believing that grasping technology is not ready for prime time, Amazon is automating around that problem when packing customer orders. Humans still place items on a conveyor, but machines then build boxes around them and take care of the sealing and labeling. This saves money not just by reducing labor but by reducing wasted packing materials as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These machines are not without flaws. CMC can only produce so many per year. They need a technician on site who can fix problems as they arise, a requirement Amazon would rather do without, the two sources said. The super-hot glue closing the boxes can pile up and halt a machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still other types of automation, like the robotic grocery assembly system of Ocado Group PLC, are the focus of much industry interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the boxing machines are already proving helpful to Amazon. The company has installed them in busy warehouses that are driving distance from Seattle, Frankfurt, Milan, Amsterdam, Manchester and elsewhere, the people said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_container Slideshow_small Slideshow_standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_preview-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20190513&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1386618769&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEF4C0H8&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;Slideshow_count&quot;&gt;(3 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The machines have the potential to automate far more than 24 jobs per facility, one of the sources said. The company is also setting up nearly two dozen more U.S. fulfillment centers for small and non-specialty inventory, according to logistics consultancy MWPVL International, which could be ripe for the machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a harbinger of automation to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A ‘lights out’ warehouse is ultimately the goal,” one of the people said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting By Jeffrey Dastin in San Francisco; additional reporting by Nandita Bose in Washington and Josh Horwitz in Shanghai; editing by Greg Mitchell and Edward Tobin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 12:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Vaslo</dc:creator>
<og:title>Exclusive: Amazon rolls out machines that pack orders and replace jobs</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-automation-exclusive-idUSKCN1SJ0X1</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Amazon.com Inc is rolling out machines to automate a job held by thousands of it...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20190513&amp;t=2&amp;i=1386618778&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEF4C0H7</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-automation-exclusive-idUSKCN1SJ0X1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fun with Snapchat&amp;#039;s Gender Swapping Filter</title>
<link>https://blog.evjang.com/2019/05/fun-with-snapchats-gender-swapping.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.evjang.com/2019/05/fun-with-snapchats-gender-swapping.html</guid>
<description>Snapchat's new gender-bending filter is a source of endless fun and laughs at parties. The results are very pleasing to look at. As someone who is used to working with machine learning algorithms, it's almost magical how robust this feature is.&lt;p&gt;I was so duly impressed that I signed up for Snapchat and fiddled around with it this morning to try and figure out what's going on under the hood and how I might break it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;N.B, this is not a serious exercise in reverse-engineering Snapchat's IPA file or studying how other apps engineer similar features; it's just some basic hypothesis testing into when it works and when it doesn't, plus a little narcissistic bathroom selfie fun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Observations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The center picture is a standard bathroom selfie. To the left is the &quot;male&quot; filter, and on the right the &quot;female&quot; filter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XziGZ_pxq1o/XNi4MGYUufI/AAAAAAAAQRE/jVkuTcJ22wcrphzwm7N4xi-PTIs6PMpAgCLcBGAs/s1600/triple.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;575&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;227&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XziGZ_pxq1o/XNi4MGYUufI/AAAAAAAAQRE/jVkuTcJ22wcrphzwm7N4xi-PTIs6PMpAgCLcBGAs/s640/triple.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The first thing most users probably notice is that the app works in &lt;em&gt;real time&lt;/em&gt;, works with a few different face angles, and does not require an internet connection to run. Hair behaves very naturally when wearing a beanie.&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-b2wOAc5YD9E/XNi00oUE6DI/AAAAAAAAQQw/XVzyfLMTXdcg00hJIJdMgE8hBPVTUYbMQCLcBGAs/s1600/beanie.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;569&quot; data-original-width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-b2wOAc5YD9E/XNi00oUE6DI/AAAAAAAAQQw/XVzyfLMTXdcg00hJIJdMgE8hBPVTUYbMQCLcBGAs/s320/beanie.gif&quot; width=&quot;179&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Here's a rotating profile shot. The app seems to detect whether the face is pointing in a permissible orientation, and only if that boolean is satisfied does the filter get applied.&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RemEbJJV6eM/XNi1RwVKtkI/AAAAAAAAQQ4/ef3cXfO-vNcDBGdgVkSTvZ2KjQzg11F0gCLcBGAs/s1600/turn.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;569&quot; data-original-width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RemEbJJV6eM/XNi1RwVKtkI/AAAAAAAAQQ4/ef3cXfO-vNcDBGdgVkSTvZ2KjQzg11F0gCLcBGAs/s320/turn.gif&quot; width=&quot;179&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Gender swap works in a variety of lighting conditions, though the hair does not seem to cast shadows.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-N22SW9ChWYw/XNi7Fb6FgKI/AAAAAAAAQRw/CAbgr1fZrYA3PUFGc43RhfVmS8GWFUmsgCLcBGAs/s1600/girls.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;793&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;197&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-N22SW9ChWYw/XNi7Fb6FgKI/AAAAAAAAQRw/CAbgr1fZrYA3PUFGc43RhfVmS8GWFUmsgCLcBGAs/s400/girls.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Damn! I look cute.&lt;p&gt;Here was an example that I thought was really cool - the hair captures the directional key lighting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uF0IbnH4iAk/XNi48XbtZqI/AAAAAAAAQRc/SBMSsbtYgn80i_Z0QBB9PU8BEgX5jPCSgCEwYBhgL/s1600/IMG_2176.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;655&quot; data-original-width=&quot;697&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uF0IbnH4iAk/XNi48XbtZqI/AAAAAAAAQRc/SBMSsbtYgn80i_Z0QBB9PU8BEgX5jPCSgCEwYBhgL/s320/IMG_2176.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Occlusion Tests&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Ok, it works pretty well. Can we get it to fail? The app detects when the face is in the wrong pose, but what if there are things occluding the face? Do those occluding objects get &quot;transformed&quot; too?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The answer is yes. Below is a test where I slide an object across my face. The app works when half the face is occluded, but it seems like if too much of the face is blocked, the &quot;should I face swap&quot; bit is set to False.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-fqXw1i3oJvY/XNi82gtYXBI/AAAAAAAAQSM/oiUvR72GEMIo_ZCRD2SZokaZfH89fxiygCEwYBhgL/s1600/occlusion.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;569&quot; data-original-width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-fqXw1i3oJvY/XNi82gtYXBI/AAAAAAAAQSM/oiUvR72GEMIo_ZCRD2SZokaZfH89fxiygCEwYBhgL/s320/occlusion.gif&quot; width=&quot;179&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's vertical occlusion, where the bit seems to depend on &quot;what percentage of the face real estate is occluded&quot; rather than what important semantic features (e.g. eyes, lips) are occluded. Right before the app decides that the &quot;should I face swap&quot; should switch to &quot;False&quot;, you can see the blurring of the white bottle. Also, my hair turns blonde as I center the bottle in view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Very interesting. This suggests to me that there &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; some machine learning going on here, and it's picking up on some statistical artifact of the data it was trained on. Do blondes tend to make more makeup tutorials or something?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4XGxONqU0s4/XNi84ARQ_8I/AAAAAAAAQSI/2U6UCHk8Nlc20Pb7PNvmtdCBQKOVZ2_EQCLcBGAs/s1600/blonde.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;569&quot; data-original-width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4XGxONqU0s4/XNi84ARQ_8I/AAAAAAAAQSI/2U6UCHk8Nlc20Pb7PNvmtdCBQKOVZ2_EQCLcBGAs/s320/blonde.gif&quot; width=&quot;179&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
I partially covered my face in a black charcoal masque, and things seemed pretty stable. The female filter does lighten the masque a bit. It's pretty easy to tell from this GIF that the &quot;face swap&quot; feature is confined to a rectangular region that tracks the head (note the sharp cutoff of the hair as it gets to my shoulders).&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-UYL9-S0VHRA/XNi8H1ufxdI/AAAAAAAAQR4/pVy7TUH8doQJOCROlZInHySH4DBEQc1aQCLcBGAs/s1600/partial_mask.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;569&quot; data-original-width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-UYL9-S0VHRA/XNi8H1ufxdI/AAAAAAAAQR4/pVy7TUH8doQJOCROlZInHySH4DBEQc1aQCLcBGAs/s320/partial_mask.gif&quot; width=&quot;179&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;The filter stops working once I cover the rest of my face in the masque. Interestingly enough, the ovoid regions of my uncovered skin seem to be detected as faces, and the app proceeds to perform the style transform on that region. You can see the head and face templates flickering in and out like some &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tomie&quot;&gt;kind of Junji Ito horror story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-9r5cnDQJJvI/XNi_DXNnBsI/AAAAAAAAQSY/v1gavHFwdVo3AbKVWgN9kOGTp5BD_D5igCLcBGAs/s1600/tomie.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;569&quot; data-original-width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-9r5cnDQJJvI/XNi_DXNnBsI/AAAAAAAAQSY/v1gavHFwdVo3AbKVWgN9kOGTp5BD_D5igCLcBGAs/s320/tomie.gif&quot; width=&quot;179&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Peeling off the masque is surprisingly stable.&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-YL41B6xofFE/XNi_zMLCLwI/AAAAAAAAQS8/lXMDZx6rxBUl-dj6nKTRFbsDsXB1zfnWQCLcBGAs/s1600/tear.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;569&quot; data-original-width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-YL41B6xofFE/XNi_zMLCLwI/AAAAAAAAQS8/lXMDZx6rxBUl-dj6nKTRFbsDsXB1zfnWQCLcBGAs/s320/tear.gif&quot; width=&quot;179&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hair Layer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I was most impressed by the realism of the hair, so I wanted to figure out whether there were any hair mesh models used for dynamic lighting, or whether it was all machine-learning based.&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vlmgv29rjug/XNjAfiHBYEI/AAAAAAAAQUw/YDiw3SN1Rio6d7uSzuM4eFI6yY_mZOqkwCLcBGAs/s1600/hair-occlude.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;569&quot; data-original-width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vlmgv29rjug/XNjAfiHBYEI/AAAAAAAAQUw/YDiw3SN1Rio6d7uSzuM4eFI6yY_mZOqkwCLcBGAs/s320/hair-occlude.gif&quot; width=&quot;179&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;The hair seems to be rendered as the topmost layer (like a Photoshop layer), but unlike your basic puppy ear/tongue filter, this hair layer has an alpha channel that is partially transparent. If you look closely there is also a clear segmentation mask for the hair that allows the face to show through. Snapchat is probably doing head tracking to figure out where the head is, computing the 2D alpha mask for the hair.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it work? A guess&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; At first glance, my mind jumped to some sort of &lt;a href=&quot;https://junyanz.github.io/CycleGAN/&quot;&gt;CycleGAN&lt;/a&gt; architecture that maps the distribution of male faces to female faces, and vice versa. The dataset would be the billions of selfies Snap has, er, not deleted in the last 8 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This does raise a lot of questions though:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are they training truly unpaired image translation? That would be incredibly impressive, given that CycleGAN is bonkers and shouldn't even work in the first place. I would bet they have an unpaired alignment objective that is regularized by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://areeweb.polito.it/ricerca/cgvg/siblingsDB.html&quot;&gt;limited dataset&lt;/a&gt; of ground-truth pairs, such as pairs of images of male/female siblings, or even a hand-designed gender transform that acts as data augmentation (e.g. making the jawline rounder can be done without machine learning). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hair and face transforms seem to be synthesized independently, given that they occupy different layers (or perhaps synthesized together and separated into different layers right before rendering). This is also the first instance I've seen of GANs being used to render the alpha channel. I am a bit dubious of whether the hair is even generated by a GAN at all. One one hand, there is clearly some smooth function that switches out highlights and hair colors as a function of the positioning of an occluding object, suggesting that colors are probably learned partially from data. On the other hand, the hair is so stable that I have a hard time believing it is synthesized completely with a GAN generator. I have seen a few examples of other East Asian male face swaps with similar hairdos, suggesting that maybe there is a large-ish template library of haridos (that is refined with some ML model).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do Snap's ML engineers know whether a CycleGAN has converged for such an enormous dataset?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do they get these neural nets to run with such limited compute budgets? What sorts of image resolutions are they generating on the fly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If it indeed is a CycleGAN, then applying the &lt;em&gt;male&lt;/em&gt; filter to a &lt;em&gt;female-filtered&lt;/em&gt; image of me should recover the original image, right? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-2iPXg9ogkh4/XNjDHF70pxI/AAAAAAAAQVE/LFwMu5XPX6wJk3_ZP7umBYLe472JhTAkQCLcBGAs/s1600/zoom_f2m.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;569&quot; data-original-width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-2iPXg9ogkh4/XNjDHF70pxI/AAAAAAAAQVE/LFwMu5XPX6wJk3_ZP7umBYLe472JhTAkQCLcBGAs/s320/zoom_f2m.gif&quot; width=&quot;179&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The image is mostly scale invariant, but as we zoom in pretty close, the face does resemble mine more. I would guess that there is a preprocessing step that crops and resizes the canonical face image prior to feeding it to a neural net.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are also probably other subroutines in the filter like jaw resizing that don't use a CycleGAN, but whose addition would cause the M2F and F2M filters to no longer be exact inverses of each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications of Technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I have a friend who does drag. It's a lot of work! I'm excited for technology like this, because it will make it easier for makeup artists, cosplayers, and drag artists to experiment with new ideas and identities cheaply and quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technology such as face and voice changing enables a wider gap between public Internet personas and the real people managing those characters. This isn't necessarily a bad thing: if you are born a man but are passionate about being a cute anime girl on the internet, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DIFbgtiQnZY&quot;&gt;who are we to judge&lt;/a&gt;? Will gender fluidity &amp;amp; drag culture will become more normalized in society as our daily social media normalize gender-bending?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The future is quite exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 12:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>homarp</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.evjang.com/2019/05/fun-with-snapchats-gender-swapping.html</og:url>
<og:title>Fun with Snapchat's Gender Swapping Filter</og:title>
<og:description>Snapchat's new gender-bending filter is a source of endless fun and laughs at parties. The results are very pleasing to look at. As someone ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XziGZ_pxq1o/XNi4MGYUufI/AAAAAAAAQRE/jVkuTcJ22wcrphzwm7N4xi-PTIs6PMpAgCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/triple.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.evjang.com/2019/05/fun-with-snapchats-gender-swapping.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sued for copyright infringement for putting legal materials online</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/13/us/politics/georgia-official-code-copyright.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/13/us/politics/georgia-official-code-copyright.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;WASHINGTON — Carl Malamud believes in open access to government records, and he has spent more than a decade putting them online. You might think states would welcome the help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But when Mr. Malamud’s group posted the Official Code of Georgia Annotated, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://law.resource.org/pub/us/code/ga/pro_v_georgia/gov.uscourts.gand.218354.1.0.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the state sued for copyright infringement&lt;/a&gt;. Providing public access to the state’s laws and related legal materials, Georgia’s lawyers said, was part of a “strategy of terrorism.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A federal appeals court &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://media.ca11.uscourts.gov/opinions/pub/files/201711589.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ruled against the state&lt;/a&gt;, which has &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/18/18-1150/90326/20190301141255519_Georgia%20Certiorari%20Petition%20-%20to%20Printer.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;asked the Supreme Court to step in&lt;/a&gt;. On Friday, in an unusual move, Mr. Malamud’s group, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://public.resource.org/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Public.Resource.Org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/18/18-1150/99349/20190510172703141_GA%20Code%20BIO%20Final.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;also urged the court to hear the dispute&lt;/a&gt;, saying that the question of who owns the law is an urgent one, as about 20 other states have claimed that parts of similar annotated codes are copyrighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The issue, the group said, is whether citizens can have access to “the raw materials of our democracy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The case, Georgia v. Public.Resource.Org, No. 18-1150, concerns the 54 volumes of the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://store.lexisnexis.com/products/official-code-of-georgia-annotated-skuSKU6647/details&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Official Code of Georgia Annotated&lt;/a&gt;, which contain state statutes and related materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The state, through a legal publisher, makes the statutes themselves available online, and it has said it does not object to Mr. Malamud doing the same thing. But people who want to see other materials in the books, the state says, must pay the publisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This is part of a disturbing trend, according to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://osf.io/preprints/lawarxiv/xnbcp/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a new law review article&lt;/a&gt;, “Who Owns the Law? Why We Must Restore Public Ownership of Legal Publishing,” by &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://law.mercer.edu/faculty/directory/leslie-street.cfm&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Leslie Street&lt;/a&gt;, a law professor and librarian at Mercer University in Macon, Ga., and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://library.duke.edu/about/directory/staff/7717&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Hansen&lt;/a&gt;, a librarian at Duke. It will be published in &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://digitalcommons.law.uga.edu/jipl/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Journal of Intellectual Property Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;States have struck deals with legal publishers, the article said, that have effectively privatized the law. “Publishers now use powerful legal tools to control who has access to the text of the law, how much they must pay and under what terms,” the article said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Malamud said those arrangements have complicated his efforts. “When I started Public Resource,” he said, “I thought our mission would be a focus on making the laws easier to use and read, but because of a buzz saw of opposition we have spent much of our time fighting back takedown notices and lawsuits.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;There is no question that judicial opinions cannot be copyrighted. The last time the Supreme Court &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/supremecourt/text/128/244&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;addressed the matter&lt;/a&gt;, in 1888, it ruled that “the whole work done by the judges constitutes the authentic exposition and interpretation of the law, which, binding every citizen, is free for publication to all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/copyright/cases/293_F3d_791.htm&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lower courts&lt;/a&gt; have said the same thing about statutes. But the status of other sorts of legal materials has not been definitively resolved. In the Georgia case, the question is whether annotations commissioned and approved by the state may be copyrighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The annotations include descriptions of judicial decisions interpreting the statutes. Only a very bad lawyer would fail to consult them in determining the meaning of a statute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For instance, Georgia has a law on the books &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://codes.findlaw.com/ga/title-16-crimes-and-offenses/ga-code-sect-16-6-2.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;making sodomy a crime&lt;/a&gt;. An annotation tells the reader that &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://caselaw.findlaw.com/ga-supreme-court/1443153.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the law has been held unconstitutional&lt;/a&gt; “insofar as it criminalizes the performance of private, unforced, noncommercial acts of sexual intimacy between persons legally able to consent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Professor Street said she tells her law students to be sure to consult the annotations in Georgia’s official code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“When you go to a statute, you see the language of the statute, but that doesn’t necessarily tell you the meaning,” she said. “You go to the annotations, which leads you to the court decisions, where the judges actually tell you what the words mean.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In ruling for Mr. Malamud, the appeals court made a similar point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The annotations clearly have authoritative weight in explicating and establishing the meaning and effect of Georgia’s laws,” &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ca11.uscourts.gov/judges/hon-stanley-marcus&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Judge Stanley Marcus&lt;/a&gt; wrote for a unanimous three-judge panel of the court, the United States Court of Appeals for the 11th Circuit, in Atlanta. “Georgia’s courts have cited to the annotations as authoritative sources on statutory meaning and legislative intent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Still, the annotations are not themselves law, Judge Marcus wrote, making the case a hard one. But he concluded that the annotations were “sufficiently lawlike” that they could not be copyrighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The annotations were prepared by lawyers working for LexisNexis as part of a financial arrangement with the state. Georgia holds the copyright to the annotations, but the company has the right to sell them while paying the state a royalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The state says this is a sensible cost-saving measure, “minimizing burdens on taxpayers” by sparing them from paying for the preparation of annotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Professor Street said there was no good reason for the state to outsource the task. “States are privatizing the functions of government,” she said. “But the incentives are different for a private company when it comes to publishing the law than it is for a state government.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;I asked Mr. Malamud why he had urged the Supreme Court to hear his case even though he had won in the appeals court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Repeating the laws of our country should not be considered a crime,” he said. “I would like the Supreme Court to tell us which laws we are allowed to speak.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 11:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/13/us/politics/georgia-official-code-copyright.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Accused of ‘Terrorism’ for Putting Legal Materials Online</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/12/us/13DC-BAR/13DC-BAR-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>After Carl Malamud posted Georgia’s annotated laws, the state sued for copyright infringement. Both sides have asked the Supreme Court to step in.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/13/us/politics/georgia-official-code-copyright.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sweden reopens Assange rape investigation, to seek extradition</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-wikileaks-assange-sweden-prosecutor/sweden-reopens-assange-rape-investigation-to-seek-extradition-idUSKCN1SJ0UZ</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-wikileaks-assange-sweden-prosecutor/sweden-reopens-assange-rape-investigation-to-seek-extradition-idUSKCN1SJ0UZ</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;STOCKHOLM (Reuters) - Sweden reopened an investigation into a rape allegation against WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange on Monday and will seek to extradite him from Britain, a potential setback to efforts by the United States to put him on trial over a huge release of secret documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deputy Chief Prosecutor Eva-Marie Persson told a news conference in Stockholm she would continue a preliminary investigation that was dropped in 2017 without charges being brought after Assange took refuge in the Ecuadorean embassy in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assange, who denies the accusation, was arrested in Britain last month after spending seven years hiding inside the embassy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Swedish prosecutor said she would request Assange be detained in his absence on probable cause for an allegation of rape and that her office would issue a European arrest warrant - the start of the extradition process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States is also seeking to extradite him on conspiracy charges relating to the public release by Wikileaks of a cache of secret documents, including assessments of foreign leaders, wars and security matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The British courts will have to rule on the two extradition requests, with Home Secretary Sajid Javid having the final say on which one takes precedence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am well aware of the fact that an extradition process is ongoing in the UK and that he could be extradited to the US,” Persson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 47-year-old Assange is currently in a London prison serving 50 weeks behind bars for jumping bail when he fled to the Ecuadorean embassy in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A British judge has given the U.S. government a deadline of June 12 to outline its case against Assange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statute of limitation for rape in Sweden is 10 years - a deadline which would be reached in mid-August next year for that alleged incident, leaving prosecutors pressed for time should they decide to file any formal charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everything depends on how this will be handled by the British authorities and courts,” said Mark Klamberg, a professor of international law at Stockholm University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There is a possibility, or risk depending on how you see it, that this is going to take a long time,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Assange was taken to the United Sattes, this would likely rule out his facing trial in Sweden due to the statute of limitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20190513&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1386635221&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEF4C0G7&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange is seen on the balcony of the Ecuadorian Embassy in London, Britain May 19, 2017. REUTERS/Peter Nicholls/File Photo&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange is seen on the balcony of the Ecuadorian Embassy in London, Britain May 19, 2017. REUTERS/Peter Nicholls/File Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persson said she would request to interview Assange while he was in British custody, but that this would require the consent of the Australian, who fought unsuccessfully through the British courts to avoid extradition before fleeing to the embassy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lawyer representing the victim in the rape investigation urged Swedish prosecutors to move quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are not going to give up until a charge is brought and the case goes to court,” lawyer Elisabeth Massi Fritz told a news conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My client feels great gratitude and she is very hopeful of getting restitution and we both hope that justice will win.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assange’s supporters cast him as a dissident facing the wrath of a superpower over one of the largest compromises of classified information in U.S. history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CLEAR NAME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikileaks said the reopening of the Swedish investigation would give Assange a chance to clear his name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Since Julian Assange was arrested on 11 April 2019, there has been considerable political pressure on Sweden to reopen their investigation, but there has always been political pressure surrounding this case,” Kristinn Hrafnsson, WikiLeaks’ editor-in-chief, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If convicted in Sweden, Assange could face a prison sentence of up to four years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“His attitude is that he is happy to cooperate with Sweden and that he wants to be interviewed and that he wants to clear his name,” Per Samuelson, a Swedish lawyer for Assange, told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How that will happen now, I don’t know. He has his hands full with, for him, much more important issues, namely avoiding being extradited to the U.S.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Vamos, lawyer at London-based firm Peters &amp;amp; Peters and former head of extradition at Britain’s Crown Prosecution Service, told Reuters before Monday’s decision that he expected a Swedish request would take supremacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the event of a conflict between a European Arrest Warrant and a request for extradition from the US, UK authorities will decide on the order of priority,” a Swedish prosecutor’s statement said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SmallImage_small-image SmallImage_standard SmallImage_caption-truncate&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption Image_full-width&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;Swedish Vice Chief Prosecutor Eva-Marie Persson announces that the prosecutor will re-open the preliminary investigation against WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange, who is accused of rape and sexual harassment of two women in 2010, at a news conference in Stockholm, Sweden May 13, 2019. TT News Agency/Anders Wiklund via REUTERS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WikiLeaks published hundreds of thousands of secret U.S. diplomatic cables that laid bare often critical U.S. appraisals of world leaders, from Russian President Vladimir Putin to members of the Saudi royal family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also published a classified U.S. military video showing a 2007 attack by Apache helicopters in Baghdad that killed a dozen people, including two Reuters news staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Additional reporting by Simon Johnson, Johan Ahlander and Helena Soderpalm in Stockholm, and Guy Faulconbridge in London; Editing by Angus MacSwan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 10:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hownottowrite</dc:creator>
<og:title>Sweden wants to extradite Assange over rape allegation,...</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-wikileaks-assange-sweden-prosecutor-idUSKCN1SJ0UZ</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Sweden reopened an investigation into a rape allegation against WikiLeaks founde...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20190513&amp;t=2&amp;i=1386635221&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEF4C0G7</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-wikileaks-assange-sweden-prosecutor/sweden-reopens-assange-rape-investigation-to-seek-extradition-idUSKCN1SJ0UZ</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>China is blocking all language editions of Wikipedia</title>
<link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ooni.torproject.org/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/</guid>
<description>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/images/ooni-header-mascot.png&quot; width=&quot;25&quot; height=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wordmark&quot; src=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/images/wordmark.png&quot; alt=&quot;OONI&quot; height=&quot;14&quot; width=&quot;53&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;iyouport.org, Sukhbir Singh (Open Web Fellow, Mozilla Foundation), Arturo Filastò (OONI), Maria Xynou (OONI)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;2019-05-04&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking.zh/&quot;&gt;translation: 中国封锁了所有语言版本的维基百科&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China recently started blocking all language editions of Wikipedia. Previously, the blocking was limited to the Chinese language edition of Wikipedia (zh.wikipedia.org), but has now expanded to include all &lt;code&gt;*.wikipedia.org&lt;/code&gt; language editions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, we share &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.ooni.io/files/by_country/CN&quot;&gt;OONI network measurement data&lt;/a&gt; on the blocking of Wikipedia in China. We found that all wikipedia.org sub-domains are blocked in China by means of DNS injection and SNI filtering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dns-injection&quot;&gt;DNS injection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.io/install/&quot;&gt;OONI Probe&lt;/a&gt;, Wikipedia domains have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.ooni.io/files/by_country/CN&quot;&gt;tested&lt;/a&gt; from multiple local vantage points in China since 2015. Most measurements have been collected from China Telecom (AS4134).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OONI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.io/nettest/web-connectivity/&quot;&gt;Web Connectivity test&lt;/a&gt; (available in the OONI Probe apps) is designed to measure the TCP/IP, HTTP, and DNS blocking of websites. &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.ooni.io/files/by_country/CN&quot;&gt;Network measurement data&lt;/a&gt; collected through this test has shown that most Wikipedia language editions were previously accessible in China, except for the Chinese edition, which has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theepochtimes.com/china-now-blocked-from-accessing-wikipedia_1384917.html&quot;&gt;reportedly been blocked&lt;/a&gt; since 19th May 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OONI data shows that China Telecom (AS4134) has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://explorer.ooni.io/measurement/20161110T035949Z_AS4134_oAjg1SM4bjI5yI2D9yhu8Rfq830QL5avcxPg8LmhEAN1u0pvYq?input=http:%2F%2Fzh.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2Fwikipedia:%25e9%25a6%2596%25e9%25a1%25b5&quot;&gt;blocking zh.wikipedia.org since at least the 10th November 2016&lt;/a&gt; (previous OONI measurements show that zh.wikipedia.org was &lt;a href=&quot;http://api.ooni.io/files/download/2015-03-04/20150304T232111Z-CN-AS4808-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.yaml&quot;&gt;accessible in March 2015&lt;/a&gt; on that network).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following chart, based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.ooni.io/files/by_country/CN&quot;&gt;OONI data&lt;/a&gt;, illustrates that multiple language editions of Wikipedia have been blocked in China as of April 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/ooni-china-blocks-wikipedia.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;Blocking of Wikipedia domains in China, Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) data: China, &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.ooni.io/files/by_country/CN&quot;&gt;https://api.ooni.io/files/by_country/CN&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our analysis of OONI measurements, used to produce the above chart, is available &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/20190502-china-wikipedia.csv&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OONI measurements show that many of these Wikipedia domains were &lt;a href=&quot;https://explorer.ooni.io/measurement/20190218T081331Z_AS4134_2CoUgy8tf1A7DF2JZNghiXWuK7ndJRnTVHsnWTTVjkJFDb1mcd?input=https:%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2Fthe_holocaust&quot;&gt;previously accessible&lt;/a&gt;, but all measurements collected from &lt;a href=&quot;https://explorer.ooni.io/measurement/20190425T070917Z_AS4134_45hNnx6LkceBitzcVB1oAGfpHyJuKFKR7NkLU5XTCdz2JKVPhy?input=https:%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;25th April 2019 onwards&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://explorer.ooni.io/measurement/20190425T070917Z_AS4134_45hNnx6LkceBitzcVB1oAGfpHyJuKFKR7NkLU5XTCdz2JKVPhy?input=https:%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;present the same DNS anomalies&lt;/a&gt; for all Wikipedia sub-domains. The few DNS anomalies that occurred in previous months were false positives, whereas the DNS anomalies from April 2019 onwards show that Wikipedia domains are blocked by means of DNS injection. Most measurements were collected from China Telecom (AS4134).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since OONI measurements collected from China suggest blocking by means of DNS injection, we can further measure the DNS-based blocking from outside of China as well. To this end, we ran the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ooni/spec/blob/master/nettests/ts-012-dns-injection.md&quot;&gt;OONI Probe DNS injection test&lt;/a&gt; from a vantage point outside of the country, pointing towards an IP address in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This test relies on the fact that the Chinese firewall will “inject” DNS requests for restricted domains, even if the request is coming from outside the country and directed at an IP address which does not run a DNS resolver. The expectation was, therefore, that if the DNS query timed out, no blocking was happening, but if we saw a response, then that response was injected by the censor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OONI Probe DNS injection test is very fast. It allowed us to &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.ooni.io/files/download/2019-04-24/20190424T200655Z-IS-AS47172-dns_injection-20190424T200655Z_AS47172_Peuv89addXJ1NZ5nTzY7i94X0rTag3QqGLwXKQcaoDTnHu9hu7-0.2.0-probe.json&quot;&gt;scan more than 2,000 Wikipedia domain names&lt;/a&gt; in less than a minute and to determine which ones were blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By analyzing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.ooni.io/files/download/2019-04-24/20190424T200655Z-IS-AS47172-dns_injection-20190424T200655Z_AS47172_Peuv89addXJ1NZ5nTzY7i94X0rTag3QqGLwXKQcaoDTnHu9hu7-0.2.0-probe.json&quot;&gt;results&lt;/a&gt; of the OONI Probe DNS injection test, we were able to understand that the restriction appears to be targeting any subdomain/language edition of wikipedia.org (i.e. &lt;code&gt;*.wikipedia.org&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;zh.wikipedia.org&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;en.wikipedia.org&lt;/code&gt;, etc.) - including &lt;code&gt;wikipedia.org&lt;/code&gt; - but to not be affecting any other Wikimedia resources, beyond zh.wikinews.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blocking appears to be targeting wikipedia.org subdomains irrespective of whether they actually exist or not (for example, even &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.ooni.io/files/download/2019-04-24/20190424T200655Z-IS-AS47172-dns_injection-20190424T200655Z_AS47172_Peuv89addXJ1NZ5nTzY7i94X0rTag3QqGLwXKQcaoDTnHu9hu7-0.2.0-probe.json&quot;&gt;doesnotexist.wikipedia.org&lt;/a&gt; was blocked!). The IP address returned in the injected DNS response also appears to be pretty random (examples of prior work analyzing the distribution of IP addresses returned by the Great Firewall include “&lt;a href=&quot;https://censorbib.nymity.ch/pdf/Lowe2007a.pdf&quot;&gt;The Great DNS Wall of China&lt;/a&gt;” and “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/conference/foci14/foci14-anonymous.pdf&quot;&gt;Towards a Comprehensive Picture of the Great Firewall’s DNS Censorship&lt;/a&gt;”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sni-filtering&quot;&gt;SNI filtering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check whether the blocking of Wikipedia domains could be circumvented by merely encrypting DNS traffic, we attempted to enable DNS over HTTPS in Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this end, we ran:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;curl -H 'accept: application/dns-json' https://cloudflare-dns.com/dns-query?name=www.wikipedia.org&amp;amp;type=A
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were able to resolve the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;www.wikipedia.org&lt;/a&gt; domain name successfully with DNS over HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tests were also validated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Trusted_Recursive_Resolver&quot;&gt;enabling DNS over HTTPS inside of Firefox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/firefox-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, the page was still not accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/firefox-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were only able to access the bare IP address from China, indicating that SNI filtering may be in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/firefox-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further validate the theory that filtering was happening based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Server_Name_Indication&quot;&gt;SNI filtering&lt;/a&gt;, we ran the following curl tests (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/venezuela-blocking-wikipedia-and-social-media-2019/&quot;&gt;we ran similar tests in Venezuela to confirm the same hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ curl -v --connect-to ::www.kernel.org: https://www.wikipedia.org

* Rebuilt URL to: https://www.wikipedia.org/
* Connecting to hostname: www.kernel.org
*   Trying 147.75.46.191...
* TCP_NODELAY set
*   Trying 2604:1380:4080:c00::1...
* TCP_NODELAY set
* Immediate connect fail for 2604:1380:4080:c00::1: 网络不可达
* Connected to www.wikipedia.org (147.75.46.191) port 443 (#0)
* ALPN, offering h2
* ALPN, offering http/1.1
* Cipher selection: ALL:!EXPORT:!EXPORT40:!EXPORT56:!aNULL:!LOW:!RC4:@STRENGTH
* successfully set certificate verify locations:
*   CAfile: /etc/ssl/certs/ca-certificates.crt
  CApath: /etc/ssl/certs
* TLSv1.2 (OUT), TLS header, Certificate Status (22):
* TLSv1.2 (OUT), TLS handshake, Client hello (1):
* Unknown SSL protocol error in connection to www.wikipedia.org:443
* Curl_http_done: called premature == 1
* stopped the pause stream!
* Closing connection 0
curl: (35) Unknown SSL protocol error in connection to www.wikipedia.org:443
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above curl test is connecting to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org&quot;&gt;www.kernel.org&lt;/a&gt; (IP 147.75.46.191), but attempting to do a TLS handshake using the SNI of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;www.wikipedia.org&lt;/a&gt;. As we can see from the output above, as soon as the &lt;code&gt;TLS handshake, Client hello&lt;/code&gt; is sent, the connection is aborted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, as seen below, if we attempt to use the SNI of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org&quot;&gt;www.kernel.org&lt;/a&gt; when doing a TLS handshake with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;www.wikipedia.org&lt;/a&gt; (we use the &lt;code&gt;--resolve&lt;/code&gt; option to skip the DNS resolution), the request is successful and we are able to finish the TLS handshake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ curl -v --resolve 'www.wikipedia.org:443:91.198.174.192' --connect-to ::www.wikipedia.org: https://www.kernel.org

* Added www.wikipedia.org:443:91.198.174.192 to DNS cache
* Rebuilt URL to: https://www.kernel.org/
* Connecting to hostname: www.wikipedia.org
* Hostname www.wikipedia.org was found in DNS cache
*   Trying 91.198.174.192...
* TCP_NODELAY set
* Connected to www.kernel.org (91.198.174.192) port 443 (#0)
* ALPN, offering h2
* ALPN, offering http/1.1
* Cipher selection: ALL:!EXPORT:!EXPORT40:!EXPORT56:!aNULL:!LOW:!RC4:@STRENGTH
* successfully set certificate verify locations:
*   CAfile: /etc/ssl/certs/ca-certificates.crt
  CApath: /etc/ssl/certs
* TLSv1.2 (OUT), TLS header, Certificate Status (22):
* TLSv1.2 (OUT), TLS handshake, Client hello (1):
* TLSv1.2 (IN), TLS handshake, Server hello (2):
* TLSv1.2 (IN), TLS handshake, Certificate (11):
* TLSv1.2 (IN), TLS handshake, Server key exchange (12):
* TLSv1.2 (IN), TLS handshake, Server finished (14):
* TLSv1.2 (OUT), TLS handshake, Client key exchange (16):
* TLSv1.2 (OUT), TLS change cipher, Client hello (1):
* TLSv1.2 (OUT), TLS handshake, Finished (20):
* TLSv1.2 (IN), TLS change cipher, Client hello (1):
* TLSv1.2 (IN), TLS handshake, Finished (20):
* SSL connection using TLSv1.2 / ECDHE-ECDSA-AES256-GCM-SHA384
* ALPN, server accepted to use h2
* Server certificate:
*  subject: C=US; ST=California; L=San Francisco; O=Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.; CN=*.wikipedia.org
*  start date: Nov  8 21:21:04 2018 GMT
*  expire date: Nov 22 07:59:59 2019 GMT
*  subjectAltName does not match www.kernel.org
* SSL: no alternative certificate subject name matches target host name 'www.kernel.org'
* Curl_http_done: called premature == 1
* stopped the pause stream!
* Closing connection 0
* TLSv1.2 (OUT), TLS alert, Client hello (1):
curl: (51) SSL: no alternative certificate subject name matches target host name 'www.kernel.org'
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on these tests, we were able to conclude that China Telecom does in fact block all language editions of Wikipedia by means of both DNS injection and SNI filtering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-internet-censorship/&quot;&gt;censorship implemented in Egypt&lt;/a&gt;, perhaps this can be viewed as a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Defense_in_depth_(computing)&quot;&gt;defense in depth&lt;/a&gt;” tactic for network filtering. By implementing both DNS and SNI-based filtering, China Telecom creates multiple layers of censorship that make circumvention harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of an encrypted DNS resolver (such as DNS over HTTPS) together with &lt;a href=&quot;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-tls-esni/&quot;&gt;Encrypted SNI (ESNI)&lt;/a&gt; could potentially work as a circumvention strategy. Wikipedia.org does not currently support ESNI, but there have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://phabricator.wikimedia.org/T205378&quot;&gt;discussions&lt;/a&gt; about enabling it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 09:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JayXon</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>