<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>I bought a Switch from Nintendo, and then they threatened me with legal action</title>
<link>https://headmelted.com/i-bought-a-switch-from-nintendo-and-they-threatened-me-with-legal-action-6ea77b4f1eb9</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://headmelted.com/i-bought-a-switch-from-nintendo-and-they-threatened-me-with-legal-action-6ea77b4f1eb9</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h2 name=&quot;d9a4&quot; id=&quot;d9a4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--h3 graf--subtitle&quot;&gt;A tale of three Switches, and a reminder of the importance of good customer service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;157&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ec54&quot; id=&quot;ec54&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;What a month it has been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8a88&quot; id=&quot;8a88&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I haven’t updated in a while, and I’m sorry for that. I’ve had quite a bit going on in the run up to the holidays — but I’m getting back up to speed on things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bd1c&quot; id=&quot;bd1c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I wanted to share an experience I had recently (&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;it’s still ongoing actually&lt;/em&gt;) that came from buying a Nintendo Switch for myself and my kid in the run up to the Super Mario Odyssey release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a7b4&quot; id=&quot;a7b4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’m a lifelong Mario fan. I’m a pretty big Nintendo fan anyway, but for me every major Mario release is just a nostalgia bomb of happy memories from my childhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e497&quot; id=&quot;e497&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;By this point, I’ve played Super Mario 3D World with my 4 year old to the point that there’s virtually no collectibles left to find (some, not many). We bought the game pretty early in the Wii U’s life, although he has only really been old enough to become curious about “dad’s video games” in the past six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;024f&quot; id=&quot;024f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I have fond memories from my younger days of waiting for release day to roll around for major entries, but my son has never had that excitement of unboxing a new system and being blown away by the next new classic to come out of Kyoto. I wanted to share this with him while he’s still at an age where he’s impressed by his father’s nerdy hobbies (and before he realizes how uncool I really am!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3668&quot; id=&quot;3668&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The timing worked out quite well as it happens — my son’s school would be shutting down for half-term break just as the game was releasing and I had already arranged to take a break from work to spend that time with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;b290&quot; id=&quot;b290&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A busted up package and a scratched-up screen&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b155&quot; id=&quot;b155&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;I ordered the Switch on October 16th from Nintendo’s UK online store. I wanted to buy direct primarily to support Nintendo, so I figured it better that more of the margin ends up with them than a reseller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5968&quot; id=&quot;5968&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It didn’t take long to arrive — but when it did, I noticed some damage to the outside of the packaging. Concerned, I opened the box further to realize that the package had been more than a little disturbed — the internal contents had been removed from the bags and stuffed back in place again, and there were scratches on the screen and around the controllers that clearly hadn’t happened in transit. My assumption is that either this was a customer return that was shipped back out as new, or that the courier had intercepted the package (seems unlikely), but I contacted Nintendo to organize a return. These things happen sometimes, and at this point at least, they were gracious in offering to replace the item. I sent it back, but heard nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;03ae&quot; id=&quot;03ae&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I spent much of the next week in an odd cat-and-mouse game with Nintendo’s support line —each day I’d be told that the replacement had already been dispatched (and that I would need to make myself available to sign for it), then be told the following day it wasn’t yet dispatched after the courier failed to show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6768&quot; id=&quot;6768&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Ultimately it seems that they received the Switch back, but for one reason or another (they offered a couple of conflicting ones), hadn’t shipped out a replacement or offered a refund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4066&quot; id=&quot;4066&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In the end I had to reorganize my work hours to make calls over the subsequent days to get the order sorted out. This was pretty disappointing, both because it was now affecting my work, and due to the plans I’d made with my kid around the school break that were now going to have to be scrapped (there’s no fun to be had in explaining to a wide-eyed four year old that the new Mario game has arrived but we don’t have the console to play it on). At this time I still figured this turn of events was not wholly out of the ordinary for customer support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c567&quot; id=&quot;c567&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And then the fun started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*ySnnGUyApi1vjo4R.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1416&quot; data-height=&quot;803&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;0*ySnnGUyApi1vjo4R.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*ySnnGUyApi1vjo4R.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;9a46&quot; id=&quot;9a46&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Here’s your Switch, and here’s someone elses, too&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2428&quot; id=&quot;2428&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;We’ve been trying to get ready for Christmas pretty early this year. Having two young kids means that I can’t really take risks with the Santa list, as the must-have toys tend to sell out &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, at least around here. So I’m guilty of having a few unmarked boxes stuffed away waiting to be sorted later (small toys — Hot Wheels, PJ Masks and the like).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;781b&quot; id=&quot;781b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Eventually the replacement Switch got delivered (packaging intact this time) and I was able to get it set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;847a&quot; id=&quot;847a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s off-topic for this article, but as an aside — I’m blown away by what they’ve done with this device. It’s almost supernaturally powerful considering it’s size. I thoroughly recommend you get one if you haven’t already — maybe just get it from Amazon, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a692&quot; id=&quot;a692&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;When checking through some boxes ahead of work the next morning I noticed an identically marked package had been delivered. I wasn’t expecting any other orders from Nintendo, so I checked inside and saw that it was another Switch (I didn’t open the packaging all of the way so as not to damage the shipping box — I could see enough of the contents to tell with some measure of confidence what it was).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;ef8d&quot; id=&quot;ef8d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some will point out (and some have!) that I could have quite easily saved myself a lot of time, hassle, and lost earnings at this point by just quietly holding on to the extra Switch and saying nothing to Nintendo about it. It certainly would have saved me a lot of stress, but it was morally not something I’d ever consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;64df&quot; id=&quot;64df&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;I reached out to Nintendo to let them know what happened as soon as I’d realized. I figured at the least I’ll get a thank you for letting them know, maybe even a poster or something in the mail for my kid’s bedroom if we’re lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2b33&quot; id=&quot;2b33&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The subsequent exchange did not go the way I imagined it would at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ecaf&quot; id=&quot;ecaf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At first, it was suggested by one representative that I just keep the extra Switch, which enthusiastically I advised I’d be happy to do if they were offering that as an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ce68&quot; id=&quot;ce68&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;I was then contacted by a second representative and promptly informed that if the item was not immediately returned they would pursue legal action against me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ef9f&quot; id=&quot;ef9f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This was shocking to say the least (given the context of the dialogue until that point). On asking at what time this collection would occur (so I could plan around it) I was told that it’s impossible to say, and I would need to make myself available to hand over the item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e652&quot; id=&quot;e652&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Being available as described would mean spending an additional day away from work to wait for a courier who (based on past experiences) may or may not turn up. &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;If the courier didn’t turn up, would I be accused of theft? Would they really proceed to legal action?&lt;/em&gt; I assumed no, but I’m no legal expert, so I decided to just co-operate until this was sorted and not risk further stress over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;1fd5&quot; id=&quot;1fd5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Where things stand now&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;91eb&quot; id=&quot;91eb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;This was a relatively straight-forward transaction that had quickly snowballed into being a very costly timesink, and just about the worst experience I’ve had purchasing something online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;680c&quot; id=&quot;680c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As I work independently, I’m not paid for time not spent directly working on client projects. Between the time spent chasing Nintendo’s support line, and waiting for their couriers, this has now cost me in lost income more than the original cost of the Switch, and I’m still waiting for Nintendo’s courier to pick up the &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;third&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Switch now, lest I get taken to court for being mistakenly sent the item in the first place. I expect I’ll incur further costs and lost income until this is sorted out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;59d7&quot; id=&quot;59d7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It has been an utterly baffling turn of events to say the least. I’ve asked for a comment from Nintendo’s UK support regarding the experience but they’ve not as yet provided one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;2b98&quot; id=&quot;2b98&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;They still make some fantastic games, though&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;95a1&quot; id=&quot;95a1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;I’m still a fan of Nintendo’s products, if not their customer service. Now that I have the Switch, I’m really impressed with it — I just really think Nintendo should look at their standards around their direct sales and their policies when things go wrong. Retailers like Amazon get this so right these days, that it’s hard to imagine the process going this far off the rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b308&quot; id=&quot;b308&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It shouldn’t need to be said that threatening customers is terrible practice in any context, especially so when it’s unprovoked and un-necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;948b&quot; id=&quot;948b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;I’ll try to update this article when the matter is finally resolved (hopefully amicably).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 11:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>headmelted</dc:creator>
<og:title>I bought a Switch from Nintendo, and they threatened me with legal action</og:title>
<og:url>https://headmelted.com/i-bought-a-switch-from-nintendo-and-they-threatened-me-with-legal-action-6ea77b4f1eb9</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/0*CsuxJwes8WDwRa5L.png</og:image>
<og:description>A tale of three Switches, and a reminder of the importance of good customer service</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://headmelted.com/i-bought-a-switch-from-nintendo-and-they-threatened-me-with-legal-action-6ea77b4f1eb9?gi=53b593844c80</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OVH datacenters are down</title>
<link>https://www.ovh.com/community/status/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ovh.com/community/status/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section2 box&quot; readability=&quot;4.3846153846154&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;bgBlue bigPadding center fs30 fw300&quot; qtlid=&quot;867190&quot;&gt;OVH Travaux&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;');

                                jQuery.getJSON( &quot;/fr/cgi-bin/travaux.cgi?lang=fr&quot;, function( data ) {
                                    jQuery.each( data.travaux.lastThreadsInTravaux, function( key, val ) {
                                        div.append(
                                            '&lt;h3 class=&quot;bgSoftGrey textcolor fs16 fw400&quot;&gt;' + val.title +
                                                '&lt;span class=&quot;fs12 fw400&quot;&gt; (' + moment(val.date*1000).fromNow() + ')&lt;/span&gt;' +
                                            '&lt;/h3&gt;' +
                                            '');
                                        return key 
&lt;br/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 08:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fvv</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ovh.com/fr/support/status/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quake on an oscilloscope (2014)</title>
<link>http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/oscilloscope_quake.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/oscilloscope_quake.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Style-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;generator&quot; content=&quot;pandoc&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;Pekka Väänänen&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;date&quot; content=&quot;2014-12-28&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Quake on an oscilloscope: A technical report&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot; name=&quot;viewport&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;css/blog.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;186.84732696497&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com&quot;&gt;back to lofibucket.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/img/quakescope.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quake 1 rendered on a Hitachi V-422 oscilloscope.&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Quake 1 rendered on a Hitachi V-422 oscilloscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A summary of some problems I faced when tinkering with Quake to get it play nicely on an oscilloscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing some cool clips like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rtR63-ecUNo&quot;&gt;this mushroom thing&lt;/a&gt; and of course &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s1eNjUgaB-g&quot;&gt;Youscope&lt;/a&gt;, playing Quake on a scope seemed like a great idea. It ticks all the marks that make me happy: low-poly, realtime rendered and open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing-testing&quot;&gt;Testing, testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/seece/034e8c3c9debb0464d3a&quot;&gt;a simple XY-oscilloscope simulator&lt;/a&gt; in Processing. Youscope rendered cleanly in it after I added some phosphorus decay simulation so that longer lines are rendered dimmer. So far so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;rendering-lines&quot;&gt;Rendering lines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The XY-mode of an oscilloscope is pretty straightforward. Two voltages specify the horizontal and vertical position of the ray, so by varying these as a function of time you can draw shapes. Basically you output a set of 2D points with coordinates in range [-1, 1], view it in XY-mode on the oscilloscope and Bob’s your uncle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing a line segment is linearly interpolating between two points during some time interval. It’s important to keep the drawing speed constant between lines of different lengths because otherwise you’ll end up having lines with varying intensities. According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jmargolin.com/vgens/vgens.htm&quot;&gt;a great page by Jed Margolin&lt;/a&gt;, you don’t actually need to calculate the length of the line to keep the intensities at bay since an approximation will be enough because of the non-linear gamma curve of the monitor. I went with the correct solution though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to line draw line segments that are not connected together, you need to move the ray quickly across the screen without actually tracing a visible line. This can be done by spending more time drawing the visible lines and then scaling the monitor intensity accordingly to hide unwanted artefacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/img/simulaattori.png&quot; title=&quot;Phosphor decay also supported!&quot; alt=&quot;A simple XY-scope simulator written in Processing.&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A simple XY-scope simulator written in Processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I whipped up a toy where you could draw a single line with a mouse and it would get played back as audio from the speakers. Then I hooked up system audio output to line-in and verified it looked OK in the scope simulator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;output&quot;&gt;Output&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using audio for outputting the two voltages is natural, this is what tejeez did in Youscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quake is a game, games are realtime, so my audio generation routines better be quick too. That’s why I picked &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audio_Stream_Input/Output&quot;&gt;ASIO&lt;/a&gt; as the audio backend. First I spent a couple of nights hacking with the Steinberg ASIO SDK, but I just couldn’t get any sound out of it. Finally I resorted to using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portaudio.com/&quot;&gt;PortAudio&lt;/a&gt; which worked just fine for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Youscope recording is a 48 kHz audio file and it seems to work great on tape. The catch here is that apparently the soundcard used on the video doesn’t apply any low-pass filtering to the output, which pretty uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All sound cards I own apply a filter, so bandwidth was pretty limited. In practice this means less lines can be drawn per frame. I thought the problem could be solved with a higher sampling rate so I picked 96 kHz, the highest number my Swissonic EASY USB supports. Seems like this didn’t make any difference in the end as the picture looks almost the same at 44.1 kHz too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;portaudio-on-windows&quot;&gt;PortAudio on Windows&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stable v19 release of PortAudio didn’t compile out of the box on Windows. I had to manually remove &lt;code&gt;ksguid.lib&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;portaudio.vxcproj&lt;/code&gt; with a text editor. Installing the ASIO SDK was also necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-vectorized&quot;&gt;Getting vectorized&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two different processes: the Darkplaces Quake game and the audio synthesizer. Interprocess communication is done via a WinAPI named pipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite Quake &lt;a href=&quot;http://quake.wikia.com/wiki/Source_port&quot;&gt;source port&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://icculus.org/twilight/darkplaces/&quot;&gt;Darkplaces&lt;/a&gt; has an excellent software renderer I abused to get access to projected scene geometry. The engine was patched to save all the clip-space triangle edges sent for drawing, and then transfer these to a synthesizer process via a named pipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This geometry extraction phase doesn’t affect normal rendering, and a proper depth buffer is actually required for the last culling stage to function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pipeline on the Quake side is basically this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;for each object being drawn
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;for each triangle
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;clip the edges to screen borders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if edge is visible
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;and not already saved this frame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;save it to a list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;render the triangle normally, even though color isn’t used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if the synth process has requested more geometry, then:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;check if lines are in front of geometry via z-buffer sampling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;submit all visible lines of this frame to the synth via pipe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;culling&quot;&gt;Culling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting rid of duplicate and unseen line geometry is important, because the time budget per frame is tight and all time spent on redundant lines is totally wasted effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/img/without_and_with_culling.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hiding occluded lines with depth buffer checks is very important.&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Hiding occluded lines with depth buffer checks is very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular back face, frustum and precalculated BSP visibility culling are done first. I also limited the draw distance by discarding all triangles whose all vertices were far enough from the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To cull the duplicates a &lt;code&gt;std::unordered_set&lt;/code&gt; of the C++ standard library is used. The indices of the triangle edges are saved in pairs, packed in a single &lt;code&gt;uint64_t&lt;/code&gt;, the lower index being first. The set is cleared between each object, so the same line could still be drawn twice or more if the same vertices are stored in different meshes. Before saving a line for end-of-the-frame-submit, its indices in the mesh are checked against the set, and discarded if already saved this frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of each frame all saved lines are checked against the depth buffer of the rendered scene. If a line lies completely behind the depth buffer, it can be safely discarded because it shouldn’t be visible. This happens if it’s behind a wall or something. These checks must be done after all draw calls are processed since geometry isn’t drawn in a back-to-front order. I implemented this as a series of ten or so depth buffer samples along the line and discarded the line if all of them were occluded. This worked well enough but left still some stray “spikes” peeking behind the corner in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-synth-rasterizer&quot;&gt;A synth rasterizer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The line synthesizer audio thread has a queue of lines to be drawn. New lines are requested from the Quake engine (by writing an integer to pipe) in the main thread if it notices we are running short on stuff to draw. The audio thread consumes this line data on its own pace - longer lines take a while to draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audio is synthesized as stereo 96 kHz 32-bit IEEE floating point data, but internally in PortAudio it’s converted to 32-bit signed integers before getting submitted to the ASIO output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, 1800 lines per frame are transferred to the synth process, and if no new data is received on time the latest frame will be shown again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-speed&quot;&gt;On speed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the video, about 5-20 samples are allocated to each line depending on the length of the segment. This means the frequencies emitted are very high (5 samples per period is 19.2 kHz) and it seems the audio output is being low pass filtered resulting in silly wobbly lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/img/speed_comparison.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image quality increases as the lines are drawn slower.&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Image quality increases as the lines are drawn slower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio synthesis takes some CPU time, but most of it is spent on Quake depth buffer rasterization. Triangle filling is slow when you do it with just one thread on a modest laptop processor :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total latency is passable and short enough to play comfortably with keyboard and mouse. This can be adjusted by tweaking audio synthesis parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-problems&quot;&gt;Open problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I was quite disappointed by the performance I got out of this. Merely 1000 lines on screen simultaneously, usually not even that. Any higher numbers end up being represented as such high frequencies the audio output can’t keep up. One can increase the time spent on each line but this causes additional latency and the image starts to flicker. Speeding up the drawing speed allows more stuff per frame, but the quality degrades quickly as can be seen in the comparison image shown earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also some &lt;em&gt;mysterious&lt;/em&gt; low frequency noise generated in the process. This is clearly visible when rotating the view quickly and the whole screen moves on the oscilloscope monitor screen. I assume this is some annoying bass boost equalization happening inside the sound card. &lt;del&gt;If you have any ideas what causes this, please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:pekka.vaananen@iki.fi&quot;&gt;email me about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mystery solved:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s the cheap sound card. (Thanks Antti!) With another USB sound card the low frequency movement is gone. Too bad there’s no proper ASIO drivers (ASIO4ALL isn’t enough) for it, making it unsuitable for realtime use because of additional latency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;possible-improvements&quot;&gt;Possible improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten some excellent ideas via email for improving the stability and quality of the rendering. I’m probably not going the develop this project further but I’m listing the suggestions here for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;audio-interface with DC-coupled outputs&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A regular sound card can be modified by removing capacitors before the analog output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.modularsynth.ru/en/2014/06/15/gigaporthd_dc_coupling/&quot;&gt;ESI Gigaport HD DC-Coupling Mod&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now the low frequencies aren’t filtered away and the picture stays stable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;strong&gt;VGA as DAC&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Really fast 8-bit digital to analog converter, precision can be increased with e.g. dithering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use red and green channels as X and Y signals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low latency and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Direct_coupling&quot;&gt;DC coupled&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No signal during vertical blanking interval, probably not a problem since it’s so short.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It actually looks &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?list=PLBPoTwsQYxSCc9C95p2RGuT-JulNEhsfH&amp;amp;v=9P1UJatH5jM&quot;&gt;pretty good!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resample the signal&lt;/strong&gt; to higher sampling rate with nearest neighbour filtering.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;strong&gt;intensity modulation&lt;/strong&gt; (Z-channel) to hide the beam when moving between lines.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Usually this input channel is on the rear panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would use three audio channels instead of two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;strong&gt;an extra sample to the beginning and end&lt;/strong&gt; of each line drawn.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Decreases wobbliness because of slightly reduced high frequency content. (thanks Andrew!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Windows, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.jriver.com/index.php/WASAPI&quot;&gt;WASAPI&lt;/a&gt; might reduce audio latency.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A good candidate if your audio-interface doesn’t have ASIO drivers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supported by PortAudio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sort the lines&lt;/strong&gt; before rendering to minimize beam travel distance.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;More geometry per frame can be drawn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/shortest_line_segment_path.html&quot;&gt;Travelling Salesman Problem reduces into this&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NP-hard&lt;/strong&gt;, so an approximation is needed:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A generic solver on the GPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dividing the screen into buckets and populate them with lines according start/end points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just draw the longest lines first
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;More time spent on drawing actual visible content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bias the selection with line distance in camera space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decrease line draw time according to camera space distance.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Less time spent on far away lines so more can be fit in per frame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Split the lines&lt;/strong&gt; to multiple segments when performing Z-buffer checks.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Picture is clearer with less line segments visible through walls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Quake level &lt;strong&gt;brush geometry&lt;/strong&gt; instead of the mesh used in rendering.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eliminates unnecessary lines since quads are rendered instead of triangles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works at least in Quake 2 (thanks Jay!)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware accelerated rendering, current system runs in software mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;video&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/aMli33ornEU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playing through the first level E1M1 of Quake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;audio-recordings&quot;&gt;Audio recordings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to watch this on your own hardware, here are recordings of the same playthrough that’s on the video. Try the fast one first and then the slow one if it doesn’t seem right. The difference is very small. I didn’t test these on the oscilloscope, I hope they work well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;e1m1_fast_48khz &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/download/e1m1_fast_48khz.wav&quot;&gt;WAV&lt;/a&gt; (36.9 MiB), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/download/e1m1_fast_48khz.flac&quot;&gt;FLAC&lt;/a&gt; (30.4 MiB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e1m1_slow_48khz &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/download/e1m1_slow_48khz.wav&quot;&gt;WAV&lt;/a&gt; (36.9 MiB), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/download/e1m1_slow_48khz.flac&quot;&gt;FLAC&lt;/a&gt; (29.3 MiB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source code for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/seece/scoperender&quot;&gt;line renderer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/seece/darkplaceswire&quot;&gt;the modified Quake&lt;/a&gt; are available. Visual Studio 2013 is required to compile the projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-history&quot;&gt;Article history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;November 12, 2016
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added link to NP-hardness article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added link to VGA oscilloscope video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;July 13, 2015
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added source code links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January 6, 2015
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;em&gt;Possible improvements&lt;/em&gt; section. Thanks for the suggestions people!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 29, 2014
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Low frequency noise explanation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added audio recordings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small additions to culling part&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added picture of the simulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For feedback email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:pekka.vaananen@iki.fi&quot;&gt;pekka.vaananen@iki.fi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 02:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ivoah</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/oscilloscope_quake.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Entrepreneurs Aren’t a Special Breed – They’re Mostly Rich Kids</title>
<link>https://www.asia.finance/entrepreneur/entrepreneurs-not-special-breed/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.asia.finance/entrepreneur/entrepreneurs-not-special-breed/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In a world where success is flashed across the globe at the speed of a tweet, where wealth can be created overnight and companies listed in a matter of years, many an anonymous entrepreneur has been thrusted into the limelight and glorified for their supersonic rise to success.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Indeed we have been conditioned to believe that entrepreneurs are a rare breed of people who possess more guts and gumption than the rest of us. Mention ‘entrepreneurs’ and images of Richard Branson, Mark Zuckerberg and Steve Jobs come to mind. The media portray them as a mysteriously talented, charismatic type with a bigger appetite for risk than the average Joe.  So it’s easy to fall into the trap of thinking that with enough attitude, one can succeed and become one of those glorified entrepreneur types.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The reality though, is that the genius, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asia.finance/entrepreneur/7-survival-tips-first-time-entrepreneurs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;risk-taking entrepreneur&lt;/a&gt; is the exception rather than the norm. Depressingly, studies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; show that most entrepreneurs are just ordinary people not much different from the rest of us, but with access to extraordinary wealth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Well-Connected&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;report, most startups are created by ex-bankers with deep connections.  And since it’s a well known fact that venture capitalists do not entertain cold calls but prefer to be introduced to founders via their own connections, this creates an ecosystem where bankers, wealthy investors and VCs can network and get their startups off the ground.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Interestingly, most of these connections begin in renowned universities. Alumnus of Harvard, MIT and Yale frequently end up working in top banks, venture capital firms and other established companies like Google and McKinsey where they continue to build networks with powerful people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jeff Bezos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, for example, appears to be a classic case of the well educated and well connected. He is a Princeton graduate who worked on Wall Street for a decade before launching Amazon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Wealthy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Being well connected usually overlaps with being wealthy. Most successful business owners can be traced back to wealthy families.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; Founders who have rich backings can tide through the early years because they have access to cash flow – something most poor and middle class entrepreneurs do not. For example, everyone knows&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Bill Gates&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;started Microsoft but not many know that his wealthy parents funded his company and helped him land his first client in IBM.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talent or Connections?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Critics argue that just being wealthy and well-connected doesn’t guarantee success. Take the case of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Its well-connected founder successfully raises USD41 million without even having a product, only to fail spectacularly not long after.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So is a successful entrepreneur like&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Brit Morin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;a product of sheer talent or good connections? Some argue it takes a good dose of talent to make it to top universities and work in renowned companies in the first place. Bill Gates, for example, was a genius coder way before he went to (and dropped out of) Harvard and started Microsoft.  And it is these capable people – the ones with &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; talent and connections to wealth – who ultimately stand out from the rest.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hustlers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Still, Silicon Valley is full of Brit Morins and the scrappy entrepreneurs who make it on their own are few and far in between. Despite the gloomy statistics, not everyone have to be wealthy and well-connected to become a successful entrepreneur as this&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;survey&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;shows. Those without cash and social capital hustle their way to success. Legendary &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asia.finance/lifestyle/lifestyle-people/these-billionaires-started-from-the-bottom-now-theyre-here/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rags-to-riches stories&lt;/a&gt; are legendary exactly because they are rare.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So remember the reality to remind yourself that it’s not easy to be a successful entrepreneur but don’t let that stop you from reaching for the skies!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>monsieurpng</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://images.asia.finance/contents/images/20161031120144/richkidsWP.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Entrepreneurs Aren’t A Special Breed - They’re Mostly Rich Kids - Asia Finance</og:title>
<og:description>The media glorifies entrepreneur. The sobering reality is that the majority of them are just regular Joes with access to wealth.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.asia.finance/entrepreneur/entrepreneurs-not-special-breed/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.asia.finance/entrepreneur/entrepreneurs-not-special-breed/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Senators push to ditch social security numbers in light of Equifax hack</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/are-social-security-numbers-going-away/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/are-social-security-numbers-going-away/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-679539624.jpg?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Eyeing more secure alternatives to Social Security numbers, lawmakers in the U.S. are looking abroad. Today, the Senate Commerce Committee questioned &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/yahoo-senate-commerce-hearing-russia-3-billion-hack/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;former Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer&lt;/a&gt;, Verizon chief privacy officer Karen Zacharia and both the current and former CEOs of Equifax on how to protect consumers against major data breaches. The consensus was that Social Security numbers have got to go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rounding out the panel, Entrust Datacard president and CEO Todd Wilkinson offered some context and insight about why the U.S. should indeed move away from Social Security numbers — a step that the witnesses unanimously agreed was necessary if not wholly sufficient to protect consumers moving forward, in light of the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/tag/equifax-hack/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Equifax hack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Over 145 million Americans’ insecure identities are now forever at risk, and they have limited ability to protect themselves,” Wilkinson said. “A key question for this committee to consider is: What do we do now given these identities are forever compromised?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social Security numbers are a privacy nightmare. While a consumer who gets hacked can replace credit card numbers and other account details, a Social Security number is relatively permanent, linked to a real identity throughout a person’s lifespan. In the hearing, Wilkinson and many of the senators present argued that the U.S. needs to move to a dynamic system of personal identity, one designed with digital security in mind — a stark contrast with an inflexible legacy system that dates back to the 1930s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some combination of digital multi-factor authentication… is the right path,” former Equifax CEO Richard Smith said when asked about such a program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multiple times throughout the hearing, Brazil’s Infraestrutura de Chaves Públicas system of citizen IDs through digital certificates came up as a potential model for the U.S. as it moves forward. In this model, a certificate lasts for three years at maximum and can be used to issue a digital signature much like written signatures are used now. Unlike its counterpart in the U.S., these identity accounts can be revoked and reissued easily through an established national protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the Senate committee also advocated for “rigorous” data security rules, expanding FTC authority to enforce them and stiffer penalties to motivate companies to protect consumers proactively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The parade of high-profile data breaches seems to have no end,” said ranking committee member Bill Nelson. “We can either take action with common sense rules or we can start planning for our next hearing on the issue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, White House cybersecurity coordinator Rob Joyce made it clear that the Trump administration is also interested in &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://thehill.com/policy/cybersecurity/353588-white-house-cyber-coordinator-calls-for-end-of-social-security-numbers&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;abandoning Social Security numbers&lt;/a&gt; in favor of a more secure, more digital form of identification, stating that the form of ID has “outlived its usefulness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Featured Image: Douglas Sacha/Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 22:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Varcht</dc:creator>
<og:title>Senators push to ditch Social Security numbers in light of Equifax hack</og:title>
<og:description>Eyeing more secure alternatives to Social Security numbers, lawmakers in the U.S. are looking abroad. Today, the Senate Commerce Committee questioned former..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-679539624.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/are-social-security-numbers-going-away/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/are-social-security-numbers-going-away/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel to Develop Discrete GPUs, Hires AMD&amp;#039;s Raja Koduri as Chief Architect</title>
<link>https://www.anandtech.com/show/12017/intel-to-develop-discrete-gpus-hires-raja-koduri-as-chief-architect</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.anandtech.com/show/12017/intel-to-develop-discrete-gpus-hires-raja-koduri-as-chief-architect</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, Intel announced that it had penned a deal with AMD to have the latter provide a discrete GPU to be integrated onto a future Intel SoC. On Tuesday, AMD announced that their chief GPU architect, Raja Koduri, was leaving the company. Now today the saga continues, as Intel is announcing that they have hired Raja Koduri to serve as their own GPU chief architect. And Raja's task will not be a small one; with his hire, Intel will be developing their own high-end discrete GPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from the top and following yesterday’s formal resignation from AMD, Raja Koduri has jumped ship to Intel, where he will be serving as a Senior VP for the company, overseeing the new Core and Visual Computing group. As a chief architect and general manager, Intel is tasking Raja with significantly expanding their GPU business, particularly as the company re-enters the discrete GPU field. Raja of course has a long history in the GPU space as a leader in GPU architecture, serving as the manager of AMD’s graphics business twice, and in between AMD stints serving as the director of graphics architecture on Apple’s GPU team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/new-mcm-small.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/new-mcm-small_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in perhaps the only news that can outshine the fact that Raja Koduri is joining Intel, is what he will be doing for Intel. As part of today’s revelation, Intel has announced that they are instituting a new top-to-bottom GPU strategy. At the bottom, the company wants to extend their existing iGPU market into new classes of edge devices, and while Intel doesn’t go into much more detail than this, the fact that they use the term “edge” strongly implies that we’re talking about IoT-class devices, where edge goes hand-in-hand with neural network inference. This is a field Intel already plays in to some extent with their Atom processors on the GPU side, and their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/11771/intel-announces-movidius-myriad-x-vpu&quot;&gt;Movidius neural compute engines&lt;/a&gt; on the dedicated silicon sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However in what’s likely the most exciting part of this news for PC enthusiasts and the tech industry as a whole, is that in aiming at the top of the market, Intel will once again be going back into developing discrete GPUs. The company has tried this route twice before; once in the early days with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/202/3&quot;&gt;i740&lt;/a&gt; in the late 90s, and again with the aborted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/3738/intel-kills-larrabee-gpu-will-not-bring-a-discrete-graphics-product-to-market&quot;&gt;Larrabee project&lt;/a&gt; in the late 2000s. However even though these efforts never panned out quite like Intel has hoped, the company has continued to develop their GPU architecture and GPU-like devices, the latter embodying the massive parallel compute focused Xeon Phi family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet while Intel has GPU-like products for certain markets, the company doesn’t have a proper GPU solution once you get beyond their existing GT4-class iGPUs, which are, roughly speaking, on par with $150 or so discrete GPUs. Which is to say that Intel doesn’t have access to the midrange market or above with their iGPUs. With the hiring of Raja and Intel’s new direction, the company is going to be expanding into full discrete GPUs for what the company calls “a broad range of computing segments.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading between the lines, it’s clear that Intel will be going after both the compute and graphics sub-markets for GPUs. The former of course is an area where Intel has been fighting NVIDIA for several years now with less success than they’d like to see, while the latter would be new territory for Intel. However it’s very notable that Intel is calling these “graphics solutions”, so it’s clear that this isn’t just another move by Intel to develop a compute-only processor ala the Xeon Phi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/wm_packages.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/wm_packages_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA are at best frenemies; the companies’ technologies complement each other well, but at the same time NVIDIA wants Intel’s high-margin server compute business, and Intel wants a piece of the action in the rapid boom in business that NVIDIA is seeing in the high performance computing and deep learning markets. NVIDIA has already begun weaning themselves off of Intel with technologies such as the NVLInk interconnect, which allows faster and cache-coherent memory transfers between NVIDIA GPUs and the forthcoming IBM POWER9 CPU. Meanwhile developing their own high-end GPU would allow Intel to further chase developers currently in NVIDIA’s stable, while in the long run also potentially poaching customers from NVIDIA’s lucrative (and profitable) consumer and professional graphics businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, I’m going to be surprised if Intel doesn’t develop a true top-to-bottom product stack that contains midrange GPUs as well – something in the vein of Polaris 10 and GP106 – but for the moment the discrete GPU aspect of Intel’s announcement is focused on high-end GPUs. And, given what we typically see in PC GPU release cycles, even if Intel does develop a complete product stack, I wouldn’t be too surprised if Intel’s first released GPU was a high-end GPU, as it’s clear this is where Intel needs to start first to best combat NVIDIA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More broadly speaking, this is an interesting shift in direction for Intel, and one that arguably indicates that Intel’s iGPU-exclusive efforts in the GPU space were not the right move. For the longest time, Intel played very conservatively with its iGPUs, maxing out with the very much low-end GT2 configuration. More recently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/6993/intel-iris-pro-5200-graphics-review-core-i74950hq-tested/2&quot;&gt;starting with the Haswell generation in 2013&lt;/a&gt;, Intel introduced more powerful GT3 and GT4 configurations. However this was primarily done at the behest of a single customer – Apple – and even to this day, we see very little OEM adoption of Intel’s higher performance graphics options by the other PC OEMs. The end result has been that Intel has spent the last decade making the kinds of CPUs that their cost-conscious customers want, with just a handful of high-performance versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/intel-8th-gen-cpu-discrete-graphics-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/intel-8th-gen-cpu-discrete-graphics-2_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would happily argue that outside of Apple, most other PC OEMs don’t “get it” with respect to graphics, but at this juncture that’s beside the point. Between &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/12003/intel-to-create-new-8th-generation-cpus-with-amd-radeon-graphics-with-hbm2-using-emib&quot;&gt;Monday’s strongly Apple-flavored Kaby Lake-G SoC announcement&lt;/a&gt; and now Intel’s vastly expanded GPU efforts, the company is, if only finally, becoming a major player in the high-performance GPU space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides taking on NVIDIA though, this is going to put perpetual underdog AMD into a tough spot. AMD’s edge over Intel for the longest time has been their GPU technology. The Zen CPU core has thankfully reworked that balance in the last year, though AMD still hasn’t quite caught up to Intel here on peak performance. The concern here is that the mature PC market has strongly favored duopolies – AMD and Intel for CPUs, AMD and NVIDIA for GPUs – so Intel’s entrance into the discrete GPU space upsets the balance on the latter. And while AMD is without a doubt more experienced than Intel, Intel has the financial and fabrication resources to fight NVIDIA, something AMD has always lacked. Which isn’t to say that AMD is by any means doom, but Intel’s growing GPU efforts and Raja’s move to Intel has definitely made AMD’s job harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, on the technical side of matters, the big question going forward with Intel’s efforts is over which GPU architecture Intel will use to build their discrete GPUs. Despite their low performance targets, Intel’s Gen9.5 graphics is a very capable architecture in terms of features and capabilities. In fact, prior to the launch of AMD’s Vega architecture a couple months back, it was arguably the most advanced PC GPU architecture, supporting higher tier graphics features than even NVIDIA’s Pascal architecture. So in terms of features alone, Gen9.5 is already a very decent base to start from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/70b_-_gt_designs.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/70b_-_gt_designs_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The catch is whether Gen9.5 and its successors can efficiently scale out to the levels needed for a high-performance GPU. Architectural scalability is in some respects the unsung hero of GPU architecture design, as while it’s kind of easy to design a small GPU architecture, it’s a lot harder to design an architecture that can scale up to multiple units in a 400mm2+ die size. Which isn’t to say that Gen9.5 can’t, only that we as the public have never seen anything bigger than the GT4 configuration, which is still a relatively small design by GPU standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/gpu-01.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/gpu-01_575px.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though perhaps the biggest wildcard here is Intel’s timetable. Nothing about Intel’s announcement says when the company wants to launch these high-end GPUs. If, for example, Intel wants to design a GPU from scratch under Raja, then this would be a 4+ year effort and we’d easily be talking about the first such GPU in 2022. On the other hand, if this has been an ongoing internal project that started well before Raja came on board, then Intel could be a lot closer. Given what kind of progress NVIDIA has made in just the last couple of years, I can only imagine that Intel wants to move quickly, and what this may boil down to is a tiered strategy where Intel takes both routes, if only to release a big Gen9.5(ish) GPU soon to buy time for a new architecture later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In directing these tasks, Raja Koduri has in turn taken on a very big role at Intel. Until recently, Intel’s graphics lead was Tom Piazza, a Sr. Fellow and capable architect, but also an individual who was never all that public outside of Intel. By contrast, Raja will be a much more public individual thanks to the combination of Intel’s expanded GPU efforts, Raja’s SVP role, and the new Core and Visual Computing group that has been created just for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what Intel is seeking to do, it’s clear why they picked Raja, given his experience inside and outside of AMD, and more specifically, with integrated graphics at both AMD and Apple. The flip side to that however is that while Apple’s graphics portfolio boomed under Raja during his time at the company, his most recent AMD stint didn’t go quite as well. AMD’s Vega GPU architecture has yet to live up to all of its promises, and while success and failure at this level is never the responsibility of a single individual, Intel will certainly be looking to have a better launch than Vega. Which, given the company’s immense resources, is definitely something they can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at the end of the day, this is just the first step for Intel and for Raja. By hiring an experienced hand like Raja Koduri and by announcing that they are getting into high-end discrete GPUs, Intel is very clearly telegraphing their intent to become a major player in the GPU space. Given Intel’s position as a market leader it’s a logical move, and given their lack of recent discrete GPU experience it’s also an ambitious move. So while this move stands to turn the PC GPU market as we know it on its head, I’m looking forward to seeing just what a GPU-focused Intel can do over the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.intel.com/news-releases/raja-koduri-joins-intel/&quot;&gt;Intel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 22:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>namlem</dc:creator>
<og:title>Intel to Develop Discrete GPUs, Hires Raja Koduri as Chief Architect &amp; Senior VP</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.anandtech.com/show/12017/intel-to-develop-discrete-gpus-hires-raja-koduri-as-chief-architect</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.anandtech.com/doci/12017/intellogo_678x452.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.anandtech.com/show/12017/intel-to-develop-discrete-gpus-hires-raja-koduri-as-chief-architect</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Justice Department moves to end routine gag orders on tech firms</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-department-moves-to-end-routine-gag-orders-on-tech-firms/2017/10/23/df8300bc-b848-11e7-9e58-e6288544af98_story.html?utm_term=.4f3da68632f5</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-department-moves-to-end-routine-gag-orders-on-tech-firms/2017/10/23/df8300bc-b848-11e7-9e58-e6288544af98_story.html?utm_term=.4f3da68632f5</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Justice Department has issued new guidelines aimed at providing more transparency around prosecutors’ secret demands for customer data stored on tech firms’ servers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.washingtonpost.com/g/documents/world/read-dojs-new-policy-on-gag-orders/2610/&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;apps.washingtonpost.com&quot;&gt;binding guidance&lt;/a&gt;, approved last week by Deputy Attorney General Rod J. Rosenstein, ends the routine imposition of gag orders barring companies from telling customers that their email or other records have been turned over in response to legal demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also bans — in most cases — indefinite gag orders that forbid a company from ever telling users that their data has been searched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move comes 1 ½ years after Microsoft sued the department, asking a federal judge in Seattle to strike down portions of a major privacy law that govern the secrecy orders. The tech giant argued that the Electronic Communications Privacy Act violated customers’ Fourth Amendment right that a search be reasonable because it did not require the government to notify them when their records were obtained. The company also argued that the law’s gag-order provision violated the company’s First Amendment right to talk to its customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new guidance requires prosecutors to tailor their applications for secrecy orders to ensure that they are necessary, and to explain why. For instance, a prosecutor might fear that targets will destroy data if they learn of the probe. Or a target might try to flee. The assessment must be “individualized and meaningful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p channel=&quot;wp.com&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.washingtonpost.com/g/documents/world/read-dojs-new-policy-on-gag-orders/2610/&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;apps.washingtonpost.com&quot;&gt;Read DOJ’s new policy on gag orders&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now there is a time limit: “Barring exceptional circumstances,” a gag order may be sought for “one year or less.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change is a recognition that privacy laws passed in the 1980s have not kept up with the advent of cloud computing in which people, at the press of a button, create and store data in servers that they do not control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This update further ensures that the department can protect the rights of citizens we serve, while allowing companies to maintain relationships with their customers by notifying those suspected of crimes, or believed to have information relevant to a crime, in a timely manner that information was obtained relating to their user accounts,” Justice Department spokeswoman Lauren Ehrsam said Monday in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is an important step for both privacy and free expression,” Microsoft’s president and chief legal officer, Brad Smith, said Monday in a blog post. “It is an unequivocal win for our customers, and we’re pleased the DOJ has taken these steps to protect the constitutional rights of all Americans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, Microsoft announced that it plans to drop its lawsuit. But it wants Congress to pass legislation to put a 90-day limit on nondisclosure orders unless the government asks for them to be renewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p channel=&quot;wp.com&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/microsoft-sues-to-block-law-banning-tech-firms-from-telling-customers-about-search-warrants/2016/04/14/6f8c36e4-01dc-11e6-9d36-33d198ea26c5_story.html?utm_term=.633bb15f6ef7&quot;&gt;Microsoft sues over law banning tech firms from telling customers about data requests&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Microsoft filed its case in April 2016, it noted that in the previous 18 months, it had received 5,600 federal demands for data and that almost 2,600 were accompanied by obligations of secrecy. Further, more than two-thirds of those — about 1,750 orders — had no fixed end date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In short, we were prevented from ever telling a large number of customers that the government had sought to access their data,” Smith said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The policy does not apply to orders under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act or to “national security letters,” a type of administrative subpoena used in national security cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Calabrese, vice president of policy at the Center for Democracy and Technology, a privacy organization, applauded the move. But, he said, “it is no substitute for statutory reform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move matters for Americans whose data is secretly obtained in criminal probes that never lead to prosecution but who never find out because of indefinite gag orders. This has become much more of a problem as people store their emails and other sensitive data in the cloud. “They’re not expecting that it’s an all-you-can-eat buffet for the government,” said John McKay, a former U.S. attorney in Seattle who is now a partner at Davis Wright Tremaine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 21:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>forapurpose</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-department-moves-to-end-routine-gag-orders-on-tech-firms/2017/10/23/df8300bc-b848-11e7-9e58-e6288544af98_story.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_1484w/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2017/10/24/National-Security/Images/2017-10-23T070946Z_795119777_RC1F64ECDEF0_RTRMADP_3_MICROSOFT-RESULTS.jpg?t=20170517</og:image>
<og:title>Justice Department moves to end routine gag orders on tech firms</og:title>
<og:description>The change follows a Microsoft lawsuit alleging the department’s secrecy orders are unconstitutional.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-department-moves-to-end-routine-gag-orders-on-tech-firms/2017/10/23/df8300bc-b848-11e7-9e58-e6288544af98_story.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Game Over We Have Obtained Fully Functional JTAG for Intel CSME via USB DCI</title>
<link>https://mobile.twitter.com/h0t_max/status/928269320064450560</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mobile.twitter.com/h0t_max/status/928269320064450560</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;But the important thing is that someone publicly saying they found this changes /nothing/. Finding an exploit does not mean creating it: the exploit was already there, and there's no way to know whether someone else has already been quietly exploiting it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 20:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>panny</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/h0t_max/status/928269320064450560</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Beer giant ABI bought many craft brews and is now buying beer rating websites</title>
<link>http://www.foodandpower.net/2017/11/02/abis-venture-capital-fund-quietly-expanding-the-mega-brewers-reach/#bookmark/0/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.foodandpower.net/2017/11/02/abis-venture-capital-fund-quietly-expanding-the-mega-brewers-reach/#bookmark/0/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foodandpower.net/2017/11/02/abis-venture-capital-fund-quietly-expanding-the-mega-brewers-reach/#bookmark/0/&quot;&gt;http://www.foodandpower.net/2017/11/02/abis-venture-capital-fund-quietly-expanding-the-mega-brewers-reach/#bookmark/0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15656918&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15656918&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 270&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 147&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 20:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.foodandpower.net/2017/11/02/abis-venture-capital-fund-quietly-expanding-the-mega-brewers-reach/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>BitTorrent inventor announces eco-friendly Bitcoin competitor Chia</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/chia-network-cryptocurrency</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/chia-network-cryptocurrency</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/bram-cohen1.jpg?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;A bitcoin transaction wastes as much electricity as it takes to power an American home for a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/ywbbpm/bitcoin-mining-electricity-consumption-ethereum-energy-climate-change&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;week&lt;/a&gt;, and legendary coder Bram Cohen wants to fix that. And considering he invented the ubiquitous peer-to-peer file transfer protocol BitTorrent, you should take him seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cohen has just started a new company called &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://chia.network&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Chia Network&lt;/a&gt; that will launch a cryptocurrency based on proofs of time and storage rather than bitcoin’s &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://digiconomist.net/bitcoin-energy-consumption&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;electricity-burning&lt;/a&gt; proofs of work. Essentially, Chia will harness cheap and abundant unused storage space on hard drives to verify its blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The idea is to make a better bitcoin, to fix the centralization problems” Cohen tells me. The two main issues he sees in bitcoin are in environmental impact and the instability that arises from the few bitcoin miners with the cheapest access to electricity exerting outsized influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chia aims to solve both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1565151 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/chia-cryptocurrency.png?w=680&amp;amp;h=508&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;508&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/chia-cryptocurrency.png?w=680&amp;amp;h=508 680w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/chia-cryptocurrency.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=112 150w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/chia-cryptocurrency.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=224 300w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/chia-cryptocurrency.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=574 768w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/chia-cryptocurrency.png 1100w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin uses proofs of work to verify the blockchain. That’s because it’s prohibitively expensive to make a fake blockchain as it wouldn’t have as much work demonstrated as the real one. But over time that’s given a massive advantage in collecting the incentives for mining bitcoin to those who operate close to low-cost electricity and naturally chill air to cool the mining rigs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright wp-image-1565157&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-07-at-12-49-00-pm.png?w=274&amp;amp;h=186&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;274&quot; height=&quot;186&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-07-at-12-49-00-pm.png?w=274&amp;amp;h=186 274w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-07-at-12-49-00-pm.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=102 150w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-07-at-12-49-00-pm.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=204 300w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-07-at-12-49-00-pm.png 446w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 274px) 100vw, 274px&quot;/&gt;Chia instead relies on proofs of space in file storage, which people often already have and can use for no additional cost. It combines this with proofs of time that disarm a wide array of attacks to which proofs of space are susceptible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;“I’m not the first person to come up with this idea,” says Cohen, but actually implementing requires the kind of advanced computer science he specializes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After inventing torrenting in the early 2000s and briefly working on Steam for Valve, Cohen had been at BitTorrent building a new protocol for peer-to-peer live video transfer. But mismanagement on the business side &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2017/01/the-inside-story-of-bittorrents-bizarre-collapse/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;caused the company to implode&lt;/a&gt;. Now it’s limping along, and Cohen says “it doesn’t need me day-to-day.” So while he’s still on the board, he left in early August to start Chia Network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1565158&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1565158&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/bram-cohen-chia.jpg?w=273&amp;amp;h=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;273&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/bram-cohen-chia.jpg?w=273&amp;amp;h=300 273w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/bram-cohen-chia.jpg?w=137&amp;amp;h=150 137w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/bram-cohen-chia.jpg 507w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 273px) 100vw, 273px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Chia Network co-founder Bram Cohen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohen has teamed up with early bitcoin exchange Tradehill’s COO Ryan Singer and they’ve raised a seed round for Chia to ramp up hiring. Cohen wouldn’t say how much it had raised, laughing that, “I’m not sure how much we want to announce right now, but it was a very hot round.” The goal is do some early sales of Chia in Q2 2018, with a full launch of its cryptocurrency by the end of 2018, though Cohen says that’s a stretch goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohen is a brilliant technologist, but it will take more than that to convince people to switch over from bitcoin to Chia. He tells me the plan for Chia is “do some smarter things about its legal status and do a bunch of technical fixes that you can do when starting from scratch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s too early to guess how this will all play out, but at least someone is trying to address the ecological impact of cryptocurrency instead of just complaining about it. Cohen seems excited though. “It’s technically ambitious and there’s a big meaty chunk of work to do. I’ve done enough raising money and recruiting. Now for the real work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Featured Image Credit: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.shinyredphoto.com&quot;&gt;Michael O’Donnell&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 19:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chriskanan</dc:creator>
<og:title>BitTorrent inventor announces eco-friendly bitcoin competitor Chia</og:title>
<og:description>A bitcoin transaction wastes as much electricity as it takes to power an American home for a week, and legendary coder Bram Cohen wants to fix that. Cohen has..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/bram-cohen1.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/chia-network-cryptocurrency/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/chia-network-cryptocurrency/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>