<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>FTC to Probe Facebook for Use of Personal Data</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-03-20/ftc-to-probe-facebook-for-use-of-personal-data</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-03-20/ftc-to-probe-facebook-for-use-of-personal-data</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook Inc. is under investigation by a U.S. privacy watchdog over the use of personal data of 50 million users by a data analytics firm to help elect President Donald Trump.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Federal Trade Commission is probing whether Facebook violated terms of a 2011 consent decree over its handing of user data that was transferred to Cambridge Analytica without their knowledge, according to a person familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Under the &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2011-11-29/facebook-said-to-reach-settlement-over-privacy-complaints-by-site-s-users&quot; title=&quot;Facebook Settles Privacy Complaints of U.S. Regulator (2)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2011 settlement&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook agreed to get user consent for certain changes to privacy settings as part of a settlement of federal charges that it deceived consumers and forced them to share more personal information than they intended. That complaint arose after the company changed some user settings without notifying its customers, according to an FTC statement at the time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An FTC spokeswoman said in emailed statement that the agency is aware of the issues that have been raised, but can’t comment on whether it is investigating. The agency takes any allegations of violations of consent decrees seriously, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If the FTC finds Facebook violated terms of the consent decree, it has the power to fine the company more than $40,000 a day per violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook said in a statement it rejected &quot;any suggestion of violation of the consent decree.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We respected the privacy settings that people had in place,&quot; the statement said. &quot;Privacy and data protections are fundamental to every decision we make.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook declined in New York trading, falling 3.2 percent to $167 as of 10:57 a.m. in New York. That follows a drop of 6.8 percent Monday that was the company’s largest since March 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite concern about Cambridge Analytica’s use of the data expressed by several Democrats and Republicans, GOP-controlled congressional committees haven’t demanded hearings with Facebook executives. The Senate Commerce Committee did &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.commerce.senate.gov/public/index.cfm/pressreleases?ID=F958259D-3076-45B6-BD9C-C815BAC06201&quot; title=&quot;thune&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;announce&lt;/a&gt; Monday evening it would like a briefing from the company on &quot;the use and sharing of individual Facebook user data.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chuck Grassley, who serves as chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, also said he was &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-03-19/grassley-considers-hearing-with-facebook-google-twitter-ceos&quot; title=&quot;Grassley Considers Hearing With Facebook, Google, Twitter CEOs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;considering&lt;/a&gt; a hearing with the CEOs of Facebook, Alphabet Inc.’s Google and Twitter Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Facebook revelations have also prompted transatlantic reaction. The chairman of a UK parliamentary committee announced Tuesday he was requesting that Facebook Chief Executive Officer Mark Zuckerberg, who has remained silent for days, appear before the panel to supplement prior testimony by the company’s executives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White House spokesman Raj Shah said Tuesday that Trump “believes that Americans’ privacy should be protected” and supports federal investigations into the incident. “If Congress wants to look into the matter or other agencies want to look into the matter, we welcome that,&quot; Shah said on Fox News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked if Zuckerberg should testify, Shah demurred. &quot;Without knowing the specifics, it’s difficult to talk about whether an individual should testify,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Facebook spokesman confirmed that the company would be holding a townhall Tuesday, where a deputy general counsel would answer questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more on Facebook, check out the &lt;em&gt;Decrypted &lt;/em&gt; podcast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Terrence Dopp, and Jennifer Epstein&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 13:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<og:description>The U.S. Federal Trade Commission is probing Facebook Inc. over whether it violated terms of a consent decree over its use of personal data, according to a person familiar with the matter.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iASFXZ1WgCDg/v0/1200x726.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>FTC Probing Facebook for Use of Personal Data, Source Says</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-03-20/ftc-said-to-be-probing-facebook-for-use-of-personal-data</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-03-20/ftc-said-to-be-probing-facebook-for-use-of-personal-data</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Utterly horrifying: ex-Facebook insider says covert data harvesting was routine</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/mar/20/facebook-data-cambridge-analytica-sandy-parakilas</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/mar/20/facebook-data-cambridge-analytica-sandy-parakilas</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;H&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;undreds of millions of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; users are likely to have had their private information harvested by companies that exploited the same terms as the firm that collected data and passed it on to Cambridge Analytica, according to a new whistleblower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandy Parakilas, the platform operations manager at Facebook responsible for policing data breaches by third-party software developers between 2011 and 2012, told the Guardian he warned senior executives at the company that its lax approach to data protection risked a major breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-2 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;“My concerns were that all of the data that left Facebook servers to developers could not be monitored by Facebook, so we had no idea what developers were doing with the data,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakilas said Facebook had terms of service and settings that “people didn’t read or understand” and the company did not use its enforcement mechanisms, including audits of external developers, to ensure data was not being misused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakilas, whose job was to investigate data breaches by developers similar to the one later suspected of Global Science Research, which harvested tens of millions of Facebook profiles and provided the data to Cambridge Analytica, said the slew of recent disclosures had left him disappointed with his superiors for not heeding his warnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It has been painful watching,” he said, “because I know that they could have prevented it.”&lt;/p&gt;

Everything you need to know about the Cambridge Analytica exposé – video explainer
&lt;p&gt;Asked what kind of control Facebook had over the data given to outside developers, he replied: “Zero. Absolutely none. Once the data left Facebook servers there was not any control, and there was no insight into what was going on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakilas said he “always assumed there was something of a black market” for Facebook data that had been passed to external developers. However, he said that when he told other executives the company should proactively “audit developers directly and see what’s going on with the data” he was discouraged from the approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said one Facebook executive advised him against looking too deeply at how the data was being used, warning him: “Do you really want to see what you’ll find?” Parakilas said he interpreted the comment to mean that “Facebook was in a stronger legal position if it didn’t know about the abuse that was happening”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He added: “They felt that it was better not to know. I found that utterly shocking and horrifying.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakilas first went public with his concerns about privacy at Facebook four months ago, but his direct experience policing Facebook data given to third parties throws new light on revelations over how such data was obtained by Cambridge Analytica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook did not respond to a request for comment on the information supplied by Parakilas, but directed the Guardian to &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/h/enforcing-our-policies-and-protecting-peoples-data/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;a November 2017 blogpost&lt;/a&gt; in which the company defended its data sharing practices, which it said had “significantly improved” over the last five years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While it’s fair to criticise how we enforced our developer policies more than five years ago, it’s untrue to suggest we didn’t or don’t care about privacy,” that statement said. “The facts tell a different story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;‘A majority of Facebook users’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakilas, 38, who now works as a product manager for Uber, is particularly critical of Facebook’s previous policy of allowing developers to access the personal data of friends of people who used apps on the platform, without the knowledge or express consent of those friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That feature, called friends permission, was a boon to outside software developers who, from 2007 onwards, were given permission by Facebook to build quizzes and games – like the widely popular FarmVille – that were hosted on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apps proliferated on Facebook in the years leading up to the company’s 2012 initial public offering, an era when most users were still accessing the platform via laptops and computers rather than smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook took a 30% cut of payments made through apps, but in return enabled their creators to have access to Facebook user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakilas does not know how many companies sought friends permission data before such access was terminated around mid-2014. However, he said he believes tens or maybe even hundreds of thousands of developers may have done so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;It has been painful watching, because I know they could have prevented it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parakilas estimates that “a majority of Facebook users” could have had their data harvested by app developers without their knowledge. The company now has stricter protocols around the degree of access third parties have to data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakilas said that when he worked at Facebook it failed to take full advantage of its enforcement mechanisms, such as a clause that enables the social media giant to audit external developers who misuse its data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legal action against rogue developers or moves to ban them from Facebook were “extremely rare”, he said, adding: “In the time I was there, I didn’t see them conduct a single audit of a developer’s systems.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook announced on Monday that it had hired a digital forensics firm to conduct an audit of Cambridge Analytica. The decision comes more than two years after Facebook was made aware of the reported data breach.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the time he was at Facebook, Parakilas said the company was keen to encourage more developers to build apps for its platform and “one of the main ways to get developers interested in building apps was through offering them access to this data”. Shortly after arriving at the company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/silicon-valley&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt; headquarters he was told that any decision to ban an app required the personal approval of the chief executive, Mark Zuckerberg, although the policy was later relaxed to make it easier to deal with rogue developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://interactive.guim.co.uk/embed/article-embeds/Sidebar-ca/embed.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the previous policy of giving developers access to Facebook users’ friends’ data was sanctioned in the small print in Facebook’s terms and conditions, and users could block such data sharing by changing their settings, Parakilas said he believed the policy was problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was well understood in the company that that presented a risk,” he said. “Facebook was giving data of people who had not authorised the app themselves, and was relying on terms of service and settings that people didn’t read or understand.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was this feature that was exploited by Global Science Research, and the data provided to Cambridge Analytica in 2014. GSR was run by the Cambridge University psychologist Aleksandr Kogan, who built an app that was a personality test for Facebook users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test automatically downloaded the data of friends of people who took the quiz, ostensibly for academic purposes. Cambridge Analytica has denied knowing the data was obtained improperly, and Kogan maintains he did nothing illegal and had a “close working relationship” with Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Kogan’s app only attracted around 270,000 users (most of whom were paid to take the quiz), the company was then able to exploit the friends permission feature to quickly amass data pertaining to more than 50 million Facebook users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Kogan’s app was one of the very last to have access to friend permissions,” Parakilas said, adding that many other similar apps had been harvesting similar quantities of data for years for commercial purposes. &lt;a href=&quot;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.591.8519&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Academic research from 2010, based on an analysis of 1,800 Facebooks apps&lt;/a&gt;, concluded that around 11% of third-party developers requested data belonging to friends of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If those figures were extrapolated, tens of thousands of apps, if not more, were likely to have systematically culled “private and personally identifiable” data belonging to hundreds of millions of users, Parakilas said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ease with which it was possible for anyone with relatively basic coding skills to create apps and start trawling for data was a particular concern, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakilas said he was unsure why Facebook stopped allowing developers to access friends data around mid-2014, roughly two years after he left the company. However, he said he believed one reason may have been that Facebook executives were becoming aware that some of the largest apps were acquiring enormous troves of valuable data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He recalled conversations with executives who were nervous about the commercial value of data being passed to other companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They were worried that the large app developers were building their own social graphs, meaning they could see all the connections between these people,” he said. “They were worried that they were going to build their own social networks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;‘They treated it like a PR exercise’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakilas said he lobbied internally at Facebook for “a more rigorous approach” to enforcing data protection, but was offered little support. His warnings included a PowerPoint presentation he said he delivered to senior executives in mid-2012 “that included a map of the vulnerabilities for user data on Facebook’s platform”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I included the protective measures that we had tried to put in place, where we were exposed, and the kinds of bad actors who might do malicious things with the data,” he said. “On the list of bad actors I included foreign state actors and data brokers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frustrated at the lack of action, Parakilas left Facebook in late 2012. “I didn’t feel that the company treated my concerns seriously. I didn’t speak out publicly for years out of self-interest, to be frank.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-2 | 2&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;That changed, Parakilas said, when he heard the congressional testimony given by Facebook lawyers to Senate and House investigators in late 2017 about Russia’s attempt to sway the presidential election. “They treated it like a PR exercise,” he said. “They seemed to be entirely focused on limiting their liability and exposure rather than helping the country address a national security issue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was at that point that Parakilas decided to go public with his concerns, writing an opinion article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/19/opinion/facebook-regulation-incentive.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;in the New York Times&lt;/a&gt; that said Facebook could not be trusted to regulate itself. Since then, Parakilas has become an adviser to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://humanetech.com/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Center for Humane Technology&lt;/a&gt;, which is run by Tristan Harris, a former Google employee turned whistleblower on the industry.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 11:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>valanto</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/mar/20/facebook-data-cambridge-analytica-sandy-parakilas</og:url>
<og:description>Sandy Parakilas says numerous companies deployed these techniques – likely affecting hundreds of millions of users – and that Facebook looked the other way</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/f8b1a18132a1d9b89cac09e82f64f7737182c5ce/0_0_2600_1560/master/2600.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=920b0d54b8587a1a3f78b6d54fd4f8be</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>'Utterly horrifying': ex-Facebook insider says covert data harvesting was routine</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/mar/20/facebook-data-cambridge-analytica-sandy-parakilas</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook’s Surveillance Machine</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/opinion/facebook-cambridge-analytica.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/opinion/facebook-cambridge-analytica.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;198&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2575&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;Facebook makes money, in other words, by profiling us and then selling our attention to advertisers, political actors and others. These are Facebook’s true customers, whom it works hard to please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;454&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3029&quot;&gt;Facebook doesn’t just record every click and “like” on the site. It also collects browsing histories. It also purchases “external” data like financial information about users (though European nations have some regulations that block some of this). Facebook recently announced its intent to merge “offline” data — things you do in the physical world, such as making purchases in a brick-and-mortar store — with its vast online databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;298&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3327&quot;&gt;Facebook even creates “shadow profiles” of nonusers. That is, even if you are not on Facebook, the company may well have compiled a profile of you, inferred from data provided by your friends or from other data. This is an involuntary dossier from which you cannot opt out in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;576&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3903&quot;&gt;Despite Facebook’s claims to the contrary, everyone involved in the Cambridge Analytica data-siphoning incident did not give his or her “consent” — at least not in any meaningful sense of the word. It is true that if you found and read all the fine print on the site, you might have noticed that in 2014, your Facebook friends had the right to turn over all your data through such apps. (Facebook has since turned off this feature.) If you had managed to make your way through a bewildering array of options, you might have even discovered how to turn the feature off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;86&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3989&quot;&gt;This wasn’t &lt;em&gt;informed&lt;/em&gt; consent. This was the exploitation of user data and user trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;519&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4508&quot;&gt;Let’s assume, for the sake of argument, that you had explicitly consented to turn over your Facebook data to another company. Do you keep up with the latest academic research on computational inference? Did you know that algorithms now do a pretty good job of inferring a person’s personality traits, sexual orientation, political views, mental health status, substance abuse history and more just from his or her Facebook “likes” — and that there are new applications of this data being discovered every day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;265&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4773&quot;&gt;Given this confusing and rapidly changing state of affairs about what the data may reveal and how it may be used, consent to ongoing and extensive data collection can be neither fully informed nor truly consensual — especially since it is practically irrevocable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;479&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5252&quot;&gt;What did Cambridge Analytica do with all the data? With whom else might it have shared it? In 2015, Facebook sent a stern letter to Cambridge Analytica asking that the data be deleted. Cambridge Analytica employees have said that the company merely checked a box indicating that the data was deleted, at which point Facebook decided not to inform the 50 million users who were affected by the breach, nor to make the issue public, nor to sanction Cambridge Analytica at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/opinion/facebook-cambridge-analytica.html#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;236&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5488&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;The New York Times and The Observer of London are reporting that the data was not deleted. And Cambridge Analytica employees are claiming that the data formed the backbone of the company’s operations in the 2016 presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;528&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6016&quot;&gt;If Facebook failed to understand that this data could be used in dangerous ways, that it shouldn’t have let anyone harvest data in this manner and that a third-party ticking a box on a form wouldn’t free the company from responsibility, it had no business collecting anyone’s data in the first place. But the vast infrastructure Facebook has built to obtain data, and its consequent half-a-trillion-dollar market capitalization, suggest that the company knows all too well the value of this kind of vast data surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;418&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6434&quot;&gt;Should we all just leave Facebook? That may sound attractive but it is not a viable solution. In many countries, Facebook and its products simply &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; the internet. Some employers and landlords demand to see Facebook profiles, and there are increasingly vast swaths of public and civic life — from volunteer groups to political campaigns to marches and protests — that are accessible or organized only via Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;523&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6957&quot;&gt;The problem here goes beyond Cambridge Analytica and what it may have done. What other apps were allowed to siphon data from millions of Facebook users? What if one day Facebook decides to suspend from its site a presidential campaign or a politician whose platform calls for things like increased data privacy for individuals and limits on data retention and use? What if it decides to share data with one political campaign and not another? What if it gives better ad rates to candidates who align with its own interests?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;383&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7340&quot;&gt;A business model based on vast data surveillance and charging clients to opaquely target users based on this kind of extensive profiling will inevitably be misused. The real problem is that billions of dollars are being made at the expense of the health of our public sphere and our politics, and crucial decisions are being made unilaterally, and without recourse or accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/opinion/facebook-cambridge-analytica.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 06:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>imartin2k</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/opinion/facebook-cambridge-analytica.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Opinion | Facebook’s Surveillance Machine</og:title>
<og:description>It’s true that the Cambridge Analytica incident wasn’t a security breach. It was something far worse.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/03/20/opinion/19tufekci/merlin_135727065_4b12c730-c73b-4cdb-9e1b-059290dfb81a-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/opinion/facebook-cambridge-analytica.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Police Say Uber Is Likely Not at Fault for Self-Driving Car Fatality in Arizona</title>
<link>http://fortune.com/2018/03/19/uber-self-driving-car-crash/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://fortune.com/2018/03/19/uber-self-driving-car-crash/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;padded&quot; readability=&quot;44.16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The police chief of Tempe, Arizona, where a woman was &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2018/03/19/uber-halts-self-driving-car-testing-fatal-accident-tempe-arizona/&quot;&gt;struck and killed by one of Uber’s self-driving cars&lt;/a&gt; Sunday, says the ride-sharing company is likely not at fault for the accident, following a preliminary investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief of Police Sylvia Moir &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sfchronicle.com/business/article/Exclusive-Tempe-police-chief-says-early-probe-12765481.php?utm_campaign=twitter-premium&amp;amp;utm_source=CMS%20Sharing%20Button&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;told the San Francisco &lt;em&gt;Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Monday that video footage taken from cameras equipped to the autonomous Volvo SUV potentially shift the blame to the victim herself, 49-year-old Elaine Herzberg, rather than the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s very clear it would have been difficult to avoid this collision in any kind of mode [autonomous or human-driven] based on how she came from the shadows right into the roadway,” Moir told the paper, adding that the incident occurred roughly 100 yards from a crosswalk. “It is dangerous to cross roadways in the evening hour when well-illuminated managed crosswalks are available,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Though the vehicle was operating in autonomous mode, a driver was present in the front seat. But Moir said there appears to be little he could have done to intervene before the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The driver said it was like a flash, the person walked out in front of them,” Moir said. “His first alert to the collision was the sound of the collision.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;, the preliminary investigation found the Uber car was driving at 38 mph in a 35 mph zone and did not attempt to brake. Herzberg is said to have abruptly walked from a center median into a lane with traffic. Police believe she may have been homeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tempe police plan to work with investigators from the National Transportation Safety Board and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to reach a conclusion about what happened, according to the &lt;em&gt;Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday’s incident appears to be the &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/5205767/uber-autonomous-car-crash-arizona/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;first-ever self-driving car fatality involving a pedestrian.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tlrobinson</dc:creator>
<og:title>Police Say Uber Is Likely Not at Fault for Its Self-Driving Car Fatality in Arizona</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://fortune.com/2018/03/19/uber-self-driving-car-crash/</og:url>
<og:description>A preliminary investigation has shifted the blame more towards the victim.</og:description>
<og:image>https://fortunedotcom.files.wordpress.com/2016/05/uatc-car.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://fortune.com/2018/03/19/uber-self-driving-car-crash/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gallery of programming UIs</title>
<link>https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1MD-CgzODFWzdpnYXr8bEgysfDmb8PDV6iCAjH5JIvaI</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1MD-CgzODFWzdpnYXr8bEgysfDmb8PDV6iCAjH5JIvaI</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1MD-CgzODFWzdpnYXr8bEgysfDmb8PDV6iCAjH5JIvaI&quot;&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1MD-CgzODFWzdpnYXr8bEgysfDmb8PDV6iCAjH5JIvaI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16624724&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16624724&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 315&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 94&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>panic</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1MD-CgzODFWzdpnYXr8bEgysfDmb8PDV6iCAjH5JIvaI/preview?_escaped_fragment_=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An employee whose job was to be sacked (2010)</title>
<link>https://henrytapper.com/2010/01/09/an-employee-whose-job-was-to-be-sacked/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://henrytapper.com/2010/01/09/an-employee-whose-job-was-to-be-sacked/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;According to no less an authority than Danny Baker, this story is absolutely true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harrods in the sixties employed someone to be sacked- surely the best job in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently  the employee was paid to sit among the boxes on Harrods top-floor smoking his pipe and reading the Sporting Life. From time to time a bell would ring and he would be summoned to a department where an irate customer was  being mollified by the Head of the Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us say today that Lady Ponsonby-Waffles has discovered one of the precious china teacups she recently purchased is chipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Department Head greets our friend with “Lady Ponsonby-Waffles is a most valued customer, your failure to check the quality of her china cups has led to her current predicament, you sir are fired”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite Lady Ponsonby-Waffles pleas for mercy, the Head cannot be swayed. Our friend slopes disconsolately to the exit. Lady Ponsonby-Waffles drops her complaint convinced to the store’s determination to enforce the highest standards. Our friend, once passing the Department’s exit, slips back to his Sporting Life and his Pipe, to await the next occasion he would be called upon to be sacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;geo-post-640&quot; class=&quot;geo geo-post&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;latitude&quot;&gt;51.487409&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;longitude&quot;&gt;-0.607190&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-rating-enabled sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sd-block sd-rating&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Rate this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-official sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-6188255-640-5ab12f587d797&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20180319#blog_id=6188255&amp;amp;post_id=640&amp;amp;origin=henrytapper.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=6188255-640-5ab12f587d797&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-6188255-640-5ab12f587d797&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 23:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hodder</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>An employee whose job was to be sacked</og:title>
<og:url>https://henrytapper.com/2010/01/09/an-employee-whose-job-was-to-be-sacked/</og:url>
<og:description>Customer service has improved little in the last fourty years. This story demonstrates the high standards that once existed in one of our leading Department Stores.</og:description>
<og:image>https://henrytapper.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/cropped-target-pensions.png?w=200</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://henrytapper.com/2010/01/09/an-employee-whose-job-was-to-be-sacked/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Security Chief Said to Leave After Clashes Over Disinformation</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/technology/facebook-alex-stamos.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/technology/facebook-alex-stamos.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;Despite the rumors, I'm still fully engaged with my work at Facebook. It's true that my role did change. I'm currently spending more time exploring emerging security risks and working on election security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 22:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aaronbrethorst</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/technology/facebook-alex-stamos.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Alex Stamos, Facebook Data Security Chief, to Leave Amid Outcry</og:title>
<og:description>The social network was said to have reached a deal with the executive to depart after disagreements over how to address its role in spreading disinformation.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/03/20/business/20STAMOS/20STAMOS-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/technology/facebook-alex-stamos.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Use Go Interfaces</title>
<link>https://blog.chewxy.com/2018/03/18/golang-interfaces/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.chewxy.com/2018/03/18/golang-interfaces/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I occasionally give free Go consults and code review on top of my daily work. As such, I tend to read a lot of other peoples’ codes. And while this is really more of a feeling &lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;refnum&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;refbody&quot;&gt;Now, you should go, really? You're a statistician by training ffs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, I’ve seen an increase in what I call “Java-style” interface usage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog post is a Go specific recommendation from me, based on my experiences writing Go code, on how to use interfaces well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this blog post, the running example will span two packages: &lt;code&gt;animal&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;circus&lt;/code&gt;. A lot of what I write about here is about code at the boundary of packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very common thing I see people do is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;package animals 

type Animal interface {
        Speaks() string
}

// implementation of Animal
type Dog struct{}
func (a Dog) Speaks() string { return &quot;woof&quot; }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;package circus

import &quot;animals&quot;

func Perform(a animal.Animal) string { return a.Speaks() }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the so-called “Java-style” interface usage. The steps are as such:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Define an interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define one type that fulfils the interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define the methods that satisfies implementation of the interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would summarize this as “writing types to fulfil interfaces”. The artefacts of such a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_smell&quot;&gt;code smell&lt;/a&gt; is clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The most obvious of which is that it has only one type that fulfils the interface with no obvious means of extension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functions typically take concrete types instead of interface types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go interfaces encourages one to be lazy, and this is a good thing. Instead of writing types to fulfil interfaces, write interfaces to fulfil usage requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean is this - instead of defining &lt;code&gt;Animal&lt;/code&gt; in package &lt;code&gt;animals&lt;/code&gt;, define it at point of use - in package &lt;code&gt;circus&lt;/code&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;refnum&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;refbody&quot;&gt;You could of course define it in the function signature but that'd be very messy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;package animals

type Dog struct{}
func (a Dog) Speaks() string { return &quot;woof&quot; }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;package circus

type Speaker interface {
        Speaks() string
}

func Perform(a Speaker) string { return a.Speaks() }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more idiomatic way would be this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Define the types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define the interface at point of use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This way shows a reduced dependency on the components of package &lt;code&gt;animals&lt;/code&gt;. Reduced dependencies is how you build robust software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good maxim for writing good software is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robustness_principle&quot;&gt;Postel’s Law&lt;/a&gt;. It’s often said as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Be conservative with what you do, be liberal with you accept”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translated to Go, the saying is as goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Accept interfaces, return structs”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By and large, this is a very good maxim on designing things to be robust&lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;refnum&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;refbody&quot;&gt;Of course there are subtleties that I am eliding. For example, context-sensitive code would benefit very much from taking interfaces and returning interfaces&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. The main unit of code in Go is a function. The pattern to follow when designing functions/methods is the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;func funcName(a INTERFACETYPE) CONCRETETYPE 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we see we accept anything that implements an interface - could be any interface, or a blank one, and return a value that is a concrete value. Of course, there is value in constraining what &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; can be. As it goes in the Go proverbs,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;1.734693877551&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PAAkCSZUG1c&amp;amp;t=7m36s&quot;&gt;the empty interface says nothing&lt;/a&gt;“ - Rob Pike&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s preferable not to have functions take &lt;code&gt;interface{}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-case-mocking&quot;&gt;Use Case: Mocking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An excellent demonstration of the usefulness of the Postel’s Law maxim is in the case of testing. If you have a function that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;func Takes(db Database) error 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &lt;code&gt;Database&lt;/code&gt; is an interface then in testing code, you can just provide a mock implementation of &lt;code&gt;Database&lt;/code&gt; without having to pass in a real database object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, programming is pretty free form - there’s no real hard and fast rules. You can of course define an interface upfront. No correctness police is going to show up and arrest you. In the context of multiple packages, if you know your functions are going take a certain interface within the package then by all means do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining an interface upfront is usually a code smell for overengineering. But there are clearly situations where you need define an interface upfront. I can think of several:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sealed interfaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abstract data types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recursive interfaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here I shall briefly visit each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sealed-interfaces&quot;&gt;Sealed Interfaces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sealed interfaces can only be discussed in the context of having multiple packages. A sealed interface is an interface with unexported methods. This means users outside the package is unable to create types that fulfil the interface. This is useful for emulating a sum type as an exhaustive search for the types that fulfil the interface can be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what you’d define something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;type Fooer interface {
        Foo() 
        sealed()
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only the package that defined &lt;code&gt;Fooer&lt;/code&gt; can use and create any valid value of &lt;code&gt;Fooer&lt;/code&gt;. This allows for exhaustive type switches to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sealed interface also allows for analysis tools to easily pick up any non-exhaustive pattern match. In fact BurntSushi’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/go-sumtype&quot;&gt;sumtypes&lt;/a&gt; package does just that for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract-data-types&quot;&gt;Abstract Data Types&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other use of defining an interface upfront is to create a abstract data type. It may or may not be sealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;sort&lt;/code&gt; package that comes in the standard library is a good example of this. It defines a sortable collection as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;type Interface interface {
    // Len is the number of elements in the collection.
    Len() int
    // Less reports whether the element with
    // index i should sort before the element with index j.
    Less(i, j int) bool
    // Swap swaps the elements with indexes i and j.
    Swap(i, j int)
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this has made a lot of people upset - because if you want to use the &lt;code&gt;sort&lt;/code&gt; package you’d have to implement the methods for the interface, and people for the most part are upset about having to type three extra lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However in my opinion this is a very elegant form of generics in Go. It should be encouraged more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alternative design that is elegant would require higher-kinded types. We shan’t go there in this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;recursive-interfaces&quot;&gt;Recursive Interfaces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably another code smell, but there are times which are unavoidable, you &lt;del&gt;perform something within a monad and&lt;/del&gt; end up with an interface that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;type Fooer interface {
        Foo() Fooer
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recursive interface pattern would require the interface be defined upfront, clearly. The guideline of defining an interface at the point of use is inapplicable here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pattern is useful for creating contexts to operate in. Context-heavy code are usually self-contained within a package, with only the contexts exported (alá the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gorgonia.org/tensor&quot;&gt;tensor&lt;/a&gt; package), so I don’t actually see a lot of this. I’ve quite a bit more to say about contextual patterns, but I’ll leave that to another blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I have a section titled “Don’t Do This”, the purpose of this post is not meant to be proscriptive. Rather, I want to encourage people to think at the boundary conditions - that’s where all the edge cases happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally found the declare-at-point-of-use pattern extremely useful. As a result I don’t particularly run into issues that I’ve observed a number of people have run into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I however also run into cases where I end up accidentally writing Java style interfaces - typically after I come back from a stint of writing code in Python or Java. The desire to overengineer and “class all the things” something is quite strong especially when writing Go code after writing a lot of object oriented code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence this post also serves as a self-reminder on what the path to pain-free code looks like. Tell me what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nstratos&quot;&gt;Stratos Neiros&lt;/a&gt; for reviewing an earlier version of this article. And to Riteek Srivastava for picking out some bugs in the example code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 22:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>boyter</dc:creator>
<og:title>How To Use Go Interfaces</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>/2018/03/18/golang-interfaces</og:url>
<og:image>/</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.chewxy.com/2018/03/18/golang-interfaces/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>At full speed with Python: a book for self-learners</title>
<link>https://github.com/joaoventura/full-speed-python</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/joaoventura/full-speed-python</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pdf and epub files can be downloaded from: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joaoventura/full-speed-python/releases/&quot;&gt;https://github.com/joaoventura/full-speed-python/releases/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book aims to teach the basics of the python programming language using a practical approach. Its method is quite basic though: after a very simple introduction to each topic, the reader is invited to learn by solving the proposed exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These exercises have been used extensively in my web development and distributed computing classes at the Superior School of Technology of Setúbal. With these exercises, most students are up to speed with Python in less than a month. In fact, students of the distributed computing course, taught in the second year of the software engineering degree, become familiar with Python's syntax in two weeks and are able to implement a distributed client-server application with sockets in the third week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is made available in github (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joaoventura/full-speed-python&quot;&gt;https://github.com/joaoventura/full-speed-python&lt;/a&gt;) so I welcome any pull requests to correct misspellings, to suggest new exercises or clarification of the current content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pdf file is built with pdflatex, so you may need to download a latex distribution. The epub file is built with &lt;a href=&quot;http://pandoc.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 19:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jventura</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/1718359?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>joaoventura/full-speed-python</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/joaoventura/full-speed-python</og:url>
<og:description>full-speed-python - Getting up to speed with Python: a book for self-learners</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/joaoventura/full-speed-python</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Cambridge Analytica scandal isn’t a scandal: this is how Facebook works</title>
<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/voices/camridge-analytica-scandal-how-facebook-works-harvesting-data-politics-trump-brexit-a8264051.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.independent.co.uk/voices/camridge-analytica-scandal-how-facebook-works-harvesting-data-politics-trump-brexit-a8264051.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It is easy to be misled into believing that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/facebook-cambridge-analytica-millions-users-data-massachusetts-investigation-maura-healy-trump-a8261526.html&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt; story is about rogue data miners taking advantage of an innocent Facebook. Facebook’s decision to suspend Cambridge Analytica’s access, the use of terms like “data breach”, and a good deal of coverage in the media seems to follow these lines. That, however, misses the key point. This is not a data breach by any means – and nor is it something that could not have been predicted or could easily have been avoided. This is, in many ways, Cambridge Analytica using Facebook exactly as the social media platform was designed to be used. This is how Facebook works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three key parts of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/Facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook’s&lt;/a&gt; model come into play: gathering data from people in order to profile them, both &lt;em&gt;en masse&lt;/em&gt; and individually, designing systems that allow that data to be used to target people for advertising and content, then allowing third parties (generally advertisers) to use the data and those targeting systems for their own purposes. The power of these systems is often underestimated, but Facebook themselves know it, and have tested it in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have demonstrated, through their “emotional contagion” experiment in 2014, that they can make people happier or sadder, simply by manipulating the order things appear in people’s timelines. They have demonstrated that they can make people more likely to vote, testing it in the 2010 US congressional elections. They can profile people based on the most mundane of information – the sheer scale of Facebook’s user-base and the amount of information given to them means that “big data” analysis can make connections that might seem bizarre, revealing insights into intelligence, politics, ethnicity and religion without people actually discussing any of those things directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They allow advertisements to be targeted to particular “racial affinity” groups – or tailored according to “racial affinity”. Not actual race, because that might conflict with various laws, but the race that your profile suggests you have the most “affinity” towards. Racial profiling without the name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-widget-wrapper context-sdl_editor_representation type-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;Cambridge &lt;span class=&quot;scayt-misspell-word&quot; data-scayt-lang=&quot;en_GB&quot; data-scayt-word=&quot;Analytica&quot;&gt;Analytica&lt;/span&gt;: Chris Wylie tells Channel 4 News data for 50 million Facebook profiles was obtained&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all seems relatively harmless when it is just restricted to advertising for products – it might be a bit creepy to find carefully targeted advertisements for holidays in places you like or musicians you admire – but a few changes in parameters for targeting change things completely. The benefits of this profiling for electoral purposes are huge. Profiling the electorate has long been a part of political campaigning, but this makes it much more detailed, much more surreptitious, and much more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parties can target and influence voters directly; make their own supporters happier and opponents’ supporters sadder; make their own more likely to vote. They can spread stories tailored to individuals’ views, focussing on the aspects of a campaign that they know the individual cares about – both positively and negatively. When you add “fake news” to this, the situation becomes even worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the real point here. When thought about in terms of profiling and micro-targeting advertising for products, this just sounds efficient and appropriate, and harmless. It is a tiny shift, however to take this into politics – and a shift that groups like Cambridge Analytica found easy to do. All they did was understand how Facebook works, and use it. On a big scale, and in a big way, but this is how Facebook works. Profiling, targeting, persuasive manipulation are the tools of the advertiser on steroids, provably effective and available to those with the money and intent to use them. Unless Facebook changes its entire business model, it will be used in ways that interfere with our lives – and in particular that interferes with our politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is more, it is only going to get &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; effective. Facebook is gathering more data all the time – including through its associated operations in Instagram, WhatsApp and more. Its analyses are being refined and becoming more effective all the time – and more people like Cambridge Analytica are becoming aware of the possibilities and how they might be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How it might be stopped, or at least slowed down, is another matter. This is all based on the fundamental operations of Facebook, so while we rely on Facebook, it is hard to see a way out. By choosing to let ourselves become dependent, we have built this trap for ourselves. Until we find our way out of Facebook, more of this is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paul Bernal is Senior Lecturer in IT, IP and Media Law, UEA Law School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;/syndication/reuse-permission-form?url=http://www.independent.co.uk/voices/camridge-analytica-scandal-how-facebook-works-harvesting-data-politics-trump-brexit-a8264051.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;syndication-btn&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/sites/all/themes/ines_themes/independent_theme/img/reuse.png&quot; width=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;Reuse content&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 18:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>auxbuss</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Cambridge Analytica: This isn't a scandal, it's how Facebook works</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.independent.co.uk/voices/camridge-analytica-scandal-how-facebook-works-harvesting-data-politics-trump-brexit-a8264051.html</og:url>
<og:description>It is easy to be misled into believing that the Cambridge Analytica story is about rogue data miners taking advantage of an innocent Facebook. Facebook’s decision to suspend Cambridge Analytica’s access, the use of terms like “data breach”, and a good deal of coverage in the media seems to follow these lines. That, however, misses the key point.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.independent.co.uk/s3fs-public/thumbnails/image/2018/02/28/11/facebook-democracy.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.independent.co.uk/voices/camridge-analytica-scandal-how-facebook-works-harvesting-data-politics-trump-brexit-a8264051.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>