<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Woman offers WaPo false tale about Roy Moore in effort to discredit the paper</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/a-woman-approached-the-post-with-dramatic--and-false--tale-about-roy-moore-sje-appears-to-be-part-of-undercover-sting-operation/2017/11/27/0c2e335a-cfb6-11e7-9d3a-bcbe2af58c3a_story.html?tidr=a_breakingnews&amp;hpid=hp_no-name_no-name:page%2Fbreaking-news-bar</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/a-woman-approached-the-post-with-dramatic--and-false--tale-about-roy-moore-sje-appears-to-be-part-of-undercover-sting-operation/2017/11/27/0c2e335a-cfb6-11e7-9d3a-bcbe2af58c3a_story.html?tidr=a_breakingnews&amp;hpid=hp_no-name_no-name%3Apage%2Fbreaking-news-bar</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;inline-video-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Reporter Stephanie McCrummen of The Washington Post interviews Jaime Phillips at a Greek restaurant in Alexandria on Wednesday. (Dalton Bennett,Thomas LeGro/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A woman who falsely claimed to The Washington Post that Roy Moore, the Republican U.S. Senate candidate in Alabama, impregnated her as a teenager appears to work with an organization that uses deceptive tactics to secretly record conversations in an effort to embarrass its targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a series of interviews over two weeks, the woman shared a dramatic story about an alleged sexual relationship with Moore in 1992 that led to an abortion when she was 15. During the interviews, she repeatedly pressed Post reporters to give their opinions on the effects that her claims could have on Moore’s candidacy if she went public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Post did not publish an article based on her unsubstantiated account. When Post reporters confronted her with inconsistencies in her story and an Internet posting that raised doubts about her motivations, she insisted that she was not working with any organization that targets journalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But on Monday morning, Post reporters saw her walking into the New York offices of Project Veritas, an organization that targets the mainstream news media and left-leaning groups. The organization sets up undercover “stings” that involve using false cover stories and covert video recordings meant to expose what the group says is media bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James O’Keefe, the founder of Project Veritas who was convicted of a misdemeanor in 2010 for using a fake identity to enter a federal building during a previous sting, declined to answer questions about the woman outside the Project Veritas office, a storefront in Mamaroneck, N.Y., on Monday morning shortly after the woman walked inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am not doing an interview right now, so I’m not going to say a word,” O’Keefe said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;inline-video-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;James O’Keefe, the founder of Project Veritas, declined to answer questions from The Post. (Aaron Davis/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a follow-up interview, O’Keefe declined to answer repeated questions about whether the woman was employed at Project Veritas. He also did not respond when asked if he was working with Moore, former White House adviser and Moore supporter Stephen K. Bannon, or Republican strategists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group’s efforts illustrate the lengths to which activists have gone to try to discredit media outlets for reporting on allegations from multiple women that Moore pursued them when they were teenagers and he was in his early 30s. Moore has denied that he did anything improper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokesman for Moore’s campaign did not immediately respond to a message for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The woman who approached Post reporters, Jaime T. Phillips, did not respond to calls to her cellphone Monday morning. Her car remained in the Project Veritas parking lot for more than an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Phillips was observed entering the Project Veritas office, The Post made the unusual decision to report her previous off-the-record comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We always honor ‘off-the-record’ agreements when they’re entered into in good faith,” said Martin Baron, The Post’s executive editor. “But this so-called off-the-record conversation was the essence of a scheme to deceive and embarrass us. The intent by Project Veritas clearly was to publicize the conversation if we fell for the trap. Because of our customary journalistic rigor, we weren’t fooled, and we can’t honor an ‘off-the-record’ agreement that was solicited in maliciously bad faith.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phillips’s arrival at the Project Veritas office capped a weeks-long effort that began only hours after The Post published an article on Nov. 9 that included allegations that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/woman-says-roy-moore-initiated-sexual-encounter-when-she-was-14-he-was-32/2017/11/09/1f495878-c293-11e7-afe9-4f60b5a6c4a0_story.html?utm_term=.ca2d4b7a348f&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;www.washingtonpost.com&quot;&gt;Moore once initiated a sexual encounter with a 14-year-old named Leigh Corfman&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post reporter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/beth-reinhard/?utm_term=.66b196b39300&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;www.washingtonpost.com&quot;&gt;Beth Reinhard&lt;/a&gt;, who co-wrote the article about Corfman, received a cryptic email early the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Roy Moore in Alabama . . . I might know something but I need to keep myself safe. How do we do this?” the apparent tipster wrote under an account with the name “Lindsay James.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The email’s subject line was “Roy Moore in AL.” The sender’s email address included “rolltide,” the rallying cry of the University of Alabama’s sports teams, which are nicknamed the Crimson Tide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinhard sent an email asking if the person was willing to talk off the record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Not sure if I trust the phone,” came the reply. “Can we just stick to email?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I need to be confident that you can protect me before I will tell all,” the person wrote in a subsequent email. “I have stuff I’ve been hiding for a long time but maybe it should stay that way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tipster’s email came amid counterattacks by Moore supporters aimed at The Post and its reporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That same day, Gateway Pundit, a conservative site, spread a false story from a Twitter account, @umpire43, that said, “A family friend in Alabama just told my wife that a WAPO reporter named Beth offer her 1000$ to accuse Roy Moore.” The Twitter account, which has a history of spreading misinformation, has since been deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Post, like many other news organizations, has a strict policy against paying people for information and did not do so in its coverage of Moore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Nov. 14, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/politics/wp/2017/11/14/alabama-pastor-says-man-posing-as-washington-post-reporter-offered-reward-for-dirt-on-roy-moore/?utm_term=.d051ed8bf4f4&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;www.washingtonpost.com&quot;&gt;pastor in Alabama said he received a voice mail&lt;/a&gt; from a man falsely claiming to be a Post reporter and seeking women “willing to make damaging remarks” about Moore for money. No one associated with The Post made any such call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days that followed the purported tipster’s initial emails, Reinhard communicated with the woman through an encrypted text messaging service and spoke by phone with the person to set up a meeting. When the woman suggested a meeting in New York, Reinhard told her she would have to know more about her story and her background. The woman offered that her real name was Jaime Phillips. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phillips said she lived in New York but would be in the D.C. area during Thanksgiving week and suggested meeting Tuesday in a shopping mall in Tysons Corner, Va. “I’m planning to do some shopping there so I’ll find a good place to meet before you get there,” Phillips wrote in a message sent via Signal, the encrypted messaging service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Reinhard suggested bringing another reporter, Phillips wrote, “I’m not really comfortable with anyone else being there this time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinhard arrived to find Phillips, wearing a brown leather jacket and with long red hair, already seated in a booth in the restaurant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 41-year-old said she had been abused as a child, Reinhard said. Her family had moved often. She said she moved in with an aunt in the Talladega area of Alabama and started attending a church youth group when she met Moore in 1992, the year he became a county judge. She said she was 15. She said they started a “secret” sexual relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I knew it wasn’t right, but I didn’t care,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said that she got pregnant, that Moore talked her into an abortion, and that he drove her to Mississippi to get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interview, she told Reinhard that she was so upset she couldn’t finish her salad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phillips said she had started thinking about coming forward after the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/style/violence-threats-begging-harvey-weinsteins-30-year-pattern-of-abuse-in-hollywood/2017/10/14/2638b1fc-aeab-11e7-be94-fabb0f1e9ffb_story.html?utm_term=.6e14c6effffb&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;www.washingtonpost.com&quot;&gt;allegations about Hollywood film producer Harvey Weinstein surfaced&lt;/a&gt;. Then she said she saw the news about Moore flashing across the television screen while in a break room at her job at a company called NFM Lending in Westchester County, N.Y., Reinhard said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phillips also repeatedly asked the reporter to guarantee her that Moore would lose the election if she came forward. Reinhard told her in a subsequent text message that she could not predict what the impact would be. Reinhard said she also explained to Phillips that her claims would have to be fact-checked. Additionally, Reinhard asked her for documents that would corroborate or support her story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that day, Phillips told Reinhard that she felt “anxiety &amp;amp; negative energy after our meeting,” text messages show. “You just didn’t convince me that I should come forward,” she wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinhard replied, “I’m so sorry but I want to be straight with you about the fact-checking process and the fact that we can’t guarantee what will happen as a result of another story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phillips was not satisfied. On Wednesday, the day before Thanksgiving, she suggested meeting with another Post reporter, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/stephanie-mccrummen/?utm_term=.82f007923db8&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;www.washingtonpost.com&quot;&gt;Stephanie McCrummen&lt;/a&gt;, who co-wrote the initial article about Corfman. “I’d rather go to another paper than talk to you again,” Phillips told Reinhard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the newsroom, Reinhard became concerned about elements of Phillips’s story. Phillips had said she lived in Alabama only for a summer while a teenager; but the cellphone number Phillips provided had an Alabama area code. Reinhard called NFM Lending in Westchester County, but they said a person named Jaime Phillips did not work there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice Crites, a Post researcher who was looking into Phillips’s background, found the document that strongly reinforced the reporters’ suspicions: a Web page for a fundraising campaign by someone with the same name. It was on the website GoFundMe.com under the name Jaime Phillips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_1484w/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2017/11/27/Investigative/Images/Croppedscreencapture-web-archive-org-web-20171122195050-https-www-gofundme-com-JaimeToNewYork-1511803913298.jpg?uuid=iR5ZotOkEee2Ldk0XO2JbQ&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_480w/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2017/11/27/Investigative/Images/Croppedscreencapture-web-archive-org-web-20171122195050-https-www-gofundme-com-JaimeToNewYork-1511803913298.jpg?uuid=iR5ZotOkEee2Ldk0XO2JbQ&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/rw/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2017/11/27/Investigative/Images/Croppedscreencapture-web-archive-org-web-20171122195050-https-www-gofundme-com-JaimeToNewYork-1511803913298.jpg?uuid=iR5ZotOkEee2Ldk0XO2JbQ&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_60w/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2017/11/27/Investigative/Images/Croppedscreencapture-web-archive-org-web-20171122195050-https-www-gofundme-com-JaimeToNewYork-1511803913298.jpg?uuid=iR5ZotOkEee2Ldk0XO2JbQ&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;The GoFundMe fundraising page. (Internet Archive)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m moving to New York!” the May 29 appeal said. “I’ve accepted a job to work in the conservative media movement to combat the lies and deceipt of the liberal MSM. I’ll be using my skills as a researcher and fact-checker to help our movement. I was laid off from my mortgage job a few months ago and came across the opportunity to change my career path.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a March posting on its Facebook page, Project Veritas said it was seeking 12 new “undercover reporters,” though the organization’s operatives use methods that are eschewed by mainstream journalists, such as misrepresenting themselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A posting for the “journalist” job on the Project Veritas website that month warned that the job “is not a role for the faint of heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The job’s listed goal: “To adopt an alias persona, gain access to an identified person of interest and persuade that person to reveal information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also listed tasks that the job applicant should be able to master, including: “Learning a script,” “Preparing a background story to support your role,” “Gaining an appointment or access to the target of the investigation,” and “Operating concealed recording equipment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Veritas, founded in 2010, is a tax-exempt charity that says its mission is to “investigate and expose corruption, dishonesty, self-dealing, waste, fraud and other misconduct.” It raised $4.8 million and employed 38 people in 2016, according to its public tax filing. It also had 92 volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Keefe’s criminal record has caused the charity problems in some states. Mississippi and Utah stripped the group of a license to raise money in those states because it failed to disclose O’Keefe’s conviction on state applications, records show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also working at Veritas is former television producer Robert J. Halderman, who was sentenced to six months in jail in 2010 after he was accused of trying to blackmail late-night host David Letterman. Halderman was with O’Keefe outside the Project Veritas offices Monday as a reporter tried to ask about Phillips’s role with the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Jaime Phillips is a relatively common name, it wasn’t a certainty that the GoFundMe page that Crites found was created by was the same woman who approached The Post. But there was another telling detail, in addition to the name. One of two donations listed on the page was from a person whose name that matched her daughter’s, according to public records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCrummen agreed to meet Phillips that afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phillips suggested meeting somewhere in Alexandria, Va., saying she was shopping in the area. Post videographers accompanied McCrummen, who brought a printout of the fundraising page to the interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, Phillips had arrived early and was waiting for McCrummen, her purse resting on the table. When McCrummen put her purse near Phillips’s purse to block a possible camera, Phillips moved hers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Post videographers sat separately, unnoticed, at an adjacent table. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phillips said she didn’t want to get into the details of what she had said happened between her and Moore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said she wanted McCrummen to assure her that the article would result in Moore’s defeat, according to a recording. McCrummen instead asked her about her story regarding Moore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phillips complained that President Trump had endorsed Moore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So my whole thing is, like, I want him to be completely taken out of the race . . . ” she said. “And I really expected that was going to happen, and now it’s not. So, I don’t know what you think about that.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCrummen asked Phillips to verify her identity with a photo identification. Phillips provided a Georgia driver’s license. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCrummen then asked her about the GoFundMe page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have a process of doing background, checking backgrounds and this kind of thing, so I wanted to ask you about one thing,” McCrummen said, pulling out a copy of the page and reading from it. “So I just wanted to ask you if you could explain this, and I also wanted to let you know, Jaime, that this is being recorded and video recorded.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Okay,” Phillips said. “Um, yeah, I was looking to take a job last summer in New York, but it fell through,” Phillips said. “Yeah, it was going to be with the Daily Caller, but it ended up falling through, so I wasn’t able to do it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asked who at the Daily Caller interviewed her, Phillips said, “Kathy,” pausing before adding the last name, “Johnson.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Conner, executive editor of the Daily Caller, said Monday that no one with the name Kathy Johnson works for the publication and that he has no record of having personally interviewed Phillips. Conner later said in email that he had asked other top editors at the Daily Caller and the affiliated Daily Caller News Foundation about Phillips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“None of us has interviewed a woman by the name Jaime Phillips,” Conner wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Alexandria restaurant on Wednesday, Phillips also told The Post that she had not been in contact with the Moore campaign. As the interview ended, Phillips told McCrummen she was not recording the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think I probably just want to cancel and not go through with it at this point,” Phillips said at Souvlaki Bar shortly before ending the interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m not going to answer any more questions,” she said. “I think I’m just going to go.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She picked up her coat and bag, returned her drink to the front counter and left the restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 7 p.m. the message on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20171122195050/https:/www.gofundme.com/JaimeToNewYork&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;web.archive.org&quot;&gt;GoFundMe page&lt;/a&gt; was gone, replaced by a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Campaign is complete and no longer active,” it read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas LeGro and Dalton Bennett contributed to this report.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 21:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fmihaila</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/a-woman-approached-the-post-with-dramatic--and-false--tale-about-roy-moore-sje-appears-to-be-part-of-undercover-sting-operation/2017/11/27/0c2e335a-cfb6-11e7-9d3a-bcbe2af58c3a_story.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_1484w/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2017/11/27/Others/Images/2017-11-27/FAKEACCUSER.jpg?t=20170517</og:image>
<og:title>A woman approached The Post with dramatic — and false — tale about Roy Moore. She appears to be part of undercover sting operation.</og:title>
<og:description>Jaime Phillips, who claimed to The Post that Moore impregnated her as a teenager, was seen on Monday walking into the headquarters of Project Veritas, a group that uses false cover stories and covert video recordings to expose what it says is media bias.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/a-woman-approached-the-post-with-dramatic--and-false--tale-about-roy-moore-sje-appears-to-be-part-of-undercover-sting-operation/2017/11/27/0c2e335a-cfb6-11e7-9d3a-bcbe2af58c3a_story.html?tidr=a_breakingnews&amp;hpid=hp_no-name_no-name:page%2Fbreaking-news-bar</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Romanian Facebook users see their protests-related content reviewed and blocked</title>
<link>http://www.business-review.eu/news/certain-facebook-users-in-romania-see-content-related-to-street-protests-reviewed-under-community-standards-153255</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.business-review.eu/news/certain-facebook-users-in-romania-see-content-related-to-street-protests-reviewed-under-community-standards-153255</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A series of Romanian bloggers, vloggers, journalists and other influencers alongside regular Facebook users said they had issues posting or sharing on Facebook content related to the street protests that took place on Sunday evening across the major cities.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dragos Stanca, managing partner digital consultancy ThinkDigital, gathered on his Facebook page print screens from users who showed the messages they got from the social media behemoth. Among those hit by restrictions there were Facebook users posting live feeds from the protests and even those sharing media pieces about the marches. Some users weren’t able to share events created on Facebook for the street protests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common notification from Facebook was that the post was under review to see if it breached the community standards. Other posts about the protests were suspected by Facebook of being spam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tens of thousands of Romanians &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.business-review.eu/featured/anti-judiciary-laws-protests-in-romania-tens-of-thousands-call-for-resignation-of-government-153178&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;marched in the main cities&lt;/a&gt;, asking the ruling coalition PSD-ALDE to drop controversial amendments to the judiciary. Around 20,000 took to the streets of Bucharest, also calling for the resignation of the center left government led by Mihai Tudose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some of the posts under review by Facebook.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-153256&quot; src=&quot;http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/23916458_1464545530310695_2609633505077512876_o-169x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;169&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/23916458_1464545530310695_2609633505077512876_o-169x300.jpg 169w, http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/23916458_1464545530310695_2609633505077512876_o-576x1024.jpg 576w, http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/23916458_1464545530310695_2609633505077512876_o-113x200.jpg 113w, http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/23916458_1464545530310695_2609633505077512876_o-42x75.jpg 42w, http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/23916458_1464545530310695_2609633505077512876_o.jpg 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-153257&quot; src=&quot;http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/24058999_10215359442207825_7655472908141260597_n-228x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;228&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/24058999_10215359442207825_7655472908141260597_n-228x300.jpg 228w, http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/24058999_10215359442207825_7655472908141260597_n-152x200.jpg 152w, http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/24058999_10215359442207825_7655472908141260597_n-57x75.jpg 57w, http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/24058999_10215359442207825_7655472908141260597_n.jpg 585w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 228px) 100vw, 228px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-153258&quot; src=&quot;http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/24068065_1716272545074112_3622703833671592893_n-264x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;264&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/24068065_1716272545074112_3622703833671592893_n-264x300.jpg 264w, http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/24068065_1716272545074112_3622703833671592893_n-155x176.jpg 155w, http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/24068065_1716272545074112_3622703833671592893_n-66x75.jpg 66w, http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/24068065_1716272545074112_3622703833671592893_n.jpg 521w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 264px) 100vw, 264px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 20:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>paganel</dc:creator>
<og:title>Certain Facebook users in Romania see content related to street protests reviewed under community standards</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.business-review.eu/news/certain-facebook-users-in-romania-see-content-related-to-street-protests-reviewed-under-community-standards-153255</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>A series of Romanian bloggers, vloggers, journalists and other influencers alongside regular Facebook users said they had issues posting or sharing on Facebook content related to the street protests that took place on Sunday evening across the major cities. Dragos Stanca, managing partner digital</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.business-review.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/facebook-community-standards.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.business-review.eu/news/certain-facebook-users-in-romania-see-content-related-to-street-protests-reviewed-under-community-standards-153255</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook censored people protesting a corrupt government</title>
<link>https://dorinlazar.ro/the-strange-case-of-facebook-censoring-people-protesting-a-corrupt-government/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://dorinlazar.ro/the-strange-case-of-facebook-censoring-people-protesting-a-corrupt-government/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The strangest thing happened yesterday, during the biggest mass protests against the corrupt government in Romania. One of the most well known online personalities, a&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mariciu.ro/echipa-eficienta-de-social-media/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; prolific local vlogger, Marian Ionescu&lt;/a&gt;, has seen his Facebook account reported for spamming, and was unable to post on his profile, to tell his friends about his participation to the protests.&lt;span id=&quot;more-12400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12401&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;12401&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://dorinlazar.ro/the-strange-case-of-facebook-censoring-people-protesting-a-corrupt-government/cica-spam/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://dorinlazar.ro/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/cica-spam.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1343,1417&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;cica-spam&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://dorinlazar.ro/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/cica-spam.png&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://dorinlazar.ro/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/cica-spam.png&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-12401&quot; src=&quot;https://dorinlazar.ro/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/cica-spam.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1343&quot; height=&quot;1417&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mariciu.ro/echipa-eficienta-de-social-media/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;See the story on his site (Romanian)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was not alone – in fact, hundreds others have seen their accounts marked as spamming, although all they did was post about their participation in the protests. After Dragoș Stanca asked people if they seen similar behavior, hundreds confirmed that their accounts have been reported for spam as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12402&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;12402&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://dorinlazar.ro/the-strange-case-of-facebook-censoring-people-protesting-a-corrupt-government/plin-de-spam-in-romania/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://dorinlazar.ro/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/plin-de-spam-in-romania.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2530,1438&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;plin-de-spam-in-romania&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://dorinlazar.ro/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/plin-de-spam-in-romania.jpg&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://dorinlazar.ro/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/plin-de-spam-in-romania.jpg&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-12402&quot; src=&quot;https://dorinlazar.ro/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/plin-de-spam-in-romania.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2530&quot; height=&quot;1438&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mariciu.ro/echipa-eficienta-de-social-media/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Again from Marian Ionescu’s site (Romanian)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is strange as it comes with a deeper context. For the past weeks, several accounts of prolific, influential social media personalities have been suspended for various reasons. People like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dailycotcodac.ro/posts/1721278084581917&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Julius Constantinescu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cabalinkabul.wordpress.com/2017/11/17/ipocrizia-fb-si-sfarsitul-democratiei-pe-internet/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Dan Alexe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://eftimie.net/banati-facebook-unde-suntem/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Ovidiu Eftimie&lt;/a&gt;, and others have been suspended for up to 30 days for posts that apparently don’t respect the Facebook Community Guideline, although some were penalized for posts made in 2009 – that’s 8 years ago. For some reason, it seems that Romanian Facebook users community has been put under the microscope lens and a sweep of „unruly elements” has been performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And everyone starts to be very upset about this. In the past years, Facebook has become more and more ubiquitous, and can now be named the de-facto „agora”, the place where people meet to discuss whatever goes on in the country, from silly things like memes about a goofy thing some actor said to political stances and mobilization for protests against the Romanian government corrupt policies. And for some reason, all the banning in the recent Facebook campaign goes towards what people perceive as „opposition voices” – people who engage in political discussions and are seen as critics of the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So naturally words like „censorship” are thrown around, and people feel that what they perceived as a platform to enable free speech is now collaborating with a corrupt government. No official answer has been offered by Facebook to the many inquiries raised by the users affected by this new vindictive facet of the social network.  Facebook ignores any attempt to get a real answer from real people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all aware that Facebook is a private enterprise, even if publicly owned. I do understand that the users are not share holders, and their opinion might not matter. But it’s strange to see what we used to perceive as a platform that will guarantee freedom of expression suddenly turning on free speech with foul reports. I understand that the issue might not even be political – it might be a simple technical issue, a bug that would allow a small team of very determined people to report and therefore block any valid account just because they don’t like what they say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But without an answer from Facebook, we can only suspect that we’re being, in a sense, betrayed. That Facebook is somehow aiding the government to start their own small censorship racket. Of course, we are the fools, for relying so much on the social network. Until then, the Romanians that try to fight corruption are not welcome on Facebook – and they’ll have to go some other places to talk among themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 20:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dcro</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The strange case of Facebook censoring people protesting a corrupt government</og:title>
<og:url>https://dorinlazar.ro/the-strange-case-of-facebook-censoring-people-protesting-a-corrupt-government/</og:url>
<og:description>The strangest thing happened yesterday, during the biggest mass protests against the corrupt government in Romania. One of the most well known online personalities, a prolific local vlogger, Marian…</og:description>
<og:image>https://dorinlazar.ro/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/cica-spam.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://dorinlazar.ro/the-strange-case-of-facebook-censoring-people-protesting-a-corrupt-government/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>American Equity</title>
<link>http://blog.samaltman.com/american-equity</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.samaltman.com/american-equity</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’d like feedback on the following idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that every adult US citizen should get an annual share of the US GDP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that owning something like a share in America would align all of us in making the country as successful as possible—the better the country does, the better everyone does—and give more people a fair shot at achieving the life they want.  And we all work together to create the system that generates so much prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that a new social contract like what I’m suggesting here—where we agree to a floor and no ceiling—would lead to a huge increase in US prosperity and keep us in the global lead.  Countries that concentrate wealth in a small number of families do worse over the long term—if we don’t take a radical step toward a fair, inclusive system, we will not be the leading country in the world for much longer.  This would harm all Americans more than most realize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are historical examples of countries giving out land to citizens (such as the Homestead Acts in the US) as a way to distribute the resources people needed to succeed.  Today, the fundamental input to wealth generation isn’t farmland, but money and ideas—you really do need money to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Equity would also cushion the transition from the jobs of today to the jobs of tomorrow.  Automation holds the promise of creating more abundance than we ever dreamed possible, but it’s going to significantly change how we think about work.  If everyone benefits more directly from economic growth, then it will be easier to move faster toward this better world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default case for automation is to concentrate wealth (and therefore power) in a tiny number of hands.  America has repeatedly found ways to challenge this sort of concentration, and we need to do so again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The joint-stock company was one of the most important inventions in human history.  It allowed us to align a lot of people in pursuit of a common goal and accomplish things no individual could.  Obviously, the US is not a company, but I think a similar model can work for the US as well as it does for companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A proposal like this obviously requires a lot of new funding [1] to do at large scale, but I think we could start very small—a few hundred dollars per citizen per year—and ramp it up to a long-term target of 10-20% of GDP per year when the GDP per capita doubles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no delusions about the challenges of such a program.  There would be difficult consequences for things like immigration policy that will need a lot of discussion.  We’d also need to figure out rules about transferability and borrowing against this equity.  And we’d need to set it up in a way that does not exacerbate short-term thinking or favor unsustainable growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as the economy grows, we could imagine a world in which every American would have their basic needs guaranteed.  Absolute poverty would be eliminated, and we would no longer motivate people through the fear of not being able to eat.  In addition to being the obviously right thing to do, eliminating poverty will increase productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Equity would create a society that I believe would work much better than what we have today.  It would free Americans to work on what they really care about, improve social cohesion, and incentivize everyone to think about ways to grow the whole pie.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[1] It’s time to update our tax system for the way wealth works in the modern world—for example, taxing capital and labor at the same rates.  And we should consider eventually replacing some of our current aid programs, which distort incentives and are needlessly complicated and inefficient, with something like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this won’t solve all our problems—we still need serious reform in areas such as housing, education, and healthcare.  Without policies that address the cost of living crisis, any sort of redistribution will be far less effective than it otherwise could be.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nebula</dc:creator>
<og:title>American Equity</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://blog.samaltman.com/american-equity</og:url>
<og:description>I’d like feedback on the following idea. I think that every adult US citizen should get an annual share of the US GDP. I believe that owning something like a share in America would align all of...</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.samaltman.com/american-equity</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Norvig&amp;#039;s Python programs to practice or demonstrate skills</title>
<link>https://github.com/norvig/pytudes</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/norvig/pytudes</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;An &lt;em&gt;étude&lt;/em&gt; (a French word meaning &lt;em&gt;study&lt;/em&gt;) is an instrumental musical composition, usually short, of considerable difficulty, and designed to provide practice material for perfecting a particular musical skill.&quot; — &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%89tude&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project contains &lt;strong&gt;pytudes&lt;/strong&gt;—Python programs for perfecting programming skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some are in Jupyter (IPython) notebooks, some in *.py files.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I got the idea for the &quot;etudes&quot; part of the name from this &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books/about/Etudes_for_programmers.html?id=u89WAAAAMAAJ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;1978 book by Charles Wetherell&lt;/a&gt; that was very influential to me when I was learning to program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/3f08a9e787adadcb78fa75a25bbae4c435c7f84a/68747470733a2f2f696d616765732d6e612e73736c2d696d616765732d616d617a6f6e2e636f6d2f696d616765732f492f35315a6e5a48323964764c2e5f53583339345f424f312c3230342c3230332c3230305f2e6a7067&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/3f08a9e787adadcb78fa75a25bbae4c435c7f84a/68747470733a2f2f696d616765732d6e612e73736c2d696d616765732d616d617a6f6e2e636f6d2f696d616765732f492f35315a6e5a48323964764c2e5f53583339345f424f312c3230342c3230332c3230305f2e6a7067&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/51ZnZH29dvL._SX394_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 13:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>federicoponzi</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/4370220?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>norvig/pytudes</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/norvig/pytudes</og:url>
<og:description>pytudes - Python programs to practice or demonstrate skills.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/norvig/pytudes</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Asking members to support journalism, The Guardian raises more revenue than ads</title>
<link>http://www.niemanlab.org/2017/11/asking-members-to-support-its-journalism-no-prizes-no-swag-the-guardian-raises-more-reader-revenue-than-ad-dollars/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.niemanlab.org/2017/11/asking-members-to-support-its-journalism-no-prizes-no-swag-the-guardian-raises-more-reader-revenue-than-ad-dollars/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of using tote bags, tickets to live events, or other swag, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;‘s &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.theguardian.com/us/contribute?acquisitionData&quot;&gt;membership program&lt;/a&gt; has grown to 800,000 supporters a year and a half after doubling down on its membership initiative. The key? A shift from a commercially focused plea to an emotional, service-based request, the two women leading the effort said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our appeal is very much an appeal from The Guardian,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/amichel&quot;&gt;Amanda Michel&lt;/a&gt;, deputy executive editor of membership and senior product manager for acquisitions and data technology, said. “It doesn’t speak to the section they’re in. It doesn’t speak to what they read. It speaks to the heart of the Guardian’s moment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-relatedstory&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;embed-relatedstory-imagelink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2015/04/newsonomics-the-guardian-is-trying-to-swing-googles-pendulum-back-to-publishers/?relatedstory&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;315&quot; height=&quot;177&quot; src=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/images/google-sign-cc-315x177.jpg&quot; class=&quot;embed-relatedstory-image wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/images/google-sign-cc-315x177.jpg 315w, http://www.niemanlab.org/images/google-sign-cc-220x124.jpg 220w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 315px) 100vw, 315px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
Financial difficulties struck The Guardian, the London-based, trust-owned international news organization, in recent years, with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2015/04/newsonomics-the-guardian-is-trying-to-swing-googles-pendulum-back-to-publishers/&quot;&gt;print-to-digital advertising downturn&lt;/a&gt; that wracked news industries around the world. It had also taken on an ambitious plan to expand internationally following its coverage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/the-nsa-files&quot;&gt;Edward Snowden’s NSA files&lt;/a&gt; and subsequent Pulitzer in 2014. That ambition didn’t quite follow through — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/stevenperlberg/how-the-guardian-lost-america&quot;&gt;Buzzfeed reported in June&lt;/a&gt; that “the thirst for global expansion was so strong, in fact, that the Guardian’s former US CEO says he was pressured to make unattainable business projections to fuel the growth.” Those figures included $15.5 million in revenue from April 2015-16 amid more than $15 million in operating losses with a revenue target of $32.2 million for 2016-2017. Faced with the heat of digital advertising and ad-blocking software, the Guardian focused on shaking things up.

The organization offers subscriptions and, as of this past summer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2017/08/could-the-guardians-quest-for-philanthropic-support-squeeze-out-other-news-nonprofits/&quot;&gt;a philanthropic arm&lt;/a&gt; as well, but turned to membership in 2014 to draw readers further in and bolster its grassroots support rather than instituting a paywall. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/gnm-press-office/2015/jan/29/andrew-miller-steps-down-as-chief-executive-of-guardian-media-group&quot;&gt;Former Guardian Media Group CEO Andrew Miller&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2014/02/ceo-andrew-miller-membership-type-propositions-will-be-key-to-the-guardians-revenue-growth/&quot;&gt;explained the mindset&lt;/a&gt; at the time:
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Will it be a wall between the reader and the content? No, it won’t be. It’ll be adding more value for people who want to get more involved in the Guardian, who feel passionate about the Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recognize we have to get more direct-to-consumer revenue over time, and the way we will do that is through membership-type propositions, but it’s going to be much more than a paywall. A paywall is to me an inverse loyalty scheme, where the more you consume the more you pay, which doesn’t seem to work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2016, The Guardian re-emphasized the potential of the membership program while embarking on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2016/01/as-the-guardian-cuts-50m-it-plans-to-build-on-its-membership-program/&quot;&gt;cutting spree of 20 percent&lt;/a&gt;, about 50 million pounds, from its budget over three years. The “enhanced membership offer” aims to double reader revenues, according to a Guardian press release detailing the cost-cutting breakdown. Around this time, “a small cross-functional team made up of editorial, commercial, UX and engineers began to reimagine what the membership scheme could be when rooted in the Guardian’s journalism,” Michel said. She and membership executive editor &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NatalieHanman&quot;&gt;Natalie Hanman&lt;/a&gt; transitioned within their Guardian roles to focus on membership. (Michel had joined the Guardian in 2011 as open editor, bringing her experience from ProPublica and Huffington Post with skills in community engagement, and Hanman was editor at the Guardian’s opinion site.) Twelve thousand members had already signed up, but the membership system largely centered on in-person events — not exactly encouraging anyone outside of London to become a member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was in April last year that Amanda and I did the first experiment basically using a carrot, not a stick, to support the Guardian’s journalism,” Hanman said, explaining that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/series/panama-papers&quot;&gt;Panama Papers investigation&lt;/a&gt; was the first test of some of those ideas. “We were really drawing the link between time and effort and skill we put into that investigation, working with these organizations around the world and asking people if you value this, please contribute toward this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2016, reader revenues — that’s memberships, subscriptions, newsstand sales, and one-time contributions — comprised more of the Guardian’s revenue than advertising dollars did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, editor-in-chief &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KathViner&quot;&gt;Katharine Viner&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/membership/2017/oct/26/together-we-are-safeguarding-the-guardians-independent-journalism?CMP=Share_iOSApp_Other&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that financial support from readers had officially surpassed advertising revenue, noting that 500,000 individuals contributed monthly to the Guardian as members and print/digital subscribers and another 300,000 one-time donations have added to the organization’s coffers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are encouraged and cheered by the hundreds of thousands of you who are supporting our journalism. In the last year alone, the number of readers who support us regularly has more than doubled, and we now receive more income from our readers than we do from advertisers. This is a significant step,” Viner wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digiday.com/media/guardian-wsj-two-approaches-membership/&quot;&gt;In its infancy&lt;/a&gt;, the membership program had invited readers to become “friends” for free while paying for events, “partners” for £15 (US $19.79) per month with discounts to ticketed events, and “patrons” for £60, with the aforementioned discounts and access to Guardian newsroom events. Now, however, readers can join as “supporters” for £5 per month with ticket access, “partners” for £15 per month that includes tickets to Guardian Live events or Guardian-published books and a welcome gift, or “patrons” or £60 per month with the other benefits plus access to “exclusive, behind-the-scenes” events. But Michel and Hamnan credit the events for catalyzing change and restoring energy to the membership drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because readers outside of London didn’t have much incentive to attend Guardian events at the newsroom in the city and the Guardian was making this international thrust, it didn’t make sense to push that as central to the journalism organization’s pitch when readers and reporters, editors, and designers could interact in more multidimensional ways. The pair revamped both the ask and the offerings — moving from 12,000 members in the beginning of 2016 to, today, 300,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A surprising number of readers also didn’t understand the financial struggles plaguing print journalistic organizations of all sizes, Hanman and Michel said. By placing an appeal on the Panama Papers articles in April 2016, “we were really drawing that link between time and effort and skill we put into that investigation, working with these organizations around the world, and asking people if you value this please contribute toward this,” Natalie said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The request at the foot of Guardian articles today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;nakedboxedimage&quot; src=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/images/guardian-membership-ask.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;491&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our marketing colleagues…are used to using one line [pitches] to advertise membership,” with a focus on pithiness and wit, Hanman said. “The longer appeal resonates with people more. We need to explain to people why we are pursuing this approach. Even as journalists used to writing snappy headlines, we need to take a bit more time here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from intricate investigations like the Panama and the more recent Paradise Papers revelations, the Guardian’s membership spiked following coverage on the environment, Brexit, and the U.K. election. Some members even double-dipped and made more donations as new reporting emerged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Quite a few readers had already supported the Guardian, and they wanted to give again,” Michel said. “A pretty significant percentage of them were educators. This was a way for them to ensure that the public could be well informed on a topic that they felt should be in the public domain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members’ responses to topics validate time and attention spent by the editorial staff to the stories on that beat. The reader feedback creates a looped “work-and-learn approach” while also validating Guardian coverage, Michel said. But this work requires feeding the beast in a different way: “We want to keep growing our base but making sure the 800,000 supporters we have feel valued,” Hanman said. “If they want to have a close relationship with us, we develop it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engagement with Guardian members includes a weekly newsletter to supporters, a weekly “behind the scenes” story production series, a Q&amp;amp;A with a columnist, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/membership/series/we-need-to-talk-about&quot;&gt;even a podcast based on supporters’ calls and questions&lt;/a&gt;. Hanman and Michel said the next goal is not based on reaching another metric milestone, but on delving further into reader relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The last year has really been a foundational year,” Michel said. “It’s about creating a network of colleagues across the Guardian to develop essentially a shared experience and expertise. Now that we have the foundation we can start becoming more creative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’ve moved away from the traditional transactional model to a more emotional one that’s rooted in our journalism,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photocredit&quot; readability=&quot;7.9306930693069&quot;&gt;Image of the US Guardian membership certificate by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MonaChalabi&quot;&gt;Mona Chalabi&lt;/a&gt; used with permission of the Guardian.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 12:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gk1</dc:creator>
<og:title>Asking members to support its journalism (no prizes, no swag), The Guardian raises more reader revenue than ad dollars</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>http://www.niemanlab.org/images/guardianmembership-700x396.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://www.niemanlab.org/2017/11/asking-members-to-support-its-journalism-no-prizes-no-swag-the-guardian-raises-more-reader-revenue-than-ad-dollars/</og:url>
<og:description>The Guardian revamped its ask and its membership offerings — moving from 12,000 members in the beginning of 2016 to 300,000 today.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.niemanlab.org/2017/11/asking-members-to-support-its-journalism-no-prizes-no-swag-the-guardian-raises-more-reader-revenue-than-ad-dollars/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Laptops Are Great, But Not During a Lecture or a Meeting</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/22/business/laptops-not-during-lecture-or-meeting.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/22/business/laptops-not-during-lecture-or-meeting.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;190&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1752&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;Researchers can solve that problem by randomly assigning some students to use laptops. With that approach, the students who use laptops are comparable in all other ways to those who don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;332&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2084&quot;&gt;In a series of experiments at Princeton University and the University of California, Los Angeles, students were randomly assigned either laptops or pen and paper for note-taking at a lecture. Those who had used laptops had substantially &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.udel.edu/victorp/files/2010/11/Psychological-Science-2014-Mueller-0956797614524581-1u0h0yu.pdf&quot;&gt;worse&lt;/a&gt; understanding of the lecture, as measured by a standardized test, than those who did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;548&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2632&quot;&gt;The researchers hypothesized that, because students can type faster than they can write, the lecturer’s words flowed right to the students’ typing fingers without stopping in their brains for substantive processing. Students writing by hand had to process and condense the spoken material simply to enable their pens to keep up with the lecture. Indeed, the notes of the laptop users more closely resembled transcripts than lecture summaries. The handwritten versions were more succinct but included the salient issues discussed in the lecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;231&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2863&quot;&gt;Even so, it may seem heavy-handed to ban electronics in the classroom. Most college students are legal adults who can serve in the armed forces, vote and own property. Why shouldn’t they decide themselves whether to use a laptop?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;608&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3471&quot;&gt;The strongest argument against allowing that choice is that one student’s use of a laptop harms the learning of students around them. In a series of lab experiments, researchers at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yorku.ca/index.html&quot;&gt;York&lt;/a&gt; University and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcmaster.ca/&quot;&gt;McMaster&lt;/a&gt; University in Canada tested the effect of laptops on students who weren’t using them. Some students were told to perform small tasks on their laptops unrelated to the lecture, like looking up movie times. As expected, these students retained less of the lecture material. But what is really interesting is that the learning of students seated near the laptop users was also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360131512002254?via%3Dihub&quot;&gt;negatively affected&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;513&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3984&quot;&gt;The economic term for such a spillover is a “negative externality,” which occurs when one person’s consumption harms the well-being of others. The classic negative externality is pollution: A factory burning coal or a car using gasoline can harm the air and environment for those around it. A laptop can sometimes be a form of visual pollution: Those nearby see its screen, and their attention is pulled toward its enticements, which often include not just note-taking but Facebook, Twitter, email and news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;237&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4221&quot;&gt;These experiments go only so far. They may not capture positive effects of laptops in real classrooms over the course of a semester, when students use their typed notes for review and grades are at stake. But another study did just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;528&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4749&quot;&gt;At the United States Military Academy, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0272775716303454&quot;&gt;team of professors&lt;/a&gt; studied laptop use in an introductory economics class. The course was taught in small sections, which the researchers randomly assigned to one of three conditions: electronics allowed, electronics banned and tablets allowed but only if laid flat on desks, where professors could monitor their use. By the end of the semester, students in the classrooms with laptops or tablets had performed substantially worse than those in the sections where electronics were banned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/22/business/laptops-not-during-lecture-or-meeting.html#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;528&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5277&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;You might question whether the experience of military cadets learning economics is relevant to students in other settings — say, community college students learning Shakespeare. But we’d expect the negative effects of laptops to be, if anything, less at West Point, where all courses are taught in small sections, than it is at institutions with many large lectures. Further, cadets have very strong incentives to perform well and avoid distractions, since class rank has a major impact on their job status after graduation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;213&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5490&quot;&gt;The best way to settle this question is probably to study laptop use in more colleges. But until then, I find the evidence sufficiently compelling that I’ve made my decision: I ban electronics in my own classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;423&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5913&quot;&gt;I do make one major exception. Students with learning disabilities may use electronics in order to participate in class. This does reveal that any student using electronics has a learning disability. That is a loss of privacy for those students, which also occurs when they are given more time to complete a test. Those negatives must be weighed against the learning losses of other students when laptops are used in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;324&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6237&quot;&gt;Students may object that a laptop ban prevents them from storing notes on their computers. But smartphones can snap pictures of handwritten pages and convert them to an electronic format. Even better, outside class, students can read their own handwritten notes and type them, if they like, a process that enhances learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;241&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6478&quot;&gt;The best evidence available now suggests that students should avoid laptops during lectures and just pick up their pens. It’s not a leap to think that the same holds for middle and high school classrooms, as well as for workplace meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/22/business/laptops-not-during-lecture-or-meeting.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 12:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danso</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/22/business/laptops-not-during-lecture-or-meeting.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Laptops Are Great. But Not During a Lecture or a Meeting.</og:title>
<og:description>A growing body of evidence shows that college students generally learn less when they use computers or tablets during lectures. That is probably true in workplace meetings, too.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/26/business/26ViewArt/26ViewArt-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/22/business/laptops-not-during-lecture-or-meeting.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stanford CS007: Personal Finance For Engineers</title>
<link>https://cs007.blog/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cs007.blog/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Session 1: Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog Post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamnash.blog/2017/09/27/stanford-cs-007-personal-finance-for-engineers-kickoff/&quot;&gt;Kickoff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seminar focuses on an introduction to personal finance and the purpose of this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Session 2: Predictably Irrational&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seminar focuses on behavioral finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Session 3: Getting Paid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seminar focuses on compensation &amp;amp; job offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Session 4: Spend Less Than You Make&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seminar focuses on income, expenses, saving &amp;amp; budgeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Session 5: Know Your Worth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seminar focuses on liquidity, emergency funds, assets &amp;amp; liabilities, and net worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Session 6: All About Debt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seminar focuses on compounding, debt, credit scores, amortization &amp;amp; payoff strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Session 7:  Good Investing is Boring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seminar focuses on compounding, types of investment, diversification, how to invest, and the four keys to good investing (keep saving, low fees, stay diversified, minimize taxes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Session 8: Financial Planning &amp;amp; Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seminar focuses on putting together all of the components covered in previous weeks to understand financial planning, financial goals, complexities when dealing with couples &amp;amp; life insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Session 9: Real Estate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be no class the week of November 21st. The next seminar will be on Tuesday, November 28th at 4:30pm in Building 200, Room 034.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 12:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>destraynor</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>CS 007: Personal Finance for Engineers</og:title>
<og:description>Stanford University 2017-8</og:description>
<og:url>https://cs007.blog/</og:url>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cs007.blog/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Sumerian: A way to create VR, AR, and 3D experiences</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/launch-presenting-amazon-sumerian/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/launch-presenting-amazon-sumerian/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;If you have had an opportunity to read any of my blog posts or attended any session I’ve conducted at various conferences, you are probably aware that I am definitively a geek girl. I am absolutely enamored with all of the latest advancements that have been made in technology areas like cloud, artificial intelligence, internet of things and the maker space, as well as, with virtual reality and augmented reality. In my opinion, it is a wonderful time to be a geek. All the things that we dreamed about building while we sweated through our algorithms and discrete mathematics classes or the technology we marveled at when watching Star Wars and Star Trek are now coming to fruition.  So hopefully this means it will only be a matter of time before I can hyperdrive to other galaxies in space, but until then I can at least build the 3D virtual reality and augmented reality characters and images like those featured in some of my favorite shows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/Sumerian-01-HeaderPic.png&quot; width=&quot;845&quot; height=&quot;176&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Sumerian&lt;/strong&gt; provides tools and resources that allows anyone to create and run augmented reality (AR), virtual reality (VR), and 3D applications with ease.  With Sumerian, you can build multi-platform experiences that run on hardware like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Oculus/pages/14586587011&quot;&gt;Oculus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/HTC-VIVE-Virtual-Reality-System-pc/dp/B00VF5NT4I/&quot;&gt;HTC Vive&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=node%3D7072561011&amp;amp;field-keywords=apple&quot;&gt;iOS devices&lt;/a&gt; using WebVR compatible browsers and with support for ARCore on Android devices coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exciting new service, currently in preview, delivers features to allow you to design highly immersive and interactive 3D experiences from your browser. Some of these features are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor:&lt;/strong&gt; A web-based editor for constructing 3D scenes, importing assets, scripting interactions and special effects, with cross-platform publishing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Object Library&lt;/strong&gt;: a library of pre-built objects and templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asset Import:&lt;/strong&gt; Upload 3D assets to use in your scene. Sumerian supports importing FBX, OBJ, and coming soon Unity projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scripting Library&lt;/strong&gt;: provides a JavaScript scripting library via its 3D engine for advanced scripting capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;: animated, lifelike 3D characters that can be customized for gender, voice, and language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS Services Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: baked in integration with Amazon Polly and Amazon Lex to add speech and natural language to into Sumerian hosts. Additionally, the scripting library can be used with AWS Lambda allowing use of the full range of AWS services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;strong&gt;Amazon Sumerian&lt;/strong&gt; doesn’t require you to have 3D graphics or programming experience to build rich, interactive VR and AR scenes, let’s take a quick run to the Sumerian Dashboard and check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/Sumerian-02-Dashboard-1.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;487&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Sumerian Dashboard, I can easily create a new scene with a push of a button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/Sumerian-03-CreateScene.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;469&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A default view of the new scene opens and is displayed in the Sumerian Editor. With the &lt;strong&gt;Tara Blog Scene&lt;/strong&gt; opened in the editor, I can easily import assets into my scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/Sumerian-04-Editor-1.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;471&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll click the &lt;strong&gt;Import Asset&lt;/strong&gt; button and pick an asset, View Room, to import into the scene. With the desired asset selected, I’ll click the &lt;strong&gt;Add&lt;/strong&gt; button to import it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/Sumerian-05-ImportAsset-1.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;466&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent, my asset was successfully imported into the Sumerian Editor and is shown in the Asset panel.  Now, I have the option to add the View Room object into my scene by selecting it in the Asset panel and then dragging it onto the editor’s canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/Sumerian-05-ImportAsset-2.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;771&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/Sumerian-06-ViewRoomScene-1.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;474&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll repeat the import asset process and this time I will add the Mannequin asset to the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/Sumerian-07-MannequinAsset-1.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;477&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, with Sumerian, I can add scripting to Entity assets to make my scene even more exciting by adding a ScriptComponent to an entity and creating a script.  I can use the provided built-in scripts or create my own custom scripts. If I create a new custom script, I will get a blank script with some base JavaScript code that looks similar to the code below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-js&quot;&gt;'use strict';
/* global sumerian */
//This is Me-- trying out the custom scripts - Tara

var setup = function (args, ctx) {
// Called when play mode starts.
};
var fixedUpdate = function (args, ctx) {
// Called on every physics update, after setup().
};
var update = function (args, ctx) {
// Called on every render frame, after setup().
};
var lateUpdate = function (args, ctx) {
// Called after all script &quot;update&quot; methods in the scene has been called.
};
var cleanup = function (args, ctx) {
// Called when play mode stops.
};
var parameters = [];&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very cool, I just created a 3D scene using &lt;strong&gt;Amazon Sumerian&lt;/strong&gt; in a matter of minutes and I have only scratched the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Summary&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Amazon Sumerian&lt;/strong&gt; service enables you to create, build, and run virtual reality (VR), augmented reality (AR), and 3D applications with ease.  You don’t need any 3D graphics or specialized programming knowledge to get started building scenes and immersive experiences.  You can import FBX, OBJ, and Unity projects in Sumerian, as well as upload your own 3D assets for use in your scene. In addition, you can create digital characters to narrate your scene and with these digital assets, you have choices for the character’s appearance, speech and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about &lt;strong&gt;Amazon Sumerian&lt;/strong&gt; and sign up for the preview to get started with the new service on the product page.  I can’t wait to see what rich experiences you all will build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/taraw&quot;&gt;Tara&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jeffbarr</dc:creator>
<og:title>Presenting Amazon Sumerian: An easy way to create VR, AR, and 3D experiences | Amazon Web Services</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/launch-presenting-amazon-sumerian/</og:url>
<og:description>If you have had an opportunity to read any of my blog posts or attended any session I’ve conducted at various conferences, you are probably aware that I am definitively a geek girl. I am absolutely enamored with all of the latest advancements that have been made in technology areas like cloud, artificial intelligence, internet […]</og:description>
<og:image>https://d2908q01vomqb2.cloudfront.net/da4b9237bacccdf19c0760cab7aec4a8359010b0/2017/11/27/Sumerian-07-MannequinAsset-1.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/launch-presenting-amazon-sumerian/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Time Inc. Sells Itself to Meredith Corp., Backed by Koch Brothers</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/26/business/dealbook/time-inc-meredith-corporation-koch-brothers.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/26/business/dealbook/time-inc-meredith-corporation-koch-brothers.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;298&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2063&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;Meredith, based in Des Moines, is a Midwestern publisher through and through. Its founder, Edwin Thomas Meredith, entered the media business in 1902 with a magazine called Successful Farming. He soon began the still-thriving Better Homes and Gardens, which has a circulation of more than 7 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;343&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2406&quot;&gt;Its popular magazines have long focused on families and women, taking aim more at Middle America. It has eschewed an expensive headquarters in Manhattan and maintained a diversified portfolio — the company also owns local television stations — that has allowed Meredith to better weather the economic storm that has faced print publishers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/27/business/27time2/27time2-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/27/business/27time2/27time2-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;The billionaire brothers David H. Koch, left, and Charles G. Koch have backed Meredith&amp;#x2019;s bid.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Paul Vernon/Associated Press, left, and Bo Rader, via The Wichita Eagle, via Associated Press&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/27/business/27time2/27time2-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;The billionaire brothers David H. Koch, left, and Charles G. Koch have backed Meredith’s bid.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Paul Vernon/Associated Press, left, and Bo Rader, via The Wichita Eagle, via Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;309&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2715&quot;&gt;But as Meredith has stood relatively strong, Time Inc. has stumbled. The company failed to keep pace as the industrywide transformation from print to digital rendered old methods of magazine-making obsolete and publishing companies crumbled under the pressure of declines in print advertising and circulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;124&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2839&quot;&gt;For Meredith, a hardy company with a loyal print readership, the acquisition of Time Inc. represents a long-elusive victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;191&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3030&quot;&gt;“This is a transformative transaction for Meredith Corporation,” Tom Harty, Meredith’s president and chief operating officer, said in the company’s statement announcing the agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;443&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3473&quot;&gt;Charles Koch, the chief executive of Koch Industries, and David Koch have long sought to shape political discourse through their support of nonprofit organizations, universities and think tanks. But in its announcement of the deal, Meredith said that the private equity fund, Koch Equity Development, would not have a seat on Meredith’s board of directors and would “have no influence on Meredith’s editorial or managerial operations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;320&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3793&quot;&gt;Steve Lombardo, a spokesman for Koch Industries, also said that the Kochs had no plans to take an active role in the expanded company. “This is a passive financial investment made through our equity development arm,” Mr. Lombardo said. The company’s role in the transaction, he said, was similar to that of a bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/26/business/dealbook/time-inc-meredith-corporation-koch-brothers.html#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;80&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3873&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Mr. Lombardo said the company is constantly evaluating investment opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;127&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4000&quot;&gt;“We’re looking at deals across all sectors, all industries,” he said. “This just happened to be one that made sense.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;415&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4415&quot;&gt;A deal between Meredith and Time Inc. fell apart in 2013 after Meredith reportedly said that it did not want to acquire some of Time Inc.’s best-known titles, including Time, Fortune and Sports Illustrated. Meredith also expressed interest in buying Time Inc. earlier this year before it walked away — in part because it could not secure sufficient financing. The Kochs helped the company overcome that problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;399&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4814&quot;&gt;Adding Time Inc.’s portfolio will give Meredith even more national scale, which will help it continue to appeal to advertisers on both the print and digital sides. But the company will also have to adjust to printing weekly titles, which it currently does not do. Meredith said it expected its deal for Time Inc. would result in $400 million to $500 million in cost savings in its first two years.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/27/business/27time1/27time1-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/27/business/27time1/27time1-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;It was not clear how much influence, if any, the Koch brothers would wield over Time Inc., should the deal be completed.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Richard Drew/Associated Press&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/27/business/27time1/27time1-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;It was not clear how much influence, if any, the Koch brothers would wield over Time Inc., should the deal be completed.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Richard Drew/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;232&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5046&quot;&gt;In a note to its staff members on Sunday night, Rich Battista, the chief executive of Time Inc., said he believed in “our strategic transformation plan and in our ability to write the next great chapter of this storied company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;298&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5344&quot;&gt;“That said, as a publicly traded company, and one operating in such a dynamic industry as media, we know circumstances can change quickly,” he said. Meredith, Mr. Battista added, “presented us with an opportunity to combine companies to create even greater scale and financial flexibility.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;202&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5546&quot;&gt;Under the terms of the deal, Meredith will pay $18.50 a share for Time Inc. The boards of both companies finalized the deal on Sunday evening. The deal is expected to close in the first quarter of 2018.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;219&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5765&quot;&gt;The investment from the Kochs, Meredith said, “underscores a strong belief in Meredith’s strength as a business operator, its strategies and its ability to unlock significant value from the Time Inc. acquisition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;519&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6284&quot;&gt;Some Koch allies have suggested that the brothers would view their investment purely as a moneymaking opportunity. But others familiar with the Kochs’ thinking speculated that they could nonetheless use the media properties — which reach millions of online and print readers — to promote their brand of conservatism. The investment would also give the Kochs a way to combine the arsenal of voter information held by a data analytics company controlled by their network, i360, with the publishers’ consumer data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;331&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6615&quot;&gt;After Time Warner, the home of HBO and Warner Bros., spun off Time Inc. in 2014, the publisher was left to fend for itself in a world increasingly turning its back on print media. Bedeviled by relentless cost cuts and executive turnover, the company has struggled to articulate a business strategy less focused on the printed page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-3&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/26/business/dealbook/time-inc-meredith-corporation-koch-brothers.html#story-continues-5&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;384&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6999&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-5&quot;&gt;Mr. Battista, who was named Time Inc.’s chief executive last year, and the new chief operating officer, Jen Wong, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/05/business/media/time-inc-magazine-jen-wong-and-rich-battista.html&quot;&gt;embarked on an aggressive strategy&lt;/a&gt; to increase digital revenue, including enhancing advertising technology capabilities and offering customers paid services, such as insurance for pets and a food and wine club. The company had also earmarked $400 million in cost cuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;397&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7396&quot;&gt;Time Inc. executives had been adamant that their stand-alone strategy could position the company for a successful future. But in an industry that increasingly values size and breadth, Time Inc. was staring into ongoing uncertainty. For its most recent quarter, it reported a 9 percent drop in total revenue compared with the same period last year, and a 12 percent decrease in advertising revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;118&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7514&quot;&gt;Mr. Battista is expected to stay on at Time Inc. through the close of the deal, after which he will leave the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/26/business/dealbook/time-inc-meredith-corporation-koch-brothers.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 03:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mudil</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/26/business/dealbook/time-inc-meredith-corporation-koch-brothers.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Time Inc. Sells Itself to Meredith Corp., Backed by Koch Brothers</og:title>
<og:description>Meredith Corporation, the publisher of Family Circle and Better Homes and Gardens, clinches a deal in a cash transaction valued at nearly $3 billion.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/27/business/27time-top/27time-top-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/26/business/dealbook/time-inc-meredith-corporation-koch-brothers.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>