<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Instacart and DoorDash’s Tip Policies Are Delivering Outrage</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/06/technology/instacart-doordash-tipping-deliveries.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/06/technology/instacart-doordash-tipping-deliveries.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Delivery has always been a rough business. Since time immemorial, couriers have braved the elements, gotten by on meager wages and dealt with annoying customers, growling dogs and fifth-floor walk-ups, all for the chance of a big tip from a happy customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But thanks to two Silicon Valley upstarts, even those tips are in doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This week, Instacart and DoorDash — two giants of the app-based delivery industry, collectively valued by investors at more than $11 billion — have come under fire from critics who have accused the companies of taking advantage of their workers with deceptive tipping policies. Both companies acknowledged putting customer tips toward workers’ minimum pay guarantees, in effect using them to subsidize their own payouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It’s offensive, it’s unethical and in this climate, it’s a very dumb thing to do,” Matthew Telles, an Instacart courier based in Chicago, said this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ashley Knudson, a Seattle-based Instacart worker, said she felt “cheated” by the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I have gone from making $1,000 a week and providing for my family to now, if I’m lucky, making $600 a week,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;[After an uproar, Instacart on Wednesday reversed its&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/06/business/instacart-tipping-practice-reversal.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;tipping policy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It’s no secret that many modern gig workers exist in a state of permanent precarity, with few legal protections, unstable working conditions and pay that varies based on who’s flush with venture capital money that week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But even by gig economy standards, the tipping policies of Instacart and DoorDash seem diabolical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The drama began in November, when Instacart &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/shopper-news/introducing-instacarts-new-earnings-structure-for-shoppers-26a11df53581&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;put into effect&lt;/a&gt; a new method of paying its contract workers, who are known as shoppers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Previously, Instacart’s shopper pay was determined by an algorithm that factored in a fixed base payment for each order, along with a per-item bonus and extra payments for certain tasks, such as delivering over long distances. Under the new model, Instacart presented shoppers with a single, itemized “earning estimate,” and guaranteed them a $10 minimum payment for each batch they accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Instacart shoppers began to notice that for some orders, the tips customers added during checkout were being counted toward their $10 minimums, rather than being paid out on top of them. In some cases, the bigger the tip, the less the company seemed to pay. DoorDash, whose minimum-pay guarantee varies based on order size, distance and other factors, has had a similar tipping policy in place for “dashers,” as its delivery workers are known, since 2017, although it mostly escaped scrutiny until last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;[Subscribe to&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/with-interest?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;“With Interest.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;It’s a Sunday newsletter with essential business insights that’ll prep you for the week ahead.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;These tipping models aren’t strictly new. Neither is worker anger at Instacart, which has frustrated shoppers with &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2017/2/20/14503128/instacart-service-fee-tips-controversy&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sudden pay changes&lt;/a&gt; in the past. But they have &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/business/business-news/why-instacart-doordash-workers-don-t-always-receive-tips-you-n965926&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;received renewed attention&lt;/a&gt; in recent weeks, as workers have &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://actionnetwork.org/petitions/instacart-heres-our-22-cents-no-more-tip-theft-low-pay-and-black-box-pay-algorithms&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;united&lt;/a&gt; in opposition to the industry’s most exploitative practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Angry shoppers gathered in Reddit forums and Facebook groups to exchange frustrations and collect shocking examples of low pay, like a receipt &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.workingwa.org/instacart-eighty-cents/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;submitted&lt;/a&gt; by an Instacart shopper who was paid a total of $10.80 after a $10 tip. After an internet uproar, Instacart &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90300962/reeling-from-algorithm-glitch-instacart-institutes-3-minimum-fee-for-drivers&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;explained&lt;/a&gt; that the order had been an “edge case,” and said it was introducing a $3 minimum “batch incentive” to prevent such incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In another example, two shoppers with &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MatthewTelles/status/1088852974322024448&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;identical Instacart batches&lt;/a&gt; were paid $10 — the guaranteed minimum — even though one received a $2 tip and the other a $6 tip. In the case of the $2 tip, Instacart’s “batch payment” came to $8; in the case of the $6 tip, Instacart paid only $4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We started to notice customers who said they tipped, but a lot of times we wouldn’t see the tips,” said Kaylania Chapman, an Orlando-based worker who delivers orders for both Instacart and DoorDash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Working Washington, a union-backed labor group based in Seattle, has collected more than 1,500 signatures of Instacart shoppers who object to the company’s pay practices. Some are asking for cash tips outside the app, while others are &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-01-17/these-instacart-workers-want-you-to-leave-them-a-22-cent-tip&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;encouraging&lt;/a&gt; customers to leave 22-cent tips — a nominal amount meant to show solidarity with workers — through the app and then adjust the tips higher after a delivery has been made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Workers deserve to know what they’re being paid — and why,” said Rachel Lauter, Working Washington’s executive director. “Customers deserve to know where their money is going. And no one should be getting 80 cents an hour.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For longtime gig-economy workers, the latest flap over delivery tips is just one skirmish in a long, wearying struggle that involves coping with opaque policies, dizzying technology changes and black-box algorithms that penalize them for minor infractions. But recently, some gig workers have had success pushing back. Drivers for Uber and Lyft in New York &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/12/5/18127208/new-york-uber-lyft-minimum-wage&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;successfully agitated&lt;/a&gt; for a citywide minimum wage that went into effect this week. Postmates, another high-flying start-up, recently &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/postmates-class-action-lawsuit-couriers-2018-1&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;settled&lt;/a&gt; a class-action suit with thousands of delivery workers who contested the way the company classified them as contract workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Representatives for Instacart and DoorDash — both of which initially tried to cloud the issue by claiming, correctly but extraneously, that “workers receive 100 percent of their tips” — eventually admitted to counting tips toward workers’ guaranteed minimums after I repeatedly pressed them on it. But they denied that the policies were misleading or unfair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“DoorDash’s pay model provides transparency, consistency and predictability,” said a company spokeswoman. “Since implementing this pay model more than a year ago, we’ve seen a significant increase in dasher retention, percentage of on-time orders and dasher satisfaction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We’re constantly reviewing and evaluating feedback from our shopper community to ensure they’re competitively compensated for the work they’re doing on behalf of our customers,” said David Hahn, Instacart’s chief product officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But this is all semantic tap-dancing, meant to distract from the core problem: Instacart and DoorDash, two Silicon Valley giants that could afford to pay workers a fair wage, have figured out a clever way to use customer tips to lower their labor expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Lawmakers may ultimately call foul on these policies. (Representative Ro Khanna, a Democrat who represents parts of Silicon Valley in Congress, told &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/carolineodonovan/delivery-startups-are-using-tips-to-fulfill-pay-promises&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/a&gt; that Instacart’s tipping policy was a “deceptive business practice that should end.”) Instacart workers have &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ashleyjohnson_54890/the-truth-about-how-instacart-pays-their-shoppers-273333d654bb&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;urged customers&lt;/a&gt; not to boycott the company, which would cut even further into their earnings. But ultimately, with so little legal protection afforded to gig-economy workers, it may be up to customers to demand accountability and more worker-friendly policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Haslam, a California-based DoorDash customer who has spent more than three years placing orders from the delivery service, told me on Tuesday that she was “shocked” to learn about the company’s tipping policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It made me really angry that I was contributing to a company that would do that,” she said. “And it makes me wonder how many other services are doing the same thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 18:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/06/technology/instacart-doordash-tipping-deliveries.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Instacart and DoorDash’s Tip Policies Deliver Outrage</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/07/business/07ROOSE-COMBO/07ROOSE-COMBO-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The delivery companies came under fire from critics who said the companies were taking advantage of their workers with deceptive tipping policies.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/06/technology/instacart-doordash-tipping-deliveries.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Happened to the 100000 Hour LED Bulbs?</title>
<link>https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Early adopters of LED lighting will remember 50,000 hour or even 100,000 hour lifetime ratings printed on the box. But during a recent trip to the hardware store the longest advertised lifetime I found was 25,000 hours. Others claimed only 7,500 or 15,000 hours. And yes, these are brand-name bulbs from Cree and GE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what happened to those 100,000 hour residential LED bulbs? Were the initial estimates just over-optimistic? Was it all marketing hype? Or, did we not know enough about LED aging to predict the true useful life of a bulb?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put these questions to the test. Join me after the break for some background on the light bulb cartel from the days of incandescent bulbs (not a joke, a cartel controlled the life of your bulbs), and for the destruction of some modern LED bulbs to see why the lifetimes are clocking in a lot lower than the original wave of LED replacements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;Ghosts of Light Bulb Cartels Past&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any discussion of light bulb lifetime would be incomplete without mention of the Phoebus cartel, an international organization formed in 1924 by the world’s leading light bulb manufacturers to manipulate the bulb market. As discussed by Markus Krajewski in &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-history/dawn-of-electronics/the-great-lightbulb-conspiracy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“The Great Lightbulb Conspiracy”&lt;/a&gt;, the cartel assigned territories to member companies, limited production, and dictated a shortened 1,000 hour bulb life. Previous bulbs had burned for a much longer 1,500 – 2,500 hours. Purportedly imposed to increase quality, efficiency, and light output, the new 1,000 hour limit also resulted in many more bulb sales. Archived documents show that significant research was expended to devise bulbs that lasted their 1,000 appointed hours and no more. It wasn’t only household lighting that took a hit: flashlight bulbs originally lasting for three sets of batteries were reduced to two, with a proposal to limit their lifetime to a single set. Again, brightness increases were touted as the reason. However, that last step, halving bulb lifetime, would increase brightness only between 11%-16%, while doubling sales. This was about selling more bulbs and making more money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;344285&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/edisontesla-incandescent-bulb/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/edisontesla-incandescent-bulb.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;785,785&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;EdisonTesla-incandescent-bulb&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/edisontesla-incandescent-bulb.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=400&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/edisontesla-incandescent-bulb.jpg?w=625&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-344285&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/edisontesla-incandescent-bulb.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/edisontesla-incandescent-bulb.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=400 400w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/edisontesla-incandescent-bulb.jpg?w=250&amp;amp;h=250 250w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/edisontesla-incandescent-bulb.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=768 768w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/edisontesla-incandescent-bulb.jpg 785w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cartel enforced production quotas and bulb lifetimes with a system of monetary fines, backed by the power of GE’s patent portfolio. Bulbs from each producer were tested, and penalties imposed for bulbs lasting significantly shorter or longer than 1,000 hours. Phoebus continued to exert influence on the market until World War II ended its reign. The cartel is often cited as one of the first instances of planned obsolescence: designing products with an artificially shortened lifespan. A 2010 documentary, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kdHIqa53-tY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“The Light Bulb Conspiracy,”&lt;/a&gt; explores the history of the cartel along with some more recent instances of planned obsolescence. I wonder what the conspirators would have thought of bulbs that supposedly last 100,000 hours? Or even 7,500?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tucked into a lower shelf in the lighting isle at the hardware store, a few lonely incandescent bulbs waited for some Luddite consumer. Picking up a box, I read the rated lifetime: 1,000 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;Measuring Lifetime of a Bulb&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly does the box mean with this 1,000 hour lifetime? This is the bulb’s Average Rated Life (ARL) — it’s  the length of time for 50% of an initial sample of bulbs to fail (abbreviated B&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt;). What “failure” means depends on the type of bulb; we’ll explore this in more depth later on. The definition of B&lt;sub&gt;50 &lt;/sub&gt;reveals a common misinterpretation, namely that a bulb will last for its rated lifetime. In reality, only half of them last that long, although this rating doesn’t tell you anything about the distribution of failures around the median lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manufacturers use these ARL values to forecast how many years a bulb will last based on using the bulb a specified number of hours per day (typically 3). LED bulbs suffer less wear-out through power cycling than incandescents, so the conversion is just a division: years of service = ARL/(3*365). For example, half of a set of 100,000-hour bulbs would still be in service after 91 years according to this calculation. But this simple metric doesn’t tell the whole story. LED bulb failure mechanisms are complex and fundamentally different from the well-known incandescents. To understand more, we need to shed some light on the inner workings of a bulb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before leaving the store, I threw a few bulbs in my cart so I could see firsthand what was inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;What’s In a Bulb? Let’s Tear Some Apart!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-teardown.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;342660&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/led-bulb-teardown/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-teardown.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;4012,1484&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;moto g(6)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1548419055&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.95&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;121&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.033333333333333&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;led-bulb-teardown&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=400&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;h=296&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-342660 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;h=296&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;296&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;h=296 800w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=1600&amp;amp;h=592 1600w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=250&amp;amp;h=92 250w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=148 400w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=284 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Left-to-right: Teardown of GE 7,500 hour “Basic”, GE 15,000 hour “Classic”, and 25,000-hour Cree A19 LED bulbs.
&lt;p&gt;There’s more to an LED bulb than just the LEDs. Outlets in our homes are actually fairly dirty sources of AC power. LEDs want clean, constant-current DC sources, so circuits inside the bulbs must rectify and filter the incoming AC, then limit current to the LED packages. To see how this is done, I dissected three different A19 style bulbs: one each from the GE “Basic” and “Classic” lines (7,500 and 15,000 hours), and a Cree model offering a 25,000 hour life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;GE Basic A19 Bulb (7,500 Hours Advertised)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/sm2082d-schematic.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;342654&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/sm2082d-schematic/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/sm2082d-schematic.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;965,351&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;sm2082d-schematic&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/sm2082d-schematic.png?w=400&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/sm2082d-schematic.png?w=800&amp;amp;h=291&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-342654 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/sm2082d-schematic.png?w=800&amp;amp;h=291&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;291&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/sm2082d-schematic.png?w=800&amp;amp;h=291 800w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/sm2082d-schematic.png?w=250&amp;amp;h=91 250w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/sm2082d-schematic.png?w=400&amp;amp;h=145 400w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/sm2082d-schematic.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=279 768w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/sm2082d-schematic.png 965w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;GE Basic A19 Bulb uses a circuit straight from the SM2082D datasheet.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-basic-bulb.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;344280&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/ge-basic-bulb/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-basic-bulb.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1301,732&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;moto g(6)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1548419055&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.95&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;121&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.033333333333333&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;ge-basic-bulb&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-basic-bulb.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=225&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-basic-bulb.jpg?w=800&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-344280&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-basic-bulb.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=225&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-basic-bulb.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=225 400w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-basic-bulb.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;h=450 800w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-basic-bulb.jpg?w=250&amp;amp;h=141 250w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-basic-bulb.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=432 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This GE bulb has a plastic dome covering a circular aluminum PCB which carries eight LED packages and the driver electronics. The driver consists of an MB10F bridge rectifier, an electrolytic capacitor rated for 105 °C, and an SM2082D linear constant-current driver. There are three resistors on the PCB: one bleeds charge from the capacitor when the bulb is off, and two others set the SM2082D current to 54 mA. In fact, the circuit looks like it was taken directly from the SM2082D datasheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven of the 3.5 x 2.8 mm LED packages show around 18 V of forward drop when driven with 50 mA, indicating that they contain six LED dice in series. One LED on the board shows a drop of 9 V, so it has only three LED chips. All the LEDs, totaling 45 dice, are wired in series to drop approximately 135V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;GE Classic A19 Bulb (15,000 Hours Advertised)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-classic-bulb.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;344281&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/ge-classic-bulb/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-classic-bulb.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1301,732&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;moto g(6)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1548419055&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.95&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;121&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.033333333333333&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;ge-classic-bulb&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-classic-bulb.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=225&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-classic-bulb.jpg?w=800&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-344281&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-classic-bulb.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=225&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-classic-bulb.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=225 400w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-classic-bulb.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;h=450 800w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-classic-bulb.jpg?w=250&amp;amp;h=141 250w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/ge-classic-bulb.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=432 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;When they say classic, they mean it. This bulb is in a glass envelope just like incandescents, and like those old bulbs, the glass is easily removed with a ball-peen hammer. In place of the tungsten filament is an aluminum PCB folded into a squat obelisk. Sixteen 3.5 x 2.8 mm LED packages are connected in series on the board, with each one showing a forward voltage of around 9 V at 50 mA. So, this version has 48 LED chips vs 45 for the Basic bulb, except they’re in twice as many packages – this is good for keeping the LEDs cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another difference with this longer-lived bulb is that the driver electronics are not thermally coupled to the LEDs; they are hidden on a separate PCB in the screw base. This keeps the rest of the components from heating with the LEDs. On the driver PCB is a bridge rectifier, an electrolytic capacitor again rated for 105&lt;strong&gt;°&lt;/strong&gt;C, and an SOIC-8 IC. Interestingly, this bulb also contains a metal-oxide varistor for transient suppression. Although I couldn’t determine what the house-marked (“BYSACT”) driver IC was, the lack of any inductive components on the PCB indicates this is another linear supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;Cree A19 Bulb (25,000 Hours Advertised)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/cree-bulb-teardown.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;344282&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/cree-bulb-teardown/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/cree-bulb-teardown.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1301,732&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;moto g(6)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1548419055&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.95&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;121&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.033333333333333&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;cree-bulb-teardown&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/cree-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=225&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/cree-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=800&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-344282&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/cree-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=225&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/cree-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=225 400w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/cree-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;h=450 800w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/cree-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=250&amp;amp;h=141 250w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/cree-bulb-teardown.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=432 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Cree bulb has a diffused plastic dome like the GE Basic model. Inside, a larger aluminum PCB holds (16) 3.5 x 2.8 mm LED packages. Each LEDs drops around 8.5 V at 50 mA, so they contain 3 chips; like the GE Classic bulb, this one uses 48 total LED dice. The LEDs are wired as eight sections of two paralleled LEDs, so the total drop is around 68 V. The LED PCB is coupled to a thick aluminum heat sink with silicone thermal compound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the GE Classic bulb, the power supply electronics are on a separate PCB, thermally decoupled from the LEDs. The driver IC is an SOT23-5 package inscrutably marked with “SaAOC”, but the presence of a transformer and stout Schottky diode reveals that this is a switch-mode power supply. The filter capacitor on the switcher output is an aluminum electrolytic rated for 130 °C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not much to go on, but what conclusions can we draw from the design of these three bulbs? It helps to consider how they typically fail, and what factors affect their lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;LEDs “Outlast” Other Components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-failure-modes.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;342658&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/led-failure-modes/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-failure-modes.png?w=800&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;394,299&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;led-failure-modes&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-failure-modes.png?w=800?w=394&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-failure-modes.png?w=800?w=394&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-342658 alignleft&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-failure-modes.png?w=800&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-failure-modes.png 394w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-failure-modes.png?w=250 250w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 394px) 100vw, 394px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Since the LED bulbs contain a number of parts, it’s natural to ask which ones might be responsible for failures. The US Department of Energy (DoE)’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.energy.gov/eere/ssl/solid-state-lighting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;solid-state lighting program&lt;/a&gt; supports research and development of LED technologies, and their website contains volumes of data on LED lighting systems. Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www1.eere.energy.gov/buildings/publications/pdfs/ssl/life-reliability_fact-sheet.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lifetime and Reliability Fact Sheet&lt;/a&gt; contains data on the failure rate of 5,400 outdoor lamps over 34 million hours of operation. Interestingly, the LEDs themselves account for only 10% of the failures; driver circuitry, on the other hand, was responsible almost 60% of the time. The remainder of failures were due to housing problems, which may not be as applicable for bulbs in indoor use. This data shows that at least for catastrophic failures (where the lamp ceases to emit light), extending lifetime means improving the power supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;Locate the Weakest Link: Component Lifetime&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lifetime of a bulb (or power supply) can be no longer than the lifetime of any of its components. Among the components found inside the bulbs, two stand out as life-limiters: the semiconductors and the electrolytic capacitors. Both of these components suffer from a failure rate that is a strong function of temperature. The typical model for this effect, based on the Arrhenius equation, predicts a doubling of lifetime for each 10 degree Celsius decrease in temperature, at least over a limited range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two longer-lived bulbs use twice as many packages to carry approximately the same number of LED dice as the GE Basic lamp, decreasing thermal resistance to their respective heatsinks, and presumably reducing their temperature. These bulbs also both mount the failure-prone driver electronics on separate PCBs from the LEDs to keep them cool. Finally, the 25,000-hour Cree bulb uses an electrolytic capacitor rated for 130 &lt;strong&gt;°&lt;/strong&gt;C as opposed to the 105 °C caps in the other two. For similar operating temperatures, this could multiply the expected life of the capacitor by a factor of five. Each of these measures probably contributes to delaying catastrophic failure of the bulb, resulting in the longer rated lifetimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when it comes to the LEDs themselves, there is more to lifetime estimates than predicting catastrophic failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;Just Fade Away&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the soldiers in Douglas MacArthur’s famous line, old LEDs don’t die, they just fade away. We all know what an incandescent lamp failure looks like: one second it’s burning bright; the next, it’s not (and every once-in-a-while, you hear a pop followed by a faint jingling as the liberated filament richochets inside the bulb). Power supplies aside, LEDs typically don’t fail with so much fanfare. Instead, they gradually lose brightness as they age. In the lighting industry, this is known as lumen depreciation, and is a separate failure mode from the catastrophic failure we usually think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;301804&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/incandescent_thumbnail/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/incandescent_thumbnail.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;600,600&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Incandescent_thumbnail&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/incandescent_thumbnail.png?w=400&amp;amp;h=400&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/incandescent_thumbnail.png?w=600&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-301804 alignright&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/incandescent_thumbnail.png?w=400&amp;amp;h=400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/incandescent_thumbnail.png?w=400&amp;amp;h=400 400w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/incandescent_thumbnail.png?w=250&amp;amp;h=250 250w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/incandescent_thumbnail.png 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;As it turns out, lumen depreciation happens to incandescent bulbs, too. By the end of their 1,000 hour life, the output has typically dropped 10-15%, but nobody ever notices. With LEDs, the effect is much worse, and the output continues to fall as the device ages. At some point, the LED is no longer producing enough light to fulfill its original purpose, even though it hasn’t “burned out.” Research says that most users won’t notice a gradual 30% drop in light levels; accordingly the industry has defined L&lt;sub&gt;70,&lt;/sub&gt; the time at which the output has dropped to 70% of its initial level, as an endpoint for measuring LED bulb lifetime. Based on how it’s estimated, this measure is typically stated as B&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt;-L&lt;sub&gt;70&lt;/sub&gt;, the point at which 50% of an initial sample of bulbs will retain 70% of their rated output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Color Shift Happens But is Unpredictable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something else happens as phosphor-based white LEDs age: they change color. The US DoE’s report on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.energy.gov/sites/prod/files/2017/04/f34/lsrc_colorshift_apr2017.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LED Luminaire Reliability: Impact of Color Shift&lt;/a&gt; defines four color-shifts (blue, yellow, red, and green) observed in LED lamps, although the yellow shift dominates in high-power white LEDs. This gradual yellowing of the light output results from phosphor cracking, delamination, and thermal effects, since the phosphor temperature can exceed that of the LED junction by 30 C – 50 °C. Modeling and predicting color shift in LEDs is a difficult task, with all of the mechanisms not yet fully understood. As a result, no standards have yet been established for accelerated testing or projection of color stability over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, these effects can be as detrimental to the function of the bulb as catastrophic failure. Given that lumen depreciation and color shift will in time render the LEDs ineffective, it may not make sense for manufacturers to design bulbs with very long electrical lifetimes. It’s possible that the reduced lifetime ratings we see on current bulbs simply reflect better knowledge about actual performance of existing LED technology over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;Lumen Depreciation in the Kitchen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/par30-bulb-aging-comparison.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;342656&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/par30-bulb-aging-comparison/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/par30-bulb-aging-comparison.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1941,1942&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;11&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 10D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1548332330&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;24&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.7&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;par30-bulb-aging-comparison&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/par30-bulb-aging-comparison.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=400&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/par30-bulb-aging-comparison.jpg?w=625&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-342656&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/par30-bulb-aging-comparison.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/par30-bulb-aging-comparison.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=400 400w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/par30-bulb-aging-comparison.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;h=800 800w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/par30-bulb-aging-comparison.jpg?w=250&amp;amp;h=250 250w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/par30-bulb-aging-comparison.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=768 768w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/par30-bulb-aging-comparison.jpg?w=625&amp;amp;h=625 625w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Heavily-used LED bulb (left) vs seldom-used bulb (right) after 8+ years.
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen lumen depreciation and color shift first-hand. In June of 2010, I replaced twelve 65W incandescent PAR30 floodlight bulbs in our kitchen with LED equivalents. At the same time, I also replaced three lights in another room with identical LED bulbs. These three bulbs see much less use, so in preparation for this article, I took one bulb from each location and put them side-by-side to see if I could tell the difference in output. The recessed light fixtures in both rooms are identical, so I expect that the bulbs are exposed to similar temperatures when on: any difference should only be due to aging effects. The results were shocking. Since these two bulbs were in different rooms, I never saw them side-by-side, so didn’t notice how bad the lumen depreciation and color shift had become. Sure, I knew they were dimmer and yellower than when I installed them, but had no idea it was this bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These bulbs were advertised with a 30,000 hour lifetime. I estimate the total use at 15,000-20,000 hours. During the 8 ½ years these were in service, one failed completely. Instead of replacing it with a newer bulb which would not match the color of the older ones (or replacing them all), I left that socket empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the hardware store, I noticed new 9-watt BR30 LED bulbs for $5 each. The PAR30s I purchased in 2010 were $45 and consume 11 watts. A quick calculation says that the old bulbs paid for themselves more than three times over in electricity savings relative to the incandescents they replaced, and put that much less carbon into the atmosphere. They may well continue to burn for another 15,000 hours, but after weighing the degraded output and the cost to replace them with brighter, more efficient versions, I’m headed back to the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;western&quot;&gt;Making Sense of It All&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/centennial-bulb.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;342666&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/centennial-bulb/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/centennial-bulb.png?w=800&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;267,374&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;centennial-bulb&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/centennial-bulb.png?w=800?w=267&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/centennial-bulb.png?w=800?w=267&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-342666&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/centennial-bulb.png?w=800&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/centennial-bulb.png 267w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/centennial-bulb.png?w=178 178w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 267px) 100vw, 267px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This bulb has burned for over 1 million hours.
&lt;p&gt;I’ve taken a look at some of the technical issues in LED lighting. Of course, there is more to LED bulbs than lifetime — color temperature and color rendering index (CRI) should factor into any purchase decision. There are also a number of larger problems involved, including issues of economics and sustainability. Some of these are addressed in J.B. MacKinnon’s 2016 article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/business/currency/the-l-e-d-quandary-why-theres-no-such-thing-as-built-to-last&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The L.E.D. Quandary: Why There’s No Such Thing as “Built to Last”&lt;/a&gt;, in The New Yorker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly moving away from incandescent bulbs to more efficient lighting makes sense, but maybe we never really needed 100,000 hour bulbs in the first place. The lifetime of even 7,500-hour bulbs is long compared to the rapid pace of advance in lighting technology. Does it makes sense to buy expensive long-lived bulbs today, when better, cheaper, more efficient ones may be available in the near future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The oldest surviving incandescent light, known as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centennialbulb.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Centennial Bulb (click to see a webcam of the lamp)&lt;/a&gt;, is a dim carbon-filament bulb that’s been burning nearly continuously since 1901 — over 1 million hours. In its current state, it throws off as much light as a modern 4-watt incandescent. Would it have made sense to pay a premium for such “million hour bulbs” at the turn of the 20th century if we had any inkling of the advances that would come in the next 117 years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new $5 BR30 LED bulbs I just installed in the kitchen are amazingly bright and crisp: tests with a lux meter show the illuminance is more than 60% higher. Plus, they’ll more than pay for themselves in electricity savings compared to the old, inefficient &lt;em&gt;LED&lt;/em&gt; bulbs they replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 16:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jccalhoun</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>What Happened to the 100,000-Hour LED Bulbs?</og:title>
<og:url>https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/</og:url>
<og:description>Early adopters of LED lighting will remember 50,000 hour or even 100,000 hour lifetime ratings printed on the box. But during a recent trip to the hardware store the longest advertised lifetime I f…</og:description>
<og:image>https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/led-bulb-lifetime-featured.jpg?w=1200</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/what-happened-to-the-100000-hour-led-bulbs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Netflix Posted Biggest-Ever Profit in 2018 and Paid $0 in Income Taxes</title>
<link>https://itep.org/netflix-posted-biggest-ever-profit-in-2018-and-paid-0-in-income-taxes/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://itep.org/netflix-posted-biggest-ever-profit-in-2018-and-paid-0-in-income-taxes/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;row visible-xs&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 5, 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br class=&quot;visible-xs visible-sm&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-xs&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 5, 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugely profitable tech company provides first look at how corporations are faring under new tax law&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The popular video streaming service Netflix posted its largest-ever U.S. profit in 2018­­—$845 million—on which it didn’t pay a dime in federal or state income taxes. In fact, the company reported a $22 million federal tax rebate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a year of speculation and spin, the public is getting its first hard look at how corporate tax law changes under the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act affected the tax-paying habits of corporations. The law sharply reduced the federal corporate rate, expanded some tax breaks and curtailed others. The new tax law took effect at the beginning of 2018, which means that companies are just now closing the books on their first full year under the new rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Netflix’s earnings report is any indication, not much has changed. Many corporations are still able to exploit loopholes and avoid paying the statutory tax rate—only now, that rate is substantially lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix’s tax avoidance should come as no surprise to those who followed the debate leading up to the passage of the new tax law: A &lt;a href=&quot;https://itep.org/the-35-percent-corporate-tax-myth/&quot;&gt;2017 ITEP report&lt;/a&gt; identified Netflix as one of 100 profitable Fortune 500 corporations that paid a 0 percent federal income tax rate in at least one profitable year between 2008 and 2015. In fact, Netflix did it twice, and paid an average tax rate of 13.6 percent over the eight-year period, meaning that the company sheltered more than half of its profits from the 35 percent federal income tax rate in effect at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading up to the 2017 tax battle, the hope of reformers was that Congress would take a fiscally responsible approach and weed out loopholes that made Netflix’s tax avoidance possible. Instead,  GOP leaders who championed the law and President Trump chose to focus on cutting the corporate tax rate as far as possible—from 35 to 21 percent—while leaving in place special breaks and loopholes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As more 2018 earnings reports begin to come in, we will see the results of this profligacy in real time. Netflix appears to be every bit as unaffected by corporate tax laws now as it was before President Trump’s “reform.” This is especially troubling because Netflix is precisely the sort of company that should be paying its fair share of income taxes. With a &lt;a href=&quot;https://variety.com/2019/digital/news/netflix-q4-2018-earnings-report-1203110722/&quot;&gt;record number of subscribers&lt;/a&gt;, the company’s profit last year equaled its haul in the previous four years put together. When hugely profitable corporations avoid tax, that means smaller businesses and working families must make up the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 16:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>smacktoward</dc:creator>
<og:title>Netflix Posted Biggest-Ever Profit in 2018 and Paid $0 in Taxes</og:title>
<og:description>The popular video streaming service Netflix posted its largest-ever U.S. profit in 2018­­—$845 million—on which it didn’t pay a dime in federal or state income taxes. In fact, the company reported a $22 million federal income tax rebate.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://itep.org/netflix-posted-biggest-ever-profit-in-2018-and-paid-0-in-income-taxes/</og:url>
<og:image>https://itep.org/wp-content/uploads/taxavoidance.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://itep.org/netflix-posted-biggest-ever-profit-in-2018-and-paid-0-in-income-taxes/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jabra: we know our Bluetooth headsets don’t work with laptops</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@daniel_36042/jabra-we-know-our-bluetooth-headsets-dont-work-with-laptops-sorry-no-refunds-80ed4cb2fc6f</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@daniel_36042/jabra-we-know-our-bluetooth-headsets-dont-work-with-laptops-sorry-no-refunds-80ed4cb2fc6f</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 name=&quot;d571&quot; id=&quot;d571&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf--leading&quot;&gt;Act two&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5710&quot; id=&quot;5710&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf--hasDropCapModel graf--hasDropCap graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;graf-dropCap&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;hat you read above was not meant to impress you — the reader — it was meant to impress Jabra executives. You see, after the Jabra Support representative casually admitted that they are just playing mind games with me, I was pissed, but after the Team Lead told me to stick my request for a refund up my …, I was furious. I have realized Jabra is never going to take me seriously and my only hope is to play the public shaming card. But there is a good chance no will give a single damn about my little rant, and I wanted to make sure I get my refund before I fire my only shot. So I made a plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bff4&quot; id=&quot;bff4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Step 1: no matter what the support said, I applied for the warranty and sent the headset off to an authorized repair shop. I don’t want it on my hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8e96&quot; id=&quot;8e96&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Step 2: I wrote the &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Act one&lt;/em&gt; of this blog post and,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;de7c&quot; id=&quot;de7c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;step 3: I cheerfully opened a LinkedIn.com in a new browser window!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;05b4&quot; id=&quot;05b4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Once the first Jabra employee added me as a connection, I was only one degree of separation away from most Jabra executives. Some people collect LinkedIn connections as if they were a meaningful indicator of professional influence (am I too cynical?). In any case, I was soon connected to a dozen Jabra directors and managers. Researching the Jabra.com website revealed the email addresses format is the typical {first_name_initial}+{surname}+”@jabra.com”. (The other typical format would be {first name}+”.”+{surname}+”@jabra.com”). With names, titles and addresses, I could start emailing my new friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;2c72&quot; id=&quot;2c72&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr CEO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;2c8d&quot; id=&quot;2c8d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;6.0840336134454&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing a blog post about my experience with your flagship headset but I am struggling with the title. I am afraid that “&lt;a href=&quot;https:///medium.com&quot; data-href=&quot;https:///medium.com&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--blockquote-anchor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jabra is falsely advertising its “bluetooth” headsets&lt;/a&gt;” is just not cutting it, if I want it to go viral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;196a&quot; id=&quot;196a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you happen to have any ideas?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;a08e&quot; id=&quot;a08e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e85e&quot; id=&quot;e85e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;Some of the reactions are worth mentioning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3007&quot; id=&quot;3007&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Managing Director Nigel was so kind as to let me know on LinkedIn that my email address may have been hacked because someone with my name sent him an uncomplimentary review on their products! Dear Nigel, I know the story sounds unbelievable, but this is indeed how your company treats its customers. I know, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7a5e&quot; id=&quot;7a5e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Senior Director Claus, who was first to offer to escalate my case internally, wrote that he read my blog post with interest and that he is “happy to see you are not without humor”. Dear Claus, the humor is a facade. I have spent many hours haggling with your support team and many more hours writing an unnecessary blog post, depressed and anxious about the outcome. Cheating is not funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1fce&quot; id=&quot;1fce&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;Then things escalated quickly. I received a full refund soon and I was even told to keep the original headset or to choose any other headset as a token of appreciation — thanks but no, thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 15:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dandare</dc:creator>
<og:title>Jabra: we know our Bluetooth headsets don’t work with laptops. Sorry, no refunds.</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@daniel_36042/jabra-we-know-our-bluetooth-headsets-dont-work-with-laptops-sorry-no-refunds-80ed4cb2fc6f</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*KTbrsW0hXQU9BglevDln_Q.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>In the end, Jabra casually admitted they knew the whole time their flagship “bluetooth” headset will never work with any laptop.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@daniel_36042/jabra-we-know-our-bluetooth-headsets-dont-work-with-laptops-sorry-no-refunds-80ed4cb2fc6f</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Startup with no website - GuerillaClick@gmail.com</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19094818</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19094818</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Show HN: Startup with no website - GuerillaClick@gmail.com&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.504451038576&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.0385756676558&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;19094818&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19094818&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Show HN: Startup with no website - GuerillaClick@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.75&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_19094818&quot;&gt;234 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=eralpb&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;eralpb&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19094818&quot;&gt;10 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_19094818&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=19094818&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D19094818&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Show%20HN%3A%20Startup%20with%20no%20website%20-%20GuerillaClick%40gmail.com&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Show%20HN%3A%20Startup%20with%20no%20website%20-%20GuerillaClick%40gmail.com&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=19094818&amp;amp;auth=beaac5d9fba024bd49b45d67d9bf9f584e99d304&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19094818&quot;&gt;156 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;Hey there, there are lot of disposable email services, but as I was thinking I realized 95% of the time, I don't care about my inbox. I just want to &quot;verify my email&quot;.
&lt;p&gt;That's why I created a startup with no website, it's called guerillaclick@gmail.com, it's a credible domain (you don't say) and it will click on any &quot;verify&quot; links you send it to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use aliases to get around of duplicate emails in the target system, so like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;guerillaclick+eralp@gmail.com guerillaclick+sdfaskdma@gmail.com guerillaclick+111@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so choose an alias and start using the service!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will provide a website to see the inbox of your alias. (maybe for services who send your pw in the email, but then you might be better off using other established servers.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gmail API is a bit slow so it might take 30 seconds for email to be received on my end, keep in mind while testing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Summer 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 13:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>eralpb</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19094818</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>There and Snack Again: How to Eat Everything in the Lord of the Rings</title>
<link>https://www.nate-crowley.com/single-post/2019/02/05/There-and-Snack-Again-How-to-eat-everything-in-Lord-of-the-Rings</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nate-crowley.com/single-post/2019/02/05/There-and-Snack-Again-How-to-eat-everything-in-Lord-of-the-Rings</guid>
<description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;In February 2018, my wife &amp;amp; I decided to embark on a gruelling quest: &lt;span&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://mashable.com/2018/02/18/lord-of-the-rings-marathon-menu/?europe=true#BrZ5gzZS8kqB&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot;&gt;to watch all three Lord of the Rings films (extended editions, of course), while attempting to eat everything that got eaten on screen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; . We were doing it in memory of my parents, who had both recently died, and who had loved both LOTR and good food. It blew up into a bit of a thing online, so we've decided to do it again this year (2019), starting at 6am on Saturday February 16th. And this time, we're inviting you to watch - and eat - along with us. In this article, I'll tell you all you need to know to follow in our footsteps: what to buy, how to prepare it, and when in the films to eat it.   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; width=&quot;341&quot; src=&quot;https://static.wixstatic.com/media/6cdb7d_8117294bb36548a7beb1babfe744e037~mv2.png/v1/fill/w_341,h_238/6cdb7d_8117294bb36548a7beb1babfe744e037~mv2.png&quot; height=&quot;238&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Reason for the Season&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;First, a bit of sentiment. As stated in the intro to this post, the whole reason for doing something this ridiculous was as a warm, joyful way to remember my parents. Dad died in February 2017, and by the time the first anniversary of his death came around, I’d lost mum as well. And so, on the eve of that drizzly day in February 2018, my wife Ashleigh and I found ourselves in their suddenly-empty house, with two lifetimes’ worth of sentimental junk to tidy away.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m not going to lie: I was feeling a bit grim. But if there was ever a story about facing an impossible task and refusing to be beaten down by it, it’s LOTR. Those stories had been perennial favourites of my parents, and we’d watched them together several times over the years. The other thing we’d always done together was cook: cook, and eat, and talk about cooking while eating.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Suddenly, looking at Frodo’s face staring pensively at me from the DVD box set in my parents’ living room, I knew what we had to do. We were going to go to the shops, get a good night’s sleep, and get up at dawn the next day with a ludicrous objective: marathon the whole LOTR trilogy, while eating an approximation of every dish that appeared on screen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And we managed it. We laughed, we cried, and we ate a lot of lembas bread. And as I live-tweeted our progress, we ended up with hundreds of thousands of people cheering us on. When it was all over, a good number of those people asked if they could join in for our next attempt - and so for them, I’ve written this guide. I hope it’s useful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re going to be starting this year’s marathon on Saturday 16th February, at the frankly insane hour of 6am, and this time we’ll be joined by our daughter, who was born six months ago. We like to think that if we’re Frodo and Sam in this journey, she’s Gollum.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Anyway, let’s get to it. If you’ve got any questions, or if you just want to follow the action on the day, you can find me on twitter at @frogcroakley.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Otherwise, let’s go #ThereAndSnackAgain….&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;(PS - as it's likely to be item #1 on my FAQ - yes, I would like to write a vegan version of this guide, but I don't know if I'll have time before the 16th. Nevertheless, if anyone else wants to propose a menu, I'd love to hear about it!)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Preparing for the journey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Researching online, I found quite a few people who had created menus to accompany LOTR marathons, but they all seemed a bit… sanitised. Typically, they comprised five to nine courses, each of which was ‘inspired’ by the food on screen, but bore little resemblance to it. They all seemed very pleasant and technically accomplished, but felt first and foremost like attempts to create a delicious themed banquet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I wanted our eat-along to be as epic as the story itself: relentless, extended, and occasionally pretty gruelling. And so, armed only with my memory of having watched the movies more times than I’d care to admit, we made a list of everything we thought got eaten in the films, and went to the shops to buy it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Here’s our shopping list, modified a little in hindsight, which you can use if you’d like to - below, there follows a guide on when to cook, prepare and eat the various dishes we did, as well as notes on optional extra courses, and the ingredients you will need for them:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;font_8&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;font_8&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;DRINKS&lt;/span&gt; : 1 box regular tea bags, 1 box herbal tea bags, 1 bottle sparkling water, 1 bottle chocolate milk, 1 bottle lemonade, 1 carton red grape juice, ale as required.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;FRUIT &amp;amp; VEG:&lt;/span&gt; 1 bag of apples, 1 carrot, 1 large pack cherry tomatoes, 4 large field mushrooms, 1 bag/tin new potatoes, 1 small pack of casserole veg, 3 varieties pickled vegetables, 2 large bunches of grapes, 1 tin tomato soup.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;BREADS&lt;/span&gt; : 1 sweet cake, 1 loaf rye bread, 1 pack lembas bread substitute.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;MEAT &amp;amp; FISH&lt;/span&gt; : 12 chipolata sausages, 6 rashers smoked streaky bacon, 1 whole chicken, 1 rack of ribs, 1 rabbit, 2 fillets smoked trout, 1 jar rilettes or tin of preserved pork, 1 jar sardine paste.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;DAIRY&lt;/span&gt; : 1 pack butter, 4+ varieties of cheese.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;EXTRAS&lt;/span&gt; : 1 tub hummus, 1 jar pesto, 1 pack rock salt.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;SNAX FOR GOLLUM&lt;/span&gt; : 1 pack jelly worms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;General considerations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Before you leave the Shire, here’s a few travel tips we gleaned from our journey:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;font_8&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Start early&lt;/span&gt; - The extended trilogy runs to 11hrs36m without credits, and considering you will need to take a few breaks to prepare food, you can easily expect to add two or three hours to this. We started at 6am, and will do so again this year, but that just means we had a great excuse to huddle under a duvet with our pyjamas on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Prepare what you can beforehand&lt;/span&gt; - With the exception of the rabbit stew (which should ideally go on the night before), all the meals listed require less than 30 minutes’ cooking time. Even so, if you can spare an hour the night before to get cold courses prepared, plated, and put in the fridge, you will save a lot of time on the day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Think small&lt;/span&gt; - Even with a halfling’s appetite, you will fill up quickly if your eyes get too big for your stomach. Err on the side of caution with portion size, and certainly keep meals small until the Two Towers. Wherever possible, you should finish each course wishing you had a little more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Scaling up&lt;/span&gt; - This menu is designed for 2 people. Scale up ingredient numbers to cater for a larger fellowship, or consider including some of the optional dishes detailed, with a view to shaaaaaring the looooad.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Do not lose heart&lt;/span&gt; - Depending on what options you take, this menu can account for between 20 and 40 courses, which seems pretty daunting. Nevertheless, many of these courses are single bites, or tiny drinks. In our experience, there were only four five dishes I’d count as major meals, which is pretty achievable - for a hobbit at least - in the space of 15 hours. We kept our portions fairly restrained, and weren’t shy to leave leftovers, so we never felt unpleasantly full.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Choose your house rules&lt;/span&gt; - The menu you set will depend on what rules you choose for your marathon. For the truly hardcore, I’ve included asterisks to indicate the meals which are actually seen being eaten on screen. My recommended menu contains almost all of these, but also some meals that represent food shown, or even abstract concepts. (NOTE: I’ve counted a meal as eaten even when it is interrupted by an attack out of nowhere by ghosts or monsters; a circumstance which occurs surprisingly often.) - so often, food gets prepared only to be abandoned as ghosts or monsters attack from nowhere.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drinks&lt;/span&gt; - There’s a lot of ale in LOTR. Due in part to Ashleigh being pregnant, and the fact I didn’t want to be shitfaced by Helm’s Deep, we didn’t include this in our menu. I have included a few of the soft drink options we identified, but a booze-along trilogy marathon is a different story indeed (see: Challenge Rules).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;So, we’ve spent enough time getting ready - let’s set out for Mordor!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Fellowship of the Ring&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;GENERAL NOTES: Although it can be tempting to make a hearty start, keep your powder dry during Fellowship. There’s a very high frequency of food shown, and in the film’s middle portion the fry-ups come thick and fast. Don’t follow the light of Too Many sausages, or you’ll end up in the cursed marsh of Feeling Full By 10am. Remember: you only need to match what’s eaten.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1) Tea and Cake*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As soon as are we introduced to Hobbits by Bilbo, we see one pinching a cake off a tray. Cut yourself a decent slice, and wash it down with a cup of sweet, milky tea to start the day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: After the introduction, Gandalf visits Bilbo and we get a good look at his larder - tomatoes, bread, cheese and jams are all in abundance here, so you could create a small buffet to match. Also worth noting Bilbo’s immortal statement about feeling like ‘butter scraped over too much bread’...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2) Cake - Round Two&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Although it’s not explicitly seen being consumed, Bilbo’s enormous birthday cake is quite a spectacle, and probably deserves a second slice of whatever you’re having. IMPORTANT: whether you attempt this or not, make sure to save some cake for later.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;3) A Bite of an Apple*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Merry takes a cheeky chomp from an apple as he prepares to create havoc with Gandalf’s fireworks, and you should do the same. The rest of the apple can be chopped and put into the rabbit stew, which should already be simmering.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: We see a cheeseboard in the scene with the Gaffer in the pub. Soon afterwards, Frodo packs apples and bread for his journey. You could choose to honour these appearances. On Sam &amp;amp; Frodo’s early journey out of the shire, we see Sam cooking sausages, mushrooms and bacon - you *could* choose to eat them then, but since we don’t see them being eaten, I think it’s best to use this scene as a signal to get them under the grill for the scenes to come.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;4) Sam’s Midnight Bread*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the first night out of the Shire, Sam inexplicably wolfs down a bite from a loaf right before he goes to sleep. This seems like it should be replicated, but please don’t go to sleep.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: As Frodo &amp;amp; Sam encounter Merry &amp;amp; Pippin, we see they have armfuls of stolen vegetables. They also find mushrooms as they fall down the hill. You could choose this moment for some sauteed vegetables, but it’s equally acceptable to just have someone run through the viewing room with an armful of cabbages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;5) Peter Jackson Gnashes On a Carrot*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As we are introduced to the Prancing Pony, we see Peter Jackson make his first cameo, as a carrot-chomping yokel. It’s pretty easy to match this, especially if you got the carrots out in the escape from the farmer’s field.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: In the Pony itself, a plate of bread is visible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;6) Second Breakfast*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;When Pippin asks Aragorn about Second Breakfast, he is thrown an apple. I chose a variety called Rockit for this scene, as they are sweet, red and perfectly hobbit-sized. Whatever type of apple you choose, it must be thrown and caught.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;7) Weathertop Fry Up*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Before the hobbits are attacked by Mean Local Ghost Kings, they begin preparing a fry-up of Tomatoes, Sausages, Crispy Bacon, and Mushrooms. Smart viewers will have put these under the grill at the sign of Sam’s fry-up listed above. I recommend eating the bacon, mushrooms and tomatoes here, but leaving the sausages to cool. Whatever you do, make sure you keep half your sausages in reserve for Two Towers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;8) Arwen’s Horse Spell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;When Liv Tyler summons a load of horses made out of river to wash away the Mean Ghost Kings, it’s a timely reminder to stay hydrated. Why not drink a refreshing pint of sparkling water to represent the magic in the water?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;9) Sausages and Bread*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the start of the second disc of Fellowship (if you’re watching on DVD), the Fellowship stops on the way to the Gap of Rohan for some fight practice and a light lunch. Now is a great time to eat the sausages you grilled earlier, along with some buttered rye bread.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: When the hobbits are practising fighting with Boromir and Aragorn, an apple rolls past Aragorn’s head - if you’re not sick of the bloody things, you could honour this. More significantly, the entrance to Moria offers two potential bonus courses. The Fellowship’s casual ganking of a giant octopus outside the mines could be an excuse for calamari, while Gimli’s excitement over Red Meat Off the Bone could justify a T-bone steak for those of a truly dwarven constitution.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;10) Lembas in Lothlorien&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In Galadriel’s weird Ewok village, the iconic travel staple of Lembas Bread is introduced. Even if you choose not to eat it until the characters do, you should get it out now. Our marathon inspired endless debates about what Lembas Bread should be represented by - some said shortbread, others said drop scones, while some even argued for Kendal Mint Cake. We opted for Jacob’s Butter Puffs, which we would have wrapped in banana leaf if we had been better prepared. We also paired them with hummus and pesto - while this was a bit of an embellishment, it seemed like an appropriately elven thing to do.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Two Towers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;GENERAL NOTES: This film sees the bulk of your eating during the marathon, and should begin in late morning, between 9.30 and 11.00 - if you get it right, you’ll have had the bulk of the food before midday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;11) The Best Salt in the Shire, Hypothetical Chicken&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is an odd, slightly metaphysical course, but one I think it’s important to include. Sam makes a big deal of having brought along a taste of home - the best salt in the shire - in case they find a chicken to roast. Frodo finds this very touching, and so we decided to recreate the moment by licking some seasoned salt while gazing longingly at the chicken we had prepared for eating during ROTK.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;12) A Bit Of Lembas Bread*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;You’ll get used to whipping out the Lembas bread, but this is (I think) its on-screen debut as a consumed item.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;13) Orc Power Drink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;While Merry &amp;amp; Pippin are being given a piggyback by the Uruk-Hai, complaints of illness see Merry being forcefed a revolting brown ‘medicine’ by the hulking, tusked jokers. While I suspect the liquid was probably more akin to Jagermeister, we decided to be kind to ourselves and have a bottle of chocolate milk instead. If you can find it, a bitter Italian Chinotto drink would be a great non-alcoholic alternative.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;14) Looks Like Meat’s Back on the Menu, Boys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;For my money, this is one of the best moments in the trilogy, if only for the haunting implication that orcs understand the concept of a menu. There will come a blog post where I consider the idea that orcs have a cultural memory of a more civilised existence. Where I wonder if maybe they are good people who have been woefully misrepresented in a history told by its victors. But it is not this blog post. For this scene, we cooked ribs in a dry rub, and arranged them like a busted-open ribcage over chipolatas roasted in a string as ‘guts’. You could use other meats - be creative. Whatever you do, make sure this is a larger meal than most on the list, and make sure your diorama of a ravaged orc has a face, in order to capture the horror of cannibalism. We used a biscuit with half-olives for eyes, an angry expression drawn in tomato paste, and pine nuts for tusks. Eat with savage gusto.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;15) Gollum Eats a Worm*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Does what it says on the tin. Unless you are feeling truly brutal, I recommend a gummy worm sweet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: There is another opportunity to eat Lembas Bread here, for the committed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;16) Gimli tastes Orc Blood*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As Aragorn, Legolas and Gimli seek the ‘White Wizard’, old Gims licks a blade of grass and remarks on it being orc blood. Best not to think too much about how he knew the taste. In any case, this can be handily replicated by saving the juices from roasting the ‘Meat’s Back’ ribs, and tasting them. Eerily reminiscent of the doctrine of transubstantiation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;17) Entish Draught&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;While being looked after by treebeard, Merry &amp;amp; Pippin cement their status as the Main Idiots of the trilogy by quaffing the ents’ special energy drink for trees. We chose to represent this with a jug of lemonade, which was very welcome after the salty meat of the orc. Feel free to fight over the lemonade, stand on tiptoe, and make weird rumbling noises in between gulps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;18) Soup at Edoras; Cheese &amp;amp; Bread&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;When the two children from the burnt village arrive at Edoras (Rohan’s capital, which now retrospectively looks like a Skyrim ripoff) on a horse, they are fed a red soup. Right afterwards, Gimli tucks into a selection of cheeses, and possibly some dry-cured ham. Although technically two separate meals, we chose to conflate them into one, with tomato soup and a cheeseboard. A bit of serrano ham probably wouldn’t go amiss either.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;19) Rabbit, Stew, Taters Cooked Three Ways*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sam has an argument with Gollum about food, which culminates in the weird grey baby man taking a bite out of a rabbit like it was an apple. Unless you can find or prepare some cured rabbit, I recommend skipping this moment and instead just enjoying a facsimile of the stew Sam cooks to demonstrate the proper preparation of a ‘brace of coneys’. It should be a simple stew, cooked for as long as possible to help the rabbit fall off the bone, and with a few root vegetables mixed in. Dry cider and rosemary make a good liquid base, but Rioja also works. Sam’s advice on potatoes - “boil ‘em, mash ‘em, stick ‘em in a stew” - also inspired us to serve a triple side dish of new potatoes, cooked in the ways prescribed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: During his row with Gollum, Sam offers a hearty shout out to Fish &amp;amp; Chips (with big fat chips), which you could use as an excuse to eat that dish, if you were feeling really committed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;20) Vile Fish Stew*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is without doubt the low point of the whole experience, but in my opinion can’t be avoided. On the road to Helm’s Deep, Eowyn cooks a horrendous, fatty fish stew which Gimli turns down entirely, and Aragorn tries (with desperate politeness) to pretend is edible. To honour this, I made an unfortunate broth comprising cheap sardine paste, rye bread crumbs and butter, which we each sampled grimly, before tipping into the garden. This is the only moment of conscious waste in the whole marathon, but I think it’s an acceptable sacrifice. After trying the stew, Aragorn sits for a long while in the dark with a haunted expression, smoking his pipe until he passes out. After following his lead, you will feel his pain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: It doesn’t get much harder than this scene, but it’s worth noting the peculiar scene just after, dedicated to showing how many potatoes were brought to helm’s deep. I guess you could eat some potato here.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;21) Fish a la Gollum #1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;After being captured by Faramir, Frodo watches Gollum brain and consumes a fish from the forbidden pool. Raw salmon or trout would be most faithful here, but considering Ashleigh was pregnant, we opted for a fillet of cooked, smoked trout. (Although I did waggle the plate as she ate it, to give some semblance of life). After the revolting fish stew, this is hardly the most welcome course of the meal.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;22) Isengard Quenched&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;When Treebeard releases the river into Isengard, Saruman’s subterranean alchemy is quenched, releasing torrents of chemical steam. This is a good moment for a big, digestion-aiding mug of herbal tea, which also helps wash away the last of the lingering fish stew tastes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: Soon after the fall of Isengard, Merry &amp;amp; Pippin find a load of preserved meat and vegetables stored by Saruman (or as I like to call him, Isengard Kingsom Brunel). Return of the King begins with the eating of these supplies, but you could start now if you were so inclined.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Return of the King&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;GENERAL NOTES: You’ve now completed the bulk of the endeavour - congrats! This movie is actually fairly light on meals, but contains possibly the largest of them all - so if you are playing this right, you should still have a decent appetite when the opening credits roll.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;23) Fish a la Gollum #2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The film begins with a seriously dark set of reminiscences by Gollum, in which he reflects on ‘forgetting the taste of bread’ as he bites into a flabby, raw fish. You could repeat the course from the forbidden pool here, or get really accurate by serving a fillet of catfish, the type of fish portrayed in the scene.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;br clear=&quot;none&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;24) Yet More Le&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;mbas Bread*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Self-explanatory….&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;25) Isengard Stores*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As introduced at the end of Two Towers. Gimli gets particularly excited by the salted pork in Saruman’s store, and so pork rilettes (or even tinned ham) are a perfect centrepiece for this meal. There’s a wealth of different vegetables and meats portrayed here, so you can be quite liberal when planning this dish - we opted for cornichons, pickled onions, smoked cheese, pickled red cabbage and preserved sweet peppers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;26) Hail, the Victorious Dead!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;At Edoras, Theoden leads a feast to commemorate the fallen at Helm’s Deep. This is the booziest scene in the trilogy, and given its memorial nature, was the one scene where I matched the characters’ drinking (or at least some of it - I didn’t want to end up like Gimli). When Theoden toasted the dead, and Aragorn paused for a long moment before drinking, I got some dust in my eye.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: While this scene is focused on the quaffing of ale, there is plenty of food on show, including plenty of cheeses, and an entire roast hog. For a large party of marathoners, an attempt could be made to replicate this.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;SUPER HARD MODE: During the remainder of the film, there are at least two scenes (Osgiliath, and the Beacon) where Gondorian soldiers are seen eating from bowls. While we thought hard about including Ambiguous Gondorian Stew on our meal list, we decided on the headcanon that the soldiers were ‘just making coffee’, and so let ourselves off. Will you be so weak?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;27) Denethor’s Grim Dinner*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Perhaps the most intense eating scene of the trilogy comes when Denethor, the miserable steward of Gondor, monsters his way through a grisly dinner of cold chicken, grapes and cherry tomatoes as his son rides towards certain death. It is vital to properly roleplay this scene in order to feel the full horror of it: diners should tear the chicken apart with grim ferocity, burst tomatoes unpleasantly between their teeth, and dribble plenty of red grape juice. It’s horrendous, but necessary. For perfect scene setting, you should arrive at this scene not so full that you can’t bear to eat more, but full enough that it seems slightly gratuitous to do so. It’s the last significant meal of the trilogy, so go for a sprint finish&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;28) Grond&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Although no food is consumed during its time in the film, I feel that Grond - the colossal, wolf-headed battering ram used to batter down the gates of Minas Tirith - is possibly the best single thing in the LOTR trilogy. As such, and as the self-appointed leader of the Grond Fandom, I insist this terrible weapon deserves special recognition in any marathon. Maybe you could choose to down a horrendously potent drink to acknowledge Grond, or kick over a model gate? Maybe you could just chant its name. Whatever you do, don’t let Grond go unremarked upon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HARD MODE: When Sam &amp;amp; Frodo are struggling up the slopes of Mt Doom, Sam tries to coax life into Frodo by reminding him of the taste of Strawberries. If you can keep yourself together at this point (goodness knows we couldn’t), you could try to share a punnet of strawberries.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;29) There And Back Again&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally, when it’s all nearly over, and the hobbits return to the Shire to try and recapture a sense of their old lives, bring out the cake you had a slice of, all those hours ago at the start of Fellowship, and share the last of it. Think about everything that has happened since then, and how you’ve changed since that innocent time. Reflect on the impossibility of recapturing the past, but console yourself with knowing that all good things come to an end, and that one has to discover a way to move on. I will not say do not weep, for not all tears are an evil.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And there you have it! You’ve completed your adventure, and things will never be the same. Hopefully it will have been fun, and maybe it will even have been meaningful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;For us, LOTR was a great way to bring cheer to an event with a very solemn purpose. It’s a story about the ending of things, and of the passing of wonder from the world - but it’s also a story about how, against that dark backdrop, good folk will go to enormous lengths for the things and the people they love. Even if that just means eating a 25 course meal in your pyjamas.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Appendix: Challenge modes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Is the above somehow not enough of a challenge for you? Why not impose some of these additional rules:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;font_8&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ale Mode&lt;/span&gt; : Attempt to match the characters drink for drink, using strong ale. Not recommended.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Smoke-along&lt;/span&gt; : Attempt to smoke along with Gandalf, Bilbo, Aragorn, Gimli, Merry &amp;amp; Pippin, using your own interpretation of the ‘Halfling’s Leaf’. By the end of Fellowship, you’ll be fighting a deep wave of blackness, and if you remember ROTK at all, you’ll probably think you were inside the film. May help with appetite, however.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Elf Mode&lt;/span&gt; : Only consume vegan ingredients from the list above. Substitutions may be made where meals are meat-only - for Meat’s Back on the Menu, you might want to draw an angry face on a roast cauliflower.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;One(ion) Ring To Rule Them All&lt;/span&gt; : During the introduction of Fellowship, one viewer (representing Sauron) cooks and presents a single onion ring to the group, which must not be eaten. One viewer is elected as Ringbearer, and must hold the onion ring for the entire trilogy. Other viewers must constantly try and cajole them into giving it up, but they must stay strong until the climax of ROTK, when a player taking the role of Gollum gets to eat it. You may also make use of a chocolate finger at this point, for added realism.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font_9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;LARP of the Rings&lt;/span&gt; : For larger parties. Each viewer is assigned a character from the film. They may only participate in meals their character is eating on screen. Combine this with the onion ring rule above, and you’re basically conducting an indoor LARP of Lord of the Rings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 12:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fanf2</dc:creator>
<og:title>There and Snack Again: How to eat everything in Lord of the Rings</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.nate-crowley.com/single-post/2019/02/05/There-and-Snack-Again-How-to-eat-everything-in-Lord-of-the-Rings</og:url>
<og:image>https://static.wixstatic.com/media/6cdb7d_8117294bb36548a7beb1babfe744e037%7Emv2.png</og:image>
<og:description>In February 2018, my wife &amp; I decided to embark on a gruelling quest: to watch all three Lord of the Rings films (extended editions, of course), while attemptin...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nate-crowley.com/single-post/2019/02/05/There-and-Snack-Again-How-to-eat-everything-in-Lord-of-the-Rings?_escaped_fragment_=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Compounding Knowledge</title>
<link>https://fs.blog/2019/02/compounding-knowledge/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://fs.blog/2019/02/compounding-knowledge/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The filing cabinet of knowledge stored in Warren Buffet’s brain has helped make him the most successful investor of our time. But it takes much more than simply reading a lot. In this article, learn how to create your own “snowball effect” to compound what you know into opportunity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice Schroeder, the author of Warren Buffett’s authorized biography &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0553384619/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=farnamstreet-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0553384619&amp;amp;linkId=abbb49dc04056132a9b34297fb8adb5b&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Snowball&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, tells the story of getting into Buffet’s thinking in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NrPBr8iFL9k&amp;amp;index=14&amp;amp;list=WL&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;informative talk&lt;/a&gt;. In her words,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting [at a young age] he’s read everything that he could find about business. The subject that interests him, he’s read newspapers, biographies, trade press. He went over to his grandfather who was a grocer and he read the progressive grocer magazine, and he read articles on how to stock a meat department. He’s gone to visit every company that he could find that was even slightly interesting to him, he went down to visit a barrel maker and spent hours talking about how to make barrels. He went to American Express, and he spent hours talking about that business, he went to GEICO and learned about the insurance business. He has stacks of reports on his desk from the companies he owns, pig stalls, jewelry, boat winches, everything you can imagine. He reads hundreds of annual reports every year from companies that he doesn’t own yet, because he just wants to understand their businesses, and then when the opportunity arises, then he’s ready and he can make a decision. What he’s really done is he’s created this immense vertical filing cabinet in his brain of layers and layers and layers of files of information that he can draw back on now for more than 70 years worth of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Expiring Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of us are on the treadmill of consuming expiring information. Not Buffett. He filled his mental filing cabinet with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fs.blog/2018/03/half-life/&quot;&gt;information that had a long half-life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While most of us focus on consuming information that we won’t care about next month, let alone next year, Buffett focused on knowledge and companies that change very, very slowly or not at all. And because the information he was learning changed slowly he could compound his knowledge over time. And as Schroeder notes, Buffett has been in business for a long time, giving him incredible opportunities to create a cumulative base of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expiring information is sexy but it’s not knowledge. Here are a few telltale signs you’re dealing with expiring information. First, it’s marketed to you. Second, lacking details and nuance, it’s easily digestible. This is why it’s commonly telling you what happened, not why it happened or under what conditions it might happen again. Third, it won’t be relevant in a month or a year.  Expiring information is &lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/2013/12/stop-reading-news/&quot;&gt;one reason&lt;/a&gt; I stopped reading most news. It’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/2015/11/map-and-territory/&quot;&gt;a false map&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is another subtle difference to Buffett’s approach that often goes unnoticed and few people talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Matching Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buffett insists on doing his own thinking and vacuums up the details. When we don’t think for ourselves it’s easy to put the blame on someone else, to “pass the buck” so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we consume information that doesn’t expire or expires slowly;  is very detailed; and we spend time thinking about it not passing the buck, we can match patterns. This is how you learn to see what other people are missing. The longer you do this, the more advantage you get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us use a computer to store information so that we can retrieve it when we need it. We’ve organized our knowledge around a computer. Not Buffett.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest thing he’s done is to learn and create this cumulative base of knowledge in his head. One reason that he doesn’t use a computer is that in a sense, he is one. He also needs a computer to get…he uses it for news. He wants to know what’s going on in the world. So he is on the internet a lot to get news reports, and he’s up late at night seeing what’s going on. He doesn’t use it as a filing cabinet or for computation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like the rest of us, Buffett’s dependent on information and knowledge to make great decisions. Unlike most of us, he has a great memory—perhaps because he’s not trying to outsource his memory or thinking to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of what the snowball is about the concept of learning, and creating, and the advantage of having the information and knowing it. When I came here today one of the things that I was thinking is that what you do is so much at the intersection, because &lt;strong&gt;retrieving information is different from having it already in your head&lt;/strong&gt;. The internet is wonderful for being able to retrieve and get information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you do is different. You work on manipulating how you use the information. In fact, Warren Buffett and Charlie Munger have the files in their head. That’s why they aren’t really out there googling all the time looking for, trying to look stuff up, because they already know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are applications that somebody who doesn’t have the upper digits memory and their computational power would need in order to be as successful as them. Sometimes when they say, we don’t use computers. An ordinary person can be them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of the work that you do here is helpful to the ordinary person, but Warren Buffett or Charlie Munger don’t need it. At the same time&lt;strong&gt;, the lesson that they have, which is that learning yourself, making yourself as smart as you can is extremely valid, and not just relying on a library where you can look something up all the time, because a lot of times when you need to make a decision, and you need 50 pieces of information, you need to know it then.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s been one of Warren Buffet’s greatest secrets of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not suggesting we all copy Buffett.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is no denying he’s successful, the way we think he developed his remarkable facility owes a great deal to living in a certain time period, with a certain biology, and a level of focus and dedication to a single pursuit that few of us can manage. That doesn’t mean we should go to the other extreme and ignore him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much we can learn from him. The key questions are: what’s he doing that works, why does it work, and can I adapt it to my circumstances?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further Considerations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Will you care about what your reading in a month? In a year? In five years?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you focused enough on the same thing to build cumulative knowledge or are you too spread out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you spend time on that’s likely to change in the next few years? What’s not likely to change?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would need to happen for you to stop outsourcing organization of information to the computer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0553384619/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=farnamstreet-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0553384619&amp;amp;linkId=abbb49dc04056132a9b34297fb8adb5b&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Snowball&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is about learning, lifelong learning. Spending some time with these questions will allow you to find ways to make your own learning and your knowledge base more powerfully productive for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Members of &lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/membership/&quot;&gt;the FS Learning Community&lt;/a&gt; can &lt;a href=&quot;https://lc.fs.blog/t/compounding-knowledge/11590&quot;&gt;discuss this article on the inside.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 12:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>golyi</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Compounding Knowledge</og:title>
<og:description>The filing cabinet of knowledge stored in Warren Buffet’s brain has helped make him the most successful investor of our time. But it takes much more than reading a lot. In this article, learn how to create your own “snowball effect” to compound what you know into opportunity.</og:description>
<og:url>https://fs.blog/2019/02/compounding-knowledge/</og:url>
<og:image>https://aub5dj147f97c3ax-zippykid.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Warren-Buffett.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://fs.blog/2019/02/compounding-knowledge/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>With React 16.8, React Hooks are available in a stable release</title>
<link>https://reactjs.org/blog/2019/02/06/react-v16.8.0.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://reactjs.org/blog/2019/02/06/react-v16.8.0.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;With React 16.8, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html&quot;&gt;React Hooks&lt;/a&gt; are available in a stable release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-hooks&quot;&gt;What Are Hooks?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hooks let you use state and other React features without writing a class. You can also &lt;strong&gt;build your own Hooks&lt;/strong&gt; to share reusable stateful logic between components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never heard of Hooks before, you might find these resources interesting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don’t have to learn Hooks right now.&lt;/strong&gt; Hooks have no breaking changes, and we have no plans to remove classes from React. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-faq.html&quot;&gt;Hooks FAQ&lt;/a&gt; describes the gradual adoption strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-big-rewrites&quot;&gt;No Big Rewrites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t recommend rewriting your existing applications to use Hooks overnight. Instead, try using Hooks in some of the new components, and let us know what you think. Code using Hooks will work &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html#gradual-adoption-strategy&quot;&gt;side by side&lt;/a&gt; with existing code using classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-i-use-hooks-today&quot;&gt;Can I Use Hooks Today?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! Starting with 16.8.0, React includes a stable implementation of React Hooks for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;React DOM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;React DOM Server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;React Test Renderer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;React Shallow Renderer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that &lt;strong&gt;to enable Hooks, all React packages need to be 16.8.0 or higher&lt;/strong&gt;. Hooks won’t work if you forget to update, for example, React DOM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;React Native will support Hooks in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/react-native-community/react-native-releases/issues/79#issuecomment-457735214&quot;&gt;0.59 release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;React Hooks are now supported by React DevTools. They are also supported in the latest Flow and TypeScript definitions for React. We strongly recommend enabling a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/eslint-plugin-react-hooks&quot;&gt;lint rule called &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;eslint-plugin-react-hooks&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to enforce best practices with Hooks. It will soon be included into Create React App by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We described our plan for the next months in the recently published &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/blog/2018/11/27/react-16-roadmap.html&quot;&gt;React Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that React Hooks don’t cover &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; use cases for classes yet but they’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-faq.html#do-hooks-cover-all-use-cases-for-classes&quot;&gt;very close&lt;/a&gt;. Currently, only &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;getSnapshotBeforeUpdate()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;componentDidCatch()&lt;/code&gt; methods don’t have equivalent Hooks APIs, and these lifecycles are relatively uncommon. If you want, you should be able to use Hooks in most of the new code you’re writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even while Hooks were in alpha, the React community created many interesting &lt;a href=&quot;https://codesandbox.io/react-hooks&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://usehooks.com&quot;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt; using Hooks for animations, forms, subscriptions, integrating with other libraries, and so on. We’re excited about Hooks because they make code reuse easier, helping you write your components in a simpler way and make great user experiences. We can’t wait to see what you’ll create next!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing-hooks&quot;&gt;Testing Hooks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have added a new API called &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;ReactTestUtils.act()&lt;/code&gt; in this release. It ensures that the behavior in your tests matches what happens in the browser more closely. We recommend to wrap any code rendering and triggering updates to your components into &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;act()&lt;/code&gt; calls. Testing libraries can also wrap their APIs with it (for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kentcdodds/react-testing-library&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;react-testing-library&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;render&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;fireEvent&lt;/code&gt; utilities do this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the counter example from &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-effect.html&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; can be tested like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;gatsby-code-jsx&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; React &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'react'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; ReactDOM &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'react-dom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-highlight-code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; act &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'react-dom/test-utils'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; Counter &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'./Counter'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; container&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;beforeEach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  container &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; document&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;createElement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'div'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  document&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;body&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;appendChild&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;container&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;afterEach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  document&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;body&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;removeChild&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;container&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  container &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'can render and update a counter'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-highlight-code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;act&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-highlight-code-line&quot;&gt;    ReactDOM&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;render&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;Counter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; container&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-highlight-code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; button &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; container&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;querySelector&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'button'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; label &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; container&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;querySelector&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'p'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;label&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;textContent&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;toBe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'You clicked 0 times'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;document&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;title&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;toBe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'You clicked 0 times'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

  
&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-highlight-code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;act&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-highlight-code-line&quot;&gt;    button&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;dispatchEvent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;MouseEvent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'click'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;bubbles&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token boolean&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-highlight-code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;label&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;textContent&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;toBe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'You clicked 1 times'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;document&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;title&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;toBe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'You clicked 1 times'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The calls to &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;act()&lt;/code&gt; will also flush the effects inside of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to test a custom Hook, you can do so by creating a component in your test, and using your Hook from it. Then you can test the component you wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reduce the boilerplate, we recommend using &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.io/react-testing-library&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;react-testing-library&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which is designed to encourage writing tests that use your components as the end users do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank everybody who commented on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/reactjs/rfcs/pull/68&quot;&gt;Hooks RFC&lt;/a&gt; for sharing their feedback. We’ve read all of your comments and made some adjustments to the final API based on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;react&quot;&gt;React&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;React v16.8.0 is available on the npm registry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install React 16 with Yarn, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;bash&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;gatsby-code-bash&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-bash&quot;&gt;yarn add react@^16.8.0 react-dom@^16.8.0&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install React 16 with npm, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;bash&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;gatsby-code-bash&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; --save react@^16.8.0 react-dom@^16.8.0&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also provide UMD builds of React via a CDN:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;html&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;gatsby-code-html&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;crossorigin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token attr-value&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;https://unpkg.com/react@16/umd/react.production.min.js&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;crossorigin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token attr-value&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;https://unpkg.com/react-dom@16/umd/react-dom.production.min.js&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refer to the documentation for &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/docs/installation.html&quot;&gt;detailed installation instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;eslint-plugin-for-react-hooks&quot;&gt;ESLint Plugin for React Hooks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, we strongly recommend using the &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;eslint-plugin-react-hooks&lt;/code&gt; lint rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using Create React App, instead of manually configuring ESLint you can wait for the next version of &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;react-scripts&lt;/code&gt; which will come out shortly and will include this rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you already have ESLint installed, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;sh&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;gatsby-code-sh&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-sh&quot;&gt;# npm
npm install eslint-plugin-react-hooks@next --save-dev

# yarn
yarn add eslint-plugin-react-hooks@next --dev&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then add it to your ESLint configuration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;gatsby-code-jsx&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;plugins&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;react-hooks&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;rules&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;react-hooks/rules-of-hooks&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;error&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;changelog&quot;&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;react-1&quot;&gt;React&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html&quot;&gt;Hooks&lt;/a&gt; — a way to use state and other React features without writing a class. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/acdlite&quot;&gt;@acdlite&lt;/a&gt; et al. in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/13968&quot;&gt;#13968&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve the &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useReducer&lt;/code&gt; Hook lazy initialization API. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/acdlite&quot;&gt;@acdlite&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14723&quot;&gt;#14723&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;react-dom&quot;&gt;React DOM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bail out of rendering on identical values for &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useState&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useReducer&lt;/code&gt; Hooks. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/acdlite&quot;&gt;@acdlite&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14569&quot;&gt;#14569&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t compare the first argument passed to &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useEffect&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useMemo&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useCallback&lt;/code&gt; Hooks. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/acdlite&quot;&gt;@acdlite&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14594&quot;&gt;#14594&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;Object.is&lt;/code&gt; algorithm for comparing &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useState&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useReducer&lt;/code&gt; values. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Jessidhia&quot;&gt;@Jessidhia&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14752&quot;&gt;#14752&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support synchronous thenables passed to &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;React.lazy()&lt;/code&gt;. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gaearon&quot;&gt;@gaearon&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14626&quot;&gt;#14626&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Render components with Hooks twice in Strict Mode (DEV-only) to match class behavior. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gaearon&quot;&gt;@gaearon&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14654&quot;&gt;#14654&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warn about mismatching Hook order in development. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/threepointone&quot;&gt;@threepointone&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14585&quot;&gt;#14585&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/acdlite&quot;&gt;@acdlite&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14591&quot;&gt;#14591&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effect clean-up functions must return either &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt; or a function. All other values, including &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;, are not allowed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/acdlite&quot;&gt;@acdlite&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14119&quot;&gt;#14119&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;react-test-renderer&quot;&gt;React Test Renderer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support Hooks in the shallow renderer. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/trueadm&quot;&gt;@trueadm&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14567&quot;&gt;#14567&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix wrong state in &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;shouldComponentUpdate&lt;/code&gt; in the presence of &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;getDerivedStateFromProps&lt;/code&gt; for Shallow Renderer. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chenesan&quot;&gt;@chenesan&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14613&quot;&gt;#14613&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;ReactTestRenderer.act()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;ReactTestUtils.act()&lt;/code&gt; for batching updates so that tests more closely match real behavior. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/threepointone&quot;&gt;@threepointone&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14744&quot;&gt;#14744&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;eslint-plugin-react-hooks&quot;&gt;ESLint Plugin: React Hooks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hooks-changelog-since-alpha-versions&quot;&gt;Hooks Changelog Since Alpha Versions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above changelog contains all notable changes since our last &lt;strong&gt;stable&lt;/strong&gt; release (16.7.0). &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/docs/faq-versioning.html&quot;&gt;As with all our minor releases&lt;/a&gt;, none of the changes break backwards compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re currently using Hooks from an alpha build of React, note that this release does contain some small breaking changes to Hooks. &lt;strong&gt;We don’t recommend depending on alphas in production code.&lt;/strong&gt; We publish them so we can make changes in response to community feedback before the API is stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are all breaking changes to Hooks that have been made since the first alpha release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remove &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useMutationEffect&lt;/code&gt;. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sophiebits&quot;&gt;@sophiebits&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14336&quot;&gt;#14336&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useImperativeMethods&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useImperativeHandle&lt;/code&gt;. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/threepointone&quot;&gt;@threepointone&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14565&quot;&gt;#14565&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bail out of rendering on identical values for &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useState&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useReducer&lt;/code&gt; Hooks. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/acdlite&quot;&gt;@acdlite&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14569&quot;&gt;#14569&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t compare the first argument passed to &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useEffect&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useMemo&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useCallback&lt;/code&gt; Hooks. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/acdlite&quot;&gt;@acdlite&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14594&quot;&gt;#14594&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;Object.is&lt;/code&gt; algorithm for comparing &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useState&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useReducer&lt;/code&gt; values. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Jessidhia&quot;&gt;@Jessidhia&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14752&quot;&gt;#14752&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Render components with Hooks twice in Strict Mode (DEV-only). (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gaearon&quot;&gt;@gaearon&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14654&quot;&gt;#14654&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve the &lt;code class=&quot;gatsby-code-text&quot;&gt;useReducer&lt;/code&gt; Hook lazy initialization API. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/acdlite&quot;&gt;@acdlite&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/react/pull/14723&quot;&gt;#14723&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 08:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Vinnl</dc:creator>
<og:title>React v16.8: The One With Hooks – React Blog</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://reactjs.org/blog/2019/02/06/react-v16.8.0.html</og:url>
<og:image>/logo-og.png</og:image>
<og:description>With React 16.8, React Hooks are available in a stable release! What Are Hooks? Hooks let you use state and other React features without writing a class. You can also build your own Hooks to share reusable stateful logic between components. If you’ve never heard of Hooks before, you might find these resources interesting: Introducing Hooks explains why we’re adding Hooks to React. Hooks at a Glance is a fast-paced overview of the built-in Hooks. Building Your Own Hooks demonstrates code…</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://reactjs.org/blog/2019/02/06/react-v16.8.0.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vanlife: Build your own van to live on the road</title>
<link>https://divineontheroad.com/build-a-van/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://divineontheroad.com/build-a-van/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://divineontheroad.com/build-a-van/&quot;&gt;https://divineontheroad.com/build-a-van/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19092074&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19092074&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 329&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 190&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 02:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>xbeta</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://divineontheroad.com/build-a-van/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dutch radio amateurs image far side of the Moon using Chinese satellite data</title>
<link>https://www.camras.nl/en/blog/2018/precious-earth-and-lunar-far-side/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.camras.nl/en/blog/2018/precious-earth-and-lunar-far-side/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;Far side of the Moon photographed by amateurs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This image shows the far side of the Moon, as well as our own planet Earth. It was taken with a camera linked to an amateur radio transceiver on board the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lilacsat.hit.edu.cn/wp/?page_id=844&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Chinese DSLWP-B / Longjiang-2 satellite&lt;/a&gt; (call sign BJ1SN), currently in orbit around the Moon, and transmitted back to Earth where it was received with the Dwingeloo Telescope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This image represents the culmination of several observing sessions spread over the past few months where we used the Dwingeloo telescope in collaboration with the Chinese team from Harbin University of Technology, who build the radio transceiver on board Longjiang-2, and radio amateurs spread across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these sessions we tested receiving telemetry through low-bit rate and error-resistant digitally modulated transmissions, as well as the JT4G modulation&lt;br/&gt;scheme designed by radio amateur and Nobel prize winning astrophysicist Joe Taylor (K1JT) for weak signal Moon bounce experiments. Besides telemetry, we performed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://destevez.net/2018/06/validation-of-dslwp-b-orbit-determination-using-vlbi-observations/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;VLBI experiment by simultaneously observing Longjiang-2 from China and Dwingeloo&lt;/a&gt;, and also &lt;a href=&quot;http://lilacsat.hit.edu.cn/dashboard/pages_en/pics-b.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;downloaded images taken by Longjiang-2&lt;/a&gt; of the lunar surface, lens flares, and the starry sky as seen from lunar orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transceiver on board Longjiang-2 was designed to allow radio amateurs to downlink telemetry and relay messages through a satellite in lunar orbit, as well as command it to take and downlink images. In that it has succeeded, as many radio amateurs have received telemetry and image data. Being able to use the Dwingeloo telescope to help with this has been a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This full color adjusted image is received by radio amateurs, including the radio amateurs of the Dwingeloo Radio Telescope (&lt;span aria-describedby=&quot;tt&quot; class=&quot;glossaryLink&quot; data-cmtooltip=&quot;200fba7ae5582762190f74ad76f9d439&quot;&gt;PI9CAM&lt;/span&gt;) operated by Tammo Jan Dijkema and myself. Commands were created by MingChuan Wei (BG2BHC) and uplinked by Reinhard Kuehn (DK5LA). The color correction of the image is done by Wei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/20181010-Our-precious-Earth-and-the-lunar-farside-annotaded.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-3641&quot; src=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/20181010-Our-precious-Earth-and-the-lunar-farside-annotaded.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/20181010-Our-precious-Earth-and-the-lunar-farside-annotaded.png 1024w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/20181010-Our-precious-Earth-and-the-lunar-farside-annotaded-80x60.png 80w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/20181010-Our-precious-Earth-and-the-lunar-farside-annotaded-300x225.png 300w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/20181010-Our-precious-Earth-and-the-lunar-farside-annotaded-768x576.png 768w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/20181010-Our-precious-Earth-and-the-lunar-farside-annotaded-705x529.png 705w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/20181010-Our-precious-Earth-and-the-lunar-farside-annotaded-450x338.png 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The annotated picture with names of Moon craters is made by Tammo Jan. Note that the crater Minnaert is named after the Dutch astronomer &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marcel_Minnaert&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Marcel Minnaert&lt;/a&gt;. Minnaert was member of the &lt;span aria-describedby=&quot;tt&quot; class=&quot;glossaryLink&quot; data-cmtooltip=&quot;14bab793d1de45d140a27852b17a4b81&quot;&gt;SRZM&lt;/span&gt; board in the time the Dwingeloo Radio Telescope was designed and build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Addendum after October 12, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are two other images, also slightly color corrected. The original images are &lt;a href=&quot;http://lilacsat.hit.edu.cn/dashboard/pages_en/pics-b.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The third image shows the Moon clearly seen from Dwingeloo Radio Telescope through the window of the observation room and the metal mesh of the mirror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animation below shows the Moon as seen from the DSLWP-B satellite as it orbits around the Moon. The animation pictures were taken on October 15. Data for the animation was collected by Cees Bassa and Tammo Jan Dijkema in the Dwingeloo Telescope (PI9CAM), by Imants Tukleris (YL3CT), Mike Rupprecht (DK3WN), and Dimitry Borzenko (4Z5CP). The satellite was commanded by Reinhard Kuehn (DK5LA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About this experiment, Cees Bassa and Tammo Jan Dijkema wrote a slightly more detailed blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.planetary.org/blogs/guest-blogs/imaging-the-earth-from-lunar-orbit.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Imaging the Earth from Lunar orbit&lt;/a&gt; in The Planetary Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find more recent technical info at Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PI9CAM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;@PI9CAM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more recent animation is on our newer blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/en/blog/2018/time-laps-of-the-earth-appearing-behind-the-moon/&quot;&gt;Time-lapse of the Earth appearing behind the Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Update February 4, 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a radio-quiet period to avoid interfering with the Chang’e 4 Lunar landing, DSLWP-B became active again on 13 January 2019. The first opportunity to take photos of Earth and Moon were on 3 February, on which a command was sent to take another timelapse. The first image from this timelapse was downloaded with the Dwingeloo telescope on February 4, 2019. For the first time, it the entire Moon and Earth are in view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-5931&quot; src=&quot;http://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/feb4-fixed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/feb4-fixed.jpg 640w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/feb4-fixed-80x60.jpg 80w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/feb4-fixed-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/feb4-fixed-450x338.jpg 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;In advance in December 2017&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December 2017, in preparation for the mission and discussion of the possibilities of the antennas and receivers in the radio telescope, Hu Chaoran (BG2CRY) and MingChuan Wei (BG2BHC) both of the Harbin Institute of Technology visited Harry Keizer (PE1CHQ) and Jan van Muijlwijk (PA3FXB) of CAMRAS. On the photo in front of the Dwingeloo Radio Telescope to the left Jan, in the middle Chaoran, and to the right Wei. In fact the Dwingeloo dish is transparent metal mesh, but on this winter photo covered with snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;gallery-2&quot; class=&quot;gallery galleryid-3639 gallery-columns-2 gallery-size-medium&quot;&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;&lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon portrait&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/PA3FXB_BG2CRY_BG2BHC_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9738-copy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/PA3FXB_BG2CRY_BG2BHC_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9738-copy-200x300.jpg&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium size-medium&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/PA3FXB_BG2CRY_BG2BHC_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9738-copy-200x300.jpg 200w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/PA3FXB_BG2CRY_BG2BHC_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9738-copy-53x80.jpg 53w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/PA3FXB_BG2CRY_BG2BHC_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9738-copy-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/PA3FXB_BG2CRY_BG2BHC_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9738-copy-687x1030.jpg 687w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/PA3FXB_BG2CRY_BG2BHC_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9738-copy-1000x1500.jpg 1000w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/PA3FXB_BG2CRY_BG2BHC_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9738-copy-470x705.jpg 470w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/PA3FXB_BG2CRY_BG2BHC_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9738-copy-450x675.jpg 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;&lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon landscape&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Wei_BG2BHC_Jan_PA3FXB_Hu_BG2CRY_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9725-copy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Wei_BG2BHC_Jan_PA3FXB_Hu_BG2CRY_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9725-copy-300x200.jpg&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium size-medium&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Wei_BG2BHC_Jan_PA3FXB_Hu_BG2CRY_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9725-copy-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Wei_BG2BHC_Jan_PA3FXB_Hu_BG2CRY_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9725-copy-80x53.jpg 80w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Wei_BG2BHC_Jan_PA3FXB_Hu_BG2CRY_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9725-copy-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Wei_BG2BHC_Jan_PA3FXB_Hu_BG2CRY_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9725-copy-1030x687.jpg 1030w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Wei_BG2BHC_Jan_PA3FXB_Hu_BG2CRY_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9725-copy-1500x1000.jpg 1500w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Wei_BG2BHC_Jan_PA3FXB_Hu_BG2CRY_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9725-copy-705x470.jpg 705w, https://www.camras.nl/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Wei_BG2BHC_Jan_PA3FXB_Hu_BG2CRY_Dwingeloo_cHarryKeizer_LR-9725-copy-450x300.jpg 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photos CAMRAS (Tammo Jan Dijkema and Harry Keizer) and Moon and Earth-images MingChuan Wei (Harbin Institute of Technology)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 02:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>followben</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.camras.nl/en/blog/2018/precious-earth-and-lunar-far-side/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>