<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Statement on Cryptocurrencies and Initial Coin Offerings</title>
<link>https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Dec. 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;224.51537090064&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world’s social media platforms and financial markets are abuzz about cryptocurrencies and “initial coin offerings” (&lt;em&gt;ICOs&lt;/em&gt;).  There are tales of fortunes made and dreamed to be made.  We are hearing the familiar refrain, “this time is different.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cryptocurrency and ICO markets have grown rapidly.  These markets are local, national and international and include an ever-broadening range of products and participants.  They also present investors and other market participants with many questions, some new and some old (but in a new form), including, to list just a few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Is the product legal?  Is it subject to regulation, including rules designed to protect investors?  Does the product comply with those rules?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the offering legal?  Are those offering the product licensed to do so?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are the trading markets fair?  Can prices on those markets be manipulated?  Can I sell when I want to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there substantial risks of theft or loss, including from hacking?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The answers to these and other important questions often require an in-depth analysis, and the answers will differ depending on many factors.  This statement provides my general views on the cryptocurrency and ICO markets&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftn1&quot; name=&quot;_ftnref1&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; and is directed principally to two groups:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“Main Street” investors, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market professionals – including, for example, broker-dealers, investment advisers, exchanges, lawyers and accountants – whose actions impact Main Street investors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Considerations for Main Street Investors&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A number of concerns have been raised regarding the cryptocurrency and ICO markets, including that, as they are currently operating, there is substantially less investor protection than in our traditional securities markets, with correspondingly greater opportunities for fraud and manipulation&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors should understand that to date no initial coin offerings have been registered with the SEC.  The SEC also has not to date approved for listing and trading any exchange-traded products (such as ETFs) holding cryptocurrencies or other assets related to cryptocurrencies.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftn2&quot; name=&quot;_ftnref2&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  If any person today tells you otherwise, be especially wary.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have issued investor alerts, bulletins and statements on initial coin offerings and cryptocurrency-related investments, including with respect to the marketing of certain offerings and investments by celebrities and others.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftn3&quot; name=&quot;_ftnref3&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;  Please take a moment to read them.  &lt;strong&gt;If you choose to invest in these products, please ask questions and demand clear answers.&lt;/strong&gt;  A list of sample questions that may be helpful is attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any other type of potential investment, if a promoter guarantees returns, if an opportunity sounds too good to be true, or if you are pressured to act quickly, please exercise extreme caution and be aware of the risk that your investment may be lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please also recognize that these markets span national borders and that significant trading may occur on systems and platforms outside the United States.  Your invested funds may quickly travel overseas without your knowledge.  As a result, risks can be amplified, including the risk that market regulators, such as the SEC, may not be able to effectively pursue bad actors or recover funds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about these markets and their regulation, please read the “Additional Discussion of Cryptocurrencies, ICOs and Securities Regulation” section below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Considerations for Market Professionals&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that initial coin offerings – whether they represent offerings of securities or not – can be effective ways for entrepreneurs and others to raise funding, including for innovative projects.  However, any such activity that involves an offering of securities must be accompanied by the important disclosures, processes and other investor protections that our securities laws require.  A change in the structure of a securities offering does not change the fundamental point that when a security is being offered, our securities laws must be followed.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftn4&quot; name=&quot;_ftnref4&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;  Said another way, replacing a traditional corporate interest recorded in a central ledger with an enterprise interest recorded through a blockchain entry on a distributed ledger may change the form of the transaction, but it does not change the substance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I urge market professionals, including securities lawyers, accountants and consultants, to read closely the investigative report we released earlier this year (the “&lt;em&gt;21(a) Report&lt;/em&gt;”)&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftn5&quot; name=&quot;_ftnref5&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; and review our subsequent enforcement actions.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftn6&quot; name=&quot;_ftnref6&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;  In the 21(a) Report, the Commission applied longstanding securities law principles to demonstrate that a particular token constituted an investment contract and therefore was a security under our federal securities laws.  Specifically, we concluded that the token offering represented an investment of money in a common enterprise with a reasonable expectation of profits to be derived from the entrepreneurial or managerial efforts of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the issuance of the 21(a) Report, certain market professionals have attempted to highlight utility characteristics of their proposed initial coin offerings in an effort to claim that their proposed tokens or coins are not securities.  Many of these assertions appear to elevate form over substance.  Merely calling a token a “utility” token or structuring it to provide some utility does not prevent the token from being a security.  Tokens and offerings that incorporate features and marketing efforts that emphasize the potential for profits based on the entrepreneurial or managerial efforts of others continue to contain the hallmarks of a security under U.S. law.  &lt;strong&gt;On this and other points where the application of expertise and judgment is expected, I believe that gatekeepers and others, including securities lawyers, accountants and consultants, need to focus on their responsibilities.  &lt;/strong&gt;I urge you to be guided by the principal motivation for our registration, offering process and disclosure requirements:  investor protection and, in particular, the protection of our Main Street investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also caution market participants against promoting or touting the offer and sale of coins without first determining whether the securities laws apply to those actions.  &lt;strong&gt;Selling securities generally requires a license, and experience shows that excessive touting in thinly traded and volatile markets can be an indicator of “scalping,” “pump and dump” and other manipulations and frauds.&lt;/strong&gt;  Similarly, I also caution those who operate systems and platforms that effect or facilitate transactions in these products that they may be operating unregistered exchanges or broker-dealers that are in violation of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On cryptocurrencies, I want to emphasize two points.  First, while there are cryptocurrencies that do not appear to be securities, simply calling something a “currency” or a currency-based product does not mean that it is not a security.  Before launching a cryptocurrency or a product with its value tied to one or more cryptocurrencies, its promoters must either (1) be able to demonstrate that the currency or product is not a security or (2) comply with applicable registration and other requirements under our securities laws.  Second, brokers, dealers and other market participants that allow for payments in cryptocurrencies, allow customers to purchase cryptocurrencies on margin, or otherwise use cryptocurrencies to facilitate securities transactions should exercise particular caution, including ensuring that their cryptocurrency activities are not undermining their anti-money laundering and know-your-customer obligations.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftn7&quot; name=&quot;_ftnref7&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;strong&gt;As I have stated previously, these market participants should treat payments and other transactions made in cryptocurrency as if cash were being handed from one party to the other.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Additional Discussion of Cryptocurrencies, ICOs and Securities Regulation  &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cryptocurrencies. &lt;/em&gt; Speaking broadly, cryptocurrencies purport to be items of inherent value (similar, for instance, to cash or gold) that are designed to enable purchases, sales and other financial transactions.  They are intended to provide many of the same functions as long-established currencies such as the U.S. dollar, euro or Japanese yen but do not have the backing of a government or other body.  Although the design and maintenance of cryptocurrencies differ, proponents of cryptocurrencies highlight various potential benefits and features of them, including (1) the ability to make transfers without an intermediary and without geographic limitation, (2) finality of settlement, (3) lower transaction costs compared to other forms of payment and (4) the ability to publicly verify transactions.  Other often-touted features of cryptocurrencies include personal anonymity and the absence of government regulation or oversight.  Critics of cryptocurrencies note that these features may facilitate illicit trading and financial transactions, and that some of the purported beneficial features may not prove to be available in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been asserted that cryptocurrencies are not securities and that the offer and sale of cryptocurrencies are beyond the SEC’s jurisdiction.  Whether that assertion proves correct with respect to any digital asset that is labeled as a cryptocurrency will depend on the characteristics and use of that particular asset.  In any event, it is clear that, just as the SEC has a sharp focus on how U.S. dollar, euro and Japanese yen transactions affect our securities markets, we have the same interests and responsibilities with respect to cryptocurrencies.  This extends, for example, to securities firms and other market participants that allow payments to be made in cryptocurrencies, set up structures to invest in or hold cryptocurrencies, or extend credit to customers to purchase or hold cryptocurrencies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Initial Coin Offerings. &lt;/em&gt; Coinciding with the substantial growth in cryptocurrencies, companies and individuals increasingly have been using initial coin offerings to raise capital for their businesses and projects.  Typically these offerings involve the opportunity for individual investors to exchange currency such as U.S. dollars or cryptocurrencies in return for a digital asset labeled as a coin or token. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These offerings can take many different forms, and the rights and interests a coin is purported to provide the holder can vary widely.  A key question for all ICO market participants: “Is the coin or token a security?”  As securities law practitioners know well, the answer depends on the facts.  For example, a token that represents a participation interest in a book-of-the-month club may not implicate our securities laws, and may well be an efficient way for the club’s operators to fund the future acquisition of books and facilitate the distribution of those books to token holders.  In contrast, many token offerings appear to have gone beyond this construct and are more analogous to interests in a yet-to-be-built publishing house with the authors, books and distribution networks all to come.  It is especially troubling when the promoters of these offerings emphasize the secondary market trading potential of these tokens.  Prospective purchasers are being sold on the potential for tokens to increase in value – with the ability to lock in those increases by reselling the tokens on a secondary market – or to otherwise profit from the tokens based on the efforts of others.  These are key hallmarks of a security and a securities offering.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By and large, the structures of initial coin offerings that I have seen promoted involve the offer and sale of securities and directly implicate the securities registration requirements and other investor protection provisions of our federal securities laws.  Generally speaking, these laws provide that investors deserve to know what they are investing in and the relevant risks involved.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have asked the SEC’s Division of Enforcement to continue to police this area vigorously and recommend enforcement actions against those that conduct initial coin offerings in violation of the federal securities laws. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Conclusion&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at the SEC are committed to promoting capital formation.  The technology on which cryptocurrencies and ICOs are based may prove to be disruptive, transformative and efficiency enhancing.  I am confident that developments in fintech will help facilitate capital formation and provide promising investment opportunities for institutional and Main Street investors alike. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encourage Main Street investors to be open to these opportunities, but to ask good questions, demand clear answers and apply good common sense when doing so.  When advising clients, designing products and engaging in transactions, market participants and their advisers should thoughtfully consider our laws, regulations and guidance, as well as our principles-based securities law framework, which has served us well in the face of new developments for more than 80 years.  I also encourage market participants and their advisers to engage with the SEC staff to aid in their analysis under the securities laws.  Staff providing assistance on these matters remain available at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:FinTech@sec.gov&quot;&gt;FinTech@sec.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Sample Questions for Investors Considering a Cryptocurrency or ICO&lt;br/&gt;Investment Opportunity&lt;/u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftn8&quot; name=&quot;_ftnref8&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[8]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Who exactly am I contracting with? 
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Who is issuing and sponsoring the product, what are their backgrounds, and have they provided a full and complete description of the product?  Do they have a clear written business plan that I understand?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is promoting or marketing the product, what are their backgrounds, and are they licensed to sell the product?  Have they been paid to promote the product?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where is the enterprise located?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where is my money going and what will be it be used for?  Is my money going to be used to “cash out” others?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What specific rights come with my investment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there financial statements?  If so, are they audited, and by whom?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there trading data?  If so, is there some way to verify it? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How, when, and at what cost can I sell my investment?  For example, do I have a right to give the token or coin back to the company or to receive a refund?  Can I resell the coin or token, and if so, are there any limitations on my ability to resell?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a digital wallet is involved, what happens if I lose the key?  Will I still have access to my investment? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a blockchain is used, is the blockchain open and public?  Has the code been published, and has there been an independent cybersecurity audit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the offering been structured to comply with the securities laws and, if not, what implications will that have for the stability of the enterprise and the value of my investment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What legal protections may or may not be available in the event of fraud, a hack, malware, or a downturn in business prospects?  Who will be responsible for refunding my investment if something goes wrong?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I do have legal rights, can I effectively enforce them and will there be adequate funds to compensate me if my rights are violated?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33.617110379898&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr align=&quot;left&quot; size=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;33%&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;ftn1&quot; readability=&quot;25.84&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftnref1&quot; name=&quot;_ftn1&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; This statement is my own and does not reflect the views of any other Commissioner or the Commission.  This statement is not, and should not be taken as, a definitive discussion of applicable law, all the relevant risks with respect to these products, or a statement of my position on any particular product.  Additionally, this statement is not a comment on any particular submission, in the form of a proposed rule change or otherwise, pending before the Commission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftnref2&quot; name=&quot;_ftn2&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; The CFTC has designated bitcoin as a commodity.  Fraud and manipulation involving bitcoin traded in interstate commerce are appropriately within the purview of the CFTC, as is the regulation of commodity futures tied directly to bitcoin.  That said, products linked to the value of underlying digital assets, including bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies, may be structured as securities products subject to registration under the Securities Act of 1933 or the Investment Company Act of 1940. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;ftn2&quot; readability=&quot;11.00758396533&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftnref3&quot; name=&quot;_ftn3&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; Statement on Potentially Unlawful Promotion of Initial Coin Offerings and Other Investments by Celebrities and Others (Nov. 1, 2017), &lt;em&gt;available at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-potentially-unlawful-promotion-icos&quot;&gt;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-potentially-unlawful-promotion-icos&lt;/a&gt;; Investor Alert:  Public Companies Making ICO-Related Claims (Aug. 28, 2017), &lt;em&gt;available at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/ia_icorelatedclaims&quot;&gt;https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/ia_icorelatedclaims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;;&lt;/em&gt; Investor Bulletin:  Initial Coin Offerings (July 25, 2017), &lt;em&gt;available at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/ib_coinofferings&quot;&gt;https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/ib_coinofferings&lt;/a&gt;; Investor Alert:  Bitcoin and Other Virtual Currency-Related Investments (May 7, 2014), &lt;em&gt;available at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investor.gov/additional-resources/news-alerts/alerts-bulletins/investor-alert-bitcoin-other-virtual-currency&quot;&gt;https://www.investor.gov/additional-resources/news-alerts/alerts-bulletins/investor-alert-bitcoin-other-virtual-currency&lt;/a&gt;; Investor Alert: Ponzi Schemes Using Virtual Currencies (July 23, 2013), &lt;em&gt;available at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/investor/alerts/ia_virtualcurrencies.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.sec.gov/investor/alerts/ia_virtualcurrencies.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;ftn3&quot; readability=&quot;11.900552486188&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftnref4&quot; name=&quot;_ftn4&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; It is possible to conduct an ICO without triggering the SEC’s registration requirements.  For example, just as with a Regulation D exempt offering to raise capital for the manufacturing of a physical product, an initial coin offering that is a security can be structured so that it qualifies for an applicable exemption from the registration requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;ftn7&quot; readability=&quot;15.77033492823&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftnref7&quot; name=&quot;_ftn7&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; I am particularly concerned about market participants who extend to customers credit in U.S. dollars – a relatively stable asset – to enable the purchase of cryptocurrencies, which, in recent experience, have proven to be a more volatile asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11#_ftnref8&quot; name=&quot;_ftn8&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; This is not intended to represent an exhaustive list.  Please also see the SEC investor bulletins, alerts and statements referenced in note 3 of this statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>corbinpage</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Former Facebook exec says social media is ripping apart society</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/11/16761016/former-facebook-exec-ripping-apart-society</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/11/16761016/former-facebook-exec-ripping-apart-society</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;W4EkDA&quot;&gt;Another former Facebook executive has spoken out about the harm the social network is doing to civil society around the world. Chamath Palihapitiya, who joined Facebook in 2007 and became its vice president for user growth, said he feels “tremendous guilt” about the company he helped make. “I think we have created tools that are ripping apart the social fabric of how society works,” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/PMotykw0SIk?t=21m21s&quot;&gt;told an audience&lt;/a&gt; at Stanford Graduate School of Business, before recommending people take a “hard break” from social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;pty6T7&quot;&gt;Palihapitiya’s criticisms were aimed not only at Facebook, but the wider online ecosystem. “The short-term, dopamine-driven feedback loops we’ve created are destroying how society works,” he said, referring to online interactions driven by “hearts, likes, thumbs-up.” “No civil discourse, no cooperation; misinformation, mistruth. And it’s not an American problem — this is not about Russians ads. This is a global problem.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0AZpj7&quot;&gt;He went on to describe an incident in India where hoax messages about kidnappings shared on WhatsApp led to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bgr.in/news/fake-whatsapp-messages-lead-to-killing-of-7-alleged-kidnappers-in-jharkhand/&quot;&gt;lynching&lt;/a&gt; of seven innocent people. “That’s what we’re dealing with,” said Palihapitiya. “And imagine taking that to the extreme, where bad actors can now manipulate large swathes of people to do anything you want. It’s just a really, really bad state of affairs.” He says he tries to use Facebook as little as possible, and that his children “aren’t allowed to use that shit.” He later adds, though, that he believes the company “overwhelmingly does good in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;MXqcNa&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PMotykw0SIk?rel=0&amp;amp;amp;start=1281&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;QBNhfB&quot;&gt;Palihapitiya’s remarks follow similar statements of contrition from others who helped build Facebook into the powerful corporation it is today. In November, early investor Sean Parker said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/9/16627724/sean-parker-facebook-childrens-brains-feedback-loop&quot;&gt;he has become&lt;/a&gt; a “conscientious objector” to social media, and that Facebook and others had succeeded by “exploiting a vulnerability in human psychology.” A former product manager at the company, Antonio Garcia-Martinez, has said Facebook &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/may/02/facebook-executive-advertising-data-comment&quot;&gt;lies about its ability&lt;/a&gt; to influence individuals based on the data it collects on them, and wrote a book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/47d1cd50-4aa5-11e6-b387-64ab0a67014c&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chaos Monkeys&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, about his work at the firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;UcwhFu&quot;&gt;These former employees have all spoken out at a time when worry about Facebook’s power is reaching fever pitch. In the past year, concerns about the company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/30/16578022/facebook-senate-testimony-russia-126-million-people&quot;&gt;role in the US election&lt;/a&gt; and its capacity to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/may/16/facebook-fake-news-tools-not-working&quot;&gt;amplify fake news&lt;/a&gt; have grown, while other reports have focused on how the social media site has been implicated in atrocities like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/27/world/asia/myanmar-government-facebook-rohingya.html&quot;&gt;the “ethnic cleansing” of Myanmar’s Rohingya ethnic group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wZZDjA&quot;&gt;In his talk, Palihapitiya criticized not only Facebook, but Silicon Valley’s entire system of venture capital funding. He said that investors pump money into “shitty, useless, idiotic companies,” rather than addressing real problems like climate change and disease. Palihapitiya currently runs his own VC firm, Social Capital, which focuses on funding companies in sectors like healthcare and education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;KhVlWI&quot;&gt;Palihapitiya also notes that although tech investors seem almighty, they’ve achieved their power more through luck than skill. “Everybody’s bullshitting,” he said. “If you’re in a seat, and you have good deal flow, and you have precious capital, and there’s a massive tailwind of technological change ... Over time you get one of the 20 [companies that become successful] and you look like a genius. And nobody wants to admit that but that’s the fucking truth.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 21:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>SREinSF</dc:creator>
<og:description>‘No civil discourse, no cooperation; misinformation, mistruth.’</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tRYwZMp1cUPWRQCWZhCddstmQLg=/0x243:2525x1565/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9847501/615649324.jpg.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Former Facebook exec says social media is ripping apart society</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/11/16761016/former-facebook-exec-ripping-apart-society</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/11/16761016/former-facebook-exec-ripping-apart-society</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Buys Shazam to Boost Apple Music</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-11/apple-buys-early-iphone-app-hit-shazam-to-boost-apple-music</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-11/apple-buys-early-iphone-app-hit-shazam-to-boost-apple-music</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/AAPL:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Apple Inc.&lt;/a&gt; agreed to acquire music-identification service &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/625238Z:LN&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Shazam&lt;/a&gt;, taking ownership of one of the first apps to demonstrate the power of the iPhone, recognizing songs after hearing just a few bars of a tune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terms of the deal weren’t disclosed, but a person familiar with the situation said Apple is paying about $400 million for the U.K.-based startup. That would be one of Apple’s largest acquisitions ever, approaching the size of its 1996 purchase of Next Computer Inc. which brought co-founder Steve Jobs back to the company. That transaction would be worth more than $600 million in today’s dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deal announced Monday will be a disappointment for some of Shazam Entertainment Ltd.’s investors, including Mexican billionaire Carlos Slim and venture capital firms Kleiner Perkins Caufield &amp;amp; Byers, Institutional Venture Partners and DN Capital Ltd. The 18-year-old company, which has required twice the average time to deliver an exit for backers, was valued at about $1 billion when it closed its last funding round in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&quot;A company isn’t worth a billion dollars until it’s sold or exited. Many of these so-called unicorns are of course fakies,&quot; Mark Tluszcz, co-founder of VC firm Mangrove Capital Partners and chairman of website building service Wix.com Ltd. &quot;They will face their day of reckoning and may turn out to be a disappointment. The case of Shazam will serve as a stark warning to other companies.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shazam app uses the microphone on a smartphone or computer to identify almost any song playing nearby, then points users to places they can listen to it in future, such as Apple Music or Google’s YouTube. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Shazam has been popular with customers, it struggled turning its clever music service into a business that justified its valuation. It expanded beyond simple audio recognition in 2010 by adding capabilities that let television viewers &quot;Shazam&quot; an ad, which would then open a promotion from the advertiser on a user’s device. The company said this feature was used 700,000 times during the 2014 Super Bowl broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Apple Music and Shazam are a natural fit, sharing a passion for music discovery and delivering great music experiences to our users,&quot; Apple said in an emailed statement on Monday. &quot;We have exciting plans in store, and we look forward to combining with Shazam upon approval of today’s agreement.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November, Shazam had about 175 million monthly active users globally across iOS and Android, according to research firm App Annie. The U.S. is the largest single market, with about 20 million active users in November, while the U.K. had about 4 million in the same month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Since the launch of the App Store, Shazam has consistently ranked as one of the most popular apps for iOS,&quot; Apple also said. &quot;Today, it’s used by hundreds of millions of people around the world, across multiple platforms.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The acquisition would help Apple embed that capability more deeply into its music offerings. The company’s digital assistant Siri gained Shazam integration in 2014, so users could ask it what song is playing in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more on Apple, check out the &lt;em&gt;Decrypted &lt;/em&gt; podcast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 18:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kentwistle</dc:creator>
<og:description>Apple Inc. agreed to acquire music-identification service Shazam, taking ownership of one of the first apps to demonstrate the power of the iPhone, recognizing songs after hearing just a few bars of a tune.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iwOef27Xaj7c/v1/1200x675.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Apple Buys Shazam to Boost Apple Music</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-11/apple-buys-early-iphone-app-hit-shazam-to-boost-apple-music</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-11/apple-buys-early-iphone-app-hit-shazam-to-boost-apple-music</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Donald Knuth&amp;#039;s Christmas Lecture: A Conjecture That Had To Be True [video]</title>
<link>http://scpd.stanford.edu/free-stuff/live-webinars-lectures/donald-knuths-annual-christmas-lecture</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://scpd.stanford.edu/free-stuff/live-webinars-lectures/donald-knuths-annual-christmas-lecture</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;A Conjecture That Had To Be True&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;A few months ago, the speaker did some extensive calculations relating to a curious problem in combinatorial geometry; and the resulting numbers satisfied an amazing formula. Although this formula was known to be true only in the five or six smallest cases of the problem, it was impossible to imagine a decent world in which the formula would not hold universally. 
Come to the lecture and learn about the interesting sequel.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;555&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BxQw4CdxLr8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; gesture=&quot;media&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
    &lt;br/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 18:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>taeric</dc:creator>
<og:type>university</og:type>
<og:title>Donald Knuth's Annual Christmas Lecture</og:title>
<og:description>A Conjecture That Had To Be True   A few months ago, the speaker did some extensive calculations relating to a curious problem in combinatorial geometry; and the resulting numbers satisfied an amazing formula. Although this formula was known to be true only in the five or six smallest cases of the problem, it was impossible to imagine a decent world in which the formula would not hold universally. Come to the lecture and learn about the interesting sequel.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://scpd.stanford.edu/free-stuff/live-webinars-lectures/donald-knuths-annual-christmas-lecture</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Estonia, the Digital Republic</title>
<link>https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/12/18/estonia-the-digital-republic</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/12/18/estonia-the-digital-republic</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; data-reactid=&quot;216&quot; readability=&quot;152&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;217&quot;&gt;Up the Estonian coast, a five-lane highway bends with the path of the sea, then breaks inland, leaving cars to follow a thin road toward the houses at the water’s edge. There is a gated community here, but it is not the usual kind. The gate is low—a picket fence—as if to prevent the dunes from riding up into the street. The entrance is blocked by a railroad-crossing arm, not so much to keep out strangers as to make sure they come with intent. Beyond the gate, there is a schoolhouse, and a few homes line a narrow drive. From Tallinn, Estonia’s capital, you arrive dazed: trees trace the highway, and the cars go fast, as if to get in front of something that no one can see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;219&quot;&gt;Within this gated community lives a man, his family, and one vision of the future. Taavi Kotka, who spent four years as Estonia’s chief information officer, is one of the leading public faces of a project known as e-Estonia: a coördinated governmental effort to transform the country from a state into a digital society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;221&quot;&gt;E-Estonia is the most ambitious project in technological statecraft today, for it includes all members of the government, and alters citizens’ daily lives. The normal services that government is involved with—legislation, voting, education, justice, health care, banking, taxes, policing, and so on—have been digitally linked across one platform, wiring up the nation. A lawn outside Kotka’s large house was being trimmed by a small robot, wheeling itself forward and nibbling the grass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;223&quot;&gt;“Everything here is robots,” Kotka said. “Robots here, robots there.” He sometimes felt that the lawnmower had a soul. “At parties, it gets &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;225&quot;&gt;close&lt;/em&gt; to people,” he explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;228&quot;&gt;A curious wind was sucking in a thick fog from the water, and Kotka led me inside. His study was cluttered, with a long table bearing a chessboard and a bowl of foil-wrapped wafer chocolates (a mark of hospitality at Estonian meetings). A four-masted model ship was perched near the window; in the corner was a pile of robot toys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;230&quot;&gt;“We had to set a goal that resonates, large enough for the society to believe in,” Kotka went on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;232&quot;&gt;He is tall with thin blond hair that, kept shaggy, almost conceals its recession. He has the liberated confidence, tinged with irony, of a cardplayer who has won a lot of hands and can afford to lose some chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;234&quot;&gt;It was during Kotka’s tenure that the e-Estonian goal reached its fruition. Today, citizens can vote from their laptops and challenge parking tickets from home. They do so through the “once only” policy, which dictates that no single piece of information should be entered twice. Instead of having to “prepare” a loan application, applicants have their data—income, debt, savings—pulled from elsewhere in the system. There’s nothing to fill out in doctors’ waiting rooms, because physicians can access their patients’ medical histories. Estonia’s system is keyed to a chip-I.D. card that reduces typically onerous, integrative processes—such as doing taxes—to quick work. “If a couple in love would like to marry, they still have to visit the government location and express their will,” Andrus Kaarelson, a director at the Estonian Information Systems Authority, says. But, apart from transfers of physical property, such as buying a house, all bureaucratic processes can be done online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Callout__inset-left___2rZjf&quot; data-type=&quot;callout&quot; data-callout=&quot;inset-left&quot; data-reactid=&quot;236&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;CartoonEmbed__container___vf5AM&quot; data-reactid=&quot;237&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;ImageCaption__caption___1EOQO ImageCaption__caption___1EOQO&quot; data-reactid=&quot;246&quot;&gt;“You call this parity?”&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;253&quot;&gt;Estonia is a Baltic country of 1.3 million people and four million hectares, half of which is forest. Its government presents this digitization as a cost-saving efficiency and an equalizing force. Digitizing processes reportedly saves the state two per cent of its G.D.P. a year in salaries and expenses. Since that’s the same amount it pays to meet the &lt;em class=&quot;small&quot; data-reactid=&quot;255&quot;&gt;NATO&lt;/em&gt; threshold for protection (Estonia—which has a notably vexed relationship with Russia—has a comparatively small military), its former President Toomas Hendrik Ilves liked to joke that the country got its national security for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;258&quot;&gt;Other benefits have followed. “If everything is digital, and location-independent, you can run a borderless country,” Kotka said. In 2014, the government launched a digital “residency” program, which allows logged-in foreigners to partake of some Estonian services, such as banking, as if they were living in the country. Other measures encourage international startups to put down virtual roots; Estonia has the lowest business-tax rates in the European Union, and has become known for liberal regulations around tech research. It is legal to test Level 3 driverless cars (in which a human driver can take control) on all Estonian roads, and the country is planning ahead for Level 5 (cars that take off on their own). “We believe that innovation happens anyway,” Viljar Lubi, Estonia’s deputy secretary for economic development, says. “If we close ourselves off, the innovation happens somewhere else.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;260&quot;&gt;“It makes it so that, if one country is not performing as well as another country, people are going to the one that is performing better—competitive governance is what I’m calling it,” Tim Draper, a venture capitalist at the Silicon Valley firm Draper Fisher Jurvetson and one of Estonia’s leading tech boosters, says. “We’re about to go into a very interesting time where a lot of governments can become virtual.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;262&quot;&gt;Previously, Estonia’s best-known industry was logging, but Skype was built there using mostly local engineers, and countless other startups have sprung from its soil. “It’s not an offshore paradise, but you can capitalize a lot of money,” Thomas Padovani, a Frenchman who co-founded the digital-ad startup Adcash in Estonia, explains. “And the administration is light, all the way.” A light touch does not mean a restricted one, however, and the guiding influence of government is everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;266&quot;&gt;As an engineer, Kotka said, he found the challenge of helping to construct a digital nation too much to resist. “Imagine that it’s your task to build the Golden Gate Bridge,” he said excitedly. “You have to change the whole way of thinking about society.” So far, Estonia is past halfway there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; data-reactid=&quot;268&quot; readability=&quot;113.89728096677&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;269&quot;&gt;One afternoon, I met a woman named Anna Piperal at the e-Estonia Showroom. Piperal is the “e-Estonia ambassador”; the showroom is a permanent exhibit on the glories of digitized Estonia, from Skype to Timbeter, an app designed to count big piles of logs. (Its founder told me that she’d struggled to win over the wary titans of Big Log, who preferred to count the inefficient way.) Piperal has blond hair and an air of brisk, Northern European professionalism. She pulled out her I.D. card; slid it into her laptop, which, like the walls of the room, was faced with blond wood; and typed in her secret code, one of two that went with her I.D. The other code issues her digital signature—a seal that, Estonians point out, is much harder to forge than a scribble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;271&quot;&gt;“This &lt;em class=&quot;small&quot; data-reactid=&quot;273&quot;&gt;PIN&lt;/em&gt; code just starts the whole decryption process,” Piperal explained. “I’ll start with my personal data from the population registry.” She gestured toward a box on the screen. “It has my document numbers, my phone number, my e-mail account. Then there’s real estate, the land registry.” Elsewhere, a box included all of her employment information; another contained her traffic records and her car insurance. She pointed at the tax box. “I have no tax debts; otherwise, that would be there. And I’m finishing a master’s at the Tallinn University of Technology, so here”—she pointed to the education box—“I have my student information. If I buy a ticket, the system can verify, automatically, that I’m a student.” She clicked into the education box, and a detailed view came up, listing her previous degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;276&quot;&gt;“My cat is in the pet registry,” Piperal said proudly, pointing again. “We are done with the vaccines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;278&quot;&gt;Data aren’t centrally held, thus reducing the chance of Equifax-level breaches. Instead, the government’s data platform, X-Road, links individual servers through end-to-end encrypted pathways, letting information live locally. Your dentist’s practice holds its own data; so does your high school and your bank. When a user requests a piece of information, it is delivered like a boat crossing a canal via locks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;280&quot;&gt;Although X-Road is a government platform, it has become, owing to its ubiquity, the network that many major private firms build on, too. Finland, Estonia’s neighbor to the north, recently began using X-Road, which means that certain data—for instance, prescriptions that you’re able to pick up at a local pharmacy—can be linked between the nations. It is easy to imagine a novel internationalism taking shape in this form. Toomas Ilves, Estonia’s former President and a longtime driver of its digitization efforts, is currently a distinguished visiting fellow at Stanford, and says he was shocked at how retrograde U.S. bureaucracy seems even in the heart of Silicon Valley. “It’s like the nineteen-fifties—I had to provide an electrical bill to prove I live here!” he exclaimed. “You can get an iPhone X, but, if you have to register your car, forget it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;282&quot;&gt;X-Road is appealing due to its rigorous filtering: Piperal’s teachers can enter her grades, but they can’t access her financial history, and even a file that’s accessible to medical specialists can be sealed off from other doctors if Piperal doesn’t want it seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;284&quot;&gt;“I’ll show you a digital health record,” she said, to explain. “A doctor from here”—a file from one clinic—“can see the research that this doctor”—she pointed to another—“does.” She’d locked a third record, from a female-medicine practice, so that no other doctor would be able to see it. A tenet of the Estonian system is that an individual owns &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2013/06/24/the-prism&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; data-reactid=&quot;286&quot;&gt;all information recorded about him or her&lt;/a&gt;. Every time a doctor (or a border guard, a police officer, a banker, or a minister) glances at any of Piperal’s secure data online, that look is recorded and reported. Peeping at another person’s secure data for no reason is a criminal offense. “In Estonia, we don’t have Big Brother; we have Little Brother,” a local told me. “You can tell him what to do and maybe also beat him up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;289&quot;&gt;Business and land-registry information is considered public, so Piperal used the system to access the profile of an Estonian politician. “Let’s see his land registry,” she said, pulling up a list of properties. “You can see there are three land plots he has, and this one is located”—she clicked, and a satellite photograph of a sprawling beach house appeared—“on the sea.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;291&quot;&gt;The openness is startling. Finding the business interests of the rich and powerful—a hefty field of journalism in the United States—takes a moment’s research, because every business connection or investment captured in any record in Estonia becomes searchable public information. (An online tool even lets citizens map webs of connection, follow-the-money style.) Traffic stops are illegal in the absence of a moving violation, because officers acquire records from a license-plate scan. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/suppression-of-the-black-vote-is-no-relic&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; data-reactid=&quot;295&quot;&gt;Polling-place intimidation&lt;/a&gt; is a non-issue if people can vote—and then change their votes, up to the deadline—at home, online. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/10/31/untangling-the-immigration-debate&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; data-reactid=&quot;298&quot;&gt;heat is taken off immigration&lt;/a&gt; because, in a borderless society, a resident need not even have visited Estonia in order to work and pay taxes under its dominion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; data-reactid=&quot;301&quot; readability=&quot;105.20319473808&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;302&quot;&gt;Soon after becoming the C.I.O., in 2013, Taavi Kotka was charged with an unlikely project: expanding Estonia’s population. The motive was predominantly economic. “Countries are like enterprises,” he said. “They want to increase the wealth of their own people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;304&quot;&gt;Tallinn, a harbor city with a population just over four hundred thousand, does not seem to be on a path toward outsized growth. Not far from the cobbled streets of the hilly Old Town is a business center, where boxy Soviet structures have been supplanted by stylish buildings of a Scandinavian cast. Otherwise, the capital seems pleasantly preserved in time. The coastal daylight is bright and thick, and, when a breeze comes off the Baltic, silver-birch leaves shimmer like chimes. “I came home to a great autumn / to a luminous landscape,” the Estonian poet Jaan Kaplinski wrote decades ago. This much has not changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;306&quot;&gt;Kotka, however, thought that it was possible to increase the population just by changing how you thought of what a population was. Consider music, he said. Twenty years ago, you bought a CD and played the album through. Now you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2014/11/24/revenue-streams&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; data-reactid=&quot;308&quot;&gt;listen track by track, on demand&lt;/a&gt;. “If countries are competing not only on physical talent moving to their country but also on how to get the best virtual talent &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;311&quot;&gt;connected&lt;/em&gt; to their country, it becomes a disruption like the one we have seen in the music industry,” he said. “And it’s basically a zero-cost project, because we already have this infrastructure for our own people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;329&quot;&gt;The program that resulted is called e-residency, and it permits citizens of another country to become residents of Estonia without ever visiting the place. An e-resident has no leg up at the customs desk, but the program allows individuals to tap into Estonia’s digital services from afar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;331&quot;&gt;I applied for Estonian e-residency one recent morning at my apartment, and it took about ten minutes. The application cost a hundred euros, and the hardest part was finding a passport photograph to upload, for my card. After approval, I would pick up my credentials in person, like a passport, at the Estonian Consulate in New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;333&quot;&gt;This physical task proved to be the main stumbling block, Ott Vatter, the deputy director of e-residency, explained, because consulates were reluctant to expand their workload to include a new document. Mild xenophobia made some Estonians at home wary, too. “Inside Estonia, the mentality is kind of ‘What is the gain, and where is the money?’ ” he said. The physical factor still imposes limitations—only thirty-eight consulates have agreed to issue documents, and they are distributed unevenly. (Estonia has only one embassy in all of Africa.) But the office has made special accommodations for several popular locations. Since there’s no Estonian consulate in San Francisco, the New York consulate flies personnel to California every three months to batch-process Silicon Valley applicants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;335&quot;&gt;“I had a deal that I did with Funderbeam, in Estonia,” Tim Draper, who became Estonia’s second e-resident, told me. “We decided to use a ‘smart contract’—the first ever in a venture deal!” Smart contracts are encoded on a digital ledger and, notably, don’t require an outside administrative authority. It was an appealing prospect, and Draper, with his market investor’s gaze, recognized a new market for élite tech brainpower and capital. “I thought, Wow! Governments are going to have to compete with each other for us,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;337&quot;&gt;So far, twenty-eight thousand people have applied for e-residency, mostly from neighboring countries: Finland and Russia. But Italy and Ukraine follow, and U.K. applications spiked during Brexit. (Many applicants are footloose entrepreneurs or solo venders who want to be based in the E.U.) Because eighty-eight per cent of applicants are men, the United Nations has begun seeking applications for female entrepreneurs in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;339&quot;&gt;“There are so many companies in the world for whom working across borders is a big hassle and a source of expense,” Siim Sikkut, Estonia’s current C.I.O., says. Today, in Estonia, the weekly e-residency application rate exceeds the birth rate. “We tried to make more babies, but it’s not that easy,” he explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; data-reactid=&quot;341&quot; readability=&quot;132&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;342&quot;&gt;With so many businesses abroad, Estonia’s startup-ism hardly leaves an urban trace. I went to visit one of the places it does show: a co-working space, Lift99, in a complex called the Telliskivi Creative City. The Creative City, a former industrial park, is draped with trees and framed by buildings whose peeling exteriors have turned the yellows of a worn-out sponge. There are murals, outdoor sculptures, and bills for coming shows; the space is shaped by communalism and by the spirit of creative unrule. One art work consists of stacked logs labelled with Tallinn startups: Insly, Leap&lt;em class=&quot;small&quot; data-reactid=&quot;344&quot;&gt;IN&lt;/em&gt;, Photry, and something called 3D Creationist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;347&quot;&gt;The office manager, Elina Kaarneem, greeted me near the entrance. “Please remove your shoes,” she said. Lift99, which houses thirty-two companies and five freelancers, had industrial windows, with a two-floor open-plan workspace. Both levels also included smaller rooms named for techies who had done business with Estonia. There was a Zennström Room, after Niklas Zennström, the Swedish entrepreneur who co-founded Skype, in Tallinn. There was a Horowitz Room, for the venture capitalist Ben Horowitz, who has invested in Estonian tech. There was also a Tchaikovsky Room, because the composer had a summer house in Estonia and once said something nice about the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;351&quot;&gt;“This is not the usual co-working space, because we choose every human,” Ragnar Sass, who founded Lift99, exclaimed in the Hemingway Room. Hemingway, too, once said something about Estonia; a version of his pronouncement—“No well-run yacht basin is complete without at least two Estonians”—had been spray-stencilled on the wall, along with his face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;353&quot;&gt;The room was extremely small, with two cushioned benches facing each other. Sass took one; I took the other. “Many times, a miracle can happen if you put talented people in one room,” he said as I tried to keep my knees inside my space. Not far from the Hemingway Room, Barack Obama’s face was also on a wall. Obama Rooms are booths for making cell-phone calls, following something he once said about Estonia. (“I should have called the Estonians when we were setting up our health-care Web site.”) That had been stencilled on the wall as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;355&quot;&gt;Some of the companies at Lift99 are local startups, but others are international firms seeking an Estonian foothold. In something called the Draper Room, for Tim Draper, I met an Estonian engineer, Margus Maantoa, who was launching the Tallinn branch of the German motion-control company Trinamic. Maantoa shares the room with other companies, and, to avoid disturbing them, we went to the Iceland Room. (Iceland was the first country to recognize Estonian independence.) The seats around the table in the Iceland Room were swings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;357&quot;&gt;I took a swing, and Maantoa took another. He said, “I studied engineering and physics in Sweden, and then, seven years ago, I moved back to Estonia because so much is going on.” He asked whether I wanted to talk with his boss, Michael Randt, at the Trinamic headquarters, in Hamburg, and I said that I did, so he opened his laptop and set up a conference call on Skype. Randt was sitting at a table, peering down at us as if we were a mug of coffee. Tallinn had a great talent pool, he said: “Software companies are absorbing a lot of this labor, but, when it comes to hardware, there are only a few companies around.” He was an e-resident, so opening a Tallinn office was fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;359&quot;&gt;Maantoa took me upstairs, where he had a laboratory space that looked like a janitor’s closet. Between a water heater and two large air ducts, he had set up a desk with a 3-D printer and a robotic motion-control platform. I walked him back to Draper and looked up another startup, an Estonian company called Ööd, which makes one-room, two-hundred-square-foot huts that you can order prefab. The rooms have floor-to-ceiling windows of one-way glass, climate control, furniture, and lovely wood floors. They come in a truck and are dropped into the countryside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;361&quot;&gt;“Sometimes you want something small, but you don’t want to be in a tent,” Kaspar Kägu, the head of Ööd sales, explained. “You want a shower in the morning and your coffee and a beautiful landscape. Fifty-two per cent of Estonia is covered by forestland, and we’re rather introverted people, so we want to be—uh, &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;363&quot;&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; near everybody else.” People of a more sociable disposition could scatter these box homes on their property, he explained, and rent them out on services like Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;366&quot;&gt;“We like to go to nature—but comfortably,” Andreas Tiik, who founded Ööd with his carpenter brother, Jaak, told me. The company had queued preorders from people in Silicon Valley, who also liked the idea, and was tweaking the design for local markets. “We’re building a sauna in it,” Kägu said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; data-reactid=&quot;368&quot; readability=&quot;118&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;369&quot;&gt;In the U.S., it is generally assumed that private industry leads innovation. Many ambitious techies I met in Tallinn, though, were leaving industry to go work for the state. “If someone had asked me, three years ago, if I could imagine myself working for the government, I would have said, ‘Fuck no,’ ” Ott Vatter, who had sold his own business, told me. “But I decided that I could go to the U.S. at any point, and work in an average job at a private company. This is so much bigger.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;371&quot;&gt;The bigness is partly inherent in the government’s appetite for large problems. In Tallinn’s courtrooms, judges’ benches are fitted with two monitors, for consulting information during the proceedings, and case files are assembled according to the once-only principle. The police make reports directly into the system; forensic specialists at the scene or in the lab do likewise. Lawyers log on—as do judges, prison wardens, plaintiffs, and defendants, each through his or her portal. The Estonian courts used to be notoriously backlogged, but that is no longer the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Callout__inset-left___2rZjf&quot; data-type=&quot;callout&quot; data-callout=&quot;inset-left&quot; data-reactid=&quot;373&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;CartoonEmbed__container___vf5AM&quot; data-reactid=&quot;374&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;ImageCaption__caption___1EOQO ImageCaption__caption___1EOQO&quot; data-reactid=&quot;383&quot;&gt;“We have ways of making you talk.”&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;390&quot;&gt;“No one was able to say whether we should increase the number of courts or increase the number of judges,” Timo Mitt, a manager at Netgroup, which the government hired to build the architecture, told me. Digitizing both streamlined the process and helped identify points of delay. Instead of setting up prisoner transport to trial—fraught with security risks—Estonian courts can teleconference defendants into the courtroom from prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;392&quot;&gt;For doctors, a remote model has been of even greater use. One afternoon, I stopped at the North Estonia Medical Center, a hospital in the southwest of Tallinn, and met a doctor named Arkadi Popov in an alleyway where ambulances waited in line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;396&quot;&gt;“Welcome to our world,” Popov, who leads emergency medical care, said grandly, gesturing with pride toward the chariots of the sick and maimed. “Intensive care!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;398&quot;&gt;In a garage where unused ambulances were parked, he took an iPad Mini from the pocket of his white coat, and opened an “e-ambulance” app, which Estonian paramedics began using in 2015. “This system had some childhood diseases,” Popov said, tapping his screen. “But now I can say that it works well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;400&quot;&gt;E-ambulance is keyed onto X-Road, and allows paramedics to access patients’ medical records, meaning that the team that arrives for your chest pains will have access to your latest cardiology report and E.C.G. Since 2011, the hospital has also run a telemedicine system—doctoring at a distance—originally for three islands off its coast. There were few medical experts on the islands, so the E.M.S. accepted volunteer paramedics. “Some of them are hotel administrators, some of them are teachers,” Popov said. At a command center at the hospital in Tallinn, a doctor reads data remotely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;402&quot;&gt;“On the screen, she or he can see all the data regarding the patient—physiological parameters, E.C.G.s,” he said. “Pulse, blood pressure, temperature. In case of C.P.R., our doctor can see how deep the compression of the chest is, and can give feedback.” The e-ambulance software also allows paramedics to pre-register a patient en route to the hospital, so that tests, treatments, and surgeries can be prepared for the patient’s arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;404&quot;&gt;To see what that process looks like, I changed into scrubs and a hairnet and visited the hospital’s surgery ward. Rita Beljuskina, a nurse anesthetist, led me through a wide hallway lined with steel doors leading to the eighteen operating theatres. Screens above us showed eighteen columns, each marked out with twenty-four hours. Surgeons book their patients into the queue, Beljuskina explained, along with urgency levels and any machinery or personnel they might need. An on-call anesthesiologist schedules them in order to optimize the theatres and the equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;406&quot;&gt;“Let me show you how,” Beljuskina said, and led me into a room filled with medical equipment and a computer in the corner. She logged on with her own I.D. If she were to glance at any patient’s data, she explained, the access would be tagged to her name, and she would get a call inquiring why it was necessary. The system also scans for drug interactions, so if your otolaryngologist prescribes something that clashes with the pills your cardiologist told you to take, the computer will put up a red flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; data-reactid=&quot;408&quot; readability=&quot;109&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;409&quot;&gt;The putative grandfather of Estonia’s digital platform is Tarvi Martens, an enigmatic systems architect who today oversees the country’s digital-voting program from a stone building in the center of Tallinn’s Old Town. I went to visit him one morning, and was shown into a stateroom with a long conference table and French windows that looked out on the trees. Martens was standing at one window, with his back to me, commander style. For a few moments, he stayed that way; then he whirled around and addressed a timid greeting to the buttons of my shirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;411&quot;&gt;Martens was wearing a red flannel button-down, baggy jeans, black socks, and the sort of sandals that are sold at drugstores. He had gray stubble, and his hair was stuck down on his forehead in a manner that was somehow both rumpled and flat. This was the busiest time of the year, he said, with the fall election looming. He appeared to run largely on caffeine and nicotine; when he put down a mug of hot coffee, his fingers shook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;413&quot;&gt;For decades, he pointed out, digital technology has been one of Estonia’s first recourses for public ailments. A state project in 1970 used computerized data matching to help singles find soul mates, “for the good of the people’s economy.” In 1997, the government began looking into newer forms of digital documents as a supplement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;415&quot;&gt;“They were talking about chip-equipped bar codes or something,” Martens told me, breaking into a nerdy snicker-giggle. “Totally ridiculous.” He had been doing work in cybernetics and security as a private-sector contractor, and had an idea. When the cards were released, in 2002, Martens became convinced that they should be both mandatory and cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;417&quot;&gt;“Finland started two years earlier with an I.D. card, but it’s still a sad story,” he said. “Nobody uses it, because they put a hefty price tag on the card, and it’s a voluntary document. We sold it for ten euros at first, and what happened? Banks and application providers would say, ‘Why should I support this card? Nobody has it.’ It was a dead end.” In what may have been the seminal insight of twenty-first-century Estonia, Martens realized that whoever offered the most ubiquitous and secure platform would run the country’s digital future—and that it should be an elected leadership, not profit-seeking Big Tech. “The only thing was to push this card to the people, without them knowing what to do with it, and then say, ‘Now people have a card. Let’s start some applications,’ ” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;419&quot;&gt;The first “killer application” for the I.D.-card-based system was the one that Martens still works on: i-voting, or casting a secure ballot from your computer. Before the first i-voting period, in 2005, only five thousand people had used their card for anything. More than nine thousand cast an i-vote in that election, however—only two per cent of voters, but proof that online voting was attracting users—and the numbers rose from there. As of 2014, a third of all votes have been cast online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;423&quot;&gt;That year, seven Western researchers published a study of the i-voting system which concluded that it had “serious architectural limitations and procedural gaps.” Using an open-source edition of the voting software, the researchers approximated a version of the i-voting setup in their lab and found that it was possible to introduce malware. They were not convinced that the servers were entirely secure, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;425&quot;&gt;Martens insisted that the study was “ridiculous.” The researchers, he said, gathered data with “a lot of assumptions,” and misunderstood the safeguards in Estonia’s system. You needed both the passwords and the hardware (the chip in your I.D. card or, in the newer “mobile I.D.” system, the &lt;em class=&quot;small&quot; data-reactid=&quot;427&quot;&gt;SIM&lt;/em&gt; card in your phone) to log in, blocking most paths of sabotage. Estonian trust was its own safeguard, too, he told me. Earlier this fall, when a Czech research team found a vulnerability in the physical chips used in many I.D. cards, Siim Sikkut, the Estonian C.I.O., e-mailed me the finding. His office announced the vulnerability, and the cards were locked for a time. When Sikkut held a small press conference, reporters peppered him with questions: What did the government gain from disclosing the vulnerability? How disastrous &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;430&quot;&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;433&quot;&gt;Sikkut looked bemused. Many upgrades to phones and computers resolve vulnerabilities that have never even been publicly acknowledged, he said—and think how much data we entrust to those devices. (“There is no government that knows more about you than Google or Facebook,” Taavi Kotka says dryly.) In any case, the transparency seemed to yield a return; a poll conducted after the chip flaw was announced found that trust in the system had fallen by just three per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; data-reactid=&quot;450&quot; readability=&quot;136&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;451&quot;&gt;From time to time, Russian military jets patrolling Estonia’s western border switch off their G.P.S. transponders and drift into the country’s airspace. What follows is as practiced as a pas de deux at the Bolshoi. &lt;em class=&quot;small&quot; data-reactid=&quot;453&quot;&gt;NATO&lt;/em&gt; troops on the ground scramble an escort. Estonia calls up the Russian Ambassador to complain; Russia cites an obscure error. The dance lets both parties show that they’re alert, and have not forgotten the history of place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;456&quot;&gt;Since the eleventh century, Estonian land has been conquered by Russia five times. Yet the country has always been an awkward child of empire, partly owing to its proximity to other powers (and their airwaves) and partly because the Estonian language, which belongs to the same distinct Uralic family as Hungarian and Finnish, is incomprehensible to everyone else. Plus, the greatest threat, these days, may not be physical at all. In 2007, a Russian cyberattack on Estonia sent everything from the banks to the media into chaos. Estonians today see it as the defining event of their recent history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;458&quot;&gt;The chief outgrowth of the attack is the &lt;em class=&quot;small&quot; data-reactid=&quot;460&quot;&gt;NATO&lt;/em&gt; Coöperative Cyber Defense Center of Excellence, a think tank and training facility. It’s on a military base that once housed the Soviet Army. You enter through a gatehouse with gray walls and a pane of mirrored one-way glass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;463&quot;&gt;“Document, please!” the mirror boomed at me when I arrived one morning. I slid my passport through on a tray. The mirror was silent for two full minutes, and I backed into a plastic chair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;465&quot;&gt;“You have to wait here!” the mirror boomed back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;467&quot;&gt;Some minutes later, a friendly staffer appeared at the inner doorway and escorted me across a quadrangle trimmed with &lt;em class=&quot;small&quot; data-reactid=&quot;469&quot;&gt;NATO&lt;/em&gt;-member flags and birch trees just fading to gold. Inside a gray stone building, another mirror instructed me to stow my goods and to don a badge. Upstairs, the center’s director, Merle Maigre, formerly the national-security adviser to the Estonian President, said that the center’s goal was to guide other &lt;em class=&quot;small&quot; data-reactid=&quot;472&quot;&gt;NATO&lt;/em&gt; nations toward vigilance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;475&quot;&gt;“This country is located—just where it is,” she said, when I asked about Russia. Since starting, in 2008, the center has done research on digital forensics, cyber-defense strategy, and similar topics. (It publishes the “Tallinn Manual 2.0 on the International Law Applicable to Cyber Operations” and organizes a yearly research conference.) But it is best known for its training simulations: an eight-hundred-person cyber “live-fire” exercise called Locked Shields was run this year alongside &lt;em class=&quot;small&quot; data-reactid=&quot;477&quot;&gt;CYBRID&lt;/em&gt;, an exercise for defense ministers of the E.U. “This included aspects such as fake news and social media,” Maigre said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;480&quot;&gt;Not all of Estonia’s digital leadership in the region is as openly rehearsed. Its experts have consulted on Georgia’s efforts to set up its own digital registry. Estonia is also building data partnerships with Finland, and trying to export its methods elsewhere across the E.U. “The vision is that I will go to Greece, to a doctor, and be able to get everything,” Toomas Ilves explains. Sandra Roosna, a member of Estonia’s E-Governance Academy and the author of the book “eGovernance in Practice,” says, “I think we need to give the European Union two years to do cross-border transactions and to recognize each other digitally.” Even now, though, the Estonian platform has been adopted by nations as disparate as Moldova and Panama. “It’s very popular in countries that want—and not all do—transparency against corruption,” Ilves says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;484&quot;&gt;Beyond X-Road, the backbone of Estonia’s digital security is a blockchain technology called K.S.I. A blockchain is like the digital version of a scarf knitted by your grandmother. She uses one ball of yarn, and the result is continuous. Each stitch depends on the one just before it. It’s impossible to remove part of the fabric, or to substitute a swatch, without leaving some trace: a few telling knots, or a change in the knit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;486&quot;&gt;In a blockchain system, too, every line is contingent on what came before it. Any breach of the weave leaves a trace, and trying to cover your tracks leaves a trace, too. “Our No. 1 marketing pitch is Mr. Snowden,” Martin Ruubel, the president of Guardtime, the Estonian company that developed K.S.I., told me. (The company’s biggest customer group is now the U.S. military.) Popular anxiety tends to focus on data security—who can see my information?—but bits of personal information are rarely truly compromising. The larger threat is data integrity: whether what looks secure has been changed. (It doesn’t really matter who knows what your blood type is, but if someone switches it in a confidential record your next trip to the emergency room could be lethal.) The average time until discovery of a data breach is two hundred and five days, which is a huge problem if there’s no stable point of reference. “In the Estonian system, you don’t have paper originals,” Ruubel said. “The question is: Do I know about this problem, and how quickly can I react?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;488&quot;&gt;The blockchain makes every footprint immediately noticeable, regardless of the source. (Ruubel says that there is no possibility of a back door.) To guard secrets, K.S.I. is also able to protect information without “seeing” the information itself. But, to deal with a full-scale cyberattack, other safeguards now exist. Earlier this year, the Estonian government created a server closet in Luxembourg, with a backup of its systems. A “data embassy” like this one is built on the same body of international law as a physical embassy, so that the servers and their data are Estonian “soil.” If Tallinn is compromised, whether digitally or physically, Estonia’s locus of control will shift to such mirror sites abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;490&quot;&gt;“&lt;em data-reactid=&quot;492&quot;&gt;If&lt;/em&gt; Russia comes—not when—and if our systems shut down, we will have copies,” Piret Hirv, a ministerial adviser, told me. In the event of a sudden invasion, Estonia’s elected leaders might scatter as necessary. Then, from cars leaving the capital, from hotel rooms, from seat 3A at thirty thousand feet, they will open their laptops, log into Luxembourg, and—with digital signatures to execute orders and a suite of tamper-resistant services linking global citizens to their government—continue running their country, with no interruption, from the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; data-reactid=&quot;495&quot; readability=&quot;78&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;496&quot;&gt;The history of nationhood is a history of boundaries marked on land. When, in the fourteenth century, peace arrived after bloodshed among the peoples of Mexico’s eastern altiplano, the first task of the Tlaxcaltecs was to set the borders of their territory. In 1813, Ernst Moritz Arndt, a German nationalist poet before there was a Germany to be nationalistic about, embraced the idea of a “Vaterland” of shared history: “Which is the German’s fatherland? / So tell me now at last the land!— / As far’s the German’s accent rings / And hymns to God in heaven sings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;498&quot;&gt;Today, the old fatuities of the nation-state are showing signs of crisis. Formerly imperialist powers have withered into nationalism (as in Brexit) and separatism (Scotland, Catalonia). New powers, such as the Islamic State, have redefined nationhood by ideological acculturation. It is possible to imagine a future in which nationality is determined not so much by where you live as by what you log on to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;500&quot;&gt;Estonia currently holds the presidency of the European Union Council—a bureaucratic role that mostly entails chairing meetings. (The presidency rotates every six months; in January, it will go to Bulgaria.) This meant that the autumn’s E.U. Digital Summit was held in Tallinn, a convergence of audience and expertise not lost on Estonia’s leaders. One September morning, a car pulled up in front of the Tallinn Creative Hub, a former power station, and Kersti Kaljulaid, the President of Estonia, stepped out. She is the country’s first female President, and its youngest. Tall and lanky, with chestnut hair in a pixie cut, she wore an asymmetrical dress of Estonian blue and machine gray. Kaljulaid took office last fall, after Estonia’s Presidential election yielded no majority winner; parliamentary representatives of all parties plucked her out of deep government as a consensus candidate whom they could all support. She had previously been an E.U. auditor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;502&quot;&gt;“I am President to a digital society,” she declared in her address. The leaders of Europe were arrayed in folding chairs, with Angela Merkel, in front, slumped wearily in a red leather jacket. “Simple people suffer in the hands of heavy bureaucracies,” Kaljulaid told them. “We must go for inclusiveness, not high end. And we must go for reliability, not complex.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;504&quot;&gt;Kaljulaid urged the leaders to consider a transient population. Theresa May had told her people, after Brexit, “If you believe you’re a citizen of the world, you’re a citizen of nowhere.” With May in the audience, Kaljulaid staked out the opposite view. “Our citizens will be global soon,” she said. “We have to fly like bees from flower to flower to gather those taxes from citizens working in the morning in France, in the evening in the U.K., living half a year in Estonia and then going to Australia.” Citizens had to remain connected, she said, as the French President, Emmanuel Macron, began nodding vigorously and whispering to an associate. When Kaljulaid finished, Merkel came up to the podium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Callout__inset-left___2rZjf&quot; data-type=&quot;callout&quot; data-callout=&quot;inset-left&quot; data-reactid=&quot;508&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;CartoonEmbed__container___vf5AM&quot; data-reactid=&quot;509&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;ImageCaption__caption___1EOQO ImageCaption__caption___1EOQO&quot; data-reactid=&quot;518&quot;&gt;“Then, after the humans harvest our noses, they liquefy them and drink the juice. They believe it gives them special powers, which they call ‘antioxidants.’ ”&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;525&quot;&gt;“You’re so much further than we are,” she said. Later, the E.U. member states announced an agreement to work toward digital government and, as the Estonian Prime Minister put it in a statement, “rethink our entire labor market.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; data-reactid=&quot;527&quot; readability=&quot;173&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;528&quot;&gt;Before leaving Tallinn, I booked a meeting with Marten Kaevats, Estonia’s national digital adviser. We arranged to meet at a café near the water, but it was closed for a private event. Kaevats looked unperturbed. “Let’s go somewhere beautiful!” he said. He led me to an enormous terraced concrete platform blotched with graffiti and weeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;530&quot;&gt;We climbed a staircase to the second level, as if to a Mayan plateau. Kaevats, who is in his thirties, wore black basketball sneakers, navy trousers, a pin-striped jacket from a different suit, and a white shirt, untucked. The fancy dress was for the digital summit. “I have to introduce the President of Estonia,” he said merrily, crabbing a hand through his strawberry-blond hair, which stuck out in several directions. “I don’t know what to say!” He fished a box of Marlboro Reds out of his pocket and tented into himself, twitching a lighter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;532&quot;&gt;It was a cloudless morning. Rounded bits of gravel in the concrete caught a glare. The structure was bare and weather-beaten, and we sat on a ledge above a drop facing the harbor. The Soviets built this “Linnahall,” originally as a multipurpose venue for sailing-related sports of the Moscow Summer Olympics. It has fallen into disrepair, but there are plans for renovation soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;534&quot;&gt;For the past year, Kaevats’s main pursuit has been self-driving cars. “It basically embeds all the difficult questions of the digital age: privacy, data, safety—everything,” he said. It’s also an idea accessible to the man and woman (literally) in the street, whose involvement in regulatory standards he wants to encourage. “What’s difficult is the ethical and emotional side,” he said. “It’s about values. What do we want? Where are the borders? Where are the red lines? These cannot be decisions made only by specialists.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;536&quot;&gt;To support that future, he has plumbed the past. Estonian folklore includes a creature known as the &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;538&quot;&gt;kratt:&lt;/em&gt; an assembly of random objects that the Devil will bring to life for you, in exchange for a drop of blood offered at the conjunction of five roads. The Devil gives the &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;541&quot;&gt;kratt&lt;/em&gt; a soul, making it the slave of its creator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;544&quot;&gt;“Each and every Estonian, even children, understands this character,” Kaevats said. His office now speaks of &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;546&quot;&gt;kratt&lt;/em&gt; instead of robots and algorithms, and has been using the word to define a new, important nuance in Estonian law. “Basically, a &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;549&quot;&gt;kratt&lt;/em&gt; is a robot with representative rights,” he explained. “The idea that an algorithm can buy and sell services &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;552&quot;&gt;on your behalf&lt;/em&gt; is a conceptual upgrade.” In the U.S., where we lack such a distinction, it’s a matter of dispute whether, for instance, Facebook is responsible for algorithmic sales to Russian forces of misinformation. #KrattLaw—Estonia’s digital shorthand for a new category of legal entity comprising A.I., algorithms, and robots—will make it possible to hold accountable whoever gave a drop of blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;555&quot;&gt;“In the U.S. recently, smart toasters and Teddy bears were used to attack Web sites,” Kaevats said. “Toasters should not be making attacks!” He squatted and emptied a pocket onto the ledge: cigarettes, lighter, a phone. “Wherever there’s a smart device, around it there are other smart devices,” he said, arranging the items on the concrete. “This smart street light”—he stood his lighter up—“asks the self-driving car”—he scooted his phone past it—“ ‘Are you O.K.? Is everything O.K. with you?’ ” The Marlboro box became a building whose appliances made checks of their own, scanning one another for physical and blockchain breaches. Such checks, device to device, have a distributed effect. To commandeer a self-driving car on a street, a saboteur would, in theory, also have to hack every street lamp and smart toaster that it passed. This “mesh network” of devices, Kaevats said, will roll out starting in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;557&quot;&gt;&lt;em data-reactid=&quot;558&quot;&gt;Is everything O.K. with you&lt;/em&gt;? It’s hard to hear about Estonians’ vision for the robots without thinking of the people they’re blood-sworn to serve. I stayed with Kaevats on the Linnahall for more than an hour. He lit several cigarettes, and talked excitedly of “building a digital society.” It struck me then how long it had been since anyone in America had spoken of society-building of any kind. It was as if, in the nineties, Estonia and the U.S. had approached a fork in the road to a digital future, and the U.S. had taken one path—personalization, anonymity, information privatization, and competitive efficiency—while Estonia had taken the other. Two decades on, these roads have led to distinct places, not just in digital culture but in public life as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;561&quot;&gt;Kaevats admitted that he didn’t start out as a techie for the state. He used to be a protester, advocating cycling rights. It had been dispiriting work. “I felt as if I was constantly beating my head against a big concrete wall,” he said. After eight years, he began to resent the person he’d become: angry, distrustful, and negative, with few victories to show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;565&quot;&gt;“My friends and I made a conscious decision then to say ‘Yes’ and not ‘No’—to be proactive rather than destructive,” he explained. He started community organizing (“analog, not digital”) and went to school for architecture, with an eye to structural change through urban planning. “I did that for ten years,” Kaevats said. Then he found architecture, too, frustrating and slow. The more he learned of Estonia’s digital endeavors, the more excited he became. And so he did what seemed the only thing to do: he joined his old foe, the government of Estonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;567&quot;&gt;Kaevats told me it irked him that so many Westerners saw his country as a tech haven. He thought they were missing the point. “This enthusiasm and optimism around technology is like a value of its own,” he complained. “This gadgetry that I’ve been ranting about? This is not &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;569&quot;&gt;important&lt;/em&gt;.” He threw up his hands, scattering ash. “It’s about the mind-set. It’s about the culture. It’s about the human relations—what it enables us to &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;572&quot;&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;575&quot;&gt;Seagulls riding the surf breeze screeched. I asked Kaevats what he saw when he looked at the U.S. Two things, he said. First, a technical mess. Data architecture was too centralized. Citizens didn’t control their own data; it was sold, instead, by brokers. Basic security was lax. “For example, I can tell you my I.D. number—I don’t fucking care,” he said. “You have a Social Security number, which is, like, a big secret.” He laughed. “This does not work!” The U.S. had backward notions of protection, he said, and the result was a bigger problem: a systemic loss of community and trust. “Snowden things and whatnot have done a lot of damage. But they have also proved that these fears are justified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;577&quot;&gt;“To regain this trust takes quite a lot of time,” he went on. “There also needs to be a vision from the political side. It needs to be there always—a policy, not politics. But the politicians need to live it, because, in today’s world, everything will be public at some point.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;579&quot;&gt;We gazed out across the blinding sea. It was nearly midday, and the morning shadows were shrinking to islands at our feet. Kaevats studied his basketball sneakers for a moment, narrowed his eyes under his crown of spiky hair, and lifted his burning cigarette with a smile. “You need to constantly be who you are,” he said. ♦&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 18:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jkaljundi</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://media.newyorker.com/photos/5a2858deb975455799c58fae/16:9/w_1200,h_630,c_limit/171218_r31150.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Estonia, the Digital Republic</og:title>
<og:description>Its government is virtual, borderless, blockchained, and secure. Has this tiny post-Soviet nation found the way of the future?</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/12/18/estonia-the-digital-republic</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/12/18/estonia-the-digital-republic</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Homebrew 1.4.0</title>
<link>https://brew.sh/2017/12/11/homebrew-1.4.0/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://brew.sh/2017/12/11/homebrew-1.4.0/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to announce Homebrew 1.4.0. The most significant change since 1.3.0 is that Homebrew filters environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major changes and deprecations since 1.3.0:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Homebrew filters all user environment variables. This reduces errors in installing formulae from source and in Homebrew commands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homebrew’s “bottle hooks” &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Homebrew/brew/pull/3510&quot;&gt;have been removed&lt;/a&gt;. These were added originally to remove Boxen’s monkey-patching of Homebrew’s internal, private APIs but are no longer necessary for or used by Boxen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Homebrew/science tap is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew-science/issues/6331&quot;&gt;migrating notable formulae to Homebrew/core&lt;/a&gt; and will &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew-science/issues/6365&quot;&gt;be archived&lt;/a&gt; in January 2018. The Homebrew/apache tap &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Homebrew/brew/pull/3274&quot;&gt;has been deprecated and archived&lt;/a&gt;. In 2018 we will also deprecate and archive the Homebrew/php tap. Over the last few minor versions of Homebrew we’ve migrated, deprecated and archived most of the formula taps in the Homebrew organisation to improve the reliability, consistency and discoverability of formulae under the Homebrew organisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;macOS version analytics &lt;a href=&quot;https://brew.sh/analytics/os-version/&quot;&gt;are available&lt;/a&gt; on the brew.sh homepage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other changes since 1.3.0 I’d like to highlight are the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all our hard-working maintainers, contributors, sponsors and supporters for getting us this far. Enjoy using Homebrew!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 17:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mikemcquaid</dc:creator>
<og:title>1.4.0</og:title>
<og:description>Today I’d like to announce Homebrew 1.4.0. The most significant change since 1.3.0 is that Homebrew filters environment variables.</og:description>
<og:url>https://brew.sh/2017/12/11/homebrew-1.4.0/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://brew.sh/2017/12/11/homebrew-1.4.0/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tech luminaries call net neutrality vote an &amp;#039;imminent threat&amp;#039;</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/11/16754040/steve-wozniak-vint-cerf-internet-pioneer-net-neutrality-letter-senate</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/11/16754040/steve-wozniak-vint-cerf-internet-pioneer-net-neutrality-letter-senate</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;41igLF&quot;&gt;A group of early internet and computing pioneers have called on the Senate’s FCC oversight committee to censure next week’s net neutrality vote. &lt;a href=&quot;https://pioneersfornetneutrality.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;In an open letter&lt;/a&gt; to the Senate Commerce Subcommittee on Communications, Technology, Innovation, and the Internet, 21 signatories said that FCC chairman Ajit Pai’s “rushed and technically incorrect” plan to repeal net neutrality “is an imminent threat to the internet we worked so hard to create.” They want the committee to ask Pai to cancel the vote, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680290/fcc-end-net-neutrality-vote-announced&quot;&gt;which is currently scheduled&lt;/a&gt; for December 14th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;XmT1AK&quot;&gt;The list includes some of the people responsible for creating the internet as we know it. That includes Steven Bellovin, a former FTC chief technologist who helped develop Usenet; Tim Berners-Lee, inventor of the World Wide Web; Vinton Cerf, who co-created the internet’s underlying TCP/IP protocol; Steve Crocker, who helped develop the protocols for internet predecessor ARPANET; and Stephen Wolff, who helped transform the military ARPANET into a civilian research and communications network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;11FHWt&quot;&gt;Other signatories include Apple co-founder Steve Wozniak, Mozilla Foundation executive chairwoman Mitchell Baker, Internet Archive founder Brewster Kahle, and Betaworks CEO John Borthwick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;k9Y4wg&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;“An imminent threat to the internet we worked so hard to create”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0cL2J6&quot;&gt;This group points to a 43-page comment submitted by internet experts in July, which was critical of Pai’s early rulemaking notice. Among other things, it said the notice put forward a flawed definition of how the internet works, suggesting that people already expected ISPs to manipulate their data. “Despite this comment, the FCC did not correct its misunderstandings,” they write. “The current technically-incorrect order discards decades of careful work by FCC chairs from both parties, who understood the threats that Internet access providers could pose to open markets on the Internet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;81OJgc&quot;&gt;The letter also raises objections we’ve seen from other groups. It notes the millions of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/4/16734308/eric-schneiderman-jessica-rosenworcel-senators-delay-net-neutrality-vote-fake-comments&quot;&gt;seemingly bot-generated submissions&lt;/a&gt; that polluted the online comment system, and more generally claims that the FCC has failed to engage with the public: it “has not held a single open public meeting to hear from citizens and experts about the proposed order.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6dIO2J&quot;&gt;Like previous calls to delay or cancel the vote — including ones from public interest groups, lawmakers, and two FCC commissioners — this probably won’t sway Pai. His office &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/12/fcc-chair-refuses-to-delay-net-neutrality-vote-despite-pending-court-case/&quot;&gt;called another recent request&lt;/a&gt; a “desperate” attempt to stall the vote, and the agency intentionally ignored even valid comments &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/22/16689838/fcc-net-neutrality-comments-were-largely-ignored&quot;&gt;unless they included&lt;/a&gt; “serious legal arguments.” But it adds some more voices to the long chorus of objectors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 16:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kjhughes</dc:creator>
<og:description>A group of early internet and computing pioneers have called on the Senate’s FCC oversight committee to censure next week’s net neutrality vote. In an open letter to the Senate Commerce...</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/24to36vIXsBwmxEQoJKUgnJhquA=/0x358:5048x3001/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9847887/682271058.jpg.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Vint Cerf, Steve Wozniak, and other tech luminaries call net neutrality vote an &quot;imminent threat&quot;</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/11/16754040/steve-wozniak-vint-cerf-internet-pioneer-net-neutrality-letter-senate</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/11/16754040/steve-wozniak-vint-cerf-internet-pioneer-net-neutrality-letter-senate</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A computer science study plan</title>
<link>https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally created this as a short to-do list of study topics for becoming a software engineer, but it grew to the large list you see today. After going through this study plan, &lt;a href=&quot;https://startupnextdoor.com/ive-been-acquired-by-amazon/?src=ciu&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;I got hired as a Software Development Engineer at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;! You probably won't have to study as much as I did. Anyway, everything you need is here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The items listed here will prepare you well for in an interview at just about any software company, including the giants: Amazon, Facebook, Google or Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best of luck to you!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translations in progress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my multi-month study plan for going from web developer (self-taught, no CS degree) to software engineer for a large company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/9e32acff11b04496eb14e09b198fcbb055c9ccf0/68747470733a2f2f646e67356c33717a7265616c362e636c6f756466726f6e742e6e65742f323031362f4175672f636f64696e675f626f6172645f736d616c6c2d313437303836363336393131382e6a7067&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/9e32acff11b04496eb14e09b198fcbb055c9ccf0/68747470733a2f2f646e67356c33717a7265616c362e636c6f756466726f6e742e6e65742f323031362f4175672f636f64696e675f626f6172645f736d616c6c2d313437303836363336393131382e6a7067&quot; alt=&quot;Coding at the whiteboard - from HBO's Silicon Valley&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://dng5l3qzreal6.cloudfront.net/2016/Aug/coding_board_small-1470866369118.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is meant for &lt;strong&gt;new software engineers&lt;/strong&gt; or those switching from software/web development to software engineering (where computer science knowledge is required). If you have many years of experience and are claiming many years of software engineering experience, expect a harder interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have many years of software/web development experience, note that large software companies like Google, Amazon, Facebook and Microsoft view software engineering as different from software/web development, and they require computer science knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be a reliability engineer or operations engineer, study more from the optional list (networking, security).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---------------- Everything below this point is optional ----------------&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why use it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started this project, I didn't know a stack from a heap, didn't know Big-O anything, anything about trees, or how to traverse a graph. If I had to code a sorting algorithm, I can tell ya it wouldn't have been very good. Every data structure I've ever used was built into the language, and I didn't know how they worked under the hood at all. I've never had to manage memory unless a process I was running would give an &quot;out of memory&quot; error, and then I'd have to find a workaround. I've used a few multidimensional arrays in my life and thousands of associative arrays, but I've never created data structures from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a long plan. It may take you months. If you are familiar with a lot of this already it will take you a lot less time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to use it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything below is an outline, and you should tackle the items in order from top to bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm using Github's special markdown flavor, including tasks lists to check progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a new branch so you can check items like this, just put an x in the brackets: [x]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Fork a branch and follow the commands below
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git checkout -b progress&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add jwasham https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git fetch --all&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Mark all boxes with X after you completed your changes
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit -m &quot;Marked x&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git rebase jwasham/master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push --force&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/#GitHub-flavored-markdown&quot;&gt;More about Github-flavored markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't feel you aren't smart enough&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About Video Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some videos are available only by enrolling in a Coursera, EdX, or Lynda.com class. These are called MOOCs. Sometimes the classes are not in session so you have to wait a couple of months, so you have no access. Lynda.com courses are not free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;I'd appreciate your help to add free and always-available public sources, such as YouTube videos to accompany the online course videos.
I like using university lectures.
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interview Process &amp;amp; General Interview Prep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pick One Language for the Interview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use a language you are comfortable in to do the coding part of the interview, but for large companies, these are solid choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;C++&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could also use these, but read around first. There may be caveats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You need to be very comfortable in the language and be knowledgeable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university/blob/master/programming-language-resources.md&quot;&gt;See language resources here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll see some C, C++, and Python learning included below, because I'm learning. There are a few books involved, see the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Book List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a shorter list than what I used. This is abbreviated to save you time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Interview Prep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have tons of extra time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Computer Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If short on time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have more time (I want this book):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Language Specific&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You need to choose a language for the interview (see above).&lt;/strong&gt; Here are my recommendations by language. I don't have resources for all languages. I welcome additions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read though one of these, you should have all the data structures and algorithms knowledge you'll need to start doing coding problems. &lt;strong&gt;You can skip all the video lectures in this project&lt;/strong&gt;, unless you'd like a review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university/blob/master/programming-language-resources.md&quot;&gt;Additional language-specific resources here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;C++&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't read these two, but they are highly rated and written by Sedgewick. He's awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a better recommendation for C++, please let me know. Looking for a comprehensive resource.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Java&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Optional Books&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some people recommend these, but I think it's going overboard, unless you have many years of software engineering experience and expect a much harder interview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;contains-task-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Algorithm-Design-Manual-Steven-Skiena/dp/1849967202&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Algorithm Design Manual&lt;/a&gt; (Skiena)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;As a review and problem recognition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The algorithm catalog portion is well beyond the scope of difficulty you'll get in an interview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This book has 2 parts:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;class textbook on data structures and algorithms
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;pros:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;is a good review as any algorithms textbook would be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nice stories from his experiences solving problems in industry and academia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code examples in C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cons:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;can be as dense or impenetrable as CLRS, and in some cases, CLRS may be a better alternative for some subjects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chapters 7, 8, 9 can be painful to try to follow, as some items are not explained well or require more brain than I have&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;don't get me wrong: I like Skiena, his teaching style, and mannerisms, but I may not be Stony Brook material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;algorithm catalog:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;this is the real reason you buy this book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;about to get to this part. Will update here once I've made my way through it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can rent it on kindle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answers:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www3.cs.stonybrook.edu/%7Eskiena/algorist/book/errata&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Errata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Introduction-Algorithms-3rd-MIT-Press/dp/0262033844&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Introduction to Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; Reading this book will only have limited value. This book is a great review of algorithms and data structures, but won't teach you how to write good code. You have to be able to code a decent solution efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aka CLR, sometimes CLRS, because Stein was late to the game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Programming-Pearls-2nd-Jon-Bentley/dp/0201657880&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Programming Pearls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The first couple of chapters present clever solutions to programming problems (some very old using data tape) but that is just an intro. This a guidebook on program design and architecture, much like Code Complete, but much shorter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&quot;Algorithms and Programming: Problems and Solutions&quot; by Shen&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A fine book, but after working through problems on several pages I got frustrated with the Pascal, do while loops, 1-indexed arrays, and unclear post-condition satisfaction results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would rather spend time on coding problems from another book or online coding problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Before you Get Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list grew over many months, and yes, it kind of got out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some mistakes I made so you'll have a better experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. You Won't Remember it All&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched hours of videos and took copious notes, and months later there was much I didn't remember. I spent 3 days going through my notes and making flashcards so I could review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read please so you won't make my mistakes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://startupnextdoor.com/retaining-computer-science-knowledge/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retaining Computer Science Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Use Flashcards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the problem, I made a little flashcards site where I could add flashcards of 2 types: general and code. Each card has different formatting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a mobile-first website so I could review on my phone and tablet, wherever I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make your own for free:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind I went overboard and have cards covering everything from assembly language and Python trivia to machine learning and statistics. It's way too much for what's required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note on flashcards:&lt;/strong&gt; The first time you recognize you know the answer, don't mark it as known. You have to see the same card and answer it several times correctly before you really know it. Repetition will put that knowledge deeper in your brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative to using my flashcard site is &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankisrs.net/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;, which has been recommended to me numerous times. It uses a repetition system to help you remember. It's user-friendly, available on all platforms and has a cloud sync system. It costs $25 on iOS but is free on other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My flashcard database in Anki format: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/25173560&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/25173560&lt;/a&gt; (thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/xiewenya&quot;&gt;@xiewenya&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Review, review, review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep a set of cheat sheets on ASCII, OSI stack, Big-O notations, and more. I study them when I have some spare time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a break from programming problems for a half hour and go through your flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. Focus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of distractions that can take up valuable time. Focus and concentration are hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What you won't see covered&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are prevalent technologies but not part of this study plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;SQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML, CSS, and other front-end technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Daily Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some subjects take one day, and some will take multiple days. Some are just learning with nothing to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each day I take one subject from the list below, watch videos about that subject, and write an implementation in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;C - using structs and functions that take a struct * and something else as args.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++ - without using built-in types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++ - using built-in types, like STL's std::list for a linked list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python - using built-in types (to keep practicing Python)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and write tests to ensure I'm doing it right, sometimes just using simple assert() statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may do Java or something else, this is just my thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don't need all these. You need only &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university#pick-one-language-for-the-interview&quot;&gt;one language for the interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why code in all of these?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Practice, practice, practice, until I'm sick of it, and can do it with no problem (some have many edge cases and bookkeeping details to remember)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work within the raw constraints (allocating/freeing memory without help of garbage collection (except Python))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make use of built-in types so I have experience using the built-in tools for real-world use (not going to write my own linked list implementation in production)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I may not have time to do all of these for every subject, but I'll try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see my code here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't need to memorize the guts of every algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write code on a whiteboard or paper, not a computer. Test with some sample inputs. Then test it out on a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisite Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Algorithmic complexity / Big-O / Asymptotic analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data Structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Arrays&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;contains-task-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Implement an automatically resizing vector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Description:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Implement a vector (mutable array with automatic resizing):
&lt;ul class=&quot;contains-task-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Practice coding using arrays and pointers, and pointer math to jump to an index instead of using indexing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; new raw data array with allocated memory
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;can allocate int array under the hood, just not use its features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start with 16, or if starting number is greater, use power of 2 - 16, 32, 64, 128&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; size() - number of items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; capacity() - number of items it can hold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; is_empty()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; at(index) - returns item at given index, blows up if index out of bounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; push(item)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; insert(index, item) - inserts item at index, shifts that index's value and trailing elements to the right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; prepend(item) - can use insert above at index 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; pop() - remove from end, return value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; delete(index) - delete item at index, shifting all trailing elements left&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; remove(item) - looks for value and removes index holding it (even if in multiple places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; find(item) - looks for value and returns first index with that value, -1 if not found&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; resize(new_capacity) // private function
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;when you reach capacity, resize to double the size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when popping an item, if size is 1/4 of capacity, resize to half&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Time
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;O(1) to add/remove at end (amortized for allocations for more space), index, or update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;O(n) to insert/remove elsewhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Space
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;contiguous in memory, so proximity helps performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;space needed = (array capacity, which is &amp;gt;= n) * size of item, but even if 2n, still O(n)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Linked Lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Queue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hash table&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;More Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Binary search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bitwise operations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Trees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trees - Notes &amp;amp; Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Binary search trees: BSTs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Heap / Priority Queue / Binary Heap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sorting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a summary, here is a visual representation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kPRA0W1kECg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;15 sorting algorithms&lt;/a&gt;. If you need more detail on this subject, see &quot;Sorting&quot; section in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university#additional-detail-on-some-subjects&quot;&gt;Additional Detail on Some Subjects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Graphs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graphs can be used to represent many problems in computer science, so this section is long, like trees and sorting were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll get more graph practice in Skiena's book (see Books section below) and the interview books&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Even More Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recursion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dynamic Programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Object-Oriented Programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design patterns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;contains-task-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3cmzqZzwNDM&amp;amp;list=PLGLfVvz_LVvQ5G-LdJ8RLqe-ndo7QITYc&amp;amp;index=3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Quick UML review (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Learn these patterns:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/LAP2A80Ajrg?list=PLJ9pm_Rc9HesnkwKlal_buSIHA-jTZMpO&amp;amp;t=3344&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chapter 6 (Part 1) - Patterns (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U8-PGsjvZc4&amp;amp;index=12&amp;amp;list=PLJ9pm_Rc9HesnkwKlal_buSIHA-jTZMpO&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chapter 6 (Part 2) - Abstraction-Occurrence, General Hierarchy, Player-Role, Singleton, Observer, Delegation (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7sduBHuex4c&amp;amp;index=13&amp;amp;list=PLJ9pm_Rc9HesnkwKlal_buSIHA-jTZMpO&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chapter 6 (Part 3) - Adapter, Facade, Immutable, Read-Only Interface, Proxy (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLF206E906175C7E07&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Series of videos (27 videos)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Head-First-Design-Patterns-Freeman/dp/0596007124&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Head First Design Patterns&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I know the canonical book is &quot;Design Patterns: Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented Software&quot;, but Head First is great for beginners to OO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourcemaking.com/design-patterns-and-tips&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Handy reference: 101 Design Patterns &amp;amp; Tips for Developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kamranahmedse/design-patterns-for-humans#structural-design-patterns&quot;&gt;Design patterns for humans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Combinatorics (n choose k) &amp;amp; Probability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NP, NP-Complete and Approximation Algorithms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Caches&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Processes and Threads&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;contains-task-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Computer Science 162 - Operating Systems (25 videos):
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-difference-between-a-process-and-a-thread&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What Is The Difference Between A Process And A Thread?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Covers:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Processes, Threads, Concurrency issues
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;difference between processes and threads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;threads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;locks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mutexes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;semaphores&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;monitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how they work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deadlock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;livelock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU activity, interrupts, context switching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modern concurrency constructs with multicore processors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LKe7xK0bF7o&amp;amp;list=PLCiOXwirraUCBE9i_ukL8_Kfg6XNv7Se8&amp;amp;index=2&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Paging, segmentation and virtual memory (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uFKi2-J-6II&amp;amp;list=PLCiOXwirraUCBE9i_ukL8_Kfg6XNv7Se8&amp;amp;index=3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Interrupts (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-Gu5mYdKbu4&amp;amp;index=4&amp;amp;list=PLCiOXwirraUCBE9i_ukL8_Kfg6XNv7Se8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Scheduling (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process resource needs (memory: code, static storage, stack, heap, and also file descriptors, i/o)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thread resource needs (shares above (minus stack) with other threads in the same process but each has its own pc, stack counter, registers, and stack)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forking is really copy on write (read-only) until the new process writes to memory, then it does a full copy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Context switching
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How context switching is initiated by the operating system and underlying hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5jc9xFGsL8E12so1wlMS0r0hTQoJL74M&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;threads in C++ (series - 10 videos)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; concurrency in Python (videos):
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Papers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scheduling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;in an OS, how it works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can be gleaned from Operating System videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Implement system routines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;understand what lies beneath the programming APIs you use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can you implement them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;String searching &amp;amp; manipulations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need more detail on this subject, see &quot;String Matching&quot; section in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university#additional-detail-on-some-subjects&quot;&gt;Additional Detail on Some Subjects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Floating Point Numbers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unicode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Endianness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Networking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;System Design, Scalability, Data Handling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;contains-task-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can expect system design questions if you have 4+ years of experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scalability and System Design are very large topics with many topics and resources, since there is a lot to consider when designing a software/hardware system that can scale. Expect to spend quite a bit of time on this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Considerations:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;scalability
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Distill large data sets to single values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transform one data set to another&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handling obscenely large amounts of data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;system design
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;features sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interfaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;class hierarchies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;designing a system under certain constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simplicity and robustness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tradeoffs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;performance analysis and optimization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;START HERE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer&quot;&gt;The System Design Primer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hiredintech.com/system-design/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;System Design from HiredInTech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-to-answer-design-questions-in-a-technical-interview?redirected_qid=1500023&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How Do I Prepare To Answer Design Questions In A Technical Inverview?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.gainlo.co/index.php/2015/10/22/8-things-you-need-to-know-before-system-design-interviews/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;8 Things You Need to Know Before a System Design Interview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hiredintech.com/algorithm-design/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Algorithm design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UrYLYV7WSHM&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Database Normalization - 1NF, 2NF, 3NF and 4NF (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/checkcheckzz/system-design-interview&quot;&gt;System Design Interview&lt;/a&gt; - There are a lot of resources in this one. Look through the articles and examples. I put some of them below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.palantir.com/2011/10/how-to-rock-a-systems-design-interview/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How to ace a systems design interview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://everythingisdata.wordpress.com/2009/10/17/numbers-everyone-should-know/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Numbers Everyone Should Know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.tsunanet.net/2010/11/how-long-does-it-take-to-make-context.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How long does it take to make a context switch?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=srOgpXECblk&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Transactions Across Datacenters (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ksat.me/a-plain-english-introduction-to-cap-theorem/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A plain English introduction to CAP Theorem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Paxos Consensus algorithm:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tom-e-white.com/2007/11/consistent-hashing.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Consistent Hashing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://horicky.blogspot.com/2009/11/nosql-patterns.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NoSQL Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Scalability:
&lt;ul class=&quot;contains-task-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-W9F__D3oY4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Great overview (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Short series:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aosabook.org/en/distsys.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Scalable Web Architecture and Distributed Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.cs.wisc.edu/%7Ezuyu/files/fallacies.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Fallacies of Distributed Computing Explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://horicky.blogspot.com/2010/10/scalable-system-design-patterns.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Pragmatic Programming Techniques&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=modXC5IWTJI&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jeff Dean - Building Software Systems At Google and Lessons Learned (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lethain.com/introduction-to-architecting-systems-for-scale/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Introduction to Architecting Systems for Scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9nWyWwY2Onc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Scaling mobile games to a global audience using App Engine and Cloud Datastore (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H4vMcD7zKM0&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How Google Does Planet-Scale Engineering for Planet-Scale Infra (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.topcoder.com/community/data-science/data-science-tutorials/the-importance-of-algorithms/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Importance of Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2009/8/6/an-unorthodox-approach-to-database-design-the-coming-of-the.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Sharding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infoq.com/presentations/Scale-at-Facebook&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Scale at Facebook (2009)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oodS71YtkGU&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Scale at Facebook (2012), &quot;Building for a Billion Users&quot; (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p0jGmgIrf_M&amp;amp;list=PLRXxvay_m8gqVlExPC5DG3TGWJTaBgqSA&amp;amp;index=4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Engineering for the Long Game - Astrid Atkinson Keynote(video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2012/3/26/7-years-of-youtube-scalability-lessons-in-30-minutes.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;7 Years Of YouTube Scalability Lessons In 30 Minutes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/8/15/how-paypal-scaled-to-billions-of-transactions-daily-using-ju.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How PayPal Scaled To Billions Of Transactions Daily Using Just 8VMs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.clevertap.com/how-to-remove-duplicates-in-large-datasets/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How to Remove Duplicates in Large Datasets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3vV4YiqKm1o&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A look inside Etsy's scale and engineering culture with Jon Cowie (video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thenewstack.io/led-amazon-microservices-architecture/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What Led Amazon to its Own Microservices Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/trip-data-squeeze/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;To Compress Or Not To Compress, That Was Uber's Question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/3/3/asyncio-tarantool-queue-get-in-the-queue.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Asyncio Tarantool Queue, Get In The Queue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/2/25/when-should-approximate-query-processing-be-used.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;When Should Approximate Query Processing Be Used?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/2/23/googles-transition-from-single-datacenter-to-failover-to-a-n.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Google's Transition From Single Datacenter, To Failover, To A Native Multihomed Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2012/9/24/google-spanners-most-surprising-revelation-nosql-is-out-and.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Spanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/2/15/egnyte-architecture-lessons-learned-in-building-and-scaling.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Egnyte Architecture: Lessons Learned In Building And Scaling A Multi Petabyte Distributed System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/7/6/machine-learning-driven-programming-a-new-programming-for-a.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Machine Learning Driven Programming: A New Programming For A New World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/6/15/the-image-optimization-technology-that-serves-millions-of-re.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Image Optimization Technology That Serves Millions Of Requests Per Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/2/1/a-patreon-architecture-short.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A Patreon Architecture Short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/1/27/tinder-how-does-one-of-the-largest-recommendation-engines-de.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tinder: How Does One Of The Largest Recommendation Engines Decide Who You'll See Next?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/1/25/design-of-a-modern-cache.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Design Of A Modern Cache&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/1/13/live-video-streaming-at-facebook-scale.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Live Video Streaming At Facebook Scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2016/1/11/a-beginners-guide-to-scaling-to-11-million-users-on-amazons.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A Beginner's Guide To Scaling To 11 Million+ Users On Amazon's AWS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2015/12/16/how-does-the-use-of-docker-effect-latency.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How Does The Use Of Docker Effect Latency?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2015/12/14/does-amp-counter-an-existential-threat-to-google.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Does AMP Counter An Existential Threat To Google?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2015/11/9/a-360-degree-view-of-the-entire-netflix-stack.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A 360 Degree View Of The Entire Netflix Stack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/latency-everywhere-and-it-costs-you-sales-how-crush-it&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Latency Is Everywhere And It Costs You Sales - How To Crush It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://martinfowler.com/articles/serverless.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Serverless (very long, just need the gist)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram-engineering.tumblr.com/post/13649370142/what-powers-instagram-hundreds-of-instances&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What Powers Instagram: Hundreds of Instances, Dozens of Technologies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2012/7/16/cinchcast-architecture-producing-1500-hours-of-audio-every-d.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cinchcast Architecture - Producing 1,500 Hours Of Audio Every Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2010/3/16/justintvs-live-video-broadcasting-architecture.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Justin.Tv's Live Video Broadcasting Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2010/9/21/playfishs-social-gaming-architecture-50-million-monthly-user.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Playfish's Social Gaming Architecture - 50 Million Monthly Users And Growing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2011/6/27/tripadvisor-architecture-40m-visitors-200m-dynamic-page-view.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;TripAdvisor Architecture - 40M Visitors, 200M Dynamic Page Views, 30TB Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/plentyoffish-architecture&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PlentyOfFish Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2013/9/23/salesforce-architecture-how-they-handle-13-billion-transacti.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Salesforce Architecture - How They Handle 1.3 Billion Transactions A Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highscalability.com/blog/2013/11/4/espns-architecture-at-scale-operating-at-100000-duh-nuh-nuhs.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ESPN's Architecture At Scale - Operating At 100,000 Duh Nuh Nuhs Per Second&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; See &quot;Messaging, Serialization, and Queueing Systems&quot; way below for info on some of the technologies that can glue services together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Twitter:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For even more, see &quot;Mining Massive Datasets&quot; video series in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university#video-series&quot;&gt;Video Series&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt; Practicing the system design process: Here are some ideas to try working through on paper, each with some documentation on how it was handled in the real world:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;review: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer&quot;&gt;The System Design Primer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hiredintech.com/system-design/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;System Design from HiredInTech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university/blob/master/extras/cheat%20sheets/system-design.pdf&quot;&gt;cheat sheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flow:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Understand the problem and scope:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;define the use cases, with interviewer's help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;suggest additional features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove items that interviewer deems out of scope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assume high availability is required, add as a use case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about constraints:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ask how many requests per month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ask how many requests per second (they may volunteer it or make you do the math)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;estimate reads vs. writes percentage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep 80/20 rule in mind when estimating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how much data written per second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;total storage required over 5 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how much data read per second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abstract design:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;layers (service, data, caching)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;infrastructure: load balancing, messaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rough overview of any key algorithm that drives the service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consider bottlenecks and determine solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercises:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Final Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;This section will have shorter videos that you can watch pretty quickly to review most of the important concepts.
It's nice if you want a refresher often.
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Coding Question Practice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you know all the computer science topics above, it's time to practice answering coding problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coding question practice is not about memorizing answers to programming problems.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why you need to practice doing programming problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;problem recognition, and where the right data structures and algorithms fit in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gathering requirements for the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;talking your way through the problem like you will in the interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coding on a whiteboard or paper, not a computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coming up with time and space complexity for your solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;testing your solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a great intro for methodical, communicative problem solving in an interview. You'll get this from the programming interview books, too, but I found this outstanding: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hiredintech.com/algorithm-design/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Algorithm design canvas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No whiteboard at home? That makes sense. I'm a weirdo and have a big whiteboard. Instead of a whiteboard, pick up a large drawing pad from an art store. You can sit on the couch and practice. This is my &quot;sofa whiteboard&quot;. I added the pen in the photo for scale. If you use a pen, you'll wish you could erase. Gets messy quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/1d833d443da32bb964e1dee3a64b8a035aab4ea6/68747470733a2f2f646e67356c33717a7265616c362e636c6f756466726f6e742e6e65742f323031362f4f63742f6172745f626f6172645f736d5f322d313437363233333633303336382e6a7067&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/1d833d443da32bb964e1dee3a64b8a035aab4ea6/68747470733a2f2f646e67356c33717a7265616c362e636c6f756466726f6e742e6e65742f323031362f4f63742f6172745f626f6172645f736d5f322d313437363233333633303336382e6a7067&quot; alt=&quot;my sofa whiteboard&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://dng5l3qzreal6.cloudfront.net/2016/Oct/art_board_sm_2-1476233630368.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplemental:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read and Do Programming Problems (in this order):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university#book-list&quot;&gt;Book List above&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coding exercises/challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you've learned your brains out, put those brains to work. Take coding challenges every day, as many as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coding Interview Question Videos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenge sites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenge repos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mock Interviews:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Once you're closer to the interview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Your Resume&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;See Resume prep items in Cracking The Coding Interview and back of Programming Interviews Exposed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Be thinking of for when the interview comes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of about 20 interview questions you'll get, along with the lines of the items below. Have 2-3 answers for each. Have a story, not just data, about something you accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why do you want this job?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's a tough problem you've solved?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biggest challenges faced?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best/worst designs seen?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideas for improving an existing product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you work best, as an individual and as part of a team?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of your skills or experiences would be assets in the role and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did you most enjoy at [job x / project y]?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the biggest challenge you faced at [job x / project y]?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the hardest bug you faced at [job x / project y]?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did you learn at [job x / project y]?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would you have done better at [job x / project y]?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Have questions for the interviewer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Some of mine (I already may know answer to but want their opinion or team perspective):
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How large is your team?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does your dev cycle look like? Do you do waterfall/sprints/agile?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are rushes to deadlines common? Or is there flexibility?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are decisions made in your team?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many meetings do you have per week?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you feel your work environment helps you concentrate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are you working on?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you like about it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the work life like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Once You've Got The Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're never really done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;*****************************************************************************************************
*****************************************************************************************************

Everything below this point is optional.
By studying these, you'll get greater exposure to more CS concepts, and will be better prepared for
any software engineering job. You'll be a much more well-rounded software engineer.

*****************************************************************************************************
*****************************************************************************************************
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Additional Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These topics will likely not come up in an interview, but I added them to help you become a well-rounded software engineer, and to be aware of certain technologies and algorithms, so you'll have a bigger toolbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Compilers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Emacs and vi(m)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Familiarize yourself with a unix-based code editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vi(m):
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emacs:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unix command line tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Information theory (videos)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Parity &amp;amp; Hamming Code (videos)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Entropy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cryptography&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Compression&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Computer Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Garbage collection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Parallel Programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Messaging, Serialization, and Queueing Systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A*&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fast Fourier Transform&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bloom Filter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;HyperLogLog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Locality-Sensitive Hashing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;used to determine the similarity of documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the opposite of MD5 or SHA which are used to determine if 2 documents/strings are exactly the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ferd.ca/simhashing-hopefully-made-simple.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Simhashing (hopefully) made simple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;van Emde Boas Trees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Augmented Data Structures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Balanced search trees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;contains-task-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know least one type of balanced binary tree (and know how it's implemented):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Among balanced search trees, AVL and 2/3 trees are now passé, and red-black trees seem to be more popular. A particularly interesting self-organizing data structure is the splay tree, which uses rotations to move any accessed key to the root.&quot; - Skiena&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of these, I chose to implement a splay tree. From what I've read, you won't implement a balanced search tree in your interview. But I wanted exposure to coding one up and let's face it, splay trees are the bee's knees. I did read a lot of red-black tree code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;splay tree: insert, search, delete functions If you end up implementing red/black tree try just these:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;search and insertion functions, skipping delete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn more about B-Tree since it's used so widely with very large data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-balancing_binary_search_tree&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Self-balancing binary search tree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AVL trees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Splay trees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red/black trees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2-3 search trees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2-3-4 Trees (aka 2-4 trees)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N-ary (K-ary, M-ary) trees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; id=&quot;&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B-Trees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;k-D Trees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Skip lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Network Flows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Disjoint Sets &amp;amp; Union Find&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Math for Fast Processing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Treap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Linear Programming (videos)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Geometry, Convex hull (videos)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Discrete math&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;see videos below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Detail on Some Subjects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;I added these to reinforce some ideas already presented above, but didn't want to include them
above because it's just too much. It's easy to overdo it on a subject.
You want to get hired in this century, right?
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Video Series&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit back and enjoy. &quot;Netflix and skill&quot; :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computer Science Courses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 16:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rhakmi</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/3771963?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>jwasham/coding-interview-university</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university</og:url>
<og:description>coding-interview-university - A complete computer science study plan to become a software engineer.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/jwasham/coding-interview-university</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Exercism – Level up your programming skills</title>
<link>http://exercism.io</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://exercism.io</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Are you a code newbie?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;12.822742474916&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feelz&quot;&gt;One moment you feel like you're getting it. The next moment you're stuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-8&quot; readability=&quot;18.854961832061&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning to program is exhilarating and challenging... and also frustrating, exhausting, and overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercism provides countless small wins. The exercises are achievable mini-quests: small and well-defined, and with enough complexity to uncover bite-sized knowledge gaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solutions you write provide reviewers with clues about what you haven't grasped yet. The feedback you receive will guide you to relevant study topics and dramatically increase the ease with which you write code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://exercism.io/how-it-works/newbie&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-lg btn-block cta-btn&quot;&gt;write code like it's prose →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Are you ramping up in a new language?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;15.87091503268&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feelz&quot;&gt;You know what it’s like to be fluent. Suddenly you’re feeling incompetent and clumsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-8&quot; readability=&quot;24.900966183575&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning a new language can be both thrilling and deeply uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re used to being productive. Now you feel hamstrung with one hand tied behind your back and an unfair suspicion that you should already know this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a gap when you're past the basics but real-world problems leave you swamped by details and wandering down rabbit holes. Exercism aims to fill that gap with lots of small, self-contained practice problems with just enough complexity to stretch your mind around new concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your solutions are the starting point for a conversation centered around style, idioms, and best practices. You can write FORTRAN in any language, as the saying famously goes, but with enough feedback, you’ll quickly find yourself writing the language the way it wants to be written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://exercism.io/how-it-works/polyglot&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-lg btn-block cta-btn&quot;&gt;become fluent in a new language →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Are you hooked on clean code?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;15.329842931937&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feelz&quot;&gt;Haphazard, convoluted code is infuriating, not to mention costly. That slapdash explosion of complexity is an expensive yak shave waiting to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-8&quot; readability=&quot;20.855284552846&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's an art and a science to transforming unmaintainable code into elegant simplicity. It takes practice, experimentation, and deep thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercism's tiny toy problems, in the form of automated tests, provide a balance of constraints and freedom. The exercises encourage you to explore trade-offs and best-practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each solution you write is an occasion to ponder readability and code smells. Each solution you review challenges you to articulate your experiences and gut feelings. Each discussion is an opportunity to strengthen your instincts for clean, well-factored code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://exercism.io/how-it-works/artisan&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-lg btn-block cta-btn&quot;&gt;master the art of clean code →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 15:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>moesart</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>http://exercism.io/icons/exercism_og.png</og:image>
<og:title>Exercism.io: Crowd-sourced code mentorship.</og:title>
<og:description>Practice having thoughtful conversations about code.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://exercism.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A decentralised Universal Basic Income platform based on personal currencies</title>
<link>https://github.com/CirclesUBI/docs/blob/master/Circles.md</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/CirclesUBI/docs/blob/master/Circles.md</guid>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A decentralised Universal Basic Income platform based on personal currencies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://joincircles.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://joincircles.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a new money system called Circles that is based on individualized cryptocurrencies and a social graph of trust between these currencies. This money system will be for the purposes of distributing and maintaining a globally accessible Universal Basic Income. When new users join Circles, a new personal cryptocurrency is created for them on a smart contract-enabled blockchain. This currency is then regularly minted and added to their account, forming the basis of Circles' UBI properties. Users have the ability to trust the personal currencies of other users, which requires them to treat this personal currency as identical to any other Circles currencies that they hold. As the social graph becomes more interconnected, these personal currencies converge on one single global monetary system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universal Basic Income is one of the most cross-culturaly appealing political movements of the modern era. It has attracted the support of thinkers from every background including Milton Friedman, Friedrich Hayek, Elon Musk, Martin Luther King Jr, Stephen Hawking, and Noam Chomsky. It is seen as a utopian project that could finally unlock the creative potential of all people, the culmination of centuries-old humanist ideals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topic of UBI has exploded in popularity in recent years, as wealth inequality grows and inflation-adjusted wages fall all across the world. Until now, the conversation has primarily been viewed through the lens of public policy and bureaucratic action. Public support for the idea of UBI has never been higher, but plans for implementation are progressing slowly and without cooperation at the international scale. It seems that UBI systems have received a &quot;too big to implement&quot; label at the highest levels of government, similar to climate change action, making development and rollout unlikely to happen any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of global blockchain networks changes the conversation about UBI significantly. Now for the first time in history, it is trivially easy to create financial applications that are universally accessible to anyone on the internet. Starting with Bitcoin and moving on to smart contract platforms like Ethereum, blockchain technology has achieved widespread popularity by routing around the gatekeepers and roadblocks that make innovation so difficult in the legacy financial system. Smart contracts and the blockchain create a very promising environment in which to implement a new UBI system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circles proposes to be the blockchain's native UBI money system. It has its own built-in resistance to Sybil attacks (i.e. fake accounts) and anyone can join the network at any time without asking permission from anyone. It has been designed with the expectation that it will be bootstrapped in a completely organic and grassroots fashion, but is extensible to allow any arbitrary governance systems to operate on top of the base protocol. Circles is an entirely new way of looking at the nature of money and what value exchange means in a post-UBI future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minting Currency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circles is a money system that is made up of individual currencies. These currencies work together to create an economy that can support Universal Basic Income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a new blockchain account joins Circles, the system creates and assigns them a unique currency via a smart contract. This is called a &lt;em&gt;Personal Currency&lt;/em&gt;, and all personal currencies operate according to a shared set of rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each personal currency continuously mints new coins and awards them to its associated person. This is the only way that new money is created in Circles and forms the basis of its UBI characteristics. All currencies mint new coins at the same rate, meaning that new money is distributed equally to all members of the system at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Alice joins the system, creating AliceCoin
PersonalCoins are all minted at a rate of 1 per minute
Five minutes later Alice has 5 AliceCoin and Bob joins the system, creating BobCoin
Five minutes later Alice has 10 AliceCoin and Bob has 5 BobCoin
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that new currency units are only awarded to the person associated with each personal currency:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Alice joins the system, creating AliceCoin
PersonalCoins are all minted at a rate of 1 per minute
Five minutes later Alice has 5 AliceCoin and Bob joins the system, creating BobCoin
Alice transfers her 5 AliceCoin to Bob
Alice has 0 PersonalCoins and Bob has 5 AliceCoin
Five minutes later Alice has 5 AliceCoin while Bob has 5 AliceCoin and 5 BobCoin
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Inflation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to disincentivize hoarding and to encourage economic activity, the system will introduce an annual inflation schedule. All personal currencies will issue progressively larger amounts of tokens per second, and new users will always start issuing at a rate that is consistent with all other personal currencies. The inflation schedule is meant to work in much the same way that inflation works in the traditional economy, but the implementation specifics are still an open topic for research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trusting Currency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to create useful money, users trust each other’s currencies. Trust is what facilitates exchange in the system. When a user trusts a currency, they tell the system that it is equivalent to any other Circles currencies that they already have. This means that anyone with this trusted currency can automatically trade it for one of your Circles currencies at a one-to-one exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Bob trusts AliceCoin
Bob has 10 CarolCoin
Dave has 10 AliceCoin
Dave gives 5 AliceCoin to Bob and takes 5 CarolCoin from him
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way of thinking about trust is that it is the user telling the system that they acknowledge specific currencies as “real money.” Since any blockchain account can join the system and start minting currency, a trivial attack is to create multiple accounts and register with each to get multiple basic incomes. This is called a Sybil attack in computer security terms. The existence of trust relationships is how users protect themselves from fake accounts by specifying which ones they know for a fact represent an individual human’s primary account, forming a native Sybil resistance in the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because trust is a way to protect from counterfeit currencies, it is a serious responsibility on the part of the user. Users will have to rely heavily on mutual connections when making direct peer-to-peer trust relationships, and new users with no trust connections will have to get their closest loved ones to be their initial connections. However in order to increase usability, some exceptions to these high requirements are covered in the Validators section below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Transitive Exchange&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trusting different currencies creates a useful form of money because of the transitive nature of social networks. Money is useful when it allows complete strangers to efficiently conduct business. When one stranger wants to send money to another in Circles, they automatically search for a transitive chain of trusted currencies between each other. The payer then trades along this chain of trusted currencies, one after the other, until they have one that the recipient accepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Bob trusts AliceCoin
Alice trusts CarolCoin
Alice has 10 AliceCoin
Carol has 10 CarolCoin
Carol wants to pay Bob 5 PersonalCoins
Carol gives 5 CarolCoin to Alice and takes 5 AliceCoin from her
Carol gives 5 AliceCoin to Bob 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CirclesUBI/docs/master/assets/diagram_1.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CirclesUBI/docs/master/assets/diagram_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transaction can be extended to include multi-hop chains of trust as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Bob trusts AliceCoin
Alice trusts CarolCoin
Carol trusts DaveCoin
Alice has 10 AliceCoin
Carol has 10 CarolCoin
Dave has 10 DaveCoin
Dave wants to pay Bob 5 PersonalCoins
Dave gives 5 DaveCoin to Carol and takes 5 CarolCoin from her
Dave gives 5 CarolCoin to Alice and takes 5 AliceCoin from her
Dave gives 5 AliceCoin to Bob
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CirclesUBI/docs/master/assets/diagram_3.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CirclesUBI/docs/master/assets/diagram_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this system, the connectedness of the social network serves as a direct measure of users’ ability to transact with each other. A familiar way of thinking about this is the famous six degrees of separation phenomenon that suggests everyone on earth is connected to everyone else by a chain of six people. Circles uses these chains to transact through the system. If a user is well-integrated into the network, with many connections to other well-integrated users, they will find it easier to send and receive personal currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Limits to Trust&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because personal currencies are only able to travel through their networks of trust, the value of a specific personal currency is a measure of how many other accounts trust it. This means that users who are new to the system and don’t have many trusted relationships have a less valuable currency than someone who is well-established in the network. It also means that the currency of new users gets more valuable over time as they create more trust relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the system internally enforces a one-to-one exchange rate, and new users’ personal currencies are less valuable than established users personal currencies, a potential problem emerges:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;25 people trust AliceCoin
Bob is new, so only Alice trusts BobCoin
Bob has 100 BobCoin
Alice has 100 AliceCoin
Bob gives 100 BobCoin to Alice and takes 100 AliceCoin from her
Bob can now spend money with 25 people (and their friends, and friends of friends, etc)
Alice can now only spend money with Bob
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CirclesUBI/docs/master/assets/diagram_4.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CirclesUBI/docs/master/assets/diagram_4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the example above, Alice needs a way to acknowledge that BobCoin is real money, while limiting her exposure to it while Bob is still new. Circles achieves this with Trust Limits. When you create a trust relationship in Circles, you have the option to include the maximum amount you are willing to accept via automatic exchange per month. With trust limits, Alice is able to help Bob integrate into the system in a more controlled way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;25 people trust AliceCoin
Bob is new, so only Alice trusts BobCoin
Alice puts a limit of 10 BobCoin per month on her trust
Bob has 100 BobCoin
Alice has 100 AliceCoin
Bob gives 10 BobCoin to Alice and takes 10 AliceCoin from her
Bob can now spend one tenth of his money with 25 people (and their friends, and friends of friends, etc)
Alice sets aside her 10 BobCoins to spend once Bob has made more trust relationships
Bob gets 10 people to trust BobCoin
Alice raises her trust limit on BobCoin to 100 per month
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust limits reduce the risk of trusting new accounts to the system, making it easier for them to build trust relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Defending Against Fake Accounts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we’ve shown, fake accounts are a primary consideration when designing protections into the system. Since money can be spent indirectly through transitive connections, let’s show how Circles defends against fake accounts that are connected to your friends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Bob trusts AliceCoin
Alice makes a fake account and trusts FakeCoin
Alice has 10 AliceCoin
FakeAlice has 10 FakeCoin
Alice wants to buy something worth 10 PersonalCoins from Bob using FakeCoin
FakeAlice gives 10 FakeCoin to Alice and takes 5 AliceCoin from her
FakeAlice gives 10 AliceCoin to Bob
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CirclesUBI/docs/master/assets/diagram_2.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CirclesUBI/docs/master/assets/diagram_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example demonstrates that Bob can only ever receive money that he trusts, and Alice can only ever spend money that other users trust in turn. Even if Alice makes 100 fake accounts and has them all trust each other, she will never be able to spend more than the amount of AliceCoins she has, since that’s the only account that other users will trust. This is why it is crucial that users take direct peer-to-peer trust relationships seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Validators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far the Circles money system is both self-sovereign and resilient to fake accounts, but it is not very user-friendly. New users are given currency that is worthless by default, and they have to take steps to increase its value. This problem is alleviated by the addition of Validators, which allow users to quickly add value to their personal currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Validators are blockchain organizations that can create and receive trust relationships just like users can. When a user trusts a validator, they automatically trust the currency of every user that the validator trusts. This means all the users that the validator trusts can transitively use the currency of anyone who trusts the validator. When a validator trusts a new user, they add them as a beneficiary of the trust relationships that the validator has already received. Users achieve this by delegating the work required to validate real accounts to the validator’s administrators. This means that admins have an even higher requirement to ensure that all accounts trusted by the validator are the primary accounts of real people. If a validator’s member set is small, it might mean that the main admin has to personally meet everyone and verify they are a member of the community. If it is large, it might require submitting government issued identification or even biometric data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Bob and Alice make a Validator called TigersFans
Carol signs up for Circles, creating CarolCoins
10 minutes pass and Carol has 10 CarolCoins
Carol asks to be trusted by the Validator and proves that she is a true Tigers Fan. Bob and Alice vote to let her join
Eve trusts the TigerFans Validator
Carol can now spend her CarolCoins with Eve
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CirclesUBI/docs/master/assets/diagram_5.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CirclesUBI/docs/master/assets/diagram_5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because membership business logic is arbitrary, any type of association can be fronted by a validator. Users might be validated as citizens of a city, tenants of an apartment building, or practitioners of a certain trade. Being validated by popular validators will dramatically increase the reach of a users personal currency. Likewise, users who trust popular validators make it easy for them to receive currency they know will be spendable elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Complementary Currency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circles is not meant to become the world's dominant currency, cryptographic or otherwise. Rather, it is a complementary currency, working in harmony alongside other stores of value and mediums of exchange. In the future Circles could even serve as a foundational &quot;hard currency&quot; for a more flexible group currency built on top. It is ideal as a hard currency because the supply of specific individual currencies is perfectly predictable and the aggregate system is highly resilient due to its lack of reliance on a centralized identity provider. This hypothetical group currency could function in much the same way that validators work, with arbitrary business logic to determine group membership. The group could then one-way convert the personal currencies of its members into a fungible group currency at a dynamic exchange rate that meets the group's needs over time. This would allow Circles to act as a staging ground for many different experiments in consensus reality (and morality), while still providing individual users the freedom to revert back to personal currencies if any one group becomes corrupted or useless. The possibilities for new political forms are numerous, but the potential for layer 2 systems on top of the base protocol is by far the most speculative aspect of the project and remains a decidedly open question for further research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Circles Money System was designed to get started creating a UBI economy today. We believe that the combination of resilience and global accessibility afforded by blockchain technology is a key catalyst that makes a Universal Basic Income achieveable within the next generation. Our system's native Sybil-attack resistance and platform for collective governance via Validators make it an ideal focus for grassroots action and community organization, which have been hallmarks of envisioned UBI economies over the years. We are actively researching the economic implications of Circles' various design tradeoffs with the intention of creating a money system that is as useful and stable as possible. Our roadmap is designed to get started with trial applications as soon as possible in order to see how this new form of value exchange behaves in real economic settings. We are very excited about the potential of this project and hope that it can serve as a critical foundation for a new economic paradigm in the decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 13:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nathanrosquist</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/30386623?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>CirclesUBI/docs</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/CirclesUBI/docs</og:url>
<og:description>Contribute to docs development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/CirclesUBI/docs/blob/master/Circles.md</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>