<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Pricing low-touch SaaS</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/saas-pricing</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/saas-pricing</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas&quot;&gt;Stripe Atlas&lt;/a&gt;, which helps internet companies get up and running, frequently gets asked questions by software-as-a-service entrepreneurs on how to improve the pricing and packaging of their SaaS products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After publishing our recent guide to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/business-of-saas&quot;&gt;low-touch and high-touch SaaS businesses&lt;/a&gt;, we had a Q&amp;amp;A session in our private forums for SaaS entrepreneurs specific to pricing and packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the entrepreneurs generously allowed us to talk about their pricing strategy publicly, to help the next generation of SaaS companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This advice is distilled from my career in running and consulting in various SaaS companies. Your mileage may vary; I’d encourage you to experiment often and boldly with pricing, as it is the easiest needle to move in your company. (Most SaaS companies is to set prices without much consideration and leave them alone for years at a time. I’d encourage you to revisit them quarterly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By coincidence, most of the companies which we’ll be talking about sell SaaS on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/business-of-saas#low-touch-saas-sales&quot;&gt;low-touch&lt;/a&gt; model. Pricing for high-touch SaaS is similarly nuanced; we’ll cover it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve organized the case studies based on the primary market for the products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pricing-and-packaging-for-things-with-no-physical-form&quot;&gt;Pricing and packaging for things with no physical form&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing&lt;/strong&gt; is easy enough to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Packaging&lt;/strong&gt; is a jargon word coming from marketing of consumer packaged goods, like soap. In SaaS, it refers to a company which has one particular underlying product which they make available to different customers in slightly different ways at different price points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In low-touch SaaS, the most common way packages are presented are as different columns in a pricing grid, with each column corresponding to a &lt;strong&gt;plan&lt;/strong&gt;, offered at a different price, with differential access to features or maximum allowable usage along some axis interesting to the business. This might be users (referred to pervasively, and unfortunately, in the industry as &lt;strong&gt;seats&lt;/strong&gt;) or servers or something with a closer connection to the problem domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cirtru-case-study&quot;&gt;Cirtru case study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cirtru helps match people with new roommates. The customer is the person seeking a roommate, not the person seeking a new apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their existing pricing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/cirtru.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/cirtru.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cirtru pricing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;reduce-decision-fatigue-for-customers&quot;&gt;Reduce decision fatigue for customers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re asking the user to make a big decision here: Concierge or Premium Listing. Those achieve different goals for different people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core insight here is great, which is that some people want to buy a tool and some people have more money and just want to buy an outcome. The desired outcome is “Find me a paying tenant who probably won’t skip out on rent or murder me in my sleep.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d probably position that choice explicitly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find me a roommate / I want to do my own legwork finding a roommate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d default people into the first option and either deemphasize the details of the second (via greying them out or something) or hide them until someone interacted with the downsell option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This decreases my cognitive load to make the decision:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do I want you to find me a roommate?” Of course yes, that is why I am here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How long should we look?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And my answer to that is probably “I don’t know, as much as required, but I want the roommate fast”, which suggests to me as the user that I don’t conceive of the value of this service along the same axis that you conceive of charging for it. You want to charge for your costs. I don’t want to pay you more for concierging longer; I want to pay you more for concierging more efficiently. The ideal for me is probably paying you a success fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether that is operationally sound for you to offer or not, I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sell-more-talk-less&quot;&gt;Sell more; talk less&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d boil those bullet points down relentlessly. Consider this copy instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We manage your listing on Cirtu and other portals [like Craigslist, presumably? If so, name them.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We screen communications; you get everything sorted in one place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You talk to only those prospects you want to talk to; you pick your roommate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;$400&lt;/del&gt; $250 (limited time offer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cirtru guarantee&lt;/strong&gt;: We’re very good at what we do. We’ll refund 50% of the purchase price if we can’t find you a roommate in 15 days or 75% if we can’t find you a roommate in 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cointracker-case-study&quot;&gt;Cointracker case study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumers are notoriously price sensitive, but sometimes software is sold to individuals who, by construction, probably have a lot of money. Cointracker is a great example; it assists cryptocurrency &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HODL&quot;&gt;hodlers&lt;/a&gt; with tax compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their original pricing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/cointracker.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/cointracker.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cointracker pricing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-the-aesthetics-of-pricing-correct-matters-in-b2c&quot;&gt;Getting the aesthetics of pricing correct matters in B2C&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$X.99 pricing is not generally used in B2B or prosumer (professional consumers) services because it communicates cheapness; I’d suggest you drop the 0.99 accordingly here, for aesthetic reasons. (No series of A/B tests I’ve ever done generated as many strong opinions as whether it was better to price a product at $49, $49.99, or $50. Despite bikeshedding this to death at several clients, I’ve yet to see it really matter, so aesthetics win the day. If your data says differently, trust the data.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lite / Standard / Premium are weak names for SaaS plans because they don’t help a user make an instant decision on which plan is right for them. I’d consider Hobbyist / Active Trader / Financial Professional. After last year, cryptocurrency enthusiasts certainly shouldn’t be hurting for money to pay for tax data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d generally advise against having Unlimited anything available for $999. If a hedge fund comes to you and says “Oh, awesome, I want to adopt this for my funds’ tax reporting”, clearly $999 is the wrong price for that user. Don’t anchor the custom services which they almost certainly need to $999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;charge-more-generally&quot;&gt;Charge more, generally&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charge more! Your offering presently labeled Premium has the value proposition “You could spend $5k talking to a non-specialist accountant who would give you the wrong answer here, resulting in you paying tens of thousands of dollars extra taxes and then get audited anyway because his work product would look obviously fishy. Or you can use our services, get the right answer, and have clearly high-quality work product.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d probably increase your pricing to $99 / $499 / $2,499. This intentionally prices out &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=patio11%20%22pathological%20customers%22&amp;amp;type=comment&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;prefix=false&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;sort=byDate&quot;&gt;pathological customers&lt;/a&gt; on the lower end, who will be exceedingly difficult to deal with. It is my impression that this market is rife with them and that they will require a lot of handholding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a person didn’t make tens of thousands of dollars while doing 1,000 transactions in 2017 in cryptocurrencies then, bluntly, there is something wrong with that person’s ability to make good decisions, and you should probably not seek their custom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;charge-more-for-priority-customer-service&quot;&gt;Charge more for priority customer service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does “Dedicated” customer service mean? Does that imply that the lower plans don’t have CS available? That’s probably not the optimal way to phrase it; I might phrase it as “Priority” customer service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an easy thing for any SaaS company to operationalize, by the way—all you need is a special email address that e.g. adds a label in your ticketing tool or gmail inbox, and then you read that label first every day while you’re answering email. That is all priority has to mean!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the easiest ways available to get price-insensitive customers to self-select as price-insensitive. Many SaaS entrepreneurs are emotionally discomfit by optimizations like this. You shouldn’t be, if you have confidence that your product works as described; a well-off person telling you “I am willing to pay extra for the white glove service” is not only doing that with regards to &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; firm. They are reaching back across their history of working with other firms and declining to use the cheapest available service because their experiences with commodity services have not been wonderful. Telling them that you have a premium service available gives them permission to adopt your service, which is in your mutual interest, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; helps you subsidize the availability of your service to more price-sensitive customers on your other plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(If you’ve followed the cryptocurrency space in the last year, you probably understand why many investors might have the reasonable fear that your baseline expectation for customer service is “Feel free to send an email to /dev/null.” Making it clear that you answer your emails is a differentiating feature in this space.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SaaS industry often describes sales of very horizontal applications as “selling to SMBs”, even though small-to-medium-sized businesses have a more official definition at various governmental agencies than “Well it’s not an individual person and not Boeing so it must be an SMB.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs new to SaaS often assume that most SaaS is sold to undifferentiated SMBs. This is probably not accurate; while there are many examples of software products which are very horizontal (sold across a variety of industries, customer archetypes, and sizes of target firm), much SaaS is actually very targeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes advice for SMB pricing a bit harder to give in the abstract, and as you’ll see, a lot of the opportunity is using pricing/packaging to assist your efforts in honing in on a concrete understanding of a target customer and delighting them, as opposed to being mediocre for a larger audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;formapi-case-study&quot;&gt;FormAPI case study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FormAPI makes it easy for programmers to generate PDFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their original pricing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/formAPI.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/formAPI.png&quot; alt=&quot;FormAPI pricing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pricing-a-saas-for-technical-users&quot;&gt;Pricing a SaaS for technical users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should I remove the credit card form on the sign up page? I’ve found that most people who sign up continue paying for the service. If I offer a free trial that doesn’t require a credit card, does that usually result in a higher number of conversions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An excellent question! Net on net, removing the CC required upfront decreases conversions in the early life of a startup, until you’re sophisticated with regards to onboarding, in-app messaging, lifecycle email, and direct reachout by a customer success team. I would not suggest you remove the CC required from this free trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many plans should a SaaS have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should expose few decisions to your users at signup. Attempting to forecast their use in advance is challenging for many users, so you should have less gradations between usage and give plans names which help users bucket themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I count 8 plans. I would recommend you condense to 3 plus “call us for enterprise pricing” presented on the page. If you do have users which appear in all of these buckets, present 3 plans but keep the other ones in reserve; you can hide their existence on the pricing page until a link is clicked on, run a window over the plans (showing only a subset at any given time), etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick hack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(e.g. an internal application or pilot)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50 PDFs per month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$49 / mo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(e.g. invoice generation for an e-commerce application)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,000 PDFs per month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$99 / mo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deployed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(e.g. line of business application)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5,000 PDFs per month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$249 / mo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;We'd love to talk about your use case. Call us and speak directly with a founding engineer.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;your-pricing-page-should-continue-the-sales-message&quot;&gt;Your pricing page should continue the sales message&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From starter plans to on-site and enterprise solutions — Choose the plan that’s best for you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing here promises value to the user; it’s all about mechanics which only you care about. Instead, you should reiterate what FormAPI does and why the plan they pick will be right for them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save weeks of development work on PDF generation; fits easily in the budget for any project.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;moving-upmarket-towards-the-enterprise&quot;&gt;Moving upmarket towards the enterprise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve indicated a desire to attempt to sell this in a high-touch fashion, and that is a natural evolution for many SaaS apps which start targeting developers but find themselves adopted by materially sized businesses. Your goal for the first 10 times you attempt to sell this to a large customer is not to get the price correct, it is to thoroughly understand what your users want out of this software and what it is worth to them. Charge based on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing nothing about a particular enterprise user, I would assume that for most of them this simply saves them 2~4 weeks of dev time at a fully-loaded cost of $25k a month plus maintenance, and accordingly I would probably start offering them two options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;$10k a year for our SaaS offering, which we either host for you or let you use on-premises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$25k one-time license + $5k a year maintenance commitment for the source code; you host it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would probe a lot with regards to what their expectations were regarding support SLAs; anything better than what you’d offer a $500 a month account gets a line item added to the invoice and that line item should cost $10k.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should certainly walk up your prices if you discover that FormAPI is key to the processes of materially-sized businesses. If an insurance company builds their entire business around shipping forms betwee them, suppliers, and regulators, and they are on FormAPI, then that is a six figure deal, minimally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;humble-dot-case-study&quot;&gt;Humble Dot case study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humble Dot is a broad B2B app which helps teams keep informed about what other team members are working on. Their existing pricing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/humbledot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/humbledot.png&quot; alt=&quot;HumbleDot pricing: $50 per month&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time for me to deploy &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=patio11%20%22charge%20more%22&amp;amp;type=comment&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;sort=byDate&quot;&gt;my catchphrase&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Charge more!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$50 per month is not an appropriate maximum price for this product, because it will be instituted at materially-sized businesses to manage teams of professionals, and no initiative worth the repeated effort of professionals caps out near $50 per month. The best customers of Humble Dot would spend more on coffee discussing buying it than they would on actually buying it; that seems like a poor allocation of value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pricing-pages-should-continue-the-sales-message&quot;&gt;Pricing pages should continue the sales message&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humble Dot’s pricing page leads with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparent and Flat Pricing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would strongly encourage you to have the title of your pricing page act like a sales representative. You have a mental of the mind for someone who has arrived at this page, right? What is your one-thought encapsulation of why they would buy Humble Dot? It can’t be simply that you’re offering Transparent and Flat Pricing, because I can offer you Transparent and Flat Pricing for a tuba, and you are not particularly enthusiastic about buying a tuba today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would encourage you to try a headline like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We cost a lot less than not knowing what happened this week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, your sub-header is giving me a response to a pricing objection. Do you know I have a pricing objection? I am probably on the pricing page because I have a pricing question, not an objection. Additionally, that is a very niche objection: if my company grows to the point where it has 100 people using Humble Dot, that doesn’t make it 50x as expensive to me as when there were 2 people using Humble Dot, it makes it 2,500x more valuable because the communication overhead of pairwise status updates increases at approximately O(n^2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-sell-unlimited-anything&quot;&gt;Don’t sell unlimited anything&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of the largest customer that you can conceive of using HumbleDot. How does the anchor of “Everything we offer costs $50/month, flat” impact your pricing discussion with that customer? It decimates your ability to charge appropriate amounts for the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of a relatively small business division missing its targets this quarter is hundreds of thousands or millions of dollars. That is the number you want to anchor enterprise sales against, not $50. You could pull teeth to get “ten freaking times what you usually charged” or you can step into the reality of B2B sales, where the cheapest service you can conveniently describe— taking out trash so your employees don’t have to—starts at about $800 a month because it isn’t even worth discussing a number below that with a business large enough to afford an office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would probably have the $50 plan flat for companies up to 10 employees, after which point their minimum possible payroll is, what, $30k a month or so? (Assumptions: full-time white collar employees in countries with costs similar to the US.) After that, $5 or $10 per employee sounds totally reasonable. You will likely “cost” your best customers more than that in staff time just filling out the updates—and, again, imagine how valuable those updates are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;firma-case-study&quot;&gt;FirmA case study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FirmA, whose name we’ve obscured at their request, automates financial performance analysis for businesses. They sell directly to end-users and through accountants as a sales channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/firm-a.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/firm-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;FirmA pricing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;minimize-distinct-products-sharing-a-single-pricing-page&quot;&gt;Minimize distinct products sharing a single pricing page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would probably pitch your product for end-users and your product for accountants separately, on two separate pricing pages. You can link each page to each other in case someone ends up in the wrong place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would free up both mental bandwidth and visual real estate for having multiple pricing plans, which you should almost certainly have. This product creates 1000X+ as much value at a $10 million a month company as at a $10k a month company, right? Why would you charge them the same amount?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;directly-price-discriminating-by-customer-success&quot;&gt;Directly price discriminating by customer success&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d probably make the axis to differentiate plans from each other revenue tiers: up to $500k yearly, $5 million yearly, $50 million yearly, Hey I Just Met You And This Is Crazy But Your CFO Has Budget So Call Me Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think you’re likely targeting ACVs of ~$500 (your current pricing), $5k, and $20k+ given those rough tiers, and that you’ll likely have to increase your level of sophistication on sales and service delivery to get into the higher tiers, but positioning yourself as capable of servicing them makes the entry offering more credible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-channel-strategies&quot;&gt;Using channel strategies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the idea of selling through accountants as a &lt;strong&gt;channel strategy&lt;/strong&gt;. (This is when a SaaS company sells to a party with a relationship with a pool of customers in return for that party selling their product through those relationships. Typically, this results in the channel taking a cut of the price the end-user pays.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do not explicitly make the case for it here, which is that it allows accountants to benefit from the upside of selling a high-margin software product in addition to their lower-margin services work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a note for folks who haven’t worked in a consultancy before: you can model the margins in an accountancy at about 30% given that the accountancy has to pay salaries and expenses related to the employee accountants who do most of the work. When the accountancy adds a line item to their invoice for access to your software, that line item has ~80% margins. This is pretty attractive as an upsell for them, and for SMB-focused accountants, which do a supermajority of their billable hours for the year in tax season, it gives them both things to bill for in Q2 through Q4 and also an ongoing reason to be in touch with their clients. Services businesses generally benefit from improvements in their offerings which increase the cadence at which they are in front of their clients. It leads to happier clients, more opportunities for follow-on work, and more opportunities to collect referrals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this example demonstrates, it is helpful to &lt;em&gt;thoroughly&lt;/em&gt; understand the business of one’s customers and/or channel partners. Understanding allows you to make relatively small changes to your offering which create outsized value for them. Often the changes are, by the standards of a software company which can quickly write code, almost trivial to deliver; for example, co-branded or white-labeled PDF reports would likely be very compelling for accountancies using your software to give their customers the impression of bespoke, authoritative guidance without costing professional time on high-quality one-off visual design. That feature is relatively easy for a software team to deliver but has impressive “wow factor” both for the channel partner and the end-user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;vempathy-case-study&quot;&gt;Vempathy case study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vempathy helps use AI to analyze user interviews and usability tests for their emotional content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their existing pricing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/vempathy.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/vempathy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Vempathy pricing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minor comment: nobody can “Choose plan” on Enterprise/Agency. I prefer the call-to-action “Call us” or “Speak with us”, in both cases directing someone to a contact form. You should not offer a 14 day free trial of your enterprise offering; you can build the demo into the sales process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I recommend that instead of the Free plan getting a column that you immediately demote it to text under the columns with similar visual weight to “No risk, 30 day money back guarantee” gets?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the copy &lt;em&gt;We also have a free plan which does not offer analysis&lt;/em&gt; and hyperlinking “free plan.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it clear from the pricing page what we charge customers for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read pricing pages for a living, which is not the case of most users of pricing pages. That said, the plan names are reasonably good and descriptive, so I think I’d be able to bucket my business accordingly based on them. (I might still tweak them, but they’re a lot better than Bronze / Silver / Gold, which would make me have to actually read what was included.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d encourage you to make the pricing page less about the transactional details and more about winning the sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-call-the-pricing-page-the-pricing-page-on-the-pricing-page&quot;&gt;Don’t call the pricing page the pricing page on the pricing page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plans &amp;amp; Pricing is a good title tag for SEO purposes, though I would generally put the product name in it as well. Plans &amp;amp; Pricing is a &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt; headline; it chews lots of visual weight and customer brainsweat without paying its rent in improved conversions. The UX designer you’re selling to &lt;em&gt;knows&lt;/em&gt; they’re on the pricing page; they just clicked a link or Googled with the specific intention of opening exactly this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A perhaps better headline, in a style which I’ve used to effect in my own software companies, is: &lt;strong&gt;“Pays for itself with a single [CONCISELY ARTICULATE YOUR VALUE].”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Pays for itself with the time you’ll save analyzing one UX experiment”, for example. You might have wording that people connect to better than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the barrier to trial low enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything I’d be looking to raise the barrier! How would you communicate that this is the very valuable AI-assisted emotional analysis software used by the most sophisticated UX designers and researchers? I would demote the risk reducers to their proper status as minor details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think the pricing tiers make sense with regards to limitations and price points?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two unlimiteds is at least one unlimited too many; I think you could probably eliminate “Unlimited Collaborators” without affecting the vast majority of customers. You can clarify it later on the page for people who are worried they have to pay per seat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charging based on AI-analyzed recordings as the primary axis makes sense. I think that is likely so much more valuable than having multiple teams/projects that I’d consider hiding the number of teams/projects from this table and only exposing that limitation in the software. See if anyone hits it. (If they complain that it wasn’t disclosed before purchase, upgrade them for free. I anticipate nobody will care, which means it doesn’t need to be on this page.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should we include an exhaustive features list?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will it cause someone to choose to buy the software? Probably not. Instead, continue the sales message: how specifically does this reduce the amount of human work to pull stunning insights from user recordings? Put that on the page; supplement with details about features where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is generally easier to sell into SMB verticals (a particularly industry or customer archetype) than across all SMBs, because it is easier to laser-focus on their specific needs, understand the factors which impact their business, and speak the language of your users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;kitchenwhiz-case-study&quot;&gt;KitchenWhiz case study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KitchenWhiz creates kitchen plans for homeowners and professionals like carpenters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their existing pricing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/kitchenwhiz.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/kitchenwhiz.png&quot; alt=&quot;KitchenWhiz pricing: $9.95 per month or $60 per year&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;saas-entrepreneurs-overestimate-the-benefit-of-low-prices-early&quot;&gt;SaaS entrepreneurs overestimate the benefit of low prices early&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many SaaS entrepreneurs describe their products as less mature than the incumbents and therefore they price far under the incumbents. This is almost always a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your customers are not buying KitchenWhiz because it is bad but attractively priced. They are buying it because your value proposition is “It produces beautifully designed professionally-produced kitchen plans easily.” Your customer is likely in the trades and this is a revenue-producing tool in their business. I would encourage you to ask them what a single remodeling job typically costs; I suspect that they quite literally discard more materials as waste than they spend on KitchenWhiz at any of your contemplated price points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You already are a revenue-producing tool for your customers, and you’re going to quickly iterate on this product and make it even better than it is now. You should price a bit ahead of where you think your maturity is; this lets you “grow into” the new price as your customers discover and onboard with you, and prevents you from having to go back to them and ask them for more money in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would probably sell 3 packages of KitchenWhiz, with arbitrary contents in them that I leave to your best judgment. These price points are my default price points for a B2B SaaS sold on the low-touch model; they work across a range of firms and industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly&lt;/strong&gt;: $49 / $99 / $249&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annually&lt;/strong&gt;: Same as above, but with one month “free.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you sell literally none of the $249 a month version then you can do away with it if you feel that is useful, but I think the market may surprise you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this proposed pricing is 10X to 50X the &lt;em&gt;maximum&lt;/em&gt; pricing contemplated by the existing pricing. This demonstrates the power of doubling down on the B2B market when you have a product which could theoretically be used by a consumer or a business. AppAmaGooBookSoft are doing their best to convince customers worldwide that software should be free (or as close at makes no difference) and subsidized by extremely lucrative advertising/hardware/e-commerce/etc ecosystems attached to it. That is a hard market expectation to go against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to price SaaS sustainably, you probably want to target primarily business users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;generous-refund-policies-are-to-your-advantage&quot;&gt;Generous refund policies are to your advantage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would generally encourage software sold on the low-touch model to offer refunds to customers who are dissatisfied. Refunds do cause a short-term cashflow hit, but dissatisfied customers are a much bigger threat to your business than that cashflow hit, because dissatisfaction that you don’t know about causes churn that is hard to control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should eagerly encourage customers who are very unhappy about your services to tell you why and with specificity; consider the refund a small consulting fee you’re giving them if it helps you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, customers who are dissatisfied with a SaaS company’s services can always escalate the decision to not refund to their bank. The bank will often take their customer’s side over yours, since you are not their customer. It will be difficult for you to prevail in a dispute along the lines of “They promised me the software would do X / Y / Z but it didn’t so I asked for my money back and they said no.” Answering that dispute is a poorer use of your time than talking to customers or building software, and you likely wouldn’t win it even if you were entirely accurate in describing the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-demo-or-not-to-demo&quot;&gt;To demo or not to demo?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re trying to strike a balance between conversion rates and learning with the decision to offer free trials or not. I would maximize for learning right now: offer a call to literally everyone who starts using the software. Use it 80% for learning about their business and 20% for showing them the important parts of your software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should use these calls for customer development and for sales, not training—if they have questions, note them for later and produce screencasts or similar that you can show to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would probably use the fact of the call and concierge onboarding to tell everyone that of course you charge for your services, just like they charge for their services, but that as a limited time offer you’ll retroactively waive one month of fees if they can commit to a 15 minute conversation about why the software didn’t work for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is effectively a demo but puts the onus on the user to organize themselves to actually use the software or feel embarrassed, as opposed to the typical free trial, which is just “Try it, or don’t, either way really.” Committing to putting a software product through its paces is &lt;strong&gt;real work&lt;/strong&gt; which software people, as inveterate early adopters, often underestimate. You’re asking a busy professional to change the way they do business with respect to an actual project with an actual customer who has an actual kitchen on the line. If you do not project manage them in the adoption of your software and process, you can reasonably expect for them to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; make effective use of your trial during the time limit, mooting any benefit of it being available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;em&gt;very common&lt;/em&gt; failure case for free software trials; they carry a cost which, despite not being charged to a credit card, is much more material than software people give it credit for. We like them too much and we should be more considered about whether offering them is in the interests of our businesses or our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;publica-case-study&quot;&gt;Publica case study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publica helps authors sell digital publications online. Their current pricing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/publica.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/publica.png&quot; alt=&quot;Publica pricing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;name-pricing-plans-to-sell-them-to-the-right-users&quot;&gt;Name pricing plans to sell them to the right users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only purpose of the name of a plan, as communicated on the pricing page, is to provide the right customer the right nudge to choose that particular plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think of the sophistication spectrum among authors who publish their work online for money, I don’t think “Initial” likely helps any to make the correct decision; I would call that plan Hobbyist, both because it helps people who have yet to sell their first book select into that plan and it helps professional authors, who are quite vocal about that being their primary career identity, select out of the cheapest plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Author” is a better name but perhaps not wonderful. How would you feel about Professional, Professional Author, or Midlist Author? (Midlist is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Midlist&quot;&gt;term of art&lt;/a&gt; in traditional publishing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flagging a plan as recommended often increases the number of people who select it, but I would probably not name the plan “Recommended.” I might describe it as an Imprint (if I suspect my customers are either traditionally published authors or emotionally affiliated with the same) or something suggesting a small business (Cottage Publisher, perhaps?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now we’re giving a 14 day free trial period to any lead but we still ask for the customer credit card to start the free trial. Should we remove that requirement? I’m afraid that by doing that we might get more trials but have them be less qualified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are almost certainly correct: most B2B SaaS companies find that removing the credit card requirement increases the number of free trial signups they get but decreases the activation rate (the number of users who make material use of the software) and conversion rate to paying use. It is generally not worth it early in the lifecycle of your company. (Your business needs to be capable operationally of doing fairly sophisticated work to nurture customers to activation and then convince them to part with their credit card details later in the trials for it to win net here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plans have a lot of features, should we put them all on the pricing columns or only the ones that matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should only include the most salient details on your pricing page. If there is a difference between plans which is not salient to your customers or to you, it should not be a difference between plans; it creates engineering work for you and frustration for your customers without doing the one thing that feature differentials is supposed to do, which is convince people to pay more for the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we need to offer different features on each plan or only different amounts of the maximum usage? i.e: Right now we charge a monthly or annual fee based on the number of users and publications each account has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, the purpose of charging different amounts for software is that different users get different amounts of value from the software, and that you want to capture some portion of the differential value created between your least successful user and your most successful user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All decisions about the pricing page are optimizations to approximate the value creation curve and charge for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of users / number of publications is an approximation for value created. Use of more sophisticated features might be another way to approximate. Is there another approximation available?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would suggest that the best approximation for value created by a publishing platform is probably the amount of money it enables your customers to earn, and therefore I would probably charge based on count or total sum of transactions facilitated. George RR Martin should pay more than a hobbyist recipe book author, even if they have the same number of titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Relatedly: I think your tiers are far, far too generous, if I understand them correctly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have different customers with different needs. Is it OK to have different pricing models for each? For example, for publishers we charge based on how many publications and users they have. Universities have many, many more publications by nature of how they operate; we only want to charge them based on the number of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely yes! This is not done much by smaller SaaS businesses, because of the operational complexity and the degree to which it requires you to understand and operate in different market segments, but it is entirely possible for you to have “special academic pricing”, “the University edition”, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do not need a differentiated feature set to justify this; it can be entirely a marketing decision. The fundamental insight is that universities have incentives very different than for-profit publishers and that, since their incentives are different, treating them as if they were equivalent is not wonderful for either group. They also likely respond to different marketing messages, will have different feature needs in the future, and have a different value proposition in mind for working with you. Packaging the software differently to them helps you to discover and address these differences in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;firmb-case-study&quot;&gt;FirmB case study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FirmB, whose name we have obscured at their request, sells a Shopify plugin which assists e-commerce businesses in optimizing their conversion rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their original pricing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/firm-b.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/firm-b.png&quot; alt=&quot;Firm B pricing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d also name the plans a bit differently: Small Store vs. Sophisticated E-Commerce Retailer vs. Enterprise, maybe. Who can resist saying that they’re the sophisticated one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;anchor-your-prices-to-the-cost-of-experts&quot;&gt;Anchor your prices to the cost of experts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Businesses buy benefits, not features, so “Unlock advanced features” is unlikely to convince someone to upgrade from Essential to Business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might position that as: &lt;strong&gt;Like having your own automated CRO agency, at a fraction of the cost.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know what e-commerce companies pay for conversion rate optimization specialists? I have some knowledge of what the typical rate cards are like in that industry. When I did CRO for software companies I charged $30k a week. That is probably above the price point for most firms which are hosted on Shopify but they certainly aren’t paying only hundreds of dollars per engagement. Accordingly, I would walk up the price of the Business offering and explicitly compare it in your sales material to hiring a CRO agency (minimum buy-in: $5k per month) or adding a CRO specialist to the team ($100k or more a year even for relatively unproven junior employees, when you evaluate the total cost of employment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, new business owners don’t model the true cost of employees’ time correctly. Assume the total cost of a white collar employee is about 140% of their quoted salary; that’s a good enough approximation to price SaaS against their true fully-loaded cost rather than their salary. Businesses have to budget for fully-loaded costs, inclusive of taxes, benefits, required contributions to social insurance schemes, and overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to your advantage, when anchoring against the price of employees, to anchor off their &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; fully-loaded costs rather than their &lt;em&gt;imaginary&lt;/em&gt; nominal costs (the salary number).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pricing-bundles-effectively&quot;&gt;Pricing bundles effectively&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that you effectively have an offering which bundles multiple discrete offerings which are popular on Shopify, correct? I would consider pricing your Essential plan up to $49 and then offering a less prominent (not a column, just a textual option below the main pricing grid) Getting Started plan at $29, which would allow only one widget (at any time). This lets price-conscious firms dip their toes into the water without cutting off the revenue from the substantial fraction of e-commerce shops which are actually legitimate businesses which pay for healthcare and everything. The difference between $29 and $49 is immaterial to them but certainly isn’t to you, once you’ve signed hundreds of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d price $199 to $249 immediately (since they’re perceived as the same amount by users); I’d probably price it higher than that, too, after you have dialed in the value provided via, for example, concierge onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;concierge-onboarding&quot;&gt;Concierge onboarding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want a great way to increase your conversion rate to mid-tier plans like the one you described as Business? Offer free consulting services which are bundled in with the offering and focused on getting someone onboarded successfully; this is often called “concierge onboarding.” If you’re worried about the amount of time required, you can restrict them to companies which elect the annual plan. (You should have an annual plan.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concierge onboarding makes your users more likely to successfully convert and more successful (so they are less likely to churn). In addition, early in the business it adds wonderful opportunities to talk with your customers and make sure you’re building the right features, training material, and workflows to meet their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also gives people who are less price sensitive a reason to hang their hat on your higher-tier offerings. What if I am making $500k a month of high-margin sales but simply am not sophisticated enough to know what multivariate testing is? Concierge onboarding helps me get into a detailed conversation with you, where you provide outstanding value by getting the plugin set up to start increasing my sales automatically, and the opportunity for you to sell me on the value of multivariate testing. Win/win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophisticated businesses have, generally, greater ability to pay for SaaS because the right SaaS creates more value in their businesses. This is orthogonal to its complexity, degree of “secret sauce”, or what it actually does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, SaaS companies which sell directly into sophisticated businesses by construction should price at a premium to companies which are selling to the broader B2B market. Companies which sell across a variety of verticals should, where possible, segment out sophisticated businesses and package the offering so it delivers them premium services at the (substantial) price points they are used to paying for valuable services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;geomodelr-case-study&quot;&gt;Geomodelr case study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geomodelr sells into the oil &amp;amp; gas industry. Their existing pricing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/geomodelr.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/atlas/guides/saas-pricing/geomodelr.png&quot; alt=&quot;Geomodelr pricing grid; Monthly Professional $199; Yearly Professional $149.92 per month&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-is-not-a-compelling-value-proposition-to-well-monied-buyers&quot;&gt;Free is not a compelling value proposition to well-monied buyers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, companies have offered software for free or nearly free to benefit from the software spreading as wide as possible. This is of sharply limited utility in selling B2B services, because price is often a proxy for value, particularly among savvy customers who are in industries which are (to pardon a pun) gushing with money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does “free” communicate to an oil company that the data / analysis / etc produced by your report is reliable enough to place a $X00k capital investment or a $Y million mineral rights lease? Does free comport with the values of decisionmakers in mining companies? Do they expect to get accounting or legal or insurance free?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would discontinue the free version immediately. Send a mail to existing free users saying that you’ve discontinued the offering and that you will honor their pricing for forever and, as a special reward for their loyalty in the early days of your company, you will give them a 20% discount to the paid version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going forward, while you can make tactical use of a limited free trial, you should probably not provide commercializable services for free again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-present-yearly-pricing&quot;&gt;How to present yearly pricing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the traditional SaaS pricing grid, there is a huge distinction between columns. Choosing between columns requires a Consequential Decision by your customer. You should minimize consequential decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monthly versus annual billing shouldn’t be a consequential decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of your customers should not have strong cash-flow considerations dominating their software budget, because they’re highly-compensated professionals in a capital intensive industry which is happy to pay for engineering services. I would have the core offering be the yearly plan and have a toggle box to select monthly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;have-multiple-packages&quot;&gt;Have multiple packages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve gotten rid of your free plan and consolidated the decision about billing cycle, so your company has essentially one package which it is selling now. There should probably be more than one packages available, to offer an appropriate incentive for companies which receive a lot of value to tell you “Actually, I receive a heck of a lot of value from this” and, simultaneously, convince them to pay more than companies which are more marginal to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d probably adjust your price points to $2.5k annual / $250 monthly for the core package (the first of many moves upward) and then test another price point at $10k annual (with either no monthly option or a $1k per month but billed quarterly option, to minimize how many checks you have to chase).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What goes in the more expensive offering? I don’t know. I’d start by putting priority support in that and then see what customers asked for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;consider-moving-up-market-to-the-enterprise&quot;&gt;Consider moving up-market to the enterprise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d also probably add an Enterprise offering where people have to call you for pricing. On your first dozen calls, you should just try to understand what they need out of the Enterprise offering and whether you can provide it. (If you are not comfortable doing that, call your existing paying customers, ask if they pay more than $50k a year for any software, and if so ask what they would need from you to justify paying more than that ballpark for you.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas?ref=saas_pricing#join&quot;&gt;incorporate with Stripe Atlas&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll receive opportunities to get feedback on parts of your businesses from experienced entrepreneurs, investors, and subject-matter experts, similar to the Q&amp;amp;A which this article is excerpted from or our &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/ama-marc-andreessen&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A with Marc Andreessen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re running a company or just thinking about it, we’d love to hear of what challenges we could help you solve. Drop us a line at atlas@stripe.com if there is a subject you’d like to see us cover in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;collect-email-guide&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;mask-container container-lg&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;collect-email-partial&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intro-copy column&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;form class=&quot;collect-form&quot; action=&quot;https://stripemail.createsend.com/t/d/s/qhkkid/&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;email-field&quot; required=&quot;required&quot; type=&quot;email&quot; name=&quot;cm-qhkkid-qhkkid&quot; spellcheck=&quot;false&quot; placeholder=&quot;Email&quot;/&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;submit-button&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot;&gt;Get updates&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;collect-error email&quot;&gt;Please enter your email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;collect-error connection&quot;&gt;You might have had an internet hiccup. Try again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;collect-success column&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;icon&quot; src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/v3/common/success.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Green checkmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;common-BodyTitle&quot;&gt;Thank you!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;common-BodyText&quot;&gt;We sent an email to &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;common-BodyText&quot;&gt;Check your inbox to confirm your email address and we’ll let you know when we publish our next guide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides&quot; class=&quot;common-Link common-Link--arrowL&quot;&gt;Return to guides&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 18:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>davidw</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stripe Atlas: Software as a Service pricing</og:title>
<og:url>https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/saas-pricing</og:url>
<og:description>Stripe Atlas’ guide to pricing and packaging for low-touch SaaS businesses</og:description>
<og:image>https://stripe.com/img/v3/atlas/guide/social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/saas-pricing</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vulkan is coming to macOS and iOS, but no thanks to Apple</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/02/vulkan-is-coming-to-macos-ios-but-no-thanks-to-apple/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/02/vulkan-is-coming-to-macos-ios-but-no-thanks-to-apple/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/vulkan-640x184.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;No, not that &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/02/vulkan-is-coming-to-macos-ios-but-no-thanks-to-apple/%22%22%22%22%22%22//cms.arstechnica.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Spock_wearing_neural_stimulator_2.jpg%22%22%22%22%22%22%22&quot;&gt;Vulcan&lt;/a&gt; (note, that's spelled with a &quot;c&quot;). This one.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;89 posters participating, including story author.&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/02/vulkan-is-coming-to-macos-ios-but-no-thanks-to-apple/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;253&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vulkan—&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2015/03/khronos-unveils-vulkan-opengl-built-for-modern-systems/&quot;&gt;the open, cross-platform GPU API&lt;/a&gt; from the Khronos Group, the industry body that also develops OpenGL—is available on Windows, Linux, Android, the Nintendo Switch, and cloud systems, but it has one sizeable gap: none of Apple's platforms support it. macOS has old, and slow, OpenGL drivers, and iOS supports OpenGL ES, the OpenGL subset designed for embedded systems. Apple has thus far shown no interest in offering the modern Vulkan API and instead has pushed &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/07/the-state-of-mac-gaming/&quot;&gt;its own proprietary API, Metal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, that gap is being substantially filled, with the open source, royalty-free release of MoltenVK—a runtime for macOS and iOS that offers an almost complete subset of the Vulkan API implemented using Metal. Released under the Apache 2 license, MoltenVK will enable developers to build their Vulkan applications for Apple's platforms, allowing for a single codebase to span Windows, Linux, Android, macOS, iOS, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/vulkan-on-macos.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot; data-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Dota 2&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; using Vulkan-on-Metal, compared to &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Dota 2&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; on Apple's OpenGL drivers.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/vulkan-on-macos-640x360.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/vulkan-on-macos-1280x720.png 2x&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Dota 2&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; using Vulkan-on-Metal, compared to &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Dota 2&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; on Apple's OpenGL drivers.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/vulkan-on-macos.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;Dota 2&lt;/em&gt; using Vulkan-on-Metal, compared to &lt;em&gt;Dota 2&lt;/em&gt; on Apple's OpenGL drivers.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Khronos Group&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valve is an early adopter of MoltenVK. The company has been testing MoltenVK for the macOS version of &lt;em&gt;Dota 2&lt;/em&gt;, and indications are extremely promising: the Vulkan-on-Metal version of the game has frame rates as much as 50 percent higher than the version using Apple's OpenGL stack. Apple's OpenGL drivers have long been criticized, both for their poor performance and for Apple's refusal to support the latest versions of the specification. The &lt;em&gt;Dota 2&lt;/em&gt; experience suggests that developers can reap big dividends by bypassing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The release is in response to demands from developers; they want a cross-platform API to maximize their reach but also need to be able to reach Apple's platforms. However, developers also told Khronos that they didn't want a &lt;em&gt;fourth&lt;/em&gt; API to learn; rather, they hoped the company could repurpose some existing API to give them this reach. The identification of a universally portable subset of Vulkan, one that can be efficiently run on top of other GPU APIs, is the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MoltenVK has been designed as a very thin layer. It has been deliberately designed to not perform any significant remapping or conversion of data and function calls, ensuring that its performance is predictable and consistent, and its overheads are low. A handful of Vulkan features aren't available, but overall the portable subset is substantial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The portable subset will also soon be able to target another platform: DirectX 12. Expected within the next few months, a similar translation layer is being developed that will enable Vulkan applications to use a DirectX 12 back-end. While Windows, unlike macOS, does have Vulkan drivers from GPU companies, applications sold through the Microsoft Store are only permitted to use DirectX. Already today, some Store applications use ANGLE—an implementation of OpenGL ES that runs on top of DirectX—so that their developers can use a cross-platform graphics API. The Vulkan layer will enable the same for software that uses the high performance, low-level GPU API.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 17:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ekianjo</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/02/vulkan-is-coming-to-macos-ios-but-no-thanks-to-apple/</og:url>
<og:title>Vulkan is coming to macOS and iOS, but no thanks to Apple</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/vulkan-640x215.png</og:image>
<og:description>Early signs are that performance is much better than Apple's awful OpenGL stack.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/02/vulkan-is-coming-to-macos-ios-but-no-thanks-to-apple/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook turned on face recognition silently</title>
<link>https://imgur.com/a/tK8eW</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://imgur.com/a/tK8eW</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Open+Sans:300,300i,400,400i,600,600i,700,700i,800,800i&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;                        
        
    

    Facebook Turned ON facial recognition silently. - Album on Imgur&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;content-type&quot; content=&quot;text/html;charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=1138&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;noindex, nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;keywords&quot; content=&quot;images, photos, gif, gifs, memes, pictures, new pictures, reaction gifs, share photos, share images, latest images, funny, cute, visual storytelling, imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Post with 16078 views. Facebook Turned ON facial recognition silently.&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;copyright&quot; content=&quot;Copyright 2018 Imgur, Inc.&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;IE=Edge;&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; href=&quot;//s.imgur.com/images/favicon-32x32.png&quot; sizes=&quot;32x32&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; href=&quot;//s.imgur.com/images/favicon-96x96.png&quot; sizes=&quot;96x96&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; href=&quot;//s.imgur.com/images/favicon-16x16.png&quot; sizes=&quot;16x16&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon-precomposed&quot; href=&quot;//s.imgur.com/images/favicon-152.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;msapplication-TileColor&quot; content=&quot;#2cd63c&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;msapplication-TileImage&quot; content=&quot;//s.imgur.com/images/favicon-144.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;//s.imgur.com/min/global.css?1519772886&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;//s.imgur.com/min/gallery.css?1519772886&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;application/json+oembed&quot; href=&quot;https://api.imgur.com/oembed.json?url=http://imgur.com/a/tK8eW&quot; title=&quot;Facebook Turned ON facial recognition silently. - Album on Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;application/xml+oembed&quot; href=&quot;https://api.imgur.com/oembed.xml?url=http://imgur.com/a/tK8eW&quot; title=&quot;Facebook Turned ON facial recognition silently. - Album on Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;!--[if IE 9]&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;//imgur.com/include/css/ie-sucks.css?0&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;![endif]--&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;https://imgur.com/a/tK8eW&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://imgur.com/a/tK8eW&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; media=&quot;only screen and (max-width: 640px)&quot; href=&quot;https://m.imgur.com/a/tK8eW&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;p:domain_verify&quot; content=&quot;834554521765408b9effdc758b69c5ee&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:admins&quot; content=&quot;12331492&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:admins&quot; content=&quot;12301369&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:app_id&quot; content=&quot;127621437303857&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:android:url&quot; content=&quot;imgur://imgur.com/a/tK8eW?from=fbreferral&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:android:app_name&quot; content=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:android:package&quot; content=&quot;com.imgur.mobile&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:ios:url&quot; content=&quot;imgur://imgur.com/a/tK8eW?from=fbreferral&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:ios:app_store_id&quot; content=&quot;639881495&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:ios:app_name&quot; content=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:web:url&quot; content=&quot;https://imgur.com/a/tK8eW&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:domain&quot; content=&quot;imgur.com&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:id:googleplay&quot; content=&quot;com.imgur.mobile&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;Facebook Turned ON facial recognition silently.&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;Facebook Turned ON facial recognition silently.&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;article:author&quot; content=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;article:publisher&quot; content=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;image_src&quot; href=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WHWtgVk.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;article&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WHWtgVk.jpg?fb&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:width&quot; content=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:height&quot; content=&quot;315&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary_large_image&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image&quot; content=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WHWtgVkh.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;!--[if lte IE 8]&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//s.imgur.com/min/iepoly.js?1519772886&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;![endif]--&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot;&gt;
    
                        
 &lt;!-- #topbar --&gt;


        
    

    

            

        
    

        
    

    
    

    &lt;div id=&quot;inside&quot;&gt;
        

        &lt;div class=&quot;left post-pad&quot;&gt;
            
            &lt;div class=&quot;post-container&quot;&gt;
                

                &lt;div class=&quot;post-images&quot;&gt;

                                    

                                            
                        
                        
                        
                                                    
                        

                        &lt;div id=&quot;WHWtgVk&quot; class=&quot;post-image-container&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
                                                            &lt;div class=&quot;post-image&quot;&gt;
    

                        &lt;a href=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WHWtgVk.png&quot; class=&quot;zoom&quot;&gt;
                                    &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WHWtgVk.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentURL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        
    
&lt;/div&gt;

                            

                            

                                                            &lt;meta itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2018-02-27&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    
                

                

                                    
                

                
                

                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;

            

            
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div id=&quot;right-content&quot; class=&quot;right post-unification&quot;&gt;

            

            

                            

                
            

            

                            
            

                            

            

            &lt;div id=&quot;post-jump-container&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div id=&quot;post-jump&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;div class=&quot;box take-me-up&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;TAKE ME UP&lt;/p&gt;
                        
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        
    

    

    &lt;input id=&quot;sid&quot; type=&quot;hidden&quot; value=&quot;d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e&quot; /&gt;

    

        

    

            
    

    

            &lt;!--[if lte IE 8]&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.11.1/jquery.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
if(typeof jQuery === 'undefined') {
    document.write('&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//s.imgur.com/include/js/ext/jquery-1.10.2.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;' + '/script&gt;');
}
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;![endif]--&gt;&lt;!--[if gt IE 8]&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/2.1.1/jquery.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
if(typeof jQuery === 'undefined') {
    document.write('&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//s.imgur.com/include/js/ext/jquery.2.1.1.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;' + '/script&gt;');
}
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;![endif]--&gt;&lt;!--[if !IE]&gt; --&gt;&lt;!--&lt;![endif]--&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://b.scorecardresearch.com/p?c1=2&amp;amp;c2=7770950&amp;amp;cv=2.0&amp;amp;cj=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
        &lt;!-- Quantcast Tag --&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;!-- End Quantcast tag --&gt;



        &lt;noscript&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
        &lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 16:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>neelkadia</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://imgur.com/a/tK8eW</og:url>
<og:title>Facebook Turned ON facial recognition silently.</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://i.imgur.com/WHWtgVk.jpg?fb</og:image>
<og:description>Imgur</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://imgur.com/a/tK8eW</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Announcing Flutter beta 1: Build beautiful native apps</title>
<link>https://developers.googleblog.com/2018/02/announcing-flutter-beta-1.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://developers.googleblog.com/2018/02/announcing-flutter-beta-1.html</guid>
<description>&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/flutter-io/announcing-flutter-beta-1-build-beautiful-native-apps-dc142aea74c0&quot;&gt;Flutter's Medium by Seth Ladd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, as part of Mobile World Congress 2018, we are excited to announce the first beta release of &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutter.io/?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=beta_announcement&quot;&gt;Flutter&lt;/a&gt;. Flutter is Google's new mobile UI framework that helps developers craft high-quality native interfaces for both iOS and Android. &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutter.io/get-started/?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=beta_get_started&quot;&gt;Get started&lt;/a&gt; today at &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutter.io/?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=beta_announcement&quot;&gt;flutter.io&lt;/a&gt; to build beautiful native apps in record time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fq4N0hgOWzU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flutter targets the sweet spot of mobile development: performance and platform integrations of native mobile, with high-velocity development and multi-platform reach of portable UI toolkits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-5AFWqIO5Uek/WpRdSe_-ApI/AAAAAAAAEj0/m5pVblyfg3AEE3MDNtMn_AILA9cWpwywwCLcBGAs/s1600/flutter%2Bbeta%2Bhero%2Bimage%2Bfor%2Bblog%2Bpost.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;732&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1251&quot; id=&quot;flutterbeta&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-5AFWqIO5Uek/WpRdSe_-ApI/AAAAAAAAEj0/m5pVblyfg3AEE3MDNtMn_AILA9cWpwywwCLcBGAs/s1600/flutter%2Bbeta%2Bhero%2Bimage%2Bfor%2Bblog%2Bpost.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designed for both new and experienced mobile developers, Flutter can help you build beautiful and successful apps in record time with benefits such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-velocity development&lt;/strong&gt; with features like stateful Hot Reload, a new reactive framework, rich widget set, and integrated tooling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expressive and flexible designs&lt;/strong&gt; with composible widget sets, rich animation libraries, and a layered, extensible architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-quality experiences&lt;/strong&gt; across devices and platforms with our portable, GPU-accelerated renderer and high-performance, native ARM code runtime, and platform interop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since our alpha release last year, we delivered, with help from our community, features such as screen reader support and other accessibility features, right-to-left text, localization and internationalization, iPhone X and iOS 11 support, inline video, additional image format support, running Flutter code in the background, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our tools also improved significantly, with support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/9212-flutter&quot;&gt;Android Studio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=Dart-Code.dart-code&quot;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;, new refactorings to help you manage your widget code, platform interop to expose the power of mobile platforms to Flutter code, improved stateful hot reloads, and a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutter.io/inspector/&quot;&gt;widget inspector&lt;/a&gt; to help you browse the widget tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-2ydRYcrPPFQ/WpRd-Jid85I/AAAAAAAAEj8/1xSv08JrXa0i2Fxa03eD7R9I3AOY8O91wCLcBGAs/s1600/image1.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;677&quot; data-original-width=&quot;881&quot; id=&quot;flutterbeta&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-2ydRYcrPPFQ/WpRd-Jid85I/AAAAAAAAEj8/1xSv08JrXa0i2Fxa03eD7R9I3AOY8O91wCLcBGAs/s1600/image1.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the many new features across the framework and tools, teams across Google (such as AdWords) and around the world have been successful with Flutter. Flutter has been used in production apps with millions of installs, apps built with Flutter have been featured in the App Store and Play Store (for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/topics/developers/it-must-be-nice-have-hamilton-your-phone/&quot;&gt;Hamilton: The Musical&lt;/a&gt;), and startups and agencies have been successful with Flutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codemate.com/&quot;&gt;Codemate&lt;/a&gt;, a development agency in Finland, attributes Flutter's high-velocity dev cycle and customizable UI toolkit to their ability to quickly build a beautiful app for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hookle.net/&quot;&gt;Hookle&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;We now confidently recommend Flutter to help our clients perform better and deliver more value to their users across mobile,&quot; said Toni Piirainen, CEO of Codemate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8xwNf3auRKk/WpReQY-f5LI/AAAAAAAAEkA/rJhD0LUUdFQC254b-aMsQMM38krB2cmKQCLcBGAs/s1600/screenshots%2Bfor%2Bflutter%2Bbeta%2Bblog%2Bpost.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;634&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1193&quot; id=&quot;flutterbeta&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8xwNf3auRKk/WpReQY-f5LI/AAAAAAAAEkA/rJhD0LUUdFQC254b-aMsQMM38krB2cmKQCLcBGAs/s1600/screenshots%2Bfor%2Bflutter%2Bbeta%2Bblog%2Bpost.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fluttercaption&quot;&gt;Apps built with Flutter deliver quality, performance, and customized designs across platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flutter's beta also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flutter/flutter/wiki/Trying-the-preview-of-Dart-2-in-Flutter&quot;&gt;works with a pre-release&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@asandholm/announcing-dart-2-80ba01f43b6&quot;&gt;Dart 2&lt;/a&gt;, with improved support for declaring UI in code with minimal language ceremony. For example, Dart 2 infers &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;const&lt;/em&gt; to remove boilerplate when building UI. Here is an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint&quot; id=&quot;flutterprint&quot;&gt;
// Before Dart 2
Widget build(BuildContext context) {
  return new Container(
    height: 56.0,
    padding: const EdgeInsets.symmetric(horizontal: 8.0),
    decoration: new BoxDecoration(color: Colors.blue[500]),
    child: new Row(
      ...
    ),
  );
}

// After Dart 2
Widget build(BuildContext context) =&amp;gt;
  Container(
    height: 56.0,
    padding: EdgeInsets.symmetric(horizontal: 8.0),
    decoration: BoxDecoration(color: Colors.blue[500]),
    child: Row(
      ...
    ),
  );
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fluttercaption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/anders-sandholm/b2153cdf4a541adc40c4dc50b5b6e227&quot;&gt;widget.dart on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're thrilled to see Flutter's ecosystem thriving. There are now over &lt;a href=&quot;https://pub.dartlang.org/flutter&quot;&gt;1000 packages that work with Flutter&lt;/a&gt; (for example: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pub.dartlang.org/packages/sqflite&quot;&gt;SQLite&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flutter/plugins/blob/master/FlutterFire.md&quot;&gt;Firebase&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pub.dartlang.org/packages/flutter_facebook_connect&quot;&gt;Facebook Connect&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pub.dartlang.org/packages/shared_preferences&quot;&gt;shared preferences&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pub.dartlang.org/packages/graphql_client&quot;&gt;GraphQL&lt;/a&gt;, and lots more), over 1700 people in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/flutter/flutter&quot;&gt;chat&lt;/a&gt;, and we're delighted to see our community launch new sites such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutter.institute/&quot;&gt;Flutter Institute&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://startflutter.com/&quot;&gt;Start Flutter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutter.rocks/&quot;&gt;Flutter Rocks&lt;/a&gt;. Plus, you can now subscribe to the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutterweekly.net/&quot;&gt;Flutter Weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt;, edited and published by our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we look forward to our 1.0 release, we are focused on stabilization and scenario completion. Our roadmap, largely influenced by our community, currently tracks features such as making it easier to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flutter/flutter/issues/14821&quot;&gt;embed Flutter into an existing app&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flutter/flutter/issues/730&quot;&gt;inline WebView&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flutter/flutter/labels/prod%3A%20routes&quot;&gt;improved routing and navigation APIs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flutter/flutter/issues?q=is%3Aopen+is%3Aissue+label%3A%22plugin%3A+firebase%22?&quot;&gt;additional Firebase support&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flutter/flutter/issues/73&quot;&gt;inline maps&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flutter/flutter/issues/12456&quot;&gt;smaller core engine&lt;/a&gt;, and more. We expect to release new betas approximately every four weeks, and we highly encourage you to vote (👍) on issues important to you and your app via our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutter.io/issues&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now is the perfect time to try Flutter. You can go from zero to your first running Flutter app quickly with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutter.io/get-started/?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=beta_get_started&quot;&gt;Getting Started guide&lt;/a&gt;. If you already have Flutter installed, you can switch to the beta channel using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flutter/flutter/wiki/Flutter-build-release-channels&quot;&gt;these instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to extend our sincere thanks for your support, feedback, and many contributions. We look forward to continuing this journey with everyone, and we can't wait to see what you build!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hello, developers in China! This post is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.googleblog.cn/2018/02/flutter-beta1.html&quot;&gt;available in Chinese&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/noscript&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 15:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nicpottier</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Announcing Flutter beta 1: Build beautiful native apps</og:title>
<og:image>http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-fWEPzhrhdqk/WKbYSrN1_8I/AAAAAAAATXE/m2-ZgsirkMYKc_YhcehEb0iUdyGtLs8KACK4B/s1600/lockup_google_developers_horizontal_knockout_wht.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://developers.googleblog.com/2018/02/announcing-flutter-beta-1.html</og:url>
<og:description>News and insights on Google platforms, tools, and events.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://developers.googleblog.com/2018/02/announcing-flutter-beta-1.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>After rising for 100 years, electricity demand is flat</title>
<link>https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2018/2/27/17052488/electricity-demand-utilities?utm_campaign=drvox&amp;utm_content=chorus&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2018/2/27/17052488/electricity-demand-utilities?utm_campaign=drvox&amp;utm_content=chorus&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;ZSrlLB&quot;&gt;The US electricity sector is in a period of unprecedented change and turmoil. Renewable energy prices are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2017/8/30/16224582/wind-solar-exceed-expectations-again&quot;&gt;falling like crazy&lt;/a&gt;. Natural gas production continues its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2014/10/2/6892781/how-the-oil-and-gas-boom-is-changing-america&quot;&gt;extraordinary surge&lt;/a&gt;. Coal, the golden child of the current administration, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2017/10/19/16494472/trump-coal-futile&quot;&gt;headed down the tubes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;DJLeDt&quot;&gt;In all that bedlam, it’s easy to lose sight of an equally important (if less sexy) trend: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-04-25/u-s-power-demand-flatlined-years-ago-and-it-s-hurting-utilities&quot;&gt;Demand for electricity is stagnant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4yD3y6&quot;&gt;Thanks to a combination of greater energy efficiency, outsourcing of heavy industry, and customers generating their own power on site, demand for utility power has been flat for 10 years, and most forecasts expect it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eia.gov/outlooks/aeo/data/browser/#/?id=8-AEO2017&amp;amp;region=0-0&amp;amp;cases=ref2017&amp;amp;start=2015&amp;amp;end=2050&amp;amp;f=A&amp;amp;linechart=~ref2017-d120816a.56-8-AEO2017&amp;amp;ctype=linechart&amp;amp;sourcekey=0&quot;&gt;stay that way&lt;/a&gt;. The die was cast around 1998, when GDP growth and electricity demand growth became “decoupled”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/10298325/_1x_1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-dynamic-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAUEBAAAACwAAAAAAQABAAACAkQBADs&quot; alt=&quot;demand vs. gdp growth&quot; data-chorus-optimize-field=&quot;main_image&quot; data-cid=&quot;site/dynamic_size_image-1519766713_2065_19370&quot; data-cdata=&quot;{&amp;quot;asset_id&amp;quot;:10298325,&amp;quot;ratio&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;*&amp;quot;}&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/10298325/_1x_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;demand vs. gdp growth&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-04-25/u-s-power-demand-flatlined-years-ago-and-it-s-hurting-utilities&quot;&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7fibzF&quot;&gt;This historic shift has wreaked havoc in the utility industry in ways large and small, visible and obscure. Some of that havoc is high-profile and headline-making, as in the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edf.org/firstenergy-bailout&quot;&gt;requests from utilities&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2018/1/9/16866196/perry-coal-bailout-nopr-ferc&quot;&gt;attempts by the Trump administration&lt;/a&gt;) to bail out large coal and nuclear plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;JB0Yt7&quot;&gt;Some of it, however, is unfolding in more obscure quarters. A great example recently popped up in Tennessee, where one utility is finding its 20-year forecasts rendered archaic almost as soon as they are released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;FB49HR&quot;&gt;Falling demand has TVA moving up its planning process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;JyOpf7&quot;&gt;Every five years, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tva.gov/&quot;&gt;Tennessee Valley Authority&lt;/a&gt; (TVA) — the federally owned regional planning agency that, among other things, supplies electricity to Tennessee and parts of surrounding states — develops an Integrated Resource Plan (IRP) meant to assess what it requires to meet customer needs for the next 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;40LKYp&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tva.gov/file_source/TVA/Site%20Content/Environment/Environmental%20Stewardship/IRP/Documents/2015_irp.pdf&quot;&gt;last IRP&lt;/a&gt;, completed in 2015, anticipated that there would be no need for major new investment in baseload (coal, nuclear, and hydro) power plants; it foresaw that energy efficiency and distributed (customer-owned) energy generation would hold down demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;K741pg&quot;&gt;Even so, TVA underestimated. Just three years later, the Chattanooga Free Press &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timesfreepress.com/news/business/aroundregion/story/2018/feb/22/tvlaunches-new-long-range-power-plan/464300/&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;, “TVA now expects to sell 13 percent less power in 2027 than it did two decades earlier — the first sustained reversal in the growth of electricity usage in the 85-year history of TVA.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;hP0TU2&quot;&gt;TVA will sell less electricity in 10 years than it did 10 years ago. That is bonkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;icucMr&quot;&gt;This startling shift in prospects has prompted the company to accelerate its schedule. It will now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tva.com/Environment/Environmental-Stewardship/Integrated-Resource-Plan&quot;&gt;develop its next IRP a year early&lt;/a&gt;, in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;OkNMyr&quot;&gt;Think for a moment about why a big utility like TVA (serving 9 million customers in seven states, with more than $11 billion in revenue) sets out to plan 20 years ahead. It is investing in extremely large and capital-intensive infrastructure like power plants and transmission lines, which cost billions of dollars and last for decades. These are not decisions to make lightly; the utility wants to be sure that they will still be needed, and will still pay off, for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;GzQRjC&quot;&gt;Now think for a moment about what it means for the electricity sector to be changing so fast that TVA’s projections are &lt;em&gt;out of date three years after its last IRP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; so much so that it needs to plunge back into the multimillion-dollar, year-long process of developing a new plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;YmUX1z&quot;&gt;TVA wanted a plan for 20 years; the plan lasted three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;qWZeT2&quot;&gt;The utility business model is headed for a reckoning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;J6SZmq&quot;&gt;TVA, as a government-owned, fully regulated utility, has only the goals of “low cost, informed risk, environmental responsibility, reliability, diversity of power and flexibility to meet changing market conditions,” as its planning manager told the Chattanooga Free Press. (Yes, that’s already a lot of goals!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;QPvZUD&quot;&gt;But investor-owned utilities (IOUs), which administer electricity for well over half of Americans, face another imperative: to make money for investors. They can’t make money selling electricity; monopoly regulations forbid it. Instead, they make money by earning a rate of return on investments in electrical power plants and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7EjZOI&quot;&gt;The problem is, with demand stagnant, there’s not much need for new hardware. And a drop in investment means a drop in profit. Unable to continue the steady growth that their investors have always counted on, IOUs are treading water, watching as revenues dry up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;RjvEmz&quot; readability=&quot;6.8286516853933&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;8.0337078651685&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;There is a lot of talk about natgas being primary cause of CO2 reductions in the US electric sector. Putting aside CH4 (for both gas and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/coal?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#coal&lt;/a&gt;), latest analysis from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BeyondCoal?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@BeyondCoal&lt;/a&gt; analysts show: 75% of carbon reductions from efficiency, wind and solar. 25% from natgas. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SierraClub?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@SierraClub&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/IrJb06GCLS&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/IrJb06GCLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Bruce Nilles (@brucenilles) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brucenilles/status/964189869445603328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 15, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0kwkEJ&quot;&gt;Utilities have been frantically adjusting to this new normal. The generation utilities that sell into wholesale electricity markets (also under pressure from falling power prices; thanks to natural gas and renewables, wholesale power prices are down 70 percent from 2007) have reacted by cutting costs and &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1516588&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fool.com%2Finvesting%2F2016%2F06%2F04%2Fwhy-consolidation-is-the-name-of-the-game-in-the-u.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;merging&lt;/a&gt;. The regulated utilities that administer local distribution grids have responded by &lt;a href=&quot;https://energynews.us/southeast/critics-say-dukes-13-billion-grid-plan-is-vague-not-worth-the-price-tag/&quot;&gt;increasing investments in those grids&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0pwYK0&quot;&gt;But these are temporary, limited responses, not enough to stay in business in the face of long-term decline in demand. Ultimately, deeper reforms will be necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;pVXMzT&quot;&gt;As I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2015/9/9/9287719/utilities-monopoly&quot;&gt;explained at length&lt;/a&gt;, the US utility sector was built around the presumption of perpetual growth. Utilities were envisioned as entities that would build the electricity infrastructure to safely and affordably meet ever-rising demand, which was seen as a fixed, external factor, outside utility control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;DWIDYN&quot;&gt;But demand is no longer rising. What the US needs now are utilities that can manage and accelerate that decline in demand, increasing efficiency as they shift to cleaner generation. The new electricity paradigm is to match flexible, diverse, low-carbon supply with (increasingly controllable) demand, through sophisticated real-time sensing and software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c447Ot&quot;&gt;That’s simply a different model than current utilities are designed for. To adapt, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2015/9/11/9306247/utilities-21st-century&quot;&gt;the utility business model must change&lt;/a&gt;. Utilities need newly defined responsibilities and new ways to make money, through services rather than new hardware. That kind of reform will require regulators, politicians, and risky experiments. Very few states — New York, California, Massachusetts, a few others — have consciously set off down that path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;rcuzlF&quot;&gt;Flat or declining demand is going to force the issue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;bGgT63&quot;&gt;Even if natural gas and renewables weren’t roiling the sector, the end of demand growth would eventually force utility reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;UUTzOT&quot;&gt;To be clear: For both economic and environmental reasons, it is &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; that US power demand has decoupled from GDP growth. As long as we’re getting the energy services we need, we &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; overall demand to decline. It saves money, reduces pollution, and avoids the need for expensive infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;vMRT3s&quot;&gt;But the way we’ve set up utilities, they must fight that trend. Every time they are forced to invest in energy efficiency or make some allowance for distributed generation (and they must always be forced), demand for their product declines, and with it their justification to make new investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;t9U3qg&quot;&gt;Only when the utility model fundamentally changes — when utilities begin to see themselves primarily as architects and managers of high-efficiency, low-emissions, multidirectional electricity systems rather than just investors in infrastructure growth — can utilities turn in earnest to the kind planning they need to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;CodEUg&quot;&gt;In a climate-aligned world, utilities would view the decoupling of power demand from GDP growth as cause for celebration, a sign of success. They would throw themselves into accelerating the trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;qDxz40&quot;&gt;Instead, utilities find themselves constantly surprised, caught flat-footed again and again by a trend they desperately want to believe is temporary. Unless we can collectively reorient utilities to pursue rather than fear current trends in electricity, they are headed for a grim reckoning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 14:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aaronbrethorst</dc:creator>
<og:description>The Tennessee Valley Authority is the latest to be caught short.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dv-LGVKnyRNKYFzafTbcwfoL0Kc=/0x87:4096x2232/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/10298503/shutterstock_101806765.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>After rising for 100 years, electricity demand is flat. Utilities are freaking out.</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2018/2/27/17052488/electricity-demand-utilities</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2018/2/27/17052488/electricity-demand-utilities</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>California to allow testing of self-driving cars without a driver present</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/27/california-to-allow-testing-of-self-driving-cars-without-a-driver-present/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/27/california-to-allow-testing-of-self-driving-cars-without-a-driver-present/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gm-cruise-av.jpg?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;California’s Department of Motor Vehicles established new rules announced Monday that will allow tech companies and others working on driverless vehicle systems to begin trialling their cars without a safety driver at the wheel. The new rules go into effect starting April 2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until now, the DMV has allowed companies approved for autonomous vehicle testing to run their cars on the roads, with autonomous driving systems engaged, provided that there’s a trained safety driver behind the wheel ready and able to take over manual control. Now, the regulators are updating their rules to allow for a fully driverless test, which is a key step along the route towards actually deploying self-driving vehicles in a commercial capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean test vehicles will be out there on the roads without any kind of human intervention backup – the DMV will require that those testing autonomous cars without a driver present have a dedicated communications channel that ties the car to a remote operator, who can take over if needed. The cars will also need to be hardened against cyber attacks and be able to provide their owner and operator info to any other parties in the event of an accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any companies wishing to test this way will need to secure a permit to do so from the DMV, just as with driver-present testing, and the new rules only apply to consumer passenger vehicles (not semi trucks, for instance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alphabet-owned Waymo and GM’s Cruise will likely welcome this news, since the former is already testing totally driver-free versions of its Chrysler Pacifica test car in Arizona, and Cruise recently showed off its fully driverless autonomous vehicle, a modified version of the Bolt EV with no steering wheel and no pedals for brake and acceleration. GM hopes to field those cars by 2019, and this will help them do that in San Francisco, the site of its current largest test pilot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 14:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doppp</dc:creator>
<og:title>California to allow testing of self-driving cars without a driver present</og:title>
<og:description>California's Department of Motor Vehicles established new rules announced Monday that will allow tech companies and others working on driverless vehicle..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gm-cruise-av.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/02/27/california-to-allow-testing-of-self-driving-cars-without-a-driver-present/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/27/california-to-allow-testing-of-self-driving-cars-without-a-driver-present/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Collection of Useful CSS Snippets</title>
<link>https://atomiks.github.io/30-seconds-of-css/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://atomiks.github.io/30-seconds-of-css/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;Clearfix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensures that an element self-clears its children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 data-type=&quot;Note: This is only useful if you are still using float to build layouts. Please consider using a modern approach with flexbox layout or grid layout.&quot;&gt;Note: This is only useful if you are still using float to build layouts. Please consider using a modern approach with flexbox layout or grid layout.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div class=&quot;floated&quot;&amp;gt;float a&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div class=&quot;floated&quot;&amp;gt;float b&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div class=&quot;floated&quot;&amp;gt;float c&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.clearfix::after {
  content: &quot;&quot;;
  display: block;
  clear: both;
}
.floated {
  float: left;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo__clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;float a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;float b&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;float c&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;.clearfix::after&lt;/code&gt; defines a pseudo-element.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;content: ''&lt;/code&gt; allows the pseudo-element to affect layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;clear: both&lt;/code&gt; indicates that the left, right or both sides of the element cannot be adjacent to earlier floated elements within the same block formatting context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;✅ No caveats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;25&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;constant-width-to-height-ratio&quot;&gt;Constant width to height ratio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given an element of variable width, it will ensure its height remains proportionate in a responsive fashion (i.e., its width to height ratio remains constant).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;constant-width-to-height-ratio&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.constant-width-to-height-ratio {
  background: #333;
  width: 50%;
  padding-top: 50%;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resize your browser window to see the proportion of the element remain the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;padding-top&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;padding-bottom&lt;/code&gt; can be used as an alternative to &lt;code&gt;height&lt;/code&gt; such that the percentage value causes an element's height to become a percentage of its parent's width, i.e. &lt;code&gt;50%&lt;/code&gt; means the height will be 50% of the parent element's width, which means it acts the same as &lt;code&gt;width&lt;/code&gt;. This allows its proportion to remain constant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;⚠️ &lt;code&gt;padding-top&lt;/code&gt; pushes any content within the element to the bottom.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;14.702702702703&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;custom-text-selection&quot;&gt;Custom text selection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes the styling of text selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;custom-text-selection&quot;&amp;gt;Select some of this text.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.custom-text-selection::selection {
  background: red;
  color: white;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;snippet-demo__custom-text-selection&quot;&gt;Select some of this text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;::selection&lt;/code&gt; defines a pseudo selector on an element to style text within it when selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;⚠️ Requires prefixes for full support and is not actually in any specification.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;76.244662435084&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;easing-variables&quot;&gt;Easing variables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Variables that can be reused for &lt;code&gt;transition-timing-function&lt;/code&gt; properties, more powerful than the built-in &lt;code&gt;ease&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ease-in&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ease-out&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ease-in-out&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;easing-variables&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;:root {
  --ease-in-quad: cubic-bezier(0.55, 0.085, 0.68, 0.53);
  --ease-in-cubic: cubic-bezier(0.55, 0.055, 0.675, 0.19);
  --ease-in-quart: cubic-bezier(0.895, 0.03, 0.685, 0.22);
  --ease-in-quint: cubic-bezier(0.755, 0.05, 0.855, 0.06);
  --ease-in-expo: cubic-bezier(0.95, 0.05, 0.795, 0.035);
  --ease-in-circ: cubic-bezier(0.6, 0.04, 0.98, 0.335);
  --ease-out-quad: cubic-bezier(0.25, 0.46, 0.45, 0.94);
  --ease-out-cubic: cubic-bezier(0.215, 0.61, 0.355, 1);
  --ease-out-quart: cubic-bezier(0.165, 0.84, 0.44, 1);
  --ease-out-quint: cubic-bezier(0.23, 1, 0.32, 1);
  --ease-out-expo: cubic-bezier(0.19, 1, 0.22, 1);
  --ease-out-circ: cubic-bezier(0.075, 0.82, 0.165, 1);
  --ease-in-out-quad: cubic-bezier(0.455, 0.03, 0.515, 0.955);
  --ease-in-out-cubic: cubic-bezier(0.645, 0.045, 0.355, 1);
  --ease-in-out-quart: cubic-bezier(0.77, 0, 0.175, 1);
  --ease-in-out-quint: cubic-bezier(0.86, 0, 0.07, 1);
  --ease-in-out-expo: cubic-bezier(1, 0, 0, 1);
  --ease-in-out-circ: cubic-bezier(0.785, 0.135, 0.15, 0.86);
}
.easing-variables {
  width: 50px;
  height: 50px;
  background: #333;
  transition: transform 1s var(--ease-out-quart);
}
.easing-variables:hover {
  transform: rotate(45deg);
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variables are defined globally within the &lt;code&gt;:root&lt;/code&gt; CSS pseudo-class which matches the root element of a tree representing the document. In HTML, &lt;code&gt;:root&lt;/code&gt; represents the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element and is identical to the selector &lt;code&gt;html&lt;/code&gt;, except that its specificity is higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;✅ No caveats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;18.842257597685&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;etched-text&quot;&gt;Etched text&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creates an effect where text appears to be &quot;etched&quot; or engraved into the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;etched-text&quot;&amp;gt;I appear etched into the background.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.etched-text {
  text-shadow: 0 2px white;
  font-size: 1.5rem;
  font-weight: bold;
  color: #b8bec5;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;snippet-demo__etched-text&quot;&gt;I appear etched into the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;text-shadow: 0 2px white&lt;/code&gt; creates a white shadow offset &lt;code&gt;0px&lt;/code&gt; horizontally and &lt;code&gt;2px&lt;/code&gt; vertically from the origin position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The background must be darker than the shadow for the effect to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text color should be slightly faded to make it look like it's engraved/carved out of the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;✅ No caveats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;14.142194744977&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;gradient-text&quot;&gt;Gradient text&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gives text a gradient color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;gradient-text&quot;&amp;gt;Gradient text&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.gradient-text {
  background: -webkit-linear-gradient(pink, red);
  -webkit-text-fill-color: transparent;
  -webkit-background-clip: text;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;snippet-demo__gradient-text&quot;&gt;Gradient text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;background: -webkit-linear-gradient(...)&lt;/code&gt; gives the text element a gradient background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;webkit-text-fill-color: transparent&lt;/code&gt; fills the text with a transparent color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;webkit-background-clip: text&lt;/code&gt; clips the background with the text, filling the text with the gradient background as the color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;⚠️ Uses non-standard properties.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;19.357865685373&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hairline-border&quot;&gt;Hairline border&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gives an element a border equal to 1 native device pixel in width, which can look very sharp and crisp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;hairline-border&quot;&amp;gt;text&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.hairline-border {
  box-shadow: 0 0 0 1px;
}
@media (min-resolution: 2dppx) {
  .hairline-border {
    box-shadow: 0 0 0 0.5px;
  }
}
@media (min-resolution: 3dppx) {
  .hairline-border {
    box-shadow: 0 0 0 0.33333333px;
  }
}
@media (min-resolution: 4dppx) {
  .hairline-border {
    box-shadow: 0 0 0 0.25px;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;snippet-demo__hairline-border&quot;&gt;Text with a hairline border around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;box-shadow&lt;/code&gt;, when only using spread, adds a psuedo-border which can use subpixels*.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;@media (min-resolution: ...)&lt;/code&gt; to check the device pixel ratio (&lt;code&gt;1ddpx&lt;/code&gt; equals 96 DPI), setting the spread of the &lt;code&gt;box-shadow&lt;/code&gt; equal to &lt;code&gt;1 / dppx&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser Support&quot;&gt;Browser Support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;⚠️ Needs alternate syntax and JavaScript user agent checking for full support.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;*Chrome does not support subpixel values on &lt;code&gt;border&lt;/code&gt;. Safari does not support subpixel values on &lt;code&gt;box-shadow&lt;/code&gt;. Firefox supports subpixel values on both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;12.244718309859&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;horizontal-and-vertical-centering&quot;&gt;Horizontal and vertical centering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horizontally and vertically centers a child element within a parent element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-and-vertical-centering&quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div class=&quot;child&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.horizontal-and-vertical-centering {
  display: flex;
  justify-content: center;
  align-items: center;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo__horizontal-and-vertical-centering&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;snippet-demo__horizontal-and-vertical-centering__child&quot;&gt;Centered content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;display: flex&lt;/code&gt; enables flexbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;justify-content: center&lt;/code&gt; centers the child horizontally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;align-items: center&lt;/code&gt; centers the child vertically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;⚠️ Needs prefixes for full support.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;30.169642857143&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mouse-cursor-gradient-tracking&quot;&gt;Mouse cursor gradient tracking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hover effect where the gradient follows the mouse cursor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;button class=&quot;mouse-cursor-gradient-tracking&quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;span&amp;gt;Hover me&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.mouse-cursor-gradient-tracking {
  position: relative;
  background: #2379f7;
  padding: 0.5rem 1rem;
  font-size: 1.2rem;
  border: none;
  color: white;
  cursor: pointer;
  outline: none;
  overflow: hidden;
}
.mouse-cursor-gradient-tracking span {
  position: relative;
}
.mouse-cursor-gradient-tracking::before {
  --size: 0;
  content: '';
  position: absolute;
  left: var(--x);
  top: var(--y);
  width: var(--size);
  height: var(--size);
  background: radial-gradient(circle closest-side, pink, transparent);
  transform: translate(-50%, -50%);
  transition: width .2s ease, height .2s ease;
}
.mouse-cursor-gradient-tracking:hover::before {
  --size: 200px;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;JavaScript&quot;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-js&quot;&gt;var btn = document.querySelector('.mouse-cursor-gradient-tracking')
btn.onmousemove = function (e) {
  var x = e.pageX - btn.offsetLeft
  var y = e.pageY - btn.offsetTop
  btn.style.setProperty('--x', x + 'px')
  btn.style.setProperty('--y', y + 'px')
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;snippet-demo__mouse-cursor-gradient-tracking&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Hover me&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TODO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the element's parent has a positioning context (&lt;code&gt;position: relative&lt;/code&gt;), you will need to subtract its offsets as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-js&quot;&gt;var x = e.pageX - btn.offsetLeft - btn.offsetParent.offsetLeft
var y = e.pageY - btn.offsetTop - btn.offsetParent.offsetTop
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requires JavaScript&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;⚠️ Requires JavaScript.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;19.470108695652&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;overflow-scroll-gradient&quot;&gt;Overflow scroll gradient&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adds a fading gradient to an overflowing element to better indicate there is more content to be scrolled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;overflow-scroll-gradient&quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div class=&quot;overflow-scroll-gradient__scroller&quot;&amp;gt;
    Content to be scrolled
  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.overflow-scroll-gradient {
  position: relative;
}
.overflow-scroll-gradient::after {
  content: '';
  position: absolute;
  bottom: 0;
  width: 300px;
  height: 25px;
  background: linear-gradient(rgba(255, 255, 255, 0.001), white); /* transparent keyword is broken in Safari */
}
.overflow-scroll-gradient__scroller {
  overflow-y: scroll;
  background: white;
  width: 300px;
  height: 250px;
  padding: 15px 0;
  line-height: 1.2;
  text-align: center;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;position: relative&lt;/code&gt; on the parent establishes a Cartesian positioning context for psuedo elements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;::after&lt;/code&gt; defines a pseudo element.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;background-image: linear-gradient(...)&lt;/code&gt; adds a linear gradient that fades from transparent to white (top to bottom).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;position: absolute&lt;/code&gt; takes the pseudo element out of the flow of the document and positions it in relation to the parent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;width: 300px&lt;/code&gt; matches the size of the scrolling element (which is a child of the parent that has the pseudo element).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;height: 25px&lt;/code&gt; is the height of the fading gradient psuedo element, which should be kept relatively small.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bottom: 0&lt;/code&gt; positions the pseudo element at the bottom of the parent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;✅ No caveats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reveals an interactive popout menu on hover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;reference&quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div class=&quot;popout-menu&quot;&amp;gt;
    Popout menu
  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.reference {
  position: relative;
}
.popout-menu {
  position: absolute;
  visibility: hidden;
  left: 100%;
}
.reference:hover &amp;gt; .popout-menu {
  visibility: visible;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;position: relative&lt;/code&gt; on the reference parent establishes a Cartesian positioning context for its child.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;position: absolute&lt;/code&gt; takes the popout menu out of the flow of the document and positions it in relation to the parent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;left: 100%&lt;/code&gt; moves the the popout menu 100% of its parent's width from the left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;visibility: hidden&lt;/code&gt; hides the popout menu initially and allows for transitions (unlike &lt;code&gt;display: none&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;.reference:hover &amp;gt; .popout-menu&lt;/code&gt; means that when &lt;code&gt;.reference&lt;/code&gt; is hovered over, select immediate children with a class of &lt;code&gt;.popout-menu&lt;/code&gt; and change their &lt;code&gt;visibility&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;visible&lt;/code&gt;, which shows the popout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;✅ No caveats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;27.614873035067&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pretty-text-underline&quot;&gt;Pretty text underline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nicer alternative to &lt;code&gt;text-decoration: underline&lt;/code&gt; where descenders do not clip the underline. Natively implemented as &lt;code&gt;text-decoration-skip-ink: auto&lt;/code&gt; but it has less control over the underline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;pretty-text-underline&quot;&amp;gt;Pretty text underline without clipping descending letters.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.pretty-text-underline {
  display: inline;
  font-size: 1.25rem;
  text-shadow: 1px 1px 0 #f5f6f9,
    -1px 1px 0 #f5f6f9,
    -1px -1px 0 #f5f6f9,
    1px -1px 0 #f5f6f9;
  background-image: linear-gradient(90deg, currentColor 100%, transparent 100%);
  background-position: 0 1.04em;
  background-repeat: repeat-x;
  background-size: 1px 1px;
}
.pretty-text-underline::-moz-selection {
  background-color: rgba(0, 150, 255, 0.3);
  text-shadow: none;
}
.pretty-text-underline::selection {
  background-color: rgba(0, 150, 255, 0.3);
  text-shadow: none;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;snippet-demo__pretty-text-underline&quot;&gt;Pretty text underline without clipping descending letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;text-shadow: ...&lt;/code&gt; has 4 values with offsets that cover a 4x4 px area to ensure the underline has a &quot;thick&quot; shadow that covers the line where descenders clip it. Use a color that matches the background. For a larger font, use a larger &lt;code&gt;px&lt;/code&gt; size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;background-image: linear-gradient(...)&lt;/code&gt; creates a 90deg gradient with the current text color (&lt;code&gt;currentColor&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;background-*&lt;/code&gt; properties size the gradient as 1x1px at the bottom and repeats it along the x-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;::selection&lt;/code&gt; pseudo selector ensures the text shadow does not interfere with text selection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;⚠️ Firefox requires a vendor prefix for the selection pseudo-selector to work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;15.67323943662&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;shape-separator&quot;&gt;Shape separator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uses an SVG shape to separate two different blocks to create more a interesting visual appearance compared to standard horizontal separation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;shape-separator&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.shape-separator {
  position: relative;
  height: 48px;
}
.shape-separator::after {
  content: '';
  background-image: url(data:image/svg+xml;base64,PHN2ZyB2aWV3Qm94PSIwIDAgMjQgMjQiIHhtbG5zPSJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnczLm9yZy8yMDAwL3N2ZyIgZmlsbC1ydWxlPSJldmVub2RkIiBjbGlwLXJ1bGU9ImV2ZW5vZGQiIHN0cm9rZS1saW5lam9pbj0icm91bmQiIHN0cm9rZS1taXRlcmxpbWl0PSIxLjQxNCI+PHBhdGggZD0iTTEyIDEybDEyIDEySDBsMTItMTJ6IiBmaWxsPSIjZmZmIi8+PC9zdmc+);
  position: absolute;
  width: 100%;
  height: 24px;
  bottom: 0;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;position: relative&lt;/code&gt; on the element establishes a Cartesian positioning context for psuedo elements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;::after&lt;/code&gt; defines a pseudo element.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;background-image: url(...)&lt;/code&gt; adds the SVG shape (a 24x24 triangle in base64 format) as the background image of the psuedo element, which repeats by default. It must be the same color as the block that is being separated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;position: absolute&lt;/code&gt; takes the pseudo element out of the flow of the document and positions it in relation to the parent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;width: 100%&lt;/code&gt; ensures the element stretches the entire width of its parent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;height: 24px&lt;/code&gt; is the same height as the shape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bottom: 0&lt;/code&gt; positions the pseudo element at the bottom of the parent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;✅ No caveats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;system-font-stack&quot;&gt;System font stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uses the native font of the operating system to get close to a native app feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;system-font-stack&quot;&amp;gt;This text uses the system font.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.system-font-stack {
  font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;snippet-demo__system-font-stack&quot;&gt;This text uses the system font.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The browser looks for each successive font, preferring the first one if possible, and falls back to the next if it cannot find the font (on the system or defined in CSS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-apple-system&lt;/code&gt; is San Francisco, used on iOS and macOS (not Chrome however)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;BlinkMacSystemFont&lt;/code&gt; is San Francisco, used on macOS Chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Segoe UI&lt;/code&gt; is used on Windows 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Roboto&lt;/code&gt; is used on Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Oxygen-Sans&lt;/code&gt; is used on GNU+Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/code&gt; is used on Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Helvetica&lt;/code&gt; is used on macOS 10.10 and below (wrapped in quotes because it has a space)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Arial&lt;/code&gt; is a font widely supported by all operating systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sans-serif&lt;/code&gt; is the fallback sans-serif font if none of the other fonts are supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;✅ No caveats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;19.520134228188&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;triangle&quot;&gt;Triangle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creates a triangle shape with pure CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;triangle&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.triangle {
  width: 0;
  height: 0;
  border-top: 20px solid #333;
  border-left: 20px solid transparent;
  border-right: 20px solid transparent;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/q/7073484&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View this link for a detailed explanation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The color of the border is the color of the triangle. The side the triangle tip points corresponds to the opposite &lt;code&gt;border-*&lt;/code&gt; property. For example, a color on &lt;code&gt;border-top&lt;/code&gt; means the arrow points downward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experiment with the &lt;code&gt;px&lt;/code&gt; values to change the proportion of the triangle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;✅ No caveats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet&quot; readability=&quot;13.237430167598&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;truncate-text&quot;&gt;Truncate text&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the text is longer than one line, it will be truncated and end with an ellipsis &lt;code&gt;…&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;HTML&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;truncate-text&quot;&amp;gt;If I exceed one line's width, I will be truncated.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-css&quot;&gt;.truncate-text {
  overflow: hidden;
  white-space: nowrap;
  text-overflow: ellipsis;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;snippet-demo&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;snippet-demo__truncate-text&quot;&gt;This text will be truncated if it exceeds 200px in width.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;overflow: hidden&lt;/code&gt; prevents the text from overflowing its dimensions (for a block, 100% width and auto height).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;white-space: nowrap&lt;/code&gt; prevents the text from exceeding one line in height.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;text-overflow: ellipsis&lt;/code&gt; makes it so that if the text exceeds its dimensions, it will end with an ellipsis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 data-type=&quot;Browser support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;snippet__support-note&quot;&gt;✅ No caveats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 13:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>marinacalado</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://atomiks.github.io/30-seconds-of-css/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Diesel cars can be banned from German cities, court rules</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-germany-emissions/german-court-backs-city-bans-on-diesel-cars-idUSKCN1GA2XD</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-germany-emissions/german-court-backs-city-bans-on-diesel-cars-idUSKCN1GA2XD</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;MegaArticleBody_first-p_2htdt&quot;&gt;LEIPZIG/FRANKFURT, Germany (Reuters) - German cities can ban the most heavily polluting diesel cars from their streets, a court ruled on Tuesday, a move that could accelerate a shift away from the combustion engine and force manufacturers to pay to improve exhaust systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The court said Stuttgart, which styles itself the birthplace of the modern automobile and is home to Mercedes-maker Daimler, should consider gradually imposing a year-round ban for older diesel models, while Duesseldorf should also think about curbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Many other German cities exceed European Union limits on nitrogen oxide (NOx), known to cause respiratory disease. After the ruling, the northern city of Hamburg said it would start to implement limits on diesel vehicles from the end of April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;There has been a global backlash against diesel-engine cars since leading German carmaker Volkswagen admitted in 2015 to cheating U.S. exhaust tests. The scandal has spread across the industry and boosted investment in electric vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Paris, Madrid, Mexico City and Athens have said they plan to ban diesel vehicles from city centers by 2025, while the mayor of Copenhagen wants to ban new diesel cars from entering the city as soon as next year. France and Britain will ban new petrol and diesel cars by 2040.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bans in the home of some of the world’s biggest automakers are a further blow for the sector, and an embarrassment for Chancellor Angela Merkel’s government, which has faced criticism for its close ties to the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Germany has long promoted diesel to help cut carbon dioxide emissions and meet climate change goals, but the country now fears a shift away from the combustion engine could endanger hundreds of thousands of jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MIXED REACTION&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The ruling was praised by environmental groups but angered many politicians and business lobbies who said millions of drivers might end up unable to use or sell vehicles they bought in good faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Driving bans have a massive impact on our ownership rights, on mobility and on our profession,” said Hans Peter Wollseifer, president of the association of German tradesmen. “The carmakers are to blame for the diesel problem, not us tradesmen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The VDA auto industry lobby took comfort from the fact the court had not insisted on bans. “It is a rejection of general driving bans . . . They must be proportional and only considered as a last resort,” the VDA’s Matthias Wissmann said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Merkel said the government would discuss with regions and municipalities how to proceed, while her ministers said they still hoped bans could be averted by steps to bolster public transport and get automakers to improve emissions systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“We must do everything possible to prevent the loss of personal freedom and the reduction in value of cars,” Transport Minister Christian Schmidt told a news conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Sales of diesel cars have been falling fast in Europe since the Volkswagen scandal, with fears of driving bans sending demand sharply lower in Germany in the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container_1tVQo&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;span class=&quot;Image_caption_KoNH1&quot;&gt;Cars are pictured near Germany's federal administrative court in Leipzig, Germany, February 27, 2018. REUTERS/Fabrizio Bensch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“CLEAN AIR”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The ruling by the country’s highest federal administrative court came after German states had appealed against bans imposed by local courts in Stuttgart and Duesseldorf in cases brought by environmental group DUH over poor air quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“This is a great day for clean air in Germany,” DUH managing director Juergen Resch said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“This is a debacle for the policies of the grand coalition, which has sided with the auto industry,” Resch added, referring to the ruling coalition of conservatives and Social Democrats that Merkel hopes to renew in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_inline-container_1QqKC Slideshow_mega_19SOz&quot;&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;Slideshow_count_3OPtf&quot;&gt;(6 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The court on Tuesday ordered Stuttgart and Duesseldorf to amend their anti-pollution plans, saying city bans could be implemented even without nationwide rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“It will not be easy to implement,” Stuttgart mayor Fritz Kuhn told a news conference, adding the regional government would probably agree a new plan within six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Germany’s police union warned it did not have capacity to enforce any bans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;UPGRADES REQUIRED&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Cars that meet Euro-4 emissions standards could be banned from Stuttgart from next January, while Euro-5 vehicles should not be banned until Sept. 1, 2019, four years after the introduction of the latest Euro-6 standard. Tradesmen and some residents should be exempted, the court added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Environment Minister Barbara Hendricks said bans could still be avoided if automakers agree to pay to upgrade the exhaust cleaning systems of older diesels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“The problem was caused by carmakers and we should not release them from their responsibility,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Of the 15 million diesel cars on Germany’s roads, only 2.7 million have Euro-6 technology. Evercore ISI has estimated that upgrading the exhaust cleaning of just the Euro-5 fleet could cost up to 14.5 billion euros ($17.9 billion).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“By the time these vehicles face the risk of being banned from certain cities, the industry, together with Berlin, will have found solutions to offer practical hardware updates and attractive scrapping schemes,” Evercore ISI analysts said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The government has begun work on legal changes to permit driving bans on certain routes on an emergency basis, transport ministry documents seen by Reuters showed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;It is also considering making public transport free in cities suffering from poor air quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container_28wm1&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution_o4ojT&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content_27_rw&quot;&gt;Additional reporting by Andreas Cremer, Maria Sheahan and Tom Sims; Writing by Emma Thomasson; Editing by Keith Weir and Mark Potter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer_1gqgJ&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle_7sKLj&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 12:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>felixbraun</dc:creator>
<og:title>Diesel cars can be banned from German cities, court rules</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-germany-emissions/german-court-to-rule-on-city-bans-for-diesel-cars-idUSKCN1GA2XD</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>German cities can ban the most heavily polluting diesel cars from their streets, a court ruled on Tuesday, a move that could accelerate a shift away from the combustion engine and force manufacturers to pay to improve exhaust systems.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20180227&amp;t=2&amp;i=1235699345&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEE1Q0TG</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-germany-emissions/german-court-backs-city-bans-on-diesel-cars-idUSKCN1GA2XD</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How GDPR Will Change The Way You Develop</title>
<link>https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2018/02/gdpr-for-web-developers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2018/02/gdpr-for-web-developers/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Europe’s imminent privacy overhaul means that we all have to become more diligent about what data we collect, how we collect it, and what we do with it. In our turbulent times, these privacy obligations are about ethics as well as law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web developers have a major role to play here. After all, healthy data protection practice is as much about the development side — code, data, and security — as it is about the business side of process, information, and strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll explore what you, as a developer, need to know about the new data protection regime. At the end, you’ll understand how the challenges posed by the privacy overhaul will ultimately help to make you a better developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;This article does not constitute legal advice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In May of 2018, a major upgrade to Europe’s overarching data protection framework becomes enforceable. This will be followed by a companion piece of legislation pertaining to data in transit. The extraterritorial nature of these two frameworks — they protect the privacy rights of people in Europe regardless of where their data is collected — means that they will become the &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; standard for privacy around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European privacy overhaul will bring positive changes to our business processes and development workflows. We all have to become more thoughtful about what data we collect, how we collect it, and what we do with it. Those changes could not have come soon enough. With data breaches and privacy violations in the headlines every day, not to mention governments expressing open malice against vulnerable citizens, our privacy obligations are as much about ethics and humanity as they are about law and policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;421.41751339368&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web developers like you have a major role to play in embracing the new frameworks as the positive tools that they are. The good news is that the obligations in the updated frameworks are not overly complex or technical, and in fact, they don’t even require lawyers. These rules are common-sense and can be immediately adopted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore what you need to know about the new data protection frameworks, and how you will need to adapt your development workflows to meet them. This article is not a comprehensive overview of the European privacy overhaul by any means; rather, it focuses on issues specific to web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-changing-privacy-landscape&quot;&gt;The Changing Privacy Landscape&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe’s data protection and privacy overhaul comes in two parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first half is the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which becomes enforceable across Europe on 25 May 2018. This is an overhaul, modernization, and replacement of the existing framework, the Data Protection Directive of 1995 (yes, 1995.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the existing principles from the original Directive stay with us under GDPR. What GDPR adds is new definitions and requirements to reflect changes in technology which simply did not exist in the dialup era. It also tightens up requirements for transparency, disclosure, and process: lessons learned from 23 years of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second half is the revamp of the ePrivacy Directive of 2002. (You know it, somewhat inaccurately, as the “cookie law.”) This revamp, which deals with data in transit such as cookies, telemetry, metadata, and consent for marketing, was originally planned to go live on 25 May, twinned with GDPR. However, as of this writing, the ePD is still in draft negotiations. The latest Brussels gossip says it should be finalized in late autumn or early winter. Regardless of when it is finalized, its requirements for consent will reference GDPR’s standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers may find the delay to be a good thing; it gives you a chance to get the wide scope of GDPR right, which will make the narrow scope of the ePD relatively easy when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-personal-data&quot;&gt;What Is Personal Data?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European data protection frameworks pertain to &lt;em&gt;personal data&lt;/em&gt;. This is defined as “any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.” This can be one piece of information or multiple data points combined to create a record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond personal data there is also &lt;em&gt;sensitive personal data&lt;/em&gt;, defined as information about a person’s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Racial or ethnic origin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Political opinions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religious or philosophical beliefs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trade union membership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sex life or sexual orientation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Past or spent criminal convictions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sensitive personal data requires stricter protections than regular personal data, and the consequences for its leakage or misuse are greater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDPR expands the definition of personal data to include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Genetic data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biometric data (such as facial recognition or fingerprint logins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pseudonymized data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online identifiers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The latter definition is important for developers. It includes things like IP addresses, mobile device IDs, browser fingerprints, RFID tags, MAC addresses, cookies, telemetry, user account IDs, and any other form of system-generated data which identifies a natural person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European term “personal data” differs from the American term “personally identifiable information.” The latter pertains to a much more limited set of information than the European model. It also does not see information as contextual, whereas the European framework emphasizes the risks inherent in data aggregation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal data is used by &lt;em&gt;data controllers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;data processors&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;data controller&lt;/em&gt; is a person or an entity, such as you or your organization, which decides what data is collected, how it is used, and whom it is shared with. The &lt;em&gt;data processor&lt;/em&gt; is any entity other than the data controller who processes the data on their behalf. As a developer, you may be a data controller, you may be a data processor, and you may be both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-is-impacted-by-the-privacy-overhaul&quot;&gt;Who Is Impacted By The Privacy Overhaul?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European data protection rules are, and always have been, extraterritorial. They apply to all personal data collected, processed, and retained about persons within the European Union regardless of citizenship or nationality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That simply means that if you do business in Europe, or collect data on European users, you must protect their data in full accordance with the regulation as if you yourself were in Europe. If you are not prepared to meet that legal requirement, you should not do business in Europe. (Indeed, any developer collecting European data who is surprised to hear this news should explain what they have been doing with that data since 1995.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDPR applies to all businesses, organizations, sectors, situations, and scenarios, regardless of a business’s size, head count, or financial turnover. A small app studio is every bit as beholden to these rules as a large corporation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Europe’s data protection regime stands in stark contrast to that of the U.S., which has no single overarching, cross-sector, or cross-situational data protection law. What little privacy law there is in the U.S. tends to be applicable only within sectors or states. The American approach also tends to view privacy as a subset of contract or property law, not its own discipline. This cultural difference often sees American developers struggling with the concept of privacy as a fundamental human right enshrined in law, a situation which has no U.S. equivalent. That gap does, unfortunately, add a few more steps to the compliance journey for U.S. developers tasked with getting to grips with the European framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-does-your-development-workflow-need-to-change&quot;&gt;How Does Your Development Workflow Need To Change?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever programming language you work in, role you hold, or product you create, GDPR requires you to be more structured and transparent about how you do things. Yet far from being a burden, you will find these obligations common-sense and surprisingly welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s go over the ways that GDPR will impact your development workflow. We can divide this into two broad areas: how you &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; within your business, and how you &lt;em&gt;develop&lt;/em&gt; with the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-you-work&quot;&gt;How You Work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDPR will impact &lt;em&gt;how you work&lt;/em&gt; in terms of business processes and project planning. These changes are cross-disciplinary and should involve your development, UX, marketing, legal, and management teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;privacy-by-design&quot;&gt;Privacy By Design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDPR requires the adoption of the Privacy by Design framework, a seven-point development methodology which requires optimal data protection to be provided as standard, by default, across all uses and applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve previously covered the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2017/07/privacy-by-design-framework/&quot;&gt;Privacy By Design Framework&lt;/a&gt;” in depth in its own article. Read it and then come back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;privacy-impact-assessments&quot;&gt;Privacy Impact Assessments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Privacy Impact Assessment (PIA), which is required under GDPR for data-intensive projects, is a living document which must be made accessible to all involved with a project. It is the process by which you discuss, audit, inventory, and mitigate the privacy risks inherent in the data you collect and process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all GDPR documentation, a PIA can be requisitioned by a data protection regulator in the event of a privacy concern or data breach. Not having a PIA is not an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A robust PIA should document the following information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;data-collection-and-retention&quot;&gt;Data collection and retention&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;What personal data is processed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is that data collected and retained?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the data stored locally, on our servers, or both?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For how long is data stored, and when is the data deleted?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the data collection and processing specified, explicit, and legitimate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the process for granting consent for the data processing, and is consent explicit and verifiable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the basis of the consent for the data processing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If not based on consent, what is the legal basis for the data processing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the data minimized to what is explicitly required?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the data accurate and kept up to date?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are users informed about the data processing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What controls do users have over the data collection and retention?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h5 id=&quot;technical-and-security-measures&quot;&gt;Technical and security measures&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Is the data encrypted?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the data anonymized or pseudonymized?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the data backed up?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the technical and security measures at the host location?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h5 id=&quot;personnel&quot;&gt;Personnel&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Who has access to the data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What data protection training have those individuals received?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What security measures do those individuals work with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What data breach notification and alert procedures are in place?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What procedures are in place for government requests?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h5 id=&quot;subject-access-rights&quot;&gt;Subject access rights&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;How does the data subject exercise their access rights?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the data subject exercise their right to data portability?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the data subject exercise their rights to erasure and the right to be forgotten?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the data subject exercise their right to restrict and object?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h5 id=&quot;legal&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are the obligations of all data processors, including subcontractors, covered by a contract?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the data is transferred outside the European Union, what are the protective measures and safeguards?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h5 id=&quot;risks&quot;&gt;Risks&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;What are the risks to the data subjects if the data is misused, mis-accessed, or breached?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the risks to the data subjects if the data is modified?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the risks to the data subjects if the data is lost?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the main sources of risk?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What steps have been taken to mitigate those risks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;training-and-professional-development&quot;&gt;Training And Professional Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing for data protection isn’t just about code: it’s about the people who write it. GDPR will require developers to know the legal and policy landscape of their profession. (This has been the norm for other fields for centuries: how embarrassing for us.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All contributors to a project, whether they are employees, contractors, or volunteers, will be expected to be competent in, at the very least:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The European data protection and privacy frameworks (GDPR and ePD);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any additional local, regional, or national privacy laws;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any industry- or sector-specific data requirements, such as those in the health and financial service industries; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any development frameworks and methodologies used as standard within the workplace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A privacy-conscious workplace will provide training on these frameworks as part of a new employee’s induction, and will also provide refresher training as required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming years, we can expect to see knowledge of legal frameworks on privacy set forth as prerequisites in job descriptions. Schools and coding academies should include the frameworks within their curricula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under GDPR, a regulator’s investigation into a data breach or a privacy concern will include an examination of what training has been provided. If there is no documented evidence that staff and contributors have been given training, or were required to be competent in the data protection and privacy frameworks which govern their work, the investigation will be more unpleasant than it would have been otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;technical-and-security-measures-1&quot;&gt;Technical And Security Measures&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical and security measures are as much a part of a healthy GDPR compliance journey as data audits and file storage. These aspects, as with everything under GDPR, have been toughened and tightened up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A privacy-conscious workflow should include an evaluation of physical access to data. This means on-premises access by staff and contractors. You will need to look at potential misuses of data such as employee logins, unencrypted hardware and peripherals, unprotected servers, and insecure connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most external data breaches begin internally. For that reason, GDPR holds that unauthorized access to data, such as giving an unvetted temp full system access on a generic login account (and didn’t that happen to all of us?), constitutes a data breach as if the data had been passed externally. User access controls have a role to play here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good security measures involve system monitoring and logging. It’s worth noting that the data you capture solely for the purpose of security monitoring and prevention should not be conflated with user-generated personal data such as account information, although all technical and security logs should, of course, be collected, retained, and deleted in full accordance with the rest of GDPR’s provisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside people and peripherals, evaluating technical and security measures must also include auditing your international data transfers. Remember that one of the fundamental principles of the European data protection regime is safeguarding data sent outside Europe to third countries. You will need to ensure that any non-European third parties you use, whether that is a web host, cloud storage, or a business partner, guarantees they are safeguarding your European data to European standards. And yes, you need to get that in your contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-you-develop&quot;&gt;How You Develop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far we’ve reviewed how GDPR will impact your development workflow from the perspective of business processes and project planning. Now let’s look into the ways it will impact &lt;em&gt;how you code&lt;/em&gt;. These changes will involve your IT and management teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;coding-standards&quot;&gt;Coding Standards&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building healthy data protection workflows, and avoiding unnecessary data capture or loss, require everyone in your project to work from a clearly defined set of code libraries, tools, and frameworks. For that reason, your GDPR compliance journey should involve creating a list of approved standards and methodologies used for both coding and testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDPR does not define a list of right or wrong programming languages, version control systems, or testing tools: what matters is that whatever you use is clearly defined and followed for each and every situation you use it in. You may, of course, modify your standard tools and infrastructure at any time, as long as you ensure they are acknowledged and documented as the frameworks which must be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your coding standards must be preventive as well. You should disable unsafe or unnecessary modules, particularly in APIs and third-party libraries. An audit of what constitutes an unsafe module should be about privacy by design, such as the unnecessary capture and retention of personal data, as well as security vulnerabilities. Likewise, code reviews should include an audit for privacy by design principles, including mapping where data is physically and virtually stored, and how that data is protected, encrypted, and sandboxed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;design-requirements&quot;&gt;Design Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of sandboxing, design requirements are also an integral part of a GDPR-conscious development workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data protection by default as a design process starts with developing with minimization in mind. Collect the absolute minimum amount of personal data required and no more, both on the front end and back end. Do not link personal data with other data sets stored in a single location. If aggregating data, remove personal and identifying data as much as possible. Anonymisation, although not explicitly required under GDPR, is recommended; however, the greater the risk that anonymized data could be indirectly identifiable or re-identified by aggregating it with additional data, the greater the risk of using it at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While GDPR requires you to define data retention and deletion schedules for all the personal data you hold, it does not require you to delete everything as a rule. You may, for example, wish to keep all purchasing records for ten years for tax and auditing purposes. That is perfectly acceptable, as long as you document that fact and its rationale. A user’s request for account deletion would not require you to delete their purchasing records from your tax and accounting records; the right to be forgotten is not the right to fly under the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data should be deleted, either automatically or through user actions, when it is no longer needed. Take care to think of how deleted data may still be present in archives and backups. You will also need to work with third parties whom you pass data to or receive it from, such as a SAAS or a cloud service, to ensure that a request for data deletion on your end also removes the data on their end, and to verify that this has been done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of privacy-conscious system design is hiding and protecting data from unnecessary user access. Personal data should not be visible in plain view, either on the front or back end, nor should all users of a system have universal access. Data should also be encrypted in transit and at rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your system design reviews should view your flows of personal data through the eyes of an attacker, be it human or otherwise. How would someone (looking for personal data to exploit) find what they were looking for and how easy have you made it for them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;consent-and-subject-access-mechanisms&quot;&gt;Consent And Subject Access Mechanisms&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European data protection overhaul is all about returning control over data to the people the data is about through consent and subject access mechanisms. We all need to be informed about the data flows containing our information, and our rights over them, in the most privacy-positive ways possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the front end, this means providing better consent mechanisms and user controls. Your projects and applications should provide optimal control over consent settings through things like control panels, user dashboards, account settings, and privacy centers. These choices, at all times, must be granular; a user must be able to invoke any aspect of control over their data at any time. (The days of having to choose between accepting anything a site wants to do with your data or deactivating your account are over.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll also need to provide an interface for individual subject access rights, such as the rights to edit and correct information, the right to download data, the right to restrict processing, and the right to data deletion (the frequently misunderstood “right to be forgotten”). Account settings and privacy dashboards are the ideal homes for these options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the back end, you should develop to enforce user consent and choice. A user setting up an account for the first time should enjoy optimal privacy settings by default; they should not have to opt-in &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; privacy, or switch &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; defaults to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, consent must never be assumed through a &lt;em&gt;lack&lt;/em&gt; of action, such as a failure to tick a box or the mere creation of an account, so you should develop ways to alert users to the fact that they have not yet granted opt-in consent to any applicable choices and options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your back-end development process will also need to ensure timestamped documentation of what consent a user gave, how they gave it, and whether or not they have withdrawn it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;testing-and-maintenance&quot;&gt;Testing And Maintenance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, developing for GDPR means adding privacy by design and data protection by default to your testing processes. These should supplement existing procedures such as penetration testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your privacy testing procedures should predict the ways unauthorized users would access actual data on your system. Would a suspicious search for user data, or an alteration to a record, be logged as a security vulnerability? Is data stored in login cookies? Could someone gain access to data by intentionally triggering an error? What do you do about users who have used plaintext or silly passwords? If you are applying privacy by design retroactively to an existing project, have you tested how easy it is to access legacy data? This is where you have to think really creatively — and somewhat maliciously — about how and where data can escape to where it should not be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing for data protection by default should also consider external alerts. Do you have a means for the public to alert you to data breaches, either potential or real? What about bug bounties and responsible disclosure programmes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And remember the golden rule of GDPR — document it, or it didn’t happen. Your testing results, and the methodologies you used to achieve them, need to be noted and actioned as living documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-it-right-from-the-start&quot;&gt;Get It Right From The Start&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve shown you how GDPR requires you to be more thoughtful about the sites and services you build, more transparent about the ways you collect and use data, more considerate of your users, and more thorough in your development and documentation processes. If you were expecting scary legal mumbo-jumbo, we won’t apologize. GDPR is only a complicated legal burden if you want it to be. The European privacy overhaul is really about adopting common-sense safeguards for data protection and privacy as fundamental parts of your development workflow on the code and process levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, did you notice that we only mentioned lawyers once? None of what we have discussed, save for contracts with your third-party suppliers, requires a legal department. You can get started with all of this right away. And you should. At a time when privacy and security are the biggest ethical challenges facing our industry, the European privacy overhaul is a powerful toolkit for taking responsibility for protecting the people in your data. Use that for what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;links-and-resources&quot;&gt;Links And Resources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/smedataprotect/index_en.htm&quot;&gt;Data protection: Better rules for small business&lt;/a&gt; ,” An overview of GDPR, European Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-single-market/en/policies/online-privacy&quot;&gt;Digital privacy&lt;/a&gt;,” Digital Single Market, European Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datatilsynet.no/en/regulations-and-tools/guidelines/data-protection-by-design-and-by-default/&quot;&gt;Software development with Data Protection by Design and by Default&lt;/a&gt;,” Datatilsynet (Norwegian data protection regulator, in English)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://newdigitalrights.projectsbyif.com/&quot;&gt;Designing for new digital rights&lt;/a&gt;,” Projects by IF (Prototypes for informed consent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://ico.org.uk/media/for-organisations/documents/1061/anonymisation-code.pdf&quot;&gt;Anonymisation: Managing data protection risk&lt;/a&gt;,” Code of practice, Data protection, Information Commissioner’s Office (PDF)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twobirds.com/en/hot-topics/general-data-protection-regulation/gdpr-tracker&quot;&gt;GDPR national implementing legislation across Europe&lt;/a&gt;,” GDPR Tracker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=OJ%3AL%3A2016%3A119%3ATOC&quot;&gt;Full EU legal text of the GDPR&lt;/a&gt;,” EUR-Lex Access to European Union law&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://globalprivacymatrix.bakermckenzie.com/&quot;&gt;Global privacy laws&lt;/a&gt;,” Baker &amp;amp; McKenzie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;signature&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/5322ca5f2bf4fad4e893ba1d32a13a16971b5212/62e76/images/logo/logo--red.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Smashing Editorial&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;(ra, il)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 12:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>_petronius</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How GDPR Will Change The Way You Develop</og:title>
<og:description>GDPR requires you to be more thoughtful about the sites and services you build, more transparent about the ways you collect and use data, more considerate of your users, and more thorough in your development and documentation processes.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2018/02/gdpr-for-web-developers/</og:url>
<og:image>//cloud.netlifyusercontent.com/assets/344dbf88-fdf9-42bb-adb4-46f01eedd629/0dcb43cf-e60e-434b-8f95-e6e5ca9df199/gdpr-illustration.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2018/02/gdpr-for-web-developers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Searching Through 500M Pwned Passwords Is So Quick</title>
<link>https://www.troyhunt.com/i-wanna-go-fast-why-searching-through-500m-pwned-passwords-is-so-quick/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.troyhunt.com/i-wanna-go-fast-why-searching-through-500m-pwned-passwords-is-so-quick/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In the immortal words of Ricky Bobby, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_qJGsSuFRIg&quot;&gt;I wanna go fast&lt;/a&gt;. When &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/ive-just-launched-pwned-passwords-version-2/&quot;&gt;I launched Pwned Passwords V2 last week&lt;/a&gt;, I made it fast - &lt;em&gt;real fast&lt;/em&gt; - and I want to talk briefly here about why that was important, how I did it and then how I've since shaved another 56% off the load time for requests that hit the origin. And a bunch of other cool perf stuff while I'm here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;whyspeedmattersforpwnedpasswords&quot;&gt;Why Speed Matters for Pwned Passwords&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, read the previous post about k-Anonymity and protecting the privacy of passwords to save me repeating it all here. I've been amazed at how quickly this has been adopted since I pushed it out very early on Thursday morning my time. Perhaps most notably is &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.agilebits.com/2018/02/22/finding-pwned-passwords-with-1password/&quot;&gt;1Password's use of the service&lt;/a&gt; having pushed out integration within 27 hours. They had no prior noticed of this either, they just got down to business and did it as soon as I launched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read through the comments on that original blog post and you'll see a heap of other integrations too. Perhaps my favourite though is this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;5.5159010600707&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Beauty of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Cloudflare?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt; Workers is that it was easy to integrate &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/troyhunt?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@troyhunt&lt;/a&gt;'s new pwned password service to add a header indicating whether a POSTed password is pwned or not. Then the server can warn the user.&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/SmCgwV1tpn&quot;&gt;https://t.co/SmCgwV1tpn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— John Graham-Cumming (@jgrahamc) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jgrahamc/status/967438451007205376?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 24, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John is the CTO of Cloudflare and his model uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-workers-is-now-on-open-beta/&quot;&gt;a Cloudflare Worker&lt;/a&gt;. This makes it possible to add that little bit of code to Cloudflare's &quot;edges&quot; (effectively the 122 data centres they have around the world sitting between browsers and servers), grab the password that's submitted by, say, a login request then check if it's been pwned and return the result in a response header. It's a beautifully elegant solution because there's no code to run on the server side and it can execute async whilst the original request is being processed by the origin server. Of course, you still need to &lt;em&gt;do something&lt;/em&gt; with the newly added header indicating pwn status, but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If people are adding this service into their sites, it has to be fast. &lt;em&gt;Super-fast.&lt;/em&gt; It can't block requests whilst searching through a large DB of half a billion records, if it's to be successful then responses must be lightening quick. There's also a direct line between execution time and the cost I incur because I'm using &lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/pricing/details/functions/&quot;&gt;Azure Functions which are priced as follows&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Azure-Function-Pricing.png&quot; alt=&quot;Azure Function Pricing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I can keep execution time and resource consumption down, I can keep costs down. But further to that, if I can keep &lt;em&gt;the number of executions&lt;/em&gt; down then that too will reduce my bill. Let's talk about how I'm doing that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;reducingexecutionsandloadtimewithcloudflarecache&quot;&gt;Reducing Executions and Load Time with Cloudflare Cache&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When data in Pwned Passwords is queried using the k-Anonymity model, the request looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;https://api.pwnedpasswords.com/range/21BD1&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last part of the path is the first 5 characters of the SHA-1 hash of the password being searched for which in this case, was &quot;P@ssw0rd&quot;. The response to that request is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; aggressively cached at Cloudflare's end such that in the last 24 hours, 47% of the requests have been served directly by their cache and never actually hit my Azure Function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Requests-Cached-by-Cloudflare.png&quot; alt=&quot;Requests Cached by Cloudflare&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually thought this number would be higher, steadily increasing as people did queries that gradually exhausted the 16^5 range for hash prefixes 00000 through FFFFF. Eventually, I theorised, there'd be 1,048,576 entries sitting in Cloudflare's cache, only refreshing themselves from the origin after they expired a month later. In practice, however, cache eviction logic turns out to be a little more nuanced than that and after many discussions with Junade at Cloudflare (he came up with the k-Anonymity model for Pwned Passwords), it seems that things are as well-optimised as they're going to get for the moment. That may change in the future, but for now I needed to look further for more optimisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(A quick tangential footnote on this: &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&quot;&gt;the password search page on HIBP&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; aggressively cached at Cloudflare. When I've had sudden, large influxes of traffic due to media coverage, only low single-digit percentages of it has hit my origin site then the search itself has gone to the Azure Function meaning almost no requests hitting the HIBP service even when things ramp right up.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tablestorageversusblobstorage&quot;&gt;Table Storage Versus Blob Storage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/working-with-154-million-records-on/&quot;&gt;a &lt;em&gt;massive&lt;/em&gt; proponent of Azure's Table Storage&lt;/a&gt; for years now. This is the construct that underlies all the breached email addresses that presently sit in HIBP and it's worked absolutely flawlessly. (Side note: we also use Azure Table Storage for all the reports in &lt;a href=&quot;https://report-uri.com/&quot;&gt;Report URI&lt;/a&gt;.) One of the observations I've long made about Table Storage is that it provides an alternate or even complementary storage model to the classic RDBMS approach. Over many years in a corporate environment, I'd constantly hear this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, we're building a web application so we'll be needing a SQL Server database&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, this was true, but more often than not it was a reflection of doing things the way they'd always been done as opposed to choosing the most optimal technology for the job. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/applied-azure-infographic-of-how-have-i/&quot;&gt;my post from a few years ago on the architecture of HIBP&lt;/a&gt;, I showed how I used both Table Storage and SQL Azure to compliment each other. I picked the best bits from both and even today, that's still precisely the same storage choice I'd make. But on reflecting about the decisions I made for Pwned Passwords V2, I found myself having fallen into that same trap of &quot;doing what I've always done&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what V2 of Pwned Passwords looks like in Table Storage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Table-storage-for-Pwned-Passwords.png&quot; alt=&quot;Table Storage for Pwned Passwords&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first 5 chars of the hash are the partition key, the remainder of the hash is the row key and then there's a count attribute (Azure adds in the Timestamp automatically). This made it very fast to look up by individual hash (just segment it into two parts and query by partition and row key), but also very easy to pull a complete hash range for the k-Anonymity model as I just dragged in the entire partition. When I analysed the function execution time, here's what I found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Table-Storage-Function-Speed-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Table Storage Function Speed&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very linear performance that barely changes with volume. Those 403k requests executed in an average of 122ms which is predominantly comprised of the function reaching out to table storage, grabbing the partition and deserialising it before returning it in the response. The execution time also had a pretty well-distributed range with 50% of them running in 100ms or lower:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Table-Storage-Function-Speed-Percentiles.png&quot; alt=&quot;Table Storage Function Speed Percentiles&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, I started thinking about it more: why am I using Table Storage? I mean why sit the data in a queryable construct when ultimately, that range search simply pulls back one of 1,048,576 different results &lt;em&gt;that don't change!&lt;/em&gt; Yes, they'll change when I release a V3, but I went 6 months between V1 and V2 and I don't expect anything to change again any time soon. Plus, when it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; change, it'll be a complete rollover in one go; I'll still have 1,048,576 different ranges just with, say, 750M hashes. Would it be faster if I just exported the data into 1,048,576 separate files, dropped them into &lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/services/storage/blobs/&quot;&gt;Blob Storage&lt;/a&gt; then pulled back the exact file I needed from the function? Kinda like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Data-in-Blob-Storage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Data in Blob Storage&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then the file has precisely the contents you get in the existing API response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Blob-Storage-Contents.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blob Storage Contents&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tl;dr - can I pull a pre-prepared file from a blob faster than I can pull a complete partition from a table? Actually, yes, a lot faster:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Blob-Storage-Function-Speed-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blob Storage Function Speed&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's just shaved 56% off the execution time! 122ms down to only 54.2ms. That's with no change to the publicly facing API and an identical response body returned. The distribution of those times is where it gets particularly interesting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Blob-Storage-Function-Speed-Percentiles-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blob Storage Function Speed Percentiles&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half of the queries now execute in 46ms or less! The interesting bit is that the distribution of execution times is a lot more erratic so the performance of this model isn't as consistent, but it's an awful lot faster. Still, look at that cluster of requests at only 10ms - wow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I can switch between the two back end repositories with a simple config setting so if I find, for example, that perf degrades on blob storage when larger volumes occur, I can always roll back in an instant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me touch on a couple of other really neat perf things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;argo&quot;&gt;Argo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know the internet is a collection of interconnected nodes with traffic bouncing around between them in order to carry your request to the origin server and then return you a response. But what's the most optimal route for the traffic? The shortest distance? Not necessarily because there's factors such as congestion and the reliability of particular nodes or connections to deal with. But typically, that's not something you really have control over, I mean in terms of deciding which route your traffic should take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in May last year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/argo/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare launched Argo&lt;/a&gt; which promised the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare’s Argo is able to deliver content across our network with dramatically reduced latency, increased reliability, heightened encryption, and reduced cost vs. an equivalent path across the open Internet. The results are impressive: &lt;strong&gt;an average 35% decrease in latency, a 27% decrease in connection errors, and a 60% decrease in cache misses&lt;/strong&gt;. Websites, APIs, and applications using Argo have seen bandwidth bills fall by more than half and speed improvements end users can feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture it like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/argo_animation.gif&quot; alt=&quot;argo_animation&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare can do this because they &quot;route more than 10% of all HTTP/HTTPS Internet traffic, providing Argo with real-time intelligence on the fastest network paths&quot;. Traffic routing in this fashion is only possible because they see such a significant portion of what's flying around the internet and can make intelligent decisions about how it should be routed. Let's look at what that actually looks like for Pwned Passwords:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Argo-Traffic-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Argo Traffic&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you see is that clearly, there's a massive improvement here; response times have been slashed by more than 60%. The next thing is you might start to wonder why even the 278ms figure is so high. What we're seeing here is Time To First Byte (TTFB) which is the delay between Cloudflare sending a request to the server and receiving the first byte in response. That figure therefore includes all the server processing time as well and whilst we know that's now only about 20% of the TTFB number, I've still got traffic traveling long distances. Remember, this is the time between one of those 122 Cloudflare edge nodes making a request and the Azure Function in Microsoft's West US data centre actually returning a response. Consider that in the context of the following map:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Argo-by-Geography-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Argo by Geography&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That biggest green dot is on Munich which is a 17,000km round trip away from Seattle. Longer distances, higher latency, greater volumes, more chance to improve things. Folks in Europe are picking up the biggest gains here whilst those on the west coast of the US are getting the smallest (but they're closer with lower latency in the first place).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;brotli&quot;&gt;Brotli&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's another great performance boost that's dead easy to enable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Brotli-Turned-On.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brotli-Turned-On&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brotli&quot;&gt;Brotli compression&lt;/a&gt; can work much more efficiently than gzip for certain content types. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/brotli-compression/&quot;&gt;Scott Helme found a 33% reduction for HTML&lt;/a&gt; when he wrote about it a couple of years back. So what does it look like for HIBP? Let's load the Pwned Passwords search page via Fiddler first with no &quot;br&quot; encoding then with brotli and we'll compare the results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/gzip.png&quot; alt=&quot;gzip&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/brotli.png&quot; alt=&quot;brotli&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not quite at the level Scott found, but it's still 8% off the response size by doing nothing more than toggling a switch. However, you might have noticed that this is the search page on HIBP rather than the API request itself; as of today, Cloudflare isn't applying brotli to &quot;text/plain&quot; content types. However, I'm told that in the very, &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; near future that'll be turned on so I decided to stick it into this post anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh - last thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://caniuse.com/#search=brotli&quot;&gt;brotli is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; well supported across modern browsers&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://caniuse.com/#search=brotli&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Brotli-support.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brotli-support&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what's not said in the image above is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://samsaffron.com/archive/2016/06/15/the-current-state-of-brotli-compression&quot;&gt;brotli is HTTPS only&lt;/a&gt; (do read that post from Sam Saffron on brotli, it has a heap of good info). As if you needed another good reason to roll over to secure communications...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;future&quot;&gt;Future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really happy with the basic philosophy of this whole thing: serve as much as possible from edge node cache, go as fast as possible across the network when the request needs to go to the origin then process that request as quickly as possible. On the one hand, that's all web performance 101 but on the other hand, it's not always that readily achievable, especially at both scale and price points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's certainly more opportunity for improvement though, for example by distributing the data and API endpoints in a more globally-accessible fashion. Putting another Azure Function in Europe with another copy of the data in Blob Storage wouldn't be hard or expensive. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-traffic-manager-the-details/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare traffic manager&lt;/a&gt; could help geo-steer requests and folks in places like Europe could realise performance gains on requests that go all the way to the origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another idea I'm toying with is to use the Cloudflare Workers John mentioned earlier to plug directly into Blob Storage. Content there can be accessed easily enough over HTTP (that's where you download the full 500M Pwned Password list from) and it could take out that Azure Function layer altogether. That's something I'll investigate further a little later on as it has to potential to bring cost down further whilst pumping up performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately though, it's all a work in progress and I'm enormously happy with the adoption and performance of the service so far. My intention is to keep working on that speed component so it's as efficient as possible for those who want to use it and hopefully, it actually makes a difference to the security posture of individuals and companies alike.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 09:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pstadler</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>I Wanna Go Fast: Why Searching Through 500M Pwned Passwords Is So Quick</og:title>
<og:description>In the immortal words of Ricky Bobby, I wanna go fast. When I launched Pwned Passwords V2 last week, I made it fast - real fast - and I want to talk briefly here about why that was important, how I did it and then how I've since shaved another</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.troyhunt.com/i-wanna-go-fast-why-searching-through-500m-pwned-passwords-is-so-quick/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2018/02/Blob-Storage-Function-Speed-5.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.troyhunt.com/i-wanna-go-fast-why-searching-through-500m-pwned-passwords-is-so-quick/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>