<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>PhantomJS: Archiving the project, suspending development</title>
<link>https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/15344</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/15344</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Due to the lack of active contribution, I am going to &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/about-archiving-repositories/&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; this project soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point in the future, if we pick up the development again (such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/15341&quot; class=&quot;issue-link js-issue-link&quot; data-error-text=&quot;Failed to load issue title&quot; data-id=&quot;302012466&quot; data-permission-text=&quot;Issue title is private&quot; data-url=&quot;https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/15341&quot;&gt;#15341&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/15342&quot; class=&quot;issue-link js-issue-link&quot; data-error-text=&quot;Failed to load issue title&quot; data-id=&quot;302013289&quot; data-permission-text=&quot;Issue title is private&quot; data-url=&quot;https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/15342&quot;&gt;#15342&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/15343&quot; class=&quot;issue-link js-issue-link&quot; data-error-text=&quot;Failed to load issue title&quot; data-id=&quot;302013575&quot; data-permission-text=&quot;Issue title is private&quot; data-url=&quot;https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/15343&quot;&gt;#15343&lt;/a&gt;), the project will be unarchived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, all the earlier plans regarding PhantomJS 2.5 (from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vitallium&quot; class=&quot;user-mention&quot;&gt;@Vitallium&lt;/a&gt;) or 2.1.x (from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pixiupl&quot; class=&quot;user-mention&quot;&gt;@pixiuPL&lt;/a&gt;) will be &lt;strong&gt;abandoned&lt;/strong&gt; effective immediately. Consequently, the source and binary packages for the above abandoned version will be removed to avoid any confusions. PhantomJS version &lt;strong&gt;2.1.1&lt;/strong&gt; will remain the last known stable release until further notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep the source repository in a sane situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the master branch will be preserved under the new &lt;code&gt;bleeding-edge&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;after that, the master branch will be restored back to the approximate state of v2.1.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That way, if anyone wants to improve PhantomJS for their own usages (internal fork, in-house patches), the master branch can still serve as a good baseline. It can still be built from source and it will still work on macOS, Linux, and Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the project is archived, no new issue can be filed. However, feel free to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/phantomjs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;mailing-list&lt;/a&gt; to post questions and discuss any relevant topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your understanding!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 21:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gowan</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/7288?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>Archiving the project: suspending the development · Issue #15344 · ariya/phantomjs</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/15344</og:url>
<og:description>Due to the lack of active contribution, I am going to archive this project soon. At some point in the future, if we pick up the development again (such as #15341, #15342, #15343), the project will ...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/15344</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Project Gutenberg blocks access from Germany</title>
<link>https://cand.pglaf.org/germany/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cand.pglaf.org/germany/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Court Order to Block Access in Germany&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/pglaf.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;264.96034816248&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page provides information about a lawsuit which was brought against the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pglaf.org/&quot;&gt;Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation&lt;/a&gt; (PGLAF, the organization that operates Project Gutenberg) and its Director &amp;amp; CEO, Greg Newby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Basics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;On December 30, 2015, PGLAF received notification that a lawsuit had been filed in Germany against it, and its CEO. The lawsuit was concerned with 18 eBooks, by three authors, which are part of the Project Gutenberg collection.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The lawsuit was filed in the Frankfurt am Main Regional Court.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Plaintiff is S. Fischer Verlag, GmbH. Hedderichstrasse 114, 60956 Frankfurt am Main, Germany. They are represented by the law firm, Waldorf Frommer of Munich.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The essence of the lawsuit is that the Plaintiff wants the 18 eBooks to no longer be accessible, at least from Germany. It also seeks punitive damages and fines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on legal advice from its US attorneys, PGLAF declined to remove or block the items. The lawsuit proceeded, with a series of document filings by both sides, and hearings before the judges (all of which occurred in German, in the German court). PGLAF hired a German law firm, Wilde Beuger Solmecke, in Köln, to represent it in Germany.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On February 9 2018, the Court issued a judgement granting essentially all of the Plaintiff's demands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PGLAF complied with the Court's order on February 28, 2018 by blocking all access to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gutenberg.org&quot;&gt;www.gutenberg.org&lt;/a&gt; and sub-pages to all of Germany.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Discussion in the form of Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: What is Project Gutenberg's basic approach to international copyright issues?&lt;br /&gt;A: Please see our &lt;a href=&quot;https://cand.pglaf.org/index.html&quot;&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt;, which is based on decades of legal guidance and was verified as being correct by our US lawyers. Further items below build on those notions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Why didn't Project Gutenberg simply remove the items?&lt;br /&gt;A: The is no reason to remove them. The 18 eBooks are all in the public domain in the US, and have been for many years. Copyright status in another country is not relevant to the legitimate ability of Project Gutenberg -- or anyone/anything in the US -- to make any use of these books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Why didn't Project Gutenberg block access until the Court made its judgement?&lt;br /&gt;A: PGLAF's legal advisors disagree that any foreign Court or entity has jurisdiction over its actions regarding copyright. The Court in Germany has promoted a theory that it has jurisdition, mainly because the www.gutenberg.org site has some content in the German language. The view of PGLAF is that it is up to the rights owner in Germany to identify people there who are infringing on its copyrights, and pursue remediation there. It is not up to PGLAF to police or defend the rights of entities in different countries. Because PGLAF is a legitimate non-profit organization, however, it is appropriate to act as the German Court ordered - pending appeal - even though it disagrees with the order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: So the court thinks that the presence of content in German means that courts in Germany have jurisdiction, regardless of the fact that PGLAF is entirely in the US?&lt;br /&gt;A: Yes, that was the original basis of the claim for jurisdiction, which the Court accepted in their judgement. Since then, there some more recent decisions in the European Court of Justice, and other German courts, that support this theory based on a Web site being accessible from a country. Those other cases involve companies that actually operate (for-profit) in Europe, and cases between two European countries (i.e. part of the EU). They are not consistent with prior laws and cases, even in Europe, and also not consistent with provisions of the Berne Convention and other international law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, PGLAF has pointed out that Germany is widely spoken in the US (the third-most common second language), and also is widely taught in schools and colleges. PGLAF has no actual presence or activity in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Who are the authors? Why are they copyrighted in Germany, but not the the US?&lt;br /&gt;A:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Heinrich Mann, who died in 1950.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thomas Mann, who died in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alfred Döblin, who died in 1957.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Germany, they are copyrighted based on &quot;life +70 years&quot; of copyright protection (so, copyright will expire after 2020, 2025 and 2027, respectively). In the US, copyright protection is based on the number of years since publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: What are these 18 books, when were they originally published, and when did Project Gutenberg add them to its collection?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heinrich Mann. 6 titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Flöten und Dolche: Novellen&lt;/u&gt; by Heinrich Mann. Originally published 1905. Entered the public domain in the US: 1961 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on February 8, 2010 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/31218&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/31218&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Flaubert und die Herkunft des modernen Romans&lt;/u&gt; by Heinrich Mann. Originally published 1917. Entered the public domain in the US: 1973 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on August 2, 2010 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/33328&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/33328&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Der Vater&lt;/u&gt; by Heinrich Mann. Originally published 1917. Entered the public domain in the US: 1973 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on August 2, 2010 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/33329&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/33329&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Professor Unrat, oder, Das Ende eines Tyrannen&lt;/u&gt; by Heinrich Mann. Originally published 1906. Entered the public domain in the US: 1962 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on February 13, 2011 &lt;a href=&quot;-&amp;quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/35264&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/35264&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Der Untertan&lt;/u&gt; by Heinrich Mann. Originally published 1918. Entered the public domain in the US: 1974 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on November 24, 2011. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/38126&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/38126&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Die Ehrgeizige: Novelle&lt;/u&gt; by Heinrich Mann. Originally published 1920. Entered the public domain in the US: 1976 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on July 28, 2013 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/43335&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/43335&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thomas Mann. 7 titles, 8 Gutenberg eBooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Gladius Dei; Schwere Stunde&lt;/u&gt; by Thomas Mann. Originally published 1903. Entered the public domain in the US: 1959 (publication + 56) Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on April 15, 2004 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/12053&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/12053&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Der Tod in Venedig&lt;/u&gt; by Thomas Mann. Originally published 1912. Entered the public domain in the US: 1968 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on April 22, 2004 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/12108&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/12108&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Tristan&lt;/u&gt; by Thomas Mann. Originally published 1903. Entered the public domain in the US: 1959 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on October 20, 2004 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/13810&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/13810&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Tonio Kröger&lt;/u&gt; by Thomas Mann. Originally published 1903. Entered the public domain in the US: 1959 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on November 6, 2007 and January 27, 2012. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/23313&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/23313&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/38692&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/38692&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Buddenbrooks: Verfall einer Familie&lt;/u&gt; by Thomas Mann. Originally published 1901. Entered the public domain in the US: 1957 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on January 1, 2011. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/34811&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/34811&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Königliche Hoheit: Roman&lt;/u&gt; by Thomas Mann. Originally published 1901. Entered the public domain in the US: 1965 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on March 6, 2012 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/35328&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/35328&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Der kleine Herr Friedemann: Novellen&lt;/u&gt; by Thomas Mann. Originally published 1897. Entered the public domain in the US: 1953 (publication + 56) Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on July 17, 2011 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/36766&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/36766&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alfred Döblin. 5 titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Die Ermordung einer Butterblume und andere Erzählungen&lt;/u&gt; by Alfred Döblin. Originally published 1913. Entered the public domain in the US: 1969 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on March 16, 2010 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/31660&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/31660&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Die Lobensteiner reisen nach Böhmen: Zwölf Novellen und Geschichten&lt;/u&gt; by Alfred Döblin. Originally published 1917. Entered the public domain in the US: 1973 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg July 20, 2011 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/36779&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/36779&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Wallenstein. 1 (of 2)&lt;/u&gt; by Alfred Döblin. Originally published 1920. Entered the public domain in the US: 1976 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on October 11, 2013 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/43931&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/43931&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Wallenstein. 2 (of 2)&lt;/u&gt; by Alfred Döblin. Originally published 1920. Entered the public domain in the US: 1976 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on October 11, 2013 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/43932&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/43932&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Die drei Sprünge des Wang-lun: Chinesischer Roman&lt;/u&gt; by Alfred Döblin. Originally published 1916. Entered the public domain in the US: 1972 (publication + 56). Digitized and published by Project Gutenberg on October 21, 2013. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/43987&quot;&gt;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/43987&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Q: The Project Gutenberg terms of use, and header, and license, say that people outside of the US should check the laws in their country before downloading. Isn't that enough to be operating legally?&lt;br /&gt;A: PGLAF received legal advice from our US lawyers that it is enough, and this was reconfirmed as part of the current German lawsuit. The header and other legalese has been updated over the years, ever since the first version of the Project Gutenberg License in 1993, to reflect changes in the legal landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: How many times were they downloaded in Germany?&lt;br /&gt;A: That is unknown. The Court ordered on February 9 2018 that download records for the 18 items be provided (i.e., Web server logs), but PGLAF had alraedy informed the Court that no such records exist. Like many libraries, especially since introduction of the US PATRIOT act in 2001, PG does not retain Web logs or any other access/download statistics that might identify individual users or IP addresses. This is to protect reader's privacy, in the event of seizure of log files. PG retains logs just for a few months, for diagnosis of problems and producing summary statistics. The summary statistics do not identify user IP addresses or geographic location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: If they were downloaded in Germany, was that definitely a violation of copyright?&lt;br /&gt;A: Under US law, this depends on the circumstances of the downloader. We do not have detailed knowledge of German laws on this matter, but will be seeking more information as part of the case for appeal. In the US, and many other countries, there are a variety of situations where people may legitimately and legally make use of digital copies of books. Fair use (or fair dealing) is one example, as are some types of educational use, use by people with visual impairments, use for reviews/quotes, and some types of research. It also may be that someone in Germany who owns a printed copy, or a duly licensed eBook, could also utilize the same eBook via Project Gutenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are examples where accessing the eBook at Project Gutenberg from Germany might not be a violation of any applicable copyrights in Germany, but our German lawyers said that the presence or absence of actual infringement was not material to the Plaintiff's case, nor to the Court's jurisdiction. From the Court's proceedings, there is no evidence that anyone in Germany ever downloaded any of the 18 items (other than Plaintiff), regardless of whether or not it would have been a violation of German copyrights to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: The judgement devotes around half of its pages to the Plaintiff's assertation that they own the copyrights. Why is that an issue, and is it settled?&lt;br /&gt;A: Plaintiff has not provided sufficient documentation to support their claim that they are the exclusive owner or licensee of copyrights for the 18 items. In fact, some of the licensing agreements presented to the Court were signed after the lawsuit was filed! The Court allowed multiple iterations by the Plaintiff to try to improve on the insufficient documentation, including hearings, to prove they were actually a rights-holder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irregularities and gaps remain, and will be revisited during the appeal. There are at least two major concerns. One is that the original printed books were published between 1897 and 1920, sometimes by other companies that were subsequently acquired by Plaintiff. Plaintiffs have never produced evidence of continuous ownership of the rights, to those original printed books that Project Gutenberg digitized. Or, that the &quot;community of heirs&quot; (the English translation referring to the family of the authors) duly inherited the rights, and can thereby assign them to the Plaintiff. The Court did not require demonstration of rights at the outset of the lawsuit, and PGLAF is not convinced that Plaintiff actually has rights to any of the 18 items, including rights for eBooks (as opposed to printed books).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second major concern is that the Project Gutenberg eBooks were, for some of the 18 items, published by Project Gutenberg prior to the rights contracts that Plaintiff presented. And, in any event, all were published by PG long after those items had lost copyright protection in the US, and therefore rights were owned in the US by the American people (i.e., that is the definition of &quot;public domain&quot;). This calls into question claims of &quot;worldwide&quot; rights, which Plaintiff seems to rely on for asserting control over PGLAF's activities in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: What does the judgement say must be done? Are there fines or penalties?&lt;br /&gt;A: The full judgement (original German, and translated into English) are linked above. Basically, the Court granted all of the Plaintiff's demands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remove the 18 books, or at least make sure they are not available from Germany. PGLAF complied by blocking access to www.gutenberg.org for all of Germany.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a listing of all the downloads that have occurred for the 18 items, so that licensing fees or other fines may be assessed. PGLAF has already told the Court that no such records exist, because Web server logs are only maintained for approximately 2 months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay Court costs, assessed at 50% of total costs. The amount is not yet known.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Q: Why block all of Germany, rather than just those 18 books?&lt;br /&gt;A: PGLAF's legal advisors disagree with all claims that there must be any blocking, or removal, or anything associated - censorship, fines/fees, disclaimers, etc. - for items that are in the public domain in the US. Period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the German Court has overstepped its jurisdiction, and allowed the world's largest publishing group to bully Project Gutenberg for these 18 books, there is every reason to think that this will keep happening. There are thousands of eBooks in the Project Gutenberg collection that could be subject to similar over-reaching and illigitimate actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PGLAF is a small volunteer organization, with no income (it doesn't sell anything), other than donations. There is every reason to fear that this huge corporation, with the backing of the German Court, will continue to take legal action. In fact, at least one other similar complaint arrived in 2017 about different books in the Project Gutenberg collection, from another company in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Gutenberg's focus is to make as much of the world's literature available as possible, to as many people as possible. But it is, and always has been, entirely US-based, and entirely operating within the copyright laws of the US. Blocking Germany, in an effort to forestall further legal actions, seems the best way to protect the organization and retain focus on its mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: The plaintiff is S. Fischer Verlag, GmbH. Is that the international conglomerate?&lt;br /&gt;A: Yes, it is part of a family of companies all under single ownership and control or majority stakeholdership, from Germany, reaching around the world. S. Fischer Verlag, GmbH is a unit of Verlagsgruppe Georg Holtzbrinck GmbH. Internationally it is known in the US and elsewhere as Holtzbrinck Publishers LLC. Readers in the US know this as Macmillan, which is one of the largest publishers in the US by revenue, and owns many familiar imprints. US readers might also recall that Macmillan was one of four companies accused by the US Dept. of Justice in 2012 of price fixing. The companies eventually settled the antitrust claims, including by giving credits to customers who had overpaid for eBooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Why did this all take place in the German Court system, rather than the US - where Plaintiff does business as Macmillan, and PGLAF is based?&lt;br /&gt;A: The legal guidance PGLAF received is that US law requires that such proceedings would have taken place in the US, and in fact any attempts at enforcement of the judgement would need to occur in the US Court system. PGLAF already informed Plaintiff and the German Court that the US Court system is the appropriate venue for Plaintiff's concerns. Plaintiff declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, international treaties - notably the Berne Convention and related treaties - provide mediation processes through the World Intellectual Property Organization. PGLAF offered to undergo this mediation process, and Plaintiff declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International treaties explicitly and unambiguously support PGLAF's legal guidance as described above: that the copyright status in one country is not impacted or enforceable or otherwise relevant in other countries. Plaintiff managed to find a German Court, and some precedents from Germany (and, after the lawsuit was filed, from the EU), which were willing to flaunt international treaties by developing a theory that PGLAF is under jurisdiction of the German Court system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision to acceed to the German Court's order to make items inaccessible from Germany is intended to be a temporary appeasement, while the appeal occurs - this is because the German appeal Court will likely look disfavorably on PGLAF if it shows contempt for the German Court. Ultimately, PGLAF seeks to establish that any complaints about copyright must be brought either to the US Courts (where PGLAF operates) or WIPO processes (as guided by international treaties).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Is there anything that can be done about the situation?&lt;br /&gt;A: Project Gutenberg is fighting for an appeal. Ideas about how to appeal the case in German, and any possible legal actions in the US, are welcome. You can reach Dr. Newby by email, gbnewby AT pglaf.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: I would like to make a donation, to help Project Gutenberg with legal expenses&lt;br /&gt;A: Donations are gratefully accepted! More information at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gutenberg.org/donate&quot;&gt;www.gutenberg.org/donate&lt;/a&gt;. One quick method is to make a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com&quot;&gt;Paypal&lt;/a&gt; donation to donate2018@pglaf.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p font=&quot;red&quot;&gt;More information may be added in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most recently updated: March 3, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 19:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jwildeboer</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cand.pglaf.org/germany/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Waymo released a 360-degree VR representation of what its robocar sees</title>
<link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/cars-that-think/transportation/self-driving/watch-waymos-carseye-virtualreality-view-of-the-world</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://spectrum.ieee.org/cars-that-think/transportation/self-driving/watch-waymos-carseye-virtualreality-view-of-the-world</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzAyNDQzMQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Graphic of intersection with hazards labeled.&quot;/&gt; Image: Waymo
&lt;section id=&quot;side-module&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;medium-top-ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-module&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;recommended-side&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor’s Picks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;article-rec&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/Mjg4MzQzNQ.jpg&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; alt=&quot;illustration of car&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Car Battery's Carbon Footprint&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzAxMjcyNw.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration of cars with company logos on them, driving on a test track.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Silicon Valley’s Secret Test Track for Self-Driving Cars&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzAwNDIyOQ.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; alt=&quot;The view inside a Phantom car shows a hands free passenger in the driver's seat, as well as a special display showing the remote driver of the car.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;CES 2018: Phantom Auto Demonstrates First Remote-Controlled Car on Public Roads&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Waymo, the robocar subsidiary of Alphabet, seems to be painting the walls and putting an apple pie in the oven before showing off its house to prospective buyers or partners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I say that because the formerly rather secretive company had to put a lot of work into making this theater-in-the-round version of what its self-driving Chrysler Pacificas see as they motor around the metro area surrounding Phoenix, Ariz. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use your mouse to drag the video through its 360 degrees of glory, but you’d be better off using a VR viewer or the YouTube app on your phone (while spinning yourself on a swivel chair).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;349&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/B8R148hFxPw&quot; width=&quot;620&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a simplified, even a dumbed-down, vision of what the car gets from its many different sensors. That includes such unrepresentable things as the absolute (rather than merely the relative) distance to objects; the presence of metallic components; the speed at which objects approach or pull away; and their precise location on a map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most human part of the exercise comes at the end of the video, when you get a sense of what it’s like to sit in the back seat—with no one sitting in the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some time, that’s been street-legal in Phoenix, an easy-peasey regulatory environment. Now, after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/26/technology/driverless-cars-california-rules.html&quot;&gt;yesterday’s announcement&lt;/a&gt; by California’s Department of Motor Vehicles, it’ll even be allowed by the toughest regulators. Any of the 50-odd companies on California’s robocar approval list will be able to dispatch experimental vehicles on public roads without having safety driver inside, beginning on 2 April. The only proviso is that the company be able to take over control of the car remotely, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/cars-that-think/transportation/self-driving/ces-2018-phantom-auto-demonstrates-first-remotecontrolled-car-on-public-roads&quot;&gt;technology that is now emerging&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 18:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>NicoJuicy</dc:creator>
<og:title>Watch Waymo's Virtual-Reality View of the World</og:title>
<og:url>https://spectrum.ieee.org/cars-that-think/transportation/self-driving/watch-waymos-carseye-virtualreality-view-of-the-world</og:url>
<og:description>The company released a 360-degree VR representation of what its robocar sees</og:description>
<og:image>https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzAyNDQ1OA.jpeg</og:image>
<og:type>blog-cars-that-think</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://spectrum.ieee.org/cars-that-think/transportation/self-driving/watch-waymos-carseye-virtualreality-view-of-the-world</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What We Found When X-Raying Some MLB Baseballs</title>
<link>https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/juiced-baseballs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/juiced-baseballs/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;O&lt;/span&gt;n 6,105 occasions last season, a major leaguer walked to the plate and hammered a baseball over the outfield wall. The 2017 season broke the home run record that was set in 2000 — the peak of the steroid era — when players hit 5,693 homers, and it built upon the remarkable 5,610 that were hit in 2016. It was a stunning display of power that played out in every MLB park almost every night. And with spring training underway in Florida and Arizona, MLB’s power surge is &lt;a href=&quot;http://mlb.mlb.com/stats/sortable.jsp#season=2018&amp;amp;elem=%5Bobject+Object%5D&amp;amp;tab_level=child&amp;amp;click_text=Sortable+Team+hitting&amp;amp;game_type='S'&amp;amp;season_type=ANY&amp;amp;league_code='MLB'&amp;amp;sectionType=st&amp;amp;statType=hitting&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;ts=1519855102844&amp;amp;playerType=QUALIFIER&amp;amp;sportCode='mlb'&amp;amp;split=&amp;amp;team_id=&amp;amp;active_sw=&amp;amp;position=&amp;amp;page_type=SortablePlayer&amp;amp;sortOrder='desc'&amp;amp;sortColumn=avg&amp;amp;results=&amp;amp;perPage=50&amp;amp;timeframe=&amp;amp;last_x_days=&amp;amp;extended=0&quot;&gt;showing no sign of letting up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But while we now know &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/mlb/topics/_/page/the-steroids-era&quot;&gt;what caused the spike&lt;/a&gt; in home runs at the turn of the century — even if we didn’t at the time — the reason for the most recent flurry of long balls remains an unsolved mystery. Any number of factors might have contributed to the home run surge, including bigger, stronger players or a new emphasis on hitting fly balls. But none of those possibilities looms larger than the ball itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MLB and its commissioner, Rob Manfred, have repeatedly denied rumors that the ball has been altered in any way — or “juiced” — to generate more homers. But a large and growing body of research shows that, beginning in the middle of the 2015 season, the MLB baseball began to fly further. And new research commissioned by “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/espn/sportscience/index&quot;&gt;ESPN Sport Science&lt;/a&gt;,” a show that breaks down the science of sports,&lt;a class=&quot;espn-footnote-link&quot; data-footnote-id=&quot;1&quot; href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/juiced-baseballs/#fn-1&quot; data-footnote-content=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;ESPN owns FiveThirtyEight.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;ss-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; suggests that MLB baseballs used after the 2015 All-Star Game were subtly but consistently different than older baseballs. The research, performed by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://keck.usc.edu/&quot;&gt;Keck School of Medicine&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Southern California and Kent State University’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kent.edu/chemistry&quot;&gt;Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry&lt;/a&gt;, reveals changes in the density and chemical composition of the baseball’s core — and provides our first glimpse &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; the newer baseballs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking inside the balls and testing their chemical composition revealed that the cores of recent balls were somewhat less dense than the cores of balls used before the 2015 All-Star Game. The newer cores weigh about a half a gram less than the older ones, which might be enough to cause baseballs hit on a typical home run trajectory to fly about 6 inches farther. That alone is hardly enough to explain the home run surge of recent seasons, but when combined with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/2017/6/14/16044264/2017-mlb-home-run-spike-juiced-ball-testing-reveal-155cd21108bc&quot;&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/in-mlbs-new-home-run-era-its-the-baseballs-that-are-juicing/&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fangraphs.com/tht/fly-ball-carry-and-the-home-run-surge/&quot;&gt;finding&lt;/a&gt; that baseballs began to change in other small ways starting around the same time, it suggests that a number of minor differences may have combined to contribute to the remarkable upswing in home run power we’ve witnessed since 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked about these findings, MLB noted that it had commissioned a group of scientists and statisticians to investigate any changes to the ball, and that the committee would issue a report on its research soon. According to Alan Nathan, one of the physicists on the commission, the task force found that all the characteristics that MLB regularly measures, including the weight, circumference, seam height and bounciness of the ball, were within ranges that meant variations in the baseballs were unlikely to significantly affect home run rates. MLB declined to provide the data supporting these assertions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Independent investigations &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/are-juiced-balls-the-new-steroids/&quot;&gt;by&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/in-mlbs-new-home-run-era-its-the-baseballs-that-are-juicing/&quot;&gt;FiveThirtyEight&lt;/a&gt;, publications like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/2017/6/14/16044264/2017-mlb-home-run-spike-juiced-ball-testing-reveal-155cd21108bc&quot;&gt;The Ringer&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fangraphs.com/tht/fly-ball-carry-and-the-home-run-surge/&quot;&gt;Nathan himself&lt;/a&gt; have shown differences in the characteristics of the ball and the way it performs. Research has shown that balls used in games after the 2015 All-Star Game were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/2017/6/14/16044264/2017-mlb-home-run-spike-juiced-ball-testing-reveal-155cd21108bc&quot;&gt;bouncier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/in-mlbs-new-home-run-era-its-the-baseballs-that-are-juicing/&quot;&gt;less air resistant&lt;/a&gt; compared with baseballs from the 2014 season, when players hit a relatively modest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fangraphs.com/leaders.aspx?pos=all&amp;amp;stats=bat&amp;amp;lg=all&amp;amp;qual=0&amp;amp;type=8&amp;amp;season=2014&amp;amp;month=0&amp;amp;season1=2014&amp;amp;ind=0&amp;amp;team=0,ss&amp;amp;rost=0&amp;amp;age=0&amp;amp;filter=&amp;amp;players=0&quot;&gt;4,186 homers&lt;/a&gt;, the fewest since 1995. (Nathan noted that MLB does not regularly measure air resistance.) Taken together, these changes would result in a ball that would come off the bat at a higher speed and carry farther. While investigations have been able to show that the baseball &lt;em&gt;behaves&lt;/em&gt; differently in recent years, no one had looked inside the ball to see if there was evidence of changes to the way the baseball is constructed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;juiced-container&quot; class=&quot;juiced-container&quot;&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;juiced-video-container&quot; class=&quot;juiced-video-container&quot;/&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;juiced-text&quot; class=&quot;juiced-text&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;So far, these investigations have primarily looked at the &lt;em&gt;exterior&lt;/em&gt; of the baseball.&lt;img class=&quot;juiced-mobile-image&quot; src=&quot;https://espnfivethirtyeight.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/mobileinfo-01.png?w=575&amp;amp;quality=90&amp;amp;strip=info&quot; alt=&quot;Unassuming photo of a baseball&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;Broadly, MLB baseballs — which are produced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-costarica-baseballs/made-in-costa-rica-u-s-major-league-baseballs-idUSTRE62831Z20100309&quot;&gt;by Rawlings in Costa Rica&lt;/a&gt; — are made of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.madehow.com/Volume-1/Baseball.html&quot;&gt;three components&lt;/a&gt;: an exterior shell of cowhide, a winding of several layers of yarn, and a core of rubber-coated cork, also known as a “pill.”&lt;img class=&quot;juiced-mobile-image&quot; src=&quot;https://espnfivethirtyeight.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/mobileinfo-02.png?w=575&amp;amp;quality=90&amp;amp;strip=info&quot; alt=&quot;Cross section of a baseball&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;To analyze possible changes to the &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; of the ball, particularly the core, “ESPN Sport Science” purchased one new ball from Rawlings and seven game-used baseballs from eBay, confirming their authenticity through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mlb.com/authentication&quot;&gt;MLB’s authenticator program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a class=&quot;espn-footnote-link&quot; data-footnote-id=&quot;2&quot; href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/juiced-baseballs/#fn-2&quot; data-footnote-content=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Contractors working for MLB affix a tamper-resistant hologram sticker to balls that they personally witness being used in the game. The sticker includes a serial number that can be entered into the MLB authenticator program to confirm that the ball is real and to find out which game it was used in.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;ss-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;The eight baseballs we tested were split into two groups: an “old group” of four balls used in games played between August 2014 and May 2015, and a “new group” of three balls used in games played between August 2016 and July 2017, plus the brand-new ball. The aim was to see if the internal composition of the baseballs had changed in ways that would affect the ball’s performance.&lt;a class=&quot;espn-footnote-link&quot; data-footnote-id=&quot;3&quot; href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/juiced-baseballs/#fn-3&quot; data-footnote-content=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This sample is admittedly small, but according to the Kent State scientists we worked with, it’s sufficient to determine statistical significance in the two groups.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;ss-3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;The balls were first analyzed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://keck.usc.edu/faculty/eu-meng-law/&quot;&gt;Dr. Meng Law&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://keck.usc.edu/faculty/jay-acharya/&quot;&gt;Dr. Jay Acharya&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://keck.usc.edu/faculty/darryl-hwa-hwang/&quot;&gt;Darryl Hwang&lt;/a&gt; at the Keck School of Medicine at USC using a computerized tomography, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emedicinehealth.com/ct_scan/article_em.htm&quot;&gt;CT&lt;/a&gt;, scan. This test is typically used to look inside a human head or body, but in this case, it allowed Dr. Law’s team to examine the interior of the baseballs without cracking them open and destroying them.&lt;img class=&quot;juiced-mobile-image&quot; src=&quot;https://espnfivethirtyeight.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/mobileinfo-03.png?w=575&amp;amp;quality=90&amp;amp;strip=info&quot; alt=&quot;CT scans of four baseballs from 2014 -- 2015 and four from 2016 -- 2017&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;Initial CT imaging showed that baseballs in the same group had a negligible variation in internal properties.&lt;img class=&quot;juiced-mobile-image&quot; src=&quot;https://espnfivethirtyeight.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/mobileinfo-04.png?w=575&amp;amp;quality=90&amp;amp;strip=info&quot; alt=&quot;Closer look at 2014 -- 2015 baseball CT scans&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;When comparing the new and old groups, however, there was a clear difference in the density of the core.&lt;img class=&quot;juiced-mobile-image&quot; src=&quot;https://espnfivethirtyeight.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/mobileinfo-05.png?w=575&amp;amp;quality=90&amp;amp;strip=info&quot; alt=&quot;Comparison of CT scans from a 2014 -- 2015 baseball to its 2016 -- 2017 counterpart&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;In an MLB baseball, the core consists of four parts: a cork pellet at the center, surrounded by a layer of black rubber held together by a rubber ring where the halves meet, all of which is then molded together in a layer of pink rubber.&lt;img class=&quot;juiced-mobile-image&quot; src=&quot;https://espnfivethirtyeight.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/mobileinfo-061.png?w=575&amp;amp;quality=90&amp;amp;strip=info&quot; alt=&quot;Labels on a cross section of the CT scan&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;Dr. Law’s team isolated the density difference to the outer (pink) layer of the core, which was, on average, about 40 percent less dense in the new group of balls.&lt;img class=&quot;juiced-mobile-image&quot; src=&quot;https://espnfivethirtyeight.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/mobileinfo-07.png?w=575&amp;amp;quality=90&amp;amp;strip=info&quot; alt=&quot;Scale showing the density of 2014 -- 2015 baseball CT scans vs. 2016 -- 2017 scans, where the newer ball is less dense&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;While other parts of the ball showed slight differences in density and volume, none were as noteworthy as the changes to the core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not just that the inside of the ball looks different — the chemical composition of the cores appears to have changed as well. After being tested at the Keck School, the same set of balls were sent to Kent State University. There, researchers at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kent.edu/chemistry/profile/soumitra-basu&quot;&gt;Soumitra Basu’s&lt;/a&gt; lab in the Chemistry and Biochemistry department cut open the balls to examine the cores using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermogravimetric_analysis&quot;&gt;thermogravimetric analysis&lt;/a&gt; (TGA). This test essentially cooks a material to see which parts parts of it vaporize at which temperatures. Using that information, researchers can create a molecular profile of a given material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This test showed that the pink layer of the core in baseballs from the new group was, on average, composed of about 7 percent more polymer than the same area in baseballs from the old group. Additionally, an analysis with a scanning electron microscope showed that the same layer in the new balls contained, on average, 10 percent less silicon, relative to the amount of other ingredients in the pill. According to the Kent State researchers, these chemical changes produced a more porous, less dense layer of rubber — which explains the results seen in the CT scan at the Keck School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may not seem obvious, but these slight changes in the chemical composition of the core could have an impact on how the balls played once they were sewn up and shipped to major league teams. Less dense cores could mean lighter baseballs. The cores of the new balls weighed, on average, about 0.5 grams less than the cores from the old group. This difference was statistically significant, which means it’s highly unlikely that it was due to sampling error. The &lt;em&gt;overall&lt;/em&gt; weight of the balls also dropped by an average of about a 0.5 grams between groups, but, unlike with the cores, this difference was not statistically significant.&lt;a class=&quot;espn-footnote-link&quot; data-footnote-id=&quot;4&quot; href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/juiced-baseballs/#fn-4&quot; data-footnote-content=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The ball as a whole weighs much more than the core alone, and there was more variation in the weight of the full baseballs than in the weight of the cores, both of which meant that the bar for statistically significant variations in weight was higher for the whole baseball than for just the core.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;ss-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half a gram isn’t much — it’s only about the weight of a paperclip. A tiny change like this might add only about 6 inches to flight of a baseball hit on a typical home run trajectory, according to Nathan’s calculations. But the timing of these changes to the weight and density of the core coincides with a much larger boost to the bounciness of the baseball. According to a previous analysis performed by The Ringer, that increase in bounciness alone would add &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/2017/6/14/16044264/2017-mlb-home-run-spike-juiced-ball-testing-reveal-155cd21108bc&quot;&gt;around 0.6 mph&lt;/a&gt; to the speed of the ball as it leaves the bat and add roughly 3 feet to the travel distance of a fly ball — enough to make the difference between the warning track and the stands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the fact that the balls became bouncier as the core itself changed, previous research at FiveThirtyEight showed that they also &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/in-mlbs-new-home-run-era-its-the-baseballs-that-are-juicing/&quot;&gt;became less air resistant&lt;/a&gt;. The decrease in drag is probably a result of a smaller, slicker baseball with lower seams. The change in air resistance could add an additional 5 feet to the travel distance of a fly ball. Combine all these factors together — a lighter, more compact baseball with tighter seams and more bounce — and the ball could fly as much as 8.6 feet farther. According to Nathan’s calculations, this would lead to a more than 25 percent increase in the number of home runs. Asked whether these changes in combination could have significantly affected the home run rate, MLB declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In actuality, home runs spiked by about 46 percent between 2014 and 2017, which means that the changes to the ball could account for more than half of the increase. The remainder could be reasonably chalked up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/the-fly-ball-revolution-is-hurting-as-many-batters-as-its-helped/&quot;&gt;a philosophical shift&lt;/a&gt; among MLB hitters, who are likely swinging upward to maximize the number of balls they hit in the air and are not shy about the increase in strikeouts that may come with that approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MLB Commissioner Rob Manfred has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/mlb/story/_/id/21188157/rob-manfred-reiterates-ball-juiced-home-run-onslaugh-world-series-game-2&quot;&gt;repeatedly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbssports.com/mlb/news/juiced-baseballs-rob-manfred-says-hes-certain-balls-are-within-specified-limits/&quot;&gt;denied&lt;/a&gt; that the baseball is juiced. On numerous occasions, he has said league testing found that baseballs continue to fall within the range that MLB designates as acceptable, and he recently said that MLB testing showed the balls to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BNightengale/status/964255852537565191&quot;&gt;fundamentally the same&lt;/a&gt;. But even if the baseballs still meet the league’s manufacturing guidelines, their performance could change &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/in-mlbs-new-home-run-era-its-the-baseballs-that-are-juicing/&quot;&gt;enough to double&lt;/a&gt; (or, theoretically, halve) the number of home runs hit in a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, in January of 2015, Rawlings &lt;a href=&quot;http://pdfaiw.uspto.gov/.aiw?PageNum=0&amp;amp;docid=20160008671&amp;amp;IDKey=BEEF4638D87E&amp;amp;HomeUrl=http%3A%2F%2Fappft.uspto.gov%2Fnetacgi%2Fnph-Parser%3FSect1%3DPTO1%2526Sect2%3DHITOFF%2526d%3DPG01%2526p%3D1%2526u%3D%25252Fnetahtml%25252FPTO%25252Fsrchnum.html%2526r%3D1%2526f%3DG%2526l%3D50%2526s1%3D%25252220160008671%252522.PGNR.%2526OS%3DDN%2F20160008671%2526RS%3DDN%2F20160008671&quot;&gt;filed a patent application&lt;/a&gt; for a manufacturing process that would allow it to produce softballs and non-MLB baseballs&lt;a class=&quot;espn-footnote-link&quot; data-footnote-id=&quot;5&quot; href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/juiced-baseballs/#fn-5&quot; data-footnote-content=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The patent applies to balls with foam cores, which might be used in softball or youth-league baseball, for example, but does not apply to the type of baseballs used in MLB, with layers of yarn around a cork-and-rubber core.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;ss-5&quot;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that were as bouncy as possible while still falling within the manufacturing specifications set by the league. This type of ball is constructed quite differently from MLB baseballs, so there’s no indication that this patent means Rawlings is deliberately manipulating major league baseballs in this way, but it demonstrates that it’s at least theoretically possible for balls to be “fundamentally the same” while also performing differently than they have in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathy Smith-Stephens, senior director of quality and compliance at Rawlings, said that no change had been made to the baseballs but that “natural variation” occurs in the manufacturing process. She noted that they “continuously tweak” — though later in the interview she asked that we say “continuously refine” — the manufacturing process in an effort to reduce variations, but said that Rawlings’ internal testing had shown no difference in the ball’s weight or bounciness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidence that the baseball is at least partially responsible for the last few years’ spike in the home run rate mounted throughout the summer of 2017 and reached &lt;a href=&quot;http://mlb.nbcsports.com/2017/10/27/rob-manfred-once-again-responds-disingenuously-to-questions-about-juiced-baseballs/&quot;&gt;a peak&lt;/a&gt; during October’s World Series. In those seven games, the Houston Astros and Los Angeles Dodgers smashed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/sports/news/world-series-2017-wild-7-games-with-record-home-runs-w510812&quot;&gt;24 homers&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/sports/la-sp-world-series-game-2-sets-world-series-records-for-1509042281-htmlstory.html&quot;&gt;eight in one game&lt;/a&gt;. In the wake of this power display, Manfred asked all 30 teams to start &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.si.com/mlb/2018/02/23/mlb-mandate-teams-store-baseballs&quot;&gt;storing baseballs in a climate-controlled room&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sports.yahoo.com/mlb-determined-find-baseballs-juiced-2017-035422507.html&quot;&gt;commissioned a task force&lt;/a&gt; of scientists and statisticians to investigate whether the ball was juiced in 2017. Our own research, combined with controlled tests from three separate academic laboratories, strongly suggests that the physical properties of the ball have changed. Taken together, all these studies give us a lot of evidence to suggest that today’s baseballs differ in meaningful ways from those of a few years ago. In other words, there are many questions for Manfred’s committee to address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Special thanks to Sean O’Rourke, Dr. Cynthia Bir and Nathan Beals for additional research assistance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 08:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gscott</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>We X-Rayed Some MLB Baseballs. Here’s What We Found.</og:title>
<og:url>https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/juiced-baseballs/</og:url>
<og:description>On 6,105 occasions last season, a major leaguer walked to the plate and hammered a baseball over the outfield wall. The 2017 season broke the home run record th…</og:description>
<og:image>https://espnfivethirtyeight.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/juice_ctscan_16x9.jpg?w=1600</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/juiced-baseballs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GDPR – A Practical Guide for Developers (2017)</title>
<link>https://techblog.bozho.net/gdpr-practical-guide-developers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techblog.bozho.net/gdpr-practical-guide-developers/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard about GDPR. The new European data protection regulation that applies practically to everyone. Especially if you are working in a big company, it’s most likely that there’s already a process for getting your systems in compliance with the regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regulation is basically a law that must be followed in all European countries (but also applies to non-EU companies that have users in the EU). In this particular case, it applies to companies that are not registered in Europe, but are having European customers. So that’s most companies. I will not go into yet another “12 facts about GDPR” or “7 myths about GDPR” posts/whitepapers, as they are often aimed at managers or legal people. Instead, I’ll focus on what GDPR means for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I qualified to do that? A few reasons – I was &lt;a ps=&quot;https://techblog.bozho.net/chose-government-advisor/&quot;&gt;advisor to the deputy prime minister of a EU country&lt;/a&gt;, and because of that I’ve been both exposed and myself wrote some legislation. I’m familiar with the “legalese” and how the regulatory framework operates in general. I’m also a privacy advocate and I’ve been writing about GDPR-related stuff in the past, i.e. “before it was cool” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://techblog.bozho.net/protecting-sensitive-data/&quot;&gt;protecting sensitive data&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techblog.bozho.net/the-right-to-be-forgotten-in-your-application/&quot;&gt;the right to be forgotten&lt;/a&gt;). And finally, I’m currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://logsentinel.com/&quot;&gt;working on a project&lt;/a&gt; that (among other things) aims to help with covering &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; GDPR aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll try to be a bit more comprehensive this time and cover as many aspects of the regulation that concern developers as I can. And while developers will mostly be concerned about how the systems they are working on have to change, it’s not unlikely that a less informed manager storms in in late spring, realizing GDPR is going to be in force tomorrow, asking “what should we do to get our system/website compliant”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rights of the user/client (referred to as “data subject” in the regulation) that I think are relevant for developers are: the right to erasure (the right to be forgotten/deleted from the system), right to restriction of processing (you still keep the data, but mark it as “restricted” and don’t touch it without further consent by the user), the right to data portability (the ability to export one’s data in a machine-readable format), the right to rectification (the ability to get personal data fixed), the right to be informed (getting human-readable information, rather than long terms and conditions), the right of access (the user should be able to see all the data you have about them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the relevant basic principles are: data minimization (one should not collect more data than necessary), integrity and confidentiality (all security measures to protect data that you can think of + measures to guarantee that the data has not been inappropriately modified).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even further, the regulation requires certain processes to be in place within an organization (of more than 250 employees or if a significant amount of data is processed), and those include keeping a record of all types of processing activities carried out, including transfers to processors (3rd parties), which includes cloud service providers. None of the other requirements of the regulation have an exception depending on the organization size, so “I’m small, GDPR does not concern me” is a myth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to know what “personal data” is. Basically, it’s every piece of data that can be used to uniquely identify a person or data that is about an already identified person. It’s data that the user has explicitly provided, but also data that you have collected about them from either 3rd parties or based on their activities on the site (what they’ve been looking at, what they’ve purchased, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, I’ll list a number of features that will have to be implemented and some hints on how to do that, followed by some do’s and don’t’s. Note that (as pointed out in each feature) they don’t necessarily have to be automated – you could just have a manual process in place. But for bigger systems it would be much better to have them automated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-17-gdpr/&quot;&gt;“Forget me”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – you should have a method that takes a userId and deletes all personal data about that user (in case they have been collected on the basis of consent or based on the legitimate interests of the controller (see more below), and not due to contract enforcement or legal obligation). &lt;a href=&quot;https://techblog.bozho.net/forget-me-and-tests/&quot;&gt;It is actually useful for integration tests to have that feature&lt;/a&gt; (to cleanup after the test), but it may be hard to implement depending on the data model. In a regular data model, deleting a record may be easy, but some foreign keys may be violated. That means you have two options – either make sure you allow nullable foreign keys (for example an order usually has a reference to the user that made it, but when the user requests his data be deleted, you can set the userId to null), or make sure you delete all related data (e.g. via cascades). This may not be desirable, e.g. if the order is used to track available quantities or for accounting purposes. It’s a bit trickier for event-sourcing data models, or in extreme cases, ones that include some sort of blockchain/hash chain/tamper-evident data structure. With event sourcing you should be able to remove a past event and re-generate intermediate snapshots. For blockchain-like structures – be careful what you put in there and avoid putting personal data of users. There is an option to use a chameleon hash function, but that’s suboptimal. Overall, you must constantly think of how you can delete the personal data. And “our data model doesn’t allow it” isn’t an excuse. What about backups? Ideally, you should keep a separate table of forgotten user IDs, so that each time you restore a backup, you re-forget the forgotten users. This means the table should be in a separate database or have a separate backup/restore process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-19-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Notify 3rd parties for erasure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – deleting things from your system may be one thing, but you are also obligated to inform all third parties that you have pushed that data to. So if you have sent personal data to, say, Salesforce, Hubspot, twitter, or any cloud service provider, you should call an API of theirs that allows for the deletion of personal data. If you are such a provider, obviously, your “forget me” endpoint should be exposed. Calling the 3rd party APIs to remove data is not the full story, though. You also have to make sure the information does not appear in search results. Now, that’s tricky, as Google doesn’t have an API for removal, only a &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/6349986?hl=en&quot;&gt;manual process&lt;/a&gt;. Fortunately, it’s only about public profile pages that are crawlable by Google (and other search engines, okay…), but you still have to take measures. Ideally, you should make the personal data page return a 404 HTTP status, so that it can be removed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-18-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Restrict processing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – in your admin panel where there’s a list of users, there should be a button “restrict processing”. The user settings page should also have that button. When clicked (after reading the appropriate information), it should mark the profile as restricted. That means it should no longer be visible to the backoffice staff, or publicly. You can implement that with a simple “restricted” flag in the users table and a few if-clasues here and there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-20-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Export data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – there should be another button – “export data”. When clicked, the user should receive all the data that you hold about them. What exactly is that data – depends on the particular usecase. Usually it’s at least the data that you delete with the “forget me” functionality, but may include additional data (e.g. the orders the user has made may not be delete, but should be included in the dump). The structure of the dump is not strictly defined, but my recommendation would be to reuse &lt;a href=&quot;http://schema.org/docs/schemas.html&quot;&gt;schema.org definitions&lt;/a&gt; as much as possible, for either JSON or XML. If the data is simple enough, a CSV/XLS export would also be fine. Sometimes data export can take a long time, so the button can trigger a background process, which would then notify the user via email when his data is ready (twitter, for example, does that already – you can request all your tweets and you get them after a while). You don’t need to implement an automated export, although it would be nice. It’s sufficient to have a process in place to allow users to request their data, which can be a manual database-querying process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-16-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Allow users to edit their profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – this seems an obvious rule, but it isn’t always followed. Users must be able to fix all data about them, including data that you have collected from other sources (e.g. using a “login with facebook” you may have fetched their name and address). Rule of thumb – all the fields in your “users” table should be editable via the UI. Technically, rectification can be done via a manual support process, but that’s normally more expensive for a business than just having the form to do it. There is one other scenario, however, when you’ve obtained the data from other sources (i.e. the user hasn’t provided their details to you directly). In that case there should still be a page where they can identify somehow (via email and/or sms confirmation) and get access to the data about them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-7-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Consent checkboxes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – “I accept the terms and conditions” would no longer be sufficient to claim that the user has given their consent for processing their data. So, for each particular processing activity there should be a separate checkbox on the registration (or user profile) screen. You should keep these consent checkboxes in separate columns in the database, and let the users withdraw their consent (by unchecking these checkboxes from their profile page – see the previous point). Ideally, these checkboxes should come directly from the register of processing activities (if you keep one). Note that the checkboxes should not be preselected, as this does not count as “consent”. Another important thing here is machine learning/AI. If you are going to use the user’s data to train your ML models, you should get consent for that as well (unless it’s for scientific purposes, which have special treatment in the regulation). Note here the so called “legitimate interest”. It is for the legal team to decide what a legitimate interest is, but direct marketing is included in that category, as well as any common sense processing relating to the business activity – e.g. if you collect addresses for shipping, it’s obviously a legitimate interest. So not all processing activities need consent checkboxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re-request consent&lt;/strong&gt; – if the consent users have given was not clear (e.g. if they simply agreed to terms &amp;amp; conditions), you’d have to re-obtain that consent. So prepare a functionality for mass-emailing your users to ask them to go to their profile page and check all the checkboxes for the personal data processing activities that you have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-15-gdpr/&quot;&gt;“See all my data”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – this is very similar to the “Export” button, except data should be displayed in the regular UI of the application rather than an XML/JSON format. I wouldn’t say this is mandatory, and you can leave it as a “desirable” feature – for example, Google Maps shows you your location history – all the places that you’ve been to. It is a good implementation of the right to access. (Though Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1131515/google-collects-android-users-locations-even-when-location-services-are-disabled/&quot;&gt;is very far from perfect&lt;/a&gt; when privacy is concerned). This is not all about the right to access – you have to let unregistered users ask whether you have data about them, but that would be a more manual process. The ideal minimum would be to have a feature “check by email”, where you check if you have data about a particular email. You also need to tell the user in what ways you are processing their data. You can simply print all the records in your data process register for which the user has consented to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-8-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Age checks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – you should ask for the user’s age, and if the user is a child (below 16), you should ask for parent permission. There’s no clear way how to do that, but my suggestion is to introduce a flow, where the child should specify the email of a parent, who can then confirm. Obviously, children will just cheat with their birthdate, or provide a fake parent email, but you will most likely have done your job according to the regulation (this is one of the “wishful thinking” aspects of the regulation).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-5-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Keeping data for no longer than necessary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – if you’ve collected the data for a specific purpose (e.g. shipping a product), you have to delete it/anonymize it as soon as you don’t need it. Many e-commerce sites offer “purchase without registration”, in which case the consent goes only for the particular order. So you need a scheduled job/cron to periodically go through the data and anonymize it (delete names and addresses), but only after a certain condition is met – e.g. the product is confirmed as delivered. You can have a database field for storing the deadline after which the data should be gone, and that deadline can be extended in case of a delivery problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now some “do’s”, which are mostly about the technical measures needed to protect personal data (outlined in &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-32-gdpr/&quot;&gt;article 32&lt;/a&gt;). They may be more “ops” than “dev”, but often the application also has to be extended to support them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://techblog.bozho.net/protecting-sensitive-data/&quot;&gt;I’ve listed most of what I could think of in a previous post&lt;/a&gt;. An important note here is that this is not mandated by the regulation, but it’s a good practice anyway and helps with protecting personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encrypt the data in transit&lt;/strong&gt;. That means that communication between your application layer and your database (or your message queue, or whatever component you have) should be over TLS. The certificates could be self-signed (and possibly pinned), or you could have an internal CA. Different databases have different configurations, just google “X encrypted connections. Some databases need gossiping among the nodes – that should also be configured to use encryption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encrypt the data at rest&lt;/strong&gt; – this again depends on the database (some offer table-level encryption), but can also be done on machine-level. E.g. using LUKS. The private key can be stored in your infrastructure, or in some cloud service like AWS KMS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encrypt your backups&lt;/strong&gt; – kind of obvious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement pseudonymisation&lt;/strong&gt; – the most obvious use-case is when you want to use production data for the test/staging servers. You should change the personal data to some “pseudonym”, so that the people cannot be identified. When you push data for machine learning purposes (to third parties or not), you can also do that. Technically, that could mean that your User object can have a “pseudonymize” method which applies hash+salt/bcrypt/PBKDF2 for some of the data that can be used to identify a person. Pseudonyms could be reversible or not, depending on the usecase (the definition in the regulation implies reversibility based on a secret information, but in the case of test/staging data it might not be). Some databases have such features built-in, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oracle.com/us/products/database/data-masking-best-practices-161213.pdf&quot;&gt;e.g. Orale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protect data integrity&lt;/strong&gt; – this is a very broad thing, and could simply mean “have authentication mechanisms for modifying data”. But you can do something more, even as simple as a checksum, or a more complicated solution (like the one I’m working on). It depends on the stakes, on the way data is accessed, on the particular system, etc. The checksum can be in the form of a hash of all the data in a given database record, which should be updated each time the record is updated through the application. It isn’t a strong guarantee, but it is at least something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have your GDPR register of processing activities in something other than Excel&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-30-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Article 30&lt;/a&gt; says that you should keep a record of all the types of activities that you use personal data for. That sounds like bureaucracy, but it may be useful – you will be able to link certain aspects of your application with that register (e.g. the consent checkboxes, or your audit trail records). It wouldn’t take much time to implement a simple register, but the business requirements for that should come from whoever is responsible for the GDPR compliance. But you can advise them that having it in Excel won’t make it easy for you as a developer (imagine having to fetch the excel file internally, so that you can parse it and implement a feature). Such a register could be a microservice/small application deployed separately in your infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Log access to personal data&lt;/strong&gt; – every read operation on a personal data record should be logged, so that you know who accessed what and for what purpose. This does not follow directly from the provisions of the regulation, but it is kinda implied from the accountability principles. What about search results (or lists) that contain personal data about multiple subjects? My hunch is that simply logging “user X did a search for criteria Y” would suffice. But don’t display too many personal data in lists – for example see how facebook makes you go through some hoops to get a person’s birthday. Note: some have treated article 30 as a requirement to keep an audit log. I don’t think it is saying that – instead it requires 250+ companies (or companies processing data regularly) to keep a register of the types of processing activities (i.e. what you use the data for). There are other articles in the regulation that imply that keeping an audit log is a best practice (for protecting the integrity of the data as well as to make sure it hasn’t been processed without a valid reason)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Register all API consumers&lt;/strong&gt; – you shouldn’t allow anonymous API access to personal data. I’d say you should request the organization name and contact person for each API user upon registration, and add those to the data processing register.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, some “don’t’s”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-6-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Don’t use data for purposes that the user hasn’t agreed with&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – that’s supposed to be the spirit of the regulation. If you want to expose a new API to a new type of clients, or you want to use the data for some machine learning, or you decide to add ads to your site based on users’ behaviour, or sell your database to a 3rd party – think twice. I would imagine your register of processing activities could have a button to send notification emails to users to ask them for permission when a new processing activity is added (or if you use a 3rd party register, it should probably give you an API). So upon adding a new processing activity (and adding that to your register), mass email all users from whom you’d like consent. Note here that additional legitimate interests of the controller might be added dynamically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t log personal data&lt;/strong&gt; – getting rid of the personal data from log files (especially if they are shipped to a 3rd party service) can be tedious or even impossible. So log just identifiers if needed. And make sure old logs files are cleaned up, just in case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t put fields on the registration/profile form that you don’t need&lt;/strong&gt; – it’s always tempting to just throw as many fields as the usability person/designer agrees on, but unless you absolutely need the data for delivering your service, you shouldn’t collect it. Names you should probably always collect, but unless you are delivering something, a home address or phone is unnecessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t assume 3rd parties are compliant&lt;/strong&gt; – you are responsible if there’s a data breach in one of the 3rd parties (e.g. “processors”) to which you send personal data. So before you send data via an API to another service, make sure they have at least a basic level of data protection. If they don’t, raise a flag with management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t assume having ISO XXX makes you compliant&lt;/strong&gt; – information security standards and even personal data standards are a good start and they will probably 70% of what the regulation requires, but they are not sufficient – most of the things listed above are not covered in any of those standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the purpose of the regulation is to make you take conscious decisions when processing personal data. It imposes best practices in a legal way. If you follow the above advice and design your data model, storage, data flow , API calls with data protection in mind, then you shouldn’t worry about the huge fines that the regulation prescribes – they are for extreme cases, like Equifax for example. Regulators (data protection authorities) will most likely have some checklists into which you’d have to somehow fit, but if you follow best practices, that shouldn’t be an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think all of the above features can be implemented in a few weeks by a small team. Be suspicious when a big vendor offers you a generic plug-and-play “GDPR compliance” solution. GDPR is not just about the technical aspects listed above – it does have organizational/process implications. But also be suspicious if a consultant claims GDPR is complicated. It’s not – it relies on a few basic principles that are in fact best practices anyway. Just don’t ignore them.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 08:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>FooBarWidget</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>GDPR - A Practical Guide For Developers - Bozho's tech blog</og:title>
<og:description>You’ve probably heard about GDPR. The new European data protection regulation that applies practically to everyone. Especially if you are working in a big company, it’s most likely that there’sContinue reading</og:description>
<og:url>https://techblog.bozho.net/gdpr-practical-guide-developers/</og:url>
<og:image>https://techblog.bozho.net/digits.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techblog.bozho.net/gdpr-practical-guide-developers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon won&amp;#039;t sell you a Chromecast, but they will sell a counterfeit</title>
<link>https://www.amazon.com/Display-Wishpower-Receiver-Miracast-AirMirror/dp/B077978NRN/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.amazon.com/Display-Wishpower-Receiver-Miracast-AirMirror/dp/B077978NRN/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;a-text-bold&quot;&gt;Special note:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;this isn't a Chromecast&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;a-text-bold&quot;&gt;❆Specification❆&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;* Wireless Connectivity 2.4GHz Wi-Fi 802.11 ac&lt;br/&gt;* WiFi Range: Up to 10m&lt;br/&gt;* WiFi Module / Version: 8188FTV&lt;br/&gt;* Resolution: 1920 x 1080P ( max )&lt;br/&gt;* HDMI: HDMI 1.4&lt;br/&gt;* DC/Power: Micro USB Port&lt;br/&gt;* Support: DLNA/ AirMirror / Airplay / Miracast&lt;br/&gt;* Material: Aluminium Alloy + ABS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;a-text-bold&quot;&gt;❆Operating System Requirement❆&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Android 4.1 and higher&lt;br/&gt;- iOS 7 and higher&lt;br/&gt;- Windows 8.1 and higher&lt;br/&gt;- Mac OS 10.7 and higher&lt;br/&gt;- System Requirements TV with an HDMI port&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;a-text-bold&quot;&gt;❆Package❆&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;1 x WiFi Display Dongle HDMI Adapter&lt;br/&gt;1 x V-shaped WiFi Part with USB cable&lt;br/&gt;1 x User Manual&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;a-text-bold&quot;&gt;❆How to Connect?❆&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;1. Connect USB to USB Power Adapter&lt;br/&gt;2. Micro USB to the Dongle&lt;br/&gt;3. Plug Dongle HDMI into your TV HDMI Port&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 07:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bb88</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.amazon.com/Display-Wishpower-Receiver-Miracast-AirMirror/dp/B077978NRN/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Doom as a tool for system administration (1999)</title>
<link>https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/flake/doom/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/flake/doom/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Doom&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#000000&quot; link=&quot;#F02020&quot; vlink=&quot;#C0C040&quot; text=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;86.566916488223&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://medio.cs.unm.edu/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/flake/mediolink.png&quot; alt=&quot;mediocre lab&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Doom as a tool for system administration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was listening to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.unm.edu/~soma&quot;&gt;Anil&lt;/a&gt; talk about daemons spawning processes and sysadmins killing them, I thought, &quot;What a great user interface!&quot; Imagine running around with a shotgun blowing away your daemons and processes, never needing to type &lt;code&gt;kill -9&lt;/code&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/flake/doom/start.gif&quot; width=&quot;328&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sneaking up on my processes.&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1981, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-rohan.sdsu.edu/faculty/vinge/&quot;&gt;Vernor Vinge&lt;/a&gt; introduced the concept of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tuxedo.org/~esr/jargon/html/entry/cyberspace.html&quot;&gt;cyberspace&lt;/a&gt; to the reading public in his novella &lt;em&gt;True Names&lt;/em&gt;, in which characters could plug into a virtual universe where their actions in a fantasy world mapped to performing sophisticated actions on the network. For example, walking along a tricky path through a swamp would be the same as going through a firewall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mapping of abstract operations to an intuitive environment is a difficult problem. There are two distinct obstacles: the environment must be intuitive and the mapping must be accurate. If the environment is not intuitive, it can alienate users. In a good environment, the user would instinctively do the right thing. The quality of the environment is for naught if the mapping is not accurate. For instance, if certain natural actions lead to detrimental results or if desired results can only achieved by performing contrived acts, the mapping to the underlying processes must be learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difficulty of the mapping is evidenced by the paucity of good user interfaces that use physical metaphors. The only widespread example is the &quot;desktop&quot; interface, where files are held in &quot;folders&quot; which may be &quot;opened&quot; or &quot;thrown away&quot;. This is a fairly good mapping, but there are certainly problems. For example, the user must understand what &quot;links&quot; are to figure out why some folders are not always accessible. The user must also realize that one can close a folder and still see the contents of its sub-folders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am proposing a new mapping for managing system loads. As mentioned above, people frequently talk about &quot;blowing processes away&quot;, and the Unix command to destroy a process is &quot;kill&quot;. This suggests a metaphor for process management. Each process can be a monster, and the machines can be represented by a series of rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idsoftware.com&quot;&gt;Id Software&lt;/a&gt; has generously released the source for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idsoftware.com/killer/doomult.html&quot;&gt;Doom&lt;/a&gt;, which has been ported to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linux.org&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;. I downloaded one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.doomworld.com/ports/linux_unix.shtml&quot;&gt;many versions&lt;/a&gt; and added a few lines of code that would spawn a new soldier for each process, renice the process when it is wounded, and kill the process when it dies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/flake/doom/attack.gif&quot; width=&quot;328&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Help! I'm being attacked by csh (pid 18729)!&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the potential benefits of using Doom as a tool for system administration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The machine load is immediately apparent to the player, who can see how crowded a room is. The player can eyeball many machines from a high vantage point and go down to a room that needs maintenance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a nice continuum for resource allocation. A user may choose to simply wound processes rather than killing them, which could naturally be translated to renicing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new sysadmin can be given less power by providing her with a smaller weapon. A rank beginner may not be given a weapon at all and be forced to attack processes with her bare hands. It would take a foolhardy player to attack a room full of monsters, just as a newbie should not kill a bunch of important processes. A more experienced sysadmin would have time to stop a newbie who is trying to kill the wrong process. The real work could be left to those with the big guns. The truly great sysadmins could have BFGs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really crowded systems would regulate their own load because monsters occasionally kill each other. Once the population in a room goes down, the monsters will stop attacking each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drastic action takes work. In a command line interface, all actions take approximately the same amount of effort. One can &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; just as easily as &lt;code&gt;rm -rf *&lt;/code&gt;, which is kind of unfortunate. In a cyberspace environment, the players are not omnipotent, so performing large actions takes time and effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important processes can be instantiated as more powerful monsters. They can then defend themselves against inexperienced sysadmins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sysadmins could cooperate or compete. Doom is a natural environment for player-to-player interactions. A team of players can cooperate to take care of a heavily-loaded system, or they can even take out rogue sysadmins who are killing the wrong processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few of the problems of using Doom as a tool for system administration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Certain processes are vital to the computer's operation and should not be killed. For example, after I took the screenshot of myself being attacked by &lt;code&gt;csh&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;csh&lt;/code&gt; was shot by friendly fire from behind, possibly by &lt;code&gt;tcsh&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;xv&lt;/code&gt;, and my session was abruptly terminated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mapping processes to appropriate monsters is difficult. Should large processes be mapped to large monsters? Should the monster type reflect the CPU as well as memory usage? Should processes and their children look alike?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is difficult to tell if your employees are doing real work or just goofing off when tools and games have the same GUI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd like to thank the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.unm.edu/~immsec/adaptive-web/ac_main.htm&quot;&gt;Adaptive Computation Group&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.unm.edu&quot;&gt;UNM&lt;/a&gt; for providing a supportive environment in which one can claim one is doing research while playing Doom for two days. This work was funded by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nsf.gov&quot;&gt;National Science Foundation&lt;/a&gt; through a BIO Research Training Group in &lt;a href=&quot;http://sevilleta.unm.edu/~ehdecker/complexity/99fall/&quot;&gt;Ecological Complexity&lt;/a&gt; (NSF &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nsf.gov/cgi-bin/showaward?award=9553623&quot;&gt;9553623&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dlchao@cs.unm.edu&quot;&gt;Mail&lt;/a&gt; me your insightful comments. I would especially be interested in hearing about implementation changes that you have tried and responses to my CHI 2001 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/flake/doom/chi/chi.html&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/flake/doom/chi/slides/html/index.html&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; on PSDoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dennis Chao&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dlchao@cs.unm.edu&quot;&gt;dlchao@cs.unm.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;October 17, 1999&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/flake/doom/after.html&quot;&gt;Click here to get the code, read the paper presented at the CHI 2001 Conference, follow links...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/begin.html&quot;&gt;back&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digits.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/flake/doom/wc-03.gif&quot; width=&quot;216&quot; height=&quot;23&quot; border=&quot;border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://counter.digits.com/wc/psdoom&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 06:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ColinWright</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cs.unm.edu/~dlchao/flake/doom/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WebAssembly architecture for Go</title>
<link>https://docs.google.com/document/d/131vjr4DH6JFnb-blm_uRdaC0_Nv3OUwjEY5qVCxCup4/preview#heading=h.mjo1bish3xni</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://docs.google.com/document/d/131vjr4DH6JFnb-blm_uRdaC0_Nv3OUwjEY5qVCxCup4/preview#heading=h.mjo1bish3xni</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;WebAssembly architecture for Go&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;article&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;Google Docs&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/131vjr4DH6JFnb-blm_uRdaC0_Nv3OUwjEY5qVCxCup4/preview?_escaped_fragment_&amp;amp;usp=embed_facebook&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/qIoP314586ONHNIkYbDzcd5eh9ULP4bZnbXwifNB4pachdLosC5UA0xddKvmVe9VsN7A9g=w1200-h630-p&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:width&quot; content=&quot;1200&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:height&quot; content=&quot;630&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;WebAssembly architecture for Go Document revision 1 - 28th February 2018 This documents describes the design decisions that went into the new WebAssembly architecture (short &amp;#x201C;wasm&amp;#x201D;) for the Go compiler. The goal is to upstream it to the official Go repository in the current development cycle, ta...&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google&quot; content=&quot;notranslate&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;IE=edge;&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;fragment&quot; content=&quot;!&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;referrer&quot; content=&quot;default&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;WebAssembly architecture for Go - Google Docs&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;shortcut icon&quot; href=&quot;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/documents/images/kix-favicon6.ico&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;chrome-webstore-item&quot; href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ghbmnnjooekpmoecnnnilnnbdlolhkhi&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;chrome-webstore-item&quot; href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/apdfllckaahabafndbhieahigkjlhalf&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta itemprop=&quot;name&quot; content=&quot;WebAssembly architecture for Go&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta itemprop=&quot;faviconUrl&quot; content=&quot;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/documents/images/kix-favicon6.ico&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta itemprop=&quot;url&quot; content=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/131vjr4DH6JFnb-blm_uRdaC0_Nv3OUwjEY5qVCxCup4/preview?_escaped_fragment_&amp;amp;usp=embed_googleplus&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta itemprop=&quot;embedURL&quot; content=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/131vjr4DH6JFnb-blm_uRdaC0_Nv3OUwjEY5qVCxCup4/preview?usp=embed_googleplus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body dir=&quot;ltr&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/CreativeWork/DocumentObject&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;153.00171772116&quot;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;docs-butterbar-container&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;docs-butterbar-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript isn't enabled in your browser, so this file can't be opened. Enable and reload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;title&quot; id=&quot;h.mjo1bish3xni&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebAssembly architecture for Go&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Document revision 1 - 28th February 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This documents describes the design decisions that went into the new WebAssembly architecture (short “wasm”) for the Go compiler. The goal is to upstream it to the official Go repository in the current development cycle, targeting Go 1.11. The WebAssembly architecture will allow Go to become an alternative to JavaScript for writing code that runs in a web browser. This new freedom of choice will hopefully have a positive impact on the software engineering ecosystem overall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.no6fy3wdxcc2&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Introduction to WebAssembly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebAssembly is in many regards quite different from all other architectures. It is not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;intended&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; to be processed by a CPU directly, but instead is an intermediate representation that&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; compiled to actual machine code by the WebAssembly runtime environment. Thus the design of WebAssembly was not constrained by hardware considerations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; and the authors could instead focus on their goals of efficiency and output size.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This put&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; constraints on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; logic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; that&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; can be efficiently expressed in WebAssembly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;These&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; constraints&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;are&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; sometimes hard to reconcile with Go’s existing design. One may hope that future versions of WebAssembly will add features&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; fill&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;these&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; gaps. Nevertheless, the current state of the WebAssembly architecture for Go passes all compiler and package tests and supports all major Go features. There was a focus on keeping changes to existing compiler and runtime code to a minimum.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=http://webassembly.github.io/spec/core/index.html&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1520154087472000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHYwhUkemUsatzS6tmVMosyDGxmfw&quot;&gt;WebAssembly specification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://github.com/WebAssembly/design/blob/master/FutureFeatures.md&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1520154087472000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNH65fO3aRT5elg0LbUC5n5d2dkBtQ&quot;&gt;WebAssembly future features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.yagsioapncj3&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Linear memory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebAssembly features a linear memory with load and store instructions. This is quite similar to normal memory pages, however it is currently not possible to reserve pages without already allocating them. This will likely be&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://github.com/WebAssembly/design/blob/master/FutureFeatures.md%23finer-grained-control-over-memory&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1520154087473000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHz6QOiEFhqssCDXxc3vSLzR6wzkg&quot;&gt;available in the future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.pi4kwpb166zn&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;64-bit architecture&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebAssembly has full support for 64 bit integers (in contrast to JavaScript). However, currently memory can only be addressed with 32 bit integers, thus limiting the memory to 4GB. However, the wasm architecture for Go has 64 bit pointers and a switchover to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://github.com/WebAssembly/design/blob/master/FutureFeatures.md%23linear-memory-bigger-than-4-gib&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1520154087473000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFCbGIXGxbi70ukBAbCUQhC-UlxqA&quot;&gt;64 bit memory operations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; is planned when they are available.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.c6ieju7hnzrz&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Threads&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Currently WebAssembly has no threads, but they are&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://github.com/WebAssembly/design/issues/1073&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1520154087474000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNG22vSyWHSicPfX43aK0EqBsy4Hwg&quot;&gt;on the roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Most Go code can run fine on a single thread. The only drawback is that “sysmon” is not available, thus there is no preemption of goroutines.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.58es2esmswsk&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebAssembly is a stack machine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;All other architectures are register machines, but WebAssembly is not. Instead, it maintains its own opaque stack and each function can have an arbitrary number of local variables.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fully using WebAssembly’s stack is currently not an option, since Go needs to be able to inspect the stack for garbage collection, stack traces, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Instead, Go maintains its own stack on the linear memory as usual. Registers get mapped to variables: SP, PC_F and PC_B (see below) are global variables. I0 to I15 (64 bit integers) and F0 to F15 (64 bit floats) are local variables. The WebAssembly runtime is likely to map those local variables to CPU registers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Go’s SSA instructions only operate on registers, for example an add instruction would read two registers, do the addition and then write to a register. WebAssembly’s instructions on the other hand operate on the stack. The add instruction first pops two values from the stack, does the addition, then pushes the result to the stack. To&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;fulfill&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; Go’s semantics, one needs to map Go’s single add instruction to 4 WebAssembly instructions:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;lst-kix_4isqroa750k0-0 start&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Push&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;value of local variable A to the stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Push&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;value of local variable B to the stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Do addition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Write value from stack to local variable C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now consider that B was set to the constant 42 before the addition:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;lst-kix_4isqroa750k0-0&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Push constant 42 to the stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Write value from stack to local variable B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This works, but is inefficient. Instead, the stack is used directly by inlining instructions if possible. With inlining it becomes:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;lst-kix_4isqroa750k0-0&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Push&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;value of local variable A to the stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Push constant 42 to the stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Do addition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Write value from stack to local variable C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Please note that the instruction “Push constant 42 to the stack” is not strictly ordered before the add instruction anymore.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.q39kpzpt2lwf&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Control structures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebAssembly has no basic blocks or jump instructions, instead it has more high level control structures resembling if-statements and loops. Unfortunately, it also does not currently have any fallback construct like a goto instruction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://github.com/WebAssembly/design/blob/master/Rationale.md%23control-flow&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1520154087476000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEhIdmBc3hW1Y0GKZbM5Ko1_U00Nw&quot;&gt;According to the authors of WebAssembly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, this should not be an issue since most control flow can be turned into high-level structures by the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://github.com/kripken/emscripten/blob/master/docs/paper.pdf?raw%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1520154087476000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFNRVot1rkvTQgnM1-cd0DRTma3Ew&quot;&gt;“relooper” algorithm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Unfortunately this is not possible for Go, since resuming a goroutine continues execution at some arbitrary call in a function, thus all those entry points must be reachable from the start of the function. One can see that the assumption of the authors only holds if one is also fully using WebAssembly’s stacks and their yet-to-be-added coroutine feature. One can hope that a goto instruction will be&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://github.com/WebAssembly/design/issues/796&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1520154087476000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEuKU2t1VaKNtsc1nT4XPWh3UXrCw&quot;&gt;added in the future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the meantime, Go generates the equivalent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; a big switch statement and uses the PC_B variable to jump to the desired basic block.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.nrkaoiab5j18&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Functions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebAssembly functions do not live in the same address space as the linear memory. Instead, they have a 0-based index. This is reconciled with Go’s concept of a program counter by splitting it into 2 parts: PC_F and PC_B. PC_F is the index of the function to be executed. PC_B is the index of the basic block to be executed. When a single 64-bit PC value is needed it currently gets built as follows: PC_F&amp;lt;&amp;lt;16 + PC_B.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.xweu6gzay871&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Garbage collection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Go’s garbage collection is fully supported. WebAssembly is planning to add&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://github.com/WebAssembly/design/issues/1079&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1520154087477000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGGMAf0FI2vSZuJk7NFKBHIlxKCSA&quot;&gt;its own garbage collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, but it is hard to imagine that it would yield a better performance than Go’s own GC which is specifically tailored to Go’s needs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.1duvpjxox23g&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Syscalls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;System calls are implemented via calls to the JS environment. Most file system operations are mapped to Node.js’ “fs” module. In the browser, file system operations are currently not available. Network operations are currently simulated internally, not touching the real network, just like with the nacl architecture used by the Go playground. This needs to be improved in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.i5j6fyy7f7nx&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;JavaScript interoperability&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Interoperability with the JavaScript environment is still in an early state. A few operations are available in the runtime/js package and are currently used by the syscall implementations. However, this package is likely to change in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.oz783lnn3frl&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Conclusion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It works, supports the full Go specification and most major features that people love with Go. There is still work to do to improve the performance. Especially a “goto” operation in WebAssembly would be very helpful. Still, it is in a state where it should be good enough to be merged upstream so more people can start experimenting and contributing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 22:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>diakritikal</dc:creator>
<og:title>WebAssembly architecture for Go</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://docs.google.com/document/d/131vjr4DH6JFnb-blm_uRdaC0_Nv3OUwjEY5qVCxCup4/preview?_escaped_fragment_&amp;usp=embed_facebook</og:url>
<og:image>https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/qIoP314586ONHNIkYbDzcd5eh9ULP4bZnbXwifNB4pachdLosC5UA0xddKvmVe9VsN7A9g=w1200-h630-p</og:image>
<og:description>WebAssembly architecture for Go Document revision 1 - 28th February 2018 This documents describes the design decisions that went into the new WebAssembly architecture (short “wasm”) for the Go compiler. The goal is to upstream it to the official Go repository in the current development cycle, ta...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://docs.google.com/document/d/131vjr4DH6JFnb-blm_uRdaC0_Nv3OUwjEY5qVCxCup4/preview?_escaped_fragment_=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Patent trolls are shaking us down for selling “rubies” in our game</title>
<link>https://www.clickerheroes2.com/patent_trolls.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.clickerheroes2.com/patent_trolls.php</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;March 1, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (Playsaurus, developers of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clickerheroes.com/&quot;&gt;Clicker Heroes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clickerheroes2.com/&quot;&gt;Clicker Heroes 2&lt;/a&gt;) are getting shaken down by patent trolls for using &quot;virtual currency&quot; in our game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GTX Corp., owners of U.S. Patent no. 7,177,838, claims that we're infringing on their patent for using &quot;electronic tokens&quot; (I assume they mean the rubies in Clicker Heroes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They offered to let us pay a *&lt;em&gt;bargain&lt;/em&gt;* $35,000 license fee to avoid &quot;costly litigation&quot;. We were given 10 days to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe their claims are completely meritless and their behavior to be abusive and terribly unethical. As I am a major owner of Playsaurus I see this as a personal attack, and the cost in my own time and well-being has already been significant and draining. It is a shame that the United States legal system can't provide a quick and easy way for us to punish them for these actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe it is unethical on our part to pay any negotiated amount, which serves to encourage the behavior of trolls with bogus claims. So, if pressed, we will take the matter to court and see it to the end. We have retained a law firm to assist and represent us if necessary. Playsaurus is a 100% privately owned organization, and we are not beholden to outside investors. We absolutely refuse to negotiate license fees with patent holders who make bogus claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see everything they sent to us in the PDFs below. I have also included our response, written by my good friend Miguel Bombach from Perkins Coie, describing to GTX how their claims are completely meritless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of this patent (known as the '838 patent) is long. It was used by several different companies who owned it to shake down countless major institutions about 10 years ago. A more recent development is that they are threatening smaller companies (like Playsaurus) who typically don't have many resources. What they're asking for, $35,000, is about half a year of salary for one of our employees. I am concerned that they may be preying on a lot of other small studios, in a final attempt for them to profit off this bogus patent (which only has about 2 years left on it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe they are targeting smaller organizations now, because recent developments in patent law have made bogus patents like these much easier to fight, but only if you have enough resources and money to properly prepare the legal challenges. If they were to go after larger organizations, the patent could easily be challenged. But smaller organizations like ours often can't afford to go through that process as easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A precursory search shows that there's a current lawsuit from GTX Corp. against Nekki (another game developer) for infringing on this same patent on February 8th. There is another lawsuit against Soccer Manager Ltd. I don't yet know any details of these cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to hear from any other game developers who are also up against this problem, so that we could exchange any information we find and collaborate. I will freely discuss any information we or our lawyers discover that can be legally shared. Maybe we can help each other put an end to this. Please contact me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:fragsworth@playsaurus.com&quot;&gt;fragsworth@playsaurus.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is what they sent to us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is our response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Fragsworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEO, Playsaurus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT (March 2, 2018): It appears that there are multiple &quot;GTX Corps&quot;, so I want to make it clear that the ones going after us don't have much of an online presence. As of today they don't even appear to have a Wikipedia article (and the current Wikipedia article is about ANOTHER GTX Corp that appears to be a legitimate company). As far as I can tell, the guys shaking us down are NOT these guys in particular: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gtxcorp.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.gtxcorp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 20:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>guildwriter</dc:creator>
<og:title>Clicker Heroes 2</og:title>
<og:description>Sign up for news and updates for Clicker Heroes 2.</og:description>
<og:image>https://d1snsxh2hr65cz.cloudfront.net/ch2/logo.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.clickerheroes2.com</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.clickerheroes2.com/patent_trolls.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: My embarrassing personal website from the 90s</title>
<link>http://boglin.iwarp.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://boglin.iwarp.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/ani_explode.gif&quot; height=&quot;31&quot; width=&quot;88&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/title2.gif&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; width=&quot;409&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/iexploit.gif&quot; height=&quot;31&quot; width=&quot;88&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/smalborg.gif&quot; height=&quot;7&quot; width=&quot;502&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/nt2.gif&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;313&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hate Microsoft? Go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.winblows.com&quot;&gt;http://www.winblows.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;span&gt;WARNING&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;span&gt;: IF YOU DON'T SIGN THE GUESTBOOK I MAY HAVE TO KILL YOU. HAVE A NICE DAY. =)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dec.2/99&lt;/strong&gt;: I was wrong. It didn't take me another year to update my page...it only took 5 months and 7 days =) Have fun and check out the new stuff&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 26/99&lt;/strong&gt;: Well, I Finally got around to updating this thing. Who knows, it'll probably be another year or so before i do it again =P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/me.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/aboutme.gif&quot; height=&quot;64&quot; width=&quot;130&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/pics.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/pics2.gif&quot; height=&quot;64&quot; width=&quot;114&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/links.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/links2.gif&quot; height=&quot;64&quot; width=&quot;91&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/fsguestbook.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;VIEW THE GUESTBOOK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://boglin.iwarp.com/fsguest.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;SIGN THE GUESTBOOK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 20:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rpeden</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://boglin.iwarp.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>