<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>How We Built the GitHub Globe</title>
<link>https://github.blog/2020-12-21-how-we-built-the-github-globe/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.blog/2020-12-21-how-we-built-the-github-globe/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;GitHub is where the world builds software. More than 56 million developers around the world build and work together on GitHub. With our new &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/home&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;, we wanted to &lt;strong&gt;show&lt;/strong&gt; how open source development transcends the borders we’re living in and to tell our product story through the lens of a developer’s journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that it’s live, we would love to share how we built the homepage-directly from the voices of our designers and developers. In this five-part series, we’ll discuss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2020-12-21-how-we-built-the-github-globe/&quot;&gt;How our globe is built&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2020-12-21-visualizing-githubs-global-community/&quot;&gt;How we collect and use the data behind the globe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we designed the homepage and wrote the narrative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we made the page fast and performant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How our illustrators work with designers and engineers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-55604&quot; src=&quot;https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/102573836-33a1fb80-40a4-11eb-8c77-e2d328f0a570.gif?resize=640%2C400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Satellite in 2019, our CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/natfriedman&quot;&gt;Nat&lt;/a&gt; showed off &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/sGC2rwOiaWc?t=109&quot;&gt;a visualization of open source activity&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub over a 30-day span. The sheer volume and global reach was astonishing, and we knew we wanted to build on that story.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1vWoKSkebo9HSPO8Vp8de8xC522t0uLxK/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The main goals we set out to achieve in the design and development of the globe were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An interconnected community&lt;/strong&gt;. We explored many different options, but ultimately landed on pull requests. It turned out to be a beautiful visualization of pull requests being opened in one part of the world and closed in another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A showcase of real work happening now&lt;/strong&gt;. We started by simply showing the pull requests’ arcs and spires, but quickly realized that we needed “proof of life.” The arcs could quite as easily just be design animations instead of real work. We iterated on ways to provide more detail and found most resonance with clear hover states that showed the pull request, repo, timestamp, language, and locations. Nat had the idea of making each line clickable, which really upleveled the experience and made it much more immersive. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2020-12-21-visualizing-githubs-global-community/&quot;&gt;Read more here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attention to detail and performance.&lt;/strong&gt; It was extremely important to us that the globe not only looked inspiring and beautiful, but that it performed well on all devices. We went through many, many iterations of refinement, and there’s still more work to be done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;rendering-the-globe-with-webgl&quot;&gt;Rendering the globe with WebGL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the most fundamental level, the globe runs in a WebGL context powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mrdoob/three.js/&quot;&gt;three.js&lt;/a&gt;. We feed it data of recent pull requests that have been created and merged around the world through a JSON file. The scene is made up of five layers: a halo, a globe, the Earth’s regions, blue spikes for open pull requests, and pink arcs for merged pull requests. We don’t use any textures: we point four lights at a sphere, use about 12,000 five-sided &lt;a href=&quot;https://threejs.org/docs/#api/en/geometries/CircleBufferGeometry&quot;&gt;circles&lt;/a&gt; to render the Earth’s regions, and draw a halo with a simple custom shader on the backside of a sphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-55606&quot; src=&quot;https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/layers-loop.h264.2020-12-21-11_16_56.gif?resize=640%2C409&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;409&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To draw the Earth’s regions, we start by defining the desired density of circles (this will vary depending on the performance of your machine—more on that later), and loop through longitudes and latitudes in a nested for-loop. We start at the south pole and go upwards, calculate the circumference for each latitude, and distribute circles evenly along that line, wrapping around the sphere:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;for (let lat = -90; lat &amp;lt;= 90; lat += 180/rows) {
  const radius = Math.cos(Math.abs(lat) * DEG2RAD) * GLOBE_RADIUS;
  const circumference = radius * Math.PI * 2;
  const dotsForLat = circumference * dotDensity;
  for (let x = 0; x &amp;lt; dotsForLat; x++) {
    const long = -180 + x*360/dotsForLat;
    if (!this.visibilityForCoordinate(long, lat)) continue;

    // Setup and save circle matrix data
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine if a circle should be visible or not (is it water or land?) we load a small PNG containing a map of the world, parse its image data through canvas’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/CanvasRenderingContext2D/getImageData&quot;&gt;context.getImageData()&lt;/a&gt;, and map each circle to a pixel on the map through the visibilityForCoordinate(long, lat) method. If that pixel’s alpha is at least 90 (out of 255), we draw the circle; if not, we skip to the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After collecting all the data we need to visualize the Earth’s regions through these small circles, we create an instance of &lt;a href=&quot;https://threejs.org/docs/#api/en/geometries/CircleBufferGeometry&quot;&gt;CircleBufferGeometry&lt;/a&gt; and use an &lt;a href=&quot;https://threejs.org/docs/#api/en/objects/InstancedMesh&quot;&gt;InstancedMesh&lt;/a&gt; to render all the geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-sure-that-you-can-see-your-own-location&quot;&gt;Making sure that you can see your own location&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you enter the new GitHub homepage, we want to make sure that you can see your own location as the globe appears, which means that we need to figure where on Earth that you are. We wanted to achieve this effect without delaying the first render behind an IP look-up, so we set the globe’s starting angle to center over Greenwich, look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Date/getTimezoneOffset&quot;&gt;your device’s timezone offset&lt;/a&gt;, and convert that offset to a rotation around the globe’s own axis (in radians):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;const date = new Date();
const timeZoneOffset = date.getTimezoneOffset() || 0;
const timeZoneMaxOffset = 60*12;
rotationOffset.y = ROTATION_OFFSET.y + Math.PI * (timeZoneOffset / timeZoneMaxOffset);&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not an &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; measurement of your location, but it’s quick, and does the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;visualizing-pull-requests&quot;&gt;Visualizing pull requests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main act of the globe is, of course, visualizing all of the pull requests that are being opened and merged around the world. The data engineering that makes this possible is a different topic in and of itself, and we’ll be sharing how we make that happen in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2020-12-21-visualizing-githubs-global-community/&quot;&gt;upcoming post&lt;/a&gt;. Here we want to give you an overview of how we’re visualizing all your pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Let’s focus on pull requests being merged (the pink arcs), as they are a bit more interesting. Every merged pull request entry comes with two locations: where it was opened, and where it was merged. We map these locations to our globe, and draw a bezier curve between these two locations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;const curve = new CubicBezierCurve3(startLocation, ctrl1, ctrl2, endLocation);&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have three different orbits for these curves, and the longer the two points are apart, the further out we’ll pull out any specific arc into space. We then use instances of &lt;a href=&quot;https://threejs.org/docs/#api/en/geometries/TubeBufferGeometry&quot;&gt;TubeBufferGeometry&lt;/a&gt; to generate geometry along these paths, so that we can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://threejs.org/docs/#api/en/core/BufferGeometry.setDrawRange&quot;&gt;setDrawRange()&lt;/a&gt; to animate the lines as they appear and disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As each line animates in and reaches its merge location, we generate and animate in one solid &lt;a href=&quot;https://threejs.org/docs/#api/en/geometries/CircleBufferGeometry&quot;&gt;circle&lt;/a&gt; that stays put while the line is present, and one &lt;a href=&quot;https://threejs.org/docs/#api/en/geometries/RingBufferGeometry&quot;&gt;ring&lt;/a&gt; that scales up and immediately fades out. The ease out easings for these animations are created by multiplying a speed (here 0.06) with the difference between the target (1) and the current value (animated.dot.scale.x), and adding that to the existing scale value. In other words, for every frame we step 6% closer to the target, and as we’re coming closer to that target, the animation will naturally slow down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;// The solid circle
const scale = animated.dot.scale.x + (1 - animated.dot.scale.x) * 0.06;
animated.dot.scale.set(scale, scale, 1);

// The landing effect that fades out
const scaleUpFade = animated.dotFade.scale.x + (1 - animated.dotFade.scale.x) * 0.06;
animated.dotFade.scale.set(scaleUpFade, scaleUpFade, 1);
animated.dotFade.material.opacity = 1 - scaleUpFade;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;creative-constraints-from-performance-optimizations&quot;&gt;Creative constraints from performance optimizations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The homepage and the globe needs to perform well on a variety of devices and platforms, which early on created some creative restrictions for us, and made us focus extensively on creating a well-optimized page. Although some modern computers and tablets could render the globe at 60 FPS with antialias turned on, that’s not the case for all devices, and we decided early on to leave antialias turned off and optimize for performance. This left us with a sharp and pixelated line running along the top left edge of the globe, as the globe’s highlighted edge met the darker color of the background:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-55575&quot; src=&quot;https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/102573561-8e872300-40a3-11eb-9feb-b480aeae0564.png?resize=1024%2C513&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;513&quot; srcset=&quot;https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/102573561-8e872300-40a3-11eb-9feb-b480aeae0564.png?resize=1024%2C513?w=1230 1230w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/102573561-8e872300-40a3-11eb-9feb-b480aeae0564.png?resize=1024%2C513?w=300 300w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/102573561-8e872300-40a3-11eb-9feb-b480aeae0564.png?resize=1024%2C513?w=768 768w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/102573561-8e872300-40a3-11eb-9feb-b480aeae0564.png?resize=1024%2C513?w=1024 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This encouraged us to explore a halo effect that could hide that pixelated edge. We created one by using a custom shader to draw a gradient on the backside of a sphere that’s slightly larger than the globe, placed it behind the globe, and tilted it slightly on its side to emphasize the effect in the top left corner:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;const halo = new Mesh(haloGeometry, haloMaterial);
halo.scale.multiplyScalar(1.15);
halo.rotateX(Math.PI*0.03);
halo.rotateY(Math.PI*0.03);
this.haloContainer.add(halo);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-55576&quot; src=&quot;https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2-2.png?resize=1024%2C613&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;613&quot; srcset=&quot;https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2-2.png?resize=1024%2C613?w=1600 1600w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2-2.png?resize=1024%2C613?w=300 300w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2-2.png?resize=1024%2C613?w=768 768w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2-2.png?resize=1024%2C613?w=1024 1024w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2-2.png?resize=1024%2C613?w=1536 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This smoothed out the sharp edge, while being a much more performant operation than turning on antialias. Unfortunately, leaving antialias off also produced a fairly prominent &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moir%C3%A9_pattern&quot;&gt;moiré effect&lt;/a&gt; as all the circles making up the world came closer and closer to each other as they neared the edges of the globe. We reduced this effect and simulated the look of a thicker atmosphere by using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shader#Pixel_shaders&quot;&gt;fragment shader&lt;/a&gt; for the circles where each circle’s alpha is a function of its distance from the camera, fading out every individual circle as it moves further away:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;if (gl_FragCoord.z &amp;gt; fadeThreshold) {
  gl_FragColor.a = 1.0 + (fadeThreshold - gl_FragCoord.z ) * alphaFallOff;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;improving-perceived-speed&quot;&gt;Improving perceived speed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t know how quickly (or slowly) the globe is going to load on a particular device, but we wanted to make sure that the header composition on the homepage is always balanced, and that you got the impression that the globe loads quickly even if there’s a slight delay before we can render the first frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created a bare version of the globe using only gradients in &lt;a href=&quot;http://figma.com/&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt; and exported it as an SVG. Embedding this SVG in the HTML document adds little overhead, but makes sure that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; is immediately visible as the page loads. As soon as we’re ready to render the first frame of the globe, we transition between the SVG and the canvas element by crossfading between and scaling up both elements using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_Animations_API&quot;&gt;Web Animations API&lt;/a&gt;. Using the Web Animations API enables us to not touch the DOM at all during the transition, ensuring that it’s as stutter-free as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;const keyframesIn = [
      { opacity: 0, transform: 'scale(0.8)' },
      { opacity: 1, transform: 'scale(1)' }
    ];
const keyframesOut = [
      { opacity: 1, transform: 'scale(0.8)' },
      { opacity: 0, transform: 'scale(1)' }
    ];
const options = { fill: 'both', duration: 600, easing: 'ease' };

this.renderer.domElement.animate(keyframesIn, options);
const placeHolderAnim = placeholder.animate(keyframesOut, options);
placeHolderAnim.addEventListener('finish', () =&amp;gt; {
  placeholder.remove();
});
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;graceful-degradation-with-quality-tiers&quot;&gt;Graceful degradation with quality tiers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim at maintaining 60 FPS while rendering an as beautiful globe as we can, but finding that balance is tricky—there are thousands of devices out there, all performing differently depending on the browser they’re running and their mood. We constantly monitor the achieved FPS, and if we fail to maintain 55.5 FPS over the last 50 frames we start to degrade the quality of the scene.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are four quality tiers, and for every degradation we reduce the amount of expensive calculations. This includes reducing the pixel density, how often we raycast (figure out what your cursor is hovering in the scene), and the amount of geometry that’s drawn on screen—which brings us back to the circles that make up the Earth’s regions. As we traverse down the quality tiers, we reduce the desired circle density and rebuild the Earth’s regions, here going from the original ~12 000 circles to ~8 000:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;// Reduce pixel density to 1.5 (down from 2.0)
this.renderer.setPixelRatio(Math.min(AppProps.pixelRatio, 1.5));
// Reduce the amount of PRs visualized at any given time
this.indexIncrementSpeed = VISIBLE_INCREMENT_SPEED / 3 * 2;
// Raycast less often (wait for 4 additional frames)
this.raycastTrigger = RAYCAST_TRIGGER + 4;
// Draw less geometry for the Earth’s regions
this.worldDotDensity = WORLD_DOT_DENSITY * 0.65;
// Remove the world
this.resetWorldMap();
// Generate world anew from new settings
this.buildWorldGeometry();
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-small-part-of-a-wide-ranging-effort&quot;&gt;A small part of a wide-ranging effort&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the techniques that we use to render the globe, but the creation of the globe and the new homepage is part of a longer story, spanning multiple teams, disciplines, and departments, including design, brand, engineering, product, and communications. We’ll continue the deep-dive in this 5-part series, so come back soon or follow us on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/github&quot;&gt;@GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for all the latest updates on this project and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next up:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2020-12-21-visualizing-githubs-global-community/&quot;&gt;how we collect and use the data behind the globe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, don’t miss out on the new GitHub globe wallpapers from the GitHub Illustration Team to enjoy the globe from your desktop or mobile device:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Love the new GitHub homepage or any of the work you see here?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/about/careers&quot;&gt;Join our team&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 18:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>scalableUnicon</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How we built the GitHub globe - The GitHub Blog</og:title>
<og:description>GitHub is where the world builds software. More than 56 million developers around the world build and work together on GitHub. With our new homepage, we wanted to show how open source development transcends the</og:description>
<og:url>https://github.blog/2020-12-21-how-we-built-the-github-globe/</og:url>
<og:image>https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/102393310-07478b80-3f8d-11eb-84eb-392d555ebd29.png?fit=1200%2C630</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.blog/2020-12-21-how-we-built-the-github-globe/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Four-day week means &amp;#039;I don&amp;#039;t waste holidays on chores&amp;#039;</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-55485010</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-55485010</guid>
<description>&lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;13k1mrq-PromoHeadline&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.css-13k1mrq-PromoHeadline{font-family:ReithSerif,Helvetica,Arial,freesans,sans-serif;font-weight:500;font-size:1rem;line-height:1.25rem;color:#3F3F42;}@media (min-width:37.5rem){.css-13k1mrq-PromoHeadline{font-size:1.125rem;line-height:1.375rem;}}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-13k1mrq-PromoHeadline e1f5wbog2&quot;&gt;&lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;1hlxxic-PromoLink&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.css-1hlxxic-PromoLink:link{color:inherit;}.css-1hlxxic-PromoLink:visited{color:#696969;}.css-1hlxxic-PromoLink:link,.css-1hlxxic-PromoLink:visited{-webkit-text-decoration:none;text-decoration:none;}.css-1hlxxic-PromoLink:link:hover,.css-1hlxxic-PromoLink:visited:hover,.css-1hlxxic-PromoLink:link:focus,.css-1hlxxic-PromoLink:visited:focus{color:#B80000;-webkit-text-decoration:underline;text-decoration:underline;}.css-1hlxxic-PromoLink:link::after,.css-1hlxxic-PromoLink:visited::after{content:'';position:absolute;top:0;right:0;bottom:0;left:0;z-index:2;}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-49803024&quot; class=&quot;css-1hlxxic-PromoLink e1f5wbog6&quot;&gt;&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;false&quot;&gt;How would a 32-hour week work in practice?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 17:39:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edward</dc:creator>
<og:description>A new study suggests a four-day working week could be introduced immediately and be affordable for most firms.</og:description>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/16D0A/production/_116305439_philitworker.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Four-day week means 'I don't waste holidays on chores'</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-55485010</og:url>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-55485010</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GHC 9.0, supporting linear types</title>
<link>https://discourse.haskell.org/t/glasgow-haskell-compiler-9-0-1-rc1-now-available/1706</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://discourse.haskell.org/t/glasgow-haskell-compiler-9-0-1-rc1-now-available/1706</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GHC team is very pleased to announce the availability of the first&lt;br/&gt;release candidate of GHC 9.0.1 series. Source and binary distributions are&lt;br/&gt;available at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://downloads.haskell.org/ghc/9.0.1-rc1/&quot;&gt;usual place&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release candidate comes quite a bit later than expected after&lt;br/&gt;difficulty finding a performance neutral fix for a critical soundness&lt;br/&gt;bug, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.haskell.org/ghc/ghc/-/issues/17760&quot;&gt;#17760&lt;/a&gt;. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.haskell.org/ghc/ghc/-/wikis/migration/9.0#ghc-prim-07&quot;&gt;migration page&lt;/a&gt; for details on the solution, particularly&lt;br/&gt;if you are a library maintainer currently using the &lt;code&gt;touch#&lt;/code&gt; primop or&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;Foreign.ForeignPtr.withForeignPtr&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, this release has nevertheless seen a considerable amount of&lt;br/&gt;testing and consequently we hope that this should be the last&lt;br/&gt;pre-release before the final release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to numerous bug fixes, GHC 9.0.1 will bring a number of new&lt;br/&gt;features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first cut of the new &lt;code&gt;LinearTypes&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ghc-proposals/ghc-proposals/blob/master/proposals/0111-linear-types.rst&quot;&gt;language extension&lt;/a&gt;, allowing use&lt;br/&gt;of linear function syntax and linear record fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new bignum library (&lt;code&gt;ghc-bignum&lt;/code&gt;), allowing GHC to be more easily&lt;br/&gt;used with integer libraries other than GMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improvements in code generation, resulting in considerable&lt;br/&gt;performance improvements in some programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improvements in pattern-match checking, allowing more precise&lt;br/&gt;detection of redundant cases and reduced compilation time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementation of the “simplified subsumption” &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ghc-proposals/ghc-proposals/blob/master/proposals/0287-simplify-subsumption.rst&quot;&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;simplifying the type system and paving the way for QuickLook&lt;br/&gt;impredicativity in GHC 9.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementation of the &lt;code&gt;QualifiedDo&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ghc-proposals/ghc-proposals/blob/master/proposals/0216-qualified-do.rst&quot;&gt;extension&lt;/a&gt;, allowing more&lt;br/&gt;convenient overloading of &lt;code&gt;do&lt;/code&gt; syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improvements in compilation time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And many more. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://downloads.haskell.org/ghc/9.0.1-rc1/docs/html/users_guide/9.0.1-notes.html&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; for a full accounting of the&lt;br/&gt;changes in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, do test this release and open tickets for whatever issues you&lt;br/&gt;encounter. To help with this, we will be publishing a blog post&lt;br/&gt;describing use of our new &lt;code&gt;head.hackage&lt;/code&gt; infrastructure to ease testing&lt;br/&gt;of larger projects with Hackage dependencies later this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool to see discourse being used for these announcements!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two minor remarks. Firstly, I think this repeat of the word ‘nevertheless’ is unintended:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;quote no-group&quot; data-username=&quot;bgamari&quot; data-post=&quot;1&quot; data-topic=&quot;1706&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://discourse.haskell.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/b/3da27b/40.png&quot; class=&quot;avatar&quot;/&gt; bgamari:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, this release has nevertheless&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I notice that this text contains manual newlines which interferes with the automatic line breaking of discourse on smaller devices, such as my smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ghc-9.0.0.20201227-x86_64-unknown-mingw32-integer-simple.tar.xz&lt;/strong&gt; seems to missing &lt;strong&gt;ghci&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;/bin&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghc-9.0.0.20201227-x86_64-unknown-mingw32-integer-simple.tar.xz&lt;/code&gt; seems to missing &lt;code&gt;ghci&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;/bin&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm, interesting. I’ll need to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;edit&lt;/em&gt; This is being tracked as &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.haskell.org/ghc/ghc/-/issues/19136&quot;&gt;#19136&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In previous versions of GHC for Windows, I had the problem that &lt;strong&gt;ghc-pkg&lt;/strong&gt; couldn’t initialize a package database if the path was longer than &lt;strong&gt;MAX_PATH&lt;/strong&gt; (even with the MAX_PATH limitation lifted in Windows 10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ghc-pkg.exe +RTS -RTS init c://reallly//long//path&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It always failed while trying to create the &lt;strong&gt;package.cache&lt;/strong&gt; file, with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;openBinaryTempFileWithDefaultPermissions: invalid argument (Invalid argument)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, it seems that with the new &lt;strong&gt;–io-manager=native&lt;/strong&gt; option in 9.0, it works correctly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ghc-pkg.exe +RTS --io-manager=native -RTS init c://reallly//long//path&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(It keeps failing without &lt;strong&gt;–io-manager=native&lt;/strong&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this will make Backpack more useable on Windows. Backpack tends to generate really long paths internally and was encountering that limitation of ghc-pkg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(post withdrawn by author, will be automatically deleted in 24 hours unless flagged)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the new Windows-native IO manager will improve many things, the file path length limit being one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 15:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cosmic_quanta</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://discourse.haskell.org/uploads/default/original/1X/89166504e40f4869ea825dd70048017861ec8578.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://discourse.haskell.org/t/glasgow-haskell-compiler-9-0-1-rc1-now-available/1706?_escaped_fragment_=</og:url>
<og:title>Glasgow Haskell Compiler 9.0.1-rc1 now available!</og:title>
<og:description>The GHC team is very pleased to announce the availability of the first release candidate of GHC 9.0.1 series. Source and binary distributions are available at the usual place. This release candidate comes quite a bit later than expected after difficulty finding a performance neutral fix for a critical soundness bug, #17760. See the migration page for details on the solution, particularly if you are a library maintainer currently using the touch# primop or Foreign.ForeignPtr.withForeignPtr....</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://discourse.haskell.org/t/glasgow-haskell-compiler-9-0-1-rc1-now-available/1706?_escaped_fragment_=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: PSX Party – Online Multiplayer Playstation 1 Emulator Using WebRTC</title>
<link>https://psxparty.kosmi.io/?ref=hn1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://psxparty.kosmi.io/?ref=hn1</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0, maximum-scale=1.0, user-scalable=no, minimal-ui&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; href=&quot;https://kosmi.io/assets/favicon.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Lato&amp;amp;display=swap&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;//fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Pacifico&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Online Multiplayer PSX Emulator using WebRTC!&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;PSX Party&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;22.806060606061&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;6.8848484848485&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PSX Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PSX Party is a way to play PSX games with your friends in online multiplayer all from within your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
This is how it works:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;You create a room with a shareable link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You or a member of the room starts a ROM and becomes a host.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play PSX in online multiplayer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; id=&quot;createRoomButton&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://app.kosmi.io/createRoom?app=PSX&quot; name=&quot;createRoomButton&quot;&gt;Click here to create a room and start playing!&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;poweredBy&quot;&gt;Powered by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 14:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hauxir</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://psxparty.kosmi.io/?ref=hn1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon still hasn’t fixed its problem with bait-and-switch reviews</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/amazon-still-hasnt-fixed-its-problem-with-bait-and-switch-reviews</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/amazon-still-hasnt-fixed-its-problem-with-bait-and-switch-reviews</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/PXL_20201228_214755210-800x600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our $24 drone. You can see the missing propeller on the right.&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/PXL_20201228_214755210.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;3024&quot; data-width=&quot;4032&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; Our $24 drone. You can see the missing propeller on the right.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Timothy B. Lee / Ars Technica&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; class=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;192 posters participating, including story author&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/amazon-still-hasnt-fixed-its-problem-with-bait-and-switch-reviews/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;192 posters participating, including story author&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/amazon-still-hasnt-fixed-its-problem-with-bait-and-switch-reviews/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;272&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 192 posters participating, including story author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like thousands of other parents, I decided to get my kids a cheap drone for Christmas. I spent $24 for a plastic flying machine with rudimentary collision-avoidance capabilities. A plastic cage mostly kept small fingers away from the four propellers. The kids were delighted for the first couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then my five-year-old daughter somehow managed to get one of the propellers stuck in her hair. The drone was never the same after that. Instead of hovering in the air, it started veering crazily to one side and falling to the floor. A couple of hours later, I noticed that another propeller—not the one that had grabbed my daughter's hair—had fallen off entirely. Now when you toss it up it immediately flips over and plunges to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kids enjoyed the drone so much in its few brief hours of functionality that I thought I might buy them another one. (Hopefully this one would avoid my daughter's hair.) If I did more research and spent a bit more money, I hoped I could find a higher-quality model that wouldn't fall apart after a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went to Amazon.com, searched for &quot;children's drone,&quot; and sorted by &quot;average customer review,&quot; figuring the best-reviewed drones were likely to be high quality. They weren't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“Absolutely love this honey”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first result of my search was a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08MQ69T16/?tag=arstech20-20&quot;&gt;$23 drone&lt;/a&gt; with 6,400 reviews and an impressive five-star average rating. This looked promising!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then I actually looked at the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/product-reviews/B08MQ69T16/ref=acr_dp_hist_5?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;filterByStar=five_star&amp;amp;reviewerType=all_reviews#reviews-filter-bar&quot;&gt;five-star reviews&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/drone-fake-review.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot; data-height=&quot;608&quot; data-width=&quot;1430&quot; alt=&quot;This drone apparently has a &amp;quot;wonderful texture&amp;quot; and tastes great.&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;This drone apparently has a &amp;quot;wonderful texture&amp;quot; and tastes great.&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/drone-fake-review-640x272.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;272&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/drone-fake-review-1280x544.png 2x&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/drone-fake-review.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;608&quot; data-width=&quot;1430&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; This drone apparently has a &quot;wonderful texture&quot; and tastes great.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Absolutely love this honey,&quot; wrote one reviewer in the UK in March 2019. &quot;It's quite different from any supermarket-purchased honey I've tried.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If you're looking to have a taste of Greece without making the journey, this honey does the trick,&quot; wrote another customer the same month. A third customer wrote in January 2019 that it was &quot;dark, luxurious pine honey, not too sweet, absolutely fantastic with strained Greek yoghurt and extra cream.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I sorted the reviews by date, I saw that the most recent reviewers actually &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; bought a drone and they were overwhelmingly &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; giving it five stars. &quot;Bought this for my Grandson,&quot; a customer wrote on December 26. &quot;He played with it for 2 hours before it broke and is no longer working.&quot; He gave the drone one star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad_wrapper&quot; aria-label=&quot;In Content advertisement&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad_notice&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the older reviews were for honey. Apparently, the manufacturer had tricked Amazon into displaying thousands of reviews for an unrelated product below its drone, helping the drone to unfairly rise to the top of Amazon's search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story was similar for the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08P14T1Z2/?tag=arstech20-20&quot;&gt;second&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N6JZW33/?tag=arstech20-20&quot;&gt;third&lt;/a&gt; results in my drone search. Both had thousands of reviews with five-star averages. In both cases, many of the five-star reviews were obviously for other products—including a bottle of vodka, a bracelet, and a box of Christmas cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, the most recent reviews were almost all negative reviews from customers who had actually bought the drones. One reviewer claimed that a drone had scratched their son's face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of review bait-and-switch is not a new problem. More than two years ago, Buzzfeed's Nicole Nguyen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/nicolenguyen/amazon-review-reuse-fraud&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about other online sellers using the same scam. For example, she found that many of the five-star reviews for a highly-rated iPhone charging dock were actually reviews for a culinary torch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Amazon is sprinkled with other examples,&quot; Nguyen wrote. &quot;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2J48LrD&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;iPhone X battery case&lt;/a&gt; listing used to be for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2KMmhx0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;leather wallet phone case&lt;/a&gt;. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2kfhh8Z&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;iPhone battery case&lt;/a&gt; page was formerly a listing for &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2018-05/23/14/asset/buzzfeed-prod-web-04/sub-buzz-25056-1527101168-12.png?downsize=1600:*&amp;amp;output-format=auto&amp;amp;output-quality=auto&quot;&gt;Lightning charging cables&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2s392QU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;This Wi-Fi router&lt;/a&gt; was previously listed as &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2x6lzbW&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;nano computers&lt;/a&gt; and has been collecting reviews since 2003. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2JaOvV4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;neck brace&lt;/a&gt; was formerly a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2xnB0wD&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;shower caddy&lt;/a&gt; listing. What was formerly a listing for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2KRFxcL&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;guitar-string&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2ISj2HO&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;action&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2rZ7AzR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;gauge&lt;/a&gt; is a now a page for &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2kkqZqL&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;magnetic, glue-free eyelashes&lt;/a&gt;.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an emailed statement, an Amazon spokesman told Ars that the bogus reviews I noticed violated Amazon's policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have clear guidelines about when products should be grouped together and we have guardrails in place to prevent products from being incorrectly grouped, either due to human error or abuse,&quot; the spokesperson wrote. &quot;The detail page in question has been fixed, and we are taking appropriate action on the bad actor.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of Amazon's action, the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08MQ69T16/?tag=arstech20-20&quot;&gt;top-ranking drone&lt;/a&gt;, which previously had more than 6,000 reviews, now has only about 50 reviews and its star rating has dropped to three and a half stars. But the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08P14T1Z2/?tag=arstech20-20&quot;&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; two &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08MQ69T16/?tag=arstech20-20&quot;&gt;listings&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned above—both of which I also mentioned in a Monday email to Amazon—still have thousands of positive reviews, including a bunch of obviously bogus ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Amazon’s approach to third-party sellers is the opposite of customer obsessed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever action Amazon ultimately takes against these particular vendors Amazon's broader efforts leave a lot to be desired. A company shouldn't be able to secure a top slot in search results with such obvious subterfuge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad_wrapper&quot; aria-label=&quot;In Content advertisement&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad_notice&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The top-reviewed drones in Amazon's search results came from brands with names that seemed to be chosen at random. My drone was made by &quot;HONGXUNJIE.&quot; Other highly-rated drones on Amazon are made by &quot;SHWD,&quot; &quot;Taktoppy,&quot; &quot;SimileLine,&quot; &quot;Hffeeque,&quot; &quot;Mafix,&quot; &quot;MINOSNEO,&quot; and so forth. Clicking on the names of these &quot;brands&quot; takes you to a search result with no additional information on who made these products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon could easily require sellers to provide some basic transparency about these listings—disclosing where these manufacturers are located, how long they've been in business, and which other brands they own. This might make it easier for Amazon to punish companies that try to mislead customers with fake reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major Internet companies often insist that policing their platforms for misinformation is a logistically insurmountable task. This argument has at least superficial plausibility for companies like Facebook and Twitter that have to deal with billions of pieces of content every week. But maintaining minimum standards for Amazon product listings shouldn't be so difficult. Amazon isn't just listing information on its website, it's offering a product for sale and taking a cut of the sale price. In many cases it's warehousing and shipping the physical products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resulting revenue should give Amazon ample resources to do basic vetting of product listings. Amazon probably can't verify every claim in a product listing, but it shouldn't be hard to detect when someone takes a listing for honey and converts it into a listing for a drone. If it can't be done algorithmically, Amazon can and should hire enough human beings to review every significant change to product listings. It shouldn't be possible for someone to change a listing for honey into a listing for a drone without anyone in Seattle noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos has long claimed that his company is laser-focused on serving the needs of customers—a philosophy he calls &quot;customer obsession.&quot; In some ways, Amazon has lived up to its own hype. Amazon offers low prices, a wide selection, and fast, convenient service. Amazon continues to get better on all these fronts—just this weekend I was able to pay an extra $3 to get same-day delivery on a $9 item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But quality is also important to customers, and here Amazon seems to be anything &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; customer-obsessed. Sometimes I want the cheapest product I can get. But other times I'm willing to pay extra to get something that will last longer than a day and won't injure my children. And for some product categories, Amazon's website makes it difficult to determine which companies actually have a track record of satisfying customers.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 14:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Carducci</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/amazon-still-hasnt-fixed-its-problem-with-bait-and-switch-reviews/</og:url>
<og:title>Amazon still hasn’t fixed its problem with bait-and-switch reviews</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/PXL_20201228_214755210-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Amazon has done little to stop sellers from gaming its search algorithm.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/amazon-still-hasnt-fixed-its-problem-with-bait-and-switch-reviews/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>IntelliJ Idea 2020.3.1 Is Out with Apple Silicon Support</title>
<link>https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2020/12/intellij-idea-2020-3-1/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2020/12/intellij-idea-2020-3-1/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today is the day! It is time to announce the release of our final major release of this year – IntelliJ IDEA 2020.3. Download it from our website, install it using the Toolbox App, upgrade from inside the IDE, or, if you are an Ubuntu user, upgrade using snaps. IntelliJ IDEA 2020.3 offers a multitude of useful features, like interactive hints while debugging, Git staging support, extended support for Java 15 records and sealed classes, and more. It simplifies your daily work with endpoints, frameworks, and the profiler. The overall UX has been improved with better code completion based on mac&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 13:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jmnicolas</dc:creator>
<og:title>IntelliJ IDEA 2020.3.1 Is Out With Apple Silicon Support – IntelliJ IDEA Blog | JetBrains</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2020/12/intellij-idea-2020-3-1/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/intellij-idea_social.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>We are back with our first bug-fix release for IntelliJ IDEA 2020.3! The improved v2020.3.1 polishes the recently released features and supports Apple Silicon! That’s right, Apple fans, you can now wo</og:description>
<dc:language>en_US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2020/12/intellij-idea-2020-3-1/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nintendo&amp;#039;s use of surveillance and private investigators to target modders</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/eclipse_tt/status/1341187958838321158</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/eclipse_tt/status/1341187958838321158</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eclipse_tt/status/1341187958838321158&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/eclipse_tt/status/1341187958838321158&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25580861&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25580861&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 258&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 104&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 11:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>areoform</dc:creator>
<og:title>IntelliJ IDEA 2020.3.1 Is Out With Apple Silicon Support – IntelliJ IDEA Blog | JetBrains</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2020/12/intellij-idea-2020-3-1/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/intellij-idea_social.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>We are back with our first bug-fix release for IntelliJ IDEA 2020.3! The improved v2020.3.1 polishes the recently released features and supports Apple Silicon! That’s right, Apple fans, you can now wo</og:description>
<dc:language>en_US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2020/12/intellij-idea-2020-3-1/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“Find Satoshi” PerplexCity puzzle solved</title>
<link>https://findsatoshi.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://findsatoshi.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/satoshi.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;43&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://findsatoshi.com/main-page/satoshi/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/satoshi.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;548,748&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;satoshi&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/satoshi.jpg?w=220&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/satoshi.jpg?w=548&quot; src=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/satoshi.jpg?w=219&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-43&quot; title=&quot;satoshi&quot; srcset=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/satoshi.jpg?w=219 219w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/satoshi.jpg?w=438 438w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/satoshi.jpg?w=110 110w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 219px) 100vw, 219px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to locate a man given only his photograph and first name? The answer is YES!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2006, UK-based game company Mind Candy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perplex_City&quot;&gt;tested the theory of six degrees of separation&lt;/a&gt; as part of an Alternate Reality Game (ARG). They gave us a photograph of a man, a name, and the Japanese characters that translate to “Find me”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, thanks to the power of community, that person has been found!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you everyone who helped participate in the quest to find Satoshi!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center has-large-font-size&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 31, 2006, an alternate reality game (ARG) called &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perplex_City&quot;&gt;Perplex City&lt;/a&gt; released foil packs of &lt;a href=&quot;http://perplexcitycardcatalog.com&quot;&gt;puzzle cards ranging in difficulty from easy (“red”) to impossible (“silver”)&lt;/a&gt;. Players could solve the cards and enter solutions into the website, to appear on a leaderboard. The game ended in 2008, and the website is now defunct. (You can read more background about the game and silver-level cards &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.argn.com/2020/12/satoshi-found-perplex-city-got-a-little-less-perplexing/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puzzle #256 was a silver card titled “Billion to One”. It features a man’s photograph and the Japanese characters 私を 見つけなさい (watashi o mitsuke nasai, “find me”). A Perplex City hint line gave the clue, “My name is Satoshi.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/silver256.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;28&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://findsatoshi.com/the-facts/silver256/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/silver256.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;283,395&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;silver256&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/silver256.jpg?w=215&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/silver256.jpg?w=283&quot; src=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/silver256.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-28&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perplex City players identified the background of the photo as being in Kaysersberg, Alsace, France. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/gh8eL2aqNwyxQ44Q6&quot;&gt;View the exact location on Google Streetview here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kaysersberg.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;29&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://findsatoshi.com/the-facts/kaysersberg/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kaysersberg.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;300,219&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;kaysersberg&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kaysersberg.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kaysersberg.jpg?w=300&quot; src=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kaysersberg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-29&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FindSatoshi.com website was started in November 2006 by &lt;a href=&quot;http://lauraehall.com&quot;&gt;Laura E. Hall&lt;/a&gt; as a way to consolidate information about the search for Satoshi for quick sharing. (There were also several other sites by enthusiastic community members, as we all were eager to solve this puzzle!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura was coincidentally near Kaysersberg in December 2007 for a work trip and was able to visit the town, standing on the same spot that Satoshi stood on for his selfie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/kaysers1.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;85&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://findsatoshi.com/kaysersberg/kaysers1/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/kaysers1.gif&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;274,374&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;kaysers1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/kaysers1.gif?w=220&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/kaysers1.gif?w=274&quot; src=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/kaysers1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-85&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mind Candy confirmed additional information about the hunt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;First, Satoshi had willingly agreed to participate in the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, he had to be contacted directly. If he saw the site, he wouldn’t reach out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third, he had been told a password, which he would reveal to whoever contacted him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center has-large-font-size&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Satoshi Was Found&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early on, there was some great news coverage, including a television interview on ABC and a writeup in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/gamesblog/2007/jan/23/findsatoshi&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pogue.blogs.nytimes.com/2007/01/22/6-billion-degrees-of-separation/&quot;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. The Internet was very different in 2006&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, Laura received many emails and tips about Satoshi’s identity, but none resulted in a connection. (There was one notable email early on that pointed the search at Los Angeles—but the person didn’t reply to follow-up questions. Laura contacted them a couple of years later and they said that at that point, they had no way to contact the person they knew, who knew Satoshi.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trail was cold, with occasional surges of interest when people found the site for the first time and shared it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://asherkaye.medium.com/do-you-know-this-man-7836e54abc10&quot;&gt;Asher Isbrucker created a podcast about the project&lt;/a&gt;, interviewing Laura and Mind Candy co-founder Adrian Hon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2020, the YouTube channel &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/o1PXriQ4frU&quot;&gt;Inside A Mind did a video about the project&lt;/a&gt;, generating a lot of community interest in the project, including the revival of &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddit.com/r/FindSatoshi&quot;&gt;the Reddit forum&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/eC4YwXH5zh&quot;&gt;a Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2020, Reddit user th0may, Tom-Lucas Säger from Hamburg, Germany, used reverse image search &lt;a href=&quot;http://pimeyes.com&quot;&gt;PimEyes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/FindSatoshi/comments/kktjhc/found_someone_similar_looking_on_japanese_webpage/&quot;&gt;discovered a photograph of a man holding a beer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi1.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;115&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://findsatoshi.com/satoshi1/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi1.jpeg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1200,900&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;satoshi1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi1.jpeg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi1.jpeg?w=590&quot; src=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi1.jpeg?w=1024&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-115&quot; srcset=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi1.jpeg?w=1024 1024w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi1.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi1.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi1.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi1.jpeg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further searching revealed more photographs of this man, who lives in Nagano, Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;116&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://findsatoshi.com/satoshi2/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi2.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;396,704&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;satoshi2&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi2.jpg?w=169&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi2.jpg?w=396&quot; src=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi2.jpg?w=396&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-116&quot; srcset=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi2.jpg 396w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi2.jpg?w=84 84w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi2.jpg?w=169 169w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 396px) 100vw, 396px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;119&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://findsatoshi.com/satoshi3/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi3.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;794,397&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;satoshi3&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi3.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi3.png?w=590&quot; src=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi3.png?w=794&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-119&quot; srcset=&quot;https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi3.png 794w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi3.png?w=150 150w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi3.png?w=300 300w, https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/satoshi3.png?w=768 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 794px) 100vw, 794px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His freckles match up exactly! But we still had to get in touch with him directly—remember, he wouldn’t contact us, even if he saw the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His email was on his company website, so with the help of a friend in Japan, Laura composed an email in English and Japanese. And a day later, she received a reply confirming that this was indeed “our” Satoshi! (She has asked permission to share the text of the email, and will post here if it is granted.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creator of the puzzle, a former employer of Mind Candy, then confirmed that it was correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 years after the hunt began, Satoshi has been found!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center has-large-font-size&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Is this related to Bitcoin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; No. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satoshi_Nakamoto&quot;&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto&lt;/a&gt; is the pseudonym used by the person who created Bitcoin, but it’s not the same Satoshi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Did Satoshi consent to the search?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, this was confirmed by Mind Candy at the start of the search:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Satoshi has agreed to appear on this card and, of course, knows you’re looking for him. He isn’t hiding, but he isn’t looking for you either. If you track him down, he will happily provide you with the information required to solve this card, and will also be able to prove his identity as The Real Satoshi – you don’t need to coerce or harass him into co-operating, you just need to find him. Satoshi has no connection with any employee of Mind Candy or Mind Candy’s business partners – pursuing them for information will be of no use. Finally, Satoshi possesses no information regarding the location of Perplex City’s $200,000 Cube, so you needn’t interrogate him about that either! As always with Perplex City, you needn’t (and mustn’t) break the law – or be mean! – in the course of your adventures. With all that said. good hunting, one and all….”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Should I contact Satoshi?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Please don’t! His agreement to participate in the game was limited to this one puzzle, and that is now complete. We are very grateful to him for allowing Mind Candy to use his image for the puzzle!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; What was the password that Satoshi was supposed to share?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; It was a question in Japanese that he would have spoken to whoever found him. The answer to the question was the puzzle’s answer. The creator of the puzzle, Jey Biddulph, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeyb/status/1344372531310968837&quot;&gt;has posted an audio clip of the question on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Can you solve it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; What was Satoshi’s connection to the game makers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; From &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeyb/status/1344375834912571393&quot;&gt;Jey Biddulph’s thread&lt;/a&gt;: “Satoshi was a friend of someone who worked at a game-focused PR agency Mind Candy worked with, who were based in LA I believe. So there weren’t too many steps involved but quite a few leaps around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; How was the puzzle supposed to be solved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Ideally, through “six degrees of separation”, the hypothesis that each person is connected to everyone else in the world through six or fewer social connections. Remember that this came out in the early 2000s. The shape of the internet was very different then—Facebook started in 2004, Youtube and Reddit started in 2005, Twitter and Google Translate started in 2006. We think it’s great that the solution happened because of the strengths of the Internet today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center has-large-font-size&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank You!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wouldn’t have been possible without the hard work of thousands of people. Everyone who read about the project, shared it with a friend, and chatted about it online made this possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to James at Inside A Mind for making &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/o1PXriQ4frU&quot;&gt;the video about the Find Satoshi project&lt;/a&gt; and sharing it with your audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone on &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddit.com/r/FindSatoshi&quot;&gt;the Find Satoshi Reddit forum&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/eC4YwXH5zh&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; for the many hours of research and conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge congratulations to Reddit user th0may for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/FindSatoshi/comments/kktjhc/found_someone_similar_looking_on_japanese_webpage/&quot;&gt;finding the photo&lt;/a&gt; and making the connection to Satoshi. You did it!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Yanis Deschamps and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mtmelvil.com/&quot;&gt;Mt. MELVIL&lt;/a&gt; for help with translation and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers to Chris Warren, who created the Billion2One website back in the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to all of the Perplex City players, a very special and fun community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the entire Mind Candy team for creating Perplex City, and to Jey Biddulph, creator of the puzzle, who has been Laura’s partner for over 10 years and who did not reveal anything about the answer the entire time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center has-large-font-size&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-22590543-42-5fed22f030a5d&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20200826#blog_id=22590543&amp;amp;post_id=42&amp;amp;origin=findsatoshi.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=22590543-42-5fed22f030a5d&amp;amp;domain=findsatoshi.com&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-22590543-42-5fed22f030a5d&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 11:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>teamonkey</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Find Satoshi</og:title>
<og:description>A Six Degrees of Separation puzzle. Is it possible to locate a man given only his photograph and first name?</og:description>
<og:url>https://findsatoshi.com/</og:url>
<og:image>https://findsatoshi.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/satoshi.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://findsatoshi.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: What&amp;#039;s a side project you built to make money that hasn&amp;#039;t?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25580637</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25580637</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Ask HN: What's a side project you built to make money that hasn't?&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.8191881918819&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.1143911439114&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;25580637&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25580637&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: What's a side project you built to make money that hasn't?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.66666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_25580637&quot;&gt;235 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=notoriousarun&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;notoriousarun&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25580637&quot;&gt;14 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_25580637&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=25580637&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D25580637&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20What's%20a%20side%20project%20you%20built%20to%20make%20money%20that%20hasn't%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=25580637&amp;amp;auth=1ef7095f7b03581247d18c6bf8f0a54e5321d212&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25580637&quot;&gt;326 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;A friend pointed out a bunch of the 'tell us about your successful side project' threads suffer from a survivorship bias. They're still great for inspiration, but I suspect we could learn a lot about challenges and wrong approaches from each others' failures. So what's a side project you built hoping to generate revenue from it, that hasn't actually earned you much / any money?
&lt;p&gt;Why do you think it hasn't been as successful as you thought it would be / what would you do differently if you did it again? How much time/money did you spend building it, and what kind of iterations / improvements did you make to try and salvage it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appreciate any and all answers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71604938271605&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 10:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>notoriousarun</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25580637</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Oxford-AstraZeneca coronavirus vaccine approved for use in UK</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-55280671</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-55280671</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It comes as millions more in England are &lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;yidnqd-InlineLink&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link{color:#3F3F42;}.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited{color:#696969;}.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited{font-weight:bolder;border-bottom:1px solid #BABABA;-webkit-text-decoration:none;text-decoration:none;}.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link:hover,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited:hover,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link:focus,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited:focus{border-bottom-color:currentcolor;border-bottom-width:2px;color:#B80000;}@supports (text-underline-offset:0.25em){.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited{border-bottom:none;-webkit-text-decoration:underline #BABABA;text-decoration:underline #BABABA;-webkit-text-decoration-thickness:1px;text-decoration-thickness:1px;-webkit-text-decoration-skip-ink:none;text-decoration-skip-ink:none;text-underline-offset:0.25em;}.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link:hover,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited:hover,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link:focus,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited:focus{-webkit-text-decoration-color:currentcolor;text-decoration-color:currentcolor;-webkit-text-decoration-thickness:2px;text-decoration-thickness:2px;color:#B80000;}}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-55489932&quot; class=&quot;css-yidnqd-InlineLink e1no5rhv0&quot;&gt;placed in tier four restrictions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 07:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>agd</dc:creator>
<og:description>The first doses are due to be given on Monday, amid concern over rising coronavirus cases.</og:description>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/11F1B/production/_116299437_e1e75d49-501e-4c4e-9f1e-e0ef1c0648ec.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Covid-19: Oxford-AstraZeneca vaccine approved for use in UK</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/health-55280671</og:url>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-55280671</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>