<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Sweden gives employees unpaid time off to be entrepreneurs</title>
<link>https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2019/02/sweden-gives-all-employees-time-off-to-be-entrepreneurs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2019/02/sweden-gives-all-employees-time-off-to-be-entrepreneurs/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;75.168437575465&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last 20 or so years, workers in Sweden have enjoyed an unusual perk – a statutory right to take six months off and start their own business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;30.333333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sabbatic.com/know-taking-sabbatical-sweden/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Right to Leave to Conduct a Business Operation Act&lt;/a&gt; is one of a series of rights afforded to Swedish employees, allowing them to take time off to study or care for a family member. It’s also one of the reasons the country’s capital, Stockholm, has become Europe’s start-up capital, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2017/10/why-does-sweden-produce-so-many-startups/&quot;&gt;second only to California’s Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt; for the number of unicorns (billion-dollar tech companies) that it produces per capita.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;31.608938547486&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such Swedish start-up success is Spotify. Set up in 2006, the company floated on the New York Stock Exchange last year and has a market capitalization of $24.5 billion. Others include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2011/05/microsoft-buys-skype-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Skype, which was acquired in 2011 by Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; for $8.5 billion, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techspot.com/news/61197-microsoft-25-billion-acquisition-mojang-suddenly-looks-like.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Mojang, the company behind Minecraft&lt;/a&gt;, which was also acquired by Microsoft, in 2014 for $2.5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who’s been in full-time employment for at least six months is entitled to apply for the unpaid sabbatical, or tjänstledighet, as it’s called in Sweden. Employers can only turn the request down if the employee is vital to the business’s operations. Also, your new idea can’t compete with your existing employer, nor cause them any significant inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; loading=&quot;lazyloadjs&quot; class=&quot;js-lazyload&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.weforum.org/editor/fhLxwPNEBWibOoZnV7tORlWnGj_wJPj_Hs-gpVVqv0E.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; loading=&quot;lazyloadjs&quot; class=&quot;js-lazyload&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.weforum.org/editor/fhLxwPNEBWibOoZnV7tORlWnGj_wJPj_Hs-gpVVqv0E.png&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://assets.weforum.org/editor/large_n286BYcSJTOmviS0-DAEARnGTVwUxKjQtRebwZKY3wU.png 850w, https://assets.weforum.org/editor/medium_8Cx9Gb_6qNJjnff47r3wcPCnlKqoXs-36p0l_Bqoenw.png 640w, https://assets.weforum.org/editor/small_8GZz7RIMPqYWRrn9jDIvF_6kA1RnuwTML9noxHM-RfE.png 320w&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image: CBInsights, Global Tech Hubs Report&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do the hustle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a growing trend in many countries for people to develop a business venture outside of regular working hours, then devote their free time to nurturing it. A side hustle, as it’s often called.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s an outlook that tallies with that of the gig economy – spare time, spare capacity, spare resources are all just waiting to be monetized. That might include delivering takeaway food, signing up to be a taxi driver or a courier for a few hours a day, or making your own arts and crafts items to sell via the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;38.601252609603&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the US Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS), there were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2018/jun/07/america-gig-economy-work-bureau-labor-statistics&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;16.5 million Americans working in the gig economy&lt;/a&gt;. By comparison, there are 80,000 people employed in the US coal industry. Although the BLS took in a broad swathe of work, including independent contractors, on-call workers, temporary help agency workers, and workers provided by contract firms, its figures demonstrate the extent to which alternative approaches to employment are entering the economic mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;41&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Nordic countries, equality is famously hard-wired into society and the economy – the so-called Nordic Model. Free education and healthcare are part of a comprehensive tax-funded welfare system with correspondingly high rates of tax. There are high levels of unionization within the labour force, low levels of corruption, and a vibrant free-market economy. There is an emphasis on supporting people when needed, enabling them to prosper, and ensuring equality. When it comes to the issue of parental leave, the Scandinavian nations are regularly cited as a model for other countries to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;41&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All new parents in Sweden, for example, are entitled to 16 months paid parental leave, during which they receive around 80% of their salary. Fathers are expected to take some of that leave, too. It’s a similar story in Norway, which introduced shared parental leave in 1977. In 1993, it followed that up by setting a 10-week quota for fathers to take during the parental leave period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Denmark, parents are entitled to 52 weeks, with mothers able to take four weeks before the birth of their child and 14 weeks after. Danish fathers can take two weeks off work during the first 14 weeks, then both parents can share the remaining 32 weeks between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The need for innovation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;27.989528795812&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest World Economic Forum &lt;a href=&quot;http://reports.weforum.org/global-competitiveness-report-2018/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Global Competitiveness report&lt;/a&gt; highlights that innovation is an imperative for countries across the globe - but most are failing to make it an engine of growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st__content-block st__content-block--text&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany, the US and Switzerland were all named innovation powerhouses, but for most countries innovation capacity remains limited, is very localized or exists in just a few sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; loading=&quot;lazyloadjs&quot; class=&quot;js-lazyload&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.weforum.org/editor/DoIT2lpbdH9eyLYj7WSN6XigAKZ3UAGrXj2-bQDdmgQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; loading=&quot;lazyloadjs&quot; class=&quot;js-lazyload&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.weforum.org/editor/DoIT2lpbdH9eyLYj7WSN6XigAKZ3UAGrXj2-bQDdmgQ.png&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://assets.weforum.org/editor/large_6EgGfD9sSUzVgR2PXUbnDj63NsdwAKUMPODhvL9Foa0.png 850w, https://assets.weforum.org/editor/medium_vrGnl-DmwzGFA0ILjN-A-LjKuhb0AXD6veMfHVYOUow.png 640w, https://assets.weforum.org/editor/small_iXggwoSmv7tZebYKVCdOl8lKnyxUIDNFIVavW73qgxQ.png 320w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-gtm-subcontext=&quot;article-footer&quot; readability=&quot;29.197080291971&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-article__license&quot; readability=&quot;28.509090909091&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License and Republishing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-article__license__description&quot;&gt;World Economic Forum articles may be republished in accordance with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weforum.org/about/privacy-and-terms-of-use&quot;&gt;Terms of Use&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-footer&quot; readability=&quot;8.312101910828&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article-footer__source&quot;&gt;The views expressed in this article are those of the author alone and not the World Economic Forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 17:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>saadalem</dc:creator>
<og:title>Sweden gives all employees time off to be entrepreneurs</og:title>
<og:description>Anyone who’s been in full-time employment for at least six months is entitled to apply for the unpaid sabbatical.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2019/02/sweden-gives-all-employees-time-off-to-be-entrepreneurs/</og:url>
<og:image>https://assets.weforum.org/editor/fhLxwPNEBWibOoZnV7tORlWnGj_wJPj_Hs-gpVVqv0E.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2019/02/sweden-gives-all-employees-time-off-to-be-entrepreneurs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Signs you’re working in a feature factory</title>
<link>https://cutle.fish/blog/12-signs-youre-working-in-a-feature-factory</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cutle.fish/blog/12-signs-youre-working-in-a-feature-factory</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cutle.fish/static/5f044b5f6162e77c50a27026ad114169/2b872/1*A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; alt=&quot;1 A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg&quot; title=&quot;1 A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg&quot; src=&quot;https://cutle.fish/static/5f044b5f6162e77c50a27026ad114169/c35de/1*A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/static/5f044b5f6162e77c50a27026ad114169/afcd2/1*A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg.jpg 300w, /static/5f044b5f6162e77c50a27026ad114169/82472/1*A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg.jpg 600w, /static/5f044b5f6162e77c50a27026ad114169/c35de/1*A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg.jpg 1200w, /static/5f044b5f6162e77c50a27026ad114169/98235/1*A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg.jpg 1800w, /static/5f044b5f6162e77c50a27026ad114169/d7d8f/1*A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg.jpg 2400w, /static/5f044b5f6162e77c50a27026ad114169/2b872/1*A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg.jpg 2560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note: This was written in 2016. I recently — in late 2019 — &lt;a href=&quot;https://amplitude.com/blog/12-signs-youre-working-in-a-feature-factory-3-years-later&quot;&gt;wrote a post about some things I've learned since then&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve used the term *Feature Factory *at a couple conference talks over the past two years. I started using the term when a software developer friend complained that he was “just sitting in the factory, cranking out features, and sending them down the line.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you know if you’re working in a feature factory?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No measurement&lt;/strong&gt;. Teams do not measure the impact of their work. Or, if measurement happens, it is done in isolation by the product management team and selectively shared. You have no idea if your work worked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rapid shuffling of teams&lt;/strong&gt; and projects (aka Team Tetris). Instead of compelling missions or initiatives, teams deal in feature and project assignments. Chronic multitasking and over-utilization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@johnpcutler/success-theater-b60a1666fe67#.5zjj95jy4&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success theater&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; around “shipping” with little discussion about impact. You can tell a great deal about an organization by what it celebrates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrequent (acknowledged) failures&lt;/strong&gt; and scrapped work. No removed features. Primary measure of success is delivered features, not delivered outcomes. Work is rarely discarded in light of data and learning. Often the team lacks the prerequisite safety to admit misfires&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No connection to core metrics&lt;/strong&gt;. Infrequent discussions about desired customer and business outcomes. Team cannot connect work to key business and customer satisfaction metrics. Impossible to connect iterations to “what matters most”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No PM retrospectives&lt;/strong&gt;. Product managers do not conduct regular retrospectives on the quality of their product decisions and compare expected benefits to actual benefits. Developers have “passing tests”, but product managers do not. Product managers view velocity and output as their key performance indicator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obsessing about prioritization&lt;/strong&gt;. Mismatch between prioritization rigor (deciding what gets worked on) and validation rigor (deciding if it was, in fact, the right thing to work on). Prioritization rigor is designed exclusively to temper internal agendas so that people “feel confident”. Lots of work goes into determining which ideas to work on, leaving little leeway for adjustments and improvisation based on data. &lt;strong&gt;Roadmaps show a list of features&lt;/strong&gt;, not areas of focus and/or outcomes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No tweaking&lt;/strong&gt;. Once work is “done”, the team moves immediately on to the next “project”, leaving no time to iterate based on qualitative and quantitative data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Culture of hand-offs&lt;/strong&gt;. Front-loaded process in place to “get ahead of the work” so that items are “ready for engineering”. Team is not directly involved in research, problem exploration, or experimentation and validation. Once work is shipped, team has little contact with support, customer success, and sales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Large batches&lt;/strong&gt;. Without the mandate to experiment, features are delivered in single large batches instead of delivering incrementally. You might still work in sprints (yay, we’re “Agile”), but nothing new is reaching customers at the conclusion of each sprint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chasing upfront revenue.&lt;/strong&gt; Features are implemented to close new deals. While not inherently wrong, the economic justifications are often flimsy (at best), and fail to account for the non-linear increase in product complexity (you make the quarter, but you pay for it many times over later). Again, this reinforces the idea that features are the unit of value measurement. Product decisions lack a sound economic grounding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shiny objects&lt;/strong&gt;. Low visibility for refactoring work and debt work-down. Low visibility for overall value delivery capabilities. As mentioned, primary measure of success is new feature output. Little appreciation for the health of the whole product as opposed to shiny new objects. Little awareness around impact of new features on usability (and maintainability and extensibility) of existing product For translations of this post see: &lt;a href=&quot;http://JeongMin%20Kwon&quot;&gt;Korean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve written about addressing this problem. Check out these posts:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 15:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aphextron</dc:creator>
<og:title>12 Signs You’re Working in a Feature Factory</og:title>
<og:description>Writing on all things product by John Cutler (@johncutlefish).</og:description>
<og:image>https://cutle.fish/static/5f044b5f6162e77c50a27026ad114169/8539d/1*A9HaI7x2MdvkTn48D9a0wg.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cutle.fish/blog/12-signs-youre-working-in-a-feature-factory/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ESbuild – A fast JavaScript bundler and minifier in Go</title>
<link>https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a JavaScript bundler and minifier. It packages up JavaScript code for distribution on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why build another JavaScript build tool? The current build tools for the web are at least an order of magnitude slower than they should be. I'm hoping that this project serves as an &quot;existence proof&quot; that our JavaScript tooling can be much, much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Benchmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use case I have in mind is packaging a large codebase for production. This includes minifying the code, which reduces network transfer time, and producing source maps, which are important for debugging errors in production. Ideally the build tool should also build quickly without having to warm up a cache first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main benchmark approximates a large codebase by duplicating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mrdoob/three.js&quot;&gt;three.js&lt;/a&gt; library 10 times and building a single bundle from scratch, without any caches. For this benchmark, esbuild is &lt;strong&gt;10-100x faster&lt;/strong&gt; than the other JavaScript bundlers I tested (webpack, rollup, and parcel). The benchmark can be run with &lt;code&gt;make bench-three&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/blob/master/images/benchmark.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/raw/master/images/benchmark.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Relative slowdown&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Absolute speed&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Output size&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;esbuild&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;0.58s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;1x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;1028 kloc/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;5.83mb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;rollup + terser&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;43.56s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;75x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;14 kloc/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;5.96mb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;webpack&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;47.85s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;83x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;12 kloc/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;5.82mb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;parcel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;120.45s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;208x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;5 kloc/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;5.90mb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm running esbuild with &lt;code&gt;--bundle --minify --sourcemap&lt;/code&gt;. I used the &lt;code&gt;rollup-plugin-terser&lt;/code&gt; plugin because rollup itself doesn't support minification. Webpack uses &lt;code&gt;--mode=production --devtool=sourcemap&lt;/code&gt;. Parcel uses the default options. The tests were done on a 6-core 2019 MacBook Pro with 16gb of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is it fast?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It's written in Go, a language that compiles to native code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parsing, printing, and source map generation are all fully parallelized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything is done in very few passes without expensive data transformations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code is written with speed in mind, and tries to avoid unnecessary allocations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently supported:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CommonJS modules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ES6 modules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bundling with static binding of ES6 modules using &lt;code&gt;--bundle&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full minification with &lt;code&gt;--minify&lt;/code&gt; (whitespace, identifiers, and mangling)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full source map support when &lt;code&gt;--sourcemap&lt;/code&gt; is enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JSX-to-JavaScript conversion for &lt;code&gt;.jsx&lt;/code&gt; files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile-time identifier substitutions via &lt;code&gt;--define&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Path substitution using the &lt;code&gt;browser&lt;/code&gt; field in &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic detection of &lt;code&gt;baseUrl&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;tsconfig.json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a hobby project that I wrote over the 2019-2020 winter break. I believe that it's relatively complete and functional. However, it's brand new code and probably has a lot of bugs. It also hasn't yet been used in production by anyone. Use at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also keep in mind that this doesn't have complete support for lowering modern language syntax to earlier language versions. Right now only class fields and the nullish coalescing operator are lowered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't personally want to run a large open source project, so I'm not looking for contributions at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The executable can be built using &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;, assuming you have the Go language toolchain installed. Prebuilt binaries are currently available on npm under separate packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;npm install -g esbuild-linux-64   # for Linux
npm install -g esbuild-darwin-64  # for macOS
npm install -g esbuild-windows-64 # for Windows
npm install -g esbuild-wasm       # for all other platforms
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This adds a command called &lt;code&gt;esbuild&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The command-line interface takes a list of entry points and produces one bundle file per entry point. Here are the available options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Usage:
  esbuild [options] [entry points]

Options:
  --name=...            The name of the module
  --bundle              Bundle all dependencies into the output files
  --outfile=...         The output file (for one entry point)
  --outdir=...          The output directory (for multiple entry points)
  --sourcemap           Emit a source map
  --error-limit=...     Maximum error count or 0 to disable (default 10)
  --target=...          Language target (default esnext)

  --minify              Sets all --minify-* flags
  --minify-whitespace   Remove whitespace
  --minify-identifiers  Shorten identifiers
  --minify-syntax       Use equivalent but shorter syntax

  --define:K=V          Substitute K with V while parsing
  --jsx-factory=...     What to use instead of React.createElement
  --jsx-fragment=...    What to use instead of React.Fragment

  --trace=...           Write a CPU trace to this file
  --cpuprofile=...      Write a CPU profile to this file

Example:
  # Produces dist/entry_point.js and dist/entry_point.js.map
  esbuild --bundle entry_point.js --outdir=dist --minify --sourcemap
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 15:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>todotask</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/406394?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>evanw/esbuild</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/evanw/esbuild</og:url>
<og:description>An extremely fast JavaScript bundler and minifier. Contribute to evanw/esbuild development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blender 2.82</title>
<link>https://www.blender.org/press/blender-2-82-released/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.blender.org/press/blender-2-82-released/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_69554&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-69554&quot; src=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/blender_282_pr.png?x71496&quot; alt=&quot;Blender 2.82&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-69554&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/blender_282_pr.png 1280w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/blender_282_pr-512x288.png 512w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/blender_282_pr-768x432.png 768w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/blender_282_pr-480x270.png 480w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-69554&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Blender 2.82&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The second update of the Blender 2.80 milestone release is here! With again over a thousand fixes and several important updates that were planned for the 2.8 series. In this release you will find UDIM and USD support, MantaFlow fluids and smoke simulation, AI denoising, GPencil improvements, and much more!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/download/releases/2-82/&quot;&gt;Check the full release log.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blender team also released a planning &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.blender.org/2020/01/2020-blender-big-projects/&quot;&gt;for projects in 2020&lt;/a&gt;. Focus for this year will be on quality and finishing up projects that already started years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release has been made possible by the fantastic community of contributors and developers on blender.org. That’s including artists making demos, people submitting bug reports, and over 3700 individuals and companies who &lt;a href=&quot;https://fund.blender.prg&quot;&gt;joined the Development Fund&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to this financial support, the Blender project can enable almost 20 people to contribute to Blender full-time now. An amazing milestone for free/open source 3D creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amsterdam 2020-02-14&lt;br/&gt;Ton Roosendaal, Chairman&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 13:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>app4soft</dc:creator>
<og:title> Blender 2.82 released — blender.org</og:title>
<og:description>Home of the Blender project - Free and Open 3D Creation Software</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.blender.org/press/blender-2-82-released/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/blender_282_pr-480x270.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.blender.org/press/blender-2-82-released/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Developer salary spreadsheet compiled from tweets</title>
<link>https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1-xIgk7Mw1S5DXTZSbKBgxlsQAn7XGIu7Mfy72lSVHKk/edit#gid=129993618</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1-xIgk7Mw1S5DXTZSbKBgxlsQAn7XGIu7Mfy72lSVHKk/edit#gid=129993618</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1-xIgk7Mw1S5DXTZSbKBgxlsQAn7XGIu7Mfy72lSVHKk/edit#gid=129993618&quot;&gt;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1-xIgk7Mw1S5DXTZSbKBgxlsQAn7XGIu7Mfy72lSVHKk/edit#gid=129993618&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22334702&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22334702&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 347&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 297&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ollieglass</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1-xIgk7Mw1S5DXTZSbKBgxlsQAn7XGIu7Mfy72lSVHKk/htmlview?sle=true</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ActivityPub, the secret weapon of the Fediverse</title>
<link>https://homehack.nl/activitypub-the-secret-weapon-of-the-fediverse/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://homehack.nl/activitypub-the-secret-weapon-of-the-fediverse/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://fediverse.party/&quot;&gt;Fediverse&lt;/a&gt; is the name for a number of interconnected (federated) social networks running on free and open software on hundreds or even thousands of servers all over the globe. These servers and networks are owned and maintained by a community of people and, contrary to networks like Facebook or Twitter, are not owned by a single corporation or organisation. Therefore all data and control of that data is distributed over individuals and (mostly) small organisations. That all users of these servers are able to socially interact with each other is because of the protocol behind most of the Fediverse, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ActivityPub&quot;&gt;ActivityPub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;857&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://homehack.nl/fediverse_logo_proposal/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/homehack.nl/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Fediverse_logo_proposal.png?fit=800%2C800&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;800,800&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Fediverse_logo_proposal&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Fediverse logo, 5 nodes in pentagon shape with all diagonals, multicoloured. Logo created to represent the Fediverse. Creative Commons CC0 1.0 Universal Public Domain Dedication. Created by Eukombos&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/homehack.nl/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Fediverse_logo_proposal.png?fit=300%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/homehack.nl/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Fediverse_logo_proposal.png?fit=800%2C800&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/homehack.nl/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Fediverse_logo_proposal.png?resize=500%2C500&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;The Fediverse logo&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-857&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;Fediverse logo, 5 nodes in pentagon shape with all diagonals, multicoloured Creative Commons CC0 1.0 Universal Public Domain Dedication. Created by Eukombos
&lt;p&gt;Now the boring stuff (which is actually very exciting). ActivityPub is a social networking protocol that enables the user (that’s you) to create, update and delete content over the network. In other words when you type a message, like a video or share a photo, the protocol ensures that these messages are exchanged properly. But that’s not what makes ActivityPub special. Other social networking protocols do the same thing, right? However ActivityPub is both open source software and it’s decentralized. This means that any developer can use the protocol to create an application for social media be it a micro-blog, a photo sharing app or a video sharing platform. Others (in fact anyone) can download the application, install it on a server and join an existing network (federate). Now this server becomes publicly available and you as a user can create an account and automatically join the Fediverse. Popular applications are &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmastodon.org/&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; (microblogging), &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma&quot;&gt;Pleroma&lt;/a&gt; (microblogging), &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinpeertube.org/en/&quot;&gt;PeerTube&lt;/a&gt; (video-streaming) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixelfed.org/&quot;&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt; (image sharing)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ActivityPub prevents that a social media platform becomes a silo (see photo) that can’t communicate with other platforms. Not only can a Mastodon user communicate with users on different servers on Mastodon, perhaps more importantly this user can also communicate e.g with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://friendi.ca/&quot;&gt;Friendica&lt;/a&gt; (macroblogging) user or a Pleroma user. These are totally different networks that all support ActivityPub. But this is even taken a step further where that same Mastodon user can follow his favourite PeerTube channel or someone that shares great photos on Pixelfed. This is like you were able to follow someone with your Twitter account on YouTube or Instagram. This also means that this Mastodon user can comment or like the PeerTube video from his/her Mastodon user interface. This is the true power of ActivityPub!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already mentioned a few but there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://fediverse.party/&quot;&gt;dozens of applications that support ActivityPub&lt;/a&gt;. All have their different purposes and one has more ActivityPub integration than the other. One that I would like to highlight is &lt;a href=&quot;https://funkwhale.audio/&quot;&gt;Funkwhale&lt;/a&gt;. Funkwhale is a music streaming application. Like all applications mentioned above anyone can create a Funkwhale server and federate with other Funkwhale servers. The user is able to stream music from a different server, but also create favourites, make a playlist etc. Currently Funkwhale isn’t integrated with the rest of the Fediverse. Now recently the Funkwhale head developer, Eliot Berriot, started integration and made it possible to share music on Mastodon (perhaps also in Pleroma and Friendica but I haven’t tried that). This all works seamlessly thanks to ActivityPub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Funkwhale example demonstrates the power of ActivityPub. Applications with different purposes can work hand in hand. It avoids that Mastodon, which is by far the largest party in the Fediverse, becomes de-facto a silo. The Fediverse is supposed to be diverse and Funkwhale and other apps are enforcing that. In January 2018, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web_Consortium&quot;&gt;World Wide Web Consortium&lt;/a&gt; (W3C) published the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/6785&quot;&gt;ActivityPub standard as a Recommendation&lt;/a&gt;. This is an important step for the acceptance of ActivityPub by developers and leads to more applications supporting ActivityPub therefore creating even greater diversity in the Fediverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the support of W3C the future of ActivityPub and the Fediverse looks bright. Chances are that more networks will start supporting ActivityPub and will join the Fediverse. And that both developers and (wannabe) admins adopt ActivityPub either for their app or their own server. I’m convinced that this is the only viable way out of the mess created of Big Tech companies like Facebook or Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further listening about the Federation and ActivityPub:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a90a46e04d18b0f85b8b54368a30dfe4?s=42&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&quot; srcset=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a90a46e04d18b0f85b8b54368a30dfe4?s=84&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&quot; class=&quot;avatar avatar-42 photo&quot; height=&quot;42&quot; width=&quot;42&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;author-title&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author-heading&quot;&gt;Author:&lt;/span&gt; eribuijs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;I’m an #privacy, #opensource, #opendata and #openstandards advocate. I’m holding a grudge against Big Tech, big IP holders and authoritharian governments. Furthermore I’m a #3Ddesigner, #3Dprinter, #webdesigner and overall #DIY guy. But most of all I’m a free man. &lt;a class=&quot;author-link&quot; href=&quot;https://homehack.nl/author/eribuijs/&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot;&gt;View all posts by eribuijs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 08:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>app4soft</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>ActivityPub, the secret weapon of the Fediverse</og:title>
<og:url>https://homehack.nl/activitypub-the-secret-weapon-of-the-fediverse/</og:url>
<og:description>If you’re new to the Fediverse you should know about ActivityPub and why it gives the Fediverse an edge over other social networks.</og:description>
<og:image>https://i2.wp.com/homehack.nl/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/1280px-ActivityPub-logo.png?fit=1200%2C312&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://homehack.nl/activitypub-the-secret-weapon-of-the-fediverse/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The dystopian world of software engineering interviews</title>
<link>https://www.jarednelsen.dev/posts/The-horrifically-dystopian-world-of-software-engineering-interviews</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.jarednelsen.dev/posts/The-horrifically-dystopian-world-of-software-engineering-interviews</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;trials&quot;&gt;Trials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My phone goes off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hello, this is Jared.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hi there. I’m calling about a phone interview with Giant Search and Advertising Company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes! I’ve been looking forward to our call!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes. Can you write an algorithm to find the Kth highest value in a binary tree?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pause. I am completely blanking. I haven’t seen one like this before. The blank Google doc stares back at me with the cursor blinking in slow motion. I cobble something together as a first pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Can you write a test case for this algorithm?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure. I could possibly do that if I wasn’t completely hazing over and my inner ego was not melting under the blazing fury of a dream dying before my very eyes. Is this what all my hard work over the past few month come down to? I had decided that it was time I found a new position around January of 2019. As if the Software Engineering Gods on high had blessed this very thought, a Giant Search and Advertising Comapny recruiter reach out to me on LinkedIn about a phone interview. This was perfect!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t the first time this had happened. As a bright eyed young engineer just out of school I had recently begun my first job and was doing quite well. But then my world got turned upside down. I was working on a particularly nasty bug and did what any self respecting software engineer would do before trying to solve it myself: Google it. As soon as I hit Enter with my suitably obtuse query in the search box the screen faded to black and I was dropped into a shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;You are speaking our language... Would you like to take a challenge?
1. Yes
2. No thanks&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I nearly spat out my lukewarm Costco coffee. I was about to jump up and scream for my coworkers to come look. But then I became suddenly concerned that I was hallucinating and realized I would be hyper embarrassed if this proved to be true. Fearing that I was about to have an out-of-body experience, I pressed 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Given an array nums containing n + 1 integers where each integer is between 1 and n (inclusive), 
prove that at least one duplicate number must exist.  Assume that there is only one duplicate
number and find the duplicate one.

You have 24 hours!&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a small heart attack. After I managed to resuscitate myself with another shot of Costco coffee I realized that I could totally do this. I already had a plan in my head about how to solve it. So I did. As soon as I hit submit I was given another problem to solve. This continued 5 more times with each challenge getting progressively harder. After I submitted the final challenge I was greeted by another message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Congratulations! The code is strong with this one! Would you like the opportunity to interview
with Giant Search and Advertising Company?&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was it. My whole professional world shifted. One of the most powerful organizations in the world had reached into the psyche of my 22 year old brain and rewrote a register. None of the previous goals I had in my career mattered. Prior to this experience I was blissfully unaware that a top tier company like this was an option for me. But apparently I had somehow proved worthy enough for consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phone interview was a lot like the nightmares that I had leading up to it. I was asked to program Conway’s Game of Life in 45 minutes. I actually did pretty well. I wrote the whole program and tested it to prove that it was working. I got the rejection the next day. Internally I was both crushed and confused. What had I done wrong exactly? Hadn’t all of the challenges I did counted for anything? Why was I expected to write such a challenging algorithm in so short a time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In light of my first experience in competing at that level, I decided that this time around I was going to up my game. My interview was in April of this year. I built myself a 3 month study plan and tore after it. I got up and did three practice problems in the morning, went into work to work the full day, came home for a run and a bite to eat and went back to my office for a quiet working environment to do more practice problems. In a three month period I did a total of 114 practice problems. Arrays, Backtracking, Binary Search, Binary Trees, Breadth First Search, Depth First Search, Dynamic Programming, Graphs, Greedy Algorithms, Hashing, Linked Lists, Probability, Sorting, Stacks, and Tries were some of the topics I studied. How could I not succeed with all of this preparation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tribulations&quot;&gt;Tribulations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interview with Giant Search and Advertising Company ended in flames. I couldn’t solve the problem. But that was only the beginning of the madness this year. At first I was very strategic about what companies I applied to. I didn’t just want ‘a’ job, but the ‘right’ job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next was a self driving car company. I got a response almost immediately after submitting my application and set up an initial code screen. The interviewer answered in a huff and with a very thick accent asked me to code up a very involved image filtration algorithm. I wrote it and asked for feedback. “This looks very good!”, he said. I got a canned rejection email the day after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came an analytics company that asked me to do a take home challenge. The challenge was a three sentence blurb. I did the best job I could on it and wrote a very involved multithreaded image processing system. I got a polite no from the recruiter and when I pressed for feedback I was told that my implementation was “too inefficient”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that was a payment processing company. I had a great call with a recruiter and she raved about how well my resume fit with the job description. The next day I got an email from her saying that they couldn’t find a position for my skillset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another instance was with a Giant Social Media Platform Company. “Jared! Thanks for your application! I think you would be a great addition to Giant Social Media Platform Company! I’ve sent your application directly to the hiring manager at your regional office!” Eight minutes after this email I get an automated rejection email saying that my skills did not fit the position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were innumerable number of third party recruiters that reached out to me. All of them ended in nothing. Perhaps my favorite was an audio processing company. The recruiter reached out and said that the team was very excited to talk to me after reviewing my resume and she would set up a call with the hiring manager. A week went by and I reached out to see what was going on. The recruiter said that she had gotten in touch with the hiring manager and that he didn’t think my skillset matched up. This made complete sense to me and I went on about my day… However, as a test I submitted my resume to a different job posting of theirs and had a different recruiter reach out to me immediately. I was astounded when they immediately set up a phone screen. I have to admit that I only put on a mediocre show for this one. I got a canned rejection email the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I finally got to an on-site interview with Giant Social Media Company. I went through a series of programming questions with a number of people across four different interviews and came up with correct and compiling solutions to all of them. Along the way I was asked a series of convoluted and tough “Tell me about a time when…” questions. This was refreshing as it had been the first time in my job search that I had been asked about my experience and acumen as an engineer at all. Then came the final System Design interview. The interviewer promptly gave me a small system to design. I started talking through my solution and was questioned along the way. Finally, we get to a point where he said “Okay, so say we have a Micro Service architecture… Can you design…?” I promptly told him that I don’t have any experience with Microservices. He looked at me quizzically and asked “You don’t? …” I said, “Thats correct. I tried to clearly spell out my skill set and background in desktop, embedded systems, and mobile development on my resume.” He pauses in the way where someone realizes he or she made a mistake. Great! So this man is telling me that after I had spent 4 months studying for this interview, spent virtually every waking hour outside of work completing practice problems, and rehearsed how to present my background in soft skills questions that he didn’t bother to spend 10 minutes to glance at my resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;analysis&quot;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on bemoaning the many disappointing experiences I had on this slog of a job search. There were many of them. 23 interviews and I didn’t get a single offer. I have always sought to be completely honest and humble with myself and others about my abilities. I didn’t apply to jobs that called for years of experience I didn’t have or for skills that were not near at hand. Sure, I was intending to move back to the web space from the embedded space but I have had two years of experience as a web engineer on top of my other experience as a mobile applications developer and a machine learning algorithm researcher. I fully acknowledge that I have an innumerable number of ways to grow and a lot of on-the-job learning to do. But on the other hand I am very confident I have to skills to get up and running with a new job very quickly. Software Engineering is, in my view, a distilled art form defined by learning and new experience. No Software Engineer seeks to become only somewhat proficient and stay there for the rest of his or her career. At least I hope not: those who do so will very quickly get left behind in the dust. So what is really going on here? After going through this dystopian process for so long I thought I would break down and analyze my observations and then reevaluate to get a clearer picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are being consumed by our own mythology&lt;/strong&gt; - Virtually every popular conception of a software engineer, especially in today’s tech-crazed world, loves the idea of a lone maverick coder who can crack any algorithm on demand with ease. The archetypal software engineer is socially disengaged, anti-structure, and highly idealistic. He or she is fiercely independent and doesn’t need to communicate with anyone in order to get the job done. It follows that because we unconsciously believe in this archetype, I as an engineer must pass a screen that tests for these traits to even warrant speaking to someone who knows anything about the position. But, to the best of our collective knowledge, these traits actually negatively indicate a high-performing candidate. Software companies are made up of collections of one or more software teams. Software teams are collections of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;In order to succeed in a group with a common goal individuals must:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communicate with one another&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - If one member of the team does not know what the goal is it will drag the entire team down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communicate with non-software engineers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - No matter how many software engineers dislike the notion, it is true that it takes more than just software engineers to run a software company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Take direction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - More often than not the direction for a product comes from outside the software team. This is sort of the point of working for an organization after all: you are bringing a vision to life that is not yours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learn from one another&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - There are always imbalances about who knows what on a team. This is true for both product-knowledge and technical skills. There is a weighted balance in the collective technical skill set for the collective team. This is why we have the hierarchy of experience and distribution of responsibilities. This balance is never, and should never be, static. Someone should always be learning and there is always someone to teach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In conclusion to this point, it seems that the popular conception of what is to be a software engineer is driving the structure of the hiring process more that the traits that actually make software engineers successful on the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We all know algorithm challenges are a contrived game&lt;/strong&gt; - This point is a little tough to elucidate as there are a number of facets to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How valuable are algorithms anyway?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - There are many points of view to this question. However much I disagree with them, there are parties out there who believe that you can be a perfectly good software engineer without knowing a darned thing about how algorithms work, or even a digital computer for that matter. My counterpoint is that there is a difference between an aircraft mechanic and an aerospace engineer. Which one is more valuable and which one would you rather be? I’ll leave that thought process up to you. A better question to ask might be an inquiry into how relevant algorithms are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How relevant are algorithms anyway?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - As much as I believe that knowledge of algorithms and how a computer works is important to be a successful and valuable software engineer, I also know, and everyone else knows, that this knowledge is rarely used on the job. The “Not Invented Here” mindset is pervasive and imposed in teams. For &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;many and most&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; applications this is good policy. If there is a well tested and sure fire library that is able to fill a need it is safer and more appropriate to incorporate it than reinventing the wheel. Round wheels are good wheels so to speak. So, if one were to consider algorithm challenges in relation to this question, it makes one wonder why the heck we even ask these questions anyway. If so many people in the industry think they are not valuable in a Software Engineer’s daily tasks then why do we use them to evaluate Software Engineers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The dark side of algorithm challenges&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - As to many philosophical questions in life, there is a dark side to these pernicious algorithm challenges. The fact of the matter is that there is a huge quantity of people that are trying to throw themselves into the tech industry. Within a day of a job posting going up on LinkedIn it indicates that there have more than a hundred applicants. Virtually no company has the resources to interview them all. The fact is that these algorithm challenges are put up as a mechanism to ward off the hoard of applicants who are not suited to the job or don’t have basic programming skills. The problem is that everyone seems to have a different notion about what the word ‘basic’ means in this context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We don’t know how difficult they should be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - In my time interviewing over the past 7 months I ran across a wide variety of difficulties in the algorithm challenges that were posed to me. On the easier side I was asked to write a function to reverse a String. On the harder side I was asked to imitate a social network and to write an image filtration algorithm. I had one company ask me to do two separate coding interviews. In the first of these I was asked to write an easy sorting algorithm which I nailed. The second was to write a recursive permutation generator using dynamic programming which is no easy task. I got totally stumped in the moment by that one. At the end of the interview I asked the interviewer “This problem seems a little steep for a phone interview. Do you often write recursive algorithms at Payment Processing Company?” He replied “No, we don’t use recursion.” “How about permutations? When have you used those?” He answered “Our algorithms have no need for permutations. Most of the engineers here work on user interfaces and infrastructure.” This made total sense to me. These two instances were for similar level-of-skill roles in different companies. So why did one company pick one difficulty over the other?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The measurement is little better than Russian Roulette&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Let’s say you are a candidate. You’ve spent the last couple of months studying every topic you can think of that might be relevant to programming interviews. Let us then say that you apply for company A. A asks you to write a binary tree search algorithm. Great! You just got done studying binary trees last week! You pass with flying colors. Now let’s say that you apply for company B. B asks you to write an implementation of a trie tree. NOOO! You forgot to study tries! Because you didn’t study that topic you fail the interview. Now reverse the order and say that company B asks you the binary tree algorithm and A asks you the trie tree algorithm: It is clear that getting hired at some company can be purely an artifact of which problem you are asked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time limits are detrimental and discriminatory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Generally in a phone screen you are given 45 minutes to solve the coding challenge. This is plenty of time for a simple problem. But when you are asked to write a complex algorithm it is patently ridiculous. When I was asked to write Conway’s Game of Life it took me 50 minutes to get a working, running piece of code and I had next to no time to test it. When I was asked to write an image filtration algorithm I spent the first 15 minutes just to understand the question. I ran out of time. If such a complex algorithm were to be written in the real world, it would likely take a week of implementation and a month or more of real life testing. At minimum. So why are we asking engineers to do it in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;45 minutes?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is a cottage industry springing up around passing interviews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - All of this algorithm challenge hubub started with popular companies like Google. There were several engineers who worked at these popular tech companies that saw an opportunity to make a few bucks be offering prep material. There were two influential books written on the subject: &lt;em&gt;Cracking the Coding Interview&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Elements of Programming Interviews&lt;/em&gt;. Both of these books offer guided interview preparation material. The problem is that the industry got a hold of these books and tailored their interviews to the book’s material. However, as soon as people started passing the basic interview questions set out in these books, the companies realized that they were now hiring from the new bottom of the barrel. So they wrote new, more challenging algorithm questions to differentiate themselves and hire the ‘more qualified candidates of all the seemingly qualified’ candidates. There are multiple anecdotes about current and former top tier engineers at particular companies who claim that the interview process has gotten so hard that they would never pass the bar if they were to go through the process now. I watched one talk that had a great story. At one particular ‘top’ tech company the process is that when a candidate goes through an interview he or she has a packet compiled about their interview performance. The packet then goes to a committee whose job it is to impartially review the packet to make a hiring decision. At one point a particular committee got so critical that they rejected every packet for several months. When HR caught wind of this they decided to set up a test. They sent the committee a new round of packets and once again the committee rejected them all. HR then called them all into a meeting and explained that they packets they had just reviewed were in fact the hiring committee member’s own packets from when they interviewed for that company. They had unknowingly rejected themselves! How could anyone pass that bar?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why are we measuring people and not learning about people?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - I watched a talk a few weeks ago about someone who had done a large number of interviews at a ‘top’ tier company. In his words the goal of his talk was to “Distill a strategy for ‘extracting a signal’ during an interview.” What?! What happened to people getting to know people? That attitude seems so utterly robotic and frankly quite dystopian. What is the logical progression here? Are we going to scan candidate’s brains to look for similarities between existing high performing candidates? This attitude stinks of an especially horrific blend of egoism and organizational machismo. It sounds to me that now companies are more &lt;strong&gt;afraid of hiring bad candidates&lt;/strong&gt; than they are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;excited about the opportunity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to hire a great candidate. Until companies are more excited about hiring again it’s doubtful it will get any better for candidates. The worst thing about it is that the first message a candidate hears from a recruiter is how great of a candidate you seem but once you hit the interview all you find is suspicion that you are some sort of fraud. It is my view that suspicion should be replaced with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;guarded optimism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am quite sure that I could go on at length. I had about eight more bullet points in my notes to write about. But at this point this article sounds more like a diatribe than a blog article. I hope at the very least I was able to impart some of the difficulty I’ve been through over the past seven months. At the end of things I find myself rather ambivalent. My current employer just laid off my entire office, leaving me without a job and alone to write about how bitter I am about it all. I am not quite sure I want to go through this process again. I have done a lot of thinking and come to some simple conclusions about my experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know how to write software&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - I’ve written approximately 85,000 lines of production Java code over 2 years which had a very positive and pronounced impact on the product I was working on. I’ve written some very complex machine learning algorithm implementations in Python along with quite a bit of scripting. I’ve written embedded C and C++ for various low level applications like embedded graphics. I’ve taught myself Flutter and have published several apps. I taught myself Clojure which opened up my brain a lot. I’ve worked on some C#. I know how to build a static web site. I have a Computer Science degree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don’t know why other people won’t let me write software&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - There is a fundamental mismatch between the public square’s claim that companies are absolutely desperate to hire software engineers and the brutal reality of being a software engineering candidate. These do-or-die high pressure coding challenges seem like more of a hazing mechanism rather than a valuable evaluation tool. Using them is like hiring a police officer by shooting at him before you ask him what he knows about the law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don’t know what its like on the other side of the table&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - The fact of the matter is that the process I am criticizing may be the only way companies have to sort through the good and the bad candidates. I have never been a part of a hiring team and I am sure there are things going on that I don’t know about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a few thoughts in conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Survival of the fittest is real&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - As much as I would like to reason my way into a cush job at a well known tech company, the reality is that there are a lot of other people out there that are competing for those jobs. Just as with everything else in life there are few resources and there is high demand. Everybody and his brother wants to get paid a lot to write code. It is my suspicion that the reason such aggressive screening barriers are put up is that the proportion of those who have an objectively (whatever that means) lower level of skill is much larger than those who do have those skills. Unfortunately this means that you must compete with this massive amount of people no matter how experienced you are. As any person who has gone through the process of learning to program understands, the learning curve to become even minimally proficient in basic skills is drastically steep. On top of that the body of knowledge that make up the core competencies needed to succeed on the job is vast. Further still it is difficult to gain proficiency in a particular set of relevant and marketable skills, even more to master them. Regardless of what route one takes into becoming a software engineer, it is clear that competition is a fact of life and is quite stiff in this industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hierarchies are real&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - I am rather confused with the advertised rankings of a software engineer. There seem to be only two rankings: non-senior and senior. In general job ads ask for 5 years of experience in order to be considered a senior. There seem to be some missing rankings. What do we call someone with 20 years of experience? Are they really the same thing as someone with 5? In my case, what do we call someone with 4 years of experience? I am not a new grad. I know how to write software on my own. I know how version control works and how to exist in an Agile environment. Depending on the situation I need people to set the direction for my work. To add further complexity to the issue, there is the the issue of years of experience &lt;em&gt;in a technology&lt;/em&gt;. If a person has 5 years of experience writing Java and moves to a team that uses Python and is made up of only people who have less than two years of experience in Python should this person be considered a junior? This is such a confusing topic that it warrants an entire article of its own and even then I am not sure I can make any sense of it. My point is that I lie somewhere between junior and senior and it seems to be slim pickings for my experience level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Complaining about it wont do any good&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Sooner or later I’m going to have to get another job. Even if I don’t like the methodology, I am going to have to go through the loop again. But for now I’ve had enough. It seems unlikely that I will get anything to happen by repeating the same process over and over again. I’ll get on the merry go round again eventually but for now I am going to choose the only option that leaves me with my sanity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to exit the loop for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>asangha</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.jarednelsen.dev/</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.jarednelsen.dev/posts/the-horrifically-dystopian-world-of-software-engineering-interviews/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google cuts jobs at cloud-computing group</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-cuts-jobs-at-cloud-computing-group-11581719153</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-cuts-jobs-at-cloud-computing-group-11581719153</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Google said it is cutting jobs at its cloud-computing unit as part of a reorganization aimed at improving operations at the business that has become more central to parent Alphabet Inc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google on Friday said “a small number of employees” have been notified their roles have been eliminated. Google didn’t specify how many roles are being cut and said it was working with affected employees to find them new positions in the company.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The...
  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 22:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pgodzin</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google Cuts Jobs at Cloud-Computing Group</og:title>
<og:description>The company said it is cutting jobs at its cloud-computing unit as part of a reorganization aimed at improving operations at the business that has become more central to parent Alphabet.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-cuts-jobs-at-cloud-computing-group-11581719153</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-154914/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-cuts-jobs-at-cloud-computing-group-11581719153</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The US Secret Service mistook a cyberpunk RPG for a hacker&amp;#039;s handbook</title>
<link>https://www.dicebreaker.com/categories/roleplaying-game/feature/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-us-secret-service</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.dicebreaker.com/categories/roleplaying-game/feature/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-us-secret-service</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;article_header&quot; readability=&quot;30&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;strapline&quot;&gt;&quot;It was dumb, not to put a fine point on it.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.dicebreaker.com/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-book-art.png/BROK/resize/1920x1920%3E/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-book-art.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.dicebreaker.com/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-book-art.png/BROK/resize/1920x1920%3E/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-book-art.png&quot; alt=&quot;gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-book-art.png&quot; class=&quot;headline&quot; data-lazyload=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only one roleplaying game has a note on the cover declaring it &quot;The book that was seized by the US Secret Service!&quot; That RPG is GURPS Cyberpunk, a 1990 supplement for the Generic Universal Roleplaying System published by Steve Jackson Games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the morning of March 1st 1990, GURPS Cyberpunk author Loyd Blankenship and his wife were woken up by six Secret Service agents who raided their home, confiscating a computer, a printer and even their telephone. Then the Secret Service headed across Austin to the office of Steve Jackson Games, where Blankenship worked as a managing editor, to do the same. The office was not yet open for the day and the Secret Service agents almost broke the door down before Blankenship, still only half-dressed, explained that he had keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I emailed Steve Jackson to ask if he remembered the day his company was raided by agents whose normal job is to stand between the US president and bullets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Not terribly well!” he replied. “I did not come to the office during the raid. Our company president was there, called me to tell me it was happening, and said, 'Don’t come in - they are not letting anyone in the office.' So I did not meet the SS people on the day of the raid, though I got to spend more than enough time with them later.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secret Service agents tore open boxes, damaged a letter opener trying to pick a locked filing cabinet and, according to some accounts, ate jelly beans off someone's desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secret Service confiscated computers Steve Jackson Games used to run its BBS (which is what people used to have in the days before online forums and comment sections existed), as well as every computer with files relating to then-unpublished GURPS Cyberpunk. They tore open boxes, damaged a letter opener trying to pick a locked filing cabinet and, according to some accounts, ate jelly beans off someone's desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;They didn’t treat the office with respect,&quot; as Jackson puts it. &quot;Things were generally a mess. Not vandalism - just dishevelment. I can’t confirm the jelly bean story - they weren’t mine. But they definitely bent a letter opener and left big scratches around the lock of a file cabinet.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time nobody knew why this was happening. The warrant granting permission for the raid was sealed - since GURPS Cyberpunk was taken, it was natural to assume that was the focus for some reason. Jackson describes the book as being heavily inspired by the high-tech low-life fiction of William Gibson and Bruce Sterling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Typical characters have 'cyborg' augmentations,&quot; he explains, &quot;Though that’s not necessary. The most typical scenarios are espionage, high-tech heists, protecting from same, and combinations of the above with plenty of double-crossing. I should emphasise that even 30 years later, this is still fiction.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://assets.dicebreaker.com/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-network-map.png/BROK/resize/1920x1920%3E/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-network-map.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-network-map.png&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.dicebreaker.com/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-network-map.png/BROK/resize/700%3E/format/jpg/quality/80/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-network-map.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The core manual for GURPS Cyberpunk included rules for exploring cyberspace and hacking networks.
&lt;p&gt;Jackson had a hard time communicating that to the Secret Service. In spite of the fact the rulebook contained rules for having your consciousness transferred to a gender-swapped clone, when he spoke to them the day after the raid he was told that his company was publishing &quot;a handbook for computer crime&quot;. When he protested that it was clearly made up, he was repeatedly informed: &quot;This is real.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strangest thing about this story isn't that government employees couldn't tell the difference between a work of science fiction and reality, but that they'd only confiscated it opportunistically. Although the warrant was sealed at the time, leaving everyone to assume that GURPS Cyberpunk was the object of the raid, the truth is even odder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems ridiculous now, but in the late 1980s hacker-mania swept the United States. The news breathlessly reported on computer crime and the movie WarGames had the public convinced kids were going to start a nuclear war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It was dumb, not to put a fine point on it,&quot; Jackson says, &quot;and it was driven by the media, with the help of law enforcement (who liked playing up threats) and the 'hackers' themselves (who liked bragging, and inventing brags for the credulous, as much as any other smart teenaged boys).&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jackson was told his company was publishing &quot;a handbook for computer crime&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a hacker calling himself Prophet broke into the mainframe of phone company Bell South in September 1988 and copied a file he found there, it was treated as serious business. It was only a text file, but it described the enhanced 911 system Bell South used to prioritise and identify emergency calls. The company valued this stolen file at $79,449 - an amount that was determined by adding together the wages of everyone who was involved in writing, editing and storing it, as well as the value of the computer hardware it was on ($31,000 for the computer, $6,000 for a printer and $850 for a monitor) and the Interleaf software it was made with ($2,500).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information that document contained was not top secret. It was mostly administrative, and everything in it was available in a document sold to the public by Bellcore - Bell South's owner - for $13. By overvaluing this file and thus exaggerating the crime, Bell South attracted the attention of the Secret Service so they could use them to frighten off any kids who might think to breach their security again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his youth Blankenship had been a member of a hacking group called the Legion of Doom - the same group as Prophet - under the pseudonym &quot;The Mentor&quot;. In 1986, after being arrested for computer crime, he wrote an essay called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phrack.org/archives/issues/7/3.txt&quot;&gt;The Conscience of the Hacker&lt;/a&gt;, which became known as the Hacker Manifesto after it was published in a zine called Phrack. That same zine later published excerpts from the stolen Bell South document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the four years since his arrest, Blankenship had gone straight. He wasn't a teenage computer criminal any more; he had a real job. He still ran a BBS from home, though, and he worked for a company that owned one. One that Steve Jackson Games had jokingly dubbed &quot;the Illuminati&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://assets.dicebreaker.com/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-glossary.png/BROK/resize/1920x1920%3E/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-glossary.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-glossary.png&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.dicebreaker.com/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-glossary.png/BROK/resize/700%3E/format/jpg/quality/80/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-glossary.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; GURPS Cyberpunk drew heavily from works of '80s sci-fi such as Neuromancer, to the point where terms from William Gibson's seminal novel were highlighted with asterisks in the tabletop RPG's glossary.
&lt;p&gt;The idea that a forum owned by an RPG publisher was worth being shut down by the Secret Service because they might republish a stolen text file full of publicly-available information is obviously laughable, and yet that's what happened. When the agents didn't find that file on the premises of Steve Jackson Games, they picked up a book about computers with Blankenship’s name on it and took that instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took days for Jackson and his attorney to learn any of this, and months to get their hardware back. When it finally turned up, much of it was in an unusable state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It all arrived at the lawyer's office in one big box with no packing material,&quot; Jackson says. &quot;For instance, a hard drive was just placed loose inside the cabinet of a PC, where it could bounce around on the motherboard during shipping. It's hard to put that down to simple ignorance; somebody was just being mean.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GURPS Cyberpunk's release was delayed, and it had to be rewritten almost from scratch based on playtest notes and memories. Losing the BBS, a direct line to their fans, was also a blow. &quot;I recognise that it had its funny elements from the outside,&quot; says Jackson, &quot;but the damage it did to the business forced me to lay off half my staff, which will never be funny.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jackson brought the Secret Service, specifically the Chicago Computer Fraud and Abuse Task Force who had come to Austin for the raid, to court in a civil lawsuit. With help from a group of technologically-literate legal experts with an interest in the recent spate of computer crime cases - that same year 15 other raids occurred across the country as part of Operation Sundevil - Jackson and three of his employees won $300,000 in statutory damages and attorney's fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recognise that it had its funny elements from the outside, but the damage it did to the business forced me to lay off half my staff, which will never be funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those legal experts would go on to found the Electronic Frontier Foundation, a non-profit group dedicated to protecting civil liberties online. The raid also inspired science-fiction author Bruce Sterling, responsible for foundational cyberpunk novels like Schismatrix and Islands in the Net, to turn his hand to non-fiction, writing The Hacker Crackdown: Law and Disorder on the Electronic Frontier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Jackson Games survived, and still publishes games today, including Munchkin, Toon and the Discworld Roleplaying Game. Looking back on the raid, Jackson says it almost killed his company, &quot;but not quite”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My best estimate, later, is that it cost us five years of growth,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loyd Blankenship no longer works in the RPG business. These days he's on the other side of cyber security, working as a UX designer for anti-virus software maker McAfee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GURPS Cyberpunk is still on sale. Its credits thank the United States Secret Service for &quot;Unsolicited Comments&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;footer class=&quot;article_footer&quot;&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Sometimes we include links to online retail stores. If you click on one and make a purchase we may receive a small commission.&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;social_share&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author_bio&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;summary&quot; data-type=&quot;persona&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;details&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Jody Macgregor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;job_title&quot;&gt;Contributor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bio&quot;&gt;Jody blames the board game HeroQuest for getting him into Games Workshop at a young age, which led to Warhammer Fantasy Roleplay and roleplaying games as a whole. He has a D&amp;amp;D and a Cyberpunk Red campaign on the go, and likes to play Kill Doctor Lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 20:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>molecule</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>That time the US Secret Service mistook a cyberpunk RPG for a hacker's handbook</og:title>
<og:description>How GURPS Cyberpunk triggered a Secret Service raid of RPG publisher Steve Jackson Games' offices.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.dicebreaker.com/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-book-art.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.dicebreaker.com/categories/roleplaying-game/feature/gurps-cyberpunk-rpg-us-secret-service</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Edge Cache</title>
<link>https://cache.edge.apple</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cache.edge.apple</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;typography-intro&quot;&gt;Your
                customers deserve the best content delivery experience
                possible. Apple Edge Cache (AEC) is Apple
                supplied and managed hardware for deployment within our ISP
                partners networks to deliver certain Apple content directly to
                our shared customers.&lt;/p&gt; </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 18:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bwilliams18</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cache.edge.apple/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>