<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The Case for RSS</title>
<link>https://www.macsparky.com/blog/2017/11/the-case-for-rss</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.macsparky.com/blog/2017/11/the-case-for-rss</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-layout sqs-grid-12 columns-12&quot; data-layout-label=&quot;Post Body&quot; data-type=&quot;item&quot; id=&quot;item-5a05e964e2c4833ff7a9fbd0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row sqs-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col sqs-col-12 span-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-a8a9bc0ca4272b3c6f82&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For several years now, the trend among geeks has been to abandon the RSS format. RSS, or Really Simple Syndication, is a way to queue up and serve content from the internet. The MacSparky RSS, for example, gives RSS applications a list of all the articles I post here since you last checked int. It is a great way to read blogs and the backbone of podcast distribution. As social networks took off, a lot of my friends that were previously big RSS fans gave up on the technology and instead relied upon sources like Twitter and Facebook to get their news.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was never me. The reason I’ve stuck with RSS is the way in which I work. Twitter is the social network that I participate in most and yet sometimes days go by where I don’t load the application. I like to work in focused bursts. If I’m deep into writing a book or a legal client project. I basically ignore everything else. I close my mail application, tell my phone service to take my calls, and I definitely don’t open Twitter. When I finish the job, I can then go back to the Internet. I’ll check in on Twitter, but I won’t be able to get my news from it. That only works if you go into Twitter much more frequently than I do. That’s why RSS is such a great solution for me. If a few days go by, I can open RSS and go through my carefully curated list of websites and get caught back up with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long time ago, I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/reeder-3/id697846300?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10laz7&quot;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt; as my primary RSS application. It’s clean, fast, and attractive. Then a few years ago I switched over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/unread-rss-reader/id1252376153?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10laz7&quot;&gt;Unread&lt;/a&gt;, which I found to be slower but a little &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macworld.com/article/2153725/when-it-comes-to-ios-productivity-delight-can-trump-efficiency.html&quot;&gt;more delightful&lt;/a&gt;. For the last week, I’ve been using Reeder again just for giggles. Their addition of dark mode for iPhone X is great, but ultimately I don’t know where I’ll land between these two great RSS Apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking about using RSS, I have a little advice. Be wary feed inflation. RSS is so easy to implement that it's a slippery slope between having RSS feeds for just a few websites and instead of having RSS feeds for hundreds of websites. If you’re not careful, every time you open your RSS reader, there will be 1,000 unread articles waiting for you, which completely defeats the purpose of using RSS. The trick to using RSS is to be brutal with your subscriptions. I think the key is looking for websites with high signal and low noise. Sites that publish one or two articles a day (or even one to two articles a week) but make them good articles are much more valuable and RSS feed than sites that published 30 articles a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 22:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mpweiher</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Case for RSS</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.macsparky.com/blog/2017/11/the-case-for-rss</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>For several years now, the trend among geeks has been to abandon the RSS format. RSS, or Really Simple Syndication, is a way to queue up and serve content from the internet. The MacSparky RSS, for example, gives RSS applications a list of all the articles I post here since you last checked int. It i</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.macsparky.com/blog/2017/11/the-case-for-rss</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Equifax CEO to Congress: Not Sure We Are Encrypting Data</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/equifax-ceo-to-congress-not-sure-we-are-encrypting-data-1510180486?mod=yahoo_hs&amp;yptr=yahoo</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/equifax-ceo-to-congress-not-sure-we-are-encrypting-data-1510180486?mod=yahoo_hs&amp;yptr=yahoo</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Two months after Equifax Inc. reported one of the worst data breaches in history, its interim chief executive told a congressional hearing Wednesday he wasn’t sure whether the company was encrypting consumer data.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Equifax announced Sept. 7 it was breached and that hackers accessed data including names, dates of birth and Social Security numbers for 145.5 million U.S. consumers. Several executives, including the CEO, stepped aside in the wake of the disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;...
  </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 18:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>boyd</dc:creator>
<og:title>Equifax CEO to Congress: Not Sure We Are Encrypting Data </og:title>
<og:description>Two months after Equifax reported one of the worst data breaches in history, its interim chief executive told a congressional hearing Wednesday he wasn’t sure whether the company was encrypting consumer data.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/equifax-ceo-to-congress-not-sure-we-are-encrypting-data-1510180486</og:url>
<og:image>https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/BN-WA959_3hW9D_TOP_20171108171726.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/equifax-ceo-to-congress-not-sure-we-are-encrypting-data-1510180486?mod=yahoo_hs&amp;yptr=yahoo</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>All about whiteboard markers</title>
<link>https://medium.com/graphicfacilitation/all-you-need-to-know-about-whiteboard-markers-2a25d1249911</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/graphicfacilitation/all-you-need-to-know-about-whiteboard-markers-2a25d1249911</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;37.552941176471&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;badd&quot; id=&quot;badd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf--leading&quot;&gt;Markers under consideration of this article&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4bce&quot; id=&quot;4bce&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;The parameters were assessed on the set of markers of 9 different brands that are the most common to find around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;eaa9&quot; id=&quot;eaa9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;(1) &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--h4-em&quot;&gt;Expo&lt;/em&gt; dry erase markers, low odour ink, chisel tip&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3f99&quot; id=&quot;3f99&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;The design of the marker is very simplistic, more or less convenient to hold in a hand. The cap is firm to cap the marker (however you need to apply some strength), there is a small nest on the back of the marker to fix the cap when the marker is uncapped, which is good — the cap will not accidentally fall off when in use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8ff6&quot; id=&quot;8ff6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Important to notice that manufacturer explicitly recommends to store the markers in horizontal position when in use (notice that it is recommended so for any other brand of a whiteboard marker). Somehow I always thought that markers are best to be stored vertically, with their felt tips pointing down. Well, that was obviously a fallacy. So store horizontally from now on (if not yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;31f7&quot; id=&quot;31f7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The manufacturer suggests a wide range of other types of whiteboard markers that vary in ink colour (e.g. there are neon colour markers), tip type and size (chisel, point, fine and super fine) and other fancy and crazy things. You can check &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.expomarkers.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.expomarkers.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Expo&lt;/em&gt; site&lt;/a&gt; if you want to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fcad&quot; id=&quot;fcad&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;By the way, they have a nice &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.expomarkers.com/faq&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.expomarkers.com/faq&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FAQ page&lt;/a&gt; where, you might want to check it out, it has some practical tips on using whiteboard markers, not necessarily the &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Expo&lt;/em&gt; ones (those tips are applicable to any whiteboard markers in fact).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--fullWidth&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*mC5oKS_huqQRfZXwY7ZQVA.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3200&quot; data-height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*mC5oKS_huqQRfZXwY7ZQVA.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Expo markers that took part in the overview.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;28.645343367827&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;13c9&quot; id=&quot;13c9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;(2) Pilot V Board Master Wytebord Marker™, medium chisel point&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5060&quot; id=&quot;5060&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;The design of a marker is somewhat unique, the marker is a bit too thick to my taste. What I find good about the design is that the cap has a little knob that I assume is intended to prevent the marker from rolling off a table for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4fba&quot; id=&quot;4fba&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Also, the ink cartridge is attached to the rear part of the marker, the cartridge is made of transparent plastic so you could easily see how much ink is still there — it is easier to predict when a marker is going to run out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;05dd&quot; id=&quot;05dd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I like the markings on the top of a marker cap — easy to identify the type of a tip (in case you are owning various types). And the cap may be placed on the back of the marker when it is in use, however, the cap is very easy to fall off when you are drawing something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9e0e&quot; id=&quot;9e0e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The description on the body suggests that there are spare tips, meaning they are replaceable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cb6f&quot; id=&quot;cb6f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The marker is available in at least three variations of the tip — bullet, chisel and extra fine. You may find more information on their &lt;a href=&quot;http://pilotpen.us/categories/dry-erase-markers/&quot; data-href=&quot;http://pilotpen.us/categories/dry-erase-markers/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;official site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--fullWidth&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*XyTBDBfE3u-YwMjGx80KYg.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3200&quot; data-height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*XyTBDBfE3u-YwMjGx80KYg.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Pilot chisel tip markers that were reviewed and some other marker types that were at hand at the time of writing this article.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;32.880866425993&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;146a&quot; id=&quot;146a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;(3) Pentel Maxiflo white board marker, bullet point&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6a87&quot; id=&quot;6a87&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;This is a nice looking and relatively easy to hold marker, slightly just a bit too thick in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8a9e&quot; id=&quot;8a9e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The unique feature of these markers is that they come with so called pump-up action — there is a button on the rear of the marker that you could push when the marker show signs of running out of ink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ac92&quot; id=&quot;ac92&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Also its body is made of a transparent plastic so you can see how much ink is remaining — a convenient feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;df6f&quot; id=&quot;df6f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Caps come with an indication of the tip type, again, useful when you possess and actively use various types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1c96&quot; id=&quot;1c96&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Cap can be attached to the rear end of a marker when in use, holds more or less firmly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0978&quot; id=&quot;0978&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The manufacturer suggests that you can leave the marker uncapped even for a long period of time. And they insist that the marker has 3 times longer distance (approx. 1100 m of an uninterrupted line) than standard marker. But it is not clear what markers they compare to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1b99&quot; id=&quot;1b99&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;These markers can be found with various types of a tip — bullet tip, chisel tip, fine bullet tip and fine chisel tip. More information can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pentel.co.uk/products.asp?group=2&amp;amp;type=8&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.pentel.co.uk/products.asp?group=2&amp;amp;type=8&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--fullWidth&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*8JFlC-lodDA60pWkiuupsA.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3200&quot; data-height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*8JFlC-lodDA60pWkiuupsA.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Pentel bullet point markers that were reviewed.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;23.893095768374&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;a8f2&quot; id=&quot;a8f2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;(4) Edding 28 EcoLine whiteboard marker, bullet tip&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3aeb&quot; id=&quot;3aeb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;It was a pure accident that I have chosen Edding 28 markers for the review — I could not acquire Edding 360 which are the most common to find in stationery shops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3bb6&quot; id=&quot;3bb6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;These two markers are almost identical, while Edding 28 is claimed to be made from recycled materials and has a removable end that makes it possible to refill it with fresh ink much faster than it is suggested by the manufacturer for Edding 360 model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9478&quot; id=&quot;9478&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I assume that the ink used for these two types is the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d305&quot; id=&quot;d305&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;You can attach a cap to the rear end of the marker while in use. Edding 360 is easy to lose the cap in that position, Edding 28 has even a shorter stub so the cap falls off even easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5e99&quot; id=&quot;5e99&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Edding whiteboard markers come in a variety of tip types and sizes, colours and form factors. There is a comprehensive catalog of products available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edding.com/fileadmin/categories/catalogue/edding-en-catalogue-2016-2017.pdf&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.edding.com/fileadmin/categories/catalogue/edding-en-catalogue-2016-2017.pdf&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, start from the page 28.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--fullWidth&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*tA-MOojXquAXzaWkSwQL0Q.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3200&quot; data-height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*tA-MOojXquAXzaWkSwQL0Q.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Edding 28 markers (under review) compared to the more common Edding 360.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;17.858823529412&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;961e&quot; id=&quot;961e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;(5) Sharpie whiteboard marker, chisel point&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;40e8&quot; id=&quot;40e8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;Sharpie markers appear to be the exact copy of Expo markers owning to the fact that these two brands belong to the same corporation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f32f&quot; id=&quot;f32f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The reason I have chosen Sharpie for this review is that Sharpie markers are available for sale in Europe, while Expo are exclusive for North America, unless you decide to order them online from US (like I did).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e7ba&quot; id=&quot;e7ba&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Sharpie whiteboard markers do not come in the same variety of tips and colours as Expo do, however. Check that out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sharpie.com/en-GB/whiteboard-markers&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.sharpie.com/en-GB/whiteboard-markers&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--fullWidth&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*gFd3tRGNRwUZaZnCcyBJGQ.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3200&quot; data-height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*gFd3tRGNRwUZaZnCcyBJGQ.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Sharpie chisel and bullet point markers, compared to Expo marker.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;22.790193842645&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;4fd1&quot; id=&quot;4fd1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;(6) Staedtler Lumocolor whiteboard marker, bullet point&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6430&quot; id=&quot;6430&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;This marker is a very standard cigar type marker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8422&quot; id=&quot;8422&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Caps are marked to simplify identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b006&quot; id=&quot;b006&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Markers come in different tip type and sizes. For all the available variations visit their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.staedtler.com/en/products/markers-refill-ink/whiteboard-flipchart-markers/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.staedtler.com/en/products/markers-refill-ink/whiteboard-flipchart-markers/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;33cc&quot; id=&quot;33cc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Cap is firmly attached to the rear end of the marker preventing it from accidentally falling off while in use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dc53&quot; id=&quot;dc53&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The manufacturer claims the markers to be refillable. Since the marker body is securely sealed, the markers are refilled via capillary action. Full refill is promised in 4 hours with a marker attached to the refill station. Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.staedtler.com/en/products/markers-refill-ink/whiteboard-flipchart-markers/lumocolor-whiteboard-park-write-set-611-s-whiteboard-set/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.staedtler.com/en/products/markers-refill-ink/whiteboard-flipchart-markers/lumocolor-whiteboard-park-write-set-611-s-whiteboard-set/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to get a general idea. I find it a German feature to suggest this type of refill technique as you do not find this method with any other manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2adf&quot; id=&quot;2adf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Their kit boxes are worth a separate mention — I find them very handy. The boxes make it easy to transport and store markers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--fullWidth&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*Q-An0_-ndrytXVF1JwxOuA.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3200&quot; data-height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*Q-An0_-ndrytXVF1JwxOuA.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Staedtler whiteboard marker sets come in handy plastic boxes.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;28.417689530686&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;dcb5&quot; id=&quot;dcb5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;(7) Neuland No.One, whiteboard marker, round nib&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0ce1&quot; id=&quot;0ce1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;This is the marker from the famous manufacturer of markers for graphic facilitation. I am personally a big fan of the other Neuland products and naturally I got myself a set of their whiteboard ones. And apparently I wanted to see how these match against more mundane whiteboard markers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;225d&quot; id=&quot;225d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Neuland markers are available in three types of nibs — bullet, chisel and fine bullet point. These markers have been designed to be refilled with an injection of refill ink into an opening in the rear end of the marker using a special hand pump. Unfortunately, Neuland had to discontinue sale of the whiteboard refill ink since February 2016 and therefore these markers are practically not refillable as of today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ed7e&quot; id=&quot;ed7e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Nibs are replaceable. See more details on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://us.neuland.com/markers-more/neuland-markers/?p=1&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;n=24&amp;amp;f=53&quot; data-href=&quot;https://us.neuland.com/markers-more/neuland-markers/?p=1&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;n=24&amp;amp;f=53&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cfac&quot; id=&quot;cfac&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Markers have a small knob on their bodies to prevent them from rolling off tables. There are two cavities on the sides of the body — those, I assume, are intended for a better and handier grip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2704&quot; id=&quot;2704&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Cap is firmly fixed on the rear end of the marker so it is secured there while marker is in use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;e306&quot; id=&quot;e306&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pullquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think it is important to state it explicitly — this is the only brand of whiteboard markers that suggests grey colour. It is very important at least to me personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0ec9&quot; id=&quot;0ec9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote&quot;&gt;There is no need to order the entire set however — you can order single colours separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--fullWidth&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*60Kq9fyqz6iyNkQcFoid0A.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3200&quot; data-height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*60Kq9fyqz6iyNkQcFoid0A.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Neuland No.One whiteboard marker, round nib, full set of colours.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;13.881355932203&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;70ea&quot; id=&quot;70ea&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;(8) Artline 519, whiteboard marker, chisel tip&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0c4a&quot; id=&quot;0c4a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;These markers appear to be very popular in Asian region and I bought a couple of them last summer when I was on a business trip to Kuala Lumpur. I purchased only black colour but still decided to give it a go in this test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;477b&quot; id=&quot;477b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Artline suggests a very elaborate product range for whiteboard markers. &lt;a href=&quot;http://artlineworld.com/products/artline/whiteboard/index.html&quot; data-href=&quot;http://artlineworld.com/products/artline/whiteboard/index.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; you can find a full catalog of available items — there are various colours (including also neon), tip types and sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--fullWidth&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*6zxBjdxOxvpkD9-bq58tcw.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3200&quot; data-height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*6zxBjdxOxvpkD9-bq58tcw.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;26.703839122486&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;e9df&quot; id=&quot;e9df&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;(9) Lyreco whiteboard marker, bullet point&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;deb2&quot; id=&quot;deb2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;This is the marker that is very common to find in Danish offices. Since I live and work in Copenhagen, I had access to these samples and decided to assess them in this review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7f16&quot; id=&quot;7f16&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;While working on this review I have accidentally run across Staples Remarx whiteboard marker that appears to be the exact copy of the Lyreco whiteboard marker (and are found in Swedish offices of my employing company). I assume these two companies just brand a “white label” whiteboard marker available from some third party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2bce&quot; id=&quot;2bce&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is a very regular, no fancy whiteboard marker. I thought it would be good to assess such a regular marker so you could get an overall idea what to expect from other lower-end markers available on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dfb9&quot; id=&quot;dfb9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The cap can be attached to the rear end of the marker, but does not hold in place and fall off immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3750&quot; id=&quot;3750&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;These markers are not available in many colours — only the basic four. But they also come with chisel tips. Here is the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lyreco.com/webshop/ENAU/lyreco-dry-wipe-bullet-tip-whiteboard-marker-1-5-2mm-assorted-wallet-of-4-product-000000000000149969.html?context=more-result&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.lyreco.com/webshop/ENAU/lyreco-dry-wipe-bullet-tip-whiteboard-marker-1-5-2mm-assorted-wallet-of-4-product-000000000000149969.html?context=more-result&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;product page&lt;/a&gt; where you could also find the specification with health safety information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--fullWidth&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*mhptr-OLMMPeNLRd88UmBw.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3200&quot; data-height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*mhptr-OLMMPeNLRd88UmBw.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;9e54&quot; id=&quot;9e54&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Other brands&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3ea5&quot; id=&quot;3ea5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;There are other brands and types, but those would be less popular and are region specific, so I kept them out of the review. That is always a hard choice, but you have to limit the scope otherwise it takes forever :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;13f8&quot; id=&quot;13f8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;So if you cannot find a marker brand that you like or if you have an elaborate overview of a marker that is not covered by this article— you are more than welcome to share your experience in a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 18:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>idoco</dc:creator>
<og:title>All you need to know about whiteboard markers – graphicfacilitation – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/graphicfacilitation/all-you-need-to-know-about-whiteboard-markers-2a25d1249911</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*CUvPY_nQhPXetY_lLcUWlQ.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>For it’s time to learn more about this tool</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/graphicfacilitation/all-you-need-to-know-about-whiteboard-markers-2a25d1249911</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Eight years of Go</title>
<link>https://blog.golang.org/8years</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.golang.org/8years</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/8years&quot;&gt;Eight years of Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;10 November 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we celebrate 8 years since Go was released as an open source project. During &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/4years&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Go’s 4th anniversary&lt;/a&gt;, Andrew finished the post with “Here's to four more years!”. Now that we have reached that milestone, I cannot help but reflect on how much the project and ecosystem has grown since then. In our post 4 years ago we included a chart demonstrating Go's rising popularity on Google Trends with the search term &quot;golang&quot;. Today, we’re including an updated chart. In this relative scale of popularity, what was 100 four years ago is now a mere 17. Go’s popularity has increased exponentially over the last 8 years and continues to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/8years/image1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=2009-10-01%202017-10-30&amp;amp;q=golang&amp;amp;hl=en-US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;trends.google.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_1.1.&quot;&gt;Developers love Go&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go has been embraced by developers all over the world with approximately one million users worldwide. In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://octoverse.github.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;freshly published 2017 Octoverse&lt;/a&gt; by GitHub, &lt;strong&gt;Go has become the #9 most popular language&lt;/strong&gt;, surpassing C. &lt;strong&gt;Go is the fastest growing language on GitHub in 2017&lt;/strong&gt; in the top 10 with &lt;strong&gt;52% growth over the previous year&lt;/strong&gt;. In growth, Go swapped places with Javascript, which fell to the second spot with 44%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/8years/image2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://octoverse.github.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;octoverse.github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2017#most-loved-dreaded-and-wanted&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow's 2017 developer survey&lt;/a&gt; , Go was the only language that was both on the &lt;strong&gt;top 5 most loved and top 5 most wanted&lt;/strong&gt; languages. People who use Go, love it, and the people who aren’t using Go, want to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/8years/image3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/8years/image4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2017#most-loved-dreaded-and-wanted&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_1.2.&quot;&gt;Go: The language of Cloud Infrastructure&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, analyst Donnie Berkholz called Go &lt;a href=&quot;http://redmonk.com/dberkholz/2014/03/18/go-the-emerging-language-of-cloud-infrastructure/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the emerging language of cloud infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;By 2017, Go has emerged as the language of cloud infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;. Today, &lt;strong&gt;every single cloud company has critical components of their cloud infrastructure implemented in Go&lt;/strong&gt; including Google Cloud, AWS, Microsoft Azure, Digital Ocean, Heroku and many others. Go is a key part of cloud companies like Alibaba, Cloudflare, and Dropbox. Go is a critical part of open infrastructure including Kubernetes, Cloud Foundry, Openshift, NATS, Docker, Istio, Etcd, Consul, Juju and many more. Companies are increasingly choosing Go to build cloud infrastructure solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_1.3.&quot;&gt;Go’s Great Community&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be hard to imagine that only four years ago the Go community was transitioning from online-only to include in-person community with its first conference. Now the Go community has had over 30 conferences all around the world with hundreds of presentations and tens of thousands of attendees. There are hundreds of Go meetups meeting monthly covering much of the globe. Wherever you live, you are likely to find a Go meetup nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two different organizations have been established to help with inclusivity in the Go community, Go Bridge and Women Who Go; the latter has grown to over 25 chapters. Both have been instrumental in offering free trainings. In 2017 alone over 50 scholarships to conferences have been given through efforts of Go Bridge and Women Who Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we had two significant firsts for the Go project. We had our first &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/contributors-summit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;contributor summit&lt;/a&gt; where people from across the Go community came together to discuss the needs and future of the Go project. Shortly after, we had the first &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/contributor-workshop&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Go contributor workshop&lt;/a&gt; where hundreds of people came to make their first Go contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/8years/photo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by Sameer Ajmani&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_1.4.&quot;&gt;Go’s impact on open source&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go has become a major force in the world of open source powering some of the most popular projects and enabling innovations across many industries. Find thousands of additional applications and libraries at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/avelino/awesome-go&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;awesome-go&lt;/a&gt;. Here are just a handful of the most popular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mobyproject.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Moby&lt;/a&gt; (formerly Docker) is a tool for packaging and running applications in lightweight containers. Its creator Solomon Hykes cited Go's standard library, concurrency primitives, and ease of deployment as key factors, and said &quot;To put it simply, if Docker had not been written in Go, it would not have been as successful.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; is a system for automating deployment, scaling and management of containerized applications. Initially designed by Google and used in the Google cloud, Kubernetes now is a critical part of every major cloud offering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gohugo.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is now the most popular open-source static website engine. With its amazing speed and flexibility, Hugo makes building websites fun again. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://w3techs.com/technologies/overview/content_management/all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;w3techs&lt;/a&gt;, Hugo now has nearly 3x the usage of Jekyll, the former leader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prometheus.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Prometheus&lt;/a&gt; is an open source monitoring solution and time series database that powers metrics and alerting designed to be the system you go to during an outage to allow you to quickly diagnose problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://grafana.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Grafana&lt;/a&gt; is an open source, feature-rich metrics dashboard and graph editor for Graphite, Elasticsearch, OpenTSDB, Prometheus and InfluxDB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getlantern.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lantern&lt;/a&gt; delivers fast, reliable and secure access to blocked websites and apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://syncthing.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Syncthing&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source cross platform peer-to-peer continuous file synchronization application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://keybase.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt; is a new and free security app for mobile phones and computers. Think of it as an open source Dropbox &amp;amp; Slack with end-to-end encryption public-key cryptography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/junegunn/fzf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fzf&lt;/a&gt; is an interactive Unix filter for command-line that can be used with any list; files, command history, processes, hostnames, bookmarks, git commits, etc. Fzf supports Unix, macOS and has beta support for Windows. It also can operate as a vim plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of these authors have said that their projects would not exist without Go. Some like Kubernetes and Docker created entirely new solutions. Others like Hugo, Syncthing and Fzf created more refined experiences where many solutions already existed. The popularity of these applications alone is proof that Go is a ideal language for a broad set of use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_1.5.&quot;&gt;Thank You&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the eighth time we have had the pleasure of writing a birthday blog post for Go and we continue to be overwhelmed by and grateful for the enthusiasm and support of the Go community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Go was first open sourced we have had 10 releases of the language, libraries and tooling with more than 1680 contributors making over 50,000 commits to the project's 34 repositories; More than double the number of contributors and nearly double the number of commits from only &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/6years&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;two years ago&lt;/a&gt;. This year we announced that we have begun planning &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/toward-go2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Go 2&lt;/a&gt;, our first major revision of the language and tooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Go team would like to thank everyone who has contributed to the project, whether you participate by contributing changes, reporting bugs, sharing your expertise in design discussions, writing blog posts or books, running events, attending or speaking at events, helping others learn or improve, open sourcing Go packages you wrote, contributing artwork, introducing Go to someone, or being part of the Go community. Without you, Go would not be as complete, useful, or successful as it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, and here’s to eight more years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;By Steve Francia&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 18:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>spacey</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.golang.org/8years</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How we do Vue at GitLab: one year later</title>
<link>https://about.gitlab.com/2017/11/09/gitlab-vue-one-year-later/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://about.gitlab.com/2017/11/09/gitlab-vue-one-year-later/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/2016/10/20/why-we-chose-vue/&quot;&gt;we wrote about Vue&lt;/a&gt;. We've been using Vue for over a year now and life has been very good. Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lnoogn&quot;&gt;@lnoogn&lt;/a&gt; for reminding me to write this article!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our situation reminds me of a quote about Scala from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/scala/comments/2hw0bp/is_scala_slowly_dying/&quot;&gt;&quot;Is Scala slowly dying?&quot;&lt;/a&gt; Someone once said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scala people don't have time for redditing and blogging, they're busy getting crap done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is exactly what we've been doing. Like Scala, Vue works really, really well, when used properly. It turns out Vue isn't a buzzword, Vue is a workhorse. A lot of our problems have been solved, by us and others. We still have problems but, we now have a reproducible &quot;way to write Vue.&quot; We don't adopt every new idea out there, but we have changed a few things since we last spoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since that last post, we published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/development/fe_guide/vue.html&quot;&gt;very extensive Vue style guide&lt;/a&gt;, after which Vue also put out a &lt;a href=&quot;https://vuejs.org/v2/style-guide/&quot;&gt;style guide&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vuejs/eslint-plugin-vue/issues/77#issuecomment-315834845&quot;&gt;taking inspiration from ours&lt;/a&gt;. The style guide has been updated several times as we discover better ways to write Vue. Here are some of the things we discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;just-use-vuex&quot;&gt;Just use VueX&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discovered that &lt;a href=&quot;https://vuex.vuejs.org/&quot;&gt;VueX&lt;/a&gt; makes our lives easier. If you are writing a medium to large feature, use VueX. If it's a tiny feature, you might get away without it. We made the mistake of not using VueX for a large feature. We wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/31890&quot;&gt;multi-file editor&lt;/a&gt; (WIP) to replace our current repo file view, to allow easy editing of multiple files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/vue_2017/multi-file-editor.png&quot; alt=&quot;multi-file-editor.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning we did not use VueX for this feature and instead used the store pattern. The Vue docs talk about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://vuejs.org/v2/guide/state-management.html#Simple-State-Management-from-Scratch&quot;&gt;store pattern&lt;/a&gt;, which works well when you are committed to strictly keeping to the pattern. We've found that you are better off spending your time with VueX instead. While VueX is initially more verbose, it is much more scalable, and will save you tons of time in the long run. Our mistake happened when we changed the data in multiple places. In VueX you are forced to change the data in one central place. If you don't do this, you will wind up chasing unexpected bugs around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;write-high-quality-code&quot;&gt;Write high quality code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though VueJS and VueX are both wonderful, it is still possible (as with any code) to write bad Vue code. While the code may work, your longevity and scalability may suffer. Performance can suffer. With Vue, it makes it so easy to have what seems like working, perfect code because Vue is so simple to write. Longevity problems can mean that your code initially works, but you (and others) will have a hard time trying to update the code. Performance problems might not crop up with small data sets, but will with larger ones. Code can get messy. Your code can get smelly. Yes, even with Vue, you can have &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_smell&quot;&gt;code smell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you add something to the &lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt; object or the &lt;code&gt;store&lt;/code&gt; for Vue to keep track of, Vue will recursively walk down your data object and keep track of everything. If your data is super hierarchical and just large in general, and you are changing things often (like maybe on &lt;code&gt;mousemove&lt;/code&gt;), then you can create jank. It's not bad to have Vue observe large data sets, but just confirm that you do in fact need the data you are watching to be reactive. It's easy with Vue to just make everything reactive, when it might not need to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why we are very strict when anyone writes Vue code. They must &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/development/fe_guide/vue.html&quot;&gt;follow our documentation&lt;/a&gt;. They must also only write Vue when it is necessary and not write it &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/development/fe_guide/vue.html#when-not-to-use-vue-js&quot;&gt;when it is overkill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of our new Vue code follows the &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.github.io/flux/&quot;&gt;Flux architecture&lt;/a&gt;. VueX also follows Flux, which is part of the reason we use VueX. You can use the previously mentioned &quot;store pattern,&quot; but VueX is a better choice because it enforces all of the rules. If you go rogue, you will wind up enforcing the rules yourself, and you will probably make mistakes. The less you put on your plate, the better. A good example of a well-written Vue app is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/merge_requests/14303&quot;&gt;registry image list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-want-to-use-jquery-with-vue&quot;&gt;I want to use jQuery with Vue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During new development, this question kept popping up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it ever OK to mix jQuery with VueJS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not talking about using &lt;a href=&quot;https://select2.org/&quot;&gt;Select2&lt;/a&gt;, which is a jQuery library. We are talking about the need to query the DOM. We had discussions about using jQuery and the following was proposed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using jQuery is OK, but only for querying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I had several discussions about using jQuery with Vue. Some had said it might be OK, but only in read-only (querying) situations. However, after doing the research, we found that it is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a good idea to use jQuery with Vue. There will always be a better solution. We found that if you ever find yourself needing to query to DOM within a Vue architecture, then you are doing something wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one were to hypothetically use jQuery for only the tiniest querying situations, one would have to quantify those situations. You should instead swear off querying the DOM when in Vue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of querying, you will find that using the &lt;code&gt;store&lt;/code&gt; in combination with the server-side code is usually a much simpler answer. The server can provide validity to your data that you cannot provide on the client side. For the most part, we find that the less we have to fool with the data on the client side the better. That's not to say it's never OK to modify the data on the client side, but that it isn't usually the cleanest solution. At GitLab we use querying only to grab endpoints from the &lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt; attribute of our main element, but we don't use jQuery, we use &lt;code&gt;el.dataset&lt;/code&gt;. At GitLab, we (the Frontend people) talk with the Backend people to ensure the structure of the data we will be consuming. In that way, both the Frontend team and the Backend team can be in control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;example-situation&quot;&gt;Example situation:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out this issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/vue_2017/issue.png&quot; alt=&quot;issue&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now render all issue comments in Vue. An example of a situation where we wanted to use jQuery was during the rewrite of the edit-the-last-user-comment feature. When someone presses that &lt;code&gt;up&lt;/code&gt; key on their keyboard from an empty new comment &lt;code&gt;textarea&lt;/code&gt; (at the very bottom of the page) we allow them to edit the last comment they created, just like in Slack. Not just the last comment, but the last comment &lt;em&gt;they created&lt;/em&gt;. We marked the last user comment in the picture in red. Of course there is a time crunch. Then someone might say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can't we just do a quick solution here and fix it later?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely you &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; query the DOM for this. A better solution, in this case, is to let the backend developers mark the last user comment in the JSON they return. Backend developers have direct access to the database, which means they may be able to optimize the code. Then no client-side work has to be done at all, in this case. Someone has to do the work to mark the last user comment. In this case the solution is just finding the right person for the job. Once you have that data from the server, the comment is in your &lt;code&gt;store&lt;/code&gt;, ready for your easy access. You can do anything now. The world is your oyster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself querying the DOM, &quot;just this one time&quot; 😉, there is always a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-proper-vue-app&quot;&gt;The proper Vue app&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Vue bundle needs one store, one service, and always has one entry point. Your entry point component is the only container component and every other component is presentational. All this information is in our Vue docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can start out with a single &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight html&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!--HAML--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
.js-vue-app{ data: { endpoint: 'foo' }}

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!--HTML--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;js-vue-app&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;data-endpoint=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;foo&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can pass your endpoints in through the data attributes. Vue can then call these endpoints with an HTTP client of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't want to do any URL building in client-side JavaScript. Make sure you pass in all your server-built URLs through endpoints. When writing Vue it's important to let the server do what it should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;improve-performance&quot;&gt;Improve performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recently rewrote our issue comments in Vue. The issue comments were previously written in Haml, jQuery, and Rails. We had a bottleneck because we were not loading the comments asynchronously. A quick solution is to load comments via ajax and populate comments after the page loads. One way to make a page load faster is to not block the page with heavy items and load them after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/vue_2017/comments.png&quot; alt=&quot;comments.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we love is that one day we turned on the new comments and some people didn't know that we had refactored it. As a result of the refactor our issue pages load much faster, and there is less jank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loading the comments on the issue page is now streamlined and now individual issues load much faster. In the past, an issue page could have tens of thousands of event listeners. Our previous code was not properly removing and keeping track of event listeners. Those massive event listeners (along with other problems) created jank, so scrolling the page was choppy with many comments. We removed jQuery and added in Vue and focused on improving the performance. You can clearly see and feel that the page is much faster. However, our work to improve the performance has just begun. This rewrite sets the foundation for performance improvements that are easier to write, because the code is much more maintainable. Previously the code was hard to maintain. Now the issue comments code is properly separated and &quot;componentized.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these new improvements, as well as other parallel improvements, e.g. loading images on scroll, we were able to make the page load and perform faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/vue_2017/speed.png&quot; alt=&quot;speed.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refactoring is that word that a new, super-green developer mentions on day one when they suggest to rewrite everything in Angular. That hasn't happened at GitLab. Our frontend devs tend to be very conservative, which is a very good thing. Which begs the question, why does it seems like &lt;a href=&quot;https://reasonml.github.io/community/blog/#reason-3&quot;&gt;everyone is always refactoring&lt;/a&gt;? What are they trying to achieve? I can only speak for GitLab. What do we want to achieve with a refactor? In reality it's going to cost a lot of money. The costs are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cost of doing the refactoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost of testing the change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost of updating tests and documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;You also have more risk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Risk of introducing bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk of taking on a huge task that you can't finish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk of not achieving the quality/improvements you intended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our goals are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal #1&lt;/strong&gt;: Make the code more maintainable. We want to make the process of adding new features easier. In the long term this refactor will save us time, but it takes a signifiant amount of time to recoup the time spent refactoring. The hard truth may be that a refactor usually does not save you time, but can save you stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal #2&lt;/strong&gt;: What it can do, if done right, is make developers happy. Nothing gives your team more horsepower than a happy, excited coder. A stressed-out coder will want to stop coding; an excited coder will not want to stop. A happy coder saves the most time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To meet our goal our next step is to refactor the merge request comments section. Our merge request comments are massively slow for merge requests with lots of comments. The comments become slower and start to be less responsive at around 200 comments. The diffs are slow as well. There are a ton of reasons for this, one of which is that JavaScript is causing multiple reflows that take tons of time. We could refactor this and have already put in a fix, but this isn't a long-term solution. In the case of a huge MR, there was code that was causing a reflow that &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/39332&quot;&gt;takes over eight seconds&lt;/a&gt;! This is now fixed. In this &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/uploads/e18856a1544d4d0e6420d11fd0479af7/ss__2017-10-20_at_1.41.04_PM.png&quot;&gt;image&lt;/a&gt; you can see there is other stuff slowing things down. Clearly there is a lot of work to do here. Our biggest problem is that the code is not maintainable, which means that fixes take longer. A refactor into Vue will provide some great initial speed improvements, and lay the groundwork for easier improvements in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is so much work to do at GitLab. If you want to be a part of exploring the massive catacombs of GitLab and writing awesome code and if you are interested in helping out our Frontend team, then &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/jobs/frontend-engineer/&quot;&gt;apply&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 17:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>unnawut</dc:creator>
<og:title>How we do Vue: one year later</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://about.gitlab.com/2017/11/09/gitlab-vue-one-year-later/</og:url>
<og:image>https://about.gitlab.com/images/vue_2017/vue-title.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://about.gitlab.com/2017/11/09/gitlab-vue-one-year-later/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Burn the Programmer</title>
<link>http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2017/11/burn-the-programmer.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2017/11/burn-the-programmer.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;asset-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post by Virtual Reality developer Hugh Hancock, creator of &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/app/488760/LeftHand_Path/&quot;&gt;VR horror RPG Left-Hand Path&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've always had a problem with Arthur C Clarke's Third Law, &quot;Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic.&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may have something to do with my career for a long time involving both magic and technology. Magic's a perennial fiction obsession of mine, and my media of choice have always been highly technological.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recently, I just released &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/app/488760/LeftHand_Path/&quot;&gt;Left-Hand Path&lt;/a&gt;. It's a Virtual Reality game for the Oculus Rift and HTC Vive - obviously fairly technological - whose central conceit is that in it, you learn the skills to cast spells. And I don't just mean you select spells from a spellbook and then press a button: I mean you have to learn the gestures necessary to create the magic, and on occasion go through a complex system of ritual magic to create the effects you desire, flipping through your grimoire to remember exactly how you summon your ancient powers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/app/488760/LeftHand_Path/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.akamai.steamstatic.com/steam/apps/488760/ss_8db4d0a937899b6b07d24faa259467a8c487155b.1920x1080.jpg?t=1507726719&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, all that makes for a great game. There's a sense of accomplishment as you learn to use the powers of magic to your advantage and remember how to cast the &quot;Vis&quot; spell as something nasty is closing on you. There's a sense of discovery as you learn more about the world, the way magic works, and find powerful new spells. And there's a sense of pant-crapping terror as you realise that the things your new ritual summons to eat your foes will cheerfully eat you as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Fun fact: horror games are more intense in VR, by some margin. So terrifying, in fact, that I added a &quot;Low Terror Mode&quot; recently, after reading a significant number of people saying &quot;I'd love to play your game, but I absolutely won't, because it sounds way too scary.&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, none of that description of magic sounds very much like the technology I use in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have to imprecate dark and terrible forces in order to use my PS4, unless you count Sony's latest privacy policy. My lovely new iPad is famously intuitive, not a quality one would ascribe to &lt;em&gt;The Lesser Key Of Solomon&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is a big but. (I cannot lie.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of what I describe sounds like the &lt;em&gt;consumer&lt;/em&gt; tech that I use. That's not so much the case for the other technology I interact with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think that distinction - and the points where Clarke's Third Law does still apply - may explain a lot about why technologists are increasingly becoming hated in many circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;more&quot; class=&quot;asset-more&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Speak friend().init and enter&lt;/h2&gt;
Magic is arcane - in the original meaning of the world. It's occult - again, in the original meaning of the world. It's difficult, dangerous, and often quite impractical despite its theoretical incredible power. ...Ever tried to set up a Sendmail server?The technology that we deal with as technologists absolutely obeys Clarke's Third Law. Indeed, I've often wondered quite how much Charlie's Laundry Files magic was inspired by the fact he had a career before &quot;Novelist&quot; writing PERL. I've occasionally wondered if inscribing a pentagram and blood sacrifice would be more effective in ranking a site on Google than the traditional approaches. I've made myself physically ill whilst creating other worlds in the first generation of VR. Sounds like magic to me. Indeed, I've read multiple books where the wizard protagonist suffers a severe &quot;magic hangover&quot; after overextending his powers, and it sounds a lot like what I experienced after finally getting Minecraft to work on my Oculus DK1. (Side note: on quality VR platforms, those being Oculus and Vive, the vomiting thing is mostly solved by now. Don't fear the Great God Huey if you're thinking of trying those.) I mean, does this look like some magical incantation stuff to you?
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t])&lt;em&gt;(?:(?:(?:[^()&amp;lt;&amp;gt;@,;:\&quot;.[] \000-\031]+(?:(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t] )+|\Z|(?=[[&quot;()&amp;lt;&amp;gt;@,;:\&quot;.[]]))|&quot;(?:[^\&quot;\r\]|\.|(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t]))&lt;/em&gt;&quot;(?:(?: \r\n)?[ \t])&lt;em&gt;)(?:.(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t])&lt;/em&gt;(?:[^()&amp;lt;&amp;gt;@,;:\&quot;.[] \000-\031]+(?:(?:( ?:\r\n)?[ \t])+|\Z|(?=[[&quot;()&amp;lt;&amp;gt;@,;:\&quot;.[]]))|&quot;(?:[^\&quot;\r\]|\.|(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t]))&quot;(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t])))&lt;em&gt;@(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t])&lt;/em&gt;(?:[^()&amp;lt;&amp;gt;@,;:\&quot;.[] \000-\0 31]+(?:(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t])+|\Z|(?=[[&quot;()&amp;lt;&amp;gt;@,;:\&quot;.[]]))|[([^[]\r\]|\.)*\ ](?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t])&lt;em&gt;)(?:.(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t])&lt;/em&gt;(?:[^()&amp;lt;&amp;gt;@,;:\&quot;.[] \000-\031]+ (?:(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t])+|\Z|(?=[[&quot;()&amp;lt;&amp;gt;@,;:\&quot;.[]]))|[([^[]\r\]|\.)&lt;em&gt;](?: (?:\r\n)?[ \t])&lt;/em&gt;))|(?:[^()&amp;lt;&amp;gt;@,;:\&quot;.[] \000-\031]+(?:(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t])+|\Z |(?=[[&quot;()&amp;lt;&amp;gt;@,;:\&quot;.[]]))|&quot;(?:[^\&quot;\r\]|\.|(?:(?:\r\n)?[ \t]))&quot;(?:(?:\r\n)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Ask the non-technologist in your life. Or just carve it on a stone tablet and leave it somewhere around Skara Brae for archaeologists to get excited about.
&lt;h2&gt;Klaatu barada MongoDB&lt;/h2&gt;
So there's this class of people in the world who can do incredible things - like, say, teaching a car to drive itself. Or indeed crafting &lt;a href=&quot;https://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-robot-vacuum/&quot;&gt;a literal Magician's Broom&lt;/a&gt; to clean their towers - I mean, apartments. And they do this by immersing themselves in obscure, difficult learning that on the face of it makes no sense to the average person. They don't need large teams of people or masses of wealth to do these things. In fact, if one of them locks themselves up in their tower, they're likely to come out in 10 years having &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bay12games.com/dwarves/&quot;&gt;created an entire world for themselves as a plaything&lt;/a&gt;. They can cause harm to people tens of thousands of miles away using weirdly-named incantations - like &quot;WannaCry&quot;. They summon and control alien entities called &quot;AIs&quot;. They don't always perfectly control those entities. And they can amass unimaginable wealth and power by using these arcane skills. What happens next? Well, it's fairly clear from a cursory read over fantasy literature - and it's fresh in my mind as humans' reactions to magic users are also a key plot-point of Left-Hand Path. They're either going to get worshipped as gods - or they get &lt;a href=&quot;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/BurnTheWitch&quot;&gt;burned as a witch&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;h2&gt;Thou Shalt Not Suffer A Programmer To Live&lt;/h2&gt;
Obviously there are plenty of other reasons why society at large might be getting a bit skeptical of the tech giants, Silicon Valley, and so on. There's the wealth disparity. The diversity culture. The threat of strong AI. And more. But I can't help but feel, looking at a lot of the media pushback at the moment, that a lot of it is straight-up fantasy novel 101 &quot;Reactions To Wizardry&quot;. And it's particularly ironic because most of the people reacting are surrounded by the same wizardry. They've got daemons in their phones. They're organising using services that have been carefully massaged to not require &quot;magic&quot; to use. Their cars and their TVs and their fridges all contain little bits of complex, arcane magic that can only be understood by the &quot;wizards&quot;. Don't get confused with the real-world &quot;witch hunts&quot; here. Those witches didn't (probably) actually have magical powers. This is something else. And as I watch 2017 unfold in all its craziness, I do start wondering whether the conversation should be less about robots, and more about straight-up magic. About a world which is increasingly splitting into those who can wield magic, those who can pay the magicians, and those who just use the things magic enables. Because that's the interesting part: whilst Arthur C Clarke's maxim was true, and &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; advanced technology was arcane and difficult, these problems didn't occur. It's only now, as technology finally surpasses magic enough to eat society as a whole, rather than just the beardy guys in the towers studying eldrich tomes, that society as a whole notices the wizards in its midst. Now, if you'll excuse me, I've just released &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/app/488760/LeftHand_Path/&quot;&gt;an army of scuttling, gliding, limbless, bodiless eldrich horrors on the general population&lt;/a&gt;, and I've got to go see how they're reacting. &lt;em&gt;What do you think? Are programmers in danger of burning?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 15:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thenomad</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2017/11/burn-the-programmer.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube says it will crack down on bizarre videos targeting children</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/9/16629788/youtube-kids-distrubing-inappropriate-flag-age-restrict</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/9/16629788/youtube-kids-distrubing-inappropriate-flag-age-restrict</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;8zpOkS&quot;&gt;Earlier this week, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/04/business/media/youtube-kids-paw-patrol.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;a report&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; and a blog post &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jamesbridle/something-is-wrong-on-the-internet-c39c471271d2&quot;&gt;on Medium&lt;/a&gt; drew a lot of attention to a world of strange and sometimes disturbing videos on YouTube aimed at young children. The genre, which we &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/20/14489052/youtube-kids-videos-superheroes-disney-characters-fart-jokes&quot;&gt;reported on&lt;/a&gt; in February of this year, makes use of popular characters from family-friendly entertainment, but it’s often created with little care, and can quickly stray from innocent themes to scenes of violence or sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4NWdT5&quot;&gt;In August of this year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/7/16108612/youtube-creators-appeal-advertising-limits&quot;&gt;YouTube announced&lt;/a&gt; that it would no longer allow creators to monetize videos which “made inappropriate use of family friendly characters.” Today it’s taking another step to try and police this genre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;q9K7an&quot;&gt;“We’re in the process of implementing a new policy that &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2802167?hl=en&quot;&gt;age restricts&lt;/a&gt; this content in the YouTube main app when flagged,” said Juniper Downs, YouTube’s director of policy. “Age-restricted content is automatically not allowed in YouTube Kids.” YouTube says that it’s been formulating this new policy for a while, and that it’s not rolling it out in direct response to the recent coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;jGyn72&quot;&gt;The first line of defense for YouTube Kids are algorithmic filters. After that, there is a team of humans that review videos which have been flagged. If a video with recognizable children’s characters gets flagged in YouTube’s main app, which is much larger than the Kids app, it will be sent to the policy review team. YouTube says it has thousands of people working around the clock in different time zones to review flagged content. If the review finds the video is in violation of the new policy, it will be age restrictied, automatically blocking it from showing up in the Kids app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;rDXkge&quot;&gt;YouTube says it typically takes at least a few days for content to make its way from YouTube proper to YouTube Kids, and the hope is that within that window, users will flag anything potentially disturbing to children. YouTube also has a team of volunteer moderators, which it calls &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7124236?hl=en&quot;&gt;Contributors&lt;/a&gt;, looking for inappropriate content. YouTube says it will start training its review team on the new policy and it should be live within a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;RjdiHj&quot;&gt;Along with filtering content out of the Kids app, the new policy will also tweak who can see these videos on YouTube’s main service. Flagged content will be age restricted, and users won’t be able to see those videos if they’re not logged in on accounts registered to users 18 years or older. All age-gated content is also automatically exempt from advertising. That means this new policy could put a squeeze on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tubefilter.com/2017/02/02/youtube-bizarre-trend-adults-spider-man-elsa-costumes/&quot;&gt;booming business&lt;/a&gt; of crafting strange kid’s content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;2cgQ6D&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fBWf6Zvn0jQ?rel=0&amp;amp;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;rep9CG&quot;&gt;YouTube is trying to walk a fine line between owning up to this problem and arguing that the issue is relatively minor. It says that the fraction of videos on YouTube Kids that were missed by its algorithmic filters and then flagged by users during the last 30 days amounted to just 0.005 percent of videos on the service. The company also says the reports that inappropriate videos racked up millions of views on YouTube Kids without being vetted are false, because those views came from activity on YouTube proper, which makes clear in its terms of service that it’s aimed at user 13 years and older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;LPbAbm&quot;&gt;In today’s policy announcement, YouTube is acknowledging the problem, and promising to police it better. It doesn’t want to outright ban the use of family-friendly characters by creators who aren’t the original copyright holders across all of YouTube. There is a place, the company is arguing, for satire about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=owm0ZgAVEWU&quot;&gt;Peppa Pig drinking bleach&lt;/a&gt;, however distasteful you might find it. But YouTube is acknowledging that YouTube Kids requires even more moderation. And, the company is willing to forgo additional ad revenue — and there is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tubefilter.com/2017/02/02/youtube-bizarre-trend-adults-spider-man-elsa-costumes/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of money&lt;/a&gt; flowing through this segment of the industry — if that’s what it takes to ensure YouTube Kids feels like a safe experience for families.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 14:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>artsandsci</dc:creator>
<og:description>Videos that violate policy will now be age restricted</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BP61zGpZ6VCx6Hp-ro_UUS1TawQ=/0x93:1716x991/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9644957/Screen_Shot_2017_11_09_at_2.33.42_PM.png</og:image>
<og:title>YouTube says it will crack down on bizarre videos targeting children</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/9/16629788/youtube-kids-distrubing-inappropriate-flag-age-restrict</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/9/16629788/youtube-kids-distrubing-inappropriate-flag-age-restrict</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“We have obtained fully functional JTAG for Intel CSME via USB DCI”</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/h0t_max/status/928269320064450560</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/h0t_max/status/928269320064450560</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;But the important thing is that someone publicly saying they found this changes /nothing/. Finding an exploit does not mean creating it: the exploit was already there, and there's no way to know whether someone else has already been quietly exploiting it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 11:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cryogenic_soul</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/h0t_max/status/928269320064450560</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Halfbakery</title>
<link>http://www.halfbakery.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.halfbakery.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.halfbakery.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.halfbakery.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15669119&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15669119&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 202&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 54&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 10:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amelius</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.halfbakery.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Secret Service Agent Sentenced In Scheme Related To Silk Road Investigation</title>
<link>https://www.justice.gov/usao-ndca/pr/former-secret-service-agent-sentenced-scheme-related-silk-road-investigation</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.justice.gov/usao-ndca/pr/former-secret-service-agent-sentenced-scheme-related-silk-road-investigation</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;SAN FRANCISCO – A former U.S. Secret Service Special Agent, who had been a member of the Baltimore Silk Road Task Force, was sentenced to prison today on charges of money laundering, announced U.S. Attorney Brian J. Stretch, Acting Assistant Attorney General Kenneth A. Blanco of the Justice Department’s Criminal Division, Chief Don Fort of the Internal Revenue Service Criminal Investigation (IRS-CI), Special Agent in Charge John F. Bennett of the FBI’s San Francisco Division, and Special Agent in Charge of the Department of Homeland Security Office of the Inspector General Houston Field Office David Green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaun W. Bridges, 35, of Laurel, Md., was sentenced to 24 months in prison by U.S. District Judge Richard Seeborg in San Francisco following his earlier guilty plea to one count of money laundering.  Judge Seeborg ordered that the sentence be served consecutively to a previous sentence that Bridges is currently serving.  Bridges was also ordered to forfeit approximately 1,500 bitcoin and other fiat currency which has a current value of approximately $10.4 million.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bridges had been a Special Agent with the U.S. Secret Service for approximately six years in the Baltimore Field Office.  Between 2012 and 2014, he was assigned to the Baltimore Silk Road Task Force, a multi-agency group investigating illegal activity on the Silk Road, a covert online marketplace for illicit goods, including drugs.  Bridges’ responsibilities included, among other things, conducting forensic computer investigations in an effort to locate, identify and prosecute targets of the Baltimore Task Force, including Ross Ulbricht, aka “Dread Pirate Roberts,” who ran the Silk Road from the Northern District of California.  In 2015, Bridges was arrested and taken into custody on charges related to the theft of approximately 1,600 bitcoin from a digital wallet belonging to the U.S. government.  According to admissions made in connection with his guilty plea, Bridges admitted to using a private key to access a digital wallet belonging to the U.S. government, and subsequently transferring the bitcoin to other digital wallets at other bitcoin exchanges to which only he had access.  As part of his plea, Bridges agreed to turn over the stolen bitcoin to U.S. agents.                 &lt;br/&gt;  &lt;br/&gt;The case is being investigated by the FBI’s San Francisco Division, IRS-CI’s Washington, D.C. Field Office Cyber Crimes Unit, and the Department of Homeland Security Office of the Inspector General in Washington D.C.  The case is being prosecuted by Assistant U.S. Attorney William Frentzen and Trial Attorney Richard B. Evans of the Criminal Division’s Public Integrity Section.  Assistant U.S. Attorney David Countryman handled the asset forfeiture aspects of the case.    &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 09:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>FriedPickles</dc:creator>
<og:title>Former Secret Service Agent Sentenced In Scheme Related To Silk Road Investigation</og:title>
<og:image>https://www.justice.gov/sites/all/modules/features/doj_sharing/images/doj-seal-fb.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.justice.gov/usao-ndca/pr/former-secret-service-agent-sentenced-scheme-related-silk-road-investigation</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>