<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Dell’s gamble on Linux laptops has paid off</title>
<link>http://www.techradar.com/news/why-dells-gamble-on-linux-laptops-has-paid-off</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.techradar.com/news/why-dells-gamble-on-linux-laptops-has-paid-off</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article was provided to TechRadar by Linux Format, the number one magazine to boost your knowledge on Linux, open source developments, distro releases and much more. It appeared in issue 220, published February 2017. Subscribe to the print or digital version of Linux Format&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.myfavouritemagazines.co.uk/computer/linux-format-magazine-subscription/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole juggernaut that is now Linux on Dell started as the brainchild of two core individuals, Barton George (Senior Principal Engineer) and Jared Dominguez (OS Architect and Linux Engineer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was their vision that began it all back in 2012. It was long hours, uncertain futures and sheer belief that people really did want Linux laptops that sustained them. Here is the untold story of how Dell gained the top spot in preinstalled Linux on laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where do you start when no one has ever really even touched such a concept? The duo did have some experience of the area before. George explained that the XPS and M3800 Linux developer’s laptops weren’t Dell’s first foray into Linux laptops. Those with long memories may remember Dell testing the waters for a brief while by having a Linux offering alongside &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techradar.com/news/dell-laptop-deals&quot;&gt;Windows laptops&lt;/a&gt;. By their own admission it didn’t work out. “We misread the market,” commented George.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first attempt at Linux on laptops failed mainly because most non-technical users were blinded by the cheap price and didn’t understand what they were actually buying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dell found itself with purchasers who thought that they had scored an incredibly cheap laptop only to hit the inevitable question: “Where the heck has Windows gone?” which was generally followed by costly support issues and potential returns for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other unfortunate side effect was that by appealing to users with low-end hardware the experience was less than impressive even for those knowledgeable in Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully Dell decided to give Linux on laptops a second attempt thanks to George and Dominguez’s internal lobbying efforts. It isn’t a well-known fact but Dell has an internal skunkworks project where tiny projects can pitch ideas and get official Dell support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proving you can’t keep a good operating system down, George and Dominguez bid for funds in the Dell projects forum to produce a quality alternative to OS X and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techradar.com/reviews/pc-mac/software/operating-systems/windows-10-1267364/review&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;. It was a tense wait to see if they had done enough to get the blessing of the skunkworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, the project scored a green light. However, the struggle was only just beginning as they had a comparatively miniscule budget of $40,000 (around £32,000, AU$52,000) and just six months to prove that not only could they build a compelling Linux on laptops offering but that Dell could turn it into a viable product and make money off of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning how not to create Linux laptops from the first time was helpful but there were some major differences with the new project. The first one being that they needed to nail their market and it was a crucial concern given their previous failure to find the right one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bordeaux-image-check&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn0.static.techradar.futurecdn.net/media/img/missing-image.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; lazy-image lazy-image-loading lazyload optional-image&quot; onerror=&quot;this.parentNode.replaceChild(window.missingImage(),this)&quot; sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-normal=&quot;http://cdn0.static.techradar.futurecdn.net/media/img/missing-image.svg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dzBrvhUM76zE3r4D3PyuT3-320-80.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dzBrvhUM76zE3r4D3PyuT3-320-80.jpg 320w, https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dzBrvhUM76zE3r4D3PyuT3-650-80.jpg 650w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-original-mos=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dzBrvhUM76zE3r4D3PyuT3.jpg&quot; data-pin-media=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dzBrvhUM76zE3r4D3PyuT3.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;know-your-market&quot;&gt;Know your market&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to make sure they had the right ideas and concepts they jumped on a plane bound for the West Coast and landed in California to speak to several “very large web shops” that the pair declined to name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made the trip that bit more awkward for them was the fact that the Dell duo could only show some prototypes of a laptop that they “may sorta perhaps” have coming to market. No guarantees, no promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universally the reception was ‘Get back to us when you have the real product but we sure are interested.’ This was positive news because the pair knew that these were the type of companies that could purchase many units and make the project financially viable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time the duo had the right initial market. It was big, commercial web-scale operators and their developers who were crying out for a fully supported Linux laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back from their successful trip, the duo realised that the project would never see the light of day without big support from someone with gravitas championing its cause. Fortunately, they didn’t have to look far. In this instance, they had Michael Dell’s executive assistant as their champion – aside from Mr Dell himself they were unlikely to top that, so the team felt confident their backs were covered, but now needed to deliver on their promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They can provide the air cover but you need to work hard on the ground,” was George’s take on the situation and when it came to the hardware they had to make sure it was a good offering and more importantly worked well with Linux. Cost was almost secondary to making sure the product worked and was popular with their big clients they’d met previously who had loved the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first offerings needed to be both priced attractively and be fairly configurable given that they had to appeal to a range of users. The XPS was seen as the obvious choice given its quality, expandability and popularity. The first XPS Linux offering (Gen1 circa 2012) was a single configuration built and offered up to the world. It couldn’t be found on Dell’s website, though. The initial notice of availability was given via George’s personal website. He also noted that it was most definitely a beta product and had all the baggage that the tag brought with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George recalled how in a typical week his blog would average 1,500 hits a day. When the XPS development station was mentioned views skyrocketed to a peak over several weeks of 9,000 views a day. Not epic, but a good start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requests for beta testers (who had to commit to purchasing their own units – this was no freebie) rolled in left, right and centre, eventually totalling over 6,000 requests to be included in the program, which quickly proved that the idea of Linux on Dell laptops had a viable and, importantly, profitable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internally, word got around about this cool new project that was going on. In typical geek fashion people started to donate time and resources for free (well, on Dell’s dime technically but no one was counting). A few lucky individuals, including Dominguez, were permanently borrowed for third line Linux server support, never to return as bigger endeavours beckoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bordeaux-image-check&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn0.static.techradar.futurecdn.net/media/img/missing-image.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; lazy-image lazy-image-loading lazyload optional-image&quot; onerror=&quot;this.parentNode.replaceChild(window.missingImage(),this)&quot; sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-normal=&quot;http://cdn0.static.techradar.futurecdn.net/media/img/missing-image.svg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VnKNfTueRGLAxttk6uc5b3-320-80.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VnKNfTueRGLAxttk6uc5b3-320-80.jpg 320w, https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VnKNfTueRGLAxttk6uc5b3-650-80.jpg 650w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-original-mos=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VnKNfTueRGLAxttk6uc5b3.jpg&quot; data-pin-media=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VnKNfTueRGLAxttk6uc5b3.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techradar.com/news/software/operating-systems/best-linux-distros-for-power-users-1153562&quot;&gt;Power users&lt;/a&gt; and developers know that RAM is king when trying to develop and perform debugging. While the Gen 1 XPS was all good, the screen was a bit small for some and the amount of RAM that could be installed was a little limiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Dominguez’s first off-the-hip moves was to get a larger, more powerful Developers Edition laptop for those they had courted earlier that same year. An M3800 notebook got the Linux makeover for those developers that wanted performance over size. Fortunately, both machines shared the same peripherals, trackpads etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as things seemed to be coming together the project narrowly avoided a near-fatal cancellation. No one saw it coming but in late 2012 Dell was looking to save money as times were proving hard after the global recession of 2008. Everyone and every project was fair game to be scaled down or closed to help the bottom line. The Linux on laptops project, just weeks from release, was a plump and juicy target for some and George and Dominguez weren’t even sure if the project would ever see the commercial light of day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They carried on anyway, half expecting to be told to stop, the dream is over. Sleepless nights plagued the project. Luckily, the team dodged the cost-cutting bullet but as Dominguez reflected on the feeling at the time: “If anything it was a call to get this puppy out the door as quickly as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Dell’s point of view it was a high-risk, high-reward scenario: a market with no other big players and ripe for the taking. There still had to be accountability in terms of costs and deliverables, however: “Our original idea of having several configurations per device wasn’t feasible so we narrowed it down to just one device with one configuration to streamline our focus,” explained George. “Slowly but surely we’ve been able to build out our portfolio and are now pleased to offer four different Precision models.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This meant a slowly but surely approach with limited but well-configured systems available, as multiple configurations cost development time, money and resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 06:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>em3rgent0rdr</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why Dell’s gamble on Linux laptops has paid off</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.techradar.com/news/why-dells-gamble-on-linux-laptops-has-paid-off</og:url>
<og:description>And what does the future hold for these notebooks?</og:description>
<og:image>http://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4XGPPkwnpAcvqnHZaafKV3-1200-80.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.techradar.com/news/why-dells-gamble-on-linux-laptops-has-paid-off</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Education Startups Do Not Succeed (2011)</title>
<link>https://avichal.com/2011/10/07/why-education-startups-do-not-succeed/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://avichal.com/2011/10/07/why-education-startups-do-not-succeed/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; I co-founded PrepMe in 2001. We were one of the first education companies online and the first purely online, personalized platform. We were acquired in 2011 by Providence Equity-backed Ascend Learning. &lt;/em&gt;In the last month, I’ve had 3 VC firms bring me in to chat with their partnership about education and 6 independent entrepreneurs reach out to me about their new education startup. This is a summary of what I tell them in person. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I am going to make some generalizations below. Clearly there are nuances around education policy, economic policy, technology, and more. But this is a blog post, not a book, so take it for what it’s worth. These views are my own, not PrepMe’s (or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getspool.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Spool’s&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Most entrepreneurs in education build the wrong type of business, because entrepreneurs think of education as a quality problem. The average person thinks of it as a cost problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building in education does not follow an Internet company’s growth curve. Do it because you want to fix problems in education for the next 20 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are opportunities in education in servicing the poor in the US and building a company in Asia — not in selling to the middle class in the US.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The underlying culture will change and expose interesting opportunities in the long term, but probably not for another 5 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Education is ripe for disruption. Technology and great products could make education so much better. If a product like Blackboard or University of Phoenix can succeed, then imagine how great a company you could build if built educational products like Apple does for consumer electronics!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let’s qualify what they’re saying here. Almost always what they are really saying is “consumer, Internet, online education in the Western world is ready for disruption. Everyone is online now and everyone gets an education, so clearly there are massive businesses to be built.” They probably aren’t talking about education in Asia because the companies in that space are started on the ground in Asia. They most likely aren’t selling to schools, districts, the government, or universities. VCs usually don’t like to invest in businesses that sell to the government until those businesses are big (at which point it’s really a private equity deal, not a venture capital deal). Angels will invest in education companies because they’re more motivated by making a difference, not by making a big return in 5 years. For now, let’s focus on US and European online education targeted at consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The average person in a developed country does not think about education the way a well educated VC or entrepreneur thinks about education.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VCs and entrepreneurs tend to be well educated. &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Well educated people think about education as an investment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; You put as many of your resources in to an investment as you can. It may take 20 years to pay off, but if the return-on-investment is high (which it is for education) then you invest. This group of people — if you’re reading this, you fall into this group — generally understand that education is an investment, and as a result are price insensitive and will optimize for quality (a higher return on investment). &lt;strong&gt;For this group of people, quality is the primary driver of a purchasing decision, not cost.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;The average, middle class person thinks about education as an expenditure, not an investment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It’s something they have to do because it’s mandated and the lack of the highest quality education hasn’t negatively impacted their lives in a meaningful way. Step back for a second before you judge. Imagine it’s 2005, and you live in a small town in the middle of Ohio (where I grew up) and you don’t get a college degree. If you get a factory job and make $25k/year and your wife gets a factory job and makes $25k/year, you’re making $50k/year. But houses only cost $90,000 and food is affordable and you can get a loan for a car for $300/month. So you’re not doing terribly and the default state for your children is the same life. You can afford a house, food, have a car, and have weekends off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what has the lack of an education done to the typical American’s life? It’s removed job security, screwed your retirement, and maybe set you up to go bankrupt if you get sick. &lt;strong&gt;There are no immediate consequences, there are no immediate consequences for your children, but there is an immediate cost. So the average person thinks of education as an expenditure. &lt;/strong&gt;If you get sick when you’re 70, you’re screwed. Or if you don’t save in your 401k, you may have to work till you’re dead. Or maybe your children won’t be as competitive in a global workforce 30 years. Don’t believe me? Only 15% of kids taking the SAT pay for an out of school test prep course like Kaplan. Over 50% of Americans don’t have beyond a high school degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fundamental investment vs. expenditure mindset changes everything. &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You think of education as fundamentally a quality problem. The average person thinks of education as fundamentally a cost problem.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educational companies that focus on delivering higher quality solutions to consumers will not scale to the mainstream. Educational companies built around driving down costs to the end consumer will scale. &lt;/strong&gt;Or a corollary, &lt;strong&gt;an enterprise sales or government sales company that taps into government revenue streams will scale but will not have a consumer Internet growth curve.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some data from the marketplace:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chegg&lt;/em&gt; – A company that is in education and sells to consumers. A $1 billion valuation and growing quickly. But, Chegg sells you the same textbook experience for much cheaper. It’s a great consumer focused business with offering real savings to students. Note that even in 2011, the “Netflix of education” is booming because of the equivalent of its DVD (physical textbook) business. Digital, personalized learning online or tablet based, interactive, social textbooks aren’t anywhere to be found.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;University of Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; – $6 billion market cap. They make it easier to get a degree because it’s convenient and subsidized by government backed loans. Consumers make the decision but ultimately the government is footing the bill. They aren’t a consumer company and they are a marketing machine. They are a company that makes it easy to get the same quality diploma that you would get at the local college. They don’t compete with Harvard, they compete with the local university that costs more and only has on campus night courses. They weren’t an overnight success either; UofP was started in 1976 and they IPO-ed in 1994.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kaplan&lt;/em&gt; – they didn’t get huge because of their test prep business, which is a consumer business and (arguably) delivers educational value. They became huge because they started following the University of Phoenix model for Kaplan University. Again, the primary value they offer is not quality of education, but convenience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;K12&lt;/em&gt; – they are not a consumer, online education company. They sell to school districts and their model revolves around being able to drive down costs for school districts in their high cost students — special needs, gifted, rural, etc. They have built an interesting consumer business overseas — in the Middle East and Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;Here are a few examples of companies that tried to do consumer Internet style education plays and how it worked for them:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;TutorVista&lt;/em&gt; – started by offering online tutoring to Western students using tutors in India. All you can eat for $99/month or so. They burned millions on search engine marketing and were able to build a business that generated eight figure revenue — nice but not enough to IPO on. So they pivoted and opened education centers in India and were acquired for $213 million by Pearson. A $200+ million acquisition in India is unheard of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tutor.com&lt;/em&gt; – started a decade ago to offer online tutoring to the masses. Never went mainstream, even after 5 rounds of funding. They’ve built a niche business that survives through deals they’ve struck with various government bodies — libraries, schools, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;GlobalScholar&lt;/em&gt; – started by the CEO of Drugstore.com, tried initially to do a direct to consumer play. Realized it wasn’t working and bought an electronic gradebook company that works with schools and was sold to Scantron that has great distribution with schools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;There are dozens of examples of companies that have tried to build around quality and hit a revenue ceiling in the few millions. Think about the 10 local tutoring centers in your city that probably make $1 million each. This early traction is very misleading because you see engaged, happy, paying customers. So you assume that it will scale but it turns out that this business won’t scale because &lt;strong&gt;your early adopters behave fundamentally differently than the mass market&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, this section is a little hand wavy and full of generalizations. These are observational insights with some data points that show the generalizations are directionally accurate at the end. This is not a rigorous sociological study, so take the generalizations for what they’re worth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re living in most of Asia (South Asia included) and you don’t get an education, you’re screwed. Part of this is cultural (you have no social capital if you’re not well educated) and a lot of it is economic (if you don’t have an education, you will do menial labor and not have enough money to feed your children). Consider the difference between some random person in China vs. some random person in Kansas. If the Chinese person doesn’t get an education there’s a good chance they will not get a job. They will die poor, unable to adequately feed their children, and unable to take care of their parents (since the model is that the young take care of the older members of the family). But if they do get an education, they have a shot at a good life — call centers, banks, government jobs, the army, etc. And if it’s too late for that individual, they know that they can give a good life to their children. The non-college educated person in Kansas probably won’t have a great life and a secure retirement without an education. But they, their children, and their parents probably won’t die hungry and homeless on the streets of Topeka. This cultural mentality is carried over to many Asian Americans via immigration. This is not universally true, of course, of Asian Americans but there is no denying there is a strong correlation. So if you want to start a consumer education company in Asia, you can make it work and make it scale — MegaStudy and Kumon are two great examples. However, there are not enough Asian Americans to support the same scale of business in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being poor also changes how you think about education. Interestingly, in the US, the people who are most willing to try new things are the poor and uneducated because they have a similar incentive structure to a person in rural India. Their default state is “screwed.” If a poor person doesn’t do something dramatic, they are going to stay screwed. Many parents and teachers in these communities understand this. So the communities are often willing to try new, experimental things — online education, charter schools, longer school days, no summer vacation, co-op programs — even if they may not work. Why? Because their students’ default state is “screwed” and they need something dramatically better. Doing something significantly higher quality is the only way to overcome the inertia of already being screwed. The affordable, but poor quality approaches just aren’t good enough. These communities are on the hunt for dramatically better approaches and willing to try new things. Unfortunately the poor don’t have a lot of money to spend so servicing this community requires selling to the schools, which is an enterprise sales type of business — not a consumer business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider Kumon, which is worth almost $1 Billion. They started in Asia, they are essentially a franchise model that caters to well educated parents, and a key part of the value proposition is in giving students a place to go and be supervised (babysitting!). It’s a great business that serves 4.2 million students worldwide. Of this, about 200,000 are in the US. The overwhelming majority are in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not a perfect dataset but the Quantcast data for Khan Academy’s US demographics support this. The people going to the site are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the already well educated who value education and want supplemental resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poorer (which unfortunately correlates with being African American and Hispanic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://avichal.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-24-at-11-08-55-am.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Khan Academy Demographics&quot; src=&quot;https://avichal.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-24-at-11-08-55-am.png?w=632&amp;amp;h=246&quot; alt=&quot;Khan Academy Demographics&quot; width=&quot;632&quot; height=&quot;246&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly education is billions (trillions!) of dollars. There are lots of opportunities, especially if you take a long term view of it and want to build something meaningful for the next 25 years. However, don’t make the following mistakes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don’t believe that building a better product will make you successful. Delivering something for cheaper will. Even if that cheaper thing is lower quality. This is usually repugnant to most well-educated entrepreneurs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t start in developed, western countries because that’s where large, Internet businesses have been built. Asia is a much better education market if you want to target consumers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t take VC funding because the growth curve in your education business will not live up to VC expectations early on. Take angel money from people who want to make a difference in education. Then take private equity money once you’ve figured out how to get to $10 million in revenue on your own. Even better, don’t take any PE money and grow it on cash flows. Successful education businesses are often not capital constrained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t target suburban or urban, middle class users with disposable income. You’ll build a niche business that can’t go mainstream. Target poor students in the US and get to charter schools who are desperate to try new things. Target families in China and India where a family will put down half of their monthly income on education. Or target people who really value education and will pay 10x more for something that is higher quality. That’s where there are big businesses to be built and a willingness for new solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t expect a quick flip or quick growth. Building a large, successful education company will take 20 years. The growth curve will not be like an Internet technology company until you hit $10+ million in revenue. Then things will ramp  quickly because you will have identified your core market and built the beginnings of a brand; the education industry is small and people will know if you deliver real value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 01:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ALee</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why Education Startups Do Not Succeed</og:title>
<og:url>https://avichal.com/2011/10/07/why-education-startups-do-not-succeed/</og:url>
<og:description> I co-founded PrepMe in 2001. We were one of the first education companies online and the first purely online, personalized platform. We were acquired in 2011 by Providence Equity-backed Ascend Lea…</og:description>
<og:image>https://avichal.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-24-at-11-08-55-am.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://avichal.com/2011/10/07/why-education-startups-do-not-succeed/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Orleans man locked up nearly 8 years awaiting trial, then case gets tossed</title>
<link>http://www.theadvocate.com/new_orleans/news/courts/article_d76e9496-c995-11e7-bd8b-4bb8d14cacbf.html?utm_content=buffera1a9c&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.theadvocate.com/new_orleans/news/courts/article_d76e9496-c995-11e7-bd8b-4bb8d14cacbf.html?utm_content=buffera1a9c&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;ndn-container p402_hide&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ndn-container p402_hide&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Kevin Smith was jailed on a drug charge in New Orleans in 2010, Blockbuster was still renting DVDs and President Barack Obama was still trying to pass his signature health care bill.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith’s case never went to a jury. On Monday, 2,832 days after he was locked up, Criminal District Court Judge Tracey Flemings-Davillier ordered Smith’s release, bowing to an appeals court ruling that prosecutors had violated his right to a speedy trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her decision represents an extreme example of how slowly the wheels of justice can grind in Orleans Parish while defendants sit in jail. All sides involved in the complicated saga point fingers at each other for the delays. No one can guarantee it won’t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Smith, 51, who is supposed to go free within a few days, has served more time in custody than any other New Orleans inmate awaiting trial for a nonviolent crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you’ve been in jail for right at eight years on the same charge and it won’t go to trial, that’s injustice,” said Smith’s cousin, Michael Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A review of court records shows that Kevin Smith’s day in court was delayed by a hurricane, questions about his mental competency and requests from lawyers on both sides. His court dockets span 161 entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The delays astounded Rafael Goyeneche, president of the Metropolitan Crime Commission, which frequently criticizes the winding road to trials at Criminal District Court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think it’s an embarrassment to the criminal justice system,” Goyeneche said of the Smith case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline-asset inline-article subscriber-hide tnt-inline-asset tnt-inline-relcontent tnt-inline-article tnt-inline-relation-sibling tnt-inline-presentation-summary tnt-inline-alignment-default tnt-inline-width-default&quot;&gt;
&lt;article id=&quot;card-summary-af158b76-c7a7-11e6-8c8d-231bdfe35a9c&quot; class=&quot;clearfix card summary has-image image-top card-section-new-orleans-news-courts&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;card-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card-image card-image-top&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;media-preview-af158b76-c7a7-11e6-8c8d-231bdfe35a9c media-preview article-asset&quot; data-aspect=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;

&lt;div itemprop=&quot;image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAEAAAABCAQAAAC1HAwCAAAAC0lEQVR42mM8Uw8AAh0BTZud3BwAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&quot; alt=&quot;Photos: New Orleans residents and officers remember fallen NOPD officer Daryle Holloway _lowres (copy)&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive lazyload full&quot; width=&quot;990&quot; height=&quot;823&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/9/87/987cf548-c874-11e6-8ea7-dff4a9f38db3/5751a3efbb742.image.jpg?resize=200%2C166 200w, https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/9/87/987cf548-c874-11e6-8ea7-dff4a9f38db3/5751a3efbb742.image.jpg?resize=300%2C249 300w, https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/9/87/987cf548-c874-11e6-8ea7-dff4a9f38db3/5751a3efbb742.image.jpg?resize=400%2C333 400w, https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/9/87/987cf548-c874-11e6-8ea7-dff4a9f38db3/5751a3efbb742.image.jpg?resize=540%2C449 540w, https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/9/87/987cf548-c874-11e6-8ea7-dff4a9f38db3/5751a3efbb742.image.jpg?resize=750%2C623 750w, https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/9/87/987cf548-c874-11e6-8ea7-dff4a9f38db3/5751a3efbb742.image.jpg 1200w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;card-lead&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Will Smith murder case was far from the only one scheduled for trial on the morning of Dec. 5, when 130 potential jurors crammed into the …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith’s saga behind bars began on Feb. 11, 2010, when State Police and federal drug agents said they discovered baggies of crack cocaine inside a safe in his Carrollton residence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a parolee with a previous drug charge to his name, Smith was looking at a sentence of 20 years to life if convicted as a habitual offender, according to one of his lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It wouldn’t have just been 'Time served, go about your day,' ” said defense attorney Christen DeNicholas, who has had a role in the case since this spring. &quot;It would have been a very big deal for him.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parole issue also prevented Smith's pretrial release on a $50,000 bail, DeNicholas said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith’s trial on a single charge of felony possession with intent to distribute crack cocaine was set for Aug. 9, 2011. The state halted the trial after seven jurors were picked. Prosecutors said they had just discovered new information against Smith that should have been handed over to his defense team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The District Attorney’s Office dismissed the original charge against Smith and brought a new one the next day, restarting the statutory two-year deadline to try the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith’s next time before a jury was set for Aug. 29, 2012. Hurricane Isaac hit the Louisiana coastline on Aug. 28 and shuttered the New Orleans courthouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Court was closed for only a few days. However, prosecutors claimed their two-year deadline to bring Smith to trial was again reset under a state law passed after Hurricane Katrina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 2012, the case — which had been assigned to Judge Robin Pittman — was transferred to a different section of court. But for reasons that remain unclear, it did not land on the desk of newly elected Judge Flemings-Davillier until May 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next three years, Smith considered and rejected a 10-year plea deal offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He could have come home as early as January of 2015,” said defense attorney Martin Regan, whose firm handled the case from the start. “There’s a man who just steadfastly said, 'I don’t care, you can keep me. I’m not guilty, I want a trial.' ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith's mental competency was examined at Regan's request in 2014 and he was found sane. He filed a motion on his own behalf to go to trial, but his attorneys ultimately told the court they weren't ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case stumbled forward again and again. Lawyers on both sides asked the judge for delays. Finally, in December 2016, Smith filed another motion on his own behalf seeking to quash his charges. He argued that his constitutional right to a speedy trial had been denied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, Smith’s lawyers took his side. At a March 22 hearing, DeNicholas asked the judge to dismiss the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flemings-Davillier ruled the next month that Hurricane Isaac and Smith’s mental competency hearing had justifiably pushed his deadline for trial back by four years. She denied the motion to quash the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith's lawyers took the case to the 4th Circuit Court of Appeal. In a June ruling, a three-judge panel ruled in Smith's favor and said he should go free. The court found that Flemings-Davillier was wrong in adopting prosecutors’ argument that the sanity hearing rolled back the deadline for trial by another two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prosecutors appealed the decision, but the Louisiana Supreme Court declined to hear the case last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, Smith ran into another roadblock: Flemings-Davillier said she would allow prosecutors to argue again that Smith should remain in jail. But after a Monday meeting in her chambers, prosecutors dropped their opposition to quashing the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At the end of the day, all those continuances that may not seem like a big deal at the time, they do add up. In Kevin Smith’s case, they added up to eight years,” DeNicholas said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;inline-asset inline-article subscriber-hide tnt-inline-asset tnt-inline-relcontent tnt-inline-article tnt-inline-relation-sibling tnt-inline-presentation-summary tnt-inline-alignment-default tnt-inline-width-default&quot;&gt;
&lt;article id=&quot;card-summary-46fa0848-d6c3-11e6-8523-13e5bad0389b&quot; class=&quot;clearfix card summary has-image image-top card-section-new-orleans-news-courts&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;card-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card-image card-image-top&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;media-preview-46fa0848-d6c3-11e6-8523-13e5bad0389b media-preview article-asset&quot; data-aspect=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theadvocate.com/new_orleans/news/courts/article_46fa0848-d6c3-11e6-8523-13e5bad0389b.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAEAAAABCAQAAAC1HAwCAAAAC0lEQVR42mM8Uw8AAh0BTZud3BwAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&quot; alt=&quot;New Orleans judge orders release of seven inmates charged with serious felonies because of lack of money for defense, but men will remain jailed pending an appeal _lowres&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive lazyload full&quot; width=&quot;990&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/c/87/c87a9b38-79ce-51e5-82ac-2b1c5c76ea74/5751c14a9bf58.image.jpg?resize=200%2C137 200w, https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/c/87/c87a9b38-79ce-51e5-82ac-2b1c5c76ea74/5751c14a9bf58.image.jpg?resize=300%2C205 300w, https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/c/87/c87a9b38-79ce-51e5-82ac-2b1c5c76ea74/5751c14a9bf58.image.jpg?resize=400%2C274 400w, https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/c/87/c87a9b38-79ce-51e5-82ac-2b1c5c76ea74/5751c14a9bf58.image.jpg?resize=540%2C369 540w, https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/c/87/c87a9b38-79ce-51e5-82ac-2b1c5c76ea74/5751c14a9bf58.image.jpg?resize=750%2C513 750w, https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/c/87/c87a9b38-79ce-51e5-82ac-2b1c5c76ea74/5751c14a9bf58.image.jpg 1200w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;card-lead&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dozen judges of Orleans Parish Criminal District Court saw their dockets increasingly laden with violent felony cases in 2015, resulting i…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goyeneche said there was plenty of blame to go around for a straightforward drug case that should have been tried quickly. Still, he believes the judge could have brought it to its conclusion sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a report issued earlier this year, his organization ranked Flemings-Davillier in a tie for last place for “judicial efficiency” at the New Orleans criminal courthouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The reason that there’s a judge involved is the judge puts the foot down and decides that one of the parties, one of the sides is being dilatory in weighing the rights of the state versus the suspect,” Goyeneche said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flemings-Davillier, who inherited a massive backlog of cases when she became a judge in 2013, has pointed to numbers that show she closes more cases than any other judge. She said she worked diligently to protect Smith’s rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There were a number of constitutional issues and procedural issues that we were dealing with,” she said. “We have to ensure that the defendant gets his due process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said the case was complicated by the many motions Smith filed on his own behalf along the way and by his shifting attorneys. Four separate lawyers from Regan’s firm represented him along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The judge said everything from the hurricane to Smith’s own motions to the sanity questions conspired to extend the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m not going to say it can’t happen again, but this one had so many factors,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others cast blame along a predictable dividing line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;District Attorney Leon Cannizzaro said he was satisfied with the judge’s decision in April that his office’s two-year deadline for prosecution had not passed. Still, he said it was “absolutely ridiculous for a narcotics case to last seven years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How do I feel about it? Why didn’t the case go to trial? Well, because the defendant did a masterful job of continuing the case over and over again,” Cannizzaro said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His assertion prompted an angry response from Regan. He said the 4th Circuit found that prosecutors blew their deadline to try the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They knew they could not convict him, so the matter drug on and on and on,” Regan said. “Mr. Cannizzaro, do not blame the defense for this.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;ndn-container p402_hide&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbcgerard</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.theadvocate.com/new_orleans/news/courts/article_d76e9496-c995-11e7-bd8b-4bb8d14cacbf.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/theadvocate.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/9/df/9df40ffe-ddb7-11e6-9fdc-43d911e77774/575209f2acec6.image.jpg?resize=976%2C630</og:image>
<og:title>New Orleans man locked up nearly 8 years awaiting trial, then drug case gets tossed</og:title>
<og:description>When Kevin Smith was jailed on a drug charge in New Orleans in 2010, Blockbuster was still renting DVDs and President Barack Obama was still trying to pass his signature</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.theadvocate.com/new_orleans/news/courts/article_d76e9496-c995-11e7-bd8b-4bb8d14cacbf.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New EU law prescribes website blocking in the name of consumer protection</title>
<link>https://juliareda.eu/2017/11/eu-website-blocking/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://juliareda.eu/2017/11/eu-website-blocking/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, the European Parliament passed the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/commissions/imco/inag/2017/07-11/IMCO_AG(2017)608048_EN.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Consumer Protection Cooperation&lt;/em&gt; regulation&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, it contains an overreaching &lt;strong&gt;general website blocking&lt;/strong&gt; provision. Additionally, consumer protection improvements were watered down or removed completely in last-minute &lt;acronym class=&quot;c2c-text-hover&quot; title=&quot;Informal meetings attended by representatives of the European Parliament, the Council and the Commission&quot;&gt;trilogue&lt;/acronym&gt; negotiations with the Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-8272 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/422077568_eb1e6f8cf3_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1184&quot; height=&quot;610&quot; srcset=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/422077568_eb1e6f8cf3_o.jpg 1184w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/422077568_eb1e6f8cf3_o-300x155.jpg 300w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/422077568_eb1e6f8cf3_o-768x396.jpg 768w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/422077568_eb1e6f8cf3_o-1024x528.jpg 1024w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/422077568_eb1e6f8cf3_o-600x309.jpg 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1184px) 100vw, 1184px&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;cc-by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/dotsandspaces/422077568/&quot;&gt;Stephan Caspar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the new rules, national consumer protection authorities can &lt;strong&gt;order any unspecified third party to block access to websites&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;without requiring judicial authorisation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This forces internet access providers to create a &lt;strong&gt;website blocking infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;, which risks being abused later on for any number of other purposes, including censorship. To give a recent example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.internetsociety.org/news/statements/2017/internet-society-statement-internet-blocking-measures-catalonia-spain/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;independence-related websites were blocked in Catalunya&lt;/a&gt; just weeks ago. These actions could only be taken so quickly because website blocking infrastructure had previously been put in place for other purposes, such as barring access to sites involving copyright infringement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The version of this rule that was now adopted was &lt;strong&gt;proposed by the member state governments&lt;/strong&gt; in the Council, who pushed to go even further than the Commission had originally proposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Parliament was finding its position on the issue in March 2017, I successfully proposed that the last resort measure must be &lt;em&gt;removing&lt;/em&gt; content that infringes on consumer protection laws, not blocking access to websites, and that fundamental rights must be safeguarded by requiring prior judicial authorisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tragically, the Parliament’s negotiator, MEP Olga Sehnalová from the Czech Social Democrats (&lt;acronym class=&quot;c2c-text-hover&quot; title=&quot;Socialists and Democrats&quot;&gt;S&amp;amp;D&lt;/acronym&gt; group), agreed to a compromise that adopted the Council’s proposal on website blocking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compromise also watered down other consumer protection measures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;bullet&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consumer compensation made voluntary: &lt;/strong&gt;The original proposal would have given consumer protection authorities the power to order traders to compensate consumers that have been harmed. The trilogue outcome essentially makes such compensation voluntary by subjecting it to ”the trader’s initiative”. The Dieselgate scandal, where US consumers were compensated and European consumers were not, has shown how important it would have been to give consumer protection authorities the power to order compensation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No restitution of profits:&lt;/strong&gt; Under the original proposal, consumer protection authorities would have received the power to restitute illicit profits, obtained as a result of infringements of consumer protection laws. These could have contributed to the scandalous underfunding of consumer protection bodies. The trilogue outcome deletes this without substitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I filed last-minute amendments to try to fix these issues in today’s plenary vote – but unfortunately, they were voted down. As a result, the &lt;acronym class=&quot;c2c-text-hover&quot; title=&quot;Greens/European Free Alliance&quot;&gt;Greens/EFA&lt;/acronym&gt; group and I voted against the new law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_QxOnv9TICE?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; gesture=&quot;media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p prefix=&quot;dct: http://purl.org/dc/terms/ cc: http://creativecommons.org/ns#&quot; class=&quot;cc-block&quot;&gt;To the extent possible under law, the creator has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;mashsb-container mashsb-main&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;mashsb-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mashsb-count&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;670&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;mashsb-sharetext&quot;&gt;SHARES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/aside&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 21:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cameronhowe</dc:creator>
<og:title>New EU law prescribes website blocking in the name of “consumer protection”</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://juliareda.eu/2017/11/eu-website-blocking/</og:url>
<og:description></og:description>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://juliareda.eu/2017/11/eu-website-blocking/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Numpy: Plan for dropping Python 2.7 support</title>
<link>https://github.com/numpy/numpy/blob/master/doc/neps/dropping-python2.7-proposal.rst</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/numpy/numpy/blob/master/doc/neps/dropping-python2.7-proposal.rst</guid>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;The Python core team plans to stop supporting Python 2 in 2020. The NumPy project has supported both Python 2 and Python 3 in parallel since 2010, and has found that supporting Python 2 is an increasing burden on our limited resources; thus, we plan to eventually drop Python 2 support as well. Now that we're entering the final years of community-supported Python 2, the NumPy project wants to clarify our plans, with the goal of to helping our downstream ecosystem make plans and accomplish the transition with as little disruption as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our current plan is as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until &lt;strong&gt;December 31, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;, all NumPy releases will fully support both Python2 and Python3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting on &lt;strong&gt;January 1, 2019&lt;/strong&gt;, any new feature releases will support only Python3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last Python2 supporting release will be designated as a long term support (LTS) release, meaning that we will continue to merge bug fixes and make bug fix releases for a longer period than usual. Specifically, it will be supported by the community until &lt;strong&gt;December 31, 2019&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;January 1, 2020&lt;/strong&gt; we will raise a toast to Python2, and community support for the last Python2 supporting release will come to an end. However, it will continue to be available on PyPI indefinitely, and if any commercial vendors wish to extend the LTS support past this point then we are open to letting them use the LTS branch in the official NumPy repository to coordinate that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a NumPy user who requires ongoing Python2 support in 2020 or later, then please contact your vendor. If you are a vendor who wishes to continue to support NumPy on Python2 in 2020+, please get in touch; ideally we'd like you to get involved in maintaining the LTS before it actually hits end of life so that we can make a clean handoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To minimize disruption, running &lt;code&gt;pip install numpy&lt;/code&gt; on Python 2 will continue to give the last working release in perpetuity, but after January 1, 2019 it may not contain the latest features, and after January 1, 2020 it may not contain the latest bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the scientific Python ecosystem's transition to Python3 only, see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python3statement.org/&quot;&gt;python3-statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on porting your code to run on Python 3, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/howto/pyporting.html&quot;&gt;python3-howto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 21:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AndrewDucker</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/288276?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>numpy/numpy</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/numpy/numpy</og:url>
<og:description>numpy - Numpy main repository</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/numpy/numpy/blob/master/doc/neps/dropping-python2.7-proposal.rst</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>All 500 of the world&amp;#039;s top 500 supercomputers are running Linux</title>
<link>http://www.zdnet.com/article/linux-totally-dominates-supercomputers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.zdnet.com/article/linux-totally-dominates-supercomputers/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Video: US to invest $258M in supercomputer race with China&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Linux rules supercomputing. This day has been coming since 1998, when Linux first appeared on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.top500.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TOP500 Supercomputer list&lt;/a&gt;. Today it finally happened: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.top500.org/statistics/sublist/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;All 500 of the world's fastest supercomputers are running Linux&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last two non-Linux systems, a pair of Chinese IBM POWER computers running AIX, dropped off the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.top500.org/news/china-pulls-ahead-of-us-in-latest-top500-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;November 2017 TOP500 Supercomputer list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/article/now-china-outguns-us-in-top-supercomputer-showdown/&quot;&gt;China now leads the supercomputing race with 202 computers to the US' 144&lt;/a&gt;. China also leads the US in aggregate performance. China's supercomputers represent 35.4 percent of the Top500's flops, while the US trails with 29.6 percent. With an anti-science regime in charge of the government, America will only continue to see its technological lead decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the &lt;a href=&quot;http://top500.org/project/introduction&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;first Top500 supercomputer list was compiled in June 1993&lt;/a&gt;, Linux was barely more than a toy. It hadn't even adopted Tux as its mascot yet. It didn't take long for Linux to start its march on supercomputing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1993/1994, at NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center, Donald Becker and Thomas Sterling designed a Commodity Off The Shelf (COTS) supercomputer: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beowulf.org/overview/faq.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Beowulf&lt;/a&gt;. Since they couldn't afford a traditional supercomputer, they built a cluster computer made up of 16 Intel 486 DX4 processors, which were connected by channel bonded Ethernet. This &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beowulf.org/overview/history.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Beowulf supercomputer&lt;/a&gt; was an instant success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this day, the Beowulf design remains a popular, inexpensive way of designing supercomputers. Indeed, in the latest Top500 list, 437 of the world's fastest computers are using cluster designs that owe a debt of gratitude to Beowulf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux first appeared on the Top500 in 1998. Before Linux took the lead, Unix was supercomputing's top operating system. Since 2003, the Top500 was on its way to Linux domination. By 2004, Linux had taken the lead for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;sharethrough-top&quot; data-component=&quot;medusaContentRecommendation&quot; data-medusa-content-recommendation-options=&quot;{&amp;quot;promo&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;promo_ZD_recommendation_sharethrough_top_in_article_desktop&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;spot&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;dfp-in-article&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Linux [became] the driving force behind the breakthroughs in computing power that have fueled research and technological innovation,&quot; as reported by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/publications/20-years-top500org-supercomputer-data-links-linux-advances-computing-performance&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; In other words, Linux is dominant in supercomputing, at least in part, because it is helping researchers push the limits on computing power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened for two reasons: First, because most of the world's top supercomputers are research machines built for specialized tasks, each machine is a standalone project with unique characteristics and optimization requirements. To save costs, no one wants to develop a custom operating system for each of these systems. With Linux, however, research teams can easily modify and optimize Linux's open-source code to their one-off designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/article/the-new-long-term-linux-kernel-linux-4-14-has-arrived/&quot;&gt;Linux 4.14&lt;/a&gt; enables supercomputers to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git/commit/?id=bffc33ec539699f045a9254144de3d4eace05f07&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Heterogeneous Memory Management (HMM)&lt;/a&gt;. This enables GPUs and CPUs to access a process's shared address space. Exactly 102 of the Top500 are using now using GPU accelerator/co-processor technology. All of these will perform better, thanks to HMM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, just as importantly, as the Linux Foundation pointed out, &quot;The licensing cost of a custom, self-supported Linux distribution is the same, whether you're using 20 nodes or 20-million nodes.&quot; Thus, &quot;by tapping into the vast open-source Linux community, projects had access to free support and developer resources to help keep developer costs on par with, or below other operating systems.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that Linux has reached the apex of supercomputing, I can't imagine it losing its leadership. It will take a hardware revolution, such as quantum computing, to shake Linux's supercomputing grip. Of course, Linux may still reign since &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxplumbersconf.org/2017/ocw//system/presentations/4704/original/QC-slides.2017.09.13f.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IBM developers are already working on porting Linux to quantum computers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related stories:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 21:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.zdnet.com/article/linux-totally-dominates-supercomputers/</og:url>
<og:title>​Linux totally dominates supercomputers | ZDNet</og:title>
<og:description>It finally happened. Today, all 500 of the world's top 500 supercomputers are running Linux.</og:description>
<og:image>https://zdnet4.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/r/2016/11/14/4e1db350-0eff-4348-b439-6cc4516911b2/thumbnail/770x578/adf35b579e931d34635dc618586ba1df/sunway-supercomputer.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.zdnet.com/article/linux-totally-dominates-supercomputers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Schneier: It&amp;#039;s Time to Regulate IoT to Improve Cyber-Security</title>
<link>http://www.eweek.com/security/schneier-it-s-time-to-regulate-iot-to-improve-cyber-security</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.eweek.com/security/schneier-it-s-time-to-regulate-iot-to-improve-cyber-security</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;6.1666666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new Account&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complete your registration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-7 col-sm-7 col-xs-7 text-right no-qs-cookie&quot;&gt;Already have an Account? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eweek.com/security/schneier-it-s-time-to-regulate-iot-to-improve-cyber-security#&quot; onclick=&quot;closeDialog('#registerLightDialog','formRegisterLight','#registrationLightMessage');showDialog('#loginDialog');return false;&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You're currently subscribed to some eWEEK features and just need to create a username and password.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;gigyaRegisterLightLoginDiv&quot; class=&quot;gigya-login-wrapper no-qs-cookie&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;formHeader&quot;&gt;Or register using your social account ...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loading Social Login...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 21:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pwg</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.eweek.com/security/schneier-it-s-time-to-regulate-iot-to-improve-cyber-security</og:url>
<og:title>Schneier: It's Time to Regulate IoT to Improve Cyber-Security</og:title>
<og:description>At the SecTor security conference in Toronto, Bruce Schneier makes a case for more regulatory oversight for software and the Internet of Things</og:description>
<og:image>/imagesvr_ez/b2bezp/2017/11/Bruce-SecTor-1088x725.jpg?alias=social_image</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.eweek.com/security/schneier-it-s-time-to-regulate-iot-to-improve-cyber-security</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Fight to Mine Your Data and Sell It to Your Boss</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-11-15/the-brutal-fight-to-mine-your-data-and-sell-it-to-your-boss</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-11-15/the-brutal-fight-to-mine-your-data-and-sell-it-to-your-boss</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;On May 23, an email landed in the sales inbox of a San Francisco startup called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/1383039D:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;HiQ Labs&lt;/a&gt;, politely asking the company to go out of business. HiQ is a “people analytics” firm that creates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hiqlabs.com/new-index&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Solutions — hiQ Labs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;software tools&lt;/a&gt; for corporate human resources departments. Its Skill Mapper graphically represents the credentials and abilities of a workforce; its Keeper service identifies when employees are at risk of leaving for another job. Both draw the overwhelming majority of their data from a single trove: the material that is posted—with varying degrees of timeliness, detail, accuracy, and self-awareness—by the 500 million people on the social networking site &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;LinkedIn: Log In or Sign Up&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The email HiQ received was from LinkedIn Senior Litigation Counsel Abhishek Bajoria. “It has come to LinkedIn’s attention that hiQ Labs, Inc. has used and is using processes to improperly, and without authorization, access and copy data from LinkedIn’s website” in violation of LinkedIn’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/legal/user-agreement&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;User Agreement | LinkedIn&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;user agreement&lt;/a&gt;, it read. Bajoria called on HiQ to cease and desist from visiting LinkedIn’s site and to destroy the data it had culled. The email set off a feud that led, a month later, to the two companies meeting in federal court, with HiQ suing LinkedIn and LinkedIn accusing HiQ of violating state and federal law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small number of the world’s most valuable companies collect, control, parse, and sell billions of dollars’ worth of personal information voluntarily surrendered by their users. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/GOOG:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/FB:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/AMZN:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/MSFT:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;—which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-06-13/microsoft-to-buy-linkedin-in-deal-valued-at-26-2-billion-ipe079k9&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Microsoft Pays $26 Billion for LinkedIn in Biggest Deal Yet&quot;&gt;bought LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; for $26.2 billion in 2016—have in turn spawned dependent economies consisting of advertising and marketing companies, designers, consultants, and app developers. Some operate on the tech giants’ platforms; some customize special digital tools; some help people attract more friends and likes and followers. Some, including HiQ, feed off the torrents of information that social networks produce, using software bots to scrape data from profiles. The services of the smaller companies can augment the offerings of the bigger ones, but the power dynamic is deeply asymmetrical, reminiscent of pilot fish picking food from between the teeth of sharks.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The terms of that relationship are set by technology, economics, and the vagaries of consumer choice, but also by the law. LinkedIn’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://static.reuters.com/resources/media/editorial/20170620/hiqvlinkedin--ceaseanddesist.pdf&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;EXHIBIT J (.pdf)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;May 23 letter to HiQ&lt;/a&gt; wasn’t the first time the company had taken legal action to prevent the perceived hijacking of its data, and Facebook Inc. and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/371007Z:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Craigslist Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, among others, have brought &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfgate.com/business/article/Craigslist-sues-Instamotor-for-allegedly-11107880.php&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Craigslist sues Instamotor for allegedly re-posting car ads&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;similar actions&lt;/a&gt;. But even more than its predecessors, this case, because of who’s involved and how it’s unfolded, has spoken to the thorniest issues surrounding speech and competition on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The courtroom clash in July drew some of the biggest names in the American litigation bar and split some of the web’s high-profile civil liberties watchdog organizations, with the Electronic Frontier Foundation coming out in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/08/judge-cracks-down-linkedins-shameful-abuse-computer-break-law&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Judge Cracks Down on LinkedIn’s Shameful Abuse of Computer Break-In Law&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;support of HiQ&lt;/a&gt; and the Electronic Privacy Information Center writing an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epic.org/amicus/cfaa/linkedin/hiQ-v-LinkedIn-EPIC-Amicus-Brief.pdf&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Brief of Amicus Curiae Electronic Privacy Information Center (EPIC) in Support of Neither Party Urging Reversal (.pdf)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;amicus brief for LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;. Depending on whom you talk to, the sides are arguing about free speech or privacy, the scourge of data scraping or the danger of digital monopolies. The outcome will determine who gets to control the wealth of information about ourselves that, often unwittingly, we’ve put at the disposal of anyone with a professional curiosity and an internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;“People analytics” is a new term, but the concept is as old as the office job. Psychology had barely been founded before its practitioners were identifying the traits of a good streetcar driver or telephone switchboard operator. In 1917 a group of prominent psychologists was asked to evaluate and sort the hundreds of thousands of young men being drafted into the U.S. Army to fight in Europe. The ensuing decades saw the American military and intelligence agencies become centers of research for psychological evaluation and aptitude testing; after World War II, many of their scientists were hired to head personnel research departments at AT&amp;amp;T, General Electric, General Motors, and other iconic corporations. There they subjected armies of salesmen, bankers, engineers, and middle managers to surveys and aptitude tests, simulations and role-playing games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;passage&quot;&gt;“Imagine you had the wherewithal to see that autonomous vehicle experts were migrating out of Google into Apple before it became public”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, in practice the selection and retention of talent remains more art than science—and often primitive art, at that. At most companies, HR isn’t where the most interesting thinking is happening. But that’s changing, as the data scientists who brought us Amazon recommendation engines, online ad auctions, and dating algorithms apply predictive analytics to how we think and act at work. The goal is to go beyond traditional but little-examined practices—for instance, the job interview (often &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.courant.com/opinion/op-ed/hc-op-wire-sunstein-hiring-interviews-not-helpful--20161104-story.html&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Hiring? Don't Bother With The Interview&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;useless&lt;/a&gt;) and the raise (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-09/we-care-less-about-what-we-re-paid-than-why&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;We Care Less About What We’re Paid Than Why&quot;&gt;not always the best way&lt;/a&gt; to retain talent)—to subtler metrics and methods. Big companies are growing more interested as the cost of replacing valued workers becomes clearer. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/CSGN:SW&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Credit Suisse Group&lt;/a&gt; recently estimated that reducing attrition by 1 percentage point saves the bank from $75 million to $100 million a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s where HiQ comes in. The company was the brainchild of Darren Kaplan, a former ad man who saw that sites such as monster.com, glassdoor.com, and, above all, LinkedIn had upended the balance of power between employers and employees. LinkedIn’s founding in 2002 had given workers a new platform for marketing themselves and made it easier for recruiters (not to mention business journalists) to find and woo them. Its economic model is built, in large part, on charging for special recruiter memberships—they run about $9,000 a year, and companies often buy more than one—that help with finding and contacting potential poaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaplan envisioned a technological defense against the forays of recruiters, an early warning system that would assist companies in identifying restless workers so their bosses could entice them to stay. (“Predictive attrition insights” is the term HiQ has come to use.) In January 2015, the company rolled out Keeper, in which variables such as “independence from employer brand,” “mobility history,” and “external footprint” are displayed on a color-coded dashboard and combined to calculate a worker’s “flight risk.” Skill Mapper was released earlier this year, not long after the company hired Mark Weidick as chief executive officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-320435543&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ivIA.8D6vcAo/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ivIA.8D6vcAo/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weidick, HiQ’s CEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Jared Soares for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An engineer and entrepreneur who’s worked at Cisco Systems Inc. and AT&amp;amp;T Inc., Weidick has the graying crew cut and earnest intensity of a high school debate team coach. “I can’t help keeping track of time,” he says apologetically, after our conversation strays from the presentation on the conference room screen beside us. He describes HiQ’s limited offerings as the first building blocks of a workforce analytics arsenal. Investors evaluating a prospective merger would pay good money, he argues, to know who’s likely to stay at a company and who might leave. “Imagine you had the wherewithal to see that autonomous vehicle experts were migrating out of Google into Apple before it became public,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cisco and other software companies already perform this sort of analysis when they’re scouting offices, surveying the talent landscape in candidate cities to see which is the best fit. HiQ’s pitch is that it can offer clients something comparable through data science backed by off-the-shelf software and tailored consulting. Reviews have been good. “My experience working with them has been fantastic,” says an HR executive at a HiQ customer with more than 20,000 employees. (Like other clients, he was leery of being quoted by name while the case was going on.) “They are really smart about the data and about presenting it so that it’s used to improve business and employee outcomes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weidick had been on the job for only three months when LinkedIn sent its cease-and-desist letter, and his first thought was that there had been a misunderstanding. Many of HiQ’s 26 employees came from LinkedIn, and one of the startup’s co-founders, Rob Desantis, had been an early LinkedIn investor and board member. LinkedIn staff regularly attended an annual people analytics conference HiQ hosted. Two weeks after receiving the letter, Weidick wrote a bewildered email to LinkedIn’s general counsel, likening himself to “a dolphin that got caught in the tuna net.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others at HiQ were less surprised. Even as LinkedIn employees mingled at HiQ’s conferences, its software engineers were implementing measures to block data scrapers, setting off a cat-and-mouse game with HiQ’s engineers. “LinkedIn had been aggressively complaining about what they considered unfair scraping practices for quite some time,” recalls Dan Miller, HiQ’s chief technology officer. “They went through a lot of trouble technically to make it difficult to collate that data. We obviously think they’re dead wrong to do that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, as far as LinkedIn was concerned, HiQ was the tuna. When the larger company’s lawyers made that clear to Weidick, he hired the law firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/531016L:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Farella Braun &amp;amp; Martel&lt;/a&gt;. Deepak Gupta, a partner there, thought the case might interest his former professor, Laurence Tribe. Tribe, who teaches at Harvard Law School, is a constitutional law luminary and a liberal icon for arguing Supreme Court cases that expanded First Amendment protections and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lawrence_v._Texas&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Lawrence v. Texas&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;sought to overturn&lt;/a&gt; state anti-sodomy laws. He has also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.masseygail.com/pdf/Tribe-Peabody_111(d)_Comments_(filed).pdf&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;COMMENTS OF LAURENCE H. TRIBE AND PEABODY ENERGY CORPORATION (.pdf)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;advocated&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/BTU:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Peabody Energy Corp.&lt;/a&gt; in its fight against greenhouse gas regulation, however, and his expansive definition of free speech has led him to &lt;a href=&quot;http://freestatefoundation.org/images/TWC_Net_Neutrality_Violates_the_First_Amendment_-Tribe_Goldstein.pdf&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Proposed “Net Neutrality” Mandates Could Be Counterproductive And Violate The First Amendment (.pdf)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;argue against net neutrality&lt;/a&gt; on behalf of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/TWX:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Time Warner Inc.&lt;/a&gt; He estimates that he receives 20 or 30 appeals for legal help a day. “I usually just shrug them off and say, ‘I’m busy,’ ” he says. Among other things, he’s writing a book, teaching a new law school course, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-01-23/lawsuit-over-trump-s-foreign-dealings-plows-uncharted-ground&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Trump’s Foreign Dealings Violate Constitution, Suit Claims&quot;&gt;suing President Trump for corruption&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tribe has a weakness for certain internet law questions, though. In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://epic.org/free_speech/tribe.html&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;The Constitution in Cyberspace: Law and Liberty Beyond the Electronic Frontier&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;seminal 1991 talk&lt;/a&gt;, he sought to delineate how the Constitution, written in the language of physical space and boundaries, should apply in the virtual reaches of cyberspace. What were the public squares and private rooms of the web? Who got to determine access? Should data be protected as speech? If so, how? Back then the internet was an exotic geek playground, but even though it’s now a global marketplace where trillions of dollars change hands, the courts have only begun to answer Tribe’s questions. When Gupta called, talking about a battle over control of social media data, Tribe says, “my constitutional nostrils flared.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 27 he took a seat next to Gupta and another Farella partner in a federal courtroom in San Francisco for the second hearing in the case. HiQ had &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/public/resources/documents/2017_0814_hiq_order.pdf&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;HIQ LABS, INC. v. LINKEDIN CORPORATION (.pdf)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;sued LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; for unfair business practices and violating the smaller company’s right to free speech under the state constitution, which has broader speech protections than the U.S. Constitution. The startup wasn’t seeking damages, only asking Judge Edward Chen to issue a preliminary injunction that would force LinkedIn to let HiQ use its data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-320435355&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iJZ9ogbZGdfE/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iJZ9ogbZGdfE/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrilli, representing LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Jared Soares for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguing LinkedIn’s case was Donald Verrilli, who served as solicitor general under President Obama, and others from the firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/31836Z:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Munger, Tolles &amp;amp; Olson&lt;/a&gt;. The demand LinkedIn had made in its cease-and-desist letter to HiQ rested largely on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/1030&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;18 U.S. Code § 1030 - Fraud and related activity in connection with computers | US Law | LII / Legal Information Institute&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Computer Fraud and Abuse Act&lt;/a&gt; (CFAA), which makes it a federal crime, with a potential punishment of 10 years in prison, to access a computer without authorization. The 1984 law has been amended multiple times, but its earliest version was meant to protect against a &lt;em&gt;WarGames&lt;/em&gt;-style hack of government mainframes. LinkedIn was contending that, although people who posted on the site owned their own data, that data was stored on LinkedIn servers, and HiQ was trespassing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HiQ’s data scraping not only violated LinkedIn’s user agreement, it also threatened the “privacy interest of LinkedIn’s members,” Verrilli told Judge Chen, “and the integrity of LinkedIn’s trust relationship with its members, which is essential to its business.” Keeper, Verrilli added, let companies snoop on LinkedIn members in ways they hadn’t signed up for and wouldn’t want: “It’s an anonymous surveillance of their behavior, to rat them out to their employers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gupta countered that Verrilli was mischaracterizing HiQ’s methods and products. LinkedIn members have the option to mark their profiles entirely private or entirely public, with gradations in between. HiQ made use only of the data LinkedIn members had indicated they wanted visible to everyone on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For LinkedIn, however, the key distinction wasn’t between public and private or visible and invisible, but between a person browsing a website and a bot brigade copying data at scale. LinkedIn’s lawyers offer an analogy in one of their briefs: The site is like “a massive job fair, held at a convention center and open to all comers.” Into this gathering HiQ sends a metaphorical swarm of interns wearing body cameras so it can track the movements of every attendee and sell the resulting information to their employers. “LinkedIn would be well within its rights,” Verrilli and his colleagues conclude, “to send a letter instructing HiQ and its camera-clad minions to stay out of its fair.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;passage&quot;&gt;“We can’t sit here today and police every possible business model that some entrepreneur in Silicon Valley might come up with”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Surveillance is a loaded word, one HiQ doesn’t like. But the pitch such companies make is that they can pick up faint signals in public data that would otherwise go unnoticed. Those signals can reveal things that weren’t actually intended to be public: the tastes and tendencies evinced by our web search patterns, the medical condition revealed by our buying history, our growing boredom with our job. Last year the American Civil Liberties Union discovered that an analytics company called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/0611063D:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Dataminr Inc.&lt;/a&gt; was allowing law enforcement and domestic intelligence analysts to use special keyword and location search tools to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/blog/privacy-technology/internet-privacy/twitter-cuts-fusion-spy-centers-access-social-media&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Twitter Cuts Off Fusion Spy Centers’ Access to Social Media Surveillance Tool&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;track people through Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, which partially owns the company. (Dataminr has since discontinued the practice.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data-scraping bots are only one of the technologies forcing us to rethink privacy protections. In 2012 the Supreme Court ruled in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.casebriefsummary.com/united-states-v-jones/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;United States v. Jones | Case Brief Summary&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;United States v. Jones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that when the police affixed a GPS tracking device to a car, they were invading the privacy of the driver, even though it would have been perfectly legal to gather the same information by following the car around. Verrilli, the solicitor general at the time, lost that case, but speaking by phone in early October, he praises the decision. “What the court said, and it’s directly applicable here, is ‘No, no. This is a difference in kind, not merely in degree,’ ” he says. “It’s a level of intrusion and a level of surveillance that you could not as a practical matter ever accomplish absent the use of this super-high-powered technology.” The expense and labor of old-fashioned surveillance imposed practical limits on its use, but just as today’s cops—provided they can get a warrant—need not physically tail someone to know where he spends his time, people analytics professionals need not rely on a battery of tests and role-playing games to get inside employees’ heads. The easier it gets to harvest and analyze information, the more actively that information has to be protected. That, Verrilli argues, is what LinkedIn is trying to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s LinkedIn, after all, not HiQ, that has the relationship with the members who have posted the information. “We’ve made promises in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Privacy Policy | LinkedIn&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;, and we have to work with regulators worldwide who hold us to our promises,” says Blake Lawit, LinkedIn’s vice president for legal. “We’re not under the radar, right? If we do something creepy with privacy, we’re going to hear about it from the FTC and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2012-02-09/can-irelands-regulators-stand-up-for-internet-privacy&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Can Ireland's Regulators Stand Up for Internet Privacy?&quot;&gt;Irish Data Protection Commissioner&lt;/a&gt; and et cetera.” In other words, LinkedIn might be big and know lots about us, but with great power comes regulatory scrutiny, and with that comes a kind of responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-320435494&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iQrs20A0xk.E/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iQrs20A0xk.E/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gupta, representing HiQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Jared Soares for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that argument is only somewhat reassuring, HiQ’s argument is effectively that we’re on our own, and that this is the price we pay for today’s internet. “There’s probably lots and lots of applications that might make someone feel a little queasy, right?” Gupta told Judge Chen. “But the thing is, we can’t sit here today and police every possible business model that some entrepreneur in Silicon Valley might come up with. It’s public information. It’s the marketplace of ideas. It’s the engine of our country’s growth.” The reason Google can put the entire internet at our fingertips is because, like HiQ, it scrapes public data. That includes LinkedIn pages, which is why they tend to be among the top results if you Google a noncelebrity (unlike HiQ, Google has LinkedIn’s explicit permission to collect data).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, even those who might prefer that someone act as the guardian of our data might not cast LinkedIn for the role. The company doesn’t have the size or sway of Facebook, but as a business networking site it has no real competition, and like Facebook its dominance is built on the wealth of data it controls. This summer, Bala Iyer, Mohan Subramaniam, and U. Srinivasa Rangan wrote an article in the &lt;em&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/em&gt; arguing that the rise of Facebook, Google, Amazon, and the like necessitated a &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2017/07/the-next-battle-in-antitrust-will-be-about-whether-one-company-knows-everything-about-you&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;The Next Battle in Antitrust Will Be About Whether One Company Knows Everything About You&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;rethinking of the idea of a monopoly&lt;/a&gt;. “Tomorrow’s monopolies won’t be able to be measured just by how much they sell us,” the authors wrote. “They’ll be based on how much they know about us and how much better they can predict our behavior than competitors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old considerations—Is pricing competitive? Does the consumer have alternatives?—haven’t gone away, but they’ve been augmented by new questions. Companies that control data capable of predicting their customers’ choices could, for example, figure out how to constrain those choices, making such dominance all the more durable. As HiQ’s lawyers were at pains to point out, LinkedIn itself is in the data-mining business and is thus a competitor to HiQ. The larger company offers a service called Update Me as part of its premium membership for recruiters. As its name suggests, the product alerts recruiters when particular people change their LinkedIn pages, mark a work anniversary, or do something else that might signal a recruitable moment. Keeper, by contrast, updates its risk profiles only monthly, not in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gupta made sure in court to carefully highlight the hypocrisy of a sentence from LinkedIn’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://business.linkedin.com/talent-solutions/blog/2015/04/linkedin-recruiter-tip-use-update-me-to-know-when-to-reach-out-to-prospects&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;LinkedIn Recruiter Tip: Use Update Me to Know When to Reach Out to Prospects&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;promotional pitch to recruiters&lt;/a&gt;: “And don’t worry—they don’t know you’re following them.” In his telling, LinkedIn wasn’t trying to prevent its members’ data from being mined and analyzed: it was just trying to muscle out a smaller competitor so it could have a new market to itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Like most legal disputes, the one between LinkedIn and HiQ is a battle of analogies, and near the end of the proceedings on July 27, Verrilli introduced one more. The information in your local library is public, but that doesn’t mean, he argued, “that you can break into the library with a crowbar at 2 in the morning because you’re seized with a desire to read &lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt;.” Libraries can impose reasonable limits on public information, and so, he said, can LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, Tribe rose to speak for the first time. When he was growing up, he recalled, library books had “a little tag inside that would tell you how often the book was taken out, and when.” Imagine, he went on, that someone wanted to collate that information to see what books were most popular. “For the government to make it a crime for me to make use of that information because they want to be the, perhaps, exclusive distributors of information about what’s popular to read would, of course, be unconstitutional.” That calculation didn’t change, Tribe argued, if it was a corporation rather than the government establishing the ban. “If LinkedIn has this power, so does Facebook, and the entire universe of cyberspace can be gobbled up by a small number of private owners,” he said. “That can’t be what the law of an open, democratic society with the First Amendment means.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-320435583&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i1qKHa1PDL4M/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i1qKHa1PDL4M/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tribe, representing HiQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Jared Soares for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Aug. 14, Judge Chen issued his &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.justia.com/cases/federal/district-courts/california/candce/3:2017cv03301/312704/63&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;ORDER by Judge Edward M for hiQ Labs, Inc. v. Linkedin Corporation :: Justia Dockets &amp;amp; Filings&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;ruling&lt;/a&gt;, and it was in favor of HiQ. He emphatically rejected LinkedIn’s interpretation of the CFAA, which would, he wrote, give a private company the power to choke off access to public data, with prohibitions “weaponized by the potential of criminal sanctions.” And although Chen was skeptical of some of Tribe’s broader First Amendment arguments, he thought HiQ had raised serious questions about antitrust violations. He arched a rhetorical eyebrow at how LinkedIn, purported guardian of its members’ secrets, enthusiastically marketed data-mining capabilities of its own “in a way that seems to afford little deference to the very privacy concerns it professes to be protecting in this case.” Chen also took the extraordinary step of enjoining LinkedIn from putting in place any measure, technological as well as legal, to prevent HiQ from accessing its site, and he ordered the company to remove any barriers already in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking a few weeks after the ruling, Lawit, LinkedIn’s vice president for legal, still seemed blindsided: “When did it happen that companies who have data are forced to provide all of it with no conditions to anyone who wants it?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At HiQ, the mood was predictably cheerier—“high-fives all around,” in Weidick’s description. Still, the costs of the litigation had been substantial. Precious startup capital had been spent on lawyers, and countless man-hours had been devoted to trying, unsuccessfully, to come up with a business model that wouldn’t depend on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn swiftly announced that it would take its case to the 9th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals, which, in the past, has been favorable to companies invoking the CFAA against data scrapers. The soonest the case would be heard by the appeals court is in early 2018, and a Supreme Court decision, should the case make it that far, wouldn’t come for a few years. That’s an eon for a tech startup: By then, HiQ might actually be the analytics powerhouse its CEO, Weidick, envisions, or it might be defunct and remembered only as a cautionary tale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The publicity around the case has led to more potential customers reaching out, Weidick says, but in recent months HiQ has also lost most of its employees, as more than a dozen data scientists, designers, and programmers, calculating the odds, have left for jobs at places not shadowed by an existential legal battle. That much attrition would be painful for any company, but it’s particularly galling for one in the attrition-insight business. “The irony is not lost on me,” Weidick says. “Not at all.”&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 19:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>artsandsci</dc:creator>
<og:description>Silicon Valley makes billions of dollars peddling personal information.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iUQ43VaRhhvY/v0/-999x-999.gif</og:image>
<og:title>The Brutal Fight to Mine Your Data and Sell It to Your Boss</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-11-15/the-brutal-fight-to-mine-your-data-and-sell-it-to-your-boss</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-11-15/the-brutal-fight-to-mine-your-data-and-sell-it-to-your-boss</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Code together in real time with Teletype for Atom</title>
<link>https://blog.atom.io/2017/11/15/code-together-in-real-time-with-teletype-for-atom.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.atom.io/2017/11/15/code-together-in-real-time-with-teletype-for-atom.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.atom.io/img/posts/teletype/original-teletype.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Old-school teletype&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing code with another programmer is a great way to absorb knowledge, challenge yourself with new perspectives, and ultimately write better software. It can also be a fulfilling way to get to know the mind of another human being. Unfortunately, the &lt;em&gt;logistics&lt;/em&gt; of writing code with another programmer can be such a hassle that many people don’t bother. Here are some of the common obstacles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sharing the same physical machine is impossible for remote teams, and can be challenging to organize even when teammates share the same office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud-based IDEs and remote &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt; sessions ask you to move your entire workflow into a hosted environment, which isn’t always possible or desirable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The connection latency of screen sharing can lead to an awkward dynamic where only one collaborator can comfortably edit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social coding shouldn’t have to be this hard! Today, we’re taking a first step toward making it just as easy to code together as it is to code alone with &lt;a href=&quot;https://teletype.atom.io&quot;&gt;Teletype for Atom&lt;/a&gt;. At the dawn of computing, teletypes were used to create a real-time circuit between two machines so that anything typed on one machine appeared at the other end immediately. Following in these electro-mechanical footsteps, Teletype for Atom wires the keystrokes of remote collaborators directly into your programming environment, enabling conflict-free, low-latency collaborative editing for any file you can open in Atom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.atom.io/img/posts/teletype/teletype.png&quot; alt=&quot;Atom Teletype&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started-with-teletype&quot;&gt;Getting started with Teletype&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you install Teletype via Atom’s settings view or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apm install teletype&lt;/code&gt; on the command line, you can open a “portal” into your local workspace from the new collaboration menu on the status bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.atom.io/img/posts/teletype/share.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Share your portal and copy its secret ID&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then just share your portal’s secret ID with collaborators via your preferred chat service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.atom.io/img/posts/teletype/invite.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Send the portal ID to a collaborator via a chat service&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborators can enter your portal by clicking “Join” in the collaboration menu and entering the portal ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.atom.io/img/posts/teletype/join.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Once someone has your portal ID, they can join&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After joining your portal, collaborators see a new tab in their workspace that lets them view and edit the contents of your active editor. Everyone gets their own cursor, and everyone can type at the same time, but since sharing is at the keystroke-level rather than the pixel-level, participants all keep their own custom key bindings, packages, and themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.atom.io/img/posts/teletype/code-together.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Everyone gets a cursor&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you share a portal, your code stays on your local disk. As you switch between files, the contents of your current active editor are transmitted to collaborators so they can follow along, but otherwise your workflow will be unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.atom.io/img/posts/teletype/follow.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Guests follow the host&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;implementation-details&quot;&gt;Implementation details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conflict-free-editing&quot;&gt;Conflict-free editing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborative editing is a tricky theoretical problem. To ensure responsive editing, each collaborator maintains their own replica of each document, applying local edits immediately before transmitting them to other collaborators. In the face of concurrency, edits end up being applied in a different order on each replica, but when the dust settles, all replicas need to have the same contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After several late nights reading research papers, we ended up deciding to base Teletype on the theoretical framework of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conflict-free_replicated_data_type&quot;&gt;conflict-free replicated data types&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;CRDTs&lt;/em&gt;. Basically, CRDTs are data structures that always converge on the same representation when updated with the same set of operations, even if those operations are applied in different orders. The CRDT for text editing we wrote for the heart of this system is available as a standalone library called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/atom/teletype-crdt&quot;&gt;teletype-crdt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;connecting-peers&quot;&gt;Connecting peers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To connect collaborators, we use &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/WebRTC_API&quot;&gt;WebRTC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/RTCDataChannel&quot;&gt;data channels&lt;/a&gt;. After an initial handshake that exchanges connection metadata via GitHub’s servers, all data flows over encrypted peer-to-peer connections. Our servers never see your files or edits, which maximizes your privacy and minimizes latency between you and your collaborators, regardless of your proximity to our data centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;editor-agnostic-client-library&quot;&gt;Editor-agnostic client library&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/atom/teletype&quot;&gt;Teletype Atom package&lt;/a&gt; implements UI components and Atom-specific integration code, but most of the logic lives in an editor-agnostic library called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/atom/teletype-client&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;teletype-client&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Our protocols and API may churn for a while as we develop the system, but it should be possible to integrate &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;teletype-client&lt;/code&gt; into any web-based application or even package it in an Electron-based server to talk to it from native editors. Supporting inter-operation between different text editors is definitely part of our long term vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;carriage-return-line-feed&quot;&gt;Carriage return, line feed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, Teletype only transmits text, so it’s a good idea to combine it with an application for voice communication. Traditional screen sharing can also be helpful for sharing the state of applications outside of Atom. Ultimately, we want to incorporate these kinds of features directly into the package along with a long list of other improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But rather than waiting for perfection, we are releasing a beta version of this package now, because we think it’s useful today. We’ve been using Teletype to build Teletype for a few months now, happily working together across two continents and three time zones. Daily teletyping has made us happier and more productive, and we hope it will do the same for you and your teammates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://teletype.atom.io&quot;&gt;teletype.atom.io&lt;/a&gt; to start coding together in Atom today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 16:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hswolff</dc:creator>
<og:title>Code together in real time with Teletype for Atom</og:title>
<og:description>Writing code with another programmer is a great way to absorb knowledge, challenge yourself with new perspectives, and ultimately write better software. It can also be a fulfilling way to get to know the mind of another human being. Unfortunately, the logistics of writing code with another programmer can be such a hassle that many people don’t bother. Here are some of the common obstacles: Sharing the same physical machine is impossible for remote teams, and can be challenging to organize even when teammates share the same office. Cloud-based IDEs and remote tmux sessions ask you to move your entire workflow into a hosted environment, which isn’t always possible or desirable. The connection latency of screen sharing can lead to an awkward dynamic where only one collaborator can comfortably edit. Social coding shouldn’t have to be this hard! Today, we’re taking a first step toward making it just as easy to code together as it is to code alone with Teletype for Atom. At the dawn of computing, teletypes were used to create a real-time circuit between two machines so that anything typed on one machine appeared at the other end immediately. Following in these electro-mechanical footsteps, Teletype for Atom wires the keystrokes of remote collaborators directly into your programming environment, enabling conflict-free, low-latency collaborative editing for any file you can open in Atom.</og:description>
<og:url>http://blog.atom.io/2017/11/15/code-together-in-real-time-with-teletype-for-atom.html</og:url>
<og:image>http://blog.atom.io/img/posts/teletype/teletype.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.atom.io/2017/11/15/code-together-in-real-time-with-teletype-for-atom.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Visual Studio Live Share</title>
<link>https://code.visualstudio.com/blogs/2017/11/15/live-share</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://code.visualstudio.com/blogs/2017/11/15/live-share</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;November 15, 2017 Amanda Silver, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/amandaksilver&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@amandaksilver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that we’re working on “Visual Studio Live Share”, which enables developers using Visual Studio 2017 or Visual Studio Code to collaborate in real-time! Learn more about Live Share and the upcoming limited private preview &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/visual-studio-live-share&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;_what-is-live-share&quot; data-needslink=&quot;_what-is-live-share&quot;&gt;What is Live Share?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live Share enables your team to quickly collaborate on the same codebase without the need to synchronize code or to configure the same development tools, settings, or environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to Live Share, seeing is believing. Watch the following video to get an idea of what we are working on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you share a collaborative session, your teammate sees the context of the workspace in their editor. This means your teammate can read the code you shared without having to clone a repo or install any dependencies your code relies on. They can use rich language features to navigate within the code; not only just opening other files as text but using semantic analysis-based navigation like Go to Definition or Peek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/assets/blogs/2017/11/15/vs-code-ls-session.png&quot; alt=&quot;Live Sharing with VS Code&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your teammate edits a file, they get editor enhancements like IntelliSense, statement completion, and suggestions. Each of you can open files, navigate, edit code, highlight, or refactor - and changes are instantly reflected. As you edit you can see your teammate’s cursor, jump to the location of your teammate’s carat, or follow their actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborative debugging goes further, allowing you and your teammate to independently inspect objects using debugging features like hovers, locals and watches, the stack trace or the debug console. You are both able to set breakpoints and advance the debug cursor to step through the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/assets/blogs/2017/11/15/vs-code-ls-session2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Live Sharing with VS Code&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;_why-live-share&quot; data-needslink=&quot;_why-live-share&quot;&gt;Why Live Share?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Microsoft Teams and Slack bring dynamic team collaboration into a digital form, there is more we can do to make it easier to work together in a development team. Screen-sharing or accessing a machine remotely means that only one person is in control while the other observes. Instant messaging, email, or other tools are great for basic messages but collaborating on a body of code often requires more than a code snippet or a single file to share the necessary context. Additionally, the validity of edits can be impacted by multiple files in the workspace. If you want to replicate your teammate’s environment, it just takes a lot of time to get everything set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live Share allows you to share the context of the code, so you get instant, bidirectional collaboration. Each of you can use a tool that you’ve personalized so you’re the most productive dev you can be. You can independently investigate an issue without stepping on each other, no need to hand-off control or deal with latency. Collaborate with shared focus only when you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;_find-out-more&quot; data-needslink=&quot;_find-out-more&quot;&gt;Find out more&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to give you an early glimpse into Live Share today. Although we are only sharing it as a demo today, we will be releasing a limited private preview soon. If you want to learn more and keep up with the project, you can sign up by clicking &lt;a href=&quot;https://aka.ms/vsls-signup&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/amandaksilver&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@amandaksilver&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;q=%23VSLiveShare&amp;amp;src=typd&quot;&gt;#VSLiveShare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 15:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>benaadams</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://code.visualstudio.com/blogs/2017/11/15/live-share</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Introducing Visual Studio Live Share</og:title>
<og:description>Real-time collaborative development</og:description>
<og:image>http://code.visualstudio.com/assets/blogs/2017/11/15/ls-social-resized.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://code.visualstudio.com/blogs/2017/11/15/live-share</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>