<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Intel patches new ME vulnerabilities</title>
<link>http://blog.ptsecurity.com/2018/07/intel-patches-new-me-vulnerabilities.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.ptsecurity.com/2018/07/intel-patches-new-me-vulnerabilities.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3zYKlTwm7iU/W073gA7hQsI/AAAAAAAAG_4/GX9JpmnPvIA88IKcqD89Cu553rSxOwBAgCLcBGAs/s1600/5d2a85fc04ad45edaafac045c794f031%2B%25284%2529.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3zYKlTwm7iU/W073gA7hQsI/AAAAAAAAG_4/GX9JpmnPvIA88IKcqD89Cu553rSxOwBAgCLcBGAs/s640/5d2a85fc04ad45edaafac045c794f031%2B%25284%2529.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;In early July, Intel issued security advisories &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/security-center/advisory/intel-sa-00112.html&quot;&gt;SA-00112&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/security-center/advisory/intel-sa-00118.html&quot;&gt;SA-00118&lt;/a&gt; regarding fixes for vulnerabilities in Intel Management Engine. Both advisories describe vulnerabilities with which an attacker could execute arbitrary code on the Minute IA PCH microcontroller.&lt;p&gt;The vulnerabilities are similar to ones previously discovered by Positive Technologies security experts last November (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/security-center/advisory/intel-sa-00086.html&quot;&gt;SA-00086&lt;/a&gt;). But that was not the end of the story, as Intel has now released fixes for additional vulnerabilities in ME.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What happened?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;CVE-2018-3627, the vulnerability at issue in advisory SA-00118, is described as a logic bug (not a buffer overflow) that may allow execution of arbitrary code. Ease of exploitation makes this vulnerability more dangerous than the one in SA-00086, which was locally exploitable only in case of OEM configuration errors; instead, an attacker simply needs local access.&lt;p&gt;Things are even worse with CVE-2018-3628, which is described in advisory SA-00112. This vulnerability enables full-blown remote code execution in the AMT process of the Management Engine. Moreover, all signs indicate that—unlike CVE-2017-5712 in advisory SA-00086—attackers do not need an AMT administrator account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intel characterizes the vulnerability as &quot;Buffer overflow in HTTP handler&quot; allowing remote code execution without authorization. This is the very scenario that used to be the stuff of nightmares for Intel users—and now has come to pass. This vulnerability is similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/security-center/advisory/intel-sa-00075.html&quot;&gt;CVE-2017-5689&lt;/a&gt;, which was found in May 2017 by Embedi, but with even worse consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Perhaps the only consolation is that for CVE-2018-3628, Intel says that exploitation is possible only from the same subnet.&lt;p&gt;Positive Technologies plans to study these vulnerabilities more closely in future research. Notably, Intel indicates the same &quot;resolved&quot; firmware versions for the vulnerabilities as for SA-00086. In other words, it is possible that these latest vulnerabilities were found during security review of Intel ME code at the same time as SA-00086, but Intel delayed publication in order to head off the alarm and disruption that could have followed from packing such a large number of critical vulnerabilities in SA-00086.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;More on Intel ME security:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nh2</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://blog.ptsecurity.com/2018/07/intel-patches-new-me-vulnerabilities.html</og:url>
<og:title>Intel patches new ME vulnerabilities</og:title>
<og:description>In early July, Intel issued security advisories SA-00112 and SA-00118 regarding fixes for vulnerabilities in Intel Management Engine. ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3zYKlTwm7iU/W073gA7hQsI/AAAAAAAAG_4/GX9JpmnPvIA88IKcqD89Cu553rSxOwBAgCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/5d2a85fc04ad45edaafac045c794f031%2B%25284%2529.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.ptsecurity.com/2018/07/intel-patches-new-me-vulnerabilities.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A new digital divide: Young people who can’t use keyboards</title>
<link>http://www.asahi.com/ajw/articles/AJ201803290068.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.asahi.com/ajw/articles/AJ201803290068.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;“How do I double click?” “What is a cell in a spreadsheet?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mashiko Ishii often hears that her fellow lecturers at Uchida Human Resources Development Center become confused when they are asked such basic questions during training for new employees of IT companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pressing the button of a computer mouse twice and knowing the basic unit for data input in spreadsheets are some of the fundamentals of using a computer, but it is not uncommon for even would-be system engineers to ask such questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason is clear. As smartphones have become extremely convenient, a growing number of students have never laid their hands on a personal computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lecturers who work with Ishii often start training by teaching students how to use a keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We need to teach them the basics before we start classes,” Ishii says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Younger generations often become underdogs in offices if they are unable to handle the technical requirements for their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yoshiaki Hashimoto, a professor of information socio-psychology at the University of Tokyo’s graduate school, is worried that “a new digital divide is being born.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to analysis by Hashimoto and the Ministry of Internal Affairs and Communications, the Internet usage rate with smartphones and mobile devices was more than 80 percent among the demographic aged 10-19 from 2012 to 2016, but the proportion of those who used personal computers plummeted from 76 percent to 56 percent over the same period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that they can write and submit their school reports with smartphones, they are not outsiders to the world of the Internet. However, much of this does not align with the knowledge necessary to work in their future jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital divide often refers to elderly people who are unfamiliar with IT equipment, but it seems that this phenomenon is also beginning to affect Japan’s youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital divide has not been resolved for the aging population. According to Hashimoto, although the Internet usage rate rose to 88 percent in 2016 among those in their 60s, the ratio of those visiting websites was only 60 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that there are many elderly people who cannot gather information they need, even though they can send e-mails on cellphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I covered a Japan-Germany symposium on digital society in Berlin in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lena-Sophie Mueller, of the German nonprofit Initiative D21, pointed out: “Timetables (for railways) are no longer available in paper form. More and more services are based on the Internet and without access, those on the other side of the Internet are excluded from social participation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the digitization of society makes our lives more convenient, it shows that there are still weaknesses in our system and that the benefits do not extend to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a good reminder to think again that we need to keep our eye on technology’s limits and to consider what we can do to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 11:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>paralelogram</dc:creator>
<og:title>A new digital divide: Young people who can’t use keyboards：The Asahi Shimbun</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.asahi.com/ajw/articles/AJ201803290068.html</og:url>
<og:image>http://www.asahicom.jp/ajw/articles/images/AS20180329005166_comm.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>“How do I double click?” “What is a cell in a spreadsheet?”Mashiko Ishii often hears that her fellow</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.asahi.com/ajw/articles/AJ201803290068.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rockstar: A programming language where programs are also song lyrics</title>
<link>https://github.com/dylanbeattie/rockstar</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/dylanbeattie/rockstar</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rockstar is a dynamically typed Turing-complete programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rockstar is designed for creating computer programs that are also song lyrics, and is heavily influenced by the lyrical conventions of 1980s hard rock and power ballads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;But why?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainly because if we make Rockstar a real (and completely pointless) programming language, then recruiters and hiring managers won't be able to talk about 'rockstar developers' any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also 'cos it's kinda fun and any language based on the idea of compiling Meatloaf lyrics has to be worth a look, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also we can make stickers. Who doesn't want a sticker on their laptop saying 'CERTIFIED ROCKSTAR DEVELOPER'?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Rockstar Language Specification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rockstar is intended to give the programmer an unprecedented degree of poetic license when it comes to the composition and structure of their programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of comments in Rockstar programs is strongly discouraged. This is rock'n'roll; it's up to the audience to find their own meaning. If you absolutely insist on commenting your Rockstar programs, comments should be contained in parentheses (). Yes, this means you can't use brackets in arithmetic expressions and may need to decompose complex expressions into multiple evaluations and assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rockstar developers are not into that whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Brevity%20Thing&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;brevity thing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Tommy was a lean mean wrecking machine.  (initialises Tommy with the value 14487) 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Variables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's two ways to declare and use variables in Rockstar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common variables&lt;/strong&gt; consist of one of the keywords &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;an&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;the&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;my&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;your&lt;/code&gt; followed by a unique variable name, which must contain only lowercase ASCII letters a-z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proper variables&lt;/strong&gt; are proper nouns - any word that isn't a reserved keyword and starts with an uppercase letter. Proper variable names can contain spaces as long as each space is followed by an uppercase letter. Whilst some developers may use this feature to create variables with names like &lt;code&gt;Customer ID&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Tax Rate&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Distance In KM&lt;/code&gt;, we recommend you favour idiomatic variable names such as &lt;code&gt;Tommy&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Gina&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Doctor Feelgood&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Mister Crowley&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Kayleigh&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Tom Sawyer&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Billie Jean&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Janie&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Although not strictly idiomatic, &lt;code&gt;Eleanor Rigby&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Peggy Sue&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Black Betty&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Layla&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Johnny B Goode&lt;/code&gt; would also all be valid variable names in Rockstar.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in Ruby, Python and VBScript, variables are dynamically typed and you don't need to declare variables before use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pronouns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keywords &lt;code&gt;it&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;he&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;she&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;him&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;her&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;them&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;they&lt;/code&gt; always refer to the most recently named variable, determined at parse time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Types&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rockstar uses a very similar type system to that defined by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ecma-international.org/ecma-262/5.1/#sec-8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ECMAScript type system&lt;/a&gt;, except &lt;code&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt; doesn't sound very rock'n'roll so we use &lt;code&gt;mysterious&lt;/code&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mysterious&lt;/strong&gt; - the value of any variable that hasn't been assigned a value, denoted by the keyword &lt;code&gt;mysterious&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Null&lt;/strong&gt; - the null type. Evaluates as equal to zero and equal to false. The keywords &lt;code&gt;nothing&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;nowhere&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;nobody&lt;/code&gt; are defined as aliases for &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boolean&lt;/strong&gt; - a logical entity having two values &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;em&gt;(The keywords &lt;code&gt;maybe&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;definitely maybe&lt;/code&gt; are reserved for future use)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;right&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;yes&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ok&lt;/code&gt; are valid aliases for &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;wrong&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;no&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;lies&lt;/code&gt; are valid aliases for &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number&lt;/strong&gt; - Numbers in Rockstar are stored using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dec64.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DEC64&lt;/a&gt; numeric type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;String&lt;/strong&gt; - Rockstar strings are sequences of 16-bit unsigned integer values representing UTF-16 code units.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Object&lt;/strong&gt; - a collection of named data properties, as in ECMAScript.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Literals and Assignment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;String literals in Rockstar use double quotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The single quote character in Rockstar is treated as a letter of the alphabet. This seems unusual until you remember that &lt;code&gt;I ain't talkin' 'bout love&lt;/code&gt; is a perfectly valid rock'n'roll sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numeric literals in Rockstar are written as decimal numbers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;123&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;3.141592654&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assignment is denoted by the &lt;code&gt;put/into&lt;/code&gt; keyword combination:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Put 123 into X&lt;/code&gt; will assign the value &lt;code&gt;123&lt;/code&gt; to the variable &lt;code&gt;X&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Put &quot;Hello World&quot; into the message&lt;/code&gt; will assign the value &lt;code&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/code&gt; to the variable &lt;code&gt;the message&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Increment and Decrement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increment and decrement are supported by the &lt;code&gt;Build {variable} up&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Knock {variable} down&lt;/code&gt; keywords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Build my world up&lt;/code&gt; will increment the value stored in &lt;code&gt;my world&lt;/code&gt; by 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Knock the walls down&lt;/code&gt; will decrement the value stored in &lt;code&gt;the walls&lt;/code&gt; by 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Arithmetic&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic arithmetic is provided by the &lt;code&gt;plus&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;minus&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;times&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;over&lt;/code&gt; keywords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arithmetic expressions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;{a} plus {b}&lt;/code&gt; - addition. Alias &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;{a} minus {b}&lt;/code&gt; - subtraction. Alias &lt;code&gt;without&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;{a} times {b}&lt;/code&gt; - multiplication. Alias &lt;code&gt;of&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;{a} over {b}&lt;/code&gt; - division.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Put the whole of your heart into my hands&lt;/code&gt; - multiply &lt;code&gt;your heart&lt;/code&gt; by &lt;code&gt;the whole&lt;/code&gt; and assign the result to &lt;code&gt;my hands&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;My world is nothing without your love&lt;/code&gt; - Initialize &lt;code&gt;my world&lt;/code&gt; with the result of subtracting &lt;code&gt;your love&lt;/code&gt; from 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;If the tears of a child is nothing&lt;/code&gt; - check whether &lt;code&gt;the tears&lt;/code&gt; * &lt;code&gt;a child&lt;/code&gt; = 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Poetic Literals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rockstar also supports a unique language feature known as &lt;strong&gt;poetic literals&lt;/strong&gt;. Inspired by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Here_document&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here-document&lt;/a&gt; syntax supported by many scripting languages, poetic literals allow the programmer to simultaneously initialize a variable and express their innermost angst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Poetic Type Literals&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the keywords &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;nothing&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;nobody&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;nowhere&lt;/code&gt;, a poetic assignment is a single line consisting of a variable name, the &lt;code&gt;is&lt;/code&gt; keyword and the required value literal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;My heart is true&lt;/code&gt; - initialises the variable &lt;code&gt;my heart&lt;/code&gt; with the Boolean value &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tommy is nobody&lt;/code&gt; - initialises the variable &lt;code&gt;Tommy&lt;/code&gt; with the value &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; using the &lt;code&gt;nobody&lt;/code&gt; alias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Poetic String Literals&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A poetic string literal assignment starts with a variable name, followed by one of the keywords &lt;code&gt;says&lt;/code&gt; followed by a single space. The rest of the line up to the &lt;code&gt;\n&lt;/code&gt; terminator is treated as an unquoted string literal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Billy says hello world!\n&lt;/code&gt; will initialise the variable &lt;code&gt;Billy&lt;/code&gt; with the string literal &lt;code&gt;&quot;hello world!&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;The world says hello back\n&lt;/code&gt; will initialise the variable &lt;code&gt;the world&lt;/code&gt; with the string literal &lt;code&gt;hello back&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Poetic Number Literals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A poetic number literal begins with a variable name, followed by the keyword &lt;code&gt;is&lt;/code&gt;, or the aliases &lt;code&gt;was&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;were&lt;/code&gt;. As long as the next symbol is not a reserved keyword, the rest of the line is treated as a decimal number in which the values of consecutive digits are given by the lengths of the subsequent barewords, up until the end of the line. To allow the digit zero, and to compensate for a lack of suitably rock'n'roll 1- and 2-letter words, word lengths are parsed modulo 10. A period (.) character denotes a decimal place. Other than the first period, any non-alphabetical characters are ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tommy was a lovestruck ladykiller&lt;/code&gt; initialises &lt;code&gt;Tommy&lt;/code&gt; with the value &lt;code&gt;100&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sweet Lucy was a dancer&lt;/code&gt; - initialises &lt;code&gt;Sweet Lucy&lt;/code&gt; with the value 16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;A killer is on the loose&lt;/code&gt; - initialises &lt;code&gt;a killer&lt;/code&gt; with the value 235.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;My dreams were ice. A life unfulfilled; wakin' everybody up, taking booze and pills&lt;/code&gt; - initialises &lt;code&gt;my dreams&lt;/code&gt; with the value &lt;code&gt;3.1415926535&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that poetic literals &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt; include reserved keywords, as with &lt;code&gt;taking&lt;/code&gt; in this example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Comparison&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the single-equals operator in Visual Basic and some scripting languages, the &lt;code&gt;is&lt;/code&gt; keyword in Rockstar is interepreted differently depending whether it appears as part of a statement or as part of an expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparison in Rockstar can only be done within an expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tommy is nobody&lt;/code&gt; initialises the variable &lt;code&gt;Tommy&lt;/code&gt; with the value &lt;code&gt;nobody&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;If Tommy is nobody&lt;/code&gt; - will execute the following block if, and only if, the variable &lt;code&gt;Tommy&lt;/code&gt; is equal to &lt;code&gt;nobody&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The modifier &lt;code&gt;not&lt;/code&gt; will invert the meaning of the comparison, similar to &lt;code&gt;IS NULL / IS NOT NULL&lt;/code&gt; in SQL. The keyword &lt;code&gt;ain't&lt;/code&gt; is an alias for &lt;code&gt;is not&lt;/code&gt;. This usage runs contrary to idiomatic English, where &quot;Tommy isn't anybody&quot;, &quot;Tommy ain't nobody&quot; and &quot;Tommy ain't not nobody&quot; somehow mean exactly the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rockstar also supports the following comparison syntax:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;is higher/greater/bigger/stronger than&lt;/code&gt; to denote 'greater than'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;is lower/less/smaller/weaker than&lt;/code&gt; to denote 'less than'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;is as high/great/big/strong as&lt;/code&gt; to denote 'greater than or equal to'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;is as low/little/small/weak as&lt;/code&gt; to denote 'less than or equal to'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Input/Output&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;code&gt;Listen&lt;/code&gt; keyword to read one line of input from &lt;code&gt;STDIN&lt;/code&gt;. Use &lt;code&gt;Listen to&lt;/code&gt; to capture the input into a named variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Listen to your heart&lt;/code&gt; - read one line of input from &lt;code&gt;STDIN&lt;/code&gt; and store it in &lt;code&gt;your heart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;code&gt;Say&lt;/code&gt; keyword to write the value of a variable to &lt;code&gt;SDTOUT&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Say Tommy&lt;/code&gt; - will output the value stored in &lt;code&gt;Tommy&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;STDOUT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rockstar defines &lt;code&gt;Shout&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Whisper&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Scream&lt;/code&gt; as aliases for &lt;code&gt;Say&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Flow Control and Block Syntax&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Conditionals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conditional expressions start with the &lt;code&gt;If&lt;/code&gt; keyword, followed by an expression. If the expression evaluates to &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;, then the subsequent code block is executed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Loops&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the &lt;code&gt;If&lt;/code&gt; statement, a loop is denoted by the &lt;code&gt;While&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Until&lt;/code&gt; keyword, which will cause the subsequent code block to be executed repeatedly whilst the expression is satisfied:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Tommy was a dancer
While Tommy ain't nothing,
Knock Tommy down
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That'll initialize Tommy with the value 16 (using the poetic number literal syntax) and then loop, decrementing Tommy by 1 each time until Tommy equals zero (i.e &lt;code&gt;ain't nothing&lt;/code&gt; returns false).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;break&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;continue&lt;/code&gt; statements work as they do in most block-based languages. Rockstar defines &lt;code&gt;Break it down&lt;/code&gt; as an alias for &lt;code&gt;break&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Take it to the top&lt;/code&gt; as an alias for &lt;code&gt;continue&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Blocks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A block in Rockstar starts with an &lt;code&gt;If&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Else&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;While&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Until&lt;/code&gt; statement, and is terminated by a blank line or the end-of-file. EOF ends all open code blocks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Tommy was a dancer
While Tommy ain't nothing
Shout it
Knock it down

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Functions are declared with a variable name followed by the &lt;code&gt;takes&lt;/code&gt; keyword and a list of argument separated by the &lt;code&gt;and&lt;/code&gt; keyword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Multiply takes X and Y&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Search takes Needle and Haystack&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The function body is a list of statements with no separating blank lines. A blank line denotes the end of a function body. Functions in Rockstar always have a return value, indicated by the &lt;code&gt;Give back&lt;/code&gt; keyword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Functions are called using the 'taking' keyword:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Multiply taking 3, 5&lt;/code&gt; is an expression returning (presumably) 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Search taking &quot;hands&quot;, &quot;lay your hands on me&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's FizzBuzz in minimalist Rockstar, with block scope indented for clarity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Modulus takes Number and Divisor
While Number is as high as Divisor
Put Number minus Divisor into Number
    (blank line ending While block)
Give back Number
    (blank line ending function declaration)
Limit is 100
Counter is 0
Fizz is 3
Buzz is 5
Until Counter is Limit
Build Counter up
If Modulus taking Counter, Fizz is 0 and Modulus taking Counter, Buzz is 0
Say &quot;FizzBuzz!&quot;
Continue
    (blank line ending 'If' Block)
If Modulus taking Counter and Fizz is 0
Say &quot;Fizz!&quot;
Continue
    (blank line ending 'If' Block)      
If Modulus taking Counter and Buzz is 0
Say &quot;Buzz!&quot;
Continue
    (blank line ending 'If' Block)
Say Counter
    (EOL ending Until block)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here's the same thing in idiomatic Rockstar, using poetic literals and no indentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Midnight takes your heart and your soul
While your heart is as high as your soul
Put your heart without your soul into your heart

Give back your heart


Desire is a lovestruck ladykiller
My world is nothing 
Fire is ice
Hate is water
Until my world is Desire,
Build my world up
If Midnight taking my world, Fire is nothing and Midnight taking my world, Hate is nothing
Shout &quot;FizzBuzz!&quot;
Take it to the top

If Midnight taking my world, Fire is nothing
Shout &quot;Fizz!&quot;
Take it to the top

If Midnight taking my world, Hate is nothing
Say &quot;Buzz!&quot;
Take it to the top

Whisper my world
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Work out if this is even remotely implementable. I'm not sold on the idea of continuation prefixes for block syntax - for starters it won't let you implement nested blocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore other ideas for Turing-complete rock ballad compilers. Maybe something based on BF where we use word length or initial letters or something to compile lyrics down to BF or some other very minimalist but Turing-complete language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make 'Certified Rockstar Developer' stickers and give them out to anybody who can write even one line of Rockstar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a score for the lyrics using a component called a &lt;code&gt;composer&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 06:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/106178?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>dylanbeattie/rockstar</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/dylanbeattie/rockstar</og:url>
<og:description>rockstar - The Rockstar programming language specification</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/dylanbeattie/rockstar</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Conflating pointers with arrays: C&amp;#039;s biggest mistake? (2009)</title>
<link>https://www.digitalmars.com/articles/b44.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.digitalmars.com/articles/b44.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;written by Walter Bright&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;December 22, 2009&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C is arguably the world's most successful programming language. Its success has, of course, endlessly tempted people to improve upon it. Thus, C is probably the patriarch of the longest list of languages. Notable among these are C++, the D programming language, and most recently, Go. There are endless discussion threads on how to fix C, going back to the 80's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is well trod ground. What could possibly be added to this soup? I posit that most such discussions center around detail. More interesting is what is the largest fundamental mistake. We should take into account the context of the times that spawned C, and the problems it was trying to solve and the environment in which it was intended to be used. Keep in mind it was developed for a 16 bit machine, with extremely limited resources available. I'd like to dismiss things like it doesn't do garbage collection, functional programming, dynamic typing, or OOP. Those aren't problems C attempted to address, so the lack of them are not mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What mistake has caused more grief, more bugs, more workarounds, more endless hours consumed, etc., than any other? Many people would say &lt;a href=&quot;http://qconlondon.com/london-2009/presentation/Null+References:+The+Billion+Dollar+Mistake&quot;&gt;null pointers&lt;/a&gt;. I don't agree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conflating pointers with arrays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't mean them using the same syntax, or the implicit conversion of arrays to pointers. I mean the inability to pass an array to a function as an array, even if it is declared to be an array. C will silently convert the array to be a pointer, and will rewrite the function declaration so it is semantically a pointer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;d_code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; foo(&lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt; a[])
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is exactly equivalent to [1]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;d_code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; foo(&lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt; *a)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seemingly innocuous convenience feature is the root of endless evil. It means that once arrays leave the scope in which they are defined, they become pointers, and lose the information which gives the extent of the array — the array dimension. What are the consequences of losing this information?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative must be used. For strings, it's the whole reason for the 0 terminator. For other arrays, it is inferred programmatically from the context. Naturally, every situation is different, and so an endless array (!) of bugs ensues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trainwreck just unfolds in slow motion from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The galaxy of C string functions, from the unsafe strcpy() to sprintf() onwards, is a direct result. There are various attempts at fixing this, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ddj.com/security/214502214&quot;&gt;Safe C Library&lt;/a&gt;. Then there are all the buffer overflows, because functions handed a pointer have no idea what the limits are, and no array bounds checking is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This problem was inherited in toto by C++, which consequently spawned 10+ years of attempts to create a usable string class. Even the eventual &lt;tt&gt;std::string&lt;/tt&gt; result is compromised by its need to be compatible with C 0-terminated strings. C++ addressed the more general array problem by inventing &lt;tt&gt;std::vector&lt;/tt&gt;, and many programming guidelines eschew using &lt;tt&gt;T[]&lt;/tt&gt; style arrays. But the legacy of C arrays continues in C++ with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boostcon.com/site-media/var/sphene/sphwiki/attachment/2009/05/08/iterators-must-go.pdf&quot;&gt;unsafe iterator design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The C99 attempted to fix this problem, but the fatal error it made was still not combining the array dimension with the array pointer into one type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all isn't lost. C can still be fixed. All it needs is a little new syntax:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;d_code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; foo(&lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt; a[..])
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;meaning an array is passed as a so-called “fat pointer”, i.e. a pair consisting of a pointer to the start of the array, and a &lt;tt&gt;size_t&lt;/tt&gt; of the array dimension. Of course, this won't fix any existing code, but it will enable new code to be written correctly and robustly. Over time, the syntax:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;d_code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; foo(&lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt; a[])
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;can be deprecated by convention and by compilers. Even better, transitioning to the new way can be done by making the declarations binary compatible with older code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;d_code&quot;&gt;
#if NEWC
  &lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;extern&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; foo(&lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt; a[..]);
#elif C99
  &lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;extern&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; foo(size_t dim, &lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt; a[dim]);
#else
  &lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;extern&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; foo(size_t dim, &lt;span class=&quot;d_keyword&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt; *a);
#endif
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change isn't going to transform C into a modern language with all the shiny bells and whistles. It'll still be C, in spirit as well as practice. It will just relieve C programmers of dealing with one particular constant, pernicious source of bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The relevant text from K+R's The C Programming Language 5.3 is “When an array name is passed to a function, what is passed is the location of the beginning of the array. Within the called function, this argument is a variable, just like any other variable, and so an array name argument is truly a pointer, that is, a variable containing an address.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The relevant text from the C 99 Standard 6.7.5.3.7 is “A declaration of a parameter as ‘array of type’ shall be adjusted to ‘qualified pointer to type’ ”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From Stroupstrup's The C++ Programming Language first edition 7.1 “and as usual, array names are converted to pointers.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Bartosz Milewski for reviewing a draft of this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 05:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>etrevino</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.digitalmars.com/articles/b44.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>p-Hacking and False Discovery in A/B Testing</title>
<link>https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3204791</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3204791</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;note note-list&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;44 Pages&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Posted: 18 Jul 2018&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;authors&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University of Pennsylvania - The Wharton School&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenDoor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Independent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University of Pennsylvania - Marketing Department&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date Written: June 28, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;abstract-text&quot; readability=&quot;49&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigate whether online A/B experimenters &quot;p-hack&quot; by stopping their experiments based on the p-value of the treatment effect. Our data contains 2,101 commercial experiments in which experimenters can track the magnitude and significance level of the effect every day of the experiment. We use a regression discontinuity design to detect p-hacking, i.e., the causal effect of reaching a particular p-value on stopping behavior.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experimenters indeed p-hack, especially for positive effects. Specifically, about 57% of experimenters p-hack when the experiment reaches 90% confidence. Furthermore, approximately 70% of the effects are truly null, and p-hacking increases the false discovery rate (FDR) from 33% to 42% among experiments p-hacked at 90% confidence. Assuming that false discoveries cause experimenters to stop exploring for more effective treatments, we estimate the expected cost of a false discovery to be a loss of 1.95% in lift, which corresponds to the 76th percentile of observed lifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; A/B testing, p-hacking, false discoveries, false positives, experimentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JEL Classification:&lt;/strong&gt; C12, C90, C93, M21, M31&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hidden-xs hidden-sm&quot;&gt;Suggested Citation:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3204791#&quot; class=&quot;suggested-citation-btn btn-link visible-xs visible-sm&quot;&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 03:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gwern</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3204791</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ex-Valve employee describes internal politics at &amp;#039;self-organizing&amp;#039; companies</title>
<link>https://www.pcgamer.com/ex-valve-employee-describes-ruthless-industry-politics/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.pcgamer.com/ex-valve-employee-describes-ruthless-industry-politics/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;bordeaux-image-check&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vanilla.futurecdn.net/pcgamer/media/img/missing-image.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; lazy-image lazy-image-loading lazyload optional-image&quot; onerror=&quot;this.parentNode.replaceChild(window.missingImage(),this)&quot; sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-normal=&quot;https://vanilla.futurecdn.net/pcgamer/media/img/missing-image.svg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zTSt2JAwMYD4Bw4zT8oKTP-320-80.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zTSt2JAwMYD4Bw4zT8oKTP-320-80.jpg 320w, https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zTSt2JAwMYD4Bw4zT8oKTP-650-80.jpg 650w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-original-mos=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zTSt2JAwMYD4Bw4zT8oKTP.jpg&quot; data-pin-media=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zTSt2JAwMYD4Bw4zT8oKTP.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former Valve employee Rich Geldreich, who worked at the company between 2009 and 2014, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;spent the past several days tweeting&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; detailed accounts of the internal politics at 'self-organizing' companies—one of which he says is based in Bellevue, Washington, where Valve is headquartered. Some of Geldreich's comments could be about any self-organizing company (that is, a company without a traditional hierarchical management structure), but other, more specific references suggest he is largely talking about Valve. For instance, he &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/1019343577237762049&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;comments on mass layoffs in 2013&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and we &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcgamer.com/valve-layoff-hardware-mobile/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;know layoffs occurred at Valve that year&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Geldreich says that he still prefers flat company structures to hierarchical structures (he's now moved on to discussing the latter on his account), many of the politics he describes at 'SelfOrganizingCo' don't sound pleasant. According to Geldreich, the company in question leaked its friendly employee handbook as a PR move, but was actually a stressful, difficult place to work, full of backstabbing and manipulation in pursuit of bonuses and job security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet hawk-ignore&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;After joining this one Bellevue company one of the psuedo-managers kept ragging on a well known physics coder I respected. He joined the company and left for another after a few months.&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/1018389695305117698&quot;&gt;July 15, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few excerpts from Geldreich's long series of tweets, and what leads us to believe they are primarily about Valve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;At a self-organizing company with bonuses: Once you modify a project you’re on the hook for anything until it ships. The team will hold your bonus hostage and claim your work broke something. It’s basically company-legalized extortion.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(In 2013, former Valve economist Yanis Varoufakis &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/187296/How_Valve_hires_how_it_fires_and_how_much_it_pays.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;explained that&lt;/a&gt; bonuses are a major part of Valve's employee compensation: &quot;The payment mechanism is to a very large extent bonus-based. So the contracts usually have a minimum pay segment in it, which is more or less established by tradition. And then the interesting part in this contract is how much is left to the peer review process, which is very complicated. It involves various layers of mutual assessment.&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;The company was moving into a new field. They made the temp strategic hire then fired her a year later with no warning after they had hired up her friends and their friends.&quot; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(During Geldreich's time at Valve, the company axed its augmented reality development, firing developer Jeri Ellsworth along with others, though he may be referring to someone else.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;Another type of temp strategic hire you can make is to recruit a well-known author, a famous dev, or a person with specialized skills (like an economist). Have them write gushingly about their amazing experiences at the company. Once you’re done with them quietly let them go.&quot; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This seems to be a reference to economist Yanis Varoufakis, who is quoted above regarding bonuses, and who did write blog posts for Valve. In 2015, Varoufakis was appointed Greek Minister of Finance.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;All legit self-organizing firms have to 'leak' an official unofficial Company Manual. It’s got to be slickly made and fun to read. Developer Marketing gurus create these productions to sway new recruits into the Hiring Funnel. Insiders laugh at these things.&quot; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Valve's employee handbook &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcgamer.com/valve-employee-handbook-leaked-read-it-here/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;was leaked in 2012&lt;/a&gt;, which was during Geldreich's time at the company.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of Geldreich's comments are similar to comments Ellsworth made after being let go by Valve. &quot;...There is actually a hidden layer of powerful management structure in the company and it felt a lot like high school,&quot; Ellsworth &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2013/07/wireduk-valve-jeri-ellsworth/&quot;&gt;said in 2013&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;There are popular kids that have acquired power in the company, then there's the trouble makers, and everyone in between.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geldreich similarly describes 'barons' who are in with the executive arm of the company in question, and a culture in which employees must curry favor with influential 'sponsors' to enjoy stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet hawk-ignore&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;At self-organizing firms you might be placed into a huge open office and given massive monitors. This is to normalize all communications and for more effective surveillance. Everything will be monitored either directly by a corporate arm employee, one of their barons or friends.&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/1018717721012289541&quot;&gt;July 16, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Valve has some glowing recommendations on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/Reviews/Valve-Corporation-Reviews-E24849_P2.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;anonymous employee review site Glassdoor&lt;/a&gt;, the testimonies of certain self-proclaimed ex-employees also mirror Geldreich and Ellsworth's comments. One Glassdoor reviewer calls Valve's employee review process a &quot;popularity contest,&quot; and another says that the &quot;opaque approach to compensation and retention breeds a culture of paranoia,&quot; despite leaving an overall positive review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If you buy [Valve's] rhetoric, you'll hear that there are no bosses, no managers, no supervisors and that there is a flat structure where everybody is so smart, so cool and so intelligent that they can work completely autonomously,&quot; reads an especially negative Glassdoor review. &quot;That is only a facade ... In order to succeed at Valve, you need to belong to the group that has more decisional power and, even when you succeed temporarily, be certain that you have an expiration date. No matter how hard you work, no matter how original and productive you are, if your bosses and the people who count don't like you, you will be fired soon or you will be managed out.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This account sounds similar to the &quot;purging&quot; described by Geldreich's tweets, as well as his claim that the lack of structure is illusory, and that company politics are actually influenced by executives and their baron confidants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet hawk-ignore&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;If you are a total outsider coming into the firm, your best bet is to buddy up with a baron and/or their friends and just make their lives easier. Be a machine and get shit done for a while. Your goal should be to rapidly up your purge immunity level before the next firing cycle.&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/1019416004357599232&quot;&gt;July 18, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valve has a reputation for being a mysterious company, where creativity and people flow between projects without restriction, and the CEO happily responds to fan emails while still maintaining an elusive and capricious persona. That mythical quality makes it difficult to get a clear picture of what it's like to work at Valve, which of course only fuels curiosity, making Geldreich's comments stand out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many have had positive experiences at Valve, or have at least said as much, and that is also reflected on Glassdoor and in other accounts of working at the company. In 2012, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.valvesoftware.com/abrash/valve-how-i-got-here-what-its-like-and-what-im-doing-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Michael Abrash praised&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the transparency and freedom he experienced at Valve, saying that the lack of hierarchy produces &quot;remarkable results, things that would never have seen the light of day under normal hierarchical management.&quot; (Abrash left Valve to join Oculus in 2014.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Criticism we've seen from ex-employees, however, suggests that while Valve works for the in-group it can be alienating and anxiety-inducing for others. Multiple ex-employees have now said that Valve's non-hierarchical structure is not what the company says it is, and that projects and people are subject to power dynamics and executive decisions just as they are in any other workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet hawk-ignore&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I'm not interested in talking to the press at all, so please stop contacting me as I won't reply. For the record, all of my tweets are based off real-life events, and I have borrowed terminology, ideas, or concepts from other current/ex-coworkers at various places.&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/1019886863144718336&quot;&gt;July 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contacted Geldreich earlier this week in an attempt to clarify his experiences at Valve, but he has not responded. On Thursday, he &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/1019886863144718336&quot;&gt;tweeted that&lt;/a&gt; he will not speak to press, and that his comments are about &quot;various places.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On why he's chosen now to reveal these abuses in the games industry, Geldreich &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/1019957184677883909&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; that &quot;nobody apparently else has the balls, the principles, or the means to push back&quot; and in various ways accuses the press of being pawns of corporations. As for why he does not name Valve directly, Geldreich &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/1018658452216807424&quot;&gt;tells one person&lt;/a&gt; that he did not use &quot;the V word&quot; specifically to avoid press. He has criticized Valve by name in the past, however, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/551067538415554560&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;calling his time there&lt;/a&gt; the &quot;worst experience&quot; of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geldreich's tweets cover many other unsavory practices at 'self-organizing companies,' all of which are unnamed. For instance, he says that at a certain company, the &quot;president/CEO&quot; held a meeting to talk about &quot;how he manipulated the press.&quot; He also &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/1020043174989815808&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;accuses the industry&lt;/a&gt; of &quot;illegal wage collusion&quot; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999/status/1019687056719532033&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blacklisting&lt;/a&gt;. You can read his tweets in full on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richgel999&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;his public Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have contacted Valve for comment, and will update this post if I hear back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are a current or ex-Valve employee and would like to talk about your experiences at the company, you can contact me at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:tyler@pcgamer.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;tyler@pcgamer.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mepian</dc:creator>
<og:title>Ex-Valve employee describes ruthless internal politics at 'self-organizing' companies</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.pcgamer.com/ex-valve-employee-describes-ruthless-industry-politics/</og:url>
<og:description>He doesn't name the company in question, but it doesn't take any stretching to figure out who he's talking about in cases.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zTSt2JAwMYD4Bw4zT8oKTP-1200-80.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.pcgamer.com/ex-valve-employee-describes-ruthless-industry-politics/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Allure of Small Towns for Big City Freelancers</title>
<link>https://slate.com/human-interest/2018/07/big-city-freelancers-look-to-small-cities-to-lower-cost-of-living.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://slate.com/human-interest/2018/07/big-city-freelancers-look-to-small-cities-to-lower-cost-of-living.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;lazy-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image__src&quot; data-normal=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/d0d91ae9-bcad-4378-bebe-f0fd2f396d0c.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0&quot; data-retina=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/d0d91ae9-bcad-4378-bebe-f0fd2f396d0c.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/d0d91ae9-bcad-4378-bebe-f0fd2f396d0c.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 1x, https://compote.slate.com/images/d0d91ae9-bcad-4378-bebe-f0fd2f396d0c.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 2x&quot; alt=&quot;A collage of a quiet suburban neighborhood and a man writing a story.&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/d0d91ae9-bcad-4378-bebe-f0fd2f396d0c.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0&quot; alt=&quot;A collage of a quiet suburban neighborhood and a man writing a story.&quot; srcset=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/d0d91ae9-bcad-4378-bebe-f0fd2f396d0c.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 1x, https://compote.slate.com/images/d0d91ae9-bcad-4378-bebe-f0fd2f396d0c.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 2x&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo illustration by Slate. Photos by karamysh/iStock; Eerik/iStock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/partner-branding/instances/cjjrllzgh001i3g5tamb8exsl@published&quot; class=&quot;partner-branding betterLifeLab&quot; data-editable=&quot;partnerBranding&quot; readability=&quot;1.6206896551724&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;partner-branding-logo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slate.com/media/components/partner-branding/partner-logo-better-life-lab.png&quot; alt=&quot;Better Life Lab&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;partner-branding-text&quot;&gt;Better Life Lab is a partnership of Slate and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newamerica.org/&quot;&gt;New America&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrl1b11002hnnm5o3lw8c65@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;72&quot;&gt;Joel Levinson knew he was good at making movies. To make a living, Levison created video content and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2008/10/28/business/media/28video.html&quot;&gt;entered online marketing contests&lt;/a&gt;. He wrote and performed his own music, initially doing all the camerawork and directing himself, and later creating teams to help produce his projects. His winnings were impressive, between $40,000 and $80,000 a year, depending on the year, he says. He supplemented his income by creating video content for advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgw5c000s3g5t4uo48dyk@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;70&quot;&gt;But Levinson wanted to write and direct a feature film. “Life in California meant that all hours were spent making money to pay for the cost of living. That is California,” he said. “It prevented there from being any free time for pursuing creative projects that are something bigger.” Half of the 10 places with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://realestate.usnews.com/real-estate/articles/10-places-with-the-highest-cost-of-living&quot;&gt;highest costs of living&lt;/a&gt; in the United States are in California, including Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgwfu00163g5ts6guorjz@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;105&quot;&gt;So in 2014, Levinson and his family moved to Yellow Springs, Ohio, a town of 3,500 that he describes as “a blue dot in the red sea of rural Ohio.” Where they once paid $1,750 a month in rent for a one-bedroom duplex in Culver City, California, they now pay $1,300 a month for a three-bedroom home with a half-acre lawn. (Levinson notes that the rent in his former Culver City duplex has since increased by $800). He cut between a half and a third of his workweek dedicated to income projects and spent the rest of his time working on his first full-length feature.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgw7n000t3g5tl2uh2nfn@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;98&quot;&gt;“In the last couple of years we’ve seen the rise of the exodus of big cities,” said Steven Pedigo, an expert in economic and urban development who teaches at NYU and directs the NYU Schack Institute of Real Estate Urban Lab. “Places are taking the ideas of what people want in urban communities, and smaller and suburban communities are trying to recreate this.” In the past few years he’s seen more people opt out of the less-affordable “superstar” cities and retreat to midsize and smaller cities, many of which have rebranded themselves and begun to attract new residents.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgw8c000u3g5tgsuv5zux@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;141&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.levinsonbrothers.com/#boyband&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boy Band&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which Levinson co-wrote with his brother, Stephen, and filmed in Ohio, was budgeted for a fraction of what it would have cost to do in Los Angeles. The Levinsons brought in their favorite comedians, including Steve Agee and Jordan Carlos, to star in the film, and the novelty of the movie meant that local venues were willing to donate locations, props, time, and labor to help out. The Levinsons even filmed a scene with the prized piece of the Dayton Art Institute collection, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daytonlocal.com/blog/lifestyle/monets-waterlilies-at-the-dayton-art-institute.asp&quot;&gt;Claude Monet’s &lt;em&gt;Waterlilies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, at minimal cost. “We’re probably the only indie film to have a $150 million prop,” says Levinson. “If I were trying to get LACMA’s permission to go in, they would laugh me out of their offices.” (A spokesman for the Dayton Art Institute could not verify the exact monetary value of the painting.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;lazy-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image__src&quot; data-normal=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/ab4d5c0f-61e0-49f5-9432-362b544bd11b.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0&quot; data-retina=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/ab4d5c0f-61e0-49f5-9432-362b544bd11b.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/ab4d5c0f-61e0-49f5-9432-362b544bd11b.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 1x, https://compote.slate.com/images/ab4d5c0f-61e0-49f5-9432-362b544bd11b.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 2x&quot; alt=&quot;Amy Westervelt records a segment at KUNR, the local Reno NPR station.&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/ab4d5c0f-61e0-49f5-9432-362b544bd11b.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0&quot; alt=&quot;Amy Westervelt records a segment at KUNR, the local Reno NPR station.&quot; srcset=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/ab4d5c0f-61e0-49f5-9432-362b544bd11b.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 1x, https://compote.slate.com/images/ab4d5c0f-61e0-49f5-9432-362b544bd11b.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 2x&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy Westervelt records a segment at KUNR, the local Reno NPR station. Westervelt began working in radio after she left the Bay Area for Truckee, California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy Westervelt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgw8x000v3g5txei7iqma@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;72&quot;&gt;Amy Westervelt has also moved in search of a more affordable place to work. Before 2013, she worked as a freelance print reporter in the Bay Area and balanced her reporting income with corporate and ghostwriting clients. Her passion was radio, but she couldn’t take the time away from her paid work to learn audio production. So in 2013, she and her husband and son relocated three hours away to Truckee, California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgw9o000w3g5tynbeba7g@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;103&quot;&gt;Westervelt spent a month as an unpaid intern at the Reno NPR station, “something I would have never been able to do living in Oakland,” before being hired as a staff reporter. Now she hosts three podcasts and has started her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.criticalfrequency.org/&quot;&gt;own podcast production company&lt;/a&gt;. Her spreadsheet calculations show her family living at 60 percent the cost of their life in Oakland (even with the addition of a second kid), and she estimates 50 percent of her work time is now devoted to her passion projects, as compared with a single hour each week—and only on good weeks—as it was in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgwbj000z3g5tod2d9gq7@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;68&quot;&gt;Like Levinson, she’s found career advantages in moving away from the creative nodes. “If you are the only journalist in the region who has worked for national publications, then everyone finds you. People in town come with interesting stories too. There’s this endless pipeline of weird, rural West stories.” She turned one set of “weird rural West stories” into a podcast series, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/range/id1070665252?mt=2&quot;&gt;Range&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, now in its third season.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgwau000x3g5tcg04156d@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;63&quot;&gt;Leaving high-cost cities in pursuit of more affordable places is a trend that is likely to increase as millennials come of age, according to Deirdre Pfeiffer, a professor at Arizona State University who studies housing across the age cycle. Housing is typically the greatest cost for a family, and that cost varies significantly across metro areas. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/resources/budget/budget-map/&quot;&gt;some locations&lt;/a&gt;, the costs are &lt;a href=&quot;https://realestate.usnews.com/real-estate/articles/10-places-with-the-highest-cost-of-living&quot;&gt;staggering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgwbi000y3g5tt8xvjnjt@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;78&quot;&gt;Pfeiffer groups millennials into two types of categories: those that are actively trying to reach adult milestones like having children and buying a home, whom she calls “attempting-adult millenials,” and those that are rejecting or delaying those milestones, which she calls “emerging-adult millennials.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://kinder.rice.edu/research/cementing-millennials-downtown-expressions-and-impacts&quot;&gt;Her research&lt;/a&gt; found that real estate development markets, with their focus on densely packed in large multi-unit buildings, without family-friendly amenities like playgrounds nearby, are catering to emerging-adult millennials while leaving the attempting-adult millennials behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgwc300103g5tjlcvceis@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;42&quot;&gt;“The attempting-adult millenials are struggling to stay in these high-cost cities, but there isn’t the housing to meet their needs,” says Pfeiffer. “The emerging adults can adapt more. [They] don’t mind having roommates, or can live in small spaces or micro apartments.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgwcx00113g5t2mwp4ep4@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;48&quot;&gt;After housing, child care is the second biggest cost for most families and is often cheaper &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newamerica.org/in-depth/care-report/&quot;&gt;outside major metropolitan areas&lt;/a&gt;. In Oakland, day care for just one of Westervelt’s children was $2,000 per month, and in Truckee, both of her children receive child care for $1,000 per month.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;lazy-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image__src&quot; data-normal=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/c8afc62e-504c-4cc1-952d-354fbf6d6ae2.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0&quot; data-retina=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/c8afc62e-504c-4cc1-952d-354fbf6d6ae2.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/c8afc62e-504c-4cc1-952d-354fbf6d6ae2.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 1x, https://compote.slate.com/images/c8afc62e-504c-4cc1-952d-354fbf6d6ae2.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 2x&quot; alt=&quot;Joel Levinson, right, directs a scene for Boy Band with Paul Rondeau, the cinematographer.&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/c8afc62e-504c-4cc1-952d-354fbf6d6ae2.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0&quot; alt=&quot;Joel Levinson, right, directs a scene for Boy Band with Paul Rondeau, the cinematographer.&quot; srcset=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/c8afc62e-504c-4cc1-952d-354fbf6d6ae2.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 1x, https://compote.slate.com/images/c8afc62e-504c-4cc1-952d-354fbf6d6ae2.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;amp;offset=0x0 2x&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joel Levinson, right, directs a scene for &lt;em&gt;Boy Band&lt;/em&gt; with Paul Rondeau, the cinematographer. &lt;em&gt;Boy Band&lt;/em&gt; is Levinson’s first feature film, and produced in Dayton, Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew Collins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgwdd00123g5tr5tlyabn@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;151&quot;&gt;There are advantages to cities with a thriving creative class, like Los Angeles with its concentration of filmmaking or New York with its concentration of publishing, that have abundant niche work and networking opportunities for people within a creative subsection. “Think about how important your professional network is. That is the whole point of cities,” said Pedigo. But Levinson, who has lived in both Los Angeles and New York City, found a similar, albeit smaller creative community in Yellow Springs. “If I am hired to make something in L.A., I can choose between 5,000 DPs [directors of photography]. If you do it in Ohio, you are picking between five to six DPs.” But Levinson says that’s not a bad thing. “You get to know people in the community much more. In L.A. there is a much bigger creative community to lean on, but here you have to be your own engine.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgwdz00133g5tdj401ejy@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;90&quot;&gt;Westervelt berates herself for her “Bay Area snobbery,” which initially colored her perception of Truckee. “I was expecting that people would be backwoods, or restaurants wouldn’t be good. It’s embarrassing to admit that now. They have a kids’ museum here. I went thinking it would be a dump, but it’s amazing. There are a lot of people in various kinds of careers—I thought it was ski bums and people who work at the resorts—but also a large creative class and professional people, and a lot more diversity on every front.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgwel00143g5th8mzekwy@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;74&quot;&gt;Pedigo says the renewed popularity of smaller cities isn’t necessarily a loss for big cities, particularly those with knowledge-based industries that will continue to attract top-tier talent and investment. “If we leave, someone is there to take our seat at the table.” The places that do struggle, he says, are exurban communities that lack economic opportunity and desired amenities but see an inflow of residents who are unable to compete in a knowledge economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph slate-paragraph--tombstone&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjjrlgwf900153g5t7gbtcx0d@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;52&quot;&gt;Levinson views his move as part of a larger effort to restore creative communities in smaller cities. “Creative people make a town more interesting,” he says. In a town of 4,000 people, it takes only two dozen creative people to be that energy. “My hope is that it spreads to other places.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 22:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wallflower</dc:creator>
<og:title>As Cost of Living Rises and Wages Stagnate, Big City Freelancers Look to Small Cities</og:title>
<og:url>https://slate.com/human-interest/2018/07/big-city-freelancers-look-to-small-cities-to-lower-cost-of-living.html</og:url>
<og:description>Why creative work is increasingly taking place outside America’s artistic hubs.</og:description>
<og:image>https://compote.slate.com/images/d0d91ae9-bcad-4378-bebe-f0fd2f396d0c.jpeg?width=780&amp;height=520&amp;rect=1560x1040&amp;offset=0x0</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://slate.com/human-interest/2018/07/big-city-freelancers-look-to-small-cities-to-lower-cost-of-living.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to beat LinkedIn: The Game</title>
<link>https://theoutline.com/post/5495/how-to-beat-linked-in-the-game</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theoutline.com/post/5495/how-to-beat-linked-in-the-game</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Since its founding in 2002, &lt;em&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/em&gt; has quickly become one of the most popular video games of all time. It currently has roughly 530 million users, and was purchased by Microsoft in 2016 for $26.2 billion, the same company that also purchased two other trendy games, &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; (2014) and &lt;em&gt;GitHub&lt;/em&gt; (2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar, &lt;em&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/em&gt; is a 2D, turn-based MMORPG that sets itself apart from its competitors by placing players not in a fantasy world of orcs and goblins, but in the treacherous world of business. Players can choose from dozens of character classes (i.e., Entrepreneurs, Social Media Mavens, Finance Wizards) each with their own skill sets and special moves (Power Lunch; Signal Boost; Invoice Dodge). They gain “experience” by networking, obtaining endorsements from other users, and posting inspirational quotes from Elon Musk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-hyyhMHopfySHrz8UWBfy?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=f34fcc5648daf22c9cb2dc2737e35db3&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-hyyhMHopfySHrz8UWBfy%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Df34fcc5648daf22c9cb2dc2737e35db3?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=c19f16f6beac1657fe8d7bbc4f319e39 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-hyyhMHopfySHrz8UWBfy%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Df34fcc5648daf22c9cb2dc2737e35db3?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=f8d2f100e9a0f25034ac6f9ae0ef0f65 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general goal of &lt;em&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/em&gt; (the game) is to find and connect with as many people on LinkedIn (the website) as possible, in order to secure vaguely defined social capital and potentially further one’s career, which allows the player to purchase consumer goods of gradually increasing quality. Like many games, &lt;a href=&quot;http://college.usatoday.com/2015/03/10/when-it-comes-to-landing-a-job-does-linkedin-actually-matter/&quot;&gt;it has&lt;/a&gt; dubious &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2017/09/01/linkedin-is-nearly-useless-for-actually-getting-a-job/&quot;&gt;real-life utility&lt;/a&gt;. The site’s popularity and success, like that of many social networks, depends heavily on obfuscating this fact. This illusion of importance creates a sense of naive trust among its users. This makes it easy to exploit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To novices, the game appears to be open-ended, and impossible to “beat” in any clearly defined sense. But it is, in fact, possible to win at &lt;em&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/em&gt;. I have done so, and you can too, by following this short strategy guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;true&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-8b3sZYX70JOMa9YJ0efJ?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=552a6b685560562f54e2958a3ba4ca6a&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-8b3sZYX70JOMa9YJ0efJ%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3D552a6b685560562f54e2958a3ba4ca6a?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=92fa94c56200714436f5b6e86c1cf93e 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-8b3sZYX70JOMa9YJ0efJ%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3D552a6b685560562f54e2958a3ba4ca6a?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=67653be531de9a5b6269f28a5374d8bc 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;photo-embed__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;photo-embed__caption__byline&quot;&gt;Box art by Joe Veix&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2&quot;&gt;One: Create The Ultimate Businessman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important part of winning LinkedIn is creating the perfect profile. Set your location to New York, San Francisco, or Los Angeles (the only three cities that matter) — or better yet, just describe yourself as “bi-coastal.” Juke your qualifications with high-powered finance jobs and an ivy league school or two (more on this later). Steal a headshot from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://realbusinessmen.com/&quot;&gt;Real Businessmen Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; to use for your profile photo, and insert stock photos of people shaking hands and taking meetings to both exude power and demonstrate that you’re no stranger to making high-powered deals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-QwO8V9cFg0NoeA0yjlNc?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=a9e6f3b24241d2219392e7ab7c8501a4&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-QwO8V9cFg0NoeA0yjlNc%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Da9e6f3b24241d2219392e7ab7c8501a4?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=2e0ba392f48282d848b13bc373ec9acf 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-QwO8V9cFg0NoeA0yjlNc%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Da9e6f3b24241d2219392e7ab7c8501a4?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=5c0faef8625c9f9096e1dcae4a864dcf 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2&quot;&gt;Two: Connect With Everyone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your profile is in decent shape, you can start connecting with strangers. Unfortunately, LinkedIn limits users to only 30,000 connections, and 3,000 connection requests, so use some discretion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend a few hours each day connecting with people. Start by searching for employees at powerful corporations like Google and Facebook. As users within various spheres of influence accept your connection requests, you will begin to gain legitimacy. At first a few people might decline your request, but eventually, once your network grows, important people will see that others they know are already connected with you, and accept your invitation without suspicion. Work your way through the corporate food chain like an intestinal parasite at a &lt;em&gt;gratis&lt;/em&gt; conference buffet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain users may require you enter their email address in order to “prove” you know them. Don’t panic — these are easy enough to guess. Remember that most people’s email addresses are merely some version of their first and last names, along with “[the company they work for].com” or “gmail.com.” Even better, most people post their email addresses on their own websites, which can be easily found by searching Google and Facebook — the very surveillance software many of them help maintain. Thanks fellas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before long, you will be friends with all of the titans of industry, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/knguyen/status/553411285430566912&quot;&gt;maybe even the bassist of Alien Ant Farm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2&quot;&gt;Three: Spam People’s Feeds With Fake Work Anniversaries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When signing up for LinkedIn, users are encouraged to input their current job, if they have one, along with the month they started, placing themselves into a social hierarchy. Additionally, each year on that starting month, the site will notify (via email and/or in-site alerts) all of a user’s connections of their work anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because there’s no limit to the number of jobs one can have simultaneously, it’s incredibly easy to spam people with superfluous work anniversaries. All you have to do is create 12 active jobs, each with a different starting month. (As far as I can tell, LinkedIn only sends one work anniversary email per user per month, so it’s not worth the trouble to input more than 12.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-EQtaN7P18DMcOT4FhQhF?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=ddf2cb330d5970d53b3dff7745b4e7f0&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-EQtaN7P18DMcOT4FhQhF%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Dddf2cb330d5970d53b3dff7745b4e7f0?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=44488092c413ac86d520136c3d8881cb 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-EQtaN7P18DMcOT4FhQhF%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Dddf2cb330d5970d53b3dff7745b4e7f0?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=fcbd53674e2fbd70770a0e676b29be11 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jobs don’t have to be real. As you can see, I’m currently the Vice President of Butt Communications, the Hot Dog Man at Goldman Sachs, and the Big Bad Pig Boy at Pig Boys, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-DEJLQ18sGYleXgrCGouP?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=170992a9c761dc2993843ad4b1315f8e&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-DEJLQ18sGYleXgrCGouP%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3D170992a9c761dc2993843ad4b1315f8e?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=5f11e45f0f2905fc6a4c233d429da58a 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-DEJLQ18sGYleXgrCGouP%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3D170992a9c761dc2993843ad4b1315f8e?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=245e7156e1533a11ddad98129ddad890 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each month, as the congratulations roll in, and you waste a few seconds of the valuable time of 30,000 or so of the wealthiest and most powerful people in the world, you’ll feel like you really accomplished something. Great work, Pig Boy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2&quot;&gt;Four: Lie, Lie, Lie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn doesn’t (can’t?) fact check every claim on their service, so users can put in anything they want. Which means everyone can get some of the social benefits of an Ivy League education, without any of the student debt. I personally attended both Yale and Harvard at the age of five, double-majoring in farm sciences and “straight A’s.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-guYfpOV0TyRyXgqf3ijH?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=61ac902d8a6ac69856b5d6ea03d63541&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-guYfpOV0TyRyXgqf3ijH%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3D61ac902d8a6ac69856b5d6ea03d63541?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=252e5acaef30f49255fa7de5de0f7457 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-guYfpOV0TyRyXgqf3ijH%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3D61ac902d8a6ac69856b5d6ea03d63541?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=d8338c408c54e46bf107366256f06cce 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weirdly, only one guy ever got suspicious. Shortly after I connected with an eagle-eyed Pulitzer Prize and Emmy nominated journalist/producer (who perhaps was initially fooled by my impressive credentials to accept my request), I received an angry message from him. “Don’t know who you are,” he wrote, “but neither school you list offers the majors or degrees you claim to have so I’m deleting you from my contacts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2&quot;&gt;Five: Engage With Recruiters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, your impressive resume will begin to attract corporate recruiters. For example, someone from Quantcast once emailed me regarding a second LinkedIn account I had set up (Pro Tip: double your connections with two accounts!) under the fake name “Greebo.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-Dsm21Cp3LKp2O8MrnUoC?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=cfd0b4651e6d56205048534017d9bad7&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-Dsm21Cp3LKp2O8MrnUoC%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Dcfd0b4651e6d56205048534017d9bad7?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=24fb35c764d67888697fc3e49f0b46fe 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-Dsm21Cp3LKp2O8MrnUoC%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Dcfd0b4651e6d56205048534017d9bad7?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=8b2962f0af9d7ff4c76d0fe95291bf40 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I missed the initial email, but thankfully, he followed up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-IG6HAuUShRzgvMW8cd9A?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=c0f4cd31f93896b3227702819ee17ade&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-IG6HAuUShRzgvMW8cd9A%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Dc0f4cd31f93896b3227702819ee17ade?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=43fc4f72f84dea5e009dab085800f56a 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-IG6HAuUShRzgvMW8cd9A%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Dc0f4cd31f93896b3227702819ee17ade?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=b08d023d8264f438b8923d756e505f36 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounded like a good opportunity, so I emailed him and tried to set up a meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-mrZdABiOZTKJ01do0PS9?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=0cbe66ad9a270105f77ad9b6a6289df4&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-mrZdABiOZTKJ01do0PS9%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3D0cbe66ad9a270105f77ad9b6a6289df4?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=2332888d3ce0fbc00c4cf16218f086e7 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-mrZdABiOZTKJ01do0PS9%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3D0cbe66ad9a270105f77ad9b6a6289df4?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=ed0f300bce500f9a2336a532580014f8 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably seemed too eager, or my story about my alias was too convoluted. He never responded, and a few days later LinkedIn banned Greebo. I consider this one of my greatest failures. Learn from my mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2&quot;&gt;$ix: $ell $kill Endor$ement$&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn is a business-focused site, so it’s only natural to create a business from it. A few years ago, I saw an opening in the market of skill endorsements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/31888/skill-endorsements-overview?lang=en&quot;&gt;According to LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, the endorsements are “a great way to showcase your abilities to other members.” They can be almost anything, like “Social Media,” “Securities Fraud,” and “TCB (Taking Care of Business).” An endorsement from a major account is a big deal. Since I attended two Ivy League schools simultaneously, I was a hot commodity. So I decided to charge people for my endorsements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, I founded the company LinkedIn Skill Endorsements, and after posting on Twitter that I was charging ten cents for endorsements (a limited time discount from the usual 50 cents), I snagged three customers. I sent them a welcome email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-ECJKmQlagxcALwDgs94J?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=0436fc66f0d21cde0e582aa16edb37e5&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-ECJKmQlagxcALwDgs94J%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3D0436fc66f0d21cde0e582aa16edb37e5?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=eae9825215dbe263864e3c2646b866b8 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-ECJKmQlagxcALwDgs94J%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3D0436fc66f0d21cde0e582aa16edb37e5?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=a7f97e28691b0221dd0b969296ab97c0 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note the highly inflated “change fee.” As soon as their payments were processed in PayPal, I endorsed them for things like “alcoholism,” “horse care,” “blood,” and “solid waste.” Since this is stuff most people wouldn’t want on their resume, they’d be forced to pay me a $10,000 fee to remove the terrible endorsements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed&quot; data-alignment=&quot;&quot; data-text=&quot;true&quot; data-type=&quot;inline&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-embed__image__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Just a few of the author’s many skills&quot; src=&quot;https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-x5lbiwXwGs5H9jMQGl2q?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;s=d49cb053e589e621987993f4e89574f0&quot; srcset=&quot;https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-x5lbiwXwGs5H9jMQGl2q%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Dd49cb053e589e621987993f4e89574f0?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=320&amp;amp;s=b25c64b889c36d9ce56c86c1e15d8dfd 320w, https://im-dev-proxy.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Foutline-prod.imgix.net%2F20180721-x5lbiwXwGs5H9jMQGl2q%3Fauto%3Dformat%26q%3D60%26w%3D1280%26s%3Dd49cb053e589e621987993f4e89574f0?auto=format&amp;amp;q=60&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;s=da147aaabe8e956686b2c63914f149e9 640w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;photo-embed__caption&quot;&gt;Just a few of the author’s many skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, none of them were willing to pay for the SkillChange™ service. One user merely responded in a one-word email that said “unsubscribe” (unfortunately for them, it costs $100 to unlock the unsubscribe service). Ultimately, it turned out the business model was severely flawed, in that users are easily able to delete endorsements. Despite this, my business is a success. In the last four years, I’ve made a whopping $1.20 ($0.53 after fees) by selling endorsements. Now &lt;em&gt;that’s&lt;/em&gt; how you business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;hr&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, these are just a few sample strategies for defeating &lt;em&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/em&gt;. I can’t give away all my secrets for free. If you’d like to receive my full course, and learn how to make a huge profit on LinkedIn without even leaving your home, please send $10,000 via PayPal to definitelynotascam420@gmail.com. Don’t worry — it’s definitely not a scam.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 18:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>davydog187</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://theoutline.com/post/5495/how-to-beat-linked-in-the-game</og:url>
<og:title>How to beat LinkedIn: The Game</og:title>
<og:description>A strategy guide for using a semi-pointless social network in all the wrong ways.</og:description>
<og:image>https://outline-prod.imgix.net/20180721-8b3sZYX70JOMa9YJ0efJ?auto=format&amp;q=60&amp;w=1280&amp;s=552a6b685560562f54e2958a3ba4ca6a</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theoutline.com/post/5495/how-to-beat-linked-in-the-game</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ecuador will hand over Julian Assange to the UK</title>
<link>https://theintercept.com/2018/07/21/ecuador-will-imminently-withdraw-asylum-for-julian-assange-and-hand-him-over-to-the-uk-what-comes-next/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theintercept.com/2018/07/21/ecuador-will-imminently-withdraw-asylum-for-julian-assange-and-hand-him-over-to-the-uk-what-comes-next/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ecuador’s President&lt;/u&gt; Lenin Moreno traveled to London on Friday for the ostensible purpose of speaking at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.internationaldisabilityalliance.org/summit&quot;&gt;2018 Global Disabilities Summit&lt;/a&gt; (Moreno has been using a wheelchair since being shot in a 1998 robbery attempt). The concealed, actual purpose of the president’s trip is to meet with British officials to finalize an agreement under which Ecuador will withdraw its asylum protection of Julian Assange, in place since 2012, eject him from the Ecuadorian Embassy in London, and then hand over the WikiLeaks founder to British authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreno’s itinerary also notably includes a trip to Madrid, where he will meet with Spanish officials &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/may/16/julian-assange-ecuador-spain-catalan-independence-meeting-separatists&quot;&gt;still seething over&lt;/a&gt; Assange’s denunciation of human rights abuses perpetrated by Spain’s central government against protesters marching for Catalonian independence. Almost three months ago, Ecuador &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/ecuadoran-embassy-in-london-cuts-off-julian-assanges-internet/2018/03/28/10322e9c-32ae-11e8-b6bd-0084a1666987_story.html?utm_term=.60d667f9234b&quot;&gt;blocked Assange&lt;/a&gt; from accessing the internet, and Assange has not been able to communicate with the outside world ever since. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelocal.es/20171217/assange-told-not-to-interfere-in-catalonia-ecuador-president&quot;&gt;primary factor&lt;/a&gt; in Ecuador’s decision to silence him was Spanish anger over Assange’s tweets about Catalonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-200901&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/07/moreno-1532182328.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=669&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Presidential decree signed on July 17 by Ecuadorian President Lenin Moreno, outlining his trip to London and Madrid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A source close to the Ecuadorian Foreign Ministry and the president’s office, unauthorized to speak publicly, has confirmed to The Intercept that Moreno is close to finalizing, if he has not already finalized, an agreement to hand over Assange to the U.K. within the next several weeks. The withdrawal of asylum and physical ejection of Assange could come as early as this week. On Friday, RT &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rt.com/news/433783-wikileaks-assange-ecuador-uk/&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that Ecuador was preparing to enter into such an agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consequences of such an agreement depend in part on the concessions Ecuador extracts in exchange for withdrawing Assange’s asylum. But as former Ecuadorian President Rafael Correa &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/05/16/ecuadors-ex-president-rafael-correa-denounces-treatment-of-julian-assange-as-torture/&quot;&gt;told The Intercept&lt;/a&gt; in an interview in May, Moreno’s government has returned Ecuador to a highly “subservient” and “submissive” posture toward western governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is thus highly unlikely that Moreno — who has shown himself willing to submit to threats and coercion from the U.K., Spain and the U.S. — will obtain a guarantee that the U.K. not extradite Assange to the U.S., where top Trump officials have vowed to prosecute Assange and destroy WikiLeaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central oddity of Assange’s case — that he has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/wikileaks/8579350/WikiLeaks-Julian-Assanges-excessive-and-dehumanising-house-arrest.html&quot;&gt;effectively imprisoned for eight years&lt;/a&gt; despite never having been charged with, let alone convicted of, any crime — is virtually certain to be prolonged once Ecuador hands him over to the U.K. Even under the best-case scenario, it appears highly likely that Assange will continue to be imprisoned by British authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only known criminal proceeding Assange currently faces is a pending 2012 arrest warrant for “failure to surrender” — basically a minor bail violation that arose when he obtained asylum from Ecuador rather than complying with bail conditions by returning to court for a hearing on his attempt to resist extradition to Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That offense &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentencingcouncil.org.uk/offences/item/bail-failure-to-surrender/&quot;&gt;carries a prison term&lt;/a&gt; of three months and a fine, though it is possible that the time Assange has already spent in prison in the U.K. could be counted against that sentence. In 2010, Assange was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2010/12/17/world/europe/17assange.html&quot;&gt;imprisoned in Wandsworth Prison&lt;/a&gt;, kept in isolation, for 10 days until he was released on bail; he was then under house arrest for 550 days at the home of a supporter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assange’s lawyer, Jen Robinson, told The Intercept that he would argue that all of that prison time already served should count toward (and thus completely fulfill) any prison term imposed on the “failure to surrender” charge, though British prosecutors would almost certainly contest that claim. Assange would also argue that he had a reasonable, valid basis for seeking asylum rather than submitting to U.K. authorities: namely, well-grounded fear that he would be extradited to the U.S. for prosecution for the act of publishing documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond that minor charge, British prosecutors could argue that Assange’s evading of legal process in the U.K. was so protracted, intentional and malicious that it rose beyond mere “failure to surrender” to “contempt of court,” which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/1981/49/crossheading/penalties-for-contempt-and-kindred-offences&quot;&gt;carries a prison term&lt;/a&gt; of up to two years. Just on those charges alone, then, Assange faces a high risk of detention for another year or even longer in a British prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, that is the only known criminal proceeding Assange faces. In May 2017, Swedish prosecutors &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2017/05/19/sweden-withdraws-arrest-warrant-for-julian-assange-but-he-still-faces-serious-legal-jeopardy/&quot;&gt;announced they were closing&lt;/a&gt; their investigation into the sexual assault allegations due to the futility of proceeding in light of Assange’s asylum and the time that has elapsed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;The far more important&lt;/u&gt; question that will determine Assange’s future is what the U.S. government intends to do. The Obama administration was eager to prosecute Assange and WikiLeaks for publishing hundreds of thousands of classified documents, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/julian-assange-unlikely-to-face-us-charges-over-publishing-classified-documents/2013/11/25/dd27decc-55f1-11e3-8304-caf30787c0a9_story.html?utm_term=.710506f98e0c&quot;&gt;ultimately concluded&lt;/a&gt; that there was no way to do so without either also prosecuting newspapers such as the New York Times and The Guardian, which published the same documents, or creating precedents that would enable the criminal prosecution of media outlets in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, it is technically a crime under U.S. law for anyone — including a media outlet — to publish certain types of classified information. Under U.S. law, for instance, it &lt;a&gt;was a felony&lt;/a&gt; for the Washington Post’s David Ignatius &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/why-did-obama-dawdle-on-russias-hacking/2017/01/12/75f878a0-d90c-11e6-9a36-1d296534b31e_story.html?utm_term=.05839fdc78c4&quot;&gt;to report on the contents&lt;/a&gt; of telephone calls, intercepted by the NSA, between then National Security Adviser nominee Michael Flynn and Russian Ambassador Sergey Kislyak, even though such reporting was clearly in the public interest since it proved Flynn lied when he denied such contacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That the Washington Post and Ignatius — and not merely their sources — violated U.S. criminal law by revealing the contents of intercepted communications with a Russian official is made clear by the text of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/798&quot;&gt;18 § 798 of the U.S. Code&lt;/a&gt;, which provides (emphasis added):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Whoever knowingly and willfully communicates&lt;/em&gt; … or otherwise makes available to an unauthorized person, &lt;em&gt;or publishes&lt;/em&gt; … any classified information … obtained by the processes of communication intelligence from the communications of any foreign government … shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the U.S. Justice Department has never wanted to indict and prosecute anyone for the crime of &lt;em&gt;publishing&lt;/em&gt; such material, contenting themselves instead to prosecuting the government sources who leak it. Their reluctance has been due to two reasons: First, media outlets would argue that any attempts to criminalize the mere &lt;em&gt;publication&lt;/em&gt; of classified or stolen documents is barred by the press freedom guarantee of the First Amendment, a proposition the DOJ has never wanted to test; second, no DOJ has wanted as part of its legacy the creation of a precedent that allows the U.S. government to criminally prosecute journalists and media outlets for reporting classified documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Trump administration has made clear that they have no such concerns. Quite the contrary: Last April, Trump’s then-CIA Director Mike Pompeo, now his secretary of state, &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2017/04/14/trumps-cia-director-pompeo-targeting-wikileaks-explicitly-threatens-speech-and-press-freedoms/&quot;&gt;delivered a deranged, rambling, highly threatening broadside&lt;/a&gt; against WikiLeaks. Without citing any evidence, Pompeo decreed that WikiLeaks is “a non-state hostile intelligence service often abetted by state actors like Russia,” and thus declared: “We have to recognize that we can no longer allow Assange and his colleagues &lt;em&gt;the latitude to use free speech values against us&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The longtime right-wing congressman, now one of Trump’s most loyal and favored cabinet officials, also explicitly rejected any First Amendment concerns about prosecuting Assange, arguing that while WikiLeaks “pretended that America’s First Amendment freedoms shield them from justice … they may have believed that, but they are wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pompeo then issued this bold threat: “To give them the space to crush us with misappropriated secrets is a perversion of what our great Constitution stands for. It ends now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/0067wS26n_E?start=90&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Trump’s Attorney General Jeff Sessions has similarly vowed not only to continue and expand the Obama DOJ’s crackdown on sources, but also to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-trump-sessions-leaks/trump-administration-goes-on-attack-against-leakers-journalists-idUSKBN1AK1UR&quot;&gt;consider the prosecution of media outlets&lt;/a&gt; that publish classified information. It would be incredibly shrewd for Sessions to lay the foundation for doing so by prosecuting Assange first, safe in the knowledge that journalists themselves — consumed with hatred for Assange due to personal reasons, professional jealousies, and anger over the role they believed he played in 2016 in helping Hillary Clinton lose — would unite &lt;em&gt;behind the Trump DOJ and in support of its efforts to imprison Assange.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;During the Obama years, it was a mainstream view among media outlets that prosecuting Assange would be a serious danger to press freedoms. Even the Washington Post editorial page, which vehemently condemned WikiLeaks, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2010/12/11/AR2010121102564.html&quot;&gt;warned in 2010&lt;/a&gt; that any such prosecution would “criminalize the exchange of information and put at risk” all media outlets. When Pompeo and Sessions last year issued their threats to prosecute Assange, former Obama DOJ spokesperson Matthew Miller insisted that no such prosecution could ever succeed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/07/miller-1532187183.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-200910&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/07/miller-1532187183.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=440&amp;amp;h=365&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;For years, the Obama DOJ searched for evidence that Assange actively assisted Chelsea Manning or other sources in the hacking or stealing of documents — in order to prosecute them for more than merely publishing documents — and found no such evidence. But even that theory — that a publisher of classified documents can be prosecuted for assisting a source — would be a severe threat to press freedom, since journalists frequently work in some form of collaboration with sources who remove or disclose classified information. And nobody has ever presented evidence that WikiLeaks conspired with whomever hacked the DNC and Podesta email inboxes to effectuate that hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;But there seems little question that, as Sessions surely knows, large numbers of U.S. journalists — along with many, perhaps most, Democrats — would actually support the Trump DOJ in prosecuting Assange for publishing documents. After all, the DNC &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/04/20/the-dncs-lawsuit-against-wikileaks-poses-a-serious-threat-to-press-freedom/&quot;&gt;sued WikiLeaks in April &lt;em&gt;for publishing documents&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — a serious, obvious threat to press freedom — and few objected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;And it was Democratic senators &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052748703989004575653280626335258&quot;&gt;such as Dianne Feinstein&lt;/a&gt; who, during the Obama years, were urging the prosecution of WikiLeaks, with the support of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/blogs/under-the-radar/2010/12/bond-and-feinstein-urge-prosecution-of-wikileaks-julian-assange-031148&quot;&gt;numerous GOP senators&lt;/a&gt;. There is no doubt that, after 2016, support among both journalists and Democrats for imprisoning Assange for publishing documents would be higher than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;If the U.S. did indict&lt;/u&gt; Assange for alleged crimes relating to the publication of documents, or if they have already obtained a sealed indictment, and then uses that indictment to request that the U.K. extradite him to the U.S. to stand trial, that alone would ensure that Assange remains in prison in the U.K. for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assange would, of course, resist any such extradition on the ground that publishing documents is not a cognizable crime and that the U.S is seeking his extradition for political charges that, by treaty, cannot serve as the basis for extradition. But it would take at least a year, and probably closer to three years, for U.K. courts to decide these extradition questions. And while all of that lingers, Assange would almost certainly be in prison, given that it is inconceivable that a British judge would release Assange on bail given what happened the last time he was released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this means that it is highly likely that Assange — under &lt;em&gt;his best-case scenario&lt;/em&gt; — faces at least another year in prison, and will end up having spent a decade in prison despite never having been charged with, let alone convicted of, any crime. He has essentially been punished — imprisoned — by process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while it is often argued that Assange has only himself to blame, it is beyond doubt, given the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.salon.com/2011/04/27/wikileaks_26/&quot;&gt;grand jury convened&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/2011/may/11/us-opens-wikileaks-grand-jury-hearing&quot;&gt;the Obama DOJ&lt;/a&gt; and now the threats of Pompeo and Sessions, that the fear that led Assange to seek asylum in the first place — being extradited to the U.S. and politically persecuted for political crimes — was well-grounded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assange, his lawyers and his supporters always said that he would immediately board a plane to Stockholm if he were guaranteed that doing so would not be used to extradite him to the U.S., and for years offered to be questioned by Swedish investigators inside the embassy in London, something Swedish prosecutors only did years later. Citing those facts, a United Nations panel &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/2016/feb/04/julian-assange-wikileaks-arrest-friday-un-investigation&quot;&gt;ruled in 2016&lt;/a&gt; that the actions of the U.K. government constituted “arbitrary detention” and a violation of Assange’s fundamental human rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if, as seems quite likely, the Trump administration finally announces that it intends to prosecute Assange for publishing classified U.S. government documents, we will be faced with the bizarre spectacle of U.S. journalists — who have spent the last two years melodramatically expressing grave concern over press freedom due to insulting tweets from Donald Trump about Wolf Blitzer and Chuck Todd or his mean treatment of Jim Acosta — possibly cheering for a precedent that would be the gravest press freedom threat in decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That precedent would be one that could easily be used to put them in a prison cell alongside Assange for the new “crime” of publishing any documents that the U.S. government has decreed should not be published. When it comes to press freedom threats, such an indictment would not be in the same universe as name-calling tweets by Trump directed at various TV personalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to denouncing due process denials and the use of torture at Guantanamo, it was not difficult for journalists to set aside their personal dislike for Al Qaeda sympathizers to denounce the dangers of those human rights and legal abuses. When it comes to free speech assaults, journalists are able to set aside their personal contempt for a person’s opinions to oppose the precedent that the government can punish people for expressing noxious ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should not be this difficult for journalists to set aside their personal emotions about Assange to recognize the profound dangers — not just to press freedoms but to themselves — if the U.S. government succeeds in keeping Assange imprisoned for years to come, all due to its attempts to prosecute him for publishing classified or stolen documents. That seems the highly likely scenario once Ecuador hands over Assange to the U.K.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 16:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sosa2k</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://theintercept.com/2018/07/21/ecuador-will-imminently-withdraw-asylum-for-julian-assange-and-hand-him-over-to-the-uk-what-comes-next/</og:url>
<og:description>Will journalists, due to hatred of Assange, unite behind the Trump DOJ in support of one of the gravest threats to press freedom in years?</og:description>
<og:image>https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2016/02/GettyImages-508571640.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;q=90&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;h=800</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Ecuador Will Imminently Withdraw Asylum for Julian Assange and Hand Him Over to the U.K. What Comes Next?</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theintercept.com/2018/07/21/ecuador-will-imminently-withdraw-asylum-for-julian-assange-and-hand-him-over-to-the-uk-what-comes-next/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Psychedelics Promote Structural and Functional Neural Plasticity</title>
<link>https://www.cell.com/cell-reports/fulltext/S2211-1247(18)30755-1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cell.com/cell-reports/fulltext/S2211-1247(18)30755-1</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cell.com/cell-reports/fulltext/S2211-1247(18)30755-1&quot;&gt;https://www.cell.com/cell-reports/fulltext/S2211-1247(18)30755-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17582238&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17582238&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 275&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 136&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 15:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lainon</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://theintercept.com/2018/07/21/ecuador-will-imminently-withdraw-asylum-for-julian-assange-and-hand-him-over-to-the-uk-what-comes-next/</og:url>
<og:description>Will journalists, due to hatred of Assange, unite behind the Trump DOJ in support of one of the gravest threats to press freedom in years?</og:description>
<og:image>https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2016/02/GettyImages-508571640.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;q=90&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;h=800</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Ecuador Will Imminently Withdraw Asylum for Julian Assange and Hand Him Over to the U.K. What Comes Next?</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theintercept.com/2018/07/21/ecuador-will-imminently-withdraw-asylum-for-julian-assange-and-hand-him-over-to-the-uk-what-comes-next/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>