<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Creating a Modern OCR Pipeline Using Computer Vision and Deep Learning</title>
<link>https://blogs.dropbox.com/tech/2017/04/creating-a-modern-ocr-pipeline-using-computer-vision-and-deep-learning/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blogs.dropbox.com/tech/2017/04/creating-a-modern-ocr-pipeline-using-computer-vision-and-deep-learning/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In this post we will take you behind the scenes on how we built a state-of-the-art Optical Character Recognition (OCR) pipeline for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.dropbox.com/dropbox/2016/06/new-dropbox-productivity-tools/&quot;&gt;mobile document scanner&lt;/a&gt;. We used computer vision and deep learning advances such as bi-directional Long Short Term Memory (LSTMs), Connectionist Temporal Classification (CTC), convolutional neural nets (CNNs), and more. In addition, we will also dive deep into what it took to actually make our OCR pipeline production-ready at Dropbox scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://dropboxmainblog.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/document-scanning.gif?w=650&amp;amp;h=325&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;325&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://dropboxmainblog.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/document-scanning.gif?w=650&amp;amp;h=325&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;325&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.dropbox.com/tech/tag/doc-scanner/&quot;&gt;previous posts&lt;/a&gt; we have described how Dropbox’s mobile document scanner works. The document scanner makes it possible to use your mobile phone to take photos and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.dropbox.com/dropbox/2016/06/new-dropbox-productivity-tools/&quot;&gt;“&lt;/a&gt;scan” items like receipts and invoices. Our mobile document scanner only outputs an image — any text in the image is just a set of pixels as far as the computer is concerned, and can’t be copy-pasted, searched for, or any of the other things you can do with text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence the need to apply Optical Character Recognition, or OCR. This process extracts actual text from our doc-scanned image. Once OCR is run, we can then enable the following features for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/business&quot;&gt;Dropbox Business&lt;/a&gt; users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Extract all the text in scanned documents and index it, so that it can be searched for later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a hidden overlay so text can be copied and pasted from the scans saved as PDFs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we built the first version of the mobile document scanner, we used a commercial off-the-shelf OCR library, in order to do product validation before diving too deep into creating our own machine learning-based OCR system. This meant integrating the commercial system into our scanning pipeline, offering both features above to our business users to see if they found sufficient use from the OCR. Once we confirmed that there was indeed strong user demand for the mobile document scanner and OCR, we decided to build our own in-house OCR system for several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there was a cost consideration: having our own OCR system would save us significant money as the licensed commercial OCR SDK charged us based on the number of scans. Second, the commercial system was tuned for the traditional OCR world of images from flat bed scanners, whereas our operating scenario was much tougher, because mobile phone photos are far more unconstrained, with crinkled or curved documents, shadows and uneven lighting, blurriness and reflective highlights, etc. Thus, there might be an opportunity for us to improve recognition accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, a sea change has happened in the world of computer vision that gave us a unique opportunity. Traditionally, OCR systems were heavily pipelined, with hand-built and highly-tuned modules taking advantage of all kinds of conditions they could assume to be true for images captured using a flatbed scanner. For example, one module might find lines of text, then the next module would find words and segment letters, then another module might apply different techniques to each piece of a character to figure out what the character is, etc. Most methods rely on binarization of the input image as an early stage, and this can be brittle and discards important cues. The process to build these OCR systems was very specialized and labor intensive, and the systems could generally only work with fairly constrained imagery from flat bed scanners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last few years has seen the successful application of deep learning to numerous problems in computer vision that have given us powerful new tools for tackling OCR without having to replicate the complex processing pipelines of the past, relying instead on large quantities of data to have the system automatically learn how to do many of the previously manually-designed steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most important reason for building our own system is that it would give us more control over own destiny, and allow us to work on more innovative features in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the rest of this blog post we will take you behind the scenes of how we built this pipeline at Dropbox scale. Most commercial machine learning projects follow three major steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Research and prototyping to see if something is possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Productionization of the model for actual end users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refinement of the system in the real world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will take you through each of these steps in turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our initial task was to see if we could even build a state of the art OCR system at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began by collecting a representative set of donated document images that match what users might upload, such as receipts, invoices, letters, etc. To gather this set, we asked a small percentage of users whether they would donate some of their image files for us to improve our algorithms. At Dropbox, we take user privacy very seriously and thus made it clear that this was completely optional, and if donated, the files would be kept private and secure. We use a wide variety of safety precautions with such user-donated data, including never keeping donated data on local machines in permanent storage, maintaining extensive auditing, requiring strong authentication to access any of it, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important, machine learning-specific component for user-donated data is how to label it. Most current machine learning techniques are &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supervised_learning&quot;&gt;strongly-supervised&lt;/a&gt;, meaning that they require explicit manual labeling of input data so that the algorithms can learn to make predictions themselves. Traditionally, this labeling is done by outside workers, often using a micro-work platform such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mturk.com/mturk/welcome&quot;&gt;Amazon’s Mechanical Turk&lt;/a&gt; (MTurk). However, a downside to using MTurk is that each item might be seen and labeled by a different worker, and we certainly don’t want to expose user-donated data in the wild like this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, our team at Dropbox created our own platform for data annotation, named DropTurk. DropTurk can submit labeling jobs either to MTurk (if we are dealing with public non-user data) or a small pool of hired contractors for user-donated data. These contractors are under a strict non-disclosure agreement (NDA) to ensure that they cannot keep or share any of the data they label. DropTurk contains a standard list of annotation task UI templates that we can rapidly assemble and customize for new datasets and labeling tasks, which enables us to annotate our datasets quite fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, here is a DropTurk UI meant to provide ground truth data for individual word images, including one of the following options for the workers to complete:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Transcribing the actual text in an image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marking whether the word is oriented incorrectly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marking whether it’s a non-English script&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marking whether it’s unreadable or contains no text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1490394894991_file.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1490394894991_file.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DropTurk UI for adding ground truth data for word images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our DropTurk platform includes dashboards to get an overview of past jobs, watch the progress of current jobs, and access the results securely. In addition, we can get analytics to assess workers’ performance, even getting worker-level graphical monitoring of annotations of ongoing jobs to catch potential issues early on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_210A512EACB734A568AA42939567DF61F69F9A67776880720B996DF23C4CF340_1491511809318_DropTurk-censored.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_210A512EACB734A568AA42939567DF61F69F9A67776880720B996DF23C4CF340_1491511809318_DropTurk-censored.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DropTurk Dashboard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using DropTurk, we collected both a word-level dataset, which has images of individual words and their annotated text, as well as a full document-level dataset, which has images of full documents (like receipts) and fully transcribed text. We used the latter to measure the accuracy of existing state-of-the-art OCR systems; this would then inform our efforts by telling us the score we would have to meet or beat for our own system. On this particular dataset, the accuracy percentage we had to achieve was in the mid-90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first task was to determine if the OCR problem was even going to be solvable in a reasonable amount of time. So we broke the OCR problem into two pieces. First, we would use computer vision to take an image of a document and segment it into lines and words; we call that the Word Detector. Then, we would take each word and feed it into a deep net to turn the word image into actual text; we call that the Word Deep Net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We felt that the Word Detector would be relatively straightforward, and so focused our efforts first on the Word Deep Net, which we were less sure about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;word-deep-net&quot;&gt;Word Deep Net&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word Deep Net combines neural network architectures used in computer vision and automatic speech recognition systems. Images of cropped words are fed into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network&quot;&gt;Convolutional Neural Net (CNN)&lt;/a&gt; with several &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network&quot;&gt;convolutional layers&lt;/a&gt;. The visual features that are output by the CNN are then fed as a sequence to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bidirectional_recurrent_neural_networks&quot;&gt;Bidirectional LSTM&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_short-term_memory&quot;&gt;Long Short Term Memory&lt;/a&gt;) — common in speech recognition systems — which make sense of our word “pieces,” and finally arrives at a text prediction using a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.toronto.edu/~graves/icml_2006.pdf&quot;&gt;Connectionist Temporal Classification (CTC)&lt;/a&gt; layer. &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1502.03167&quot;&gt;Batch Normalization&lt;/a&gt; is used where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1490396191936_file.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1490396191936_file.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCR Word Deep Net&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we had decided on this network architecture for turning an image of a single word into text, we then needed to figure out how to collect enough data to train it. Deep learning systems typically need huge amounts of training data to achieve good recognition performance; in fact, the amount of training data is often the most significant bottleneck in current systems. Normally, all this data has to be collected and then labeled manually, a time-consuming and expensive process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative is to programmatically generate training data. However, in most computer vision problems it’s currently too difficult to generate realistic-enough images for training algorithms: the variety of imaging environments and transformations is too varied to effectively simulate. (One promising area of current research is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_adversarial_networks&quot;&gt;Generative Adversarial Networks&lt;/a&gt; (GANs), which seem to be well-suited to generating realistic data.) Fortunately, our problem in this case is a perfect match for using synthetic data, since the types of images we need to generate are quite constrained and can thus be rendered automatically. Unlike images of natural or most manmade objects, documents and their text are synthetic and the variability of individual characters is relatively limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our synthetic data pipeline consists of three pieces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;A corpus with words to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A collection of fonts for drawing the words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A set of geometric and photometric transformations meant to simulate real world distortions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The generation algorithm simply samples from each of these to create a unique training example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1489522702588_file.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1489522702588_file.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synthetically generated word images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started simply with all three, with words coming from a collection of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gutenberg.org/&quot;&gt;Project Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt; books from the 19th century, about a thousand fonts we collected, and some simple distortions like rotations, underlines, and blurs. We generated about a million synthetic words, trained our deep net, and then tested our accuracy, which was around 79%. That was okay, but not good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through many iterations, we evolved each piece of our synthetic data pipeline in many ways to improve the recognition accuracy. Some highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We noticed that we weren’t doing well on receipts, so we expanded our word corpus to include the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Product_Code&quot;&gt;Uniform Product Code&lt;/a&gt; (UPC) database, which has entries like “24QT TISSUE PAPER” which commonly occur on receipts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We noticed the network was struggling with letters with disconnected segments. This revealed a deeper problem: receipts are often printed with thermal fonts that have stippled, disconnected, or ink smudged letters, but our network had only been given training data with smooth continuous fonts (like from a laser printer) or lightly bit-mapped characters (like in a screenshot). To address this shortcoming, we eventually tracked down a font vendor in China who could provide us with representative ancient thermal printer fonts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1489522804692_file.png&quot; width=&quot;686&quot; height=&quot;54&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1489522804692_file.png&quot; width=&quot;686&quot; height=&quot;54&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synthetically generated words using different thermal printer fonts, common in receipts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Our font selection procedure was too naive initially. We ended up hand-selecting about 2,000 fonts. Not all fonts are used equally. So, we did research on the top 50 fonts in the world and created a font frequency system that allowed us to sample from common fonts (such as Helvetica or Times New Roman) more frequently, while still retaining a long tail of rare fonts (such as some ornate logo fonts). In addition, we discovered that some fonts have incorrect symbols or limited support, resulting in just squares, or their lower or upper case letters are mismatched and thus incorrect. We had to go through all two thousand fonts by hand and mark those that had invalid symbols, numbers, or casing, so that we didn’t inadvertently train the network with incorrect data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The upstream Word Detector (described later) was tuned to provide high recall and low precision. It was overzealous in finding text in images so that it wouldn’t miss any of the actual text (high recall) at the expense of often “finding” words that weren’t actually there (low precision). This meant that the Word Deep Net had to deal with a very large number of essentially empty images with noise. So we had our synthetic data pipeline generate representative negative training examples with empty ground truth strings, including common textured backgrounds, like wood, marble countertops, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1489523002348_file.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1489523002348_file.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synthetically generated negative training examples&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;From a histogram of the synthetically generated words, we discovered that many symbols were underrepresented, such as / or &amp;amp;. We artificially boosted the frequency of these in our synthetic corpus, by synthetically generating representative dates, prices, URLs, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We added a large number of visual transformations, such as warping, fake shadows, and fake creases, and much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1489523118327_file.png&quot; width=&quot;262&quot; height=&quot;52&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1489523118327_file.png&quot; width=&quot;262&quot; height=&quot;52&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fake shadow effect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is as important as the machine learning model used, so we spent a great deal of time refining this data generation pipeline. At some point, we will open source and release this synthetically generated data for others to train and validate their own systems and research on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We trained our network on Amazon EC2 G2 GPU instances, spinning up many experiments in parallel. All of our experiments went into a lab notebook that included everything necessary to replicate experiments so we could track unexpected accuracy bumps or losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab notebook contained numbered experiments, with the most recent experiment first. It tracked everything needed for machine learning &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/blog/reproducible-research&quot;&gt;reproducibility&lt;/a&gt;, such as a unique git hash for the code that was used, pointers to &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/s3/&quot;&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt; with generated data sets and results, evaluation results, graphs, a high-level description of the goal of that experiment, and more. As we built our synthetic data pipeline and trained our network, we also built many special purpose tools to visualize fonts, debug network guesses, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1490402580761_file.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1490402580761_file.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example early experiment tracking error rate vs. how long our Word Deep Net had trained, against an evaluation dataset that consisted of just single words (Single Word Accuracy)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our early experiments tracked how well Word Deep Net did on OCR-ing images of single words, which we called Single Word Accuracy (SWA). Accuracy in this context meant how many of the ground truth words the deep net got right. In addition, we tracked precision and recall for the network. Precision refers to the fraction of words returned by the deep net that were actually correct, while recall refers to the fraction of evaluation data that is correctly predicted by the deep net. There tends to be a tradeoff between precision and recall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, imagine we have a machine learning model that is designed to classify an email as spam or not. Precision would be whether all the things that were labeled as spam by the classifier, how many were actually spam? Recall, in contrast, would be whether of all the things that truly are spam, how many did we label? It is possible to correctly label spam emails (high precision) while not actually labeling all the true spam emails (low recall).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week over week, we tracked how well we were doing. We divided our dataset into different categories, such as &lt;code&gt;register_tapes&lt;/code&gt; (receipts), &lt;code&gt;screenshots&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;scanned_docs&lt;/code&gt;, etc., and computed accuracies both individually for each category and overall across all data. For example, the entry below shows early work in our lab notebook for our first full end-to-end test, with a real Word Detector coupled to our real Word Deep Net. You can see that we did pretty terribly at the start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1490403314138_file.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1490403314138_file.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshot from early end-to-end experiments in our lab notebook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a certain point our synthetic data pipeline was resulting in a Single Word Accuracy (SWA) percentage in the high-80s on our OCR benchmark set, and we decided we were done with that portion. We then collected about 20,000 real images of words (compared to our 1 million synthetically generated words) and used these to fine tune the Word Deep Net. This took us to an SWA in the mid-90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now had a system that could do very well on individual word images, but of course a real OCR system operates on images of entire documents. Our next step was to focus on the document-level Word Detector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;word-detector&quot;&gt;Word Detector&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our Word Detector we decided to not use a deep net-based approach. The primary candidates for such approaches were object detection systems, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbgirshick/rcnn&quot;&gt;RCNN&lt;/a&gt;, that try to detect the locations (bounding boxes) of objects like dogs, cats, or plants from images. Most images only have perhaps one to five instances of a given object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, most documents don’t just have a handful of words — they have hundreds or even thousands of them, i.e., a few orders of magnitude more objects than most neural network-based object detection systems were capable of finding at the time. We were thus not sure that such algorithms would scale up to the level our OCR system needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important consideration was that traditional computer vision approaches using feature detectors might be easier to debug, as neural networks as notoriously opaque and have internal representations that are hard to understand and interpret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up using a classic computer vision approach named &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maximally_stable_extremal_regions&quot;&gt;Maximally Stable Extremal Regions&lt;/a&gt; (MSERs), using &lt;a href=&quot;http://opencv.org/&quot;&gt;OpenCV&lt;/a&gt;’s implementation. The MSER algorithm finds connected regions at different thresholds, or levels, of the image. Essentially, they detect blobs in images, and are thus particularly good for text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Word Detector first detects MSER features in an image, then strings these together into word and line detections. One tricky aspect is that our word deep net accepts fixed size word image inputs. This requires the word detector to thus sometimes include more than one word in a single detection box, or chop a single word in half if it is too long to fit the deep net’s input size. Information on this chopping then has to be propagated through the entire pipeline, so that we can re-assemble it after the deep net has run. Another bit of trickiness is dealing with images with white text on dark backgrounds, as opposed to dark text on white backgrounds, forcing our MSER detector to be able to handle both scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;combined-end-to-end-system&quot;&gt;Combined End-to-End System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we had refined our Word Detector to an acceptable point, we chained it together with our Word Deep Net so that we could benchmark the entire combined system end-to-end against document-level images rather than our older Single Word Accuracy benchmarking suite. However, when we first measured the end-to-end accuracy, we found that we were performing around 44% — quite a bit worse than the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary issues were spacing and spurious garbage text from noise in the image. Sometimes we would incorrectly combine two words, such as “&lt;em&gt;helloworld”&lt;/em&gt;, or incorrectly fragment a single word, such as “&lt;em&gt;wo rld”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our solution was to modify the Connectionist Temporal Classification (CTC) layer of the network to also give us a confidence score in addition to the predicted text. We then used this confidence score to bucket predictions in three ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If the confidence was high, we kept the prediction as is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the confidence was low, we simply filtered them out, making a bet that these were noise predictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the confidence was somewhere in the middle, we then ran it through a lexicon generated from the Oxford English Dictionary, applying different transformations between and within word prediction boxes, attempting to combine words or split them in various ways to see if they were in the lexicon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also had to deal with issues caused by the previously mentioned fixed receptive image size of the Word Deep Net: namely, that a single “word” window might actually contain multiple words or only part of a very long word. We thus run these outputs along with the original outputs from the Word Detector through a module we call the Wordinator, which gives discrete bounding boxes for each individual OCRed word. This results in individual word coordinates along with their OCRed text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the following debug visualization from our system you can see boxes around detected words before the Wordinator:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1490404408762_file.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1490404408762_file.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wordinator will break some of these boxes into individual word coordinate boxes, such as “of” and “Engineering”, which are currently part of the same box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, now that we had a fully working end-to-end system, we generated more than ten million synthetic words and trained our neural net for a very large number of iterations to squeeze out as much accuracy as we could. All of this finally gave us the accuracy, precision, and recall numbers that all met or exceeded the OCR state-of-the-art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We briefly patted ourselves on the back, then began to prepare for the next tough stage: productionization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we had a collection of prototype Python and Lua scripts wrapping Torch — and a trained model, of course! — that showed that we could achieve state of the art OCR accuracy. However, this is a long way from a system an actual user can use in a distributed setting with reliability, performance, and solid engineering. We needed to create a distributed pipeline suitable for use by millions of users and a system replacing our prototype scripts. In addition, we had to do this without disrupting the existing OCR system using the commercial off the shelf SDK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a diagram of the productionized OCR pipeline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1491598157110_ocr_system_diagram.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2mxuefqeaa7sj.cloudfront.net/s_A5D57EE03480AD99ADF37089497274A382BEAFCAAC54E1A98F6D51E323E2FC30_1491598157110_ocr_system_diagram.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall Productionized OCR Pipeline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started by creating an abstraction for different OCR engines, including our own engine and the commercial one, and gated this using our in-house experiments framework, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.dropbox.com/tech/2017/03/introducing-stormcrow/&quot;&gt;Stormcrow&lt;/a&gt;. This allowed us to introduce the skeleton of our new pipeline without disrupting the existing OCR system, which was already running in production for millions of our Business customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also ported our Torch based model, including the CTC layer, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/&quot;&gt;TensorFlow&lt;/a&gt; for a few reasons. First, we’d already standardized on TensorFlow in production to make it easier to manage models and deployments. Second, we prefer to work with Python rather than Lua, and TensorFlow has excellent Python bindings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the new pipeline, mobile clients upload scanned document images to our in-house asynchronous work queue. When the upload is finished, we then send the image via a Remote Procedure Call (RPC) to a cluster of servers running the OCR service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual OCR service uses OpenCV and TensorFlow, both written in C++ and with complicated library dependencies; so security exploits are a real concern. We’ve isolated the actual OCR portion into jails using technologies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LXC&quot;&gt;LXC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cgroups&quot;&gt;CGroups&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_namespaces&quot;&gt;Linux Namespaces&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seccomp&quot;&gt;Seccomp&lt;/a&gt; to provide isolation and syscall whitelisting, using IPCs to talk into and out of the isolated container. If someone compromises the jail they will still be completely separated from the rest of our system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our jail infrastructure allows us to efficiently set up expensive resources a single time at startup, such as loading our trained models, then have these resources be cloned into a jail to satisfy a single OCR request. The resources are cloned &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copy-on-write&quot;&gt;Copy-on-Write&lt;/a&gt; into the forked jail and are read-only for how we use our models so it’s quite efficient and fast. We had to patch TensorFlow to make it easier to do this kind of forking. (We submitted the patch upstream.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we get word bounding boxes and their OCRed text, we merge them back into the original PDF produced by the mobile document scanner as an OCR hidden layer. The user thus gets a PDF that has both the scanned image and the detected text. The OCRed text is also added to Dropbox’s search index. The user can now highlight and copy-paste text from the PDF, with the highlights going in the correct place due to our hidden word box coordinates. They can also search for the scanned PDF via its OCRed text on Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;performance-tuning&quot;&gt;Performance tuning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, we now had an actual engineering pipeline (with unit tests and continual integration!), but still had performance issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first question was whether we would use CPUs or GPUs in production at inference time. Training a deep net takes much longer than using it at inference time. It is common to use GPUs during training (as we did), as they vastly decrease the amount of time it takes to train a deep net. However, using GPUs at inference time is a harder call to make currently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, having high-end GPUs in a production data center such as Dropbox’s is still a bit exotic and different than the rest of the fleet. In addition, GPU-based machines are more expensive and configurations are churning faster based on rapid development. We did an extensive analysis of how our Word Detector and Word Deep Net performed on CPUs vs GPUs, assuming full use of all cores on each CPU and the characteristics of the CPU. After much analysis, we decided that we could hit our performance targets on just CPUs at similar or lower costs than with GPU machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we decided on CPUs, we then needed to optimize our system &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basic_Linear_Algebra_Subprograms&quot;&gt;BLAS&lt;/a&gt; libraries for the Word Deep Net, to tune our network a bit, and to configure TensorFlow to use available cores. Our Word Detector was also a significant bottleneck. We ended up essentially rewriting OpenCV’s C++ MSER implementation in a more modular way to avoid duplicating slow work when doing two passes (to be able to handle both black on white text as well as white on black text); to expose more to our Python layer (the underlying MSER tree hierarchy) for more efficient processing; and to make the code actually readable. We also had to optimize the post-MSER Word Detection pipeline to tune and vectorize certain slow portions of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all this work, we now had a productionized and highly-performant system that we could “shadow turn on” for a small number of users, leading us to the third phase: refinement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our proposed system running silently in production side-by-side with the commercial OCR system, we needed to confirm that our system was truly better, as measured on real user data. We take user data privacy very seriously at Dropbox, so we couldn’t just view and test random mobile document scanned images. Instead, we used the user-image donation flow detailed earlier to get evaluation images. We then used these donated images, being very careful about their privacy, to do a qualitative blackbox test of both OCR systems end-to-end, and were elated to find that we indeed performed the same or better than the older commercial OCR SDK, allowing us to ramp up our system to 100% of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/business/landing-t61fl&quot;&gt;Dropbox Business&lt;/a&gt; users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we tested whether fine-tuning our trained deep net on these donated documents versus our hand chosen fine tuning image suite helped accuracy. Unfortunately, it didn’t move the needle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important refinement was doing orientation detection, which we had not done in the original pipeline. Images from the mobile document scanner can be rotated by 90° or even upside down. We built an orientation predictor using another deep net based on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.googleblog.com/2016/08/improving-inception-and-image.html&quot;&gt;Inception Resnet v2&lt;/a&gt; architecture, changed the final layer to predict orientation, collected an orientation training and validation data set, and fine-tuned from an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ImageNet&quot;&gt;ImageNet&lt;/a&gt;-trained model biased towards our own needs. We put this orientation predictor into our pipeline, using its detected orientation to rotate the image to upright before doing word detection and OCRing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One tricky aspect of the orientation predictor was that only a small percentage of images are actually rotated; we needed to make sure our system didn’t inadvertently rotate upright images (the most common case) while trying to fix the orientation for the smaller number of non-upright images. In addition, we had to solve various tricky issues in combining our upright rotated images with the different ways the PDF file format can apply its own transformation matrices for rotation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we were surprised to find some tough issues with the PDF file format containing our scanned OCRed hidden layer in Apple’s native Preview application. Most PDF renderers respect spaces embedded in the text for copy and paste, but Apple’s Preview application performs its own heuristics to determine word boundaries based on text position. This resulted in unacceptable quality for copy and paste from this PDF renderer, causing most spaces to be dropped and all the words to be “glommed together”. We had to do extensive testing across a range of PDF renderers to find the right PDF tricks and workarounds that would solve this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, this entire round of researching, productionization, and refinement took about 8 months, at the end of which we had built and deployed a state-of-the-art OCR pipeline to millions of users using modern computer vision and deep neural network techniques. Our work also provides a solid foundation for future OCR-based products at Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interested in applying the latest machine learning research to hard, real&lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt;world problems and shipping to millions of Dropbox users?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/jobs/listing/533100&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our team is hiring&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 17:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wwarner</dc:creator>
<og:title>Creating a Modern OCR Pipeline Using Computer Vision and Deep Learning</og:title>
<og:url>https://blogs.dropbox.com/tech/2017/04/creating-a-modern-ocr-pipeline-using-computer-vision-and-deep-learning/</og:url>
<og:image>https://dropboxtechblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/ocr-teaser.png?w=150</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blogs.dropbox.com/tech/2017/04/creating-a-modern-ocr-pipeline-using-computer-vision-and-deep-learning/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>.IO domain name reliability issues and how we’re working around them</title>
<link>https://getstream.io/blog/stop-using-io-domain-names-for-production-traffic/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://getstream.io/blog/stop-using-io-domain-names-for-production-traffic/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Note: If you’re a user of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://getstream.io/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stream&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, be sure to update your API client to the latest version for a large improvement in reliability. For those of you on a custom API client, have a look at our updated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://getstream.io/docs_rest/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;REST documentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Domain resolution is one of the backbone services of the Internet. It’s something we typically spend very little time thinking about. Of course, that changes when it breaks. Over the past year, IO domain outages have been the number one reason our customers couldn’t use &lt;a href=&quot;https://getstream.io/&quot;&gt;Stream&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically, the outage on September 20th, 2017 turned out to be a major headache. This article will go into the details behind the .IO domain name reliability issues and how we’re working around them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;The infrastructure of internet Domain Name System (DNS) is large and complex. Due to its centralized and distributed nature, if the problem is with your DNS provider or the broader DNS infrastructure, there is little you can do other than sit and wait for the problem to be resolved. The only practical solution for dealing with DNS outages is to fallback to a backup domain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;This makes DNS outages quite nasty. Many risks are complex and costly to mitigate and in some scenarios, it is virtually impossible to do so.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;What Went Wrong: A Global Outage at the ‘.io’ Top Level Domain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;On September 20th, 2017, our system monitors and health checks started to show intermittent failures. Pings to our website and API servers were failing to resolve “getstream.io” records to a valid hostname.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Domain name resolution is necessary to access our core API service and dashboard. Without it, clients are not able to find the address to our servers. It goes without saying that this was immediately triaged as critical and received the full attention of our team.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;After an initial investigation, we discovered that resolving any getstream.io record would randomly fail with an incorrect NXDOMAIN error returned. Subsequently, one of our engineers identified that the resolution of .io domains would consistently fail on 2 of the 6 authoritative .io nameservers. The remaining four were operating correctly which explained the apparent random nature of the errors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;oembed-gist&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View the code on &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/jessienewell/099666e5832fcf4b0224012a87b7411c&quot;&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;A bad one looks like the following:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;oembed-gist&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View the code on &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/jessienewell/633c842968a7b030bdd229140af4738d&quot;&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Since this happened on the authoritative nameservers, we reached out to our DNS provider and then tried to get in touch with NIC.io as well. To our surprise, we found out that &lt;strong&gt;NIC.io could only be reached via phone between 7 AM to 12 AM UTC Monday through Friday and did not expose any status about the health of the service&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;In the meantime, we started looking at who else was affected by this outage and posted about it on Twitter and &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15293578&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While waiting for the outage to end, we also increased DNS TTL so that the amount of DNS queries would be as low as possible. Shortly after that, we received a reply from Gandi.net informing us that NIC.io was fixing the problem.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://status.getstream.io/incidents/kgqqpz89lpr0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;outage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; lasted for almost 2 hours, during which 1/5th of DNS queries for any .getstream.io record would fail. For something that sits in front of our service, this is a huge problem and raised a more than a few questions on our end.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Couldn’t This Happen with Any TLD?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;We get it. Sometimes things break. Realistically a similar outage could have occurred to any top level domain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Back when we started in 2014 we decided that .io was great from a branding perspective. &lt;a href=&quot;https://getstream.io/&quot;&gt;Stream&lt;/a&gt; is a technical product and our audience is mainly technical, so .io seemed like a great match. Using the same domain for the APIs was more of a consequence than a thoughtful decision.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;It is impossible to estimate the likelihood of .com nameservers having the same kind of outages as the .io nameservers. One thing that surprised us was that while &lt;strong&gt;about 20% of DNS resolutions for all .io domains were totally broken&lt;/strong&gt;, it was hard to find people complaining about that on Twitter. In fact I believe we were one of the first to tweet this. Had this happened on all .com domains, all news sources would have been on fire.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;What Really Went Wrong&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Unfortunately, we found out the hard way that NIC.IO isn’t equipped with the technical support and systems necessary to manage a top-level domain. Being unable to reach them while a major outage was happening is unacceptable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Looking further, it does not take a lot of research to find out that the .io TLD team made several mistakes over the past few years. Just to name a few:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Searching for &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=io%20domain&amp;amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;.io on HN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; returns a long list of similar outages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;What Is the Best Immediate Solution?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Adding a .com domain and using it as the default on all our API clients is clearly the low hanging fruit. Of course we could have the same problem if .com had an outage, however, we are vastly more confident in the management behind .com. It is clear that not only would the issue have been identified earlier, but it also wouldn’t have taken hours for people to acknowledge and remedy the situation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Our Roadmap to a DNS Outage-Free Service&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;These DNS issues caused us to pause and think about all the ways in which a DNS can break.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lose control of our own domain.&lt;/strong&gt; This can happen in an alarmingly large amount of ways:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Route53 outage.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Since we are delegating getstream.io to Route53 nameservers, an outage on their nameservers would disrupt our service. The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://dyn.com/blog/dyn-statement-on-10212016-ddos-attack/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;DynDNS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;DDoS outage from 2016 is an example.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;com TLD outage.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Since we control the API clients, implementing a failover mechanism is easy. Setting up and maintaining a backup domain and/or a backup DNS provider can be very challenging. In the first case, we would need to keep hundreds of DNS records in sync and double our SSL certificates; secondly we would need to only change our infrastructure to not use any Route53 specific feature. For that, we need to keep all DNS records in sync across two different providers and ensure we don’t use any vendor specific feature. As an AWS customer, this is a major challenge as DNS is deeply integrated in many ways.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Looking forward, our plan is to add a .org domain and find a DNS provider to manage the nameservers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;In hindsight, using a .IO domain for our core APIs was not a great choice. The outage on September 20th showed how severe the problems and support infrastructure are. Based on our experience we would advise against using a .IO domain name if availability is important.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;To work around the DNS issue, Stream’s API traffic now runs on a .com domain name. The site still runs on .io since this is harder to change and not as critical in terms of uptime. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://getstream.io/get_started/&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; powers the feeds for over 200 million end users and we don’t want to take any risk in terms of uptime. To further improve reliability we’re considering:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;ul1&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;li2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Adding a backup .ORG domain name.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;li2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Using a backup DNS provider for either the .COM or .ORG domain name.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;li2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Implementing client-side DNS failover in our SDKs.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;DNS as a whole is one of those things that most take for granted but can easily cause serious downtime and trouble. Using a widely used TLD like .com/.net/.org is the best and easiest way to ensure reliability.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! If you’ve never used Stream before, you’ll enjoy this quick &lt;a href=&quot;https://getstream.io/get_started/&quot;&gt;5 minute tutorial about the API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@tommaso_82444/stop-using-io-domain-names-for-production-traffic-46f89b1f1012&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 17:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sbierwagen</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why Stream Stopped Using .IO Domain Names for Production Traffic</og:title>
<og:description>Switching from a .io domain name to a .com domain name helped with downtime and improve reliability on our API clients.</og:description>
<og:url>https://getstream.io/blog/stop-using-io-domain-names-for-production-traffic/</og:url>
<og:image>https://getstream-blog.imgix.net/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/stop-io.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://getstream.io/blog/stop-using-io-domain-names-for-production-traffic/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Low-cost, non-invasive melanoma detector wins award</title>
<link>https://jamesdysonaward.org/news/skan-james-dyson-award-2017-international-winner/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jamesdysonaward.org/news/skan-james-dyson-award-2017-international-winner/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A team of medical and bioengineering undergraduates from McMaster University, Canada have been chosen as the international James Dyson Award 2017 winners. Their design solution, the sKan, is a low cost and non-invasive melanoma detection device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sKan was chosen as the international winner by James Dyson who says “by using widely available and inexpensive components, the sKan allows for melanoma skin cancer detection to be readily accessible to the many. It’s a very clever device with the potential to save lives around the world. This is why I have selected it at this year’s international winner.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annually, skin cancer accounts for 1 in every 3 cancer diagnoses&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;. The estimated 5-year survival rate for patients whose melanoma is detected early is approximately 98 percent&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;. Current melanoma detection methods either rely on a visual inspection, or need a specialist’s opinion which is time consuming and costly. With high numbers of patients needing a rapid diagnosis to begin treatment, the health services are at maximum capacity. The sKan poses a viable solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1dtbef22buhyxzall2snlwn1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Screen-Shot-2017-11-08-at-9.48.04-AM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-342317&quot; src=&quot;https://1dtbef22buhyxzall2snlwn1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Screen-Shot-2017-11-08-at-9.48.04-AM-300x224.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;224&quot; srcset=&quot;https://1dtbef22buhyxzall2snlwn1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Screen-Shot-2017-11-08-at-9.48.04-AM-300x224.png 300w, https://1dtbef22buhyxzall2snlwn1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Screen-Shot-2017-11-08-at-9.48.04-AM-768x575.png 768w, https://1dtbef22buhyxzall2snlwn1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Screen-Shot-2017-11-08-at-9.48.04-AM-1024x766.png 1024w, https://1dtbef22buhyxzall2snlwn1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Screen-Shot-2017-11-08-at-9.48.04-AM-476x356.png 476w, https://1dtbef22buhyxzall2snlwn1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Screen-Shot-2017-11-08-at-9.48.04-AM-980x733.png 980w, https://1dtbef22buhyxzall2snlwn1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Screen-Shot-2017-11-08-at-9.48.04-AM-873x653.png 873w, https://1dtbef22buhyxzall2snlwn1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Screen-Shot-2017-11-08-at-9.48.04-AM.png 1188w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that cancerous cells have a higher metabolic rate than normal tissue cells. When an area of interest on the skin is rapidly cooled, cancerous tissue will regain heat at a faster rate than non-cancerous tissue. The sKan uses accurate and inexpensive temperature sensors to pinpoint areas of tissue that gain heat quicker than the surrounding area of skin. The results of this are displayed as a heat map and temperature difference time plot on using a regular computer. A medical professional can use the quantitative findings produced by the sKan to indicate whether the patient needs to be referred for further investigation or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are truly humbled and excited to be given this remarkable opportunity,” says the sKan team. The team plans to use the $40,000 prize money to reiterate and refine their design to ensure it passes the US Food and Drug Administration’s standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BY3DbQxuM5U&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Watch the winners’ video.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The international James Dyson Award runners up are Atropos and Twistlight. Atropos is a 6-axis 3D printing robotic arm that uses continuous fiber composites material, to produce high-performance objects. The designers, Gabriele Natale and Michele Tonizzo, hope to tackle the amount of waste produced by current high performance 3D printing tools. Twistlight, designed by Tina Zimmer, uses LED lights to make veins appear highly contrasted within their surrounding dermal tissue. The light can be used to easily insert needles and catheters into a patient’s skin.  Despite being the most common medical procedure, 33% of first vein puncture attempts fail. Multiple discarded attempts cause patient pain and waste medical materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/uv/faq/skincancer/en/index1.html&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/uv/faq/skincancer/en/index1.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skincancer.org/skin-cancer-information/skin-cancer-facts&quot;&gt;http://www.skincancer.org/skin-cancer-information/skin-cancer-facts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 14:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ductionist</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The sKan is James Dyson Award 2017 international winner - James Dyson Award</og:title>
<og:description>A team of medical and bioengineering undergraduates from McMaster University, Canada have been chosen as the international James Dyson Award 2017 winners.</og:description>
<og:url>https://jamesdysonaward.org/news/skan-james-dyson-award-2017-international-winner/</og:url>
<og:image>https://jamesdysonaward.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/20171030_dyson_jda_1273.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jamesdysonaward.org/news/skan-james-dyson-award-2017-international-winner/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sean Parker unloads on Facebook “exploiting” human psychology</title>
<link>https://www.axios.com/sean-parker-unloads-on-facebook-2508036343.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.axios.com/sean-parker-unloads-on-facebook-2508036343.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Keith Schiller, who was Donald Trump's bodyguard for many years and served in the White House as Director of Oval Office Operations, told congressional investigators this week that a Russian associated with the 2013 Miss Universe pageant offered to &quot;send five women&quot; to Trump's Moscow hotel room, but was rejected, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/trump-bodyguard-testifies-russian-offered-trump-women-was-turned-down-n819386&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NBC News reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per the report, Schiller said he thought the offer was a joke and said, &quot;we don't do that type of stuff.&quot; Schiller was before the House Intelligence Committee, and addressing the contents of the Steele dossier, which alleged that Russia had tapes of Trump engaging in compromising activities in his hotel room. Schiller testified he was &quot;confident&quot; nothing of the sort had taken place, per the report.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 13:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jbuild</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.axios.com/sean-parker-unloads-on-facebook-2508036343.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://axios-img.rbl.ms/simage/https%3A%2F%2Fassets.rbl.ms%2F13705169%2F1200x600.jpg/2000%2C2000/BLlkY95AmgsXKLGy/img.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Sean Parker unloads on Facebook: “God only knows what it's doing to our children's brains”</og:title>
<og:description>Sean Parker, the founding president of Facebook, gave me a candid insider's look at how social networks purposely hook and potentially hurt our brains.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.axios.com/sean-parker-unloads-on-facebook-2508036343.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Skyrim rendered in text</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@filiph/skyrim-rendered-in-text-1899548ab2c4</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@filiph/skyrim-rendered-in-text-1899548ab2c4</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h2 name=&quot;4fc6&quot; id=&quot;4fc6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--h3 graf--subtitle&quot;&gt;Fractal stories, or how to build an open-world text adventure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;423.90225118483&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9308&quot; id=&quot;9308&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;I decided some time ago to create a text-based Skyrim. That sounds overly ambitious at first, but as I developed the story and the game’s mechanics, I discovered its basic elements: a sword &amp;amp; sorcery game in a living, simulated world that is presented as a Choose Your Own Adventure (CYOA) book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*4ua91tHXnmxS9kf0qwW8IQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;936&quot; data-height=&quot;833&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*4ua91tHXnmxS9kf0qwW8IQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*4ua91tHXnmxS9kf0qwW8IQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1085&quot; id=&quot;1085&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The idea has already brought a short game into the world, &lt;a href=&quot;https://egamebook.com/vermin&quot; data-href=&quot;https://egamebook.com/vermin&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Insignificant Little Vermin&lt;/a&gt;, which I submitted to this year’s IFCOMP. In this article, I’ll walk you through the process of building that game and talk about what I learned from watching people play it (on Twitch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a300&quot; id=&quot;a300&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Why Skyrim?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bb00&quot; id=&quot;bb00&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Don’t get too hung up on the fact that I’m referring to Skyrim here. Skyrim, for me, is just a sufficiently well-known fantasy open-world videogame that we can use as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;040b&quot; id=&quot;040b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Sufficiently well-known&lt;/strong&gt; because I want people to immediately have an image in mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;c488&quot; id=&quot;c488&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Fantasy&lt;/strong&gt; because the combat style in fantasy games is especially well-suited for our needs (more on that later).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;cc25&quot; id=&quot;cc25&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Open-world&lt;/strong&gt; because these types of games are a great form of escapism, and therefore a good fit for our needs (more on that later).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;5f42&quot; id=&quot;5f42&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Videogame&lt;/strong&gt; because I put emphasis on the play/flow aspect more than on the interactive story (again, more on that later).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;cf25&quot; id=&quot;cf25&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;The important thing is that we simulate a world that the player can explore. This world is inhabited by actors (monsters, NPCs) and entities (swords, doors, chests, etc.) that the player can interact with. In Skyrim, the world is rendered in 3D, and the player gives low-level commands such as “move forward” or “use weapon in left hand”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;001c&quot; id=&quot;001c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The goal of the simulation is to entertain the player. That is to say, I’m not using the word “simulation” to suggest that Skyrim tries to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simulation#Classification_and_terminology&quot; data-href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simulation#Classification_and_terminology&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;imitate real-world processes&lt;/a&gt;” as closely as possible. To me, every videogame that has a steady &lt;a href=&quot;http://gameprogrammingpatterns.com/game-loop.html&quot; data-href=&quot;http://gameprogrammingpatterns.com/game-loop.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;update loop&lt;/a&gt; is a simulation of some sort — even if it’s a 2D simulation of an Italian plumber’s journey to save a princess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bc6e&quot; id=&quot;bc6e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;First try, a deliberately naive start&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;442d&quot; id=&quot;442d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The most naive way of porting Skyrim to a text adventure would be to take the world simulation as it exists in the 3D game and play it one frame at a time, describing what’s going on and asking the player for low level input. It would look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;009e&quot; id=&quot;009e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;Outside of Whiterun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;92ee&quot; id=&quot;92ee&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;465a&quot; id=&quot;465a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You stand on coordinates {351.0, 211.9}, facing NNE. Your sword is 12% midswing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;fd65&quot; id=&quot;fd65&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see a bandit on coordinates {351.1, 210.8}, facing SSW. His axe is 78% midswing and it missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;b4d0&quot; id=&quot;b4d0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;push up arrow&lt;br/&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; push down arrow&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;push left arrow&lt;br/&gt;push right arrow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;97b3&quot; id=&quot;97b3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You take a step back to coordinates {354.9, 212.5}. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;065f&quot; id=&quot;065f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;As you can imagine, the gameplay and story experience here would absolutely suck. And no matter how you tweak the output, the input, or the length of each frame represented in text, it would still suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;21ce&quot; id=&quot;21ce&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Second try&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2c54&quot; id=&quot;2c54&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;One way to solve this is by increasing the level of abstraction. We still use Skyrim’s world simulation, but only on the highest level — the map, distances between objects and places, the location of actors, NPCs, where to spawn monsters, etc. That gives us something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;44b7&quot; id=&quot;44b7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;Outside of Whiterun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;cbca&quot; id=&quot;cbca&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You arrive at Whiterun from the south. There’s a solitary bandit waiting for you, axe in hand and ready to fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;64da&quot; id=&quot;64da&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; kill bandit&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;e9ae&quot; id=&quot;e9ae&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You raise your sword and charge the bandit. &amp;lt;Insert interesting description of a fight.&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;9e03&quot; id=&quot;9e03&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last swing connects with the bandit’s throat and he falls to the ground. As you kneel next to him and try taking his gold, an arrow slams into the ground less than an inch from your knee. You jump up and catch sight of an archer on a knoll nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;bc65&quot; id=&quot;bc65&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; kill archer&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;search bandit&lt;br/&gt;run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;cd6f&quot; id=&quot;cd6f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Insert another interesting fight description.&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;12e2&quot; id=&quot;12e2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;Now, the gameplay here is a bit better, and this kind of experience could even be fun. The player could go to the different places in the simulated world, talk to people, quest for them, and experience the Skyrim storyline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*9gHq7Zf_YPfHe8teQM0LGw.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3732&quot; data-height=&quot;1572&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*9gHq7Zf_YPfHe8teQM0LGw.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*9gHq7Zf_YPfHe8teQM0LGw.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6e8d&quot; id=&quot;6e8d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;But let’s face it, combat is a big part of what makes Skyrim fun. So “kill bandit, kill archer” doesn’t quite cut it. At best, with really interesting descriptions of the fights, you’ll have a longer version of something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://ifdb.tads.org/viewgame?id=lb2hf5pqx68wbqhh&quot; data-href=&quot;http://ifdb.tads.org/viewgame?id=lb2hf5pqx68wbqhh&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Conan Kill Everything&lt;/a&gt;. More likely, though, the player will get bored after the first few fights and will quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4aca&quot; id=&quot;4aca&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;That brings us to an important question: What makes combat in Skyrim fun, anyway? We do the same things over and over again and each battle is largely similar. How do we not get bored with them after the first dungeon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fadf&quot; id=&quot;fadf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The answer is twofold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;3596&quot; id=&quot;3596&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;You have a high level of agency during the fights. At any time, you can advance, retreat, attack, defend, change weapons, jump, crouch, flank, climb a rock, use magic, etc. This means you can &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--li-em&quot;&gt;get better at fighting&lt;/em&gt; as a player. &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--li-em&quot;&gt;You&lt;/em&gt; have to fight. Therefore, you can experience, well, &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--li-em&quot;&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; (as it’s defined in books like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theoryoffun.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.theoryoffun.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Theory of Fun for Game Design&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;2737&quot; id=&quot;2737&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Fights are highly unpredictable. You never know how each combat will turn out. You can do battle with the same group of enemies three times in a row and the course of the fight will be different each time. This means you get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00LMGLXTS/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00LMGLXTS/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;variable rewards&lt;/a&gt; — an important ingredient for getting you “hooked” on the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;e32b&quot; id=&quot;e32b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Skyrim can throw similar combat at you over and over again, and not only does it not become boring, it’s great entertainment! This is not &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;despite&lt;/em&gt; the fact that it’s repetitive, it is &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of the cocktail of repetition, agency, and unpredictability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9aff&quot; id=&quot;9aff&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Therein lies the fundamental challenge of trying to marry videogames and text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;d35b&quot; id=&quot;d35b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Good videogames &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;always have&lt;/strong&gt; some repetition. All gaming from Pong through Tetris to Portal to Skyrim is based on repeatedly throwing a similar problem at you, the player, so that you can get better at solving it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;8ea7&quot; id=&quot;8ea7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Good text &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;cannot have&lt;/strong&gt; too much repetition. Repetitive text is boring. Try writing up everything that happens in the first five minutes of some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0q5uDKtI1Go&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0q5uDKtI1Go&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Super Mario gameplay&lt;/a&gt; with prose that is fun to read. It’s impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;429e&quot; id=&quot;429e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Text games normally solve this in two ways: they either stay away from repetition as much as possible (which makes the game more intellectual — all situations and solutions are unique) or they break up repetitive gameplay into a bunch of minigames. For great examples of the former approach, see almost any of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ifdb.tads.org/search?sortby=rcu&amp;amp;newSortBy.x=0&amp;amp;newSortBy.y=0&amp;amp;searchfor=&amp;amp;browse=1&quot; data-href=&quot;http://ifdb.tads.org/search?sortby=rcu&amp;amp;newSortBy.x=0&amp;amp;newSortBy.y=0&amp;amp;searchfor=&amp;amp;browse=1&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;top traditional interactive fiction&lt;/a&gt;. For an example of the latter, see the brilliant &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inklestudios.com/sorcery/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.inklestudios.com/sorcery/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sorcery!&lt;/a&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1a09&quot; id=&quot;1a09&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Third try&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6901&quot; id=&quot;6901&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Since we already understand that Skyrim’s gameplay is largely centered around combat, let’s try the minigame approach (and not the more intellectual, non-repetitive one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;cd16&quot; id=&quot;cd16&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;Outside of Whiterun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;ccdd&quot; id=&quot;ccdd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You arrive at Whiterun from the south. There’s a solitary bandit waiting for you, axe in hand and ready to fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;2e79&quot; id=&quot;2e79&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; kill bandit&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;f693&quot; id=&quot;f693&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;A graphical combat minigame.&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;fa9a&quot; id=&quot;fa9a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bandit keels over and dies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*KWIDOqkcgL5Uwm5a.&quot; data-width=&quot;1024&quot; data-height=&quot;768&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;0*KWIDOqkcgL5Uwm5a.&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/0*KWIDOqkcgL5Uwm5a.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9a04&quot; id=&quot;9a04&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The minigame can have some text in it, but the mechanics are not tied to the text. In Sorcery!, the combat minigame consists of a series of decisions about how hard to hit (on a scale of total defense to all-out attack). But there are no limits to the design of the minigames we can use. It can be a simple card game, a match 3 puzzle, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f79b&quot; id=&quot;f79b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This works. I, for one, would buy a mobile version of Skyrim done in the same fashion as Sorcery!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6cd8&quot; id=&quot;6cd8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;But I also think we can do better. Much of my enjoyment of Skyrim stems from the fact that it’s an open world where anything can happen almost anywhere. There’s no switching between “exploration mode” and “combat mode”. An inn where you’re talking to an NPC can become a point of tactical cover moments later. You can maneuver around a patrol and hit them with something nasty at long range from the relative safety of a cliff. And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*nRRqtVBwuP8JYWMLo3Eslw.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3732&quot; data-height=&quot;1572&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*nRRqtVBwuP8JYWMLo3Eslw.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*nRRqtVBwuP8JYWMLo3Eslw.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1c3c&quot; id=&quot;1c3c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;None of this translates well into the text-with-minigame solution. So let’s go further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;765d&quot; id=&quot;765d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Fourth try&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;52c8&quot; id=&quot;52c8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We’re going to tweak the level of abstraction yet again. Going frame-by-frame in our naive start was obviously the wrong move. And going with “kill bandit” obviously made the level of abstraction too high, no matter whether the fight was described in text or represented through a minigame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8687&quot; id=&quot;8687&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Let’s descend just a little bit from “kill bandit” into a tactics-based approach. Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;7d06&quot; id=&quot;7d06&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;Outside of Whiterun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;b96a&quot; id=&quot;b96a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You arrive at Whiterun from the south. There’s a solitary bandit waiting for you, axe in hand and ready to fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;facc&quot; id=&quot;facc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; kill bandit&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;a97c&quot; id=&quot;a97c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How exactly do you want to go about killing the bandit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;b08e&quot; id=&quot;b08e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… with sword&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; … with bow and arrow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;5b47&quot; id=&quot;5b47&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You quickly string the bow and let it fly. The arrow whirls just past the bandit’s ear. &amp;lt;Rest of fight description.&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;156d&quot; id=&quot;156d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;This approach creates more options than just “kill”, but after a while it’s not much fun. Each player gravitates toward a certain style of play (stealth, long range, melee, magic, etc.) and therefore there’s really not much choice involved. For an archer, the best tactic will almost always be “bow and arrow” or “sneak around”. Another player will see very different combat sequences, but that doesn’t necessarily make the experience fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*-Wf0d8uYp8DrHrHCvDv9ww.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3732&quot; data-height=&quot;1572&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*-Wf0d8uYp8DrHrHCvDv9ww.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*-Wf0d8uYp8DrHrHCvDv9ww.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1185&quot; id=&quot;1185&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;So we’ll need to offer players meaningful choices on a lower level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a8f2&quot; id=&quot;a8f2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Fifth try&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cc53&quot; id=&quot;cc53&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Alright, fine. Let’s go with action-by-action level combat, &lt;a href=&quot;https://roll20.net/compendium/dnd5e/Combat#toc_5&quot; data-href=&quot;https://roll20.net/compendium/dnd5e/Combat#toc_5&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;D-style&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;f918&quot; id=&quot;f918&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;Outside of Whiterun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;7759&quot; id=&quot;7759&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You arrive at Whiterun from the south. There’s a solitary bandit waiting for you, axe in hand and ready to fight. You unsheathe your sword and approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;1419&quot; id=&quot;1419&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; thrust sword&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;swing sword&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;c7d0&quot; id=&quot;c7d0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your blade moves fast but misses, just left of the bandit’s chest. The bandit swings the axe and lightly cleaves your leather jerkin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;7cbf&quot; id=&quot;7cbf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;thrust sword&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; swing sword&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;51e5&quot; id=&quot;51e5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sword cuts the bandit’s thigh and he yells in pain. He tries to strike at you from above, but the axe goes wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;937b&quot; id=&quot;937b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Rest of fight.&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;df40&quot; id=&quot;df40&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;This starts to look like the player has actual agency. There are many possible moves that fit different playing styles (a swordsman can thrust, swing, tackle, decapitate; an archer can target different parts of the body) and those moves can be combined in a myriad of different ways. Players can develop their own tactics!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*KglqnCOqHlgHBe_ecbxh7Q.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3732&quot; data-height=&quot;1572&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*KglqnCOqHlgHBe_ecbxh7Q.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*KglqnCOqHlgHBe_ecbxh7Q.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6106&quot; id=&quot;6106&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;But there are issues with this approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;7739&quot; id=&quot;7739&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The prose ends up being very mechanical. It’s not as bad as our first naive approach, but it’s still something a real author would never write. “You do X, opponent does Y.” Repeat. That gets boring quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;15de&quot; id=&quot;15de&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;There is no easy way to deal with reactions. A strike with a sword either hits or misses. Sure, the receiving side can anticipate the strike and can be defending at that time (“assume defensive stance” or “raise shield”), but players generally hate doing that. It means trading your opportunity to strike (awesome) for &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--li-em&quot;&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; taking less damage (meh). It might be the rational choice in some situations, but it definitely doesn’t feel like an adventure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;0b02&quot; id=&quot;0b02&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;So now it looks like we’re screwed. We covered the whole spectrum of abstraction and nothing quite makes the game we want work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1619&quot; id=&quot;1619&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is where I found myself after tinkering with the game for 5 years. I almost gave up, thinking that I proved — for myself at least — that there is no way to build a Skyrim-like open world game in text. Not even in theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6e76&quot; id=&quot;6e76&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I decided to take a break from this “Skyrim in text” project. Instead, I started building something completely different. The game was still text-based, but gamplay was more procedural and psychological. It was about survival in a group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7ef4&quot; id=&quot;7ef4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And during &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; project, I realized that text stories are fractal. Unlinke in videogames (which need a steady update method), in text we don’t actually need to stick to a single level of abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;776f&quot; id=&quot;776f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Sixth and final try&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5ca8&quot; id=&quot;5ca8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Let me show you what I mean:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;fdb0&quot; id=&quot;fdb0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;Outside of Whiterun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;eab3&quot; id=&quot;eab3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You arrive at Whiterun from the south. There’s a solitary bandit waiting for you, axe in hand and ready to fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;6af7&quot; id=&quot;6af7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; charge at the bandit&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;use bow and arrow&lt;br/&gt;run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;ba92&quot; id=&quot;ba92&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You raise your sword and dash at the bandit. He takes a few quick steps back and when you come in range, he swiftly swings at you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;d322&quot; id=&quot;d322&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jump back&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; dodge&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;block&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;2d3e&quot; id=&quot;2d3e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You duck and the bandit’s sword swings an inch above your head. This briefly exposes the bandit’s side, which has no armor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;c398&quot; id=&quot;c398&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--blockquote-strong&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; thrust sword&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;punch flank&lt;br/&gt;ignore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;dcc6&quot; id=&quot;dcc6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Rest of fight.&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d2fa&quot; id=&quot;d2fa&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;Notice how the “charge” command is a tactical one — it’s on a higher level of abstraction than slash or thrust. Then the bandit’s first swing is on the action-by-action level. But then, before the swing even finishes, we go one level deeper, and the player can react to that situation by dodging (or blocking or jumping back). And since that succeeds, we stay at that low level, and the player can insert a counter-thrust &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;during&lt;/em&gt; the bandit’s dodged swing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;19c4&quot; id=&quot;19c4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Now the fight includes many choices on all levels, from tactical positioning to split-second actions. Repetition is then more fun to the player, because the same action can be performed in vastly different contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*VgFUxD7mhk9MHSSZvsKi4g.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3732&quot; data-height=&quot;1572&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*VgFUxD7mhk9MHSSZvsKi4g.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*VgFUxD7mhk9MHSSZvsKi4g.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;785d&quot; id=&quot;785d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The resulting prose reads like something a human would write. It’s not just two people exchanging damage, it’s an actual swordfight with dynamic potential outcomes every step of the way. And gameplay flows through different levels of abstraction, like a book would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0845&quot; id=&quot;0845&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Caveats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bb77&quot; id=&quot;bb77&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So there you have it: Insignificant Little Vermin, my submission to IFCOMP, is working with the concept of fractal stories in an open-world simulation to produce a relatively fluid, readable text adventure. Some players have even assumed the text is &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; procedurally generated in parts where I know it is. More importantly, though, players tend to have a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;2062&quot; id=&quot;2062&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;It’s not all fireworks and applause, though, of course. The short game made it clear to me what the limitations of such an approach are, and just how much more work there is to be done before I accomplish my vision of a completely open world rendered in text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b561&quot; id=&quot;b561&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;First of all, this game is really just the first stab in this direction. I discovered many of the insights above while developing Vermin. There is no playbook, no best practices, no industry events about fractal stories or “Skyrims in text”. There is, thankfully, an abundance of literature about interactive fiction, though most of it focuses on a very different aspect of fiction than what I’m after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4b22&quot; id=&quot;4b22&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For one, there’s much less content in Vermin than I’d like it to have. It’s nowhere near an AAA game (like Skyrim) in scope. It currently only offers limited RPG progression (player character doesn’t learn new stuff, for example), and the combat could use more variability. Also, there is no mapping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;adc3&quot; id=&quot;adc3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;That’s all quite easily solved by putting more work in on this project, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;54c1&quot; id=&quot;54c1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;What I find more interesting are the limitations that won’t go away so easily. The ones that stem from the nature of the system, and from text in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0635&quot; id=&quot;0635&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;The need for clarity and (surface) simplicity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;66f1&quot; id=&quot;66f1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In text, it is very easy to give too much information. A completely chaotic engagement is fine when it develops in 3D graphics, but unreadable when it’s rendered in prose. A swordfight with 10 actors must be broken down or abstracted — a possible solution being something like Level of Detail (LoD) or Limelight, where the actions of actors who are distant from the player are either ignored or described only in broad strokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0074&quot; id=&quot;0074&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In text, it’s hard (and boring) to explain spatial relations. Read any sword and sorcery novel and you’ll see how Conan/Fafhrd/Elric always swings at the pirate/swordsman/lich but never “forward and to the left”. Position is always described only in the most general way. No matter how clear you think you are, you’ll never beat 2D or 3D graphics in terms of quickly letting the player know where everyone is and what they’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;13c7&quot; id=&quot;13c7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In text, you have to think about names, categories, and pronouns, too. It actually helps to have a variety of genders at play at any given time, because then it’s easier to use pronouns to let the player know who we’re focusing on. For example, when you have a scene with a male thief, a female warrior, and a spider, your natural language generation algorithm will get by with “he”, “she” and “it” for the most part. Which is great. Contrast that with a scene that contains 3 male orc warriors and you’ll probably have a lot of sentences like “The orc on the left makes a move.” Which is boring and difficult to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d1ab&quot; id=&quot;d1ab&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In text, it’s harder to work with a myriad of characters’ states. You can’t expect the player to remember that, for example, the orc has his arm extended to the left. Fortunately, people have imagination (and love to use it!), so your underlying simulation &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be complex — you just need to make sure to only foreground the most important things, and let the reader get the rest from subtext.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0675&quot; id=&quot;0675&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;The need for a casual feel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2ecc&quot; id=&quot;2ecc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In text, you can’t have your mechanics too stats-based or competitive. If you go that path, sooner or later, your game becomes a spreadsheet with some text sprinkled on top to provide a narrative. Not that this is a bad thing — I like these kinds of games (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://philome.la/johnayliff/seedship/play&quot; data-href=&quot;http://philome.la/johnayliff/seedship/play&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Seedship&lt;/a&gt;). It’s just that this is not what we’re going for with fractal stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2a9e&quot; id=&quot;2a9e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Procedural content isn’t a silver bullet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1314&quot; id=&quot;1314&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In text, combat (and procedural content in general) works much better when intermixed with something else. Context, character, and narrative development are part of what makes a game fun. In Vermin, all fights have at least some flavor text (opponents talking to each other) and so do the sectiones in which you’re roaming the world. You can’t just defer to procedural generation — you should still have a lot of content (even if that content is, in the end, used procedurally). This follows the general rule, though, that procedural content is not for “lazy developers”. It’s not there to free you from creating content. It’s there to let content react to the player. You still need a lot of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;63e7&quot; id=&quot;63e7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Writing is hard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ea11&quot; id=&quot;ea11&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It’s easy to come up with “You hit orc for 15 HP”. It’s much harder to come up with many versions of “your blade misses the orc”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9f74&quot; id=&quot;9f74&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Natural language generation is hard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c528&quot; id=&quot;c528&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It’s easier than modern 3D programming (at least in terms of person-hours), but not by much. Human language is rich and full of pitfalls. Fortunately, we can choose a subset of natural language that is quite easy to do (specifically, present-tense action). Still, for something like this to work, you can’t expect someone who is primarily a writer to successfully program the game. This is &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the next Twine or Inform. This is for a development team, not a single author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f6ca&quot; id=&quot;f6ca&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Not for just any genre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5361&quot; id=&quot;5361&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Lastly, not all types of content are a good fit for fractal stories. Or, at the very least, some genres are much better suited for this approach. Sword &amp;amp; sorcery is great because it’s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;d107&quot; id=&quot;d107&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A lot of action described straightforwardly, in present tense.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;5cb2&quot; id=&quot;5cb2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Immediate, visceral conflict.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;68ef&quot; id=&quot;68ef&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Reactive (counter a slash by blocking it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;4d12&quot; id=&quot;4d12&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Physical exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;4a88&quot; id=&quot;4a88&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Contrast this to something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/app/400/Portal/&quot; data-href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/app/400/Portal/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Portal&lt;/a&gt;, which features actions that are hard to imagine occuring in spaces that are hard to describe, involving lots of skill on the player’s end. But we don’t need to go as far as 3D puzzlers to find subject matter that won’t work. Even other combat-oriented open world games are significantly harder to “port to text” once they involve relatively realistic modern-day shooting instead of fantasy combat. Maybe it’s just my lack of imagination (and almost no experience with literature involving gun fights), but I can’t see a good combat mechanic that would work with the immediacy of firearms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;004f&quot; id=&quot;004f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;To end on a high note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2c4b&quot; id=&quot;2c4b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So I’ve spent quite a lot of time here explaining the problems of fractal stories. Let’s end on a high note. I want to explain why I’m so enthusiastic about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*z1VRhWGR-_oU_ca3uM7o7Q.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1080&quot; data-height=&quot;1920&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*z1VRhWGR-_oU_ca3uM7o7Q.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*z1VRhWGR-_oU_ca3uM7o7Q.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;206e&quot; id=&quot;206e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The form factor that Insignificant Little Vermin ended up with is a great fit for casual play, especially on mobile. It’s not taxing in terms of skill. It can be consumed in short bites of gameplay, or as a whole. It provides an element of chance. It lets you read a story that is unique to you, and lets you explore a world at your own pace. It doesn’t require you to squint to see what’s going on on the screen — it’s just text and a few static paintings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;542e&quot; id=&quot;542e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In short, it’s something that you can read &amp;amp; play while waiting on a bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5386&quot; id=&quot;5386&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I really, earnestly believe that this could be transformational for many indie game developers (some of whom are not even thinking of themselves as game developers yet). As I said before, this is not a system for a single writer-author-developer. Compared to Twine, the barrier to entry is very high. But compared to even the simplest 2D platformer, it’s relatively low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;6594&quot; id=&quot;6594&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;You can move you developers from graphics programming and 60fps performance optimization to core mechanics, simulation, and natural language generation. Remember, you don’t have a 16ms frame budget anymore, so your simulation and AI can take its time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;7c61&quot; id=&quot;7c61&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Your artists can spend less time filling in the details of the environment (grass here, wall texture there) and more time imagining interesting worlds and characters. They are also unrestricted by capabilities of the rendering engine. If they can describe it, they can use it. An army of 500 thousand dwarves streaming down a valley? Sure. A Ringworld-type structure where you can see terrain millions of kilometers away? Go for it. A Lovecraftian/Escheresque/non-Euclidean architecture? No problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;5b11&quot; id=&quot;5b11&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Designers are less bound to a single level of detail. Instead, they can let the player be both a general and a soldier in one game, and it will never be a problem. There’s so much less you need to implement with text than there is with graphics. Adding any gameplay mechanic is suddenly much cheaper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;cb5e&quot; id=&quot;cb5e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;A small team can create something that meets Skyrim in scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;f62d&quot; id=&quot;f62d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I can’t wait to see where this approach to game development goes. I’ll be updating this blog and my Twitter account with my progress. If you want less noise, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://egamebook.com/signup/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://egamebook.com/signup/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to the mailing list that I created to keep you updated on key moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;479b&quot; id=&quot;479b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;And if you missed the link, &lt;a href=&quot;https://egamebook.com/vermin&quot; data-href=&quot;https://egamebook.com/vermin&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here’s Insignificant Little Vermin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifcomp.org/ballot/#entry-1669&quot; data-href=&quot;https://ifcomp.org/ballot/#entry-1669&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here’s its submission&lt;/a&gt; at IFCOMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 11:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ellinokon</dc:creator>
<og:title>Skyrim rendered in text – Filip Hracek – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@filiph/skyrim-rendered-in-text-1899548ab2c4</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*VgFUxD7mhk9MHSSZvsKi4g.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>Fractal stories, or how to build an open-world text adventure</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@filiph/skyrim-rendered-in-text-1899548ab2c4</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I bought a Switch from Nintendo and they threatened me with legal action</title>
<link>https://headmelted.com/i-bought-a-switch-from-nintendo-and-they-threatened-me-with-legal-action-6ea77b4f1eb9</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://headmelted.com/i-bought-a-switch-from-nintendo-and-they-threatened-me-with-legal-action-6ea77b4f1eb9</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h2 name=&quot;d9a4&quot; id=&quot;d9a4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--h3 graf--subtitle&quot;&gt;A tale of three Switches, and a reminder of the importance of good customer service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;157&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ec54&quot; id=&quot;ec54&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;What a month it has been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8a88&quot; id=&quot;8a88&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I haven’t updated in a while, and I’m sorry for that. I’ve had quite a bit going on in the run up to the holidays — but I’m getting back up to speed on things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bd1c&quot; id=&quot;bd1c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I wanted to share an experience I had recently (&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;it’s still ongoing actually&lt;/em&gt;) that came from buying a Nintendo Switch for myself and my kid in the run up to the Super Mario Odyssey release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a7b4&quot; id=&quot;a7b4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’m a lifelong Mario fan. I’m a pretty big Nintendo fan anyway, but for me every major Mario release is just a nostalgia bomb of happy memories from my childhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e497&quot; id=&quot;e497&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;By this point, I’ve played Super Mario 3D World with my 4 year old to the point that there’s virtually no collectibles left to find (some, not many). We bought the game pretty early in the Wii U’s life, although he has only really been old enough to become curious about “dad’s video games” in the past six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;024f&quot; id=&quot;024f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I have fond memories from my younger days of waiting for release day to roll around for major entries, but my son has never had that excitement of unboxing a new system and being blown away by the next new classic to come out of Kyoto. I wanted to share this with him while he’s still at an age where he’s impressed by his father’s nerdy hobbies (and before he realizes how uncool I really am!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3668&quot; id=&quot;3668&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The timing worked out quite well as it happens — my son’s school would be shutting down for half-term break just as the game was releasing and I had already arranged to take a break from work to spend that time with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;b290&quot; id=&quot;b290&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A busted up package and a scratched-up screen&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b155&quot; id=&quot;b155&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;I ordered the Switch on October 16th from Nintendo’s UK online store. I wanted to buy direct primarily to support Nintendo, so I figured it better that more of the margin ends up with them than a reseller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5968&quot; id=&quot;5968&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It didn’t take long to arrive — but when it did, I noticed some damage to the outside of the packaging. Concerned, I opened the box further to realize that the package had been more than a little disturbed — the internal contents had been removed from the bags and stuffed back in place again, and there were scratches on the screen and around the controllers that clearly hadn’t happened in transit. My assumption is that either this was a customer return that was shipped back out as new, or that the courier had intercepted the package (seems unlikely), but I contacted Nintendo to organize a return. These things happen sometimes, and at this point at least, they were gracious in offering to replace the item. I sent it back, but heard nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;03ae&quot; id=&quot;03ae&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I spent much of the next week in an odd cat-and-mouse game with Nintendo’s support line —each day I’d be told that the replacement had already been dispatched (and that I would need to make myself available to sign for it), then be told the following day it wasn’t yet dispatched after the courier failed to show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6768&quot; id=&quot;6768&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Ultimately it seems that they received the Switch back, but for one reason or another (they offered a couple of conflicting ones), hadn’t shipped out a replacement or offered a refund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4066&quot; id=&quot;4066&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In the end I had to reorganize my work hours to make calls over the subsequent days to get the order sorted out. This was pretty disappointing, both because it was now affecting my work, and due to the plans I’d made with my kid around the school break that were now going to have to be scrapped (there’s no fun to be had in explaining to a wide-eyed four year old that the new Mario game has arrived but we don’t have the console to play it on). At this time I still figured this turn of events was not wholly out of the ordinary for customer support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c567&quot; id=&quot;c567&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And then the fun started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*ySnnGUyApi1vjo4R.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1416&quot; data-height=&quot;803&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;0*ySnnGUyApi1vjo4R.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*ySnnGUyApi1vjo4R.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;9a46&quot; id=&quot;9a46&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Here’s your Switch, and here’s someone elses, too&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2428&quot; id=&quot;2428&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;We’ve been trying to get ready for Christmas pretty early this year. Having two young kids means that I can’t really take risks with the Santa list, as the must-have toys tend to sell out &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, at least around here. So I’m guilty of having a few unmarked boxes stuffed away waiting to be sorted later (small toys — Hot Wheels, PJ Masks and the like).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;781b&quot; id=&quot;781b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Eventually the replacement Switch got delivered (packaging intact this time) and I was able to get it set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;847a&quot; id=&quot;847a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s off-topic for this article, but as an aside — I’m blown away by what they’ve done with this device. It’s almost supernaturally powerful considering it’s size. I thoroughly recommend you get one if you haven’t already — maybe just get it from Amazon, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a692&quot; id=&quot;a692&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;When checking through some boxes ahead of work the next morning I noticed an identically marked package had been delivered. I wasn’t expecting any other orders from Nintendo, so I checked inside and saw that it was another Switch (I didn’t open the packaging all of the way so as not to damage the shipping box — I could see enough of the contents to tell with some measure of confidence what it was).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;ef8d&quot; id=&quot;ef8d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some will point out (and some have!) that I could have quite easily saved myself a lot of time, hassle, and lost earnings at this point by just quietly holding on to the extra Switch and saying nothing to Nintendo about it. It certainly would have saved me a lot of stress, but it was morally not something I’d ever consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;64df&quot; id=&quot;64df&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;I reached out to Nintendo to let them know what happened as soon as I’d realized. I figured at the least I’ll get a thank you for letting them know, maybe even a poster or something in the mail for my kid’s bedroom if we’re lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2b33&quot; id=&quot;2b33&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The subsequent exchange did not go the way I imagined it would at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ecaf&quot; id=&quot;ecaf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At first, it was suggested by one representative that I just keep the extra Switch, which enthusiastically I advised I’d be happy to do if they were offering that as an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ce68&quot; id=&quot;ce68&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;I was then contacted by a second representative and promptly informed that if the item was not immediately returned they would pursue legal action against me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ef9f&quot; id=&quot;ef9f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This was shocking to say the least (given the context of the dialogue until that point). On asking at what time this collection would occur (so I could plan around it) I was told that it’s impossible to say, and I would need to make myself available to hand over the item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e652&quot; id=&quot;e652&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Being available as described would mean spending an additional day away from work to wait for a courier who (based on past experiences) may or may not turn up. &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;If the courier didn’t turn up, would I be accused of theft? Would they really proceed to legal action?&lt;/em&gt; I assumed no, but I’m no legal expert, so I decided to just co-operate until this was sorted and not risk further stress over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;1fd5&quot; id=&quot;1fd5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Where things stand now&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;91eb&quot; id=&quot;91eb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;This was a relatively straight-forward transaction that had quickly snowballed into being a very costly timesink, and just about the worst experience I’ve had purchasing something online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;680c&quot; id=&quot;680c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As I work independently, I’m not paid for time not spent directly working on client projects. Between the time spent chasing Nintendo’s support line, and waiting for their couriers, this has now cost me in lost income more than the original cost of the Switch, and I’m still waiting for Nintendo’s courier to pick up the &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;third&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Switch now, lest I get taken to court for being mistakenly sent the item in the first place. I expect I’ll incur further costs and lost income until this is sorted out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;59d7&quot; id=&quot;59d7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It has been an utterly baffling turn of events to say the least. I’ve asked for a comment from Nintendo’s UK support regarding the experience but they’ve not as yet provided one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;2b98&quot; id=&quot;2b98&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;They still make some fantastic games, though&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;95a1&quot; id=&quot;95a1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;I’m still a fan of Nintendo’s products, if not their customer service. Now that I have the Switch, I’m really impressed with it — I just really think Nintendo should look at their standards around their direct sales and their policies when things go wrong. Retailers like Amazon get this so right these days, that it’s hard to imagine the process going this far off the rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b308&quot; id=&quot;b308&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It shouldn’t need to be said that threatening customers is terrible practice in any context, especially so when it’s unprovoked and un-necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;948b&quot; id=&quot;948b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;I’ll try to update this article when the matter is finally resolved (hopefully amicably).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 11:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>headmelted</dc:creator>
<og:title>I bought a Switch from Nintendo, and they threatened me with legal action</og:title>
<og:url>https://headmelted.com/i-bought-a-switch-from-nintendo-and-they-threatened-me-with-legal-action-6ea77b4f1eb9</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/0*CsuxJwes8WDwRa5L.png</og:image>
<og:description>A tale of three Switches, and a reminder of the importance of good customer service</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://headmelted.com/i-bought-a-switch-from-nintendo-and-they-threatened-me-with-legal-action-6ea77b4f1eb9?gi=b5cf2bfbbe18</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OVH Incident in Strasbourg</title>
<link>http://status.ovh.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://status.ovh.com</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;tasklist_table&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Sort by this column&quot; href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?order=id&amp;amp;project=0&amp;amp;tasks=&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;sort=desc&amp;amp;order2=lastedit&amp;amp;sort2=desc&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;ID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Sort by this column&quot; href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?order=proj&amp;amp;project=0&amp;amp;tasks=&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;sort=asc&amp;amp;order2=lastedit&amp;amp;sort2=desc&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Sort by this column&quot; href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?order=type&amp;amp;project=0&amp;amp;tasks=&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;sort=asc&amp;amp;order2=lastedit&amp;amp;sort2=desc&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Task Type&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Sort by this column&quot; href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?order=cat&amp;amp;project=0&amp;amp;tasks=&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;sort=asc&amp;amp;order2=lastedit&amp;amp;sort2=desc&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Category&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Summary&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Sort by this column&quot; href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?order=status&amp;amp;project=0&amp;amp;tasks=&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;sort=desc&amp;amp;order2=lastedit&amp;amp;sort2=desc&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;orderby&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Sort by this column&quot; href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?order=lastedit&amp;amp;project=0&amp;amp;tasks=&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;sort=asc&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort2=desc&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Last Edited  &lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/desc.png&quot; alt=&quot;icon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Sort by this column&quot; href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?order=prog&amp;amp;project=0&amp;amp;tasks=&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;sort=desc&amp;amp;order2=lastedit&amp;amp;sort2=desc&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Progress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15162&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15162&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15162&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Incident&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Strasbourg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15162&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;SBG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;In progress&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15161&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15161&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15161&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;SBG-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15161&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;sbg2-19a/b-n56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15160&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15160&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15160&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;RBX-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15160&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Rack/Baie 31A03 - vRack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15159&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15159&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15159&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Planned Work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;BHS-6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15159&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Nexus 3k bhs6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15158&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.14&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15158&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15158&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Planned Work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Whole Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15158&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Nexus 3k lim1/gra1/rbx4/rbx6/sbg1/waw1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15154&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15154&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15154&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Backbone APAC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15154&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;SYD &amp;lt;&amp;gt; SGP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15153&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.1764705882353&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15153&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15153&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Gravelines&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15153&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Gravelines &amp;lt; &amp;gt; Frankfurt links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15157&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.2183908045977&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15157&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15157&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Backbone US&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15157&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Beauharnois &amp;lt; &amp;gt; Toronto links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15156&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15156&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15156&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;RBX-6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15156&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;rbx6-21a/b-n56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15155&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15155&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15155&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;GRA-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15155&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;gra1-24a/b-n56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15151&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.1111111111111&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15151&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15151&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Strasbourg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15151&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Strasbourg &amp;lt; &amp;gt; Zurich / Milan links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-06&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15152&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15152&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15152&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Backbone EU&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15152&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;bor-1-6k &amp;lt;&amp;gt; th2-1-n7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-03&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15146&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15146&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15146&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;RBX-6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15146&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;rbx6-sd1ab-n9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-03&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-10.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;10% complete&quot; title=&quot;10% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15142&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.1363636363636&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15142&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15142&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Strasbourg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15142&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Routing - Strasbourg Datacenter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-03&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15150&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;3.2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15150&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15150&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;GRA-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15150&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;G113B04, G114B04, G114B11, G115A13, G115A24, G115A25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15149&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;3.5121951219512&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15149&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15149&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;GRA-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15149&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;G105B19, G106A04, G106B03, G106A09, G106A10, G106A11, G106A17, G106A19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15148&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;3.3684210526316&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15148&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15148&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;GRA-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15148&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;G104A19, G104A20, G104B03, G104B14, G104B16, G105B07, G105B18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15147&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;3.3488372093023&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15147&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15147&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;RBX-6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15147&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;46A16, 46A26, 46B08, 46B09, 46C02&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15136&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;3.3176470588235&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15136&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15136&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;SBG-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15136&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;71A36, 71A37, 71A39, 71B06, 71B04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15145&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15145&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15145&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Incident&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Whole Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15145&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Phone support - APAC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15143&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.0823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15143&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15143&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Sydney&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15143&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;syd1-c1/c2-n92 - network migration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15144&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.2134831460674&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15144&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15144&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Whole Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15144&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Strasbourg &amp;lt; &amp;gt; Frankfurt links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-11-01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15127&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15127&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15127&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Gravelines&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15127&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Gravelines &amp;lt; &amp;gt; Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15141&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.2405063291139&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15141&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15141&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Singapore&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15141&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Singapore DC - sgp-g2-a72&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15140&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15140&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15140&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;SGP-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15140&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;sgp1-c1/c2-n92&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15139&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15139&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15139&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;SYD-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15139&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;syd1-c1/c2-n92&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15138&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15138&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15138&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;SBG-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15138&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;71B55, 71B37, 71B54&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15137&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;3.3488372093023&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15137&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15137&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;SBG-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15137&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;71B08, 71B51, 71B52, 71B36, 71B33&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15135&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;3.0128205128205&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15135&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15135&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;SBG-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15135&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;71A46, 71A47, 71A48, 71A49&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15133&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;2.7325581395349&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15133&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15133&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;GRA-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15133&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;G113A15, G113B08, G115A20, G115A23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15134&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;2.7325581395349&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15134&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15134&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;GRA-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15134&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;G115A12, G115A22, G115B14, G104A09&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15131&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;2.7325581395349&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15131&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15131&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;GRA-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15131&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;G114B19, G115A07, G115A10, G115A11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15130&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;2.7325581395349&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15130&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15130&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;GRA-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15130&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;G114A09, G114A16, G114A19, G114A20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15126&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.0309278350515&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15126&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15126&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Strasbourg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15126&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Routing Protocol - Strasbourg Datacenter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15132&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15132&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15132&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;GRA-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15132&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;gra1-c1/c2-n92&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15129&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15129&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15129&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Incident&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Backbone US&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15129&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;CHI-PAO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15128&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15128&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15128&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Incident&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;BHS-6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15128&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;bhs6-c1/c2-n92&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15125&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15125&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15125&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Modernization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;BHS-6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15125&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;bhs6-sd1ab-n9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15123&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.0526315789474&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15123&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15123&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Strasbourg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15123&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Routing Protocol - Strasbourg Datacenter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15122&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15122&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15122&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Planned Work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;BHS-4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15122&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;bhs2-16ab-n56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15124&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.2405063291139&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15124&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15124&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Singapore&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15124&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Singapore DC - sgp-g1-a72&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15120&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot; readability=&quot;1.0561797752809&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15120&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15120&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Warsawa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15120&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Routing Protocol - Warsawa Datacenter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15121&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15121&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15121&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;SBG-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15121&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;sbg2-106a-n56-vrack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-0.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;0% complete&quot; title=&quot;0% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15112&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15112&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15112&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Whole Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15112&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;vac1-1-n7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15083&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15083&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15083&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Whole Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15083&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Gravelines &amp;lt; &amp;gt; Brussels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15119&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15119&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15119&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Incident&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;BHS-4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15119&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;BHS4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15110&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15110&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15110&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Incident&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Gravelines&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15110&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;gra-d1-a75&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15118&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15118&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15118&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;RBX-5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15118&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;vss-12ab-6k&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15117&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15117&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15117&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Whole Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15117&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;167.114.0.0/16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;task15116&quot; class=&quot;severity1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;task_id&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15116&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;15116&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_project&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_tasktype&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_category&quot;&gt;Whole Network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?do=details&amp;amp;id=15116&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;54.36.0.0/14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_status&quot;&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_lastedit&quot;&gt;2017-10-20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;task_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/themes/Bluey/percent-100.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;100% complete&quot; title=&quot;100% complete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;pagenumbers&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.2470588235294&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;taskrange&quot;&gt;Showing tasks 1 - 50 of 15085&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;numbers&quot;&gt;Page 1 of 302 &lt;span class=&quot;DoNotPrint&quot;&gt;  --   &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?pagenum=2&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;order=lastedit&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?pagenum=3&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;order=lastedit&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?pagenum=4&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;order=lastedit&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?pagenum=2&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;order=lastedit&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Next &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://status.ovh.com/?pagenum=302&amp;amp;string=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;sev=&amp;amp;dev=&amp;amp;due=&amp;amp;cat=&amp;amp;status=&amp;amp;order2=&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;sort2=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;project=&amp;amp;order=lastedit&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=a5382561e67d14e087fd62b12c44a9e5&quot;&gt;Last &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 08:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fvv</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-AU</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://status.ovh.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quake on an oscilloscope (2014)</title>
<link>http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/oscilloscope_quake.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/oscilloscope_quake.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Style-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;generator&quot; content=&quot;pandoc&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;Pekka Väänänen&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;date&quot; content=&quot;2014-12-28&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Quake on an oscilloscope: A technical report&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot; name=&quot;viewport&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;css/blog.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;186.84732696497&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com&quot;&gt;back to lofibucket.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/img/quakescope.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quake 1 rendered on a Hitachi V-422 oscilloscope.&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Quake 1 rendered on a Hitachi V-422 oscilloscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A summary of some problems I faced when tinkering with Quake to get it play nicely on an oscilloscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing some cool clips like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rtR63-ecUNo&quot;&gt;this mushroom thing&lt;/a&gt; and of course &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s1eNjUgaB-g&quot;&gt;Youscope&lt;/a&gt;, playing Quake on a scope seemed like a great idea. It ticks all the marks that make me happy: low-poly, realtime rendered and open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing-testing&quot;&gt;Testing, testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/seece/034e8c3c9debb0464d3a&quot;&gt;a simple XY-oscilloscope simulator&lt;/a&gt; in Processing. Youscope rendered cleanly in it after I added some phosphorus decay simulation so that longer lines are rendered dimmer. So far so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;rendering-lines&quot;&gt;Rendering lines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The XY-mode of an oscilloscope is pretty straightforward. Two voltages specify the horizontal and vertical position of the ray, so by varying these as a function of time you can draw shapes. Basically you output a set of 2D points with coordinates in range [-1, 1], view it in XY-mode on the oscilloscope and Bob’s your uncle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing a line segment is linearly interpolating between two points during some time interval. It’s important to keep the drawing speed constant between lines of different lengths because otherwise you’ll end up having lines with varying intensities. According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jmargolin.com/vgens/vgens.htm&quot;&gt;a great page by Jed Margolin&lt;/a&gt;, you don’t actually need to calculate the length of the line to keep the intensities at bay since an approximation will be enough because of the non-linear gamma curve of the monitor. I went with the correct solution though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to line draw line segments that are not connected together, you need to move the ray quickly across the screen without actually tracing a visible line. This can be done by spending more time drawing the visible lines and then scaling the monitor intensity accordingly to hide unwanted artefacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/img/simulaattori.png&quot; title=&quot;Phosphor decay also supported!&quot; alt=&quot;A simple XY-scope simulator written in Processing.&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A simple XY-scope simulator written in Processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I whipped up a toy where you could draw a single line with a mouse and it would get played back as audio from the speakers. Then I hooked up system audio output to line-in and verified it looked OK in the scope simulator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;output&quot;&gt;Output&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using audio for outputting the two voltages is natural, this is what tejeez did in Youscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quake is a game, games are realtime, so my audio generation routines better be quick too. That’s why I picked &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audio_Stream_Input/Output&quot;&gt;ASIO&lt;/a&gt; as the audio backend. First I spent a couple of nights hacking with the Steinberg ASIO SDK, but I just couldn’t get any sound out of it. Finally I resorted to using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portaudio.com/&quot;&gt;PortAudio&lt;/a&gt; which worked just fine for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Youscope recording is a 48 kHz audio file and it seems to work great on tape. The catch here is that apparently the soundcard used on the video doesn’t apply any low-pass filtering to the output, which pretty uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All sound cards I own apply a filter, so bandwidth was pretty limited. In practice this means less lines can be drawn per frame. I thought the problem could be solved with a higher sampling rate so I picked 96 kHz, the highest number my Swissonic EASY USB supports. Seems like this didn’t make any difference in the end as the picture looks almost the same at 44.1 kHz too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;portaudio-on-windows&quot;&gt;PortAudio on Windows&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stable v19 release of PortAudio didn’t compile out of the box on Windows. I had to manually remove &lt;code&gt;ksguid.lib&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;portaudio.vxcproj&lt;/code&gt; with a text editor. Installing the ASIO SDK was also necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-vectorized&quot;&gt;Getting vectorized&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two different processes: the Darkplaces Quake game and the audio synthesizer. Interprocess communication is done via a WinAPI named pipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite Quake &lt;a href=&quot;http://quake.wikia.com/wiki/Source_port&quot;&gt;source port&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://icculus.org/twilight/darkplaces/&quot;&gt;Darkplaces&lt;/a&gt; has an excellent software renderer I abused to get access to projected scene geometry. The engine was patched to save all the clip-space triangle edges sent for drawing, and then transfer these to a synthesizer process via a named pipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This geometry extraction phase doesn’t affect normal rendering, and a proper depth buffer is actually required for the last culling stage to function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pipeline on the Quake side is basically this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;for each object being drawn
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;for each triangle
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;clip the edges to screen borders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if edge is visible
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;and not already saved this frame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;save it to a list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;render the triangle normally, even though color isn’t used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if the synth process has requested more geometry, then:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;check if lines are in front of geometry via z-buffer sampling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;submit all visible lines of this frame to the synth via pipe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;culling&quot;&gt;Culling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting rid of duplicate and unseen line geometry is important, because the time budget per frame is tight and all time spent on redundant lines is totally wasted effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/img/without_and_with_culling.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hiding occluded lines with depth buffer checks is very important.&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Hiding occluded lines with depth buffer checks is very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular back face, frustum and precalculated BSP visibility culling are done first. I also limited the draw distance by discarding all triangles whose all vertices were far enough from the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To cull the duplicates a &lt;code&gt;std::unordered_set&lt;/code&gt; of the C++ standard library is used. The indices of the triangle edges are saved in pairs, packed in a single &lt;code&gt;uint64_t&lt;/code&gt;, the lower index being first. The set is cleared between each object, so the same line could still be drawn twice or more if the same vertices are stored in different meshes. Before saving a line for end-of-the-frame-submit, its indices in the mesh are checked against the set, and discarded if already saved this frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of each frame all saved lines are checked against the depth buffer of the rendered scene. If a line lies completely behind the depth buffer, it can be safely discarded because it shouldn’t be visible. This happens if it’s behind a wall or something. These checks must be done after all draw calls are processed since geometry isn’t drawn in a back-to-front order. I implemented this as a series of ten or so depth buffer samples along the line and discarded the line if all of them were occluded. This worked well enough but left still some stray “spikes” peeking behind the corner in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-synth-rasterizer&quot;&gt;A synth rasterizer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The line synthesizer audio thread has a queue of lines to be drawn. New lines are requested from the Quake engine (by writing an integer to pipe) in the main thread if it notices we are running short on stuff to draw. The audio thread consumes this line data on its own pace - longer lines take a while to draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audio is synthesized as stereo 96 kHz 32-bit IEEE floating point data, but internally in PortAudio it’s converted to 32-bit signed integers before getting submitted to the ASIO output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, 1800 lines per frame are transferred to the synth process, and if no new data is received on time the latest frame will be shown again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-speed&quot;&gt;On speed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the video, about 5-20 samples are allocated to each line depending on the length of the segment. This means the frequencies emitted are very high (5 samples per period is 19.2 kHz) and it seems the audio output is being low pass filtered resulting in silly wobbly lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/img/speed_comparison.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image quality increases as the lines are drawn slower.&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Image quality increases as the lines are drawn slower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio synthesis takes some CPU time, but most of it is spent on Quake depth buffer rasterization. Triangle filling is slow when you do it with just one thread on a modest laptop processor :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total latency is passable and short enough to play comfortably with keyboard and mouse. This can be adjusted by tweaking audio synthesis parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-problems&quot;&gt;Open problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I was quite disappointed by the performance I got out of this. Merely 1000 lines on screen simultaneously, usually not even that. Any higher numbers end up being represented as such high frequencies the audio output can’t keep up. One can increase the time spent on each line but this causes additional latency and the image starts to flicker. Speeding up the drawing speed allows more stuff per frame, but the quality degrades quickly as can be seen in the comparison image shown earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also some &lt;em&gt;mysterious&lt;/em&gt; low frequency noise generated in the process. This is clearly visible when rotating the view quickly and the whole screen moves on the oscilloscope monitor screen. I assume this is some annoying bass boost equalization happening inside the sound card. &lt;del&gt;If you have any ideas what causes this, please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:pekka.vaananen@iki.fi&quot;&gt;email me about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mystery solved:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s the cheap sound card. (Thanks Antti!) With another USB sound card the low frequency movement is gone. Too bad there’s no proper ASIO drivers (ASIO4ALL isn’t enough) for it, making it unsuitable for realtime use because of additional latency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;possible-improvements&quot;&gt;Possible improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten some excellent ideas via email for improving the stability and quality of the rendering. I’m probably not going the develop this project further but I’m listing the suggestions here for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;audio-interface with DC-coupled outputs&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A regular sound card can be modified by removing capacitors before the analog output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.modularsynth.ru/en/2014/06/15/gigaporthd_dc_coupling/&quot;&gt;ESI Gigaport HD DC-Coupling Mod&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now the low frequencies aren’t filtered away and the picture stays stable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;strong&gt;VGA as DAC&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Really fast 8-bit digital to analog converter, precision can be increased with e.g. dithering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use red and green channels as X and Y signals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low latency and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Direct_coupling&quot;&gt;DC coupled&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No signal during vertical blanking interval, probably not a problem since it’s so short.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It actually looks &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?list=PLBPoTwsQYxSCc9C95p2RGuT-JulNEhsfH&amp;amp;v=9P1UJatH5jM&quot;&gt;pretty good!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resample the signal&lt;/strong&gt; to higher sampling rate with nearest neighbour filtering.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;strong&gt;intensity modulation&lt;/strong&gt; (Z-channel) to hide the beam when moving between lines.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Usually this input channel is on the rear panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would use three audio channels instead of two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;strong&gt;an extra sample to the beginning and end&lt;/strong&gt; of each line drawn.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Decreases wobbliness because of slightly reduced high frequency content. (thanks Andrew!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Windows, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.jriver.com/index.php/WASAPI&quot;&gt;WASAPI&lt;/a&gt; might reduce audio latency.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A good candidate if your audio-interface doesn’t have ASIO drivers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supported by PortAudio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sort the lines&lt;/strong&gt; before rendering to minimize beam travel distance.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;More geometry per frame can be drawn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/shortest_line_segment_path.html&quot;&gt;Travelling Salesman Problem reduces into this&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NP-hard&lt;/strong&gt;, so an approximation is needed:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A generic solver on the GPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dividing the screen into buckets and populate them with lines according start/end points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just draw the longest lines first
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;More time spent on drawing actual visible content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bias the selection with line distance in camera space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decrease line draw time according to camera space distance.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Less time spent on far away lines so more can be fit in per frame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Split the lines&lt;/strong&gt; to multiple segments when performing Z-buffer checks.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Picture is clearer with less line segments visible through walls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Quake level &lt;strong&gt;brush geometry&lt;/strong&gt; instead of the mesh used in rendering.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eliminates unnecessary lines since quads are rendered instead of triangles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works at least in Quake 2 (thanks Jay!)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware accelerated rendering, current system runs in software mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;video&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/aMli33ornEU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playing through the first level E1M1 of Quake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;audio-recordings&quot;&gt;Audio recordings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to watch this on your own hardware, here are recordings of the same playthrough that’s on the video. Try the fast one first and then the slow one if it doesn’t seem right. The difference is very small. I didn’t test these on the oscilloscope, I hope they work well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;e1m1_fast_48khz &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/download/e1m1_fast_48khz.wav&quot;&gt;WAV&lt;/a&gt; (36.9 MiB), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/download/e1m1_fast_48khz.flac&quot;&gt;FLAC&lt;/a&gt; (30.4 MiB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e1m1_slow_48khz &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/download/e1m1_slow_48khz.wav&quot;&gt;WAV&lt;/a&gt; (36.9 MiB), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lofibucket.com/download/e1m1_slow_48khz.flac&quot;&gt;FLAC&lt;/a&gt; (29.3 MiB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source code for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/seece/scoperender&quot;&gt;line renderer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/seece/darkplaceswire&quot;&gt;the modified Quake&lt;/a&gt; are available. Visual Studio 2013 is required to compile the projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-history&quot;&gt;Article history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;November 12, 2016
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added link to NP-hardness article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added link to VGA oscilloscope video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;July 13, 2015
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added source code links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January 6, 2015
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;em&gt;Possible improvements&lt;/em&gt; section. Thanks for the suggestions people!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 29, 2014
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Low frequency noise explanation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added audio recordings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small additions to culling part&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added picture of the simulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For feedback email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:pekka.vaananen@iki.fi&quot;&gt;pekka.vaananen@iki.fi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 02:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ivoah</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.lofibucket.com/articles/oscilloscope_quake.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Entrepreneurs Aren’t a Special Breed – They’re Mostly Rich Kids</title>
<link>https://www.asia.finance/entrepreneur/entrepreneurs-not-special-breed/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.asia.finance/entrepreneur/entrepreneurs-not-special-breed/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In a world where success is flashed across the globe at the speed of a tweet, where wealth can be created overnight and companies listed in a matter of years, many an anonymous entrepreneur has been thrusted into the limelight and glorified for their supersonic rise to success.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Indeed we have been conditioned to believe that entrepreneurs are a rare breed of people who possess more guts and gumption than the rest of us. Mention ‘entrepreneurs’ and images of Richard Branson, Mark Zuckerberg and Steve Jobs come to mind. The media portray them as a mysteriously talented, charismatic type with a bigger appetite for risk than the average Joe.  So it’s easy to fall into the trap of thinking that with enough attitude, one can succeed and become one of those glorified entrepreneur types.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The reality though, is that the genius, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asia.finance/entrepreneur/7-survival-tips-first-time-entrepreneurs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;risk-taking entrepreneur&lt;/a&gt; is the exception rather than the norm. Depressingly, studies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; show that most entrepreneurs are just ordinary people not much different from the rest of us, but with access to extraordinary wealth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Well-Connected&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;report, most startups are created by ex-bankers with deep connections.  And since it’s a well known fact that venture capitalists do not entertain cold calls but prefer to be introduced to founders via their own connections, this creates an ecosystem where bankers, wealthy investors and VCs can network and get their startups off the ground.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Interestingly, most of these connections begin in renowned universities. Alumnus of Harvard, MIT and Yale frequently end up working in top banks, venture capital firms and other established companies like Google and McKinsey where they continue to build networks with powerful people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jeff Bezos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, for example, appears to be a classic case of the well educated and well connected. He is a Princeton graduate who worked on Wall Street for a decade before launching Amazon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Wealthy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Being well connected usually overlaps with being wealthy. Most successful business owners can be traced back to wealthy families.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; Founders who have rich backings can tide through the early years because they have access to cash flow – something most poor and middle class entrepreneurs do not. For example, everyone knows&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Bill Gates&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;started Microsoft but not many know that his wealthy parents funded his company and helped him land his first client in IBM.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talent or Connections?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Critics argue that just being wealthy and well-connected doesn’t guarantee success. Take the case of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Its well-connected founder successfully raises USD41 million without even having a product, only to fail spectacularly not long after.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So is a successful entrepreneur like&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Brit Morin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;a product of sheer talent or good connections? Some argue it takes a good dose of talent to make it to top universities and work in renowned companies in the first place. Bill Gates, for example, was a genius coder way before he went to (and dropped out of) Harvard and started Microsoft.  And it is these capable people – the ones with &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; talent and connections to wealth – who ultimately stand out from the rest.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hustlers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Still, Silicon Valley is full of Brit Morins and the scrappy entrepreneurs who make it on their own are few and far in between. Despite the gloomy statistics, not everyone have to be wealthy and well-connected to become a successful entrepreneur as this&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;survey&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;shows. Those without cash and social capital hustle their way to success. Legendary &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asia.finance/lifestyle/lifestyle-people/these-billionaires-started-from-the-bottom-now-theyre-here/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rags-to-riches stories&lt;/a&gt; are legendary exactly because they are rare.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So remember the reality to remind yourself that it’s not easy to be a successful entrepreneur but don’t let that stop you from reaching for the skies!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>monsieurpng</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://images.asia.finance/contents/images/20161031120144/richkidsWP.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Entrepreneurs Aren’t A Special Breed - They’re Mostly Rich Kids - Asia Finance</og:title>
<og:description>The media glorifies entrepreneur. The sobering reality is that the majority of them are just regular Joes with access to wealth.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.asia.finance/entrepreneur/entrepreneurs-not-special-breed/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.asia.finance/entrepreneur/entrepreneurs-not-special-breed/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Senators push to ditch social security numbers in light of Equifax hack</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/are-social-security-numbers-going-away/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/are-social-security-numbers-going-away/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-679539624.jpg?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Eyeing more secure alternatives to Social Security numbers, lawmakers in the U.S. are looking abroad. Today, the Senate Commerce Committee questioned &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/yahoo-senate-commerce-hearing-russia-3-billion-hack/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;former Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer&lt;/a&gt;, Verizon chief privacy officer Karen Zacharia and both the current and former CEOs of Equifax on how to protect consumers against major data breaches. The consensus was that Social Security numbers have got to go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rounding out the panel, Entrust Datacard president and CEO Todd Wilkinson offered some context and insight about why the U.S. should indeed move away from Social Security numbers — a step that the witnesses unanimously agreed was necessary if not wholly sufficient to protect consumers moving forward, in light of the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/tag/equifax-hack/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Equifax hack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Over 145 million Americans’ insecure identities are now forever at risk, and they have limited ability to protect themselves,” Wilkinson said. “A key question for this committee to consider is: What do we do now given these identities are forever compromised?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social Security numbers are a privacy nightmare. While a consumer who gets hacked can replace credit card numbers and other account details, a Social Security number is relatively permanent, linked to a real identity throughout a person’s lifespan. In the hearing, Wilkinson and many of the senators present argued that the U.S. needs to move to a dynamic system of personal identity, one designed with digital security in mind — a stark contrast with an inflexible legacy system that dates back to the 1930s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some combination of digital multi-factor authentication… is the right path,” former Equifax CEO Richard Smith said when asked about such a program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multiple times throughout the hearing, Brazil’s Infraestrutura de Chaves Públicas system of citizen IDs through digital certificates came up as a potential model for the U.S. as it moves forward. In this model, a certificate lasts for three years at maximum and can be used to issue a digital signature much like written signatures are used now. Unlike its counterpart in the U.S., these identity accounts can be revoked and reissued easily through an established national protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the Senate committee also advocated for “rigorous” data security rules, expanding FTC authority to enforce them and stiffer penalties to motivate companies to protect consumers proactively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The parade of high-profile data breaches seems to have no end,” said ranking committee member Bill Nelson. “We can either take action with common sense rules or we can start planning for our next hearing on the issue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, White House cybersecurity coordinator Rob Joyce made it clear that the Trump administration is also interested in &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://thehill.com/policy/cybersecurity/353588-white-house-cyber-coordinator-calls-for-end-of-social-security-numbers&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;abandoning Social Security numbers&lt;/a&gt; in favor of a more secure, more digital form of identification, stating that the form of ID has “outlived its usefulness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Featured Image: Douglas Sacha/Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 22:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Varcht</dc:creator>
<og:title>Senators push to ditch Social Security numbers in light of Equifax hack</og:title>
<og:description>Eyeing more secure alternatives to Social Security numbers, lawmakers in the U.S. are looking abroad. Today, the Senate Commerce Committee questioned former..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-679539624.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/are-social-security-numbers-going-away/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/are-social-security-numbers-going-away/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>