<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>US Federal Ban on Making Lethal Viruses Is Lifted</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/health/lethal-viruses-nih.html?_r=0</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/health/lethal-viruses-nih.html?_r=0</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;166&quot; data-total-count=&quot;776&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-2&quot;&gt;Now, a government panel will require that researchers show that their studies in this area are scientifically sound and that they will be done in a high-security lab.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;207&quot; data-total-count=&quot;983&quot;&gt;The pathogen to be modified must pose a serious health threat, and the work must produce knowledge — such as a vaccine — that would benefit humans. Finally, there must be no safer way to do the research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;108&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1091&quot;&gt;“We see this as a rigorous policy,” Dr. Collins said. “We want to be sure we’re doing this right.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;215&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1306&quot;&gt;In October 2014, all federal funding was halted on efforts to make three viruses more dangerous: the flu virus, and those causing Middle East respiratory syndrome (MERS) and severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;203&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1509&quot;&gt;But the new regulations apply to any pathogen that could potentially cause a pandemic. For example, they would apply to a request to create an Ebola virus transmissible through the air, said Dr. Collins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-1&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/health/lethal-viruses-nih.html?_r=0#story-continues-3&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;162&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1671&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;There has been a long, fierce debate about projects — known as “gain of function” research — intended to make pathogens more deadly or more transmissible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;246&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1917&quot;&gt;In 2011, an outcry arose when laboratories in Wisconsin and the Netherlands revealed that they were trying to mutate the lethal H5N1 bird flu in ways that would let it jump easily between ferrets, which are used to model human flu susceptibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;201&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2118&quot;&gt;Tensions rose in 2014 after the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention accidentally exposed lab workers to anthrax and shipped a deadly flu virus to a laboratory that had asked for a benign strain.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;101&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2219&quot;&gt;That year, the N.I.H. also found vials of smallpox in a freezer that had been forgotten for 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;234&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2453&quot;&gt;When the moratorium was imposed, it effectively halted 21 projects, Dr. Collins said. In the three years since, the N.I.H. created exceptions that funded ten of those projects. Five were flu-related, and five concerned the MERS virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;197&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2650&quot;&gt;That virus is a coronavirus carried by camels that has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/emergencies/mers-cov/en/&quot; title=&quot;WHO page on MERS&quot;&gt;infected about 2,100 people&lt;/a&gt; since it was discovered in 2012, and has killed about a third of them, according to the World Health Organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;178&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2828&quot;&gt;Critics of such research had mixed reactions. “There’s less than meets the eye,” said Richard H. Ebright, a molecular biologist and bioweapons expert at Rutgers University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;119&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2947&quot;&gt;Although he applauded the requirement for review panels, he said he would prefer independent panels to government ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;234&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3181&quot;&gt;He also wanted the rules to cover all such research rather than just government-funded work, as well as clearer minimum safety standards and a mandate that the benefits “outweigh” the risks instead of merely “justifying” them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/health/lethal-viruses-nih.html?_r=0#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;178&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3359&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Marc Lipsitch, an epidemiologist who directs the Center for Communicable Disease Dynamics at the Harvard School of Public Health, called review panels “a small step forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;214&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3573&quot;&gt;Recent disease-enhancing experiments, he said, “have given us some modest scientific knowledge and done almost nothing to improve our preparedness for pandemics, and yet risked creating an accidental pandemic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;66&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3639&quot;&gt;Therefore, he said, he hoped the panels would turn down such work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;233&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3872&quot;&gt;Michael T. Osterholm, director of the Center for Infectious Disease Research and Policy at the University of Minnesota, said he believed some laboratories could do such work safely, but wanted restrictions on what they could publish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;187&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4059&quot;&gt;“If someone finds a way to make the Ebola virus more dangerous, I don’t believe that should be available to anybody off the street who could use it for nefarious purposes,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;227&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4286&quot;&gt;“Physicists long ago learned to distinguish between what can be publicly available and what’s classified,” he added, referring to nuclear weapons research. “We want to keep some of this stuff on a need-to-know basis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/health/lethal-viruses-nih.html?_r=0#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 19:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fern12</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/health/lethal-viruses-nih.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>A Federal Ban on Making Lethal Viruses Is Lifted</og:title>
<og:description>The N.I.H. will create expert panels to assess controversial research into creating pathogens that easily infect humans.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/20/science/20VIRUS/20VIRUS-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/health/lethal-viruses-nih.html?_r=0</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Funding Yourself as a Free Software Developer</title>
<link>https://tyil.nl/articles/funding-yourself-as-free-software-developer.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://tyil.nl/articles/funding-yourself-as-free-software-developer.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d love to receive feedback on this, as I think being able to get donations easily for the work free software developers put in to their projects is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting to know more platforms and giving them a small write-up should help out other developers like me looking for the best platform for their use case. I’d also like to hear from developers already using a platform, to extend this article with more useful information on how to successfully get donors for their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;9.4067796610169&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to contact me, do take a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tyil.nl/&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt; section, and let me know about your experiences with funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 15:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mabynogy</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://tyil.nl/articles/funding-yourself-as-free-software-developer.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Plans Combined iPhone, iPad and Mac Apps to Create One User Experience</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-20/apple-is-said-to-have-plan-to-combine-iphone-ipad-and-mac-apps</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-20/apple-is-said-to-have-plan-to-combine-iphone-ipad-and-mac-apps</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/AAPL:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Apple Inc.’s&lt;/a&gt; iPhone and iPad introduced a novel way of interacting with computers: via easy-to-use applications, accessible in the highly curated App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same approach hasn’t worked nearly as well on Apple’s desktops and laptops. The Mac App Store is a ghost town of limited selection and rarely updated programs. Now Apple plans to change that by giving people a way to use a single set of apps that work equally well across its family of devices: iPhones, iPads and Macs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting as early as next year, software developers will be able to design a single application that works with a touchscreen or mouse and trackpad depending on whether it’s running on the iPhone and iPad operating system or on Mac hardware, according to people familiar with the matter. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Developers currently must design two different apps -- one for iOS, the operating system of Apple’s mobile devices, and one for macOS, the system that runs Macs. That’s a lot more work. What’s more, Apple customers have long complained that some Mac apps get short shrift. For example, while the iPhone and iPad Twitter app is regularly updated with the social network’s latest features, the Mac version hasn’t been refreshed recently and is widely considered substandard. With a single app for all machines, Mac, iPad and iPhone users will get new features and updates at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unifying the apps could help the iOS and macOS platforms “evolve and grow as one, and not one at the expense of the other,” says Steven Troughton-Smith, an app developer and longtime voice in the Apple community. “This would be the biggest change to Apple’s software platform since iOS was introduced.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple is developing the strategy as part of the next major iOS and macOS updates, said the people, who requested anonymity to discuss an internal matter. Codenamed “Marzipan,” the secret project is planned as a multiyear effort that will start rolling out as early as next year and may be announced at the company’s annual developers conference in the summer. The plans are still fluid, the people said, so the implementation could change or the project could still be canceled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Apple spokeswoman declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple wouldn’t be first to bring mobile and desktop apps closer together. Before it discontinued Windows software for smartphones, &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/MSFT:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Microsoft Corp.&lt;/a&gt; pushed a technology called Universal Windows Platform that let developers create single applications that would run on all of its devices -- tablets, phones, and full-fledged computers. Similarly, Google has &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-05-19/google-s-android-and-chrome-operating-systems-get-closer&quot; title=&quot;Google’s Android and Chrome Operating Systems Get Closer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;brought the Play&lt;/a&gt; mobile app store to some laptops running its desktop Chrome OS, letting computer users run smartphone and tablet apps like Instagram and Snapchat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s unclear if Apple plans to merge the separate Mac and iOS App Stores as well, but it is notable that the version of the store running on iPhones and iPads was redesigned this year while the Mac version has not been refreshed since 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple’s apps initiative is part of a larger, longer-term push to make the underpinnings of its hardware and software more similar. Several years ago, the company began designing its own processors for iOS devices. It has started doing the same for the Mac, recently launching a T2 chip in the iMac Pro that offloads features like security and power management from the main Intel processor onto Apple-designed silicon. Much the way Apple plans to unify apps, it could also one day use the same main processor on Macs and iOS devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more on Apple, check out the &lt;em&gt;Decrypted&lt;/em&gt;  podcast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That would make it easier to create a single operating system for all Apple gadgets. Will Apple go there? Chief Executive Officer Tim Cook has resisted doing so, arguing that merging iOS and macOS would degrade the experience. “You can converge a toaster and a refrigerator, but those things are probably not going to be pleasing to the user,” Cook said in 2012. Apple software chief Craig Federighi has called the blending of iOS and macOS “a compromise.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe so. But Apple has a long history of insisting it would never do something -- make a small iPad, say, or a big iPhone -- and then doing it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 14:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:description>Apple Inc.’s iPhone and iPad introduced a novel way of interacting with computers: via easy-to-use applications, accessible in the highly curated App Store.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iEm5Eple8YYg/v1/1200x800.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Apple Plans Combined iPhone, iPad &amp; Mac Apps to Create One User Experience</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-20/apple-is-said-to-have-plan-to-combine-iphone-ipad-and-mac-apps</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-20/apple-is-said-to-have-plan-to-combine-iphone-ipad-and-mac-apps</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Magic Leap One</title>
<link>https://www.magicleap.com/?utm_source=reveal&amp;utm_medium=TW&amp;utm_campaign=WTDO</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.magicleap.com/?utm_source=reveal&amp;utm_medium=TW&amp;utm_campaign=WTDO</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 iiWdod&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;Digital Lightfield&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Our lightfield photonics generate digital light at different depths and blend seamlessly with natural light to produce lifelike digital objects that coexist in the real world. This advanced technology allows our brain to naturally process digital objects the same way we do real-world objects, making it comfortable to use for long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 dOObLD&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;Visual Perception&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;The robust sensor suite on Magic Leap One detects surfaces, planes and objects, allowing for digital reconstruction of your physical surroundings. The result is a system that sees what you see, allowing lightfield objects to not only exist in the physical world but actually interact with it. Whether it’s virtual displays sitting alongside the computer monitor on your desk or a virtual panda that climbs across your living room couch, visual perception with machine learning unlocks the power of spatial computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 dOObLD&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;Persistent Objects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Our visual perception and room-mapping technology builds a digital replica of your physical environment – detecting and storing the precise location of walls, surfaces and other physical objects. Lightfield objects stay where you put them, just as they would in real life. Place a virtual TV on the wall over your fireplace and when you return later, the TV will be right where you &lt;span class=&quot;AttributesContent__StickySpace-s1v7p212-4 gIHnok&quot;&gt;left it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 dOObLD&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;Soundfield Audio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;To feel real, it must sound real. Our soundfield audio mimics the real world and relays distance and intensity with amazing quality. This allows you to hear exactly where a sound is coming from, meaning you’ll know how close a virtual T-Rex is as it stomps up &lt;span class=&quot;AttributesContent__StickySpace-s1v7p212-4 gIHnok&quot;&gt;behind you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 dOObLD&quot; readability=&quot;40&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;High-Powered Chipset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Our integrated processing unit delivers high-fidelity, gaming-quality graphics, with the power and performance of a laptop computer. From editing an elaborate 3D model to playing a first-person shooter in your living room, Magic Leap One produces lightfield objects in intricate detail, all on a highly responsive, self-contained wearable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 dOObLD&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;Next Generation Interface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;We live and think in a 3D world, not on a flat screen. Our spatial interface includes multiple input modes including voice, gesture, head pose and eye tracking. This collective input system provides the tools needed to break free from outdated conventions of point and click interfaces, delivering a more natural and intuitive way to interact with technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 14:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.magicleap.com/</og:url>
<og:title>Welcome</og:title>
<og:image>https://www.magicleap.com/static/icons/magicleap-og.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.magicleap.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SpaceX’s Falcon Heavy rocket sets up at Cape Canaveral ahead of launch</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/20/spacexs-falcon-heavy-rocket-sets-up-at-cape-canaveral-ahead-of-launch/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/20/spacexs-falcon-heavy-rocket-sets-up-at-cape-canaveral-ahead-of-launch/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-201.jpg?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;SpaceX won’t hit its 2017 target for a test flight of its new, huge Falcon Heavy rocket – but the massive launch craft is now in place at Cape Canaveral in Florida, where it will undergo testing including a full static test fire, as well as final assembly, before attempting its inaugural launch early next year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SpaceX CEO Elon Musk shared images of the Falcon Heavy set up in a Cape Canaveral facility, nearly complete minus some remaining elements like the fairing and payload that will top the rocket. You can however see the three boosters, each of which contains nine Merlin engines. Each of these three essentially represents a current Falcon 9, and the two that flank the central column are re-used Falcon 9s that SpaceX has flown for previous missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Falcon Heavy is SpaceX’s high-capacity rocket – it’ll be able to fly around 140,000 pounds of payload per launch once it’s ready to go. Bringing that kind of tonnage into low Earth orbit will mean that SpaceX can do things like combine more missions, as well as service a new category of customer with heavier cargo requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;slideshow slideshowify&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-thumb=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20-2.jpg?w=80&amp;amp;h=60&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; data-full-size-image=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20-2.jpg&quot; data-large-size-image=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20-2.jpg?w=1&amp;amp;h=1&quot; data-trigger-notification=&quot;1&quot; data-scalable=&quot;false&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20-2.jpg?w=1&amp;amp;h=1&quot; data-tc-lazyload=&quot;deferred&quot; src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/themes/vip/techcrunch-2013/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;elonmusk_2017-Dec-20 2&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-thumb=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20-1.jpg?w=80&amp;amp;h=60&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; data-full-size-image=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20-1.jpg&quot; data-large-size-image=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20-1.jpg?w=1&amp;amp;h=1&quot; data-trigger-notification=&quot;1&quot; data-scalable=&quot;false&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20-1.jpg?w=1&amp;amp;h=1&quot; data-tc-lazyload=&quot;deferred&quot; src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/themes/vip/techcrunch-2013/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;elonmusk_2017-Dec-20 1&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-thumb=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20.jpg?w=80&amp;amp;h=60&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; data-full-size-image=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20.jpg&quot; data-large-size-image=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20.jpg?w=1&amp;amp;h=1&quot; data-trigger-notification=&quot;1&quot; data-scalable=&quot;false&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-20.jpg?w=1&amp;amp;h=1&quot; data-tc-lazyload=&quot;deferred&quot; src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/themes/vip/techcrunch-2013/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;elonmusk_2017-Dec-20&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SpaceX is currently aiming to do its first Falcon Heavy launch in January – and it’s apparently going to carry Musk’s own Tesla Roadster as its payload – something that seemed like a joke until it wasn’t. Also, the first Falcon Heavy flight has a chance of ending with a spectacular explosion, as Musk himself has cautioned in the past that there’s some chance things could go up in flames shortly after launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing rockets is always a risky proposition, and this one has unmatched thrust and power, so how it works in actual use is something that SpaceX can only find out by actually launching one, no matter what ground test and simulations say.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 13:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mkarthik</dc:creator>
<og:title>SpaceX’s Falcon Heavy rocket sets up at Cape Canaveral ahead of launch</og:title>
<og:description>SpaceX won't hit its 2017 target for a test flight of its new, huge Falcon Heavy rocket – but the massive launch craft is now in place at Cape Canaveral in..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/elonmusk_2017-dec-201.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2017/12/20/spacexs-falcon-heavy-rocket-sets-up-at-cape-canaveral-ahead-of-launch/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/20/spacexs-falcon-heavy-rocket-sets-up-at-cape-canaveral-ahead-of-launch/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We Only Have Hours Left to Stop the NSA Expansion Bill</title>
<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/12/urgent-we-only-have-hours-left-stop-nsa-expansion-bill</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/12/urgent-we-only-have-hours-left-stop-nsa-expansion-bill</guid>
<description>&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;According to reports published Tuesday evening by Politico, a group of surveillance hawks  in the House of Representatives is trying to ram through a bill that would extend mass surveillance by the National Security Agency. We expect a vote to happen on the House floor as early as tomorrow, which means there are only a few hours to rally opposition.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The backers of this bill are attempting to rush a vote on a bill that we’ve criticized for failing to secure Americans’ privacy. If this bill passes,we will miss the opportunity to prevent the FBI from searching through NSA databases for American communications without a warrant. Worse, nothing will be done to rein in the massive, unconstitutional surveillance of the NSA on Americans or innocent technology users worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/11/house-intelligence-committees-nsa-surveillance-bill-includes-new-threats-and-old?page=8&quot;&gt;we wrote&lt;/a&gt;, the bill, originally introduced by Chairman Devin Nunes before the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, “allows warrantless search of American communications, expands how collected data can be used, and treats constitutional protections as voluntary.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The bill would  create an easy path for the NSA to restart an invasive type of surveillance (called &quot;about&quot; searches) that the agency voluntarily ended earlier this year because of criticisms from the FISA court. It would also give FBI agents the power to decide whether or not to seek a warrant to read American communications collected under Section 702.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Backers of this bill are rushing because they know that time is on our side. If we can rally enough voices of opposition, we can delay or defeat this vote, sending a powerful message to Congress. Every day can make a huge difference in this fight because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/702-spying&quot;&gt;Section 702, originally enacted as part of the FISA Amendments Ac&lt;/a&gt;t—the legal authority the NSA relies on to engage in this mass surveillance—expires in 12 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The vote on this is likely to happen today, so there’s no time to make phone calls or send emails. We are asking people to use social media to contact their representatives. &lt;a href=&quot;https://act.eff.org/action/urgent-we-only-have-hours-left-to-stop-the-nsa-expansion-bill&quot;&gt;We’ve set up a tool to help you tweet at your member of Congress&lt;/a&gt;. We also encourage you to find other social media accounts for your representatives (such as an official Facebook account) and post a comment there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;take-action&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://act.eff.org/action/urgent-we-only-have-hours-left-to-stop-the-nsa-expansion-bill&quot;&gt;Tweet Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;take-explainer&quot;&gt;Tweet at Congress&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 12:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DiabloD3</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Urgent: We Only Have Hours Left to Stop the NSA Expansion Bill</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/12/urgent-we-only-have-hours-left-stop-nsa-expansion-bill</og:url>
<og:description>According to reports published Tuesday evening by Politico, a group of surveillance hawks in the House of Representatives is trying to ram through a bill that would extend mass surveillance by the National Security Agency. We expect a vote to happen on the House floor as early as tomorrow,...</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.eff.org/files/issues/og-nsa-1.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/12/urgent-we-only-have-hours-left-stop-nsa-expansion-bill</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber is officially a cab firm, says European court</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com/news/business-42423627</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.bbc.com/news/business-42423627</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Uber app on a smartphone in front of a car&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef-1.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/140DB/production/_99293128_ubergetty.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Uber is officially a transport company and not a digital service, the European Court of Justice (ECJ) has ruled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ride-hailing firm argued it was an information society service - helping people to make contact with each other electronically - and not a cab firm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The case arose after Uber was told to obey local taxi rules in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uber said the verdict would make little difference to the way it operated in Europe, but experts say the case could have implications for the gig economy.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An Uber spokesperson said: &quot;This ruling will not change things in most EU countries where we already operate under transportation law. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;However, millions of Europeans are still prevented from using apps like ours. As our new CEO has said, it is appropriate to regulate services such as Uber and so we will continue the dialogue with cities across Europe. This is the approach we'll take to ensure everyone can get a reliable ride at the tap of a button.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In its ruling, the ECJ said that a service whose purpose was &quot;to connect, by means of a smartphone application and for remuneration, non-professional drivers using their own vehicle with persons who wish to make urban journeys&quot; must be classified as &quot;a service in the field of transport&quot; in EU law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It added: &quot;As EU law currently stands, it is for the member states to regulate the conditions under which such services are to be provided in conformity with the general rules of the treaty on the functioning of the EU.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption body-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Analysis: Theo Leggett, BBC business correspondent&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;EPA&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;This ruling is another example of how the courts and regulators are struggling to make sense of the phenomenon known as the gig economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since Uber was first launched less than a decade ago, it has repeatedly fallen foul of regulators in different countries - and has frequently been forced to change its business model as a result.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This ruling sets out clearly that Uber is, in legal terms at least, a transport company. Uber itself insists that there won't be a huge immediate impact on its business, but it could still affect how it operates in future and how it liaises with national governments. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uber itself has previously said this will undermine the reform of what it calls outdated laws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a wider basis, it could have implications for other gig economy businesses that try to portray themselves as little more than an app on a phone, connecting providers with customers; it appears the courts, so far, are taking a different view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That could ultimately have an impact, not just on ride-hailing services, but on other gig economy services - such as couriers and accommodation providers - who operate a similar model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption body-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;TUC general secretary Frances O'Grady said the verdict meant Uber must &quot;play by the same rules as everybody else&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She added: &quot;Their drivers are not commodities. They deserve at the very least the minimum wage and holiday pay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Advances in technology should be used to make work better, not to return to the type of working practices we thought we'd seen the back of decades ago.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The verdict comes after Uber was told last month that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-42012719&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;the appeal to renew its licence in London could take years,&lt;/a&gt; according to Mayor Sadiq Khan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uber's presence around the world has often been controversial, with protests staged against it in various cities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, Rohan Silva, a tech entrepreneur and former adviser to David Cameron, says the firm has made competitors up their game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Millions of people use these ride-hailing apps every day - not just Uber, but dozens of others too. They have brought real benefits, making it cheaper, easier and more convenient to get around the city,&quot; he told &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006qj9z&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Radio 4's Today programme.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;There has also been a benefit in incumbent London taxi cabs, which are now taking credit cards, which they resisted for years. That is a response to competition.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He added that similar services could soon face regulation as a result of the ECJ ruling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;There could be big implications for a sharing economy service like Airbnb, which will probably be regulated by the EU,&quot; he said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;What is fascinating about this right now is that different countries are taking very different views. Portugal has legalised Uber and Airbnb, whereas France is clamping down.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prof Andre Spicer, from the Cass Business School, welcomed the ruling. He told Today: &quot;Many people see the EU is actually leading the way in pushing back the almost unlimited power of tech firms and beginning to provide some limits around that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We also claim this fosters competition, but what Uber's model is based on is pricing, so much that they basically drove everyone else out of the market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This judgement will allow normal competition, so what we will see is lots of other smaller apps appearing around Europe.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 08:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chrisper</dc:creator>
<og:title>Uber is officially a cab firm, says court</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The ride-hailing firm had argued that it was an information society service.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.bbc.com/news/business-42423627</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/cpsprodpb/140DB/production/_99293128_ubergetty.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.bbc.com/news/business-42423627</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Artists and writers whose works enter the public domain in 2018</title>
<link>http://publicdomainreview.org/collections/class-of-2018</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://publicdomainreview.org/collections/class-of-2018</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;cc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://publicdomainreview.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/class-of-2018-version2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;817&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-25214&quot; srcset=&quot;http://publicdomainreview.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/class-of-2018-version2.jpg 1024w, http://publicdomainreview.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/class-of-2018-version2-300x239.jpg 300w, http://publicdomainreview.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/class-of-2018-version2-768x613.jpg 768w, http://publicdomainreview.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/class-of-2018-version2-600x479.jpg 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Top Row (left to right): Aleister Crowley; René Magritte; Siegfried Sassoon&lt;br/&gt;Middle Row (left to right): Alice B. Toklas; Pierre Bonnard; Winston Churchill; M. P. Shiel&lt;br/&gt;Bottom Row (left to right): Jean Toomer; P. D. Ouspensky; Anna Wickham; Hans Fallada&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured above is our top pick of artists and writers whose works will, on 1st January 2018, enter the public domain in many countries around the world. Of the eleven featured, seven will be entering the public domain in countries with a “life plus 70 years” copyright term (e.g. most European Union members, Brazil, Israel, Nigeria, Russia, Turkey, etc.) and four in countries with a “life plus 50 years” copyright term (e.g. Canada, New Zealand, and many countries in Asia and Africa) — those that died in the year 1947 and 1967 respectively. &lt;a href=&quot;http://publicdomainreview.org/search/%22Class+of+20%22&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;As always&lt;/a&gt; it’s a miscellaneous medley assembled for our graduation photo, including one of the chief figures of the Surrealist movement, Gertrude Stein’s lover, the other Winston Churchill, a war poet, and a mystic, magician, and mountaineer once denounced as the “the wickedest man in the world”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a little bit more about each of their lives (with each name linking through to their respective Wikipedia pages, from which each text has been based).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aleister_Crowley&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Aleister Crowley&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1875–1947)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aleister Crowley was an English occultist, ceremonial magician, poet, painter, novelist, and mountaineer. He founded the religion of Thelema, identifying himself as the prophet entrusted with guiding humanity into the Æon of Horus in the early 20th century. After attending the University of Cambridge (where some biographers allege he was recruited as a British spy), in 1898 he joined the esoteric Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn, where he was trained in ceremonial magic by Samuel Liddell MacGregor Mathers and Allan Bennett. Moving to Boleskine House by Loch Ness in Scotland, he went mountaineering in Mexico with Oscar Eckenstein, before studying Hindu and Buddhist practices in India. In 1904, while on his honeymoon in Cairo, Crowley claimed to have been contacted by a supernatural entity named Aiwass, who provided him with The Book of the Law, a sacred text that served as the basis for Thelema. Crowley gained widespread notoriety during his lifetime, being a recreational drug experimenter, bisexual and an individualist social critic. He was denounced in the popular press as “the wickedest man in the world” and a Satanist. Crowley has remained a highly influential figure over Western esotericism and the counter-culture, and continues to be considered a prophet in Thelema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ren%C3%A9_Magritte&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;René Magritte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1898–1967)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;René François Ghislain Magritte was a Belgian surrealist artist. He became well known for creating a number of witty and thought-provoking images which often depicted ordinary objects in an unusual context, and so challenging the observers’ preconditioned perceptions of reality. His work was hugely influential, especially in pop, minimalist and conceptual art. Magritte described his paintings as “visible images which conceal nothing; they evoke mystery and, indeed, when one sees one of my pictures, one asks oneself this simple question, ‘What does that mean?’. It does not mean anything, because mystery means nothing either, it is unknowable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Siegfried_Sassoon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Siegfried Sassoon&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1886–1967)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siegfried Loraine Sassoon was an English poet, writer, and soldier. Decorated for bravery on the Western Front, he became one of the leading poets of the First World War. His poetry both described the horrors of the trenches, and satirised the patriotic pretensions of those who, in Sassoon’s view, were responsible for a jingoism-fuelled war. Sassoon became a focal point for dissent within the armed forces when he made a lone protest against the continuation of the war in his “Soldier’s Declaration” of 1917, culminating in his admission to a military psychiatric hospital; this resulted in his forming a friendship with Wilfred Owen, who was greatly influenced by him. Sassoon later won acclaim for his prose work, notably his three-volume fictionalised autobiography, collectively known as the “Sherston trilogy”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alice_B._Toklas&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alice B. Toklas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1877–1967)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice Babette Toklas was an American-born member of the Parisian avant-garde of the early 20th century, and the life partner of American writer Gertrude Stein. Toklas met Stein in Paris on September 8, 1907, the day she arrived there from San Francisco after the devastating 1906 San Francisco earthquake. Together they hosted a salon in the home they shared that attracted expatriate American writers, such as Ernest Hemingway, Paul Bowles, Thornton Wilder, and Sherwood Anderson; and avant-garde painters, including Picasso, Matisse, and Braque. Acting as Stein’s confidante, lover, cook, secretary, muse, editor, critic, and general organizer, Toklas remained a background figure, chiefly living in the shadow of Stein, until the publication by Stein of Toklas’ “memoirs” in 1933 under the teasing title &lt;em&gt;The Autobiography of Alice B. Toklas&lt;/em&gt;, which went on to become Stein’s best-selling book. In 1954 Toklas published a book of her own, &lt;em&gt;The Alice B. Toklas Cookbook&lt;/em&gt;, which mixed reminiscences and recipes. The most famous recipe, contributed by her friend Brion Gysin, is for “Haschich Fudge”, a mixture of fruit, nuts, spices, and “canibus sativa” [sic] or marijuana. Her name was later lent to the range of cannabis concoctions called “Alice B. Toklas brownies” (despite the fact that the “Haschich Fudge” recipe did not originate with Toklas, nor is there any record that she ever made it herself). In 1963 Toklas published her autobiography &lt;em&gt;What Is Remembered&lt;/em&gt;, which ends abruptly with the death of Stein.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pierre_Bonnard&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pierre Bonnard&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1867–1947)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pierre Bonnard was a French painter and printmaker, as well as a founding member of the Post-Impressionist group of avant-garde painters &lt;em&gt;Les Nabis&lt;/em&gt;. Bonnard preferred to work from memory, using drawings as a reference, and his paintings are often characterized by a dreamlike quality. The intimate domestic scenes, for which he is perhaps best known, often include his wife Marthe de Meligny. Bonnard has been described as “the most thoroughly idiosyncratic of all the great twentieth-century painters”, and the unusual vantage points of his compositions rely less on traditional modes of pictorial structure than voluptuous color, poetic allusions and visual wit. Identified as a late practitioner of Impressionism in the early 20th century, Bonnard has since been recognized for his unique use of color and his complex imagery. “It’s not just the colors that radiate in a Bonnard”, writes Roberta Smith, “there’s also the heat of mixed emotions, rubbed into smoothness, shrouded in chromatic veils and intensified by unexpected spatial conundrums and by elusive, uneasy figures.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Winston_Churchill_(novelist)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Winston Churchill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1871–1947)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winston Churchill was an American best-selling novelist of the early 20th century. He is nowadays overshadowed, even as a writer, by a certain cigar-toting British statesman of the same name, with whom he was acquainted, but not related. Their lives had some interesting parallels. They both gained their tertiary education at service colleges and briefly served (during the same period) as officers in their respective countries’ armed forces (one was a naval, the other an army officer). Both Churchills were keen amateur painters, as well as writers. Both were also politicians; although here the comparison is far more tenuous: the British Churchill’s political career being far more illustrious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/M._P._Shiel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;M. P. Shiel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1865–1947)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew Phipps Shiell – known as M. P. Shiel – was a prolific British writer of West Indian descent. His legal surname remained “Shiell” though he adopted the shorter version as a de facto pen name. He is remembered mostly for supernatural horror and scientific romances, and his work was published as serials, novels, and as short stories. &lt;em&gt;The Purple Cloud&lt;/em&gt; (1901) remains his most famous and often reprinted novel. H. G. Wells lauded the novel as “brilliant” and H. P. Lovecraft later praised it as exemplary weird fiction, “delivered with a skill and artistry falling little short of actual majesty.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean_Toomer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jean Toomer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1894–1967)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jean Toomer was an African American poet and novelist commonly associated with the Harlem Renaissance (though he actively resisted the association) and modernism. His first book &lt;em&gt;Cane&lt;/em&gt;, published in 1923, is considered by many to be his most significant. He continued to write poetry, short stories and essays. After his second marriage in 1934, he moved from New York to Doylestown, Pennsylvania, where he became a member of the Religious Society of Friends (also known as Quakers) and retired from public life. His papers are held by the Beinecke Rare Book Library at Yale University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/P._D._Ouspensky&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;P. D. Ouspensky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1878–1947)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyotr Demianovich Ouspenskii (known in English as Peter D. Ouspensky), was a Russian mathematician and esotericist known for his expositions of the early work of the Greek-Armenian teacher of esoteric doctrine George Gurdjieff, whom he met in Moscow in 1915. He shared the (Gurdjieff) “system” for 25 years in England and the United States, having separated from Gurdjieff in 1924 personally, for reasons he explains in the last chapter of his book &lt;em&gt;In Search of the Miraculous&lt;/em&gt;, which recounts what he learned from Gurdjieff during those years. Some, including his close pupil Rodney Collin, say that he finally gave up the system in 1947, just before his death, but his own recorded words on the subject (“A Record of Meetings”, published posthumously) do not clearly endorse this judgement, nor does Ouspensky’s emphasis on “you must make a new beginning” after confessing “I’ve left the system”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anna_Wickham&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Anna Wickham&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1883–1947)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Wickham was the pseudonym of Edith Alice Mary Harper, a British poet with strong Australian connections. She is remembered as a modernist figure and feminist writer, though one who did not command sustained critical attention in her lifetime. Her reputation has improved since her death and she is now regarded as an important early 20th-century writer. During the 1930s she was well known in literary London, and wrote a great deal of poetry (much of which was later lost in war damage); but found it harder to get published. She did have support from the somewhat louche quarter of John Gawsworth, who put out a Richards Press collection of her work in 1936. An extended autobiographical essay &lt;em&gt;Prelude to a Spring Clean&lt;/em&gt; dates from 1935, the year in which she supported the just-married Dylan Thomas and Caitlin, and then quarrelled with them. She committed suicide during the winter of 1947.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hans_Fallada&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hans Fallada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1893–1947)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hans Fallada (born Rudolf Wilhelm Friedrich Ditzen) was a German writer whose better known novels include &lt;em&gt;Little Man, What Now?&lt;/em&gt; (1932) and &lt;em&gt;Every Man Dies Alone&lt;/em&gt; (1947). The latter — based on the true story of a German couple, Otto and Elise Hampel, who were executed for producing and distributing anti-Nazi material in Berlin during the war — was completed just before his death from a weakened heart after years of addiction to morphine, alcohol and other drugs. It was published by Penguin in 2010 under the title &lt;em&gt;Alone in Berlin&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 07:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>benbreen</dc:creator>
<og:title>Class of 2018</og:title>
<og:description></og:description>
<og:url>http://publicdomainreview.org/collections/class-of-2018/</og:url>
<og:image>http://publicdomainreview.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/class-of-2018-version2.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://publicdomainreview.org/collections/class-of-2018/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>DAWN: Tools for AI and Data Product Development</title>
<link>http://dawn.cs.stanford.edu/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://dawn.cs.stanford.edu/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;DAWN is a five-year research project to democratize AI by making it dramatically easier to build AI-powered applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our past research–from &lt;a href=&quot;http://cacm.acm.org/magazines/2016/11/209116-apache-spark/fulltext&quot;&gt;Spark&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.stanford.edu/~matei/papers/2011/nsdi_mesos.pdf&quot;&gt;Mesos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www-cs.stanford.edu/people/chrismre/papers/modiv923-zhangA.pdf&quot;&gt;DeepDive&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.stanford.edu/hazy/papers/hogwild-nips.pdf&quot;&gt;HogWild!&lt;/a&gt;–already powers major functionality all over Silicon Valley–and the world. Between &lt;a href=&quot;http://deepdive.stanford.edu/showcase/apps#memex-human-trafficking&quot;&gt;fighting against human trafficking&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms12474&quot;&gt;assisting in cancer diagnosis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.stanford.edu/~matei/papers/2014/genome_research_surpi.pdf&quot;&gt;performing high-throughput genome sequencing&lt;/a&gt;, we’ve invested heavily in tools for AI and data product development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1705.07538.pdf&quot;&gt;next step is to make these tools more efficient and more accessible&lt;/a&gt;, from training set creation and model design to monitoring, efficient execution, and hardware-efficient implementation. This technology holds the power to change science and society—and we’re creating this change with partners throughout campus and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re proud to be supported by the following founding members:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;member-logo&quot; src=&quot;http://dawn.cs.stanford.edu/assets/logos/members/intel.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;member-logo&quot; src=&quot;http://dawn.cs.stanford.edu/assets/logos/members/microsoft.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;member-logo&quot; src=&quot;http://dawn.cs.stanford.edu/assets/logos/members/teradata.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;member-logo&quot; id=&quot;vmware&quot; src=&quot;http://dawn.cs.stanford.edu/assets/logos/members/vmware.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 01:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>indescions_2017</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://dawn.cs.stanford.edu/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Buy, sell, send and receive Bitcoin Cash on Coinbase</title>
<link>https://blog.coinbase.com/buy-sell-send-and-receive-bitcoin-cash-on-coinbase-65f1b2c7214b</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.coinbase.com/buy-sell-send-and-receive-bitcoin-cash-on-coinbase-65f1b2c7214b</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;52.600941176471&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*icfZmzq9EV_eGw-fDRnb8w.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1600&quot; data-height=&quot;617&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*icfZmzq9EV_eGw-fDRnb8w.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*icfZmzq9EV_eGw-fDRnb8w.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;aa2c&quot; id=&quot;aa2c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;We’re excited to announce that customers will be able to buy, sell, send and receive Bitcoin Cash on Coinbase. You can read more about Bitcoin Cash on our FAQ page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1b39&quot; id=&quot;1b39&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Sends and receives are available immediately.&lt;/strong&gt; Buys and sells will be available to all customers once there is sufficient liquidity on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gdax.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.gdax.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GDAX&lt;/a&gt;. We anticipate that this will take a few hours. S&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;ee our update below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;d19b&quot; id=&quot;d19b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Our customers should benefit from forks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a88a&quot; id=&quot;a88a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Coinbase operates by the principle that our customers should benefit to the greatest extent possible from forks or other networks events. This is essential in our mission to make Coinbase the most trusted, safe, and easy-to-use digital currency exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7237&quot; id=&quot;7237&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash was created by a fork on August 1st, 2017. All customers who held a Bitcoin balance on Coinbase at the time of the fork will now see an equal balance of Bitcoin Cash available in their Coinbase account. Your Bitcoin Cash balance will reflect your Bitcoin balance at the time of the Bitcoin Cash Fork, which occurred at 13:20 UTC, August 1, 2017. You can read more about what a bitcoin fork is &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/what-is-a-bitcoin-fork-cba07fe73ef1&quot; data-href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/what-is-a-bitcoin-fork-cba07fe73ef1&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and our previous update on Bitcoin Cash &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/update-on-bitcoin-cash-8a67a7e8dbdf&quot; data-href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/update-on-bitcoin-cash-8a67a7e8dbdf&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;01cf&quot; id=&quot;01cf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We have been monitoring the Bitcoin Cash network over the last few months and have decided to enable full support including the ability to buy, sell, send and receive. Factors we considered include developer and community support, security, stability, market price and trading volume. You can learn more about Bitcoin Cash &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noopener noopener noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f909&quot; id=&quot;f909&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We will abbreviate Bitcoin Cash as BCH on our platform. Customers will be able to buy Bitcoin Cash using all of our supported fiat currencies: USD, EUR, GBP, CAD, AUD and SGD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f149&quot; id=&quot;f149&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Coinbase maintains a strict trading policy and internal guidelines for employees. Coinbase employees have been prohibited from trading in Bitcoin Cash for several weeks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;970f&quot; id=&quot;970f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Update on December 19 at 8:15pm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7273&quot; id=&quot;7273&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3 graf--trailing&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash sends and receives are functional. Buys and sells on the Coinbase website and in our mobile apps will be available to all customers once there is sufficient liquidity on GDAX. We anticipate that this will happen tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wlj</dc:creator>
<og:title>Buy, sell, send and receive Bitcoin Cash on Coinbase</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.coinbase.com/buy-sell-send-and-receive-bitcoin-cash-on-coinbase-65f1b2c7214b</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*icfZmzq9EV_eGw-fDRnb8w.png</og:image>
<og:description>We’re excited to announce that customers will be able to buy, sell, send and receive Bitcoin Cash on Coinbase. You can read more about…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.coinbase.com/buy-sell-send-and-receive-bitcoin-cash-on-coinbase-65f1b2c7214b?gi=580adeb4e2d6</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>