<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Gorilla Youngsters Seen Dismantling Poachers&amp;#039; Traps</title>
<link>https://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/2012/07/120719-young-gorillas-juvenile-traps-snares-rwanda-science-fossey/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/2012/07/120719-young-gorillas-juvenile-traps-snares-rwanda-science-fossey/</guid>
<description>&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just days after a poacher's snare had killed one of their own, two young &lt;a href=&quot;http://animals.nationalgeographic.com/animals/mammals/mountain-gorilla/&quot;&gt;mountain gorillas&lt;/a&gt; worked together Tuesday to find and destroy traps in their &lt;a href=&quot;http://travel.nationalgeographic.com/travel/countries/rwanda-guide/&quot;&gt;Rwandan&lt;/a&gt; forest home, according to conservationists on the scene.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 20:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>johnny313</dc:creator>
<og:title>Gorilla Youngsters Seen Dismantling Poachers' Traps—A First</og:title>
<og:description>Just days after a snare had killed one of their own, four-year-old wild gorillas worked together to find and destroy other traps in their forest home.</og:description>
<og:url>https://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/2012/07/120719-young-gorillas-juvenile-traps-snares-rwanda-science-fossey/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://news.nationalgeographic.com/content/dam/news/photos/000/569/56901.ngsversion.1421961417131.adapt.1900.1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/2012/07/120719-young-gorillas-juvenile-traps-snares-rwanda-science-fossey/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Level Design Patterns in 2D Games</title>
<link>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/AhmedKhalifa/20190610/344344/Level_Design_Patterns_in_2D_Games.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/AhmedKhalifa/20190610/344344/Level_Design_Patterns_in_2D_Games.php</guid>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;The following blog post, unless otherwise noted, was written by a member of Gamasutra’s community.&lt;br/&gt;The thoughts and opinions expressed are those of the writer and not Gamasutra or its parent company.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post is a more friendly and accessible version for our &lt;a href=&quot;http://akhalifa.com/documents/level-design-patterns.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; (by &lt;a href=&quot;http://akhalifa.com&quot;&gt;Ahmed Khalifa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#3a5c5749080a0a0f7a5d575b535614595557&quot;&gt;Fernando de Mesentier Silva&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://julian.togelius.com&quot;&gt;Julian Togelius&lt;/a&gt;). Also, we added some extra text that got cut from the paper due to the page limit. In this blog post, we discuss six of the most common level design patterns present in 2D videogames that are common and impactful for the overall player experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;161&quot; src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/dta9vk0dj4GfV6XvLNI2rsplhqoRgIoaqit9cRSQrDKL6IDcx2mjW6Tlpy6dJlIP-vhCYN4E6cCS_W32xp99OAY1EY4IbCJboSwA9wGlpr-hQlvlrbOTxP3bqhjl9PYuvrlgJ4Yi&quot; width=&quot;624&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;Table of Contents:&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many games depend on content variety to tailor their gameplay experience. Having repetitive challenges can lead to player boredom, so designers generally aim to create an experience that is constantly engaging. Games usually consist of many facets such as levels, mechanics, graphics, sounds, etc. One of the most unique is level design. It does not introduce a new dimension in the game, instead, it is concerned with the arrangement of the existing elements. With the high demand for content in games, level design becomes a major task in game design. Its role is of pivotal importance, to the extent of being assigned to a different team than the one responsible for game and mechanics design, for games with large scopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating levels, innovation and variation alone are not enough to provide quality player experience. Having frustrating scenarios, unclear directions or unappealing challenges are reasons that could lead a level to have a negative impact on players. When observing levels from existing games, it is possible to highlight common patterns that play a part in improving the quality of the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These patterns are simple conventions, meant to describe common practices used in level design. Level design is a subconcept of game design. As such, so are level design pattern a subset of game design patterns. However, level design presents many intricacies that stand out inside the scope of game design. The major role levels play in the experience of the game is reflected by the number of resources put into this facet of the design during production. Levels can highlight the story, create smaller short-term achievable goals and help shape the player experience, with the objective of enhancing player immersion. Level creation plays such an important part in a game that sometimes developers provide their audience with level design tools, so they can create and share new levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the level design patterns we present might be well known to game designers, it is important to formally document them. By doing such, we can facilitate communication between experienced and novice designers, ultimately contributing to the growth and sharing of level design practices. For this purpose, this work aims at formalizing the concept of level design patterns, providing not only valuable resource to novice designers but also groundwork for future study and design of such patterns. It is also our understanding that this work could be beneficial to the research community, especially in the fields of game design, game analytics, procedural content generation, and automated level design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, we describe in detail six level design patterns. These patterns are noticeable across a variety of 2D games. We discuss the principles and motivation behind applying these patterns and show examples of it being used across multiple games. This work does not showcase all potential or even existing level design patterns, choosing instead to focus on some of the most common, with the intent of formalizing the concept and laying the foundation for future research and discussion to extend upon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design patterns date back to the seventies, with origins in the work by architect Christopher Alexander [1]. Alexander created these patterns to find a more formal language to communicate with. The design patterns summarized recurrent problems that could be found in the environment and their respective solutions. The solutions provided worked as guidelines, and not as definitive answers, to the problems shown. This idea was transferred to software engineering in the nineties, when Erich Gamma, Richard Helm, Ralph Johnson, and John Vlissides published a book discussing software design patterns [2]. Similar to Alexander, they summarized recurrent problems in object-oriented design and suggested respective solutions to them. Kreimeier [3] introduced game design patterns in a similar manner to software design patterns as a way to solve recurrent problems. This definition has changed to be less strict so it views the game design patterns as a common reoccurring game design elements that affect gameplay [4], [5].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers, designers, academics, game makers and critics have been discussing design patterns for a long time. Often they are not referred to as design patterns, but as tips, tricks, guidelines, tools of the trade, etc. They usually refer to design pattern concepts by analyzing a certain level or area [6], [7], [7]–[9], game [10]–[22], genre [23]–[31], or being as general as possible [3]–[5], [32]–[42]. That information is usually based on their experiences from designing, developing and playing games. Most notable are patterns that are recurrent across multiple games. We list similarities between previous attempts at cataloging and classifying level design patterns and our own work in the upcoming sections whenever relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to finding and taxonomizing design patterns, studies have investigated how to use such patterns in procedural content generation. Thus, design patterns have been used for level generation [19], [25], [38], [43]–[48], but also in attempts to generate game rules [49], [50]. A common approach is to use design patterns as constraints during generation to limit the generative space to only include levels that make use of them [38], [43], [44], [48], [49]; this is most often seen in constructive generators [51]. Another approach is to use design patterns in fitness functions for search-based generators [52], to guide the search towards levels that utilize these patterns [25], [38], [45], [46], [50], and yet another to include patterns in a training set for a PCGML algorithm [53] to help in generating new content [19], [47].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The patterns we discuss are elements that are present in levels across multiple games, rather than being a feature that is recurrent on the same title. To this point, we choose to showcase these with screenshots from different games. We believe that having examples from different sources supports our point that these are valuable concepts with longevity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patterns were chosen to take into account their relevancy (if it is often discussed in the community or other works), their recurrence (if they were observed in a substantial amount of the games that were played) and their impact (how important is the pattern in the games that have it). Over 30 Games were chosen to form a representative set, mixing older titles and new ones; published from large companies to independent developers; different gameplaying experiences (such as platforming, racing games, combat-based, puzzle-based, etc); while prioritizing games that are relevant, either from being popular, having a strong community (or cult following) or being commonly referenced as a positive example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Definition&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;36.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Avatar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;the game entity the players control inside the game. For instance, Mario and Luigi in Super Mario Bros (Nintendo, 1985).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Boss&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;an enemy that poses a bigger threat than most. An example is Iceman from Megaman (Capcom, 1987).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Collectible&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;a game object that can be collected by the players. An example is the coins in Super Mario Bros (Nintendo, 1985).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Enemy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;a hazard that takes the persona of a character. Goombas from Super Mario Bros (Nintendo, 1985) are one example of enemies.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Environment Tile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;entities used to decorate the game, usually not interactable. Clouds in Super Mario Bros (Nintendo, 1985).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hazard&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;entities that hinder the player from completing their goal. An example is the spikes in 1001 Spikes (Nicalis and 8bits Fanatics, 2014).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Inaccessible Area&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;an area that players cannot reach, but that might become accessible at some point in the game. For instance, dungeon rooms in The Legend of Zelda (Nintendo, 1986) that require a key to enter.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Level&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;section of the game, where players act towards winning the game. An example is World 1-1 from Super Mario Bros (Nintendo, 1985).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mechanic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;an element in the game, visible or not, that enforces a rule. An example is the checkpoints in Sonic the Hedgehog (Sega, 1991).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Object&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;any entity that appears in a game scene and can change state. It includes hazards, enemies, power-ups and etc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Power-up&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;a collectible that positively impacts the players. The mushroom in Super Mario Bros (Nintendo, 1985) is an example of power-up.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Projectiles&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;moving entities projected from a hazard or avatar. Hammers thrown in Super Mario Bros (Nintendo, 1985) are an example.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rule&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;describes how the game is played and controlled. An example is a rule to collect all pellets to win in Pac-Man (Namco, 1980).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scene&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;a slice of a level/world that revolves around a concept, usually a challenge.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Screen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;the part of the game level/world that is currently visible to the players.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Solid Tile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;a game object that prevents the players from passing through it. An example is the floor in Super Mario Bros (Nintendo, 1985).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;World&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;a large game area that is built from multiple levels. For example, Brinstar in Super Metroid (Nintendo, 1994).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before presenting the patterns we observed, we identify the vocabulary we are using throughout the post. Such vocabulary is listed in the above table. This vocabulary is extracted from Anthropy and Clark [35], Bjork and Holopainen [4] and design pattern wiki [5]. It was then adapted to fit our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work, the patterns presented are the result of the position of game elements in the level in relation to each other. The reason we do not list checkpoints as a pattern, for instance, is that we frame it as a mechanic in the game. Nonetheless, the checkpoint mechanic can be used in conjunction with the patterns presented here. For instance, checkpoints are usually present in Safe Zones and are commonly associated with Pace Breaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the patterns are presented individually, they can be combined or modified to provide a new and fresh experience. It is recurrent that new design patterns can be generated from the combination or variation of existing patterns. For example, Thompson [30] showed that a pattern from New Super Mario Bros U (Nintendo, 2012) is a combination of multiple known patterns. It is also worth noting that the absence of a pattern does not represent bad design. These are guidelines and ultimately it is the designer’s decision to make use of such concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all patterns are applicable to all games or levels, so we choose to focus on those we believe to be the most common across different games. In this work, we present six patterns: Guidance, Foreshadowing, Safe Zone, Layering, Branching, and Pace Breaking. In the following subsections we discuss each individually, and present examples of how games have made use of them, by presenting screenshots as visual evidence whenever possible or necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;guidance&quot;&gt;Guidance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When playing a level, it is possible for players to lose track of the path they need to take, especially when exploration is an aspect of the design. The pattern we name Guidance refers to the use of non-verbal game elements to guide players in an intended direction. We rather classify verbal guidance and tutorials (verbal or not), such as a non-playable character giving instructions or tips, or a character showing you an action you can replicate, as a game design element of teaching or narrative purpose. This pattern encompasses the concept of guiding players both towards making direct progress in the level, as well as in the direction of a secret or collectible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;294&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/GedNq1A.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to guide the player is through the level shape. In this pattern, designers use solid tiles to guide the player eyes towards the target direction. This pattern has been discussed more often in 3D games [31], [32], [42], [54] than 2D ones [17], [36]. The main reason is in 3D games players usually have more freedom of movement which requires the designers to have to push them towards the next location. The previous figure shows how Super Meat Boy (Team Meat, 2010) and Super Mario World (Nintendo, 1990) use solid tiles to convey the direction the player needs to traverse the level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;289&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/dvswjZP.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most common representations of Guidance is done through the use of collectibles. It can indicate the main path, as well as provide awareness to areas players are not able to see yet. Developers can use this technique to guide players away from “bad decisions” such as performing a blind jump because they cannot perceive the correct path through another location. Collectibles can also be used to guide players into exploring a path that initially looks “dangerous” or incorrect, or to steer them into a safe location or target area when they cannot see ahead of them. An example can be seen in the previous figure. The figure shows two follow-up screens in Donkey Kong Country 2 (Rare, 1994). At the end of the second level of the game, if players dive where the bananas are located, as in the left image, in what looks like a bottomless pit, they will be greeted with the platform below, shown in the right image. This type of guidance has been mentioned in previous work by Anthropy [36], Smith [24], Pugh [32], Koncewicz [23], and Kremers [40]. The concept is referenced under multiple names, such as breadcrumbing [32] and signifiers [36], but the meaning remains the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3goqMGk.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hazards are another common artifact to represent Guidance. With positioning alone, hazards can influence players inertia, as pointed out by Anna Anthropy [36] and Milam and El Nasr [42]. In Expand (Chris Johnson and Chris Larkin, 2015) players move a pink rectangle in Polar coordinates, as opposed to Cartesian coordinates, trying to reach the center of the circle. The previous figure shows the comparison of a scene with and without a hazard, the red floor, in the inner circle. In such a scene, if the hazard is absent as in the right image, players can always resort to touching the inner circle and thus giving them more time to avoid the moving hazards. With the inner circle covered by the red floor, which kills on touch, players are forced to keep a safe distance from that area, as shown in the left image. Although both are the same scene, players usually proceed differently when approaching each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;296&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/R9sXdn5.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enemies can induce Guidance in a different fashion than most hazards. Enemies can be used to attract players attention, as they intend to fight them. This type of guidance has been discussed in the Boss Key Series [15] during the analysis of Super Metroid (Nintendo, 1994), it was discussed in the work Milam and El Nasr [42] during analysis of pursue AI pattern in 3D games, and in Hoeg’s work [22] during discussing the effect of movement on player choices in FPS games. The presence of enemies guides players towards their location. For instance, enemies in seemingly inaccessible locations cause the players to wonder how to reach such. The left image in the previous figure shows how Super Metroid (Nintendo, 1994) uses enemies to guide players into the intended path. The right image shows enemies being used to attracting players to a trap (where the floor collapses), rather than a rewarding path, in Castlevania Legends (Konami, 1997).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;282&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/4o8Qo4N.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another common representation of Guidance is using environmental cues such as highlighted tiles (changing the color or texture of certain tiles in the scene instigates player curiosity). This technique has been discussed in several previous work [3], [10], [15], [18], [31], [41], [42], [54]. Authors discuss how the use of different environment tiles can draw players’ focus to certain areas, instigating them to explore. The previous figure shows how different textured tiles are used in Super Metroid (Nintendo, 1994) and The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past (Nintendo, 1991), respectively, to evoke player exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;safezone&quot;&gt;Safe Zone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safe Zone is the pattern that refers to one or more areas in the current scene where the players are not exposed to negative interactions (hazards, enemies, and etc). Having Safe Zones creates pockets of space where players can analyze the surroundings and safely plan their next actions. They are especially important at the starting point (spawn point) for the avatar, as not to punish players before they can become aware of the challenge ahead of them. Safe Zones are rarely effectively drawn on the screen, but rather being identified after observing the scene for a short amount of time to notice hazard reach and patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;251&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3wtqKeu.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous figure, we draw, with red dotted lines, the line of fire of the enemies present on the screen, which are invisible in the actual game. In these examples, the Safe Zone is a space where the avatar can stand in without intersecting any line of fire. In the scene from Mega Man (Capcom, 1987) shown in the left image, we can notice Safe Zones on the bottom-most platforms, right above the leftmost ladder and at the top-right of the screen. In the scene from Star Guard (Loren Schmit, 2010) we can notice the Safe Zones as the empty black spaces. In these scenarios, it is common for players to try and devise strategies of how to move between Safe Zones while proceeding closer to their goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;262&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/6i1pbLA.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous figure, we draw dotted red rectangles to highlight Safe Zones in the scene. The level from Linelight (Brett Taylor, 2017) shown in the left image has a big center area where the moving hazards cannot reach the player. It is important for players to use the Safe Zone to maneuver the scene, as hazards move faster than their avatar. The right image shows that doorways of dungeon rooms in The Legend of Zelda (Nintendo, 1986) are Safe Zones that allow players to become familiar with the challenge they are about to face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safe Zones can provide the opportunity for Pace Breaking, a pattern we describe later in this post. They can also be used to express Guidance, guiding the player to favor certain paths over others. The same concept of Safe Zone has appeared in previous work [8], [24], [26], [34], but has usually been used to host checkpoints and save rooms [4], [5], [14], [36].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;foreshadowing&quot;&gt;Foreshadowing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foreshadowing is a literary concept [55]–[57] where the author hints at something that will happen later in the story. The general concept can be applied to games [6], [10], [14], [15], [41]. We then call Foreshadowing the pattern of introducing the player to an element under a controlled environment, before this element is more integral to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;278&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/i5DeTDi.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foreshadowing is a helpful pattern to help players experience a new game mechanic or game object without an explicit tutorial. Once players learned the basics, the game can present a challenging situation around this concept. The previous figure shows how Mighty Jill Off (Anna Anthropy, 2008) introduces a new hazard. The spider is first introduced in the scene shown in the left image and becomes more threatening later in the game as shown in the right image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/NlOKT4r.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above figure shows how a stage hazard in Mega Man (Capcom, 1987) foreshadows the boss fight in that level. During the level, players are confronted by the scissor-shaped projectiles shown in the left image which foreshadows the stage’s boss’s weapon, as shown in the right image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;294&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/gqhWNaa.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foreshadowing can also instigate players curiosity, making them excited about future possibilities. This is a common feature in games with an exploratory nature. The previous figure shows two examples of such. The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past (Nintendo, 1991) introduces objects that the player can only interact with later in the game, as shown in the left image. Super Metroid (Nintendo, 1994) teases paths only accessible after acquiring a power-up present later in the game. This application of Foreshadow tends to reflect a design that gives players incentives to backtrack, which is a common action associated with exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;layering&quot;&gt;Layering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Layering is the pattern of combining multiple objects to create a new experience. It often relies on Foreshadowing to be able to present a fair challenge to the player. The most common use of Layering is to introduce new and harder challenges, without the need to present new elements to the player. It benefits from previously introducing the different elements separately, which players are familiar with their behaviors, but have to devise a new strategy to overcome them. This pattern can lead to frustrating experiences when the outcome of mixing these elements is not planned. Many games use this pattern efficiently [9], [11], [13], [17], [20], [28], [35], so as not to have game objects that seldom appear and are deemed unimportant by the player (which is similar to Thompson’s Throw away pattern [12]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;280&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/uFaUGN7.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous figure shows how games can create harder experiences by combining multiple instances of the same enemy or hazard. While Lesbian Spider-Queens of Mars (Anna Anthropy, 2011) achieves such by using multiple of the same enemy, VVVVVV (Terry Cavanagh, 2010) does so by placing several copies of a moving hazard in a specific layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;278&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/BXO2Squ.png&quot; width=&quot;599&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous figure shows games that create a whole new experience by combining different elements. In Mega Man (Capcom, 1987), shown on the left image, the players have to wait to jump on the disappearing platforms when they become solid, but also have to pay attention to the enemy that runs from side to side on the floor they are standing. While in Mighty Jill Off (Anna Anthropy, 2008) players need to crawl up the level as fast as possible without touching the flames and before the spider comes out of the yellow box at the top left of the screen to follow the player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;branching&quot;&gt;Branching&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Branching refers to providing the players with multiple paths to reach their objective. Giving players a choice leads to a feeling of empowerment. As previous work before [4], [5], [7], [9], [12], [14], [15], [20], [24]–[28], [30], [34], [37], [39], we deduced that there are various ways in which this pattern has been leveraged to produce different experiences. Sometimes the game provides a false sense of choice [21] when to complete the level exploration of most paths are required, as is common with dungeons in The Legend of Zelda (Nintendo, 1986). In Mega Man (Capcom, 1987) levels were designed to be played in any order, as the players could choose to visit stages in any order. Therefore, every level had to be designed to be beatable with only the tools players are provided with at the beginning. Super Mario Bros (Nintendo, 1985) is famous for having pipes that players can enter to find an alternative path through the level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;284&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/6kWtIfU.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Levels can have Branching with no restrictions, meaning that all paths are open for players to select from. This reinforces the feeling of exploration during gameplay. The previous figure shows two scenes that use Branching with no restrictions. In L’Abbaye Des Morts (Locomalito, 2010) shown in the left image and The Legend of Zelda (Nintendo, 1986) shown in the right image, the players are allowed to freely choose which path to take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;301&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/LQE8Csq.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conditional Branching presents the players with multiple paths, but only allows them to access certain paths after meeting specific criteria. This form of Branching stimulates player curiosity and might require backtracking or repeated attempts to explore more than 1 path. The above figure shows 2 examples of Conditional Branching. As shown in the left image, Super Metroid (Nintendo, 1994) has doors scattered throughout levels that are locked until players find the weapon that can open them. In the case of Super Mario Land (Nintendo, 1989), the avatar can be in 1 of 2 states, small or big. The right image shows a level in Super Mario Land (Nintendo, 1989) where players can only access one of the paths if their character is small. This leads players to interesting decisions, as being small makes the player more fragile, but only then can they reach certain paths [7].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/oNPMSnV.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Branching can be used to create a risk-reward scenario [4], [5], [12], [14], [26], [30], [34], [37]. When presenting players with multiple paths, one can be a safer alternative with a small reward, while another requires higher skill, but has a bigger payoff. This gives incentive for players to spend more time with the game, as they are rewarded for their investment. The previous figure shows the racing games Excitebike (Nintendo, 1984) and SpeedRunners (DoubleDutch Games, 2013) applying risk-reward Branching. In both games players can choose to take a path the requires them to be more skilled at the game, but if successful puts them ahead of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pacebreaking&quot;&gt;Pace Breaking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pace breaking refers to purposely changing the dramatic arc of the game from one scene to the next. It is commonly used to either increase or decrease tension, in order to make players more invested in the overall experience. Audio and visual cues are some of the most powerful tools to convey Pace Breaking to the players. Layering is one pattern commonly coupled with Pace Breaking as the presence of multiple elements tends to generate natural tension, especially when creating a harder challenge [24], [25]. Safe Zones, on the other hand, can be used to have the opposite effect and break the pace to reduce the tension [24], [25].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;226&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/NoIRjBv.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common feature that creates Pace Breaking is the introduction of a hazard of conspicuous difficulty. Whether it is considered a boss fight or not, recognizing that they are in the presence of a bigger threat usually draws players attention, increasing the tension. The previous figure shows the difference between normal gameplay and boss fights in Final Fight (Capcom, 1989). In the transition to the boss fight scene, the game changes the scenario and background music, it then reveals an enemy bigger in size, wielding a weapon and with a different health bar, all which indicate this to be a new, harder challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;252&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/bDXtGmY.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decreasing the pace of the game can lead to interesting results. It can be used to give players time to relax and enjoy other aspects of the game, such as new environments or abilities. In other times, it is interesting to give players a moment of peace right before an intense scene to generate a climax (the calm before the storm) [35]. The above figure shows two examples of Pace Breaking to reduce players tension. In L’Abbaye Des Morts (Locomalito, 2010) shown in the left image, players are given time to relax after a sequence of stressful challenges and enjoy the scenery of the night sky. In turn, Mega Man 11 (Capcom, 2018) introduces a completely empty room right before the climax of a stage, the boss fight, as shown in the right image. This creates a calm sequence right before the height of the dramatic arc for the level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;288&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/eU8nd7o.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pace Breaking can be a powerful tool to introduce players to a new experience, feeling or mechanic in the game [36]. In Super Metroid (Nintendo, 1994) when players acquire a new power-up, it is common for them to have to make use of such in a very simple scenario to proceed. These usually come right after a climactic moment in the game, as the power-ups in Super Metroid (Nintendo, 1994) are usually given as rewards for beating hard challenges. The previous figure shows a similar approach in Lesbian Spider-Queens of Mars (Anna Anthropy, 2011). In the left image, we can see a regular level from the game, where the players have to use their laser to capture the other characters. Meanwhile, in the right image, there is the introduction of a level where the players are trying to reach the other characters before they break free and become stronger enemies. This change of pace breaks the normal gameplay of the game, that requires reaction and dexterity, to introduce a level with a run against the clock (timer) challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;293&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/vnULcpj.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example of Pace Breaking are levels designed to have choke points [4], [5], [28], arenas [29], or collision points [26]. These take players from a space where they have more freedom to move and escape hazards to a tighter space where interaction with hazards is usually unavoidable. The previous figure shows this concept in Mighty Bomb Jack (Tecmo, 1986). On the longer section of levels, as shown in the left image players control their avatar in a long corridor collecting power-ups and collectibles, while avoiding hazards. Meanwhile on the bonus stage, as in the right image, players are trapped in a small room where hazards are much harder to avoid while having to collect all bombs to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we introduced 6 level design patterns extracted from observing multiple 2D games. These are meant as conventions that can improve player experience and not requirements to create a quality game. The formalization of these patterns contributes to creating a universal language for developers, helping knowledge share and expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patterns are presented in this work individually, but it is common for them to be used in conjunction. Layering multiple hazards can create tension, resulting in Pace Breaking. Locked doors can foreshadow future branches to pursue. It is important to experiment around these patterns and not be restricted by them, as the solution to a design problem might require such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Level design patterns are generally used to have a positive impact on the gameplay experience. But it is worth noting that consciously subverting such concepts can provide a unique experience. For instance, Syobon Action (Chiku, 2007) and I Wanna Be The Guy (Michael &quot;Kayin&quot; O'Reilly, 2007) use the element of surprise in their level design. By presenting features common to famous 2D platform games, players are caught off guard with their unexpected behavior, such as having deadly traps where power-ups would usually be and having enemies spawn on top of the player character with no prior warning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The level design patterns show in this work are not restricted to 2D games. They were presented as the result of studying 2D games, but all are applicable to 3D games as well. The definitions are not restricted to 2D space, changing the context does not invalidate their application. Zombie hordes on Left 4 Dead (Valve, 2008) are a result of Layering and create tension with Pace Breaking. The concept of open world games, such as Red Dead Redemption (Rockstar Games, 2010), is an extrapolation of the Branching pattern. Super Mario 64 (Nintendo, 1996) constantly uses coins to guide players and foreshadow to instigate player curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patterns in this post can have a more technical application as well. They can be used as guidelines to procedural level generators, as part of fitness functions for search based generator, as training sets for machine learning algorithms or to guide towards having intentional level generators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, level design patterns have always been used in games. Having guidelines on how to improve the player experience is a very valuable tool. A formal taxonomy facilitates wider dissemination of these concepts, stimulating expansion and contribution, helping improve level design practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] C. Alexander, A pattern language: towns, buildings, construction. Oxford university press, 1977.&lt;br/&gt;[2] E. Gamma, Design patterns: elements of reusable object-oriented software. Pearson Education India, 1995.&lt;br/&gt;[3] B. Kreimeier, “The case for game design patterns,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/132649/the_case_for_game_design_patterns.php?print=1&quot;&gt;https://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/132649/the_case_for_game_design_patterns.php?print=1&lt;/a&gt;, last Accessed: May 23, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[4] S.Bjork and J.Holopainen, Patterns in game design (game development series). Charles River Media, 2004.&lt;br/&gt;[5] S. Bjork, “Gameplay design patterns collection,” &lt;a href=&quot;http://virt10.itu.chalmers.se/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;http://virt10.itu.chalmers.se/index.php/Main_Page&lt;/a&gt;, 2009, last Accessed: May 30, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[6] A. Anthropy, “Level design lesson: To the right, hold on tight”, &lt;a href=&quot;http://auntiepixelante.com/?p=465&quot;&gt;http://auntiepixelante.com/?p=465&lt;/a&gt;, 2009, Last Accessed: March 5, 2018.&lt;br/&gt;[7] A. Anthropy, “Level design lesson: In the pyramid”, &lt;a href=&quot;http://auntiepixelante.com/?p=459&quot;&gt;http://auntiepixelante.com/?p=459&lt;/a&gt;, 2009, Last Accessed: March 5, 2018.&lt;br/&gt;[8] A. Anthropy, “Star guard”, &lt;a href=&quot;http://auntiepixelante.com/?p=499&quot;&gt;http://auntiepixelante.com/?p=499&lt;/a&gt;, 2009, Last Accessed: March 5, 2018.&lt;br/&gt;[9] A. Anthropy, “Level design lesson: Low overhead”, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.auntiepixelante.com/?p=1022&quot;&gt;http://www.auntiepixelante.com/?p=1022&lt;/a&gt;, 2011, Last Accessed: March 5, 2018.&lt;br/&gt;[10] J. Penner, “Breaking the law of Miyamoto”, The Gamer’s Quarter, no. 7, pp. 4–11, 2006.&lt;br/&gt;[11] A. Anthropy, “Knytt syndromes”, &lt;a href=&quot;http://knyttlevels.com/levels/dessgeega-KnyttSyndromes.knytt.bin&quot;&gt;http://knyttlevels.com/levels/dessgeega-KnyttSyndromes.knytt.bin&lt;/a&gt;, 2011, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[12] T. Thompson, “Researching super mario bros. level design”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tzXpKlccRE&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tzXpKlccRE&lt;/a&gt;, 2015, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[13] M. Brown, “Super mario 3d world’s 4 step level design”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dBmIkEvEBtA&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dBmIkEvEBtA&lt;/a&gt;, 2015, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[14] G. Soup, “Cave story’s masterful game design”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c0sjTBzCW0&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c0sjTBzCW0&lt;/a&gt;, 2015, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[15] M. Brown, “Boss keys series”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLc38fcMFcVul4D6OChdWhsNsYY3NA5B2&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLc38fcMFcVul4D6OChdWhsNsYY3NA5B2&lt;/a&gt;, 2018, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[16] M. Thorson, “Level design workshop: Designing celeste”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4RlpMhBKNr0&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4RlpMhBKNr0&lt;/a&gt;, 2018, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[17] M. Brown, “How mega man 11’s levels do more with less”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nYxHMZX6lN8&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nYxHMZX6lN8&lt;/a&gt;, 2018, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[18] G. Soup, “Crosscode’s brilliant level design: Analysis”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dk9OEt02aDE&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dk9OEt02aDE&lt;/a&gt;, 2017, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[19] M. Guzdial, J. Reno, J. Chen, G. Smith, and M. Riedl, “Explainable pcgml via game design patterns”, arXiv preprint arXiv:1809.09419, 2018.&lt;br/&gt;[20] S. Dahlskog and J. Togelius, “Patterns and procedural content generation: revisiting mario in world 1 level 1”, in Workshop on Design Patterns in Games. ACM, 2012, p. 1.&lt;br/&gt;[21] M. Stout, “Learning from the masters: Level design in the legend of zelda”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/6582/learningfromthemasterslevel.php?print=1&quot;&gt;https://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/6582/learningfromthemasterslevel.php?print=1&lt;/a&gt;, 2012, Last Accessed: Jan 8, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[22] T. Hoeg, The invisible hand: Using level design elements to manipulate player choice. Guildhall at Southern Methodist University, 2008.&lt;br/&gt;[23] R. Koncewicz, “What made those old, 2d platformers so great?” &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.significant-bits.com/what-made-those-old-2d-platformers-so-great/&quot;&gt;http://www.significant-bits.com/what-made-those-old-2d-platformers-so-great/&lt;/a&gt;, 2009, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[24] G. Smith, M. Cha, and J. Whitehead, “A framework for analysis of 2d platformer levels”, in SIGGRAPH symposium on Video games. ACM, 2008, pp. 75–80.&lt;br/&gt;[25] K. Compton and M. Mateas, “Procedural level design for platform games.”, in AIIDE, 2006, pp. 109–111.&lt;br/&gt;[26] S. Larsen and E. Aarseth, “Level design patterns”, 2006.&lt;br/&gt;[27] S. Dahlskog, S. Bjork, and J. Togelius, “Patterns, dungeons and generators”, in Foundations of Digital Games. ACM, 2015.&lt;br/&gt;[28] K. Hullett and J. Whitehead, “Design patterns in fps levels”, in Foundations of Digital Games. ACM, 2010, pp. 78–85.&lt;br/&gt;[29] G. Smith, R. Anderson, B. Kopleck, Z. Lindblad, L. Scott, A. Wardell, J. Whitehead, and M. Mateas, “Situating quests: Design patterns for quest and level design in role-playing games”, in International Conference on Interactive Digital Storytelling. Springer, 2011, pp. 326–329.&lt;br/&gt;[30] T. Thompson, “The fine line between rehash and sequel: Design patterns of the super mario series”, in Workshop on Design Patterns in Games, vol. 15, 2015.&lt;br/&gt;[31] G. J. Winters and J. Zhu, “Guiding players through structural composition patterns in 3d adventure games.”, in FDG, 2014.&lt;br/&gt;[32] T. Pugh, “Level design tips and tricks”, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/TomPugh/20181022/329044/LevelDesignTipsandTricks.php&quot;&gt;http://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/TomPugh/20181022/329044/LevelDesignTipsandTricks.php&lt;/a&gt;, 2018, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[33] R. Terrell, “Folded level design”, &lt;a href=&quot;http://critical-gaming.com/blog/2008/8/5/folded-level-design.html&quot;&gt;http://critical-gaming.com/blog/2008/8/5/folded-level-design.html&lt;/a&gt;, 2008, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[34] A. Stamos, “Level design primer”, &lt;a href=&quot;http://renegadesector.com/level-design-primer/&quot;&gt;http://renegadesector.com/level-design-primer/&lt;/a&gt;, 2014, Last Accessed: Jan 4, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[35] A. Anthropy and N. Clark, A game design vocabulary: Exploring the foundational principles behind good game design. London, United Kingdom: Pearson Education, 2013.&lt;br/&gt;[36] A. Anthropy, “Game dev 1”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1l-uRlLM6jjQ1vwyyb-QPphk-EIAAEiOfayMrvZwEQOQ&quot;&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1l-uRlLM6jjQ1vwyyb-QPphk-EIAAEiOfayMrvZwEQOQ&lt;/a&gt;, 2017, Last Accessed: March 5, 2018.&lt;br/&gt;[37] M. Sharif, A. Zafar, and U. Muhammad, “Design patterns and general video game level generation”, International Journal of Advanced Computer Science and Applications, vol. 8, no. 9, pp. 393–398, 2017.&lt;br/&gt;[38] S. M. Beaupre and T. G. Wiles, “General video game level generation”, 2018.&lt;br/&gt;[39] E. Adams and J. Dormans, Game mechanics: advanced game design. New Riders, 2012.&lt;br/&gt;[40] R. Kremers, Level design: concept, theory, and practice. CRC Press, 2009.&lt;br/&gt;[41] S. Rogers, “Everything I learned about level design I learned from Disneyland”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gdcvault.com/play/1305/Everything-I-Learned-About-Level&quot;&gt;https://www.gdcvault.com/play/1305/Everything-I-Learned-About-Level&lt;/a&gt;, 2009, Last Accessed: March 24, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;[42] D. Milam and M. S. El Nasr, “Design patterns to guide player movement in 3d games”, in Proceedings of the 5th ACM SIGGRAPH Symposium on Video Games. ACM, 2010, pp. 37–42.&lt;br/&gt;[43] A. Khalifa, D. Perez-Liebana, S. M. Lucas, and J. Togelius, “General video game level generation”, in Genetic and Evolutionary Computation Conference. ACM, 2016, pp. 253–259.&lt;br/&gt;[44] A. Khalifa and M. Fayek, “Automatic puzzle level generation: A general approach using a description language”, in Computational Creativity and Games Workshop, 2015.&lt;br/&gt;[45] S. Dahlskog and J. Togelius, “Patterns as objectives for level generation,” 2013.&lt;br/&gt;[46] A. Baldwin, S. Dahlskog, J. M. Font, and J. Holmberg, “Mixed-initiative procedural generation of dungeons using game design patterns”, in Computational Intelligence and Games. IEEE, 2017, pp. 25–32.&lt;br/&gt;[47] S. Dahlskog, J. Togelius, and M. J. Nelson, “Linear levels through ngrams”, in International Academic MindTrek Conference. ACM, 2014, pp. 200–206.&lt;br/&gt;[48] G. Smith, J. Whitehead, M. Mateas, M. Treanor, J. March, and M. Cha, “Launchpad: A rhythm-based level generator for 2-d platformers”, pp. 1–16, 2011.&lt;br/&gt;[49] A. Khalifa, M. C. Green, D. Perez-Liebana, and J. Togelius, “General video game rule generation”, in Computational Intelligence and Games. IEEE, 2017, pp. 170–177.&lt;br/&gt;[50] T. S. Nielsen, G. A. Barros, J. Togelius, and M. J. Nelson, “General video game evaluation using relative algorithm performance profiles”, in EvoStar. Springer, 2015, pp. 369–380.&lt;br/&gt;[51] N. Shaker, J. Togelius, and M. J. Nelson, Procedural content generation in games. Springer, 2016.&lt;br/&gt;[52] J. Togelius, G. N. Yannakakis, K. O. Stanley, and C. Browne, “Search based procedural content generation: A taxonomy and survey”, Transactions on Computational Intelligence and AI in Games, vol. 3, no. 3, pp. 172–186, 2011.&lt;br/&gt;[53] A. Summerville, S. Snodgrass, M. Guzdial, C. Holmgard, A. K. Hoover, A. Isaksen, A. Nealen, and J. Togelius, “Procedural content generation via machine learning (pcgml)”, Transactions on Games, vol. 10, no. 3, pp. 257–270, 2018.&lt;br/&gt;[54] C. W. Totten, An architectural approach to level design. AK Peters/CRC Press, 2014.&lt;br/&gt;[55] B. Ciplijauskaite, “Foreshadowing as technique and theme in “one hundred years of solitude”, Books Abroad, vol. 47, no. 3, pp. 479–484, 1973.&lt;br/&gt;[56] F. Muecke, “Foreshadowing and dramatic irony in the story of dido”, The American Journal of Philology, vol. 104, no. 2, pp. 134–155, 1983. [57] B.-C. Bae and R. M. Young, “A use of flashback and foreshadowing for surprise arousal in narrative using a plan-based approach”, in International Conference on Interactive Digital Storytelling. Springer, 2008, pp. 156–167.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 17:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>homarp</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/AhmedKhalifa/20190610/344344/Level_Design_Patterns_in_2D_Games.php</og:url>
<og:title>Level Design Patterns in 2D Games</og:title>
<og:description>This post discusses six common level design patterns present in 2D videogames that we found from analyzing over thirty 2D games.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/AhmedKhalifa/20190610/344344/Level_Design_Patterns_in_2D_Games.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dear Bureaucrat, my job wants me to lie</title>
<link>https://www.federaltimes.com/your-career/the-bureaucrat/2019/03/07/dear-bureaucrat-my-job-wants-me-to-lie/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.federaltimes.com/your-career/the-bureaucrat/2019/03/07/dear-bureaucrat-my-job-wants-me-to-lie/</guid>
<description>
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear Bureaucrat,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I supervise a procurement team. Every month, I’m supposed to sign a form acknowledging “responsibility to authorize and approve only essential obligations and expenditures.” But I can’t know whether each item we purchase is essential. Many of them are highly technical. I told the person in finance who collects the forms that I can’t judge whether any purchase is essential, but she said every account manager needs to sign the form and that includes me. I talked to my boss, and he told me to work it out with finance. I don’t like making these false certifications. It’s not ethical and I’m afraid it sets me up to catch the blame if it turns out one of the technical managers is requisitioning things we don’t need. Signed, George “Cannot Tell a Lie” W.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;Dear George,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;You are not alone. Government work often pressures us to make certifications that we cannot know the truth of, or that we know are false. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.strategicstudiesinstitute.army.mil/pdffiles/PUB1250.pdf&quot;&gt;Wong and Gerras&lt;/a&gt; did a frightening study of the need for Army officers to lie routinely. For example, they found commanders were required to certify their troops completed 297 days of mandatory training, when only 256 days were available for training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;The pressure to certify something you cannot know is more than an affront to your personal ethics. It is an excuse for your agency to not apply real controls that would prevent unnecessary purchases. It is also one more brick in building an agency culture where dishonesty is viewed as normal and necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;So what can you do? There’s the idealistic way, the popular way, or the subversive way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;The idealistic way is to work within your agency to eliminate this requirement to lie. Try to engage allies, such as the other people who are required to sign the false certification. This might lead to valuable and fulfilling professional relationships, but do not be surprised if the people you approach are unwilling to make waves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;When you get the issue in front of an official with power to make the change, she might join your effort to improve the process, or she may resist because reform is contrary to her interests. Requiring you to sign the form lets your agency’s officials claim they are assuring only essential items are bought. Eliminating that sham control would increase the risk to the officials of catching the blame if a scandal ever arises about unnecessary purchases. So the idealistic way might solve the problem, plus give you personal fulfillment and get you noticed as a leader, or it might cost you a lot of effort just to get branded a troublemaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container signup newsletter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-subscribe&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-subscribe-signup subtitle col-xs-12 col-sm-8&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Sign up for the Daily Brief&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Get the top federal headlines each morning&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;form id=&quot;newsletterForm&quot; name=&quot;emailsignup&quot; target=&quot;subscribeFrame&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; action=&quot;https://link.federaltimes.com/s/Editorial+-+Daily+Brief&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-subscribe-submit col-xs-12 col-sm-5 hide&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;email&quot; required=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Enter a valid email address&quot; id=&quot;email&quot; name=&quot;email&quot; class=&quot;form-signup&quot; placeholder=&quot;Enter your email address&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;form-country-dropdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newsletter-subscribe-submit-error hide&quot;&gt;Enter a valid email address&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-confirmation col-xs-12 col-sm-6 hide&quot;&gt;Thanks for signing up!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;close&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;&gt;×&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal-nl-cont row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;header col-lg-12 col-md-12 col-sm-12 col-xs-12 nopad&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;newsletter-description&quot;&gt;We've got you covered. Sign up to get the top federal headlines each morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;disclaimer col-lg-12 col-md-12 col-sm-12 col-xs-12 nopad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-9 col-md-9 col-sm-8 col-xs-12 disclaimer-copy nopad-left-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;nl-signup-disclaimer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newsletter-list-name&quot;&gt;By giving us your email, you are opting in to the Daily Brief.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-4 col-xs-12 logo nopad-left-right&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Federal Times Logo&quot; class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;https://www.militarytimes.com/pb/resources/assets/svg/federal-logo.svg&quot; width=&quot;150px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;The popular way is to go along with how things are done; sign the form even though you cannot know if it is true. As you noted, this is unethical and it creates a paper trail that might be used against you if your agency ever needs a scapegoat. But we get used to rationalizing compliance with bad requirements, as in “it’s above my pay grade.” And if others in your agency routinely sign the same false certification, then you have a little safety in numbers. It would be prudent to keep evidence that you presented your concerns to the finance person and your supervisor, and what they told you. If your exchanges with them were oral rather than email, then you can at least record the particulars of those conversations in an email to yourself — the modern version of a memorandum for the record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;The subversive way is to circumvent the requirement to lie. Can you cross out the offending sentence on the form each month before you sign it? Can you write in “Subject to attached explanation” before your signature and then staple on a page clarifying the extent to which you can assure that purchases are essential? On-line forms are harder than paper to hack in this manner, but there may be a field such as “comments” where you can enter text to condition your certification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;The point is to make a change that avoids putting a false certification in the record, while being unobtrusive enough that people up the line will file the form as usual rather than making you re-do it. I have used this method. It is not as heroic as fighting for explicit change, but it avoids creating a paper trail that could be used to make you a scapegoat. It also serves the public interest, because the culture of dishonesty in an agency is built or undermined by a thousand small actions. Whenever you comply with a requirement to lie, it helps lull yourself and your colleagues into accepting “that’s just the way things are done.” And whenever you comply, it shows your agency’s officials that they can depend on employees’ willingness to make false certifications, to cover up for official procedures that don’t work. When you circumvent a requirement to falsify records, that undermines the agency’s culture of dishonesty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; mco-body-item mco-body-type-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;element element-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear Bureaucrat is a new feature on Federal Times, providing the federal workforce with the opportunity to submit questions about their careers to David S. Reed, founder of the Center for Public Administrators, a 501(c)(3) civil society organization that builds communities of practice in the public sector. Reed has spent 35 years in and around government. He has worked for large contractors, owned a small contractor, and is currently a government employee. He holds a Master in Public Policy from the Harvard Kennedy School, and is a frequent speaker at public administration&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://conferences.is/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;conferences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send your question to&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:DearBureaucrat@PubAdmin.org&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DearBureaucrat@PubAdmin.org&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 14:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>David_Reed</dc:creator>
<og:title>Dear Bureaucrat, my job wants me to lie</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.federaltimes.com/your-career/the-bureaucrat/2019/03/07/dear-bureaucrat-my-job-wants-me-to-lie/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.armytimes.com/resizer/C3F-m8NPoqEKaHqPkbCQiTtV2wk=/1200x630/filters:quality(100)/arc-anglerfish-arc2-prod-mco.s3.amazonaws.com/public/HGESO37ZOBCNLBE4AHMGEWRYKQ.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The pressure to certify something you cannot know is more than an affront to your personal ethics. It is an excuse for your agency to not apply real controls that would prevent unnecessary purchases.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.federaltimes.com/your-career/the-bureaucrat/2019/03/07/dear-bureaucrat-my-job-wants-me-to-lie/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nearly 400 medical devices, procedures and practices found ineffective in study</title>
<link>https://www.sciencealert.com/recent-study-finds-400-medical-devices-procedures-or-practices-that-are-ineffective</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sciencealert.com/recent-study-finds-400-medical-devices-procedures-or-practices-that-are-ineffective</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We like to view modern medicine as based on rigorous science, and while it certainly beats the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencealert.com/alternative-medicine-more-than-doubles-your-risk-of-dying-in-cancer-treatments&quot;&gt;various&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencealert.com/what-is-black-salve-and-can-it-cure-cancer&quot;&gt;dangerous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencealert.com/this-case-study-shows-why-naturopathy-isn-t-evidence-based-medicine&quot;&gt;alternatives&lt;/a&gt; out there, sometimes physicians still end up &lt;a href=&quot;https://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2015/11/19/when-medicine-reverses-itself/&quot;&gt;adopting practices&lt;/a&gt; based on little evidence.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When a medical treatment, device or procedure is no better than previous or lesser alternatives, it's deemed a 'medical reversal'. These discredited practices are a major barrier to better and cheaper healthcare, but actually identifying them is surprisingly difficult and rarely done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent study, designed to create a more comprehensive list, has unearthed nearly 400 established treatments, devices and procedures that fit this bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We hope our broad results may serve as a starting point for researchers, policy makers and payers who wish to have a list of practices that likely offer no net benefit to use in future work,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2019-06/e-a4m061119.php&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; hematologist-oncologist Vinay Prasad from Oregon Health &amp;amp; Science University (OHSU), who helped coin the term 'medical reversal'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings are based on more than 15 years of randomised controlled trials, a type of research that aims to reduce bias when testing new treatments. Across 3,000 articles in three leading medical journals from the UK and the US, the authors found 396 reversals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these were found in every medical discipline, cardiovascular disease was by far the most commonly represented category, at 20 percent; it was followed by preventative medicine and critical care.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Taken together, it appears that medication was the most common reversal at 33 percent; procedures came in second at 20 percent, and vitamins and supplements came in third at 13 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This line-up is unsurprising given the history of medical reversals that we do know about. In the late 20th century, for instance, sudden cardiac death was deemed a &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3238324/#R14&quot;&gt;world wide public health problem&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. Most cases were thought to arise from an irregular heart rhythm, and so a new generation of antiarrhythmic drugs were developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Cardiologists began using these medications in widespread fashion,&quot; Prasad and another colleague &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3238324/#R14&quot;&gt;explain&lt;/a&gt; in a 2011 paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In the late 1980s, the Cardiac Antiarrhythmic Suppression Trial (CAST) was conducted to assess the safety of what was then commonplace. Interestingly, recruitment for the trial was hindered by physicians who refused to let patients undergo randomisation with a 50 percent chance of not receiving these medications.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, however, the randomised trial found that the medication was even more deadly than a placebo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Once an ineffective practice is established, it may be difficult to convince practitioners to abandon its use,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2019-06/e-a4m061119.php&quot;&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt; Prasad.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&quot;By aiming to test novel treatments rigorously before they become widespread, we can reduce the number of reversals in practice and prevent unnecessary harm to patients.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While not all of these medical reversals are deadly, they are all, by definition, useless expenses. Past research in the US has predicted that in the Medicare population from 2008 to 2009, these services cost between $1.9 and $8.5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In countries like the US, where there was a 20 [percent] increase in spending between 2013 and 2015, and drug prices alone surpassed the increase in aggregate health care spending, the identification and disuse of costly and ineffective (or possibly harmful) medications and practices are especially important,&quot; the authors &lt;a href=&quot;https://elifesciences.org/articles/45183&quot;&gt;write&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They point to Avastin as an example. This was a metastatic breast cancer medication, approved by the FDA in 2008; it cost each patient US$88,000 per year. The FDA removed its approval for the drug in 2011 after studies showed it did not increase survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly why Prasad and others are calling on the FDA and other similar agencies to not only raise the bar for future practices, but also to actively seek out independent, governmental and non-conflicted clinical research.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&quot;The majority of reversal studies we found were funded by such sources (63.9 percent), with a minority funded solely by the industry (9.1 percent),&quot; the authors &lt;a href=&quot;https://elifesciences.org/articles/45183&quot;&gt;write&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Conversely, industry funded research represented between 35–49 percent of trials registered on ClinicalTrials.gov during years 2006 through 2014.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost of doing nothing is not simply financial, either. If randomised independent trials are not conducted rigorously and these medical reversals continue to claim lives and cost absurd amounts of money, public trust in the medical system is bound to disintegrate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late night TV host John Oliver touched on this recently in a segment on medical devices. He &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/tv/tv-news/john-oliver-medical-devices-last-week-tonight-843618/&quot;&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt; that in 2018, the company DePuy was cleared for a hip replacement that used a ball and socket made from metal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its FDA clearance was based on &quot;substantial equivalence&quot; to six previous devices, some of which dated back to 1975 and others which had been taken off the markets decades ago. But while the device may have looked similar to its elders, those metal on metal hips caused grim consequences for patients; many had to be taken out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-tIdzNlExrw&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;414&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any other study on medical reversals, the most recent one comes with its limitations. It only looked at three journals, for instance, and the authors admit that other researchers may have categorised the results slightly differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the message is the same: there are many defunct, dangerous and expensive medical practices out there, hiding amongst the more legitimate sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Taken together, we hope our findings will help push medical professionals to evaluate their own practices critically and demand high-quality research before adopting a new practice in future,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2019-06/e-a4m061119.php&quot;&gt;concludes&lt;/a&gt; epidemiologist Alyson Haslam from OHSU Knight Cancer Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Especially for those that are more expensive and/or aggressive than the current standard of care.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research was published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://elifesciences.org/articles/45183&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;eLife&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 14:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>EndXA</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Study Finds Nearly 400 Medical Devices, Procedures And Practices That Are Ineffective</og:title>
<og:description>We like to view modern medicine as based on rigorous science, and while it certainly beats the various dangerous alternatives out there, sometimes physicians still end up adopting practices based on little evidence.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.sciencealert.com/recent-study-finds-400-medical-devices-procedures-or-practices-that-are-ineffective</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2019-06/processed/medicaldevices_1024.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sciencealert.com/recent-study-finds-400-medical-devices-procedures-or-practices-that-are-ineffective</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Software Below the Poverty Line</title>
<link>https://staltz.com/software-below-the-poverty-line.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://staltz.com/software-below-the-poverty-line.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;centered&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;Software below the poverty line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;13 Jun 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people believe that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fordfoundation.org/about/library/reports-and-studies/roads-and-bridges-the-unseen-labor-behind-our-digital-infrastructure/&quot;&gt;open source sustainability is a difficult problem&lt;/a&gt; to solve. As an open source developer myself, my own perspective to this problem was more optimistic: I believe in the donation model, for its simplicity and possibility to scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I recently met other open source developers that make a living from donations, and they helped widen my perspective. At Amsterdam.js, I heard &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hzoo/open-source-charity-or-business/&quot;&gt;Henry Zhu speak about sustainability&lt;/a&gt; in the Babel project and beyond, and it was a pretty dire picture. Later, over breakfast, Henry and I had a deeper conversation on this topic. In Amsterdam I also met up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wooorm&quot;&gt;Titus&lt;/a&gt;, who maintains the &lt;a href=&quot;https://unified.js.org/&quot;&gt;Unified&lt;/a&gt; project full-time. Meeting with these people I confirmed my belief in the donation model for sustainability. It works. But, what really stood out to me was the question: is it fair?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to collect data from OpenCollective and GitHub, and take a more scientific sample of the situation. The results I found were shocking: there were two clearly sustainable open source projects, but the majority (more than 80%) of projects that we usually consider sustainable are actually receiving income below industry standards or even below the poverty threshold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-the-data-says&quot;&gt;What the data says&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked &lt;a href=&quot;https://opencollective.com/discover&quot;&gt;popular open source projects&lt;/a&gt; from OpenCollective, and selected the yearly income data from each. Then I looked up their GitHub repositories, to measure the count of stars, and how many “full-time” contributors they have had in the past 12 months. Sometimes I also looked up the Patreon pages for those few maintainers that had one, and added that data to the yearly income for the project. For instance, it is obvious that Evan You gets money on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/evanyou&quot;&gt;Patreon to work on Vue.js&lt;/a&gt;. These data points allowed me to measure: project &lt;strong&gt;popularity&lt;/strong&gt; (a proportional indicator of the number of users), &lt;strong&gt;yearly revenue&lt;/strong&gt; for the whole team, and &lt;strong&gt;team size&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to derive exactly how many users there are for each project, specially because they may be transitive users, not aware that they are using the project. This is why I went with GitHub stars as a good enough measurement for user count, because it counts &lt;em&gt;persons&lt;/em&gt; (unlike download count which can include CI computers) that are &lt;em&gt;conscious&lt;/em&gt; about the project’s worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I scanned 58 projects in total, which may seem like a small number, but this was done from the most popular to the least. Popularity is very important to scale the donations, and it turns out that very few projects have enough popularity to achieve fair compensation. In other words, among these fifty most popular projects, the majority of them are below sustainability thresholds. I believe that if I would cover more data points, those would be likely less popular than these ones. This data set might be biased towards JavaScript projects on OpenCollective, but the choice for sampling OpenCollective is because it provides easy transparent data on the finances of various projects. I want to remind the reader of the existence of other popular open source projects such as Linux, nginx, VideoLAN, and others. It would be good to incorporate the financial data from those projects in this data set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From GitHub data and OpenCollective, I was able to calculate how much yearly revenue for a project goes to each “full-time equivalent” contributor. This is essentially their salary. Or, said better, this is how much their salary via donations would be if they were working exclusively on the open source project, without any complementary income. It is likely that a sizable amount of creators and maintainers work only part-time on their projects. Those that work full-time sometimes complement their income with savings or by living in a country with lower costs of living, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sindresorhus/status/902954660285128704&quot;&gt;or both (Sindre Sorhus)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, based on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2019#work-_-salary-by-developer-type&quot;&gt;latest StackOverflow developer survey&lt;/a&gt;, we know that the low end of developer salaries is around $40k, while the high end of developer salaries is above $100k. That range depicts the industry standard for developers, given their status as knowledge workers, many of which are living in OECD countries. This allowed me to classify the results into four categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;BLUE: 6-figure salary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GREEN: 5-figure salary within industry standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ORANGE: 5-figure salary below our industry standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RED: salary below the &lt;a href=&quot;https://poverty.ucdavis.edu/faq/what-are-poverty-thresholds-today&quot;&gt;official US poverty threshold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first chart, below, shows team size and “price” for each GitHub star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/poverty-teamsize.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/poverty-teamsize.png&quot; alt=&quot;Open source projects, income-per-star versus team size&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More than 50% of projects are red&lt;/strong&gt;: they cannot sustain their maintainers above the poverty line. 31% of the projects are orange, consisting of developers willing to work for a salary that would be considered unacceptable in our industry. 12% are green, and only 3% are blue: Webpack and Vue.js. Income per GitHub star is important: sustainable projects generally have above $2/star. The median value, however, is $1.22/star. Team size is also important for sustainability: the smaller the team, the more likely it can sustain its maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The median donation per year is $217, which is substantial when understood on an individual level, but in reality includes sponsorship from companies that are doing this also for their own marketing purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next chart shows how revenue scales with popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/poverty-popularity.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/poverty-popularity.png&quot; alt=&quot;Open source projects, yearly revenue versus GitHub stars&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can browse the data yourself by accessing this &lt;a href=&quot;https://datproject.org/&quot;&gt;Dat archive&lt;/a&gt; with a LibreOffice Calc spreadsheet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;dat://bf7b912fff1e64a52b803444d871433c5946c990ae51f2044056bf6f9655ecbf
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;popularity-versus-fairness&quot;&gt;Popularity versus fairness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While popularity is key to green and blue sustainability, there are popular products that are below the poverty line, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prettier/prettier&quot;&gt;Prettier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/curl/curl&quot;&gt;Curl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/electron/electron&quot;&gt;Electron&lt;/a&gt;. This doesn’t mean the people working on those projects are poor, because in several cases the maintainers have jobs at companies that allow open source contributions. What it does mean, however, is that unless companies take an active role in supporting open source with significant funding, what’s left is a situation where most open source maintainers are severely underfunded. On donations alone, open source is sustainable (fairly within industry standards) in a sweet spot: when a popular project, with a sufficiently small team, knows how to gather significant funding from a crowd of donators or sponsor organizations. Fair sustainability is sensitive to these parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because visibility is fundamental for donation-driven sustainability, the “invisible infrastructure” projects are often in a much worse situation that the visible ones. For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zloirock/core-js&quot;&gt;Core-js&lt;/a&gt; is less popular than &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/babel/babel&quot;&gt;Babel&lt;/a&gt;, although &lt;a href=&quot;https://babeljs.io/docs/en/next/babel-polyfill.html&quot;&gt;it is a dependency in Babel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Library&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Used by&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Stars&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;'Salary'&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Babel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350284&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;33412٭&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$70016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Core-js&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2442712&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8702٭&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$16204&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some proposed solutions have been to “trickle down” donations from the well-known projects to the least, guided by tools such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://backyourstack.com/&quot;&gt;BackYourStack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2019-05-23-announcing-github-sponsors-a-new-way-to-contribute-to-open-source/#native-to-your-github-workflow&quot;&gt;GitHub’s new Contributor overview&lt;/a&gt;. This would work if the well-known projects had a huge surplus to share with transitive dependencies. That is hardly possible, only Vue.js has enough surplus to share, and it could only do that with 3 or 4 other developers. Vue.js is the exception, other projects cannot afford sharing their income, because that would cause everyone involved to receive poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Babel and Core-js, there isn’t a lot of surplus to share forwards. One of Henry Zhu’s points in his talk was precisely that the money received is already too limited. It might seem like Babel is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; visible project in this situation, but it surprised me to hear from Henry that many people are not aware of Babel although they use it, because they might be using it as a transitive dependency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the other side of the coin, the maintainers of lower level libraries recognize the need to partner with more visible projects or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wooorm/status/1062404997240012800&quot;&gt;even merge projects&lt;/a&gt; in order to increase overall visibility, popularity, and thus funding. This is the case of Unified by Titus, which is a project you might not have heard of, but Unified and its many packages are used in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdx-js/mdx/blob/deff36bebfedb3a9de0a0575ee9a1b55b9b8aa18/package.json#L20&quot;&gt;MDX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gatsbyjs/gatsby/blob/25d4a4dab66e04717fb09dc5edb1f7b856fc41ff/packages/gatsby-transformer-remark/package.json#L26&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prettier/prettier/blob/24f161db565c1a6692ee98191193d9cf9ff31d6f/package.json#L66&quot;&gt;Prettier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/storybookjs/storybook/blob/fed2ffa5e2919220f0508e540b2eae848523fee5/package.json#L214&quot;&gt;Storybook&lt;/a&gt; and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also not true that popular projects are financially better off than their less popular dependencies. Prettier (32k stars) uses Unified (1k stars) as a dependency, but Unified has more yearly revenue than Prettier. In fact, many of the popular projects that depend on Unified are receiving less funding per team member. But Unified itself is still receiving below industry standards, not in a situation of trickling down (or up?) that funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other times, it’s not easy to say that when a project A is using project B, it should necessarily donate to B, because it might be that B also uses A! For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prettier/prettier/blob/24f161db565c1a6692ee98191193d9cf9ff31d6f/package.json#L19&quot;&gt;Babel is a dependency in Prettier&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/babel/babel/blob/f92c2ae830dbb32013a36fa74facd2ef95b9947d/package.json#L59&quot;&gt;Prettier is a dependency in Babel&lt;/a&gt;. Probably many of the projects covered in this study have a complex web of dependencies &lt;em&gt;between&lt;/em&gt; each other, that it becomes difficult to say how should money flow within these projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;exploitation&quot;&gt;Exploitation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total amount of money being put into open source is not enough for all the maintainers. If we add up all of the yearly revenue from those projects in this data set, it’s $2.5 million. The median salary is approximately $9k, which is below the poverty line. If split up that money evenly, that’s roughly $22k, which is still below industry standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core problem is not that open source projects are not sharing the money received. The problem is that, in total numbers, open source is not getting enough money. $2.5 million is not enough. To put this number into perspective, startups get typically much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/tidelift&quot;&gt;Tidelift has received $40 million&lt;/a&gt; in funding, to “help open source creators and maintainers get fairly compensated for their work” &lt;a href=&quot;https://tidelift.com/docs/lifting/paying&quot;&gt;(quote)&lt;/a&gt;. They have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://tidelift.com/about&quot;&gt;team of 27 people&lt;/a&gt;, some of them ex-employees from large companies (such as Google and GitHub). They probably don’t receive the lower tier of salaries. Yet, many of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tidelift.com/subscription&quot;&gt;open source projects they showcase&lt;/a&gt; on their website are below poverty line regarding income from donations. We actually do not know how much Tidelift is giving to the maintainers of these projects, but their &lt;a href=&quot;https://tidelift.com/subscription/pricing&quot;&gt;subscription pricing&lt;/a&gt; is very high. Opaqueness of price and cost structure has historically helped companies hide inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub was &lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2018/06/04/microsoft-confirms-it-will-acquire-github-for-7-5-billion/&quot;&gt;bought by Microsoft for $7.5 billion&lt;/a&gt;. To make that quantity easier to grok, the amount of money Microsoft paid to acquire GitHub – the company – is more than &lt;strong&gt;3000x&lt;/strong&gt; what the open source community is getting yearly. In other words, if the open source community saved up every penny of the money they ever received, after a couple thousand years they could perhaps have enough money to buy GitHub jointly. And now GitHub itself has its own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n47rCa9dxf8&quot;&gt;Open Source Economy team&lt;/a&gt; (how big is this team and what are their salaries?), but the new GitHub sponsors feature is far less transparent than OpenCollective. Against GitHub’s traditional culture of open data (such as the commits calendar or the contributors chart), when it comes to donations, a user cannot know how much each open source maintainer is getting. It’s opaque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Microsoft GitHub is serious about helping fund open source, they should put their money where their mouth is: donate at least $1 billion to open source projects. Even a mere $1.5 million per year would be enough to make all the projects in this study become green. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/en/articles/about-github-sponsors#about-the-github-sponsors-matching-fund&quot;&gt;Matching Fund&lt;/a&gt; in GitHub Sponsors is not enough, it gives a maintainer at most just $5k in a year, which is not sufficient to raise the maintainer from the poverty threshold up to industry standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have data to say that open source creators and maintainers are receiving poor income, and we have data to say that companies “helping” open source are receiving millions, and most likely top salaries. Other millionaire and billionaire companies are making profits by combining open source libraries and components to build proprietary software. I understand &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/VBwWbFpkltg?list=PLE7tQUdRKcyaOq3HlRm9h_Q_WhWKqm5xc&amp;amp;t=1362&quot;&gt;DHH’s stance on &lt;em&gt;‘There is no tragedy’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in open source sustainability, and in fact when I watched his talk I was inclined to agree. However, the recent data I compiled – out of curiosity – showed me the default reality of open source finances, indicating a severe imbalance between work quality and compensation. Full-time maintainers are technically talented people responsible for issue management, security, navigating toxic complaints, while receiving below the poverty threshold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The struggle of open source sustainability is the millennium-old struggle of humanity to free itself from slavery, colonization, and exploitation. This is not the first time hard-working honest people are giving their all, for unfair compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is therefore not a new problem, and it does not require complicated new solutions. It is simply a version of injustice. To fix it is not a matter of receiving compassion and moral behavior from companies, for companies are fundamentally built to do something else than that. Companies simply follow some basic financial rules of society while trying to optimize for profit and/or domination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source infrastructure is a commons, much like our ecological systems. Because our societies did not have rules to prevent the ecological systems from being exploited, companies have &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourworldindata.org/fossil-fuels&quot;&gt;engaged in industrialized resource extraction&lt;/a&gt;. Over many decades this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourworldindata.org/forests&quot;&gt;depleting the environment&lt;/a&gt;, and now we are facing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2019/may/17/why-the-guardian-is-changing-the-language-it-uses-about-the-environment&quot;&gt;climate crisis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.nasa.gov/&quot;&gt;proven&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ipcc.ch/pdf/assessment-report/ar5/syr/SYR_AR5_FINAL_full_wcover.pdf&quot;&gt;through scientifical consensus&lt;/a&gt; to be a &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.un.org/en/story/2018/05/1009782&quot;&gt;substantial threat to humanity&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ipbes.net/news/Media-Release-Global-Assessment&quot;&gt;all life on the planet&lt;/a&gt;. Open source misappropriation is simply a small version of that, with less dramatic consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to help open source become sustainable, rise up and help humanity write new rules for society, that keep power and capitalist thirst accountable for abuse. If you are wondering what that looks like, here are some initial suggestions of concrete actions to take:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Only accept jobs at companies that donate a significant portion of their profit (at least 0,5%) to open source, or companies which don’t fundamentally depend on open source for their products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donate to open source if you have a decent enough salary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t discard unionizing (I am writing this in Finland, where 65% of all workers are in unions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t discard &lt;a href=&quot;https://licensezero.com/&quot;&gt;alternative licenses&lt;/a&gt; for new projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressure Microsoft to donate millions to open source projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expose the truth on how companies are behaving by publishing data studies like this one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you liked this article, consider sharing &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?original_referer=https%3A%2F%2Fstaltz.com%2Fsoftware-below-the-poverty-line.html&amp;amp;text=Software%20below%20the%20poverty%20line&amp;amp;tw_p=tweetbutton&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstaltz.com%2Fsoftware-below-the-poverty-line.html&amp;amp;via=andrestaltz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;tweeting&quot;&gt;(tweeting)&lt;/a&gt; it to your followers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;verify-in-keybase&quot;&gt;Copyright (C) 2019 Andre 'Staltz' Medeiros, licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;, translations to other languages allowed. You can make sure that the author wrote this post by copy-pasting &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/staltz/staltz.com/master/signed_posts/2019-06-13-software-below-the-poverty-line.md.asc&quot;&gt;this signature&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;a href=&quot;https://keybase.io/verify&quot;&gt;this Keybase page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 13:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fold_left</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://staltz.com/software-below-the-poverty-line.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Browser Extension to Refine the HN Experience</title>
<link>https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/529677780e8b6679cbbdac082b34ad60200fb8b1/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f4c6963656e73652d4d49542d677265656e2e7376673f7374796c653d666c61742d737175617265&quot; alt=&quot;Licence&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-green.svg?style=flat-square&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/4b6c984cfe11b5a33e35e0ee0fb68d907779ab25/68747470733a2f2f6d616465776974686c6f76652e6e6f772e73682f696e3f68656172743d7472756526636f6c6f72423d2532336666373031662674656d706c6174653d666c61742d737175617265&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/4b6c984cfe11b5a33e35e0ee0fb68d907779ab25/68747470733a2f2f6d616465776974686c6f76652e6e6f772e73682f696e3f68656172743d7472756526636f6c6f72423d2532336666373031662674656d706c6174653d666c61742d737175617265&quot; alt=&quot;Made with love in India&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://madewithlove.now.sh/in?heart=true&amp;amp;colorB=%23ff701f&amp;amp;template=flat-square&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✨ Browser extension that adds useful features and tweaks a few stuff on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; to make the experience better... without changing the look and feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minimalist design of Hacker News is best at offering news the way we like it. Yet there are a few small interface tweaks and additional features that can drastically improve our experience while browsing through items and comments which this extension implements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, in due course, a few of these tweaks can be implemented by Hacker News themselves. You can help too by emailing &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;hn@ycombinator.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sindresorhus&quot;&gt;Sindre Sorhus&lt;/a&gt;'s extension &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sindresorhus/refined-github&quot;&gt;Refined GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;Reply to comments without leaving page&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;Navigate through items and comments using your keyboard&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/assets/demos/reply-same-page.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/raw/master/assets/demos/reply-same-page.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/assets/demos/keyboard-nav.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/raw/master/assets/demos/keyboard-nav.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;Easily &lt;em&gt;favorite&lt;/em&gt; items and comments&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;Hide and sort stories, and auto-refresh the page from the options bar&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/assets/demos/favorite.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/raw/master/assets/demos/favorite.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/assets/demos/options-bar.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/raw/master/assets/demos/options-bar.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;Show user or item information when hovering over the links&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;Highlight new, unread comments on subsequent visits&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/assets/demos/user-item-hover.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/raw/master/assets/demos/user-item-hover.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/assets/demos/highlight-unread-comments.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/raw/master/assets/demos/highlight-unread-comments.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Added features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;UI tweaks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/src/features/change-dead-comments-color.js&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;change-dead-comments-color&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; If &quot;showdead&quot; is enabled in user settings, color of dead comments changes to light-red (&lt;code&gt;#d89899&lt;/code&gt;) instead of the barely visible light-grey (&lt;code&gt;#dddddd&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/src/features/comments-ui-tweaks.js&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;comments-ui-tweaks&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Tweaks include:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add border to indentation to make to show indent separation between comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom indent-width (default is 40px), which can be set using the extension popup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight item's original poster, displayed as &lt;code&gt;[op]&lt;/code&gt; next to username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bolden your own comments' username.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/src/features/highlight-unread-comments.js&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight-unread-comments&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Highlight new and unread comments after your second and subsequent visits to the comments page of an item. Data resets after three days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/src/features/linkify-user-about.js&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;linkify-user-about&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Linkify all links and emails IDs that are on the &quot;about&quot; of the user's profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;More actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;More info at a glance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/src/features/input-field-tweaks.js&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;input-field-tweaks&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Tweaks include:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Show how many characters are left in the 'title' field when submitting an item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase width of 'title' field dynamically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase height of any textareas (even those that are dynamically created), dynamically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/src/features/on-link-focus-comment.js&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;on-link-focus-comment&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Navigate to that specific comment when clicking the 'on: ' link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Keyboard bindings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;On items and comments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On items/stories:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Key-binding&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;J&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Next item (down)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;K&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Previous item (up)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Enter&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl/Cmd&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;Enter&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Open link and focus tab&lt;br/&gt;Open link in the background&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Esc&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Un-highlight item&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;U&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Upvote item&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;F&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Favorite item&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;C&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl/Cmd&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;C&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Open item's comments on same tab&lt;br/&gt;Open item's comments on new tab&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Shift&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;X&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Flag/unflag item&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Shift&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;H&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hide item&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On comments:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Key-binding&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;J&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Shift&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;J&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Next comment (down)&lt;br/&gt;Next comment with same indentation and parent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;K&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Shift&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;K&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Previous comment (down)&lt;br/&gt;Previous comment with same indentation and parent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Enter&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Toggle comment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Esc&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Un-highlight comment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;U&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Upvote comment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;R&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reply to comment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;F&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Favorite comment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;0&lt;/kbd&gt; to &lt;kbd&gt;9&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Open numbered/index reference link in the comment&lt;br/&gt;Eg: &lt;code&gt;[1] https://mihir.ch ...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h4&gt;On input fields&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Key-binding&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl/Cmd&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;Enter&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Submit form&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl/Cmd&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;I&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Italicise selected portion (wrap selected text in asterisks)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Abandoned features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;blur-story-scores&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;custom-font-face&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hide-bad-words&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;load-more-stories&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;scale-font-size&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;show-karma-left&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Customisation and Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extension options can be found in the extension's popup. There, you can&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;specify which features you want to disable by entering features' IDs (listed above), preferably listed on new lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;specify custom CSS, which is useful to override CSS implemented by this extension, or any other UI tweaks you prefer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issues and feature requests can be created on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/issues&quot;&gt;issues page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create new features, please take a look at the format of any one of the features' file &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/src/features&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Proper documentation for contributing is a work in progress. Thanks for the patience! 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Donate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refined Hacker News was made by me during my study-breaks and free time. If you like and have enjoyed it, please consider donating a small amount (any amount will be really appreciated!) to support and sustain its development. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://paypal.me/plibither8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/a433a909fb9c52a9e87370e5107fd2e1732c270f/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f646f6e6174652d50617950616c2d626c75652e7376673f7374796c653d666f722d7468652d6261646765266c6f676f3d70617970616c&quot; alt=&quot;Donate&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/donate-PayPal-blue.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;logo=paypal&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/plibither8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/b8efed595794b7c415163a48f4e4a07771b20abe/68747470733a2f2f7777772e6275796d6561636f666665652e636f6d2f6173736574732f696d672f637573746f6d5f696d616765732f707572706c655f696d672e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Buy Me A Coffee&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/assets/img/custom_images/purple_img.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 12:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>plibither8</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://repository-images.githubusercontent.com/174383593/8c744200-8de4-11e9-97cd-320ca57e1e2c</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>plibither8/refined-hacker-news</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news</og:url>
<og:description>✨ Hacker News, but refined — Interface tweaks and features to make the HN experience better - plibither8/refined-hacker-news</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/plibither8/refined-hacker-news</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to parent more predictably (2018)</title>
<link>https://www.jefftk.com/p/how-to-parent-more-predictably</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.jefftk.com/p/how-to-parent-more-predictably</guid>
<description>&lt;em&gt;(As with anything else I write about parenting, this is mostly just my observations with my own two kids and may not generalize as well as I think it does.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I wrote about why I think it's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jefftk.com/p/predictable-parenting&quot;&gt;valuable for parents to be predictable&lt;/a&gt;. I was mostly describing an end state, though, and reasons why it's a good place to be, but what should you do if you're interested in being more consistent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it breaks down into three pretty different skills. The first is only saying things you're comfortable fully standing behind. Many people especially when irritable, sleep deprived, or surprised, can quickly spit out a consequence that is harsher than is fair. Things like, &quot;if you don't stop this minute it's no desserts for a week!&quot; Then when the threat fails the consequence feels too extreme, and they don't follow through. If someone read my earlier post and decided they needed to stand by their quickly distributed threats I'd be pretty sad, and not expect this to make things better. Instead, any consequences need to be reasonable and proportionate, where you feel fair when you do have to enforce them (which, ideally, is rarely).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that can be helpful is having a system of simple stock responses. The simplest is just a stern voice. If you reserve speaking firmly for rare circumstances, then saying something intensely and seriously can feel very significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time outs can also work well: we use a system where we make it clear what needs to change (&quot;stop shouting&quot;, &quot;brush your teeth&quot;), count to three, slowly and clearly, stopping if they do what we want, and if we get to three then it's time out. Serious things can be time out immediately. If you reliably use these, then not only does the kid understand how they work and what they mean but you don't have to come up with a novel appropriate response at a time when you're very stressed (&quot;Do not bite me. That's time out.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even better, though, is avoiding commands and threats entirely. If they've been playing with a puzzle and they ask you to read to them, you can say you'll read once they clean up the puzzle (and depending on age maybe help them clean it up). They probably want you to read badly enough that they clean up, but if not that's ok too. You're using something they want you to do as leverage to get them do something they should do, but you're also teaching them the general practice of cleaning up one thing before getting out another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, don't make committments unnecessarily. Instead of &quot;I'll go downstairs and get your bear&quot; maybe &quot;I'll go downstairs and look for your bear.&quot; While with adults we understand that when a person says they'll do something they mean they'll put in a reasonable effort and may fail if the task is surprisingly difficult or if factors outside their control intervene, I find that with kids being explicit about likely failure possibilities is helpful. &quot;I'll go see if we have any more cheese sticks.&quot; Similarly, adults understand that you don't have authority over everyone around you, but with kids phrasing like &quot;Mama can read to you when we get home&quot; isn't as good as &quot;I'll ask Mama if she'll read to you when we get home.&quot; Or, even better, &quot;when we get home you can ask Mama if she'll read to you.&quot; [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next skill is thinking of rules that will work well in a range of situations. These can be explicit rules (&quot;hold hands &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jefftk.com/p/street-training&quot;&gt;when crossing the street&lt;/a&gt;) or implicit ones (saying yes/no without explaining reasoning but following a pattern you could explain if asked). I find thinking &quot;saying yes/no no means saying the same thing in this sort of situation in general&quot; is a helpful way of thinking about it. [2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another case where preparation can help. Before going to the beach, think about what rule you'll have for the water: &quot;stay with a grown up the whole time&quot;, &quot;only go in the water with a grown up&quot;, &quot;only go in the water by yourself right in front of the lifeguard.&quot; If you notice yourself giving inconsistent answers to questions, take some time later to figure out if there's a rule that would work better (&quot;one short video each night, after dinner&quot;). It's ok, and expected, to end up with a rule that doesn't match some of your previous decisions, just try to get a rule you'll be happy with. (&quot;I know we did let you stand on the table sometimes, but from now on there's no standing on the table.&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest rules to be consistent with are the ones our culture has for adults, since you and everyone else more or less know what these are. As kids are generaly less capable, tall, intelligent, prudent, etc than the people these rules have evolved for, you are going to need to make accomodations. But I find that starting with a perspective of treating kids like adults unless there is a reason otherwise works well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third skill is actually following through on things you've said. The better you get at the two skills above the easier this is: you're saying fewer things that need to be backed up, the consequences you've promised are ones that generally seem fair, and your kids generally understand the patterns and choose to avoid the consequences. But they will still test to see if maybe the boundary has retracted while they weren't looking, and when they do you need to be firm. Sometimes this is unpleasant for both of you but it makes the rest of your interactions far better. [3]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(One way that poverty is harmful, and that parenting while well off is unfairly easy, is that external factors can keep you from being reliable for your kids. If I tell them I will do something I have enough control that I can make sure it happens, but if I had work with less flexibility, less money, or generally less slack this would be much harder. Similarly, it's much harder to be predictable when you're tired, hungry, overworked, or otherwise not at your best. If I tell my kid no and they decide to test me by tantruming, I'm going to be able to be stubborn longer than they can. But I'm only able to be in a good mental state for that because I've been lucky in how well my life has gone.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[1] The first version, &quot;Mama can read to you when we get home,&quot; has a different downside which is that one parent is making a promise on behalf of another. We try very hard not to do this, and being careful about it generally makes our interactions a lot better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] This is also useful for yourself. Instead of &quot;do I want to skip exercising this morning because I'm sleepy&quot; it works better to ask &quot;do I want to skip exercising every morning where I'm this sleepy.&quot; Sometimes the answer is yes, often it's no, but it's much more likely to be a decision that looking back you'll think was the right one for you to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] I've phrased this as about verbal consistency, but it works even when the kid is too young for words. Sleep training, for example, generally needs a bunch of thinking &quot;I know they're really sad right now and short term would like a cuddle, but we will both be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jefftk.com/p/baby-sleep-ii&quot;&gt;much happier&lt;/a&gt; long term if they learn how to sleep on their own.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 11:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wheresvic1</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.jefftk.com/p/how-to-parent-more-predictably</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introducing a new HTML element – welcome </title>
<link>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2019/06/introducing-the-new-html-element-welcome/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2019/06/introducing-the-new-html-element-welcome/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! It looks like you're writing a blog post - would you like help with that? &lt;em&gt;chuckles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/giphy.gif&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-32279 alignnone size-full&quot; width=&quot;220&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; animated-media=&quot;animated-media&quot; alt=&quot;An animated paperclip wiggling its eyebrows. &quot; data-temp-aztec-id=&quot;02c06c3a-54c5-49be-b9ff-042a337f0f18&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me and my colleagues at Microsoft have decided that the world needs more Clippy - the &lt;em&gt;adorable&lt;/em&gt; animated paperclip. To help with that, we're bringing a new feature to Edge 6.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web Developers can now use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;clippy&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to call up an animated virtual assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've spoken to several people in Microsoft, and we all agree it is a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We looked through a number of great software projects (mostly from Microsoft) and found lots of inconsistencies in the way Clippy is presented and invoked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I've written a spec for how I think it should work. I've not actually spoken to many other developers about what their user needs are. I'm pretty sure I'm representative of the majority viewpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because users keep buying and using our products, I'm going to assume they all love Clippy as much as I do. The little rascal! So, no need to waste time worrying about how users actually feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can start using Clippy on your websites &lt;strong&gt;right now!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fear not my friends! I don't work for MS and this isn't a real proposal. The above is a satirical look at the current state of web &quot;standards&quot; development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Web standardization according to Google? &quot;Nobody outside my team has reviewed or approved of the explainer in my private repo, but if we implement and encourage devs to use it, surely our competitors will agree to implement it [because our market dominance determines compat]&quot;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/aeOCxhLulb&quot;&gt;https://t.co/aeOCxhLulb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— fantasai (@fantasai) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fantasai/status/1139001078953971714?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 13, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google have decided the world needs a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;toast&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element. For the record - I think that's probably a great idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But my views don't matter much. They shouldn't matter much. I'm not the average user. I'm not representative of all developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way Google has gone about this seems to be…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ooh! I have a cool idea!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other people in Google agree with me!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Google projects could benefit from this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let's stick it in Chrome!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oh, guess we should tell the community what we're doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;(I'm deliberately simplifying and probably being a bit rude to the people behind this.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's (my) idealised version of how a new element should be introduced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have a cool idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak to real users and see if it meets a user need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish the (vague) user research and start discussing with peers around the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design and iterate based on feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test with users. Pass/Fail based on beta testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish test results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work with community to improve things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look, I get the &quot;Move fast! Break things!&quot; attitude. And I think it is exactly right that Google should experiment with the web. We all should! And, again, I think that &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;toast&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is probably a useful addition to HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the way Google has gone about introducing it to the world betrays a huge lack of empathy for the poor sods who have review standards, for other browsers, for users, and for the broader Web community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like a Google-designed, Google-approved, Google-benefiting idea which has been dumped onto the Web without any consideration for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that isn't the case. And I know how many dedicated people have worked hard on this proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For old fart like me, this feels like the Microsoft Internet Explorer days. MS dumping features onto the web and everyone had to do what they say because they're the biggest kid in the playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the chaps at Google probably think they're the good guys. That they're doing the web a favour. That users love them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They genuinely don't see that people feel they have to give in to Google's demands or face irrelevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reiterate - I think &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;toast&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is a good idea. But Google have presented it in such an arrogant way - and with no user research - that I'm getting afraid of what they'll do next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like you've finished writing this blog post. Would you like help publishing it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(And, a special note for Geeks like me. All analogies break down eventually. They are a rhetorical device used to illustrate a problem space - not to fully map it out. Please don't let the inconsistencies of the analogy be the focus of your comments.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 11:12:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edent</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Introducing the new HTML element - welcome &lt;clippy&gt;!</og:title>
<og:url>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2019/06/introducing-the-new-html-element-welcome/</og:url>
<og:description>Hello! It looks like you’re writing a blog post – would you like help with that? chuckles Me and my colleagues at Microsoft have decided that the world needs more Clippy – the ado…</og:description>
<og:image>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/giphy-1.gif</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2019/06/introducing-the-new-html-element-welcome/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WeChat is Watching: Living in China with the app that knows everything about me</title>
<link>http://nautil.us/issue/73/play/wechat-is-watching</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://nautil.us/issue/73/play/wechat-is-watching</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;t’s 9 a.m. on a typical morning in Chengdu and I’m awakened by the sound of my phone alarm. The phone is in my study, connected to my bedroom by sliding doors. I turn off the alarm, pick up my phone, and, like millions of people in China, the first thing I do is check my WeChat. At 9:07, I send my first message of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WeChat, the brainchild of Tencent—one of China’s big three tech giants—is often referred to in the West as a social media app, something equivalent to Facebook or WhatsApp, but that’s to undersell it. WeChat has over 1 billion active users. In China, people don’t refer to it as a social media platform but rather as a social &lt;em&gt;ecosystem&lt;/em&gt;. The features are seemingly endless. Beyond the typical social media functions of messaging and a Twitter-style feed called “friend circle,” it can be used to make payments for almost anything. Because developers can slot their apps directly into WeChat and tie them into the social and payment functions, it acts like a very sleek and efficient operating system. If it wasn’t for the fact that I grew up in London and use a VPN to jump the great firewall to keep in touch with my friends at home and use Google, I could go entire days without leaving WeChat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.nautil.us/16112_0a09b1d63341c622851a50e02d48e19c.png&quot; width=&quot;733&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WE RUN:&lt;/strong&gt; A screenshot from the author’s WeChat app compares how many steps he’s taken in a day, ranked against his friends—a reminder that even with a daily action like walking, the omniscient app has got his number.
&lt;p&gt;At 9:27, once I’ve brushed my teeth, answered a few messages, and wiped the sleep from my eyes, I order a coffee through WeChat. There’s a payments window on the app, and when you click on it you see various options, some proprietary to WeChat and some which are independent apps that run on WeChat’s platform. I open the Meituan delivery app and scroll through all the coffee options around me. I order an Americano. I have my WeChat linked with the facial recognition scanner on my iPhone; when I pay, I just hold my phone up to my face and a green tick flicks across the screen. Seven minutes later, I get a message telling me the coffee is on the way, with the name and number of the delivery driver. It arrives at 9:53.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before 10 on a normal day in Chengdu, WeChat knows the following things about me: It knows roughly when I wake up, it knows who has messaged me and who I message, it knows what we talk about. It knows my bank details, it knows my address and it knows my coffee preference in the morning. It knows my biometric information; it knows the very contours of my face.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this isn’t all it knows. I use WeChat to pay my rent. I use it to pay for my utilities. I use it to top up my phone credit. I use WeChat to pay for the metro system. I use it to scan QR codes on the back of shared-bike schemes throughout the city. I use it to call cabs. It knows where I go and how I go there. I follow bloggers on it, I follow media organizations and NGOs and government offices (there are over 20 million official accounts associated with governmental institutions, agencies, or officials) and I read their content through it. It knows what academic interests I have—I’m researching mental health and I pay for and attend online courses in psychology through the app. I book movie tickets, order things through Jingdong’s page (the Chinese Amazon), and I recently downloaded a WeChat app which allows me to take a photo of a flower and have it tell me the name. It also tells me anytime it’s been mentioned in Chinese poetry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WeChat knows what I am reading. It would discover I am doing research for this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are the features I don’t use. I could get a loan through WeChat. I thankfully haven’t had to book a doctor’s appointment through WeChat yet, but if I did it would know what afflicts me. I’m not married but those who are can, if they must, book divorce proceedings through WeChat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this is to say that WeChat has metastasized into every aspect of people’s lives in China. The scholar Yujie Chen, a lecturer in Digital Media and Communication at the University of Leicester, who has written a book on WeChat, calls it “super-sticky” because of the way that it has managed to make itself inextricable to so many aspects of daily life in the country. According to one estimate, WeChat alone ploughed $50 billion into the Chinese economy in 2017.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; It is the ultimate in data centralization and because of the nature of the digital economy the more data it has the more efficient it becomes—and the more easily it can pivot into new markets.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research by Seagate and IDC group, a data intelligence firm, has recently announced that by 2025 China will hold 27.8 percent of the world’s data, compared with 17.5 percent that will reside in the United States. This data will also be far more concentrated in an even smaller oligopoly of titanic tech firms, making it even more useful for the development of artificial intelligence and the next generation of big-data technologies. While it is true that all the data I share with WeChat I also share with Google, Amazon, Uber, Twitter, and Instagram, WeChat is unique in that it has managed to capture all of the functionalities that these companies do separately in the West. By co-opting their Chinese equivalents into its social ecosystem, it swallows all of the data they generate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As debates rage in the West about the extent to which we are comfortable with tech monopolies and what happens with our data, WeChat provides a window into a world of almost total data-centralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he word 隐私 &lt;em&gt;yinsi,&lt;/em&gt; which is often how privacy is translated, is an imperfect match for the English term and reads more as something that is secretive or needing to be hidden. Something that is private in English is inherently neutral, as it is assumed in our individualistic society that there should be spaces beyond the reach of governments, corporations, or others. In China, where society is more collective, family units less atomized, and a long history of the government being minutely involved in all aspects of a person’s life, the private realm is far less demarcated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The irony of WeChat is that part of its initial success as a platform was predicated on the idea that the user interface provided more privacy than that of its rival Weibo. While Weibo functions much more like Twitter—posts can be viewed by anyone and users have visible follower counts and their public influence is more easily gauged—WeChat initially functioned more as a private messenger along the lines of WhatsApp. Later features like friend circle, which allow posts to be viewed by all of a person’s followers, were more private in the sense that only once your friend request had been accepted could you view that person’s posts. You can’t view the number of likes under a post; you can only see if mutual friends have liked them. You can also create groups on WeChat and broadcast within them to people outside of your friend circle, but they are capped at 500 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are regularly arrested for messages they send in “private” group chats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, after Xi Jinping emerged as China’s leader and started to draw tightly on the reins of power, one of his early moves was to invite a number of “big V” account holders&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; (verified Weibo accounts of celebrities and popular bloggers with thousands or millions of followers) for “tea”—a euphemism for a stern talking to from the central government—and to publish new guidelines which said a post viewed over 5,000 times that offended government sensibilities such as “damaging the national image” and “causing adverse international effects” would lead to three years in prison.&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; There was a swift exodus from Weibo toward WeChat as the latter was deemed politically safer because of its more closed and intimate design.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This design feature, which came out of the demands of a heavily censored Internet environment, is ironically finding its adherents in the Internet free-for-all of the West. Facebook’s recent announcement to push for a more private user-experience lead many commenters to note that the reformed Facebook sounded a lot like WeChat.&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite WeChat’s somewhat more private design, Amnesty International, in a 2016 report on user privacy, gave WeChat zero out of a 100 for its lack of freedom of speech protection and lack of end-to-end encryption. By comparison, Facebook scored 73. People are regularly arrested for messages they send in supposedly “private” group chats. In 2017, two people were arrested in Nanjing for separate instances of making satirical comments referring the massacre in the city by the Japanese in 1937.&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; One person, seeking a job in the city and down on his luck, wrote in a group for job-seekers that “Nanjing is a pit. We should let the Japanese come slaughter again.” He was detained two days later. A similar case that same year saw a 31-year-old man jailed for joking about joining the Islamic State in a group-chat. He was arrested under China’s anti-terrorism laws and given a 9-month prison sentence.&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, regulations were passed that said the “owners” of WeChat groups are legally responsible for content posted by other members, and that complete chat logs should also be stored for potential police use for a period of at least six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.nautil.us/16114_157e7c339794a3641f69bc0d49cbb969.png&quot; width=&quot;733&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FLOWER POWER:&lt;/strong&gt; A screenshot of a WeChat app that identifies flowers and informs users when that flower is mentioned in Chinese poetry. Everything on WeChat is part of China’s social ecosystem.
&lt;p&gt;Despite its user interface being more private in a general sense than Weibo, the fact that it is censored is widely known and has been a point of contention in its wider plans for global expansion. The Citizen Lab, an interdisciplinary lab at the Munk School of Global Affairs and Public Policy, at the University of Toronto, reports that WeChat’s censorship is stronger for people who are registered with a domestic phone number.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; Messages and photos that won’t show up for a person who registered in China might show up for a foreigner. Today, you don’t know when a message has been censored. In earlier versions of WeChat, a message would show up and tell you that your message had been blocked for containing keywords that violated certain laws and regulations of the PRC (People’s Republic of China). Today, messages just don’t appear at all. You’ll only know if you compare your chat log with that of the sender.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this reality, there is a nascent privacy awakening in China. A number of domestic scholars wrote that 2018 was a landmark year in both awareness of privacy and the construction of a legal regime to protect personal data.&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; But this conversation isn’t about privacy from the government—that is a moot point in the context of China. Rather, the privacy debate is about what happens to your data. As Yujie Chen notes, part of the driver behind the privacy awakening in China is a global trend in which people “now understand the business model of the internet companies—that is, selling individual’s data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In China, where there has until only recently been little in the way of legal protection over personal data, it is common for granular private information to be sold by tech companies to third parties who use them for targeted advertising. The artist Deng Yufeng exposed this reality in his solo show at the Wuhan Art Museum in 2018, where he displayed the private details of over 300,000 people—their addresses, names, bank numbers, and phone numbers—that he had bought online from data they had shared willingly to a tech company which had sold it on without their permission. “Do we have any secrets anymore?” a neon-panel asked in the final room of the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combating this trend has led the Chinese government to issue comprehensive data privacy rules. In May 2018, the government issued a “Personal information security specification,”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; a standard for enhanced privacy, and an auditor affiliated with the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology published a list of 14 mobile apps that had “excessively collected sensitive personal data” without user consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new data rules, however, underscore how privacy in China is not the same as in the West. Advocates here warn that an individual’s rights to privacy, free speech, and a free press—the principles of democracy—are undermined by government surveillance. In China, privacy rules are designed to curtail private companies from collecting and profiting from data. The Chinese government retains the right to use it for political purposes, such as quelling public protests before they happen. Still, to the extent that the Chinese government is increasing privacy protections on my data on WeChat, the user experience is little changed. Nothing has changed with how I use the app or how much data I willingly hand over to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;t 10:44 a.m. in Chengdu, I get a text from &lt;em&gt;yidong,&lt;/em&gt; the mobile service provider I use, to say I am out of credit. When I see the text at 11:04, I pay my phone bill immediately through the payments page on WeChat. At 11:15, I walk to a yoga class. I had asked the teacher, via WeChat message, a few days before if the class was still happening because of spring festival. I check in at the gym with WeChat and then for two hours WeChat doesn’t know exactly what I am doing since I put my phone in my locker—but it would be able to make a fairly good guess. As I leave the gym I get a coffee at 1:30 p.m. and open some articles my friend has sent. They open within WeChat—there are no external links within the WeChat universe—so WeChat knows what I am reading. It would discover I am doing research for this article. I am reading about WeChat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data that WeChat creates is a boon for the government. On an aggregate level, WeChat provides “heat-maps” that can show the government in real-time how many people are using the service based on location data, which allows them to predict and outrun mounting protests or build-ups of people. On a granular level, the government has exemptions from data-protection laws which anonymize data and which, supposedly, prevent companies from singling out specific individuals from their wider data pool.&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; WeChat’s encryption doesn’t prevent the government from being able to use the data as it sees fit. Legally, WeChat’s terms and conditions allow for user data to be retained “as long as is necessary” to “comply with laws and regulations.” Tencent doesn’t disclose when the government requests user data and gives no detail of the kind of encryption, if any, it employs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we are our own informants, writing the most detailed personal accounts ever collated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At around 4 p.m., I have a problem with a money transfer. So I call the bank branch where I opened the account in the northeastern city of Dalian, a full four hours away by flight. The bank teller tells me that I was getting money from an institution (a scholarship from my university in the United Kingdom), so I need to prove my student credentials before they process the transfer. She adds me on WeChat, using the phone number I’d called into the bank, and I send her all the relevant documents. She processes the transfer and sends me screenshots of her authorizing the money to be sent into my account.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyper-centralization makes life convenient. It also presents a worrying potential for fraud. On a typical day I’ve paid my phone bill, sent money to people, bought groceries, and even sent authorized documents to the bank, all through one app, protected by one password and kept intentionally unencrypted to comply with government data-sharing regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is extremely difficult to gauge the number of accounts that get hacked on WeChat per year (Tencent declined to comment for this article). But the scope of the problem of online fraud in China is widespread. In a survey held by Internet Society of China, an NGO made up of 1,200 members, including key Internet leaders in the country, 84 percent of respondents said they had suffered some sort of data theft. In 2016, the death of Xu Yuyu, an 18-year-old girl whose family was defrauded of the savings they’d accumulated for her to go to university, sparked a debate about data privacy.&lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt; A court ruled her death, by heart attack, had been the direct result of the fraud. A man was sentenced to life in prison for paying a hacker to steal her private details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the data centralization that has enabled WeChat to map itself neatly onto users’ personal and commercial lives, has now created an opportunity for the government to step in and invite it into their political lives. Beyond sharing data with the government, WeChat is now rolling out a digital ID card. Every Chinese citizen is issued an ID card. It functions like a domestic passport and is needed for any interaction with the state—at hospitals, booking trains, flying domestically, or making bank transactions. In Guangzhou, the provincial government has already debuted a WeChat ID card and there are plans for it to be rolled out across the whole of China. Hijiacking WeChat in the future could grant a hacker everything from a user’s government-approved identity to his or her bank details, address, and coffee preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;reco&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;issue-article&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/32/Space/ingenious-ken-perlin&quot; class=&quot;obnd_lnk&quot; data-trval=&quot;ingenious-ken-perlin&quot; data-trlbl=&quot;foc_rec&quot; data-tract=&quot;internal_art&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.nautil.us/8201_c61aed648da48aa3893fb3eaadd88a7f.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sapolsky_TH-F1&quot; width=&quot;314&quot; height=&quot;177&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-tag-focus&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/term/f/Technology&quot;&gt;Also in Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;article-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/32/Space/ingenious-ken-perlin&quot; class=&quot;obnd_lnk&quot; data-trval=&quot;ingenious-ken-perlin&quot; data-trlbl=&quot;foc_rec&quot; data-tract=&quot;internal_art&quot;&gt;Ingenious: Ken Perlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-author&quot;&gt;By Brian Gallagher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken Perlin doesn’t hesitate to say that he’s more than just a scientist. Along with being a professor of computer science at New York University and directing the NYU Games For Learning Institute, he said he’s writing, doing art, doing...&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/32/Space/ingenious-ken-perlin&quot; class=&quot;obnd_lnk&quot; data-trval=&quot;ingenious-ken-perlin&quot; data-trlbl=&quot;foc_rec&quot; data-tract=&quot;internal_art&quot;&gt;READ MORE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WeChat’s data centralization makes it a cornerstone of the government’s social-credit system that is feted to appear nationwide in 2020. Mooted in 2014 in a document entitled “Planning Outline for the Construction of a Social Credit System,” the plan is to build a system that incentivizes good behavior and punishes that deemed unconducive to the construction of a harmonious society or, as the document itself dictates, a system that will “allow the trustworthy to roam everywhere under heaven while making it hard for the discredited to take a single step.”&lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt; Under the pilot scheme, people with outstanding court orders or who have defaulted on loans can’t book high-speed rail tickets and can’t fly in planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nationwide social credit system will be compiled by combining government records with commercial profiles. At present, Ant Financial, the finance-arm of Alibaba, China’s Internet conglomerate, has rolled out “sesame credit,” which gives people a score out of 950 based on their punctuality paying back loans, their purchase history, their social networks (having friends with high scores boosts your own score), and data shared from the government such as court-orders and fines. People with high-scores get preferential loans, can rent cars without deposits and are even guaranteed visas for countries like Luxemburg and Singapore, among other perks. China Rapid Finance, which is partnered with Tencent, is responsible for creating a similar scheme off the back of WeChat data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what does this mean for me? It isn’t clear yet how the social credit system will play out for foreigners in China. My sesame-credit score is a paltry 570 and China Rapid Finance hasn’t made its social scores available to view yet. There is, however, already a feature on WeChat that has been rolled out in Hebei province. It shows you the deadbeats in your vicinity—a literal map, dotted with clickable icons of anyone within 500 meters of you who has failed to pay back a loan recently.&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt; It also shows their national ID numbers and explains why they’re being named and shamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often hear people repeat the refrain, both here in China and in the West, that they have nothing to hide, so they have nothing to fear from the data that they’ve handed over. In the West, where we have a neo-liberally informed suspicion of government, we’ve gladly handed over our data to corporations, believing them to be benign. Amazon already has a system that installs a digital key on people’s homes that their delivery drivers can open to ensure safer deliveries.&lt;sup&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt; People then buy an Amazon cloud cam to watch the delivery in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is only in the wake of scandals such as Cambridge Analytica and the Russian leveraging of social media to influence the 2016 election that we have started to question whether this trust might have been misplaced. In China, where people have a different relationship to privacy and a tacit understanding that the government was always going to take hold of this data once it became available, voices in dissent are muted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is WeChat is vulnerable. I don’t know what I’d do if my account was hacked today; and this is without WeChat being my government issued ID and prior to it influencing my social credit score. I may have nothing to hide, but that presupposes two conditions; one, that I understand where society stands on a particular behavior or thought and that I am on the right side of it (and that the line won’t move once I’ve chosen where to stand), and secondly that I know what I am supposedly hiding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WeChat has read every-single message I have ever sent and hasn’t understood a single word. Who knows what the algorithms flag in my daily life; how it chooses to interpret my interactions and to what end? I’ve said that WeChat knows what I read and where I took a cab to last night, but that isn’t quite accurate. It has data about all of this, but &lt;em&gt;knowledge&lt;/em&gt; implies understanding and interpretation—and that will be done by someone else, with their own ulterior motives. Perhaps you have nothing to hide from WeChat, but you might from whoever ends up with your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author Timothy Garton Ash was a correspondent in East Germany during the time of the Stasi secret police. After the fall of the Berlin wall, he wrote a moving account, &lt;em&gt;The File: A Personal History&lt;/em&gt;, of re-reading the information the Stasi collected on him. “Like the materials used in a collage, these pieces of evidence have very different textures: here a fragment of hard metal, there a scrap of folded newspaper, there again a wisp of cotton-wool,” he wrote, marvelling at the details he himself had forgotten of his life in East Germany but that seemed so relevant to the security forces and their web of informants. He concluded that what the files ultimately presented were “a vast anthology of human weakness,” predicated on turning approximately 1 out of every 100 members of the overall population into informants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we are our own informants. We have written our own digital files and diligently update them with the most frighteningly detailed accounts ever collated in human history. We have created an infinite anthology, but of what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, a friend showed me a feature on WeChat that I hadn’t realized existed. &lt;em&gt;We Run&lt;/em&gt; links up your account with the activity monitor on your iPhone and measures your steps. At the end of every day, WeChat broadcasts the number of steps I’ve walked and ranks me against my friends. Since friending a herder I met on a hike in the Tibetan foothills I’ve given up ever coming in first place. On that day in February I ranked 30th overall among my friends, even though I’d decided to walk to and from a restaurant with a friend to boost my score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total I had walked 10,771 steps. WeChat had been with me every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Barclay Bram is an anthropology Ph.D. candidate at the University of Oxford’s School of Global and Area Studies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Iqbal, M. WeChat Revenue and Usage Statistics (2019). businessofapps.com (2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Muncaster, P. China’s ‘Big Vs’ disown selves online to avoid new gossip laws. Theregister.co.uk (2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Guilford, G. In China, being retweeted 500 times can get you three years in prison. &lt;em&gt;Quartz&lt;/em&gt; (2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Yuan, L. Mark Zuckerberg Wants Facebook to Emulate WeChat. Can It? &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; (2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Davis, K. More Nanjing Miscreants Detained by Police. Sixthtone.com (2018).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Zheng, S. Comment about Islamic State on social media lands Chinese man in prison. scmp.com (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7. Ruan, L., Knockel, J., Ng, J.Q., &amp;amp; Crete-Nishihata, M. One App, Two Systems. citizenlab.ca (2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8. Sacks, S. &amp;amp; Laskai, L. China’s Privacy Conundrum. &lt;em&gt;Slate&lt;/em&gt; (2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9. Xia, S. China’s Personal Information Security Specification: Get Ready for May 1. Chinalawblog.com (2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10. McLaughlin, H. We(Chat) The People: Technology and Social Control in China. Harvardpolitics.com (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11. In China, consumers are becoming more anxious about data privacy. &lt;em&gt;The Economist&lt;/em&gt; (2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12. Botsman, R. Big data meets Big Brother as China moves to rate its citizens. Wired.co.uk (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13. Shen, X. “Deadbeat Map” shows which people around you are on a financial blacklist. Abacusnews.com (2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14. Liao, S. After trying your front door, Amazon wants to let people deliver packages inside your garage. Theverge.com (2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead image credits: gyn9037 / Shutterstock; Freepik&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;leaderboard-ad-belt&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;leaderboard-ad-belt-inner adarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-1380044019755-0&quot; class=&quot;leaderboard-ad&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 11:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ForHackernews</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://nautil.us/issue/73/play/wechat-is-watching</og:url>
<og:title>WeChat Is Watching - Issue 73: Play - Nautilus</og:title>
<og:description>It’s 9 a.m. on a typical morning in Chengdu and I’m awakened by the sound of my phone alarm. The phone is in my study, connected&amp;#8230;</og:description>
<og:image>http://static.nautil.us/16105_1c1608a9365a88dc7e6a214c8b89e3f8.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://nautil.us/issue/73/play/wechat-is-watching</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>US efforts to jail Assange for espionage are a grave threat to a free media</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/may/26/prosecuting-julian-assange-for-espionage-poses-danger-freedom-of-press</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/may/26/prosecuting-julian-assange-for-espionage-poses-danger-freedom-of-press</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;o you remember the &lt;a href=&quot;https://collateralmurder.wikileaks.org/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Collateral Murder&lt;/a&gt; video – the one that showed US air crew in Apache helicopters killing people as though playing computer games, laughing at the dead after slaughtering a dozen people, including two Iraqis working for the Reuters news agency? Do you remember how the US military had lied about what happened in that incident in July 2007 – first claiming that all the dead were insurgents, and then that the helicopters were responding to an active firefight? Neither claim was true. Do you recall that Reuters had spent three years unsuccessfully trying to obtain the video?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was it in the public interest that the world should have eventually seen the raw footage of what happened? You bet. Was it acutely embarrassing for the US military and government? Of course. Was the act of revelation espionage or journalism? You know the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have two people to thank for us knowing the truth about how those Reuters employees died, along with 10 others who ended up in the crosshairs of the laughing pilots that day: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/apr/22/chelsea-manning-federal-appeals-court-rejects-release-bail&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Chelsea Manning&lt;/a&gt;, who leaked it, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/2019/may/01/julian-assange-jailed-for-50-weeks-for-breaching-bail-in-2012&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Julian Assange&lt;/a&gt;, who published it. But the price of their actions has been considerable. Manning spent seven years in jail for her part in releasing that video, along with a huge amount of other classified material she was able to access as an intelligence analyst in the US army. Assange has been indicted on 17 new counts of violating the Espionage Act, with the prospect that he could spend the rest of his life in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As editor of the &lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;, I worked with Assange when we jointly (along with newspapers in the US and Europe) published other material Manning had leaked. &lt;em&gt;Vanity Fair&lt;/em&gt; called the resultant stories “one of the greatest journalistic scoops of the last 30 years… they have changed the way people think about how the world is run”. The stories were, indeed, significant – but the relationship with Assange was fraught. We fell out, as most people eventually do with Assange. I found him mercurial, untrustworthy and dislikable: he wasn’t keen on me, either. All the collaborating editors disapproved of him releasing unredacted material from the Manning trove in September 2011. Nevertheless, I find the Trump administration’s use of the Espionage Act against him profoundly disturbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;Imagine the precedent if the Trump administration gets away with this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Espionage Act was a panic measure enacted by Congress to clamp down on dissent or “sedition” when the US entered the First World War in 1917. In the subsequent 102 years it has never been used to prosecute a media organisation for publishing or disseminating unlawfully disclosed classified information. Nobody prosecuted under the act is permitted to offer a public interest defence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever Assange got up to in 2010-11, it was not espionage. Nor is he a US citizen. The criminal acts this Australian maverick allegedly committed all happened outside the US. As Joel Simon, director of the Committee to Protect Journalists, has observed: “Under this rubric, anyone anywhere in the world who publishes information that the US government deems to be classified could be prosecuted for espionage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine the precedent if the Trump administration gets away with this. Israel and India have extensive nuclear weapons programmes – each protected by ferocious domestic official secrets acts. Think of the outcry if the Netanyahu or Modi governments attempted to extradite a British or US journalist to face life in jail for writing true things about their nuclear arsenals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Pentagon Papers whistleblower Daniel Ellsberg in 2010&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6a588ed6a7da13ba94c559d9bd7398967cdcdb07/0_113_3336_2001/master/3336.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=067059189bb3968d0c5efae3b65cf96a&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Pentagon Papers whistleblower Daniel Ellsberg in 2010. Photograph: Rex/Shutterstock
&lt;p&gt;The new indictment against Assange falls into three parts – each of them attempting to criminalise things journalists regularly do as they receive and publish true information given to them by sources or whistleblowers. Assange is accused of trying to persuade a source to disclose yet more secret information. Most reporters would do the same. Then he is charged with behaviour that, on the face of it, looks like a reporter seeking to help a source protect her identity. If that’s indeed what Assange was doing, good for him. Finally, he is accused of repeatedly publishing material that “could harm the national security of the US”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you read about journalists harming national security, massive alarm bells should start ringing. Think no further than Richard Nixon trying to prosecute the Pentagon Papers whistleblower, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/jan/16/is-whistleblowing-worth-prison-or-a-life-in-exile-edward-snowden-talks-to-daniel-ellsberg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Daniel Ellsberg&lt;/a&gt;, for harming national security in 1971. Ellsberg, an intelligence analyst, found that the Vietnam war had been prosecuted on the basis of a web of lies and thought the public deserved to know. To Nixon, Ellsberg’s commitment to the truth was treason. He reached for the Espionage Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today Ellsberg is celebrated as a principled whistleblower – but he came close to being jailed for his courage. That the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; was free to publish the leaked papers was down to judges. Murray Gurfein, a federal judge, refused an injunction, saying: “The security of the nation is not at the ramparts alone. Security also lies in the value of our free institutions. A cantankerous press, an obstinate press, an ubiquitous press must be suffered by those in authority in order to preserve the even greater values of freedom of expression and the right of the people to know.” Gurfein’s ringing judgment was subsequently endorsed by the supreme court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need judges to defend free speech, because governments rarely do. When Theresa May was home secretary in 2015, the Law Commission was asked to review the British laws around official secrecy. In 2017, it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2017/feb/12/the-guardian-view-on-official-secrets-new-proposals-threaten-democracy&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;recommended reforms&lt;/a&gt; that could see journalists prosecuted for simply holding secret material, never mind publishing it. The Commission also sought to deny reporters the ability to advance a public interest defence and suggested jail sentences of up to 14 years. Oh, and it suggested that the “public interest” when it came to national security should be defined by the government of the day. Leave it to Richard Nixon or Donald Trump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much may depend on the UK supreme court, which – subject to the home secretary’s deliberations – could well end up deciding this extradition request. Assange is a problematic figure in many ways. But the attempt to lock him up under the Espionage Act is a deeply troubling move that should serve as a wake-up call to all journalists. You may not like Assange, but you’re next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alan Rusbridger, a former editor of the&lt;/em&gt; Guardian&lt;em&gt;, is now principal of Lady Margaret Hall, Oxford&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 10:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rrgmitchell</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/may/26/prosecuting-julian-assange-for-espionage-poses-danger-freedom-of-press</og:url>
<og:description>I found the WikiLeaks co-founder a troubling figure when I worked with him, but America’s case would criminalise journalistic inquiry</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/e1fd225d4fbeaa4000615baa44da0900c84d8caf/0_17_4256_2554/master/4256.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdG8tb3BpbmlvbnMucG5n&amp;enable=upscale&amp;s=bb84af41d80fd66fe290ea05369d333e</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>US efforts to jail Assange for espionage are a grave threat to a free media | Alan Rusbridger</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/may/26/prosecuting-julian-assange-for-espionage-poses-danger-freedom-of-press</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>