<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Interviews with developers who became managers</title>
<link>https://devtomanager.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://devtomanager.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;h1 font-weight-bold dtm-large-heading&quot;&gt;Get first-hand advice from seasoned experts to become a kick-ass engineering manager&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;h6 font-weight-bold&quot;&gt;LEARN FROM THE BEST&lt;/span&gt; engineering managers in Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;h6 font-weight-bold&quot;&gt;SET YOURSELF UP FOR SUCCESS&lt;/span&gt; with first-hand best practices, pitfall strategies, people tips, ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;h6 font-weight-bold&quot;&gt;FIND YOU CAREER PATH&lt;/span&gt; and figure out if management is the right career direction for you&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>siddhant</dc:creator>
<og:title>Developer to Manager</og:title>
<og:url>https://devtomanager.com/</og:url>
<og:description>Interviews with experienced software developers on moving to management</og:description>
<og:image>https://devtomanager.com/static/images/logo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://devtomanager.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Adult Brain Does Grow New Neurons After All, Study Says</title>
<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-adult-brain-does-grow-new-neurons-after-all-study-says/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-adult-brain-does-grow-new-neurons-after-all-study-says/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region mura-region-loose&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region-local&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the memory center of the human brain can grow new cells, it might help people recover from depression and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), delay the onset of Alzheimer’s, deepen our understanding of epilepsy and offer new insights into memory and learning. If not, well then, it’s just one other way people are different from rodents and birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decades, scientists have debated whether the birth of new neurons—called neurogenesis—was possible in an area of the brain that is responsible for learning, memory and mood regulation. A growing body of research suggested they could, but then a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature25975&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; paper last year raised doubts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, a new study published today in another of the Nature family of journals—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-019-0375-9&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature Medicine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—tips the balance back toward “yes.” In light of the new study, “I would say that there is an overwhelming case for the neurogenesis throughout life in humans,” Jonas Frisén, a professor at the Karolinska Institute in Sweden, said in an e-mail. Frisén, who was not involved in the new research, wrote a News and Views about the study in the current issue of &lt;em&gt;Nature Medicine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone was convinced. Arturo Alvarez-Buylla was the senior author on last year’s &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; paper, which questioned the existence of neurogenesis. Alvarez-Buylla, a professor of neurological surgery at the University of California, San Francisco, says he still doubts that new neurons develop in the brain’s hippocampus after toddlerhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think this at all settles things out,” he says. “I’ve been studying adult neurogenesis all my life. I wish I could find a place [in humans] where it does happen convincingly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decades, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/does-the-adult-brain-really-grow-new-neurons/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;some researchers&lt;/a&gt; have thought that the brain circuits of primates—including humans—would be too disrupted by the growth of substantial numbers of new neurons. Alvarez-Buylla says he thinks the scientific debate over the existence of neurogenesis should continue. “Basic knowledge is fundamental. Just knowing whether adult neurons get replaced is a fascinating basic problem,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New technologies that can locate cells in the living brain and measure the cells’ individual activity, none of which were used in the &lt;em&gt;Nature Medicine&lt;/em&gt; study, may eventually put to rest any lingering questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of researchers praised the new study as thoughtful and carefully conducted. It’s a “technical tour de force,” and addresses the concerns raised by last year’s paper, says Michael Bonaguidi, an assistant professor at the University of Southern California Keck School of Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers, from Spain, tested a variety of methods of preserving brain tissue from 58 newly deceased people. They found that different methods of preservation led to different conclusions about whether new neurons could develop in the adult and aging brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brain tissue has to be preserved within a few hours after death, and specific chemicals used to preserve the tissue, or the proteins that identify newly developing cells will be destroyed, said Maria Llorens-Martin, the paper’s senior author. Other researchers have missed the presence of these cells, because their brain tissue was not as precisely preserved, says Llorens-Martin, a neuroscientist at the Autonomous University of Madrid in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenny Hsieh, a professor at the University of Texas San Antonio who was not involved in the new research, said the study provides a lesson for all scientists who rely on the generosity of brain donations. “If and when we go and look at something in human postmortem, we have to be very cautious about these technical issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Llorens-Martin said she began carefully collecting and preserving brain samples in 2010, when she realized that many brains stored in brain banks were not adequately preserved for this kind of research. In their study, she and her colleagues examined the brains of people who died with their memories intact, and those who died at different stages of Alzheimer’s disease. She found that the brains of people with Alzheimer’s showed few if any signs of new neurons in the hippocampus—with less signal the further along the people were in the course of the disease. This suggests that the loss of new neurons—if it could be detected in the living brain—would be an early indicator of the onset of Alzheimer’s, and that promoting new neuronal growth could delay or prevent the disease that now affects more than 5.5 million Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rusty Gage, president of the Salk Institute for Biological Studies and a neuroscientist and professor there, says he was impressed by the researchers’ attention to detail. “Methodologically, it sets the bar for future studies,” says Gage, who was not involved in the new research but was the senior author in 1998 of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nm1198_1313&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; that found the first evidence for neurogenesis. Gage says this new study addresses the concerns raised by Alvarez-Buylla’s research. “From my view, this puts to rest that one blip that occurred,” he says. “This paper in a very nice way… systematically evaluates all the issues that we all feel are very important.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurogenesis in the hippocampus matters, Gage says, because evidence in animals shows that it is essential for pattern separation, “allowing an animal to distinguish between two events that are closely associated with each other.” In people, Gage says, the inability to distinguish between two similar events could explain why patients with PTSD keep reliving the same experiences, even though their circumstances have changed. Also, many deficits seen in the early stages of cognitive decline are similar to those seen in animals whose neurogenesis has been halted, he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In healthy animals, neurogenesis promotes resilience in stressful situations, Gage says. Mood disorders, including depression, have also been linked to neurogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hsieh says her research on epilepsy has found that newborn neurons get miswired, disrupting brain circuits and causing seizures and potential memory loss. In rodents with epilepsy, if researchers prevent the abnormal growth of new neurons, they prevent seizures, Hsieh says, giving her hope that something similar could someday help human patients. Epilepsy increases someone’s risk of Alzheimer’s as well as depression and anxiety, she says. “So, it’s all connected somehow. We believe that the new neurons play a vital role connecting all of these pieces,” Hsieh says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mice and rats, researchers can stimulate the growth of new neurons by getting the rodents to exercise more or by providing them with environments that are more cognitively or socially stimulating, Llorens-Martin says. “This could not be applied to advanced stages of Alzheimer’s disease. But if we could act at earlier stages where mobility is not yet compromised,” she says, “who knows, maybe we could slow down or prevent some of the loss of plasticity [in the brain].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 18:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elof</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Adult Brain Does Grow New Neurons After All, Study Says</og:title>
<og:description>Study points toward lifelong neuron formation in the human brain&amp;rsquo;s hippocampus, with implications for memory and disease</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.scientificamerican.com/sciam/cache/file/CCAC1D52-4A4B-43A2-924211EFA5A16F7C.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-adult-brain-does-grow-new-neurons-after-all-study-says/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-adult-brain-does-grow-new-neurons-after-all-study-says/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Linux touchpad like a Macbook: progress and a call for help</title>
<link>https://public.amplenote.com/4wdQRLmYVU6wAHo1V9yKgaJK</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://public.amplenote.com/4wdQRLmYVU6wAHo1V9yKgaJK</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://public.amplenote.com/4wdQRLmYVU6wAHo1V9yKgaJK&quot;&gt;https://public.amplenote.com/4wdQRLmYVU6wAHo1V9yKgaJK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19485178&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19485178&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 270&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 133&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 18:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wbharding</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://public.amplenote.com/4wdQRLmYVU6wAHo1V9yKgaJK</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple announces Apple Card credit card</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/25/18277417/apple-pay-credit-card-announcement-goldman-sachs-event-2019</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/25/18277417/apple-pay-credit-card-announcement-goldman-sachs-event-2019</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;AIdFvs&quot;&gt;At Apple’s “show time” services event today, it announced a new Apple Card credit card, promising to improve things about the credit card experience with simpler applications, no fees, lower interest rates, and better rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;HrAVNh&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;PjaBrL&quot;&gt;To get an Apple Card, users will be able to sign up on their iPhone in the Apple Wallet app and get a digital card that they can use anywhere Apple Pay is accepted “within minutes.” Customers will also be able to track purchases, check balances, and see when their bill is due right from the app. There will be a physical titanium card, too, but there’s no credit card number, CVV, expiration date, or signature. All of that authorization information is stored directly in the Apple Wallet app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qJgG0Gm3ksXJgJ8uvn4anCZi1Os=/0x0:2000x1333/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jCu9Kf24KZALtw4Y993hsFySqMY=/0x0:2000x1333/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lzohzKv_1NC_JA2FxRtL8GPJ-YM=/0x0:2000x1333/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t5MRFBcg3EMJCcmVXVhaL5Nk00M=/0x0:2000x1333/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iFqGL0XmPvl3JeijA59-J5ICzN0=/0x0:2000x1333/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o5IRa1-4efrhseWvzx85UGv4RyA=/0x0:2000x1333/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gmDmm7obJjvRcDM_NZWpFSDTJzE=/0x0:2000x1333/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rQJWEbzufbvdolp_UfjWCFPtYVE=/0x0:2000x1333/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9e-PMOah0u4MsPS_8PNOl2O2k2A=/0x0:2000x1333/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-upload-width=&quot;2000&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5rAmFWuNW7uP0bbFs8wAlzDhBaM=/0x0:2000x1333/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985634/lcimg_a9595576_7dec_4d02_8303_da468c7fd352.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;PrDkcI&quot;&gt;Apple also says that it’ll use machine learning and Apple Maps to label stores that you use in the app, and use that data to track purchases across categories like “food and drink” or “shopping.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;FopmUm&quot;&gt;Instead of a points-based reward program, Apple Card gives cash back rewards in the form of Daily Cash, which is applied straight to your Apple Card to spend or put toward your purchases. Apple is offering 2 percent cash back on purchases made through Apple Pay using an Apple Card, and purchases from Apple will get 3 percent cash back. Purchases made through the physical card will get just 1 percent cash back, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y9HeYV9f5FdMYDK0S0R_POFSVUI=/0x0:2000x1333/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k5IT-vQ_CUW_rLRg8o5BsbRlgyo=/0x0:2000x1333/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KVnK6gsKzEwVRXnp4beswW7zb9k=/0x0:2000x1333/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KfxlMFs7FoQvVdF7pQpRjPz3PgM=/0x0:2000x1333/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LsHhWZcrstzRv3wmClAGmLUpHU4=/0x0:2000x1333/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lISIJMArpVi8qUFdVT2J7bYcYkI=/0x0:2000x1333/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ua240CLT314Ysddh7SNnKBzmjGM=/0x0:2000x1333/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZyEauChGLYFFZeYucRRQoo6H-GQ=/0x0:2000x1333/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8I0krJWFoWH_8ctLPSJeGDmVlB0=/0x0:2000x1333/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-upload-width=&quot;2000&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U6Ctnz5fEMpn67psV4nyyzAFu0Q=/0x0:2000x1333/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1333):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985633/lcimg_aed3a291_dcab_4ff5_9951_5969b9dbd89b.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;lUFozQ&quot;&gt;As rumored, Apple is partnering with Goldman Sachs for Apple Card, with Mastercard handling payment processing. Additionally, the company is promising that there will be “no late fees, no annual fees, no international fees, and no over limit fees” with the Apple Card and “lower interest rates” with no penalties for missing payments, with APR rates ranging from 13.24 percent to 24.24 percent based on credit. (The company also notes that “late or missed payments will result in additional interest accumulating toward the customer’s balance.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8pvVsN&quot;&gt;Like many of Apple’s products, privacy is a big push here. “Apple doesn’t know what you bought, where you bought it, and how much you paid for it,” said Jennifer Bailey, VP of Apple Pay. All of the spending tracking and other information is stored directly on the device, not Apple’s servers. The company also promises that “Goldman Sachs will never sell your data to third parties for marketing and advertising.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 17:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cdoxsey</dc:creator>
<og:description>Coming summer 2019.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NG6oEIglf5r5rgZYdcVCfWJQVtU=/0x34:2000x1081/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985639/lcimg_97920430_16e8_4b75_88cf_02bb6ba9942a.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Apple announces Apple Card credit card</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/25/18277417/apple-pay-credit-card-announcement-goldman-sachs-event-2019</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/25/18277417/apple-pay-credit-card-announcement-goldman-sachs-event-2019</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nobody wants to read your shit (2009)</title>
<link>https://stevenpressfield.com/2009/10/writing-wednesdays-2-the-most-important-writing-lession-i-ever-learned/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stevenpressfield.com/2009/10/writing-wednesdays-2-the-most-important-writing-lession-i-ever-learned/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;My first real job was in advertising. I worked as a copywriter for an agency called Benton &amp;amp; Bowles in New York City. An artist or entrepreneur’s first job inevitably bends the twig. It shapes who you’ll become. If your freshman outing is in journalism, your brain gets tattooed (in a good way) with who-what-where-when-why, fact-check-everything, never-bury-the-lead. If you start out as a photographer’s assistant, you learn other stuff. If you plunge into business on your own, the education is about self-discipline, self-motivation, self-validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Advertising teaches its own lessons. For starters, everyone hates advertising. Advertising lies. Advertising misleads. It’s evil, phony, it’s trying to sell us crap we don’t need. I can’t argue with any of that, except to observe that for a rookie wordsmith, such obstacles can be a supreme positive. Why? Because you have to sweat blood to overcome them–and in that grueling process, you learn your craft.&lt;span id=&quot;more-524&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Here it is. Here’s the #1 lesson you learn working in advertising (and this has stuck with me, to my advantage, my whole working life):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Nobody wants to read your shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Let me repeat that. Nobody–not even your dog or your mother–has the slightest interest in your commercial for Rice Krispies or Delco batteries or Preparation H. Nor does anybody care about your one-act play, your Facebook page or your new sesame chicken joint at Canal and Tchopotoulis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;It isn’t that people are mean or cruel. They’re just busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Nobody wants to read your shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;There’s a phenomenon in advertising called Client’s Disease. Every client is in love with his own product. The mistake he makes is believing that, because &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; loves it, everyone else will too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;They won’t. The market doesn’t know what you’re selling and doesn’t care. Your potential customers are so busy dealing with the rest of their lives, they haven’t got a spare second to give to your product/work of art/business, no matter how worthy or how much you love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;What’s your answer to that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;1) Reduce your message to its simplest, clearest, easiest-to-understand form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;2) Make it fun. Or sexy or interesting or informative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;3) Apply that to all forms of writing or art or commerce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;When you understand that nobody wants to read your shit, your mind becomes powerfully concentrated. You begin to understand that writing/reading is, above all, a transaction. The reader donates his time and attention, which are supremely valuable commodities. In return, you the writer, must give him something worthy of his gift to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;When you, the student writer, understand that nobody wants to read your shit, you develop empathy. You acquire that skill which is indispensable to all artists and entrepreneurs: the ability to switch back and forth in your imagination from your own point of view as writer/painter/seller to the point of view of your imagined reader/gallery-goer/customer. You learn to ask yourself with every sentence and every phrase: Is this interesting? Is this fun or challenging or inventive? Am I giving the reader enough? Is she bored? Is she following where I want to lead her?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;When I began to write novels, this mindset proved indispensable. It steered me away from Client’s Disease. It warned me not to fall in love with my own shit &lt;em&gt;just because it was my own shit&lt;/em&gt;. Don’t be lazy, Steve. Don’t assume. Look at every word through the eye of the busy, impatient, skeptical (but also generous and curious) reader. Give him something worthy of the time and attention he’s giving you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;The awareness that nobody wants to read/hear/see/buy what we’re writing/singing/filming/selling is the Plymouth Rock upon which all successful artists and entrepreneurs base their public communications. They know that, before all else, they must overcome this natural resistance in their audience. They must find a way to cut through the clutter. As a fledgling cub at B&amp;amp;B, I remember days, weeks, months when our various creative teams did nothing but beat our brains out trying to find some way to make the dull exciting and the unlovely beautiful–and to make the beautiful-but-overlooked gorgeous too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;How, you ask? You’ll know you’re on the right track when beads of blood begin to pop out on your forehead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Future “Writing Wednesdays” articles will be inspired by quotes from &lt;em&gt;The War of Art&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Please post your favorite quotes in the comment section following this post, DM them to my Twitter account (@spressfield) or post them to the Wall of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/StevePressfield?ref=ts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Writer” Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I will pick one or two quotes the Thursday BEFORE the next “Writing Wednesdays” post. The person whose quote I use in my Wednesday, August 5, post will receive a signed copy of &lt;em&gt;The War of Art&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Reminder: Submit your quotes by midnight tomorrow, Thursday, July 30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Please limit the quotes you submit to one quote per week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 15:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>todsac</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Most Important Writing Lesson I Ever Learned</og:title>
<og:url>https://stevenpressfield.com/2009/10/writing-wednesdays-2-the-most-important-writing-lession-i-ever-learned/</og:url>
<og:description>My first real job was in advertising. I worked as a copywriter for an agency called Benton &amp; Bowles in New York City. An artist or entrepreneur’s first job inevitably bends the twig. It s…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stevenpressfield.com/2009/10/writing-wednesdays-2-the-most-important-writing-lession-i-ever-learned/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Golden Rules for Making Money (1880)</title>
<link>http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting.html</guid>
<description>&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap1.html&quot;&gt;ART OF MONEY GETTING&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.24242424242424&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap2.html&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap2.html&quot;&gt;DON'T MISTAKE YOUR VOCATION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.25806451612903&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap3.html&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap3.html&quot;&gt;SELECT THE RIGHT LOCATION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap4.html&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap4.html&quot;&gt;AVOID DEBT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap5.html&quot;&gt;4.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap5.html&quot;&gt;PERSEVERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.25&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap6.html&quot;&gt;5.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap6.html&quot;&gt;WHATEVER YOU DO, DO IT WITH ALL YOUR MIGHT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.17777777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap7.html&quot;&gt;6.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap7.html&quot;&gt;DEPEND UPON YOUR OWN PERSONAL EXERTIONS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap8.html&quot;&gt;7.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap8.html&quot;&gt;USE THE BEST TOOLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.22857142857143&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap9.html&quot;&gt;8.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap9.html&quot;&gt;DON'T GET ABOVE YOUR BUSINESS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap10.html&quot;&gt;9.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap10.html&quot;&gt;LEARN SOMETHING USEFUL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.15384615384615&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap11.html&quot;&gt;10.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap11.html&quot;&gt;LET HOPE PREDOMINATE BUT BE NOT TOO VISIONARY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.24242424242424&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap12.html&quot;&gt;11.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap12.html&quot;&gt;DO NOT SCATTER YOUR POWERS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap13.html&quot;&gt;12.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap13.html&quot;&gt;BE SYSTEMATIC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap14.html&quot;&gt;13.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap14.html&quot;&gt;READ THE NEWSPAPERS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.19512195121951&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap15.html&quot;&gt;14.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap15.html&quot;&gt;BEWARE OF “OUTSIDE OPERATIONS”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.21621621621622&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap16.html&quot;&gt;15.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap16.html&quot;&gt;DON'T INDORSE WITHOUT SECURITY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap17.html&quot;&gt;16.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap17.html&quot;&gt;ADVERTISE YOUR BUSINESS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.18604651162791&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap18.html&quot;&gt;17.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap18.html&quot;&gt;BE POLITE AND KIND TO YOUR CUSTOMERS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap19.html&quot;&gt;18.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap19.html&quot;&gt;BE CHARITABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap20.html&quot;&gt;19.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap20.html&quot;&gt;DON'T BLAB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap21.html&quot;&gt;20.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;m&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting_chap21.html&quot;&gt;PRESERVE YOUR INTEGRITY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 15:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zygimantasdev</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.fourmilab.ch/etexts/www/barnum/moneygetting/moneygetting.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A new Einstein cross is discovered</title>
<link>https://phys.org/news/2019-03-einstein.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://phys.org/news/2019-03-einstein.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;first-block&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-ins&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/gfx/news/2019/gtcdiscovers.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The newly discovered Einstein Cross J2211-3050. An elliptical galaxy (the yellow object)  is acting as a lens, producing the four blue objects (marked ABCD) that are the images of a galaxy about 3 times more distant. With GTC it was possible to isolate and disperse the light of objects ABC, demonstrating that they belong to the same light source. Credit: Hubble Space Telescope Credit: Instituto de Astrofísica de Canarias&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/800/2019/gtcdiscovers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GTC discovers a new Einstein cross&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The newly discovered Einstein Cross J2211-3050. An elliptical galaxy (the yellow object)  is acting as a lens, producing the four blue objects (marked ABCD) that are the images of a galaxy about 3 times more distant. With GTC it was possible to isolate and disperse the light of objects ABC, demonstrating that they belong to the same light source. Credit: Hubble Space Telescope Credit: Instituto de Astrofísica de Canarias
&lt;p&gt;This study, which has combined images from the Hubble Space Telescope with spectroscopic observations from the GTC, has confirmed the existence of a new example of a gravitational lens, a phenomenon predicted by Albert Einstein's theory of General Relativity. In this case, the observed effect is due to the alteration caused by a galaxy that acts like a magnifying glass amplifying and distorting, in four separate images in the form of a cross, the light of another galaxy located 20,000 million light years away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;article-banner first-banner&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most striking conclusions of Albert Einstein's theory of &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/tags/general+relativity/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;general relativity&lt;/a&gt; is that the trajectory of light curves in the presence of matter. This effect can be observed in the case of light emitted by a distant galaxy, when its light passes close to another galaxy on its way to the observer. The phenomenon is known as gravitational lensing, because it is comparable to the deviation of light rays by the classic glass lenses. Similarly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/tags/gravitational+lenses/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;gravitational lenses&lt;/a&gt; act like magnifying glasses that change the size, shape, and intensity of the image of the distant object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the degree of alignment of the two &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/tags/sources/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/a&gt;, multiple images of the distant source can be observed, such as four separate images in the form of a cross (hence the name &quot;Einstein's cross&quot;), rings, or arcs. It is in general extremely difficult to spot a gravitational lens, because the separation between the images produced by the lens is usually very small, requiring high-resolution images to see them. It was precisely analyzing Hubble Space Telescope high-resolution images that it was possible to locate an asterism that looked like a new example of Einstein cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An exceptional discovery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, spotting four points of light in the shape of a cross positioned around a galaxy does not assure us that it is a lens, so we must show that the 4 images belong to the same object. To do this spectroscopic observations are needed. For this reason, a team of Italian scientists led by Daniela Bettoni of the Padova Observatory and Riccardo Scarpa of the IAC, decided to observe spectroscopically with GTC the supposed lens. According to Scarpa, &quot;the result could not have been better. The atmosphere was very clean and with minimum turbulence (seeing), which allowed us to clearly separate the emission of three of the four images. The spectrum immediately gave us the answer we were looking for, the same emission line due to ionized hydrogen appeared in all three spectra at the same wavelength. There could be no doubt that it was actually the same source of light&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-ins&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/gfx/news/2019/5c8f8a60dba4f.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Part of the GTC spectrum of sources ABC, centered on the Lyman alpha emission line. All three sources show the same line at the same wavelength, indicating the ligth is actually coming from the same object. Credit: GTC&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/800/2019/5c8f8a60dba4f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GTC discovers a new Einstein cross&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Part of the GTC spectrum of sources ABC, centered on the Lyman alpha emission line. All three sources show the same line at the same wavelength, indicating the ligth is actually coming from the same object. Credit: GTC
&lt;p&gt;A new Einstein cross had been discovered, named J2211-0350 according to its coordinates on the sky. The object acting as a lens turns out to be an elliptical galaxy located at a distance of approximately 7 billion &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/tags/light+years/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;light years&lt;/a&gt; (z = 0.556), while the source is at least 20 billion light years away (z = 3.03). &quot;Normally the source is a quasar, it was with great surprise that we realized the source in this case was another galaxy, in fact a galaxy with very intense emission lines which indicates it is a young object still forming large amounts of stars&quot;, explain Bettoni. Quite an achievement for GTC, considering only another lens of this type was known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New research tool&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to these new observations, presented in &lt;em&gt;The Astrophysical Journal&lt;/em&gt;, astronomers now have one more tool to investigate the Universe. Gravitational lenses are important because they allow the study of the Universe in a unique way. Because the light of the different images, initially the same light, follows different paths in the Universe, thus any spectral differences must be due to the material that is between us and the source. Moreover, if the source is variable, we can see a time delay (one image illuminates before the others), which provides valuable information about the shape of the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the mass of the lens responsible for bending the light can be accurately derived, providing an important independent method to weight &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/tags/galaxies/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;galaxies&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, as with a normal glass lens, the gravitational lens concentrates toward us the &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/tags/light/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;light&lt;/a&gt; from the source, making it possible to see intrinsically unreachable objects. In this case it could be calculated that the source is 5 times brighter than it would be without the &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/tags/lens/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;lens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;news-relevant&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/WebPage&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2019-03-einstein.html#&quot; id=&quot;inl-rel-href&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;toolsicon ic-rel&quot; src=&quot;https://cf3e497594.site.internapcdn.net/tmpl/v5/img/1x1.gif&quot; width=&quot;14&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Explore further:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a itemprop=&quot;relatedLink&quot; href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2013-10-distant-gravitational-lens-galaxies.html&quot;&gt;Most distant gravitational lens helps weigh galaxies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More information:&lt;/strong&gt; Daniela Bettoni et al. A New Einstein Cross Gravitational Lens of a Lyman-break Galaxy, &lt;em&gt;The Astrophysical Journal Letters&lt;/em&gt; (2019). &lt;a data-doi=&quot;1&quot; href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/ab0aeb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOI: 10.3847/2041-8213/ab0aeb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;post-floor clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;10.09756097561&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-copyright&quot; readability=&quot;12.32967032967&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal reference:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;news&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot; href=&quot;https://phys.org/journals/astrophysical-journal/&quot;&gt;Astrophysical Journal&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provided by:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;news&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot; href=&quot;https://phys.org/partners/instituto-de-astrof--sica-de-canarias/&quot;&gt;Instituto de Astrofísica de Canarias&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-rating&quot; id=&quot;rank&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;flip-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flip&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;shares&quot;&gt;5723&lt;/span&gt; shares &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 14:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>arunc</dc:creator>
<og:title>A new Einstein cross is discovered</og:title>
<og:description>This study, which has combined images from the Hubble Space Telescope with spectroscopic observations from the GTC, has confirmed the existence of a new example of a gravitational lens, a phenomenon predicted by Albert Einstein's theory of General Relativity. In this case, the observed effect is due to the alteration caused by a galaxy that acts like a magnifying glass amplifying and distorting, in four separate images in the form of a cross, the light of another galaxy located 20,000 million light years away.</og:description>
<og:image>https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/gfx/news/2019/gtcdiscovers.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://phys.org/news/2019-03-einstein.html</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://phys.org/news/2019-03-einstein.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Baxx – Unix-friendly backup service</title>
<link>https://txt.black/~jack/baxx-dev.txt</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://txt.black/~jack/baxx-dev.txt</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;41&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;██████╗ █████╗ ██╗ ██╗██╗ ██╗ ██████╗ ███████╗██╗ ██╗ ██╔══██╗██╔══██╗╚██╗██╔╝╚██╗██╔╝ ██╔══██╗██╔════╝██║ ██║ ██████╔╝███████║ ╚███╔╝ ╚███╔╝ ██║ ██║█████╗ ██║ ██║ ██╔══██╗██╔══██║ ██╔██╗ ██╔██╗ ██║ ██║██╔══╝ ╚██╗ ██╔╝ ██████╔╝██║ ██║██╔╝ ██╗██╔╝ ██╗██╗██████╔╝███████╗ ╚████╔╝ ╚═════╝ ╚═╝ ╚═╝╚═╝ ╚═╝╚═╝ ╚═╝╚═╝╚═════╝ ╚══════╝ ╚═══╝ I have just finished the prototype for my first product without a website. It is a backup service with unix philosophy in mind, and curl as main interface and (soon) machine learning alerting. # Register ssh register@ui.baxx.dev or go to https://ui.baxx.dev (it is the same program run from shellinabox) ┌────────────────────────────────────────────┐ │ │ │ ██████╗ █████╗ ██╗ ██╗██╗ ██╗ │ │ ██╔══██╗██╔══██╗╚██╗██╔╝╚██╗██╔╝ │ │ ██████╔╝███████║ ╚███╔╝ ╚███╔╝ │ │ ██╔══██╗██╔══██║ ██╔██╗ ██╔██╗ │ │ ██████╔╝██║ ██║██╔╝ ██╗██╔╝ ██╗ │ │ ╚═════╝ ╚═╝ ╚═╝╚═╝ ╚═╝╚═╝ ╚═╝ │ │ │ │ Storage 10G │ │ Trial 1 Month 0.1EUR │ │ Subscription: 5EUR per Month │ │ Availability: ALPHA │ │ │ │ │ │ E-mail │ │ █ │ │ │ │ Password │ │ │ │ │ │ Confirm Password │ │ │ │ │ │ Registering means you agree with │ │ the terms of service! │ │ │ │ [Register] [Login] │ │ │ │ [Help] [What/Why/How] [Terms Of Service] │ │ │ │ [Quit] │ └────────────────────────────────────────────┘ after that you will receive email with instructions # Let me illustrate what I mean by unix friendly: Example 1 directional rsync * find all files * run shasum on them (in parallel) * send the text to baxx.dev, you get only the shasums that are not uploaded * simply upload the missing files(in parallel): find path/.. -type f \ | xargs -P4 -I '{}' \ shasum -a 256 {} \ | curl -s --data-binary @- https://baxx.dev/sync/sha256/$BAXX_TOKEN \ | awk '{ print $2 }' \ | xargs -P4 -I '{}' \ curl -s -T {} https://baxx.dev/io/$BAXX_TOKEN/backup/{} # Why another backup service? I want to build: * completely transparent service and pricing * allow people to host it themselves * use machine learning to improve the relevancy of the alerts * easy to use and plug into existing backup scripts Some of my friends have simple backup scripts such as: mysqldump | gzip &amp;gt; backup.sql.gz &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \ scp backup.sql.gz remote_box:backup/backup.$(date +%u).sql.gz to get daily rotation backups (date +%u is day of the week). Some of the common things that happen after that: * remote box gets full disk * table is renamed * mysql credentials are changed * database is split * ssh keys get changed * local partition gets full * etc.. of course usually after the first missing backup you overcompensate and start sending daily reports to your mail, which end up being ignored until the next issue pops up, you fix it and add more monitoring and since you usually need backups ~1 time a year you forget how annoying this whole thing is. (not to mention when your monitoring gets marked as spam) with baxx.dev and one simple change: mysqldump | gzip | encrypt -k .pass | \ curl --data-binary @- https://baxx.dev/$BAXX_TOKEN/backup.sql.gz * get notified if the file is too small * get notified if the file is too old # Transparency * source https://github.com/jackdoe/baxx/ * infrastructure and pricing https://github.com/jackdoe/baxx/blob/master/infra-and-pricing.txt * todo https://github.com/jackdoe/baxx/blob/master/TODO.txt # No website The way you register is through ssh, just `ssh register@ui.baxx.dev`, the help is optimized for tty such as `curl https://baxx.dev/help`, payments are with paypal subscription and IPN, and you get instructions via email. Now the flow works very well and I love how simple it is to register and pay, get help and use the service. I used https://github.com/marcusolsson/tui-go to build the registration UI and it was pure joy! The font I got from: http://patorjk.com/software/taag/#p=display&amp;amp;f=ANSI%20Shadow&amp;amp;t=amazing and it gave me such a retro feeling, I felt like a kid again. # Charge during ALPHA I decided to charge 5EUR (0.1EUR trial) during the alpha, even my friends. This way they will also tell me if the service is worth its money. # Next Steps * get feedback * improve the api * improve the help * work on vowpal wabbit integration * repeat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 13:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zulgan</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/plain</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://txt.black/~jack/baxx-dev.txt</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Procrastination Has Nothing to Do with Self-Control</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/25/smarter-living/why-you-procrastinate-it-has-nothing-to-do-with-self-control.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/25/smarter-living/why-you-procrastinate-it-has-nothing-to-do-with-self-control.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;If you’ve ever put off an important task by, say, alphabetizing your spice drawer, you know it wouldn’t be fair to describe yourself as lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;After all, alphabetizing requires focus and effort — and hey, maybe you even went the extra mile to wipe down each bottle before putting it back. And it’s not like you’re hanging out with friends or watching Netflix. You’re cleaning — something your parents would be proud of! This isn’t laziness or bad time management. This is procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-sbs9ef eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-46f8a25d&quot;&gt;If procrastination isn’t about laziness, then what is it about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Etymologically, “procrastination” is derived from the Latin verb &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;procrastinare&lt;/em&gt; — to put off until tomorrow. But it’s more than just voluntarily delaying. Procrastination is also derived from the ancient Greek word &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;akrasia —&lt;/em&gt; doing something against our better judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It’s self-harm,” said Dr. Piers Steel, a professor of motivational psychology at the University of Calgary and the author of “The Procrastination Equation: How to Stop Putting Things Off and Start Getting Stuff Done&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;That self-awareness is a key part of why procrastinating makes us feel so rotten. When we procrastinate, we’re not only aware that we’re avoiding the task in question, but also that doing so is probably a bad idea. And yet, we do it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“This is why we say that procrastination is essentially irrational,” said Dr. Fuschia Sirois, professor of psychology at the University of Sheffield. “It doesn’t make sense to do something you know is going to have negative consequences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;She added: “People engage in this irrational cycle of chronic procrastination because of an inability to manage negative moods around a task.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-sbs9ef eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-5d097699&quot;&gt;Wait. We procrastinate because of bad moods?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In short: yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Procrastination isn’t a unique character flaw or a mysterious curse on your ability to manage time, but a way of coping with challenging emotions and negative moods induced by certain tasks — boredom, anxiety, insecurity, frustration, resentment, self-doubt and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Procrastination is an emotion regulation problem, not a time management problem,” said Dr. Tim Pychyl, professor of psychology and member of the Procrastination Research Group at Carleton University in Ottawa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://eprints.whiterose.ac.uk/91793/1/Compass%20Paper%20revision%20FINAL.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In a 2013 study&lt;/a&gt;, Dr. Pychyl and Dr. Sirois found that procrastination can be understood as “the primacy of short-term mood repair … over the longer-term pursuit of intended actions.” Put simply, procrastination is about being more focused on “the immediate urgency of managing negative moods” than getting on with the task, Dr. Sirois said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The particular nature of our aversion depends on the given task or situation. It may be due to something inherently unpleasant about the task itself — having to clean a dirty bathroom or organizing a long, boring spreadsheet for your boss. But it might also result from deeper feelings related to the task, such as self-doubt, low self-esteem, anxiety or insecurity. Staring at a blank document, you might be thinking, &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;I’m not smart enough to write this. Even if I am, what will people think of it? Writing is so hard. What if I do a bad job?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;All of this can lead us to think that putting the document aside and cleaning that spice drawer instead is a pretty good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;[Like what you’re reading?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/smarter-living?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Sign up here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;for the Smarter Living newsletter to get stories like this (and much more!) delivered straight to your inbox every Monday morning.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But, of course, this only compounds the negative associations we have with the task, and those feelings will still be there whenever we come back to it, along with increased &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10942-012-0151-y&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;stress and anxiety&lt;/a&gt;, feelings of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4359724/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;low self-esteem&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/234130824_Procrastination_and_Stress_Exploring_the_Role_of_Self-compassion&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;self-blame&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In fact, there’s an entire body of research dedicated to the ruminative, self-blaming thoughts many of us tend to have in the wake of procrastination, which are known as “&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10942-012-0150-z&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;procrastinatory cognitions&lt;/a&gt;.” The thoughts we have about procrastination typically exacerbate our distress and stress, which contribute to further procrastination, Dr. Sirois said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But the momentary relief we feel when procrastinating is actually what makes the cycle especially vicious. In the immediate present, putting off a task provides relief — “you’ve been rewarded for procrastinating,” Dr. Sirois said. And we know from basic behaviorism that when we’re rewarded for something, we tend to do it again. This is precisely why procrastination tends not to be a one-off behavior, but a cycle, one that easily becomes a chronic habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Over time, chronic procrastination has not only productivity costs, but measurably destructive effects on our mental and physical health, including &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/276345113_The_Prevalence_Predictors_Causes_Treatment_and_Implications_of_Procrastination_Behaviors_in_General_Academic_and_Work_Setting&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chronic stress&lt;/a&gt;, general &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4752450/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;psychological distress and low life satisfaction&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/297747096_Procrastination_and_Depression_from_a_Cognitive_Perspective_An_Exploration_of_the_Associations_Among_Procrastinatory_Automatic_Thoughts_Rumination_and_Mindfulness&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;symptoms of depression&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Procrastination%2C+negative+self-evaluation%2C+and+stress+in+depression+and+anxiety%3A&amp;amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enUS520US520&amp;amp;oq=Procrastination%2C+negative+self-evaluation%2C+and+stress+in+depression+and+anxiety%3A&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j0.289j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;anxiety&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886902003264?via%3Dihub&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;poor health behaviors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/B9780128028629000049&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chronic illness&lt;/a&gt; and even &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs10865-015-9629-2&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hypertension and cardiovascular disease.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-sbs9ef eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-405b3d9b&quot;&gt;But I thought we procrastinate to feel better?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;If it seems ironic that we procrastinate to avoid negative feelings, but end up feeling even worse, that’s because it is. And once again, we have evolution to thank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Procrastination is a perfect example of &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;present bias&lt;/em&gt;, our hard-wired tendency to prioritize short-term needs ahead of long-term ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We really weren’t designed to think ahead into the further future because we needed to focus on providing for ourselves in the here and now,” said psychologist Dr. Hal Hershfield, a professor of marketing at the U.C.L.A. Anderson School of Management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3764505/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dr. Hershfield’s research&lt;/a&gt; has shown that, on a neural level, we perceive our “future selves” more like strangers than as parts of ourselves. When we procrastinate, parts of our brains actually think that the tasks we’re putting off — and the accompanying negative feelings that await us on the other side — are somebody else’s problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;To make things worse, we’re even less able to make thoughtful, future-oriented decisions in the midst of stress. When faced with a task that makes us feel anxious or insecure, the amygdala — the “threat detector” part of the brain — perceives that task as a genuine threat, in this case to our self-esteem or well-being. Even if we intellectually recognize that putting off the task will create more stress for ourselves in the future, our brains are still wired to be more concerned with removing the threat in the present. Researchers call this “amygdala hijack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Unfortunately, we can’t just tell ourselves to stop procrastinating. And despite the prevalence of “productivity hacks,” focusing on the question of how to get more work done doesn’t address the root cause of procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Erik Winkowski&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-cch8ym&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1dv1kvn&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-sbs9ef eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-38ba2d8a&quot;&gt;O.K. How do we get to the root cause of procrastination?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;We must realize that, at its core, procrastination is about emotions, not productivity. The solution doesn’t involve downloading a time management app or learning new strategies for self-control. It has to do with managing our emotions in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Our brains are always looking for relative rewards. If we have a habit loop around procrastination but we haven’t found a better reward, our brain is just going to keep doing it over and over until we give it something better to do,” said psychiatrist and neuroscientist Dr. Judson Brewer, Director of Research and Innovation at Brown University’s Mindfulness Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;To rewire any habit, we have to give our brains what Dr. Brewer called the “Bigger Better Offer” or “B.B.O.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In the case of procrastination, we have to find a better reward than avoidance — one that can relieve our challenging feelings in the present moment without causing harm to our future selves. The difficulty with breaking the addiction to procrastination in particular is that there is an infinite number of potential substitute actions that would still be forms of procrastination, Dr. Brewer said. That’s why the solution must therefore be internal, and not dependent on anything but ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One option is to forgive yourself in the moments you procrastinate. In &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://law.utexas.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/25/Pretend-Paper.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a 2010 study&lt;/a&gt;, researchers found that students who were able to forgive themselves for procrastinating when studying for a first exam ended up procrastinating less when studying for their next exam. They concluded that self-forgiveness supported productivity by allowing “the individual to move past their maladaptive behavior and focus on the upcoming examination without the burden of past acts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Another tactic is the related practice of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/15298860309032&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;self-compassion&lt;/a&gt;, which is treating ourselves with kindness and understanding in the face of our mistakes and failures. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/15298868.2013.763404#.U8WXw41dWnC&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In a 2012 study&lt;/a&gt; examining the relationship between stress, self-compassion and procrastination, Dr. Sirois found that procrastinators tend to have high stress and low self-compassion, suggesting that self-compassion “provide a buffer against negative reactions to self-relevant events.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In fact, several studies show that self-compassion supports motivation and personal growth. Not only does it &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S027273581200092X&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;decrease psychological distress&lt;/a&gt;, which we now know is a primary culprit for procrastination, it also actively &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0146167212445599&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;boosts motivation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1467-6494.2008.00537.x?deniedAccessCustomisedMessage=&amp;amp;userIsAuthenticated=false&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;enhances feelings of self-worth&lt;/a&gt; and fosters &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S009265660600095X&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;positive emotions&lt;/a&gt; like optimism, wisdom, curiosity and personal initiative. Best of all, self-compassion doesn’t require anything external — just a commitment to meeting your challenges with greater acceptance and kindness rather than rumination and regret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;That may be easier said than done, but try to reframe the task by considering a positive aspect of it. Perhaps you remind yourself of a time you did something similar and it turned out O.K. Or maybe you think about the beneficial outcome of completing the task. What might your boss or partner say when you show them your finished work? How will you feel about yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-sbs9ef eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-4b4a8e3b&quot;&gt;What are some other, healthier ways to manage the feelings that typically trigger procrastination?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;Cultivate curiosity:&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re feeling tempted to procrastinate, bring your attention to the sensations arising in your mind and body. What feelings are eliciting your temptation? Where do you feel them in your body? What do they remind you of? What happens to the thought of procrastinating as you observe it? Does it intensify? Dissipate? Cause other emotions to arise? How are the sensations in your body shifting as you continue to rest your awareness on them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;Consider the next action:&lt;/strong&gt; This is different than the age-old advice to break up a task you’re tempted to avoid into bite-sized chunks. According to Dr. Pychyl, focusing only on the “next action” helps calm our nerves, and it allows for what Dr. Pychyl called “a layer of self-deception.” At the start of a given task, you can consider the next action as a mere possibility, as if you were method acting: “What’s the next action I’d take on this if I were going to do it, even though I’m not?” Maybe you &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; open your email. Or perhaps you &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; put the date at the top of your document. Don’t wait to be in the mood to do a certain task. “Motivation follows action. Get started, and you’ll find your motivation follows,” Dr. Pychyl said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;Make your temptations more inconvenient:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s still easier to change our circumstances than ourselves, said Gretchen Rubin, author of “Better Than Before: What I Learned About Making and Breaking Habits.” According to Ms. Rubin, we can take what we know about procrastination and “use it to our advantage” by placing obstacles between ourselves and our temptations to induce a certain degree of frustration or anxiety. If you compulsively check social media, delete those apps from your phone or “give yourself a really complicated password with not just five digits, but 12,” Ms. Rubin said. By doing this, you’re adding friction to the procrastination cycle and making the reward value of your temptation less immediate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;On the other side of the coin, Ms. Rubin also suggested that we make the things we want to do as easy as possible for ourselves. If you want to go to the gym before work but you’re not a morning person, sleep in your exercise clothes. “Try to remove every, every, every roadblock,” Ms. Rubin said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Still, procrastination is deeply existential, as it raises questions about individual agency and how we want to spend our time as opposed to how we actually do. But it’s also a reminder of our commonality — we’re all vulnerable to painful feelings, and most of us just want to be happy with the choices we make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Now go finish up alphabetizing that spice drawer before it becomes your next procrastination albatross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 13:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>noego</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/25/smarter-living/why-you-procrastinate-it-has-nothing-to-do-with-self-control.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why You Procrastinate (It Has Nothing to Do With Self-Control)</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/25/smarter-living/25sl_procrastination_promo/25sl_procrastination_promo-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>If procrastination isn’t about laziness, then what is it about?</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/25/smarter-living/why-you-procrastinate-it-has-nothing-to-do-with-self-control.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hackers Hijacked Asus Software Updates to Install Backdoors</title>
<link>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/pan9wn/hackers-hijacked-asus-software-updates-to-install-backdoors-on-thousands-of-computers</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/pan9wn/hackers-hijacked-asus-software-updates-to-install-backdoors-on-thousands-of-computers</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at cybersecurity firm Kaspersky Lab say that ASUS, one of the world’s largest computer makers, was used to unwittingly install a malicious backdoor on thousands of its customers’ computers last year after attackers compromised a server for the company’s live software update tool. The malicious file was signed with legitimate ASUS digital certificates to make it appear to be an authentic software update from the company, Kaspersky Lab says.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ASUS, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asus.com/us/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;multi-billion dollar computer hardware company&lt;/a&gt; based in Taiwan that manufactures desktop computers, laptops, mobile phones, smart home systems, and other electronics, was pushing the backdoor to customers for at least five months last year before it was discovered, according to new research from the Moscow-based security firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers estimate half a million Windows machines received the malicious backdoor through the ASUS update server, although the attackers appear to have been targeting only about 600 of those systems. The malware searched for targeted systems through their unique MAC addresses. Once on a system, if it found one of these targeted addresses, the malware reached out to a command-and-control server the attackers operated, which then installed additional malware on those machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaspersky Lab said it uncovered the attack in January after adding a new supply-chain detection technology to its scanning tool to catch anomalous code fragments hidden in legitimate code or catch code that is hijacking normal operations on a machine. The company plans to release a full technical paper and presentation about the ASUS attack, which it has dubbed ShadowHammer, next month at its &lt;a href=&quot;https://sas.kaspersky.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Security Analyst Summit&lt;/a&gt; in Singapore. In the meantime, Kaspersky has published some of the technical details on &lt;a href=&quot;https://securelist.com/operation-shadowhammer/89992/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;its website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;“We saw the updates come down from the Live Update ASUS server. They were trojanized, or malicious updates, and they were signed by ASUS.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue highlights the growing threat from so-called supply-chain attacks, where malicious software or components get installed on systems as they’re manufactured or assembled, or afterward via trusted vendor channels. Last year the US launched a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dhs.gov/news/2018/11/15/dhs-announces-ict-supply-chain-risk-management-task-force-members&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;supply chain task force&lt;/a&gt; to examine the issue after a number of supply-chain attacks were uncovered in recent years. Although most attention on supply-chain attacks focuses on the potential for malicious implants to be added to hardware or software during manufacturing, vendor software updates are an ideal way for attackers to deliver malware to systems after they’re sold, because customers trust vendor updates, especially if they’re signed with a vendor’s legitimate digital certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This attack shows that the trust model we are using based on known vendor names and validation of digital signatures cannot guarantee that you are safe from malware,” said Vitaly Kamluk, Asia-Pacific director of Kaspersky Lab’s Global Research and Analysis Team who led the research. He noted that ASUS denied to Kaspersky that its server was compromised and that the malware came from its network when the researchers contacted the company in January. But the download path for the malware samples Kaspersky collected leads directly back to the ASUS server, Kamluk said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motherboard sent ASUS a list of the claims made by Kaspersky in three separate emails on Thursday but has not heard back from the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__blockquote&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more: &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/d3y48v/what-is-a-supply-chain-attack&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;What Is a 'Supply Chain Attack?'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the US-based security firm Symantec confirmed the Kaspersky findings on Friday after being asked by Motherboard to see if any of its customers also received the malicious download. The company is still investigating the matter but said in a phone call that at least 13,000 computers belonging to Symantec customers were infected with the malicious software update from ASUS last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We saw the updates come down from the Live Update ASUS server. They were trojanized, or malicious updates, and they were signed by ASUS,” said Liam O’Murchu, director of development for the Security Technology and Response group at Symantec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time attackers have used trusted software updates to infect systems. The infamous &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2013/03/flame-windows-update-copycat/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Flame spy tool&lt;/a&gt;, developed by some of the same attackers behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/11/countdown-to-zero-day-stuxnet/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stuxnet&lt;/a&gt;, was the first known attack to trick users in this way by hijacking the Microsoft Windows updating tool on machines to infect computers. Flame, discovered in 2012, was signed with an unauthorized Microsoft certificate that attackers tricked Microsoft’s system into issuing to them. The attackers in that case did not actually compromise Microsoft’s update server to deliver Flame. Instead, they were able to redirect the software update tool on the machines of targeted customers so that they contacted a malicious server the attackers controlled instead of the legitimate Microsoft update server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two different attacks discovered in 2017 also compromised trusted software updates. One involved the computer security cleanup tool known as CCleaner that was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcworld.com/article/3225407/ccleaner-downloads-infected-malware.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;delivering malware to customers&lt;/a&gt; via a software update. More than 2 million customers received that malicious update before it was discovered. The other incident involved the infamous notPetya attack that began in Ukraine and infected machines via a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csoonline.com/article/3233210/petya-ransomware-and-notpetya-malware-what-you-need-to-know-now.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;malicious update&lt;/a&gt; to an accounting software package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costin Raiu, company-wide director of Kaspersky’s Global Research and Analysis Team, said the ASUS attack is different from these others. “I’d say this attack stands out from previous ones while being one level up in complexity and stealthiness. The filtering of targets in a surgical manner by their MAC addresses is one of the reasons it stayed undetected for so long. If you are not a target, the malware is virtually silent,” he told Motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even if silent on non-targeted systems, the malware still gave the attackers a backdoor into every infected ASUS system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tony Sager, senior vice president at the Center for Internet Security who did defensive vulnerability analysis for the NSA for years, said the method the attackers chose to target specific computers is odd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Supply chain attacks are in the ‘big deal’ category and are a sign of someone who is careful about this and has done some planning,” he told Motherboard in a phone call. “But putting something out that hits tens of thousands of targets when you’re really going only after a few is really going after something with a hammer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaspersky researchers first detected the malware on a customer’s machine on January 29. After they created a signature to find the malicious update file on other customer systems, they discovered that more than 57,000 Kaspersky customers had been infected with it. That victim toll only accounts for Kaspersky customers, however. Kamluk said the real number is likely in the hundreds of thousands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the infected machines belonging to Kaspersky customers (about 18 percent) were in Russia, followed by fewer numbers in Germany and France. Only about 5 percent of infected Kaspersky customers were in the United States. Symantec’s O’Murchu said that about 15 percent of the 13,000 machines belonging to his company’s infected customers were in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kamluk said Kaspersky notified ASUS of the problem on January 31, and a Kaspersky employee met with ASUS in person on February 14. But he said the company has been largely unresponsive since then and has not notified ASUS customers about the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attackers used two different ASUS digital certificates to sign their malware. The first expired in mid-2018, so the attackers then switched to a second legitimate ASUS certificate to sign their malware after this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kamluk said ASUS continued to use one of the compromised certificates to sign its own files for at least a month after Kaspersky notified the company of the problem, though it has since stopped. But Kamluk said ASUS has still not invalidated the two compromised certificates, which means the attackers or anyone else with access to the un-expired certificate could still sign malicious files with it, and machines would view those files as legitimate ASUS files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wouldn't be the first time ASUS was accused of compromising the security of its customers. In 2016, the company was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/system/files/documents/cases/1607asustekcmpt.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;charged by the Federal Trade Commission&lt;/a&gt; with misrepresentation and unfair security practices over multiple vulnerabilities in its routers, cloud back-up storage and firmware update tool that would have allowed attackers to gain access to customer files and router log-in credentials, among other things. The FTC claimed ASUS knew about those vulnerabilities for at least a year before fixing them and notifying customers, putting nearly a million US router owners at risk of attack. ASUS settled the case by agreeing to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2016/02/asus-settles-ftc-charges-insecure-home-routers-cloud-services-put&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;establish and maintain a comprehensive security program&lt;/a&gt; that would be subject to independent audit for 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ASUS live update tool that delivered malware to customers last year is installed at the factory on ASUS laptops and other devices. When users enable it, the tool contacts the ASUS update server periodically to see if any firmware or other software updates are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;“They wanted to get into very specific targets and they already knew in advance their network card MAC address, which is quite interesting.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The malicious file pushed to customer machines through the tool was called setup.exe, and purported to be an update to the update tool itself. It was actually a three-year-old ASUS update file from 2015 that the attackers injected with malicious code before signing it with a legitimate ASUS certificate. The attackers appear to have pushed it out to users between June and November 2018, according to Kaspersky Lab. Kamluk said the use of an old binary with a current certificate suggests the attackers had access to the server where ASUS signs its files but not the actual build server where it compiles new ones. Because the attackers used the same ASUS binary each time, it suggests they didn’t have access to the whole ASUS infrastructure, just part of the signing infrastructure, Kamluk notes. Legitimate ASUS software updates still got pushed to customers during the period the malware was being pushed out, but these legitimate updates were signed with a different certificate that used enhanced validation protection, Kamluk said, making it more difficult to spoof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kaspersky researchers collected more than 200 samples of the malicious file from customer machines, which is how they discovered the attack was multi-staged and targeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buried in those malicious samples were hard-coded MD5 hash values that turned out to be unique MAC addresses for network adapter cards. MD5 is an algorithm that creates a cryptographic representation or value for data that is run through the algorithm. Every network card has a unique ID or address assigned by the manufacturer of the card, and the attackers created a hash of each MAC address it was seeking before hard-coding those hashes into their malicious file, to make it more difficult to see what the malware was doing. The malware had 600 unique MAC addresses it was seeking, though the actual number of targeted customers may be larger than this. Kaspersky can only see the MAC addresses that were hard-coded into the particular malware samples found on its customers’ machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1553292749933-shutterstock_1181403586.jpeg?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1553292749933-shutterstock_1181403586&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1553292749933-shutterstock_1181403586.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image: Shutterstock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kaspersky researchers were able to crack most of the hashes they found to determine the MAC addresses, which helped them identify what network cards the victims had installed on their machines, but not the victims themselves. Any time the malware infected a machine, it collected the MAC address from that machine’s network card, hashed it, and compared that hash against the ones hard-coded in the malware. If it found a match to any of the 600 targeted addresses, the malware reached out to &lt;a href=&quot;http://asushotfix.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;asushotfix.com&lt;/a&gt;, a site masquerading as a legitimate ASUS site, to fetch a second-stage backdoor that it downloaded to that system. Because only a small number of machines contacted the command-and-control server, this helped the malware stay under the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They were not trying to target as many users as possible,” said Kamluk. “They wanted to get into very specific targets and they already knew in advance their network card MAC address, which is quite interesting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Symantec’s O’Murchu said he’s not sure yet if any of his company’s customers were among those whose MAC addresses were on the target list and received the second-stage backdoor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The command-and-control server that delivered the second-stage backdoor was registered May 3 last year but was shut down in November before Kaspersky discovered the attack. Because of this, the researchers were unable to obtain a copy of the second-stage backdoor pushed out to victims or identify victim machines that had contacted that server. Kaspersky believes at least one of its customers in Russia got infected with the second-stage backdoor when his machine contacted the command-and-control server on October 29 last year, but Raiu says the company doesn’t know the identity of the machine’s owner in order to contact him and investigate further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were early hints that a signed and malicious ASUS update was being pushed to users in June 2018, when a number of people posted comments in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ASUS/comments/8qznaj/asusfourceupdaterexe_is_trying_to_do_some_mystery/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reddit forum&lt;/a&gt; about a suspicious ASUS alert that popped up on their machines for a “critical” update. “ASUS strongly recommends that you install these updates now,” the alert warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a post titled “ASUSFourceUpdater.exe is trying to do some mystery update, but it won't say what,” a user named GreyWolfx wrote, “I got an update popup from a .exe that I had never seen before today….I’m just curious if anyone knows what this update would possibly be for?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he and other users clicked on their ASUS updater tool to get information about the update, the tool showed no recent updates had been issued from ASUS. But because the file was digitally signed with an ASUS certificate and because scans of the file on the VirusTotal web site indicated it was not malicious, many accepted the update as legitimate and downloaded it to their machines. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/09/how-hackers-use-virustotal/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VirusTotal&lt;/a&gt; is a site that aggregates dozens of antivirus programs; users can upload suspicious files to the site to see if any of the tools detect it as malicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I uploaded the executable [to VirusTotal] and it comes back as a validly signed file without issue,” one user wrote. “The spelling of 'force' and the empty details window are indeed odd, but I noticed odd grammar errors in other ASUS software installed on this system, so it's not a smoking gun by itself,” he noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kamluk and Raiu said this may not be the first time the ShadowHammer attackers have struck. They said they found similarities between the ASUS attack and ones previously conducted by a group dubbed ShadowPad by Kaspersky. ShadowPad targeted a Korean company that makes enterprise software for administering servers; the same group was also linked to the CCleaner attack. Although millions of machines were infected with the malicious CCleaner software update, only a subset of these got targeted with a second stage backdoor, similar to the ASUS victims. Notably, ASUS systems themselves were on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.avast.com/additional-information-regarding-the-recent-ccleaner-apt-security-incident&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;targeted CCleaner list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kaspersky researchers believe the ShadowHammer attackers were behind the ShadowPad and CCleaner attacks and obtained access to the ASUS servers through the latter attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“ASUS was one of the primary targets of the CCleaner attack,” Raiu said. “One of the possibilities we are taking into account is that’s how they intially got into the ASUS network and then later through persistence they managed to leverage the access … to launch the ASUS attack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/cyber/id1441708044?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen to CYBER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, Motherboard’s new weekly podcast about hacking and cybersecurity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 13:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yankcrime</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Hackers Hijacked ASUS Software Updates to Install Backdoors on Thousands of Computers</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5c95589b230c840007f72aca/lede/1553292021826-shutterstock_1153426579.jpeg?crop=1xw:0.8439609902475619xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/pan9wn/hackers-hijacked-asus-software-updates-to-install-backdoors-on-thousands-of-computers</og:url>
<og:description>The Taiwan-based tech giant ASUS is believed to have pushed the malware to hundreds of thousands of customers through its trusted automatic software update tool after attackers compromised the company’s server and used it to push the malware to machines.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/pan9wn/hackers-hijacked-asus-software-updates-to-install-backdoors-on-thousands-of-computers</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>