<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Linus Torvalds: “Do No Harm”</title>
<link>https://lkml.org/lkml/2017/11/21/356</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lkml.org/lkml/2017/11/21/356</guid>
<description>&lt;pre itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
[ This turned longer than it should have. I guess jet lag is a good thing ]&lt;p&gt;On Tue, Nov 21, 2017 at 3:48 AM, Jason A. Donenfeld &amp;lt;Jason@zx2c4.com&amp;gt; wrote:&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; It might be news to you that actually some security people scoff at&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; other security peoples' obsession with &quot;security bugs&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heh. I'm not actually surprised. It's just that the public &quot;look at&lt;br /&gt;this security bug&quot; ones are the ones  you see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The security industry is largely obsessed by finding (and&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; selling/using/patching/reporting/showcasing/stockpiling/detecting/stealing)&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; these &quot;dangerous/useful&quot; variety of bugs. And this obsession is&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; continually fulfilled because bugs keep happening -- which is just the&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; nature of software development -- and so this &quot;security bug&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; infatuation continues. It even leads to people upset with you that you&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; don't care about CVEs and so forth, because they're so fixated on&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; individual bugs and their security impact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agreed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; So what's the&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; alternative to obsessing over each individual software bug?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; In the context of the kernel, the solution from Spender and Pipacs,&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; and more recently &quot;adopted&quot; by Kees and his KSPP project, has been to&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; try to eliminate the &quot;security utility&quot; of bugs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the thing is, I obviously agree very much about the whole &quot;let's&lt;br /&gt;have multiple layers of security even within the kernel, so that&lt;br /&gt;random individual bugs don't end up being so exploitable&quot;. Bugs will&lt;br /&gt;happen, let's aim to limit their damage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To turn them &quot;benign&quot; in your words.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I should be thrilled pink about the hardening efforts, right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I would - except for what &quot;benign&quot; means in that context, and&lt;br /&gt;how security people have very different expectations from users - and&lt;br /&gt;how those are both different from developers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From a security standpoint, when you find an invalid access, and you&lt;br /&gt;mitigate it, you've done a great job, and your hardening was&lt;br /&gt;successful and you're done. &quot;Look ma, it's not a security issue any&lt;br /&gt;more&quot;, and you can basically ignore it as &quot;just another bug&quot; that is&lt;br /&gt;now in a class that is no longer your problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So to you, the big win is when the access is _stopped_. That's the end&lt;br /&gt;of the story from a security standpoint - at least if you are one of&lt;br /&gt;those bad security people who don't care about anything else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But from a developer standpoint, things _really_ are not done. Not&lt;br /&gt;even close. From a developer standpoint, the bad access was just a&lt;br /&gt;symptom, and it needs to be reported, and debugged, and fixed, so that&lt;br /&gt;the bug actually gets corrected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So from a developer standpoint, the end point of  hardening is just&lt;br /&gt;the starting point, and when _you_ think you're done, we're really&lt;br /&gt;only getting started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And from a _user_ standpoint, it's something else altogether. For a&lt;br /&gt;user, pretty much EVERY SINGLE TIME, it wasn't actually a security&lt;br /&gt;attack at all, it was just a latent bug that got exposed. And the&lt;br /&gt;keyword here is that it was _latent_, and things used to work, and the&lt;br /&gt;hardening patch did something - probably fairly drastic - to turn it&lt;br /&gt;from &quot;dangerous&quot; to &quot;benign&quot; from a security perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So from a user standpoint, the hardening was just a big nasty&lt;br /&gt;annoyance, and probably made their workflow _break_, without actually&lt;br /&gt;helping their case at all, because they never really saw the original&lt;br /&gt;bug as a problem to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notice? BIG disconnect in what &quot;hardening&quot; means for three groups, and&lt;br /&gt;in particular, the number one rule of kernel development is that &quot;we&lt;br /&gt;don't break users&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because without users, your program is pointless, and all the&lt;br /&gt;development work you've done over decades is pointless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;.. and security is pointless too, in the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, the thing that annoys me and that makes me so _angry_ about this,&lt;br /&gt;is that it shouldn't need to be that huge a disconnect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It shouldn't need to be a big issue, because pretty much all the work&lt;br /&gt;done for hardening should be able to actually make both the developers&lt;br /&gt;and the users _happier_, instead of just making their lives miserable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But that does mean that he hardening people need to really see past&lt;br /&gt;that &quot;endpoint&quot; that they were looking at.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a developer, the hardening effort _could_ be a great boon, in that&lt;br /&gt;it could show nasty bugs early, it could make them easier to report,&lt;br /&gt;and it could add a lot of useful information to that report that makes&lt;br /&gt;them easier to fix too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And from a user perspective, the hardening work shouldn't have to mean&lt;br /&gt;&quot;the latent bug that I didn't care about now screwed me over and is an&lt;br /&gt;overt bug for me&quot;. It might not help the user directly, but if a year&lt;br /&gt;from now, the latent bug that made their machine occasionally go all&lt;br /&gt;wonky is fixed, the hardening effort did end up helping them too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what do we need for this to actually happen?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a developer, I do want the report. But if you killed the user&lt;br /&gt;program in the process, I'm actually _less_ likely to get the report,&lt;br /&gt;because the latent access was most likely in some really rare and&lt;br /&gt;nasty case, or we would have found it already. In the kernel, there's&lt;br /&gt;a high likelihood that it was in a driver, for example. Maybe an&lt;br /&gt;unusual ioctl() that is not getting a huge amount of attention,&lt;br /&gt;because it's one driver ramong thousands, and it's probably not used&lt;br /&gt;every time anyway. But because it's the kernel, and because it's a&lt;br /&gt;driver, it's quite likely that killing the offender will do bad things&lt;br /&gt;to various random locks that were held, or maybe it happens in an&lt;br /&gt;interrupt and the whole machine is now dead if we're unlucky because&lt;br /&gt;there really were some very core locks being held.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And as a user, my unhappiness is obvious. You don't even have to kill&lt;br /&gt;the machine and make it hard to report to make a user unhappy, just&lt;br /&gt;&quot;the new kernel didn't work for me&quot; will make that user skittish about&lt;br /&gt;upgrading the kernel at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the fix really looks fairly straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- when adding hardening features, you as a security person should&lt;br /&gt;always see that hardening to be the _endpoint_, but not the immediate&lt;br /&gt;goal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- when adding hardening features, the first step should *ALWAYS* be&lt;br /&gt;&quot;just report it&quot;. Not killing things, not even stopping the access.&lt;br /&gt;Report it. Nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Do no harm&quot; should be your mantra for any new hardening work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that &quot;do no harm&quot; may feel antithetical to the whole point. You go&lt;br /&gt;&quot;but t hat doesn't work - then the bug still exists&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But remember - keep your eye on the endpoint, and that this is just&lt;br /&gt;the first step. You need to not piss off users, and you need to not&lt;br /&gt;piss of developers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because if you as a security person just piss off users, and piss off&lt;br /&gt;developers, I'm not going to take your work, and I'm going to call you&lt;br /&gt;a bad security person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because in the end, those users really do matter. Without those users,&lt;br /&gt;your system may be &quot;secure&quot;, but all your security work was still just&lt;br /&gt;masturbation. You didn't do anything useful at all in the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So if hardening people can learn to &quot;always report first&quot;, then I&lt;br /&gt;think we can all work together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But that really does mean that you don't start killing processes until&lt;br /&gt;after you've shown that &quot;look, the code to report these things has&lt;br /&gt;been there for months, can we start doing more drastic things now?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And remember: it's not that the code is  months old. It's that the&lt;br /&gt;code has been RUN BY USERS for months. If it's been in your tree, or&lt;br /&gt;in grsecurity for five years, that doesn't mean a thing. It only means&lt;br /&gt;that hardly anybody actually ever ran it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If it's been on a random cellphone for a few months, and real users&lt;br /&gt;used it, and had facebook and candy crush running on it, that's a&lt;br /&gt;pretty different deal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If it's been in a released kernel for a year, and Ubuntu and Fedora&lt;br /&gt;and SuSE had it enabled, and there aren't reports, that's a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In contrast, if it's been on your server farm for three months, that&lt;br /&gt;means _nothing_. You have pretty much zero coverage of the driver&lt;br /&gt;situation, or of the random apps that people run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All I need is that the whole &quot;let's kill processes&quot; mentality goes&lt;br /&gt;away, and that people acknowledge that the first step is always &quot;just&lt;br /&gt;report&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do no harm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 07:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ekianjo</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lkml.org/lkml/2017/11/21/356</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Join the Battle for Net Neutrality</title>
<link>https://www.battleforthenet.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.battleforthenet.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;IE=edge&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1, user-scalable=no&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Join the Battle for Net Neutrality&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;The FCC is trying to kill the Internet again. This time, it’s even worse. Here’s how to stop them...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;Fight for the Future&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta itemprop=&quot;name&quot; content=&quot;Battle for the Net&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta itemprop=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;The FCC is trying to kill the Internet again. This time, it’s even worse. Here’s how to stop them...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta itemprop=&quot;image&quot; content=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/images/share_images/urgent.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;website&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/images/share_images/urgent.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;Comcast wants to control what you do online. Do you want to let them?&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;Comment for “no”. Share this for “oh hell no.” Then click through to actually stop it.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;Battle For The Net&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary_large_image&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@FightForTheFtr&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;Battle for the Net&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;The FCC is trying to kill the Internet again. This time, it’s even worse. Here’s how to stop them...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image&quot; content=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/images/share_images/urgent.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Montserrat:400,700|Open+Sans:400,700&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/open-iconic/1.1.1/font/css/open-iconic.min.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;/dist/index.css?v=8f333317de43db70fd6f34d8f21ee58799bfff67&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;bftn-homepage&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;88.960726846424&quot;&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;unit calls-number&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who's driving the most calls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; net neutrality? Why does it matter?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;unit&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Net neutrality&lt;/em&gt; is the principle that Internet providers like Comcast &amp;amp; Verizon should not control what we see and do online. In 2015, startups, Internet freedom groups, and 3.7 million commenters won strong net neutrality rules from the US Federal Communication Commission (FCC). The rules prohibit Internet providers from blocking, throttling, and paid prioritization—&quot;fast lanes&quot; for sites that pay, and slow lanes for everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;unit&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We are Team Internet. We support net neutrality, freedom of speech.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly everyone who understands and depends on the Internet supports net neutrality, whether they're startup founders, activists, gamers, politicians, investors, comedians, YouTube stars, or typical Internet users who just want their Internet to work as advertised—regardless of their political party. But don't take our word for it. Ask around, or watch some of these videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;They are Team Cable. They want to end net neutrality, to control &amp;amp; tax the Internet.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;unit&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cable companies are famous for high prices and poor service. Several rank as the most hated companies in America. Now, they're lobbying the FCC and Congress to end net neutrality. Why? It's simple: &lt;em&gt;if they win the power to slow sites down, they can bully any site into paying millions to escape the &quot;slow lane.&quot;&lt;/em&gt; This would amount to a tax on every sector of the American economy. Every site would cost more, since they'd all have to pay big cable. Worse, it would extinguish the startups and independent voices who can't afford to pay. If we lose net neutrality, the Internet will never be the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;unit participants&quot; readability=&quot;11.983240223464&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On July 12, 2017, thousands of us protested to defend Internet freedom.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In just one day, websites large and small participated in one of the biggest online protests ever, reaching tens of millions of people, driving over 2 million comments to the FCC and over 5 million emails—and over 124,000 calls—to members of Congress. &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/a/vYVet&quot;&gt;See the screenshots&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/july12/#participants&quot;&gt;View More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;join&quot; class=&quot;unit join&quot; readability=&quot;15.126213592233&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Now, we must convince Congress to stop the FCC. Can you display an alert?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need your help. Congress could come out to stop the FCC, but generating calls in every House district requires massive amounts of traffic. You can display a prominent alert on your site that shows the world what the web will look like without net neutrality—and asks your visitors to call. &lt;a href=&quot;https://widget.battleforthenet.com/demos/modal.html&quot;&gt;Click here for a demo&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fightforthefuture/battleforthenet-widget&quot;&gt;grab the code on GitHub.&lt;/a&gt; None of these will actually block, slow, or paywall your site. But, they will let your users contact their representatives in Congress without having to leave your page. They appear once per user per day and users can easily click away. &lt;em&gt;Just add this line of code to your site's header:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script src=&quot;https://widget.battleforthenet.com/widget.js&quot; async&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You can use these banners and images too...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;unit&quot; readability=&quot;14.36773255814&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where do your members of Congress stand? Find out, and tweet them!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To win, we need to bring more members of Congress onto &quot;Team Internet&quot;—especially Republicans. Republican members of Congress face massive pressure from party leadership to oppose Net Neutrality, partly because of lobbying by Team Cable, and partly because they see it as &quot;Obama era&quot; policy. But Net Neutrality predates Obama, has always been a design principle of the Internet, and does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; need to be a partisan issue. Some Republicans are open to the need for rules—but they won't break ranks from party leaders unless they hear from constituents. Tweets are surprisingly effective—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/#bftn-action-form&quot;&gt;and you should still call too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;unit&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Extra Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some excellent articles for additional depth. They cover the issue, its political history, the struggles we've overcome, and the fight ahead in Congress and at the FCC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/tr?id=1762844240629117&amp;amp;ev=PageView&amp;amp;noscript=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 04:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rayalez</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.battleforthenet.com</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.battleforthenet.com/images/share_images/urgent.png</og:image>
<og:title>Comcast wants to control what you do online. Do you want to let them?</og:title>
<og:description>Comment for “no”. Share this for “oh hell no.” Then click through to actually stop it.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.battleforthenet.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A CEO&amp;#039;s Guide to Emacs (2015)</title>
<link>https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Years—no, decades—ago, I lived in Emacs. I wrote code and documents, managed email and calendar, and shelled all in the editor/OS. I was quite happy. Years went by and I moved to newer, shinier things. As a result, I forgot how to do tasks as basic as efficiently navigating files without a mouse. About three months ago, noticing just how much of my time was spent switching between applications and computers, I decided to give Emacs another try. It was a good decision for several reasons that will be covered in this post. Covered too are &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; and Dropbox tips so that you can set up a good, movable environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who haven't used Emacs, it's something you'll likely hate, but may love. It's sort of a Rube Goldberg machine the size of a house that, at first glance, performs all the functions of a toaster. That hardly sounds like an endorsement, but the key phrase is &quot;at first glance.&quot; Once you grok Emacs, you realize that it's a thermonuclear toaster that can also serve as the engine for... well, just about anything you want to do with text. When you think about how much your computing life revolves around text, this is a rather bold statement. Bold, but true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps more importantly to me though, it's the one application I've ever used that makes me feel like I really own it instead of casting me as an anonymous &quot;user&quot; whose wallet is cleverly targeted by product marketing departments in fancy offices somewhere near &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/zachary-ehren/soma-isnt-a-drug-san-fran_b_987841.html&quot;&gt;Soma&lt;/a&gt; or Redmond. Modern productivity and authoring applications (e.g., Pages or IDEs) are like carbon fiber racing bikes. They come kitted out very nicely and fully assembled. Emacs is like a box of classic &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.campagnolo.com/US/en&quot;&gt;Campagnolo&lt;/a&gt; parts and a beautiful lugged steel frame that's missing one crank arm and a brake lever that you have to find in some tiny subculture on the Internet. The first one is faster and complete. The second is a source of endless joy or annoyance depending on your personality—and will last until your dying day. I'm the sort of person who feels equal joy at finding an old stash of Campy parts or tweaking my editor with eLisp. YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/assets/images/bicycle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1933 steel bicycle&quot;/&gt; A 1933 steel bicycle that I still ride. Check out this comparison of frame tubes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=khJQgRLKMU0&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=khJQgRLKMU0&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;This may give the impression that Emacs is anachronistic or old-fashioned. It's not. It's powerful and timeless, but demands that you patiently understand it on its terms. The terms are pretty far off the beaten path and seem odd, but there is a logic to them that is both compelling and charming. To me, Emacs feels like the future rather than the past. Just as the lugged steel frame will be useful and comfortable in decades to come and the carbon fiber wunderbike will be in a landfill, having shattered on impact, so will Emacs persist as a useful tool when the latest trendy app is long forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the notion of building your own personal working environment by editing Lisp code and having that fits-like-a-glove environment follow you to any computer is appealing to you, you may really like Emacs. If you like the new and shiny and want to get straight to work without much investment of time and mental cycles, it's likely not for you. I don't write code any more (other than Ludwig and Emacs Lisp), but many of the engineers at Fugue use Emacs to good effect. I'd say our engineers are about 30% Emacs, 40% IDEs, and 30% Vim users. But, this post is about Emacs for CEOs and other &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/best-pointy-haired-boss-moments-from-dilbert-2013-10&quot;&gt;Pointy-Haired Bosses&lt;/a&gt; (PHB)&lt;sup id=&quot;phbOrigin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html#phb&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (and, hey, anyone who’s curious), so I'm going to explain and/or rationalize why I love it and how I use it. I also hope to provide you with enough detail that you can have a successful experience with it, without hours of Googling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;lasting-advantages&quot;&gt;Lasting Advantages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long-term advantages that come with using Emacs just make life easier. The net gain makes the initial lift entirely worthwhile. Consider these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-more-context-switching&quot;&gt;No More Context Switching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Org Mode alone is worth investing some serious time in, but if you are like me, you are usually working on a dozen or so documents—from blog posts to lists of what you need to do for a conference to employee reviews. In the modern world of computing, this generally means using several applications, all of which have distracting user interfaces and different ways to store, sort, and search. The result is that you need to constantly switch mental contexts and remember minutiae. I hate context switching because it is an imposition put on me due to a broken interface model&lt;sup id=&quot;tufteOrigin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html#tufte&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and I hate having to remember things my computer should remember for me in any rational world. In providing a single environment, Emacs is even more powerful for the PHB than the programmer, since programmers tend to spend a greater percentage of their day in a single application. Switching mental contexts has a higher cost than is often apparent. OS and application vendors have tarted up interfaces to distract us from this reality. If you’re technical, having access to a powerful &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/I/interpreter.html&quot;&gt;language interpreter&lt;/a&gt; in a single keyboard shortcut (&lt;code&gt;M-:&lt;/code&gt;) is especially useful.&lt;sup id=&quot;interpreterOrigin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html#interpreter&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many applications can be full screened all day and used to edit text. Emacs is singular because it is both an editor and a Lisp interpreter. In essence, you have a Turing complete machine a keystroke or two away at all times, while you go about your business. If you know a little or a lot about programming, you'll recognize that this means you can do &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; in Emacs. The full power of your computer is available to you in near real time while you work, once you have the commands in memory. You won't want to re-create Excel in eLisp, but most things you might do in Excel are smaller in scope and easy to accomplish in a line or two of code. If I need to crunch numbers, I'm more likely to jump over to the scratch buffer and write a little code than open a spreadsheet. Even if I have an email to write that isn't a one-liner, I'll usually just write it in Emacs and paste it into my email client. Why context switch when you can just flow? You might start with a simple calculation or two, but, over time, anything you need computed can be added with relative ease to Emacs. This is perhaps unique in applications that also provide rich features for creating things for other humans. Remember those magical terminals in Isaac Asimov's books? Emacs is the closest thing I've encountered to them.&lt;sup id=&quot;ewwOrigin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html#eww&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I no longer decide what app to use for this or that thing. Instead, I just work. There is real power and efficiency to having a great tool and committing to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-things-in-peace-and-quiet&quot;&gt;Creating Things in Peace and Quiet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the end result of having the best text editing features I've ever found? Having a community of people making all manner of useful additions? Having the full power of Lisp a keychord away? It’s that I use Emacs for all my creative work, aside from making music or images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a dual monitor set up at my desk. One of them is in portrait mode with Emacs full screened all day long. The other one has web browsers for researching and reading; it usually has a terminal open as well. I keep my calendar, email, etc., on another desktop in OS X, which is hidden while I'm in Emacs, and I keep all notifications turned off. This allows me to actually concentrate on what I'm doing. I've found eliminating distractions to be almost impossible in the more modern UI applications due to their efforts to be helpful and easy to use. I don't need to be constantly reminded how to do operations I've done tens of thousands of times, but I do need a nice, clean white sheet of paper to be thoughtful. Maybe I'm just bad at living in noisy environments due to age and abuse, but I’d suggest it’s worth a try for anyone. See what it's like to have some actual peace and quiet in your computing environment. Of course, lots of apps now have modes that hide the interface and, thankfully, both Apple and Microsoft now have meaningful full-screen modes. But, no other application is powerful enough to “live in” for most things. Unless you are writing code all day or perhaps working on a very long document like a book, you're still going to face the noise of other apps. Also, most modern applications seem simultaneously patronizing and lacking in functionality and usability.&lt;sup id=&quot;usabilityOrigin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html#usability&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The only applications I dislike more than office apps are the online versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/assets/images/desktop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1933 steel bicycle&quot;/&gt; My desktop arrangement. Emacs on the left.
&lt;p&gt;But what about communicating? The difference between creating and communicating is substantial. I'm much more productive at both when I set aside distinct time for each. We use Slack at Fugue, which is both wonderful and hellish. I keep it on a messaging desktop alongside my calendar and email, so that, while I'm actually making things, I'm blissfully unaware of all the chatter in the world. It takes just one Slackstorm or an email from a VC or Board Director to immediately throw me out of my work. But, most things can usually wait an hour or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;taking-everything-with-you-and-keeping-it-forever&quot;&gt;Taking Everything with You and Keeping It Forever&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third reason I find Emacs more advantageous than other environments is that it's easy to take all your stuff with you. By this, I mean that, rather than having a plethora of apps interacting and syncing in their own ways, all you need is one or two directories syncing via Dropbox or the like. Then, you can have all your work follow you anywhere in the environment you have crafted to suit your purposes. I do this across OS X, Windows, and sometimes Linux. It's dead simple and reliable. I've found this capability to be so useful that I dread dealing with Pages, GDocs, Office, or other kinds of files and applications that force me back into finding stuff somewhere on the filesystem or in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limiting factor in keeping things forever on a computer is file format. Assuming that humans have now solved the problem of storage &lt;sup id=&quot;s3Origin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html#s3&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for good, the issue we face over time is whether we can continue to access the information we've created. Text files are the most long-lived format for computing. You easily can open a text file from 1970 in Emacs. That’s not so true for Office applications. Text files are also nice and small—radically smaller than Office application data files. As a digital pack rat and as someone who makes lots of little notes as things pop into my head, having a simple, light, permanent collection of stuff that is always available is important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re feeling ready to give Emacs a try, read on! The sections that follow don’t take the place of a full tutorial, but will have you operational by the time you finish reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-to-ride-emacs-a-technical-setup&quot;&gt;Learning To Ride Emacs - A Technical Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The price of all this power and mental peace and quiet is that you have a steep learning curve with Emacs and it does everything differently than you're used to. At first, this will make you feel like you’re wasting time on an archaic and strange application that the modern world passed by. It’s a bit like learning to ride a bicycle&lt;sup id=&quot;bicyclesOrigin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html#bicycles&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; if you've only driven cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;which-emacs-&quot;&gt;Which Emacs?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the plain vanilla Emacs from GNU for OS X and Windows. You can get the OS X version at &lt;a href=&quot;http://emacsformacosx.com/&quot;&gt;http://emacsformacosx.com/&lt;/a&gt; and the Windows version at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&lt;/a&gt;. There are a bunch of other versions out there, especially for the Mac, but I've found the learning curve for doing powerful stuff (which involves Lisp and lots of modes) to be much lower with the real deal. So download it, and we can get started!&lt;sup id=&quot;nottutorialOrigin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html#nottutorial&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-you-ll-need-to-learn-how-to-navigate&quot;&gt;First, You'll Need To Learn How To Navigate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the Emacs conventions for keys and combinations in this document. These are 'C' for control, 'M' for meta (which is usually mapped to Alt or Option), and the hyphen for holding down the keys in combination. So &lt;code&gt;C-h t&lt;/code&gt; means to hold down control and type h, then release control and type t. This is the command for bringing up the tutorial, which you should go ahead and do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't use the arrow keys or the mouse. They work, but you should give yourself a week of using the native navigation commands in Emacs. Once you have them committed to muscle memory, you'll likely enjoy them and miss them badly everywhere else you go. The Emacs tutorial does a pretty good job of walking you through them, but I'll summarize so you don't need to read the whole thing. The boring stuff is that, instead of arrows, you use &lt;code&gt;C-b&lt;/code&gt; for back, &lt;code&gt;C-f&lt;/code&gt; for forward, &lt;code&gt;C-p&lt;/code&gt; for previous (up), and &lt;code&gt;C-n&lt;/code&gt; for next (down). You may be thinking &quot;why in the world would I do that, when I have perfectly good arrow keys?&quot; There are several reasons. First, you don't have to move your hands from the typing position, and the forward and back keys used with Alt (or Meta in Emacspeak) navigate a word at a time. This is more handy than is obvious. The third good reason is that, if you want to repeat a command, you can precede it with a number. I often use this when editing documents by estimating how many words I need to go back or lines up or down and doing something like &lt;code&gt;C-9 C-p&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;M-5 M-b&lt;/code&gt;. The other really important navigation commands are based on &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; for the beginning of a thing and &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt; for the end of a thing. Using &lt;code&gt;C-a|e&lt;/code&gt; are on lines, and using &lt;code&gt;M-a|e&lt;/code&gt;, are on sentences. For the sentence commands to work properly, you'll need to double space after periods, which simultaneously provides a useful feature and takes a shibboleth of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/29/two-spaces-after-period-debate_n_7455660.html&quot;&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; off the mental table. If you need to export the document to a single space &lt;a href=&quot;http://practicaltypography.com/one-space-between-sentences.html&quot;&gt;publication environment&lt;/a&gt;, you can write a macro in moments to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It genuinely is worth going through the tutorial that ships with Emacs. I'll cover a few important commands for the truly impatient, but the tutorial is gold. Reminder: &lt;code&gt;C-h t&lt;/code&gt; for the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-to-copy-and-paste&quot;&gt;Learn To Copy and Paste&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can put Emacs into &lt;code&gt;CUA&lt;/code&gt; mode, which will work in familiar ways, but the native Emacs way is pretty great and plenty easy once you learn it. You mark regions (like selecting) by using Shift with the navigation commands. So &lt;code&gt;C-F&lt;/code&gt; selects one character forward from the cursor, etc. You copy with &lt;code&gt;M-w&lt;/code&gt;, you cut with &lt;code&gt;C-w&lt;/code&gt;, and you paste with &lt;code&gt;C-y&lt;/code&gt;. These are actually called killing and yanking, but it's very similar to cut and paste. There is magic under the hood here in the kill ring, but for now, just worry about cut, copy, and paste. If you start fumbling around at this point, &lt;code&gt;C-x u&lt;/code&gt; is undo...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-learn-ido-mode&quot;&gt;Next, Learn Ido Mode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust me. Ido makes working with files much easier. You don't generally use a separate Finder|Explorer window to work with files in Emacs. Instead you use the editor's commands to create, open, and save files. This is a bit of a pain without Ido, so I recommend installing it before learning the other way. Ido comes with Emacs beginning with version 22, but you'll want to make some tweaks to your &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; file so that it is always used. This is a good excuse to get your environment set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most features in Emacs come in modes. To install any given mode, you'll need to do two things. Well, at first you'll need to do a few extra things, but these only need to be done once, and thereafter only two things. So the extra things are that you'll need a single place to put all your eLisp files and you'll need to tell Emacs where that place is. I suggest you make a single directory in, say, Dropbox that is your Emacs home. Inside this, you'll want to create an &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; file and an &lt;code&gt;.emacs.d&lt;/code&gt; directory. Inside the &lt;code&gt;.emacs.d&lt;/code&gt;, make a directory called &lt;code&gt;lisp&lt;/code&gt;. So you should have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;home
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
+.emacs
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
-.emacs.d
  &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
  -lisp&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll put the &lt;code&gt;.el&lt;/code&gt; files for things like modes into the &lt;code&gt;home/.emacs.d/lisp&lt;/code&gt; directory, and you'll point to that in your &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(add-to-list 'load-path &quot;~/.emacs.d/lisp/&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ido Mode comes with Emacs, so you won't need to put an &lt;code&gt;.el&lt;/code&gt; file into your Lisp directory for this, but you'll be adding other stuff soon that will go in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;symlinks-are-your-friend&quot;&gt;Symlinks are Your Friend&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, that says that &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.emacs.d&lt;/code&gt; are in your home directory, and we put them in some dumb folder in Dropbox! Correct. This is how you make it easy to have your environment anywhere you go. Keep everything in Dropbox and make symbolic links to &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.emacs.d&lt;/code&gt;, and your main document directories in &lt;code&gt;~&lt;/code&gt;. On OS X, this is super easy with the &lt;code&gt;ln -s&lt;/code&gt; command, but on Windows this is a pain. Fortunately, Emacs provides an easy alternative to symlinking on Windows, the HOME environment variable. Go into Environment Variables in Windows (as of Windows 10, you can just hit the Windows key and type &quot;Environment Variables&quot; to find this with search, which is the best part of Windows 10), and make a HOME environment variable in your account that points to the Dropbox folder you made for Emacs. If you want to make it easy to navigate to local files that aren't in Dropbox, you may instead want to make a symbolic link to the Dropbox Emacs home in your actual home directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now you've done all the jiggery-pokery needed to get any machine pointed to your Emacs setup and files. If you get a new computer or use someone else's for an hour or a day, you get your entire work environment. This seems a little difficult the first time you do it, but it's about a ten minute (at most) operation once you know what you're doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we were configuring Ido...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-x&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;C-f&lt;/code&gt; and type &lt;code&gt;~/.emacs RET RET&lt;/code&gt; to create your &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; file. Add these lines to it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; `ido)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;setq&lt;/span&gt; ido-enable-flex-matching &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-literal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;setq&lt;/span&gt; ido-everywhere &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-literal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;ido-mode&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; buffer open, do an &lt;code&gt;M-x evaluate-buffer&lt;/code&gt; command, and you'll either get an error if you munged something or you'll get Ido. Ido changes how the minibuffer works when doing file operations. There is great documentation on it, but I'll point out a few tips. Use the &lt;code&gt;~/&lt;/code&gt; effectively; you can just type &lt;code&gt;~/&lt;/code&gt; at any point in the minibuffer and it'll jump back to home. Implicit in this is that you should have most of your stuff a short hop off your home. I use &lt;code&gt;~/org&lt;/code&gt; for all my non-code stuff and &lt;code&gt;~/code&lt;/code&gt; for code. Once you’re in the right directory, you'll often have a collection of files with different extensions, especially if you use Org Mode and publish from it. You can type period and the extension you want no matter where you are in the file name and Ido will limit the choices to files with that extension. For example, I'm writing this blog post in Org Mode, so the main file is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/org/blog/emacs.org&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also occasionally push it out to HTML using Org Mode publishing, so I've got an &lt;code&gt;emacs.html&lt;/code&gt; file in the same directory. When I want to open the Org file, I will type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-x C-f ~/o[RET]/bl[RET].or[RET]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The [RET]s are me hitting return for auto completion for Ido Mode. So, that’s 12 characters typed and, if you're used to it, a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; less time than opening Finder|Explorer and clicking around. Ido Mode is plenty useful, but really is a utility mode for operating Emacs. Let's explore some modes that are useful for getting work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;fonts-and-styles&quot;&gt;Fonts and Styles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend getting the excellent input family of typefaces for use in Emacs. They are customizable with different braces, zeroes, and other characters. You can build in extra line spacing into the font files themselves. I recommend a 1.5X line spacing and using their excellent proportional fonts for code and data. I use Input Serif for my writing, which has a funky but modern feel. You can find them on &lt;a href=&quot;http://input.fontbureau.com/&quot;&gt;http://input.fontbureau.com/&lt;/a&gt; where you can customize to your preferences. You can manually set the fonts using menus in Emacs, but this puts code into your &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; file and, if you use multiple devices, you may find you want some different settings. I've set up my &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; to look for the machine I'm using by name and configure the screen appropriately. The code for this is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;setq&lt;/span&gt; myfont &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;InputSerif&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;cond&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;string-equal&lt;/span&gt; system-name &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;Sampo.local&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;set-face-attribute&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-quoted&quot;&gt;'default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-literal&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;:font&lt;/span&gt; myfont &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;:height&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;144&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;toggle-frame-fullscreen&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;string-equal&lt;/span&gt; system-name &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;Morpheus.local&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;set-face-attribute&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-quoted&quot;&gt;'default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-literal&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;:font&lt;/span&gt; myfont &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;:height&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;144&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;string-equal&lt;/span&gt; system-name &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;ILMARINEN&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;set-face-attribute&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-quoted&quot;&gt;'default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-literal&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;:font&lt;/span&gt; myfont &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;:height&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;106&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;string-equal&lt;/span&gt; system-name &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;UKKO&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;set-face-attribute&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-quoted&quot;&gt;'default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-literal&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;:font&lt;/span&gt; myfont &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;:height&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;104&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should replace the &lt;code&gt;system-name&lt;/code&gt; values with what you get when you evaluate &lt;code&gt;(system-name)&lt;/code&gt; in your copy of Emacs. Note that on Sampo (my MacBook), I also set Emacs to full screen. I'd like to do this on Windows as well, but Windows and Emacs don't really love each other and it always ends up in some wonky state when I try this. Instead, I just fullscreen it manually after launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also recommend getting rid of the awful toolbar that Emacs got sometime in the 90s when the cool thing to do was to have toolbars in your application. I also got rid of some other &quot;chrome&quot; so that I have a simple, productive interface. Add these to your &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; file to get rid of the toolbar and scroll bars, but to keep your menu available (on OS X, it'll be hidden unless you mouse to the top of the screen anyway):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-built_in&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;fboundp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-variable&quot;&gt;'scroll-bar-mode&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;scroll-bar-mode&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;-1&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-built_in&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;fboundp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-variable&quot;&gt;'tool-bar-mode&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;tool-bar-mode&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;-1&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-built_in&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;fboundp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-variable&quot;&gt;'menu-bar-mode&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;menu-bar-mode&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;org-mode&quot;&gt;Org Mode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pretty much live in Org Mode. It is my go-to environment for authoring documents, keeping notes, making to-do lists and 90% of everything else I do. Org was originally conceived as a combination note-taking and to-do list utility by a fellow who is a laptop-in-meetings sort. I am against use of laptops in meetings and don't do it myself, so my use cases are a little different than his. For me, Org is primarily a way to handle all manner of content within a structure. There are heads and subheads, etc., in Org Mode, and they function like an outline. Org allows you to expand or hide the contents of the tree and also to rearrange the tree. This fits how I think very nicely and I find it to be just a pleasure to use in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Org Mode also has a lot of little things that make life pleasant. For example, the footnote handling is excellent and the LaTeX/PDF output is great. Org has the ability to generate agendas based on the to-do's in all your documents and a nice way to relate them to dates/times. I don't use this for any sort of external commitments, which are handled on a shared calendar, but for creating things and keeping track of what I need to create in the future, it's invaluable. Installing it is as easy as adding the &lt;code&gt;org-mode.el&lt;/code&gt; to your Lisp directory and adding these lines to your &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt;, if you want it to indent based on tree location and to open documents fully expanded:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;setq&lt;/span&gt; org-startup-indented &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-literal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;setq&lt;/span&gt; org-startup-folded &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;showall&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;setq&lt;/span&gt; org-directory &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;~/org&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last line is there so that Org knows where to look for files to include in agendas and some other things. I keep Org right in my home directory, i.e., a symlink to the directory that lives in Dropbox, as described earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a &lt;code&gt;stuff.org&lt;/code&gt; file that is always open in a buffer. I use it like a notepad. Org makes it easy to extract things like TODOs and stuff with deadlines. It's especially useful when you can inline Lisp code and evaluate it whenever you need. Having code with content is super handy. Again, you have access to the actual computer with Emacs, and this is a liberation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;publishing-with-org-mode&quot;&gt;Publishing with Org Mode&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I care about the appearance and formatting of my documents. I started my career as a designer, and I think information can and should be presented clearly and beautifully. Org has great support for generating PDFs via LaTeX, which has a bit of its own learning curve, but doing simple things is pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to use fonts and styles other than the typical LaTeX ones, you've got a few things to do. First, you'll want XeLaTeX so you can use normal system fonts rather than LaTeX specific fonts. Next, you'll want to add this to &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;setq&lt;/span&gt; org-latex-pdf-process
 '&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;xelatex -interaction nonstopmode %f&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;xelatex -interaction nonstopmode %f&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put this right at the end of my Org section of &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; to keep things tidy. This will allow you to use more formatting options when publishing from Org. For example, I often use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-preprocessor&quot;&gt;#+LaTeX_HEADER: \usepackage{fontspec}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-preprocessor&quot;&gt;#+LATEX_HEADER: \setmonofont[Scale=0.9]{Input Mono}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-preprocessor&quot;&gt;#+LATEX_HEADER: \setromanfont{Maison Neue}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-preprocessor&quot;&gt;#+LATEX_HEADER: \linespread{1.5}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-preprocessor&quot;&gt;#+LATEX_HEADER: \usepackage[margin=1.25in]{geometry}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-preprocessor&quot;&gt;#+TITLE: Document Title Here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These simply go somewhere in your &lt;code&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt; file. Our corporate font for body copy is Maison Neue, but you can put whatever is appropriate here. I strongly discourage the use of Maison Neue. It’s a terrible font and no one should ever use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This file is an example of PDF output using these settings. This is what out-of-the-box LaTeX always looks like. It's fine I suppose, but the fonts are boring and a little odd. Also, if you use the standard format, people will assume they are reading something that is or pretends to be an academic paper. You've been warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ace-jump-mode&quot;&gt;Ace Jump Mode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more of a gem than a major feature, but you want it. It works a bit like Jef Raskin's Leap feature from days gone by.&lt;sup id=&quot;canoncatOrigin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html#canoncat&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The way it works is you type &lt;code&gt;C-c&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;C-SPC&lt;/code&gt; and then type the first letter of the word you want to jump to. It highlights all occurrences of words with that initial character, replacing it with a letter of the alphabet. You simply type the letter of the alphabet for the location you want and your cursor jumps to it. I find myself using this as often as the more typical nav keys or search. Download the &lt;code&gt;.el&lt;/code&gt; to your Lisp directory and put this in your &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;add-to-list&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-variable&quot;&gt;'load-path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;which-folder-ace-jump-mode-file-in/&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-built_in&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-variable&quot;&gt;'ace-jump-mode&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;define-key&lt;/span&gt; global-map &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-list&quot;&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;kbd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;C-c C-SPC&quot;&lt;/span&gt; )&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-variable&quot;&gt;'ace-jump-mode&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-later&quot;&gt;More Later&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's enough for one post—this may get you somewhere you'd like to be. I'd love to hear about your uses for Emacs aside from programming (or for programming!) and whether this was useful at all. There are likely some boneheaded PHBisms in how I use Emacs, and if you want to point them out, I'd appreciate it. I'll probably write some updates over time to introduce additional features or modes. I'll certainly show you how to use Fugue with Emacs and Ludwig-mode as we evolve it into something more useful than code highlighting. Send your thoughts to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fugueHQ&quot;&gt;@fugueHQ&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prakashk</dc:creator>
<og:title>A CEO's Guide to Emacs</og:title>
<og:type>blog</og:type>
<og:url>https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.fugue.co/assets/images/opengraph.png</og:image>
<og:description>Once you grok Emacs, you realize that it's a thermonuclear toaster that can also serve as the engine for... well, just about anything you want to do with text. When you think about how much your computing life revolves around text, this is a rather bold statement. Bold, but true.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Warning Signs About Another Giant Bitcoin Exchange</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/21/technology/bitcoin-bitfinex-tether.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/21/technology/bitcoin-bitfinex-tether.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;226&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1239&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;In the latest blow, on Tuesday, an alternative virtual currency that is owned and operated by the same people as Bitfinex, known as Tether, announced that it had been hacked and lost around $30 million worth of digital tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;274&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1513&quot;&gt;None of that has been enough to stop customers from pumping billions of dollars worth of virtual currency trades through Bitfinex in recent weeks — on some days, the exchange claimed to be doing more trades, by dollar value, than some stock exchanges in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;267&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1780&quot;&gt;Even many people who believe in virtual currencies worry that the mixture of loose controls and booming trading at the world’s largest exchange is likely to cause trouble for all the investors piling into virtual currencies, even those who don’t go near Bitfinex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/21/business/22BITFINEX-2/22BITFINEX-2-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/21/business/22BITFINEX-2/22BITFINEX-2-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;On some days, Bitfinex claims to carry more transactions, in dollar volume, than major stock exchanges.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/21/business/22BITFINEX-2/22BITFINEX-2-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;On some days, Bitfinex claims to carry more transactions, in dollar volume, than major stock exchanges.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;336&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2116&quot;&gt;“I’m worried about the systemic risk that this centralized company poses, and I’m worried that if they go down, they will take down the space with them,” said Emin Gün Sirer, a computer science professor at Cornell University, who has a track record of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/28/business/dealbook/paper-points-up-flaws-in-venture-fund-based-on-virtual-money.html&quot;&gt;successfully predicting problems&lt;/a&gt; in the growing virtual currency industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;174&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2290&quot;&gt;The chief executive of Bitfinex and Tether, Jan Ludovicus van der Velde, said in an email on Tuesday that “the financial position of the company has never been stronger.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;180&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2470&quot;&gt;Concerns over virtual currency exchanges are nothing new. The first and largest Bitcoin exchange, Mt. Gox, collapsed in 2014 after losing $500 million of customer money to hackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;201&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2671&quot;&gt;This year, law enforcement took down another large Bitcoin exchange, BTC-E, which was accused of being a way station for many of the Bitcoin flowing through online black markets and ransomware attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/21/technology/bitcoin-bitfinex-tether.html#story-continues-5&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;181&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2852&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-5&quot;&gt;Regulators in the United States and a few other countries have tried to tame the business, and the largest exchanges in the United States and Japan are now under official oversight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;168&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3020&quot;&gt;Those regulated exchanges, though, are dwarfed by unregulated ones like Bitfinex and several that have popped up in South Korea, where regulators have been slow to act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;284&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3304&quot;&gt;The liquid nature of the Bitcoin markets, flowing around national borders and laws, is a product of the virtual currency’s unusual structure. Bitcoin is stored and moved through a decentralized network of computers that are not under the control of any single company or government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;&gt;The New York Times Explains...&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;149&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3453&quot;&gt;This structure means that the virtual currency continues to be an easy target for people who want to manipulate its price or use it to launder money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/21/business/22BITFINEX-4/22BITFINEX-4-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/21/business/22BITFINEX-4/22BITFINEX-4-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;The chief executive of Mt. Gox, Mark Karpel&amp;#xE8;s, second from left, at a 2014 news conference with lawyers in Tokyo after his virtual currency exchange collapsed.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Kimimasa Mayama/European Pressphoto Agency&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/21/business/22BITFINEX-4/22BITFINEX-4-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;The chief executive of Mt. Gox, Mark Karpelès, second from left, at a 2014 news conference with lawyers in Tokyo after his virtual currency exchange collapsed.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Kimimasa Mayama/European Pressphoto Agency&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;226&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3679&quot;&gt;“Unregulated, unregistered exchanges are a very big concern for the industry and the community broadly,” said Kathryn Haun, a former federal prosecutor who is on the board of the American virtual currency company Coinbase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;295&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3974&quot;&gt;The most frequent face of Bitfinex is its chief strategy officer, Phil Potter. Mr. Potter worked for Morgan Stanley in New York in the 1990s but lost his job after &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1997/10/19/business/faces-of-the-new-york-economy-big-earner-big-spender-little-burden.html&quot;&gt;bragging at length in The New York Times&lt;/a&gt; about his $3,500 Rolex, his opulent lifestyle and his aggressive tactics for making money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;215&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4189&quot;&gt;Mr. Potter, 45, runs Bitfinex alongside Mr. Van der Velde, a Dutch-speaking man living in Hong Kong, and Giancarlo Devasini, an Italian man who lives on the French Riviera, according to company filings in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;209&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4398&quot;&gt;The company lost 1,500 Bitcoin, worth around $400,000, to a hacker in 2015. But the most damaging incident happened in August 2016 when a thief got almost 120,000 Bitcoin, worth around $75 million at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;213&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4611&quot;&gt;The company spread out the losses to all customers — even those who were not holding Bitcoin at the time of the hacking — by forcing customers to take a 36 percent haircut or loss on any money at the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-3&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/21/technology/bitcoin-bitfinex-tether.html#story-continues-6&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;178&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4789&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-6&quot;&gt;The lack of detail that Bitfinex provided about the hacking drove away some large customers like Arthur Hayes, the founder of Bitmex, a Hong Kong-based virtual currency exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;138&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4927&quot;&gt;“There are so many questions about them,” Mr. Hayes said. “All of this could be easily rectified by just showing all the figures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;173&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5100&quot;&gt;Mr. van der Velde said the company had “been as public and transparent as possible about the security incident in August 2016 given the ongoing criminal investigations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/21/business/22BITFINEX-3/22BITFINEX-3-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/21/business/22BITFINEX-3/22BITFINEX-3-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Coinone Blocks, a walk-in cryptocurrency exchange in Seoul, the first in South Korea.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Jean Chung for The New York Times&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/21/business/22BITFINEX-3/22BITFINEX-3-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Coinone Blocks, a walk-in cryptocurrency exchange in Seoul, the first in South Korea.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Jean Chung for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;355&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5455&quot;&gt;Banks have also been put off by Bitfinex’s operations. Wells Fargo said this year that it would no longer move money from Bitfinex accounts. Shortly after, Bitfinex said its main banks in Taiwan were shutting it off. Since then, it has moved between a series of banks in other countries, without telling customers where the exchange’s money is stored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;159&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5614&quot;&gt;But nothing has drawn more criticism than the operation of Tether, a virtual currency that is supposed to be tied — or tethered — to the value of a dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;407&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6021&quot;&gt;Customers can buy Tether coins on Bitfinex and then transfer them to other virtual currency exchanges, providing a way to move dollars between countries without going through banks. Tether has also become a very popular way to buy Bitcoin. In recent weeks, a few hundred millions dollars’ worth of Tether has changed hands on a daily basis across several exchanges, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/tether/#markets&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; on CoinMarketCap.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;316&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6337&quot;&gt;Tether and Bitfinex have insisted that the two operations are separate. But &lt;a href=&quot;https://offshoreleaks.icij.org/nodes/82024464&quot;&gt;leaked documents known as the Paradise Papers&lt;/a&gt;, which were made public this month, show that Appleby, an offshore law firm, helped Mr. Potter and Mr. Devasini, the Bitfinex operators, set up Tether in the British Virgin Islands in late 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;252&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6589&quot;&gt;One persistent online critic, going by the screen name Bitfinex’ed, has written &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@bitfinexed&quot;&gt;several very detailed essays on Medium&lt;/a&gt; arguing that Bitfinex appears to be creating Tether coins out of thin air and then using them to buy Bitcoin and push the price up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-4&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/21/technology/bitcoin-bitfinex-tether.html#story-continues-7&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;294&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6883&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-7&quot;&gt;Tether and Bitfinex have countered this criticism in statements on the companies’ websites and promised that every Tether is backed up by a dollar sitting in a bank account. In September, the companies &lt;a href=&quot;https://tether.to/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Final-Tether-Consulting-Report-9-15-17_Redacted.pdf&quot;&gt;provided an accounting document&lt;/a&gt; intended to prove that Tether is financed with real money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;216&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7099&quot;&gt;Lewis Cohen, a lawyer at the law firm Hogan Lovells who advises many virtual currency projects, said the document, because of the careful way it was phrased, did not prove that the Tether coins are backed by dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;207&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7306&quot;&gt;Even if they are, he said, Tether and Bitfinex appear to be violating laws in the United States and Europe that govern investments like Tether, which has qualities very similar to a money market mutual fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;105&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7411&quot;&gt;“There are a long list of reasons that you don’t want to deal with them,” Mr. Cohen said of Tether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;189&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7600&quot;&gt;On Tuesday, Tether announced that an “external attacker” had taken $30 million worth of Tether from the company’s online wallets. The company said it was working to recover the coins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/21/technology/bitcoin-bitfinex-tether.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>donohoe</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/21/technology/bitcoin-bitfinex-tether.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Warning Signs About Another Giant Bitcoin Exchange</og:title>
<og:description>On some days, Bitfinex claims to be doing more trades than some stock exchanges. But it has lost millions in two hackings and has no government oversight.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/11/22/business/22BITFINEX-1/22BITFINEX-1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/21/technology/bitcoin-bitfinex-tether.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ketamine lifts rodents&amp;#039; mood only if administered by male researchers</title>
<link>http://www.nature.com/news/sex-matters-in-experiments-on-party-drug-in-mice-1.23022</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.nature.com/news/sex-matters-in-experiments-on-party-drug-in-mice-1.23022</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;img img-middle&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-content cleared&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/polopoly_fs/7.47732.1510951473!/image/2017_11_17_ON_ketaminemice_WEB_GETTY.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_630/2017_11_17_ON_ketaminemice_WEB_GETTY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;unoL/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;When it comes to lab mice and antidepressants, it's complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mouse experiments with the popular club drug ketamine may be skewed by the sex of the researcher performing them, a study suggests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings, presented on 14 November at the Society for Neuroscience (SfN) meeting in Washington DC, only &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545017a&quot;&gt;deepen the mystery&lt;/a&gt; of how ketamine, which has powerful mood-lifting properties, interacts with the brain. They also raise questions about the reproducibility of behavioural experiments in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ketamine is best known as a psychoactive recreational drug. But it has caught psychiatrists’ interest because of its &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/517130a&quot;&gt;potential to treat depression&lt;/a&gt; within hours. It’s unclear exactly how the drug works, however, and many researchers are using animal models to suss out the mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polymnia Georgiou, a neuroscientist at the University of Maryland in Baltimore, is one of them. In 2015, a male colleague asked her to run some experiments for him while he was out of town, including a standard way of testing antidepressants called the forced-swim test. In this assay, researchers inject healthy mice with a drug, place them into a tank of water and measure how long they swim before they give up and wait for someone to rescue them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antidepressants can cause healthy mice to swim for longer than their untreated counterparts, which is what Georgiou’s male colleague found during his experiments using ketamine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Scents and the brain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But although Georgiou followed his protocol exactly, she found that treated mice did not swim for any longer than mice injected with a placebo. When she and three female and four male researchers investigated this disconnect by performing the experiments, they discovered that the ketamine acted as an antidepressant only when it was administered by men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspecting that scent was involved, the researchers put the animals inside a fume hood so that the mice couldn’t smell who was injecting them. This completely eliminated the effect of the ketamine, regardless of the experimenter’s sex. When Georgiou and her colleagues placed a t-shirt worn by a man next to the mice in the fume hood, mice injected with ketamine swam for longer than those injected with a placebo. This suggested that male odour was necessary for the drug to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The head of Georgiou’s lab, neuroscientist Todd Gould, learned that antidepressant researcher Ronald Duman at Yale University in New Haven, Connecticut, was seeing similar effects with female researchers in his lab that were working on ketamine experiments. So Gould asked Duman to repeat Georgiou's swim-test experiment in his own lab. When eight male and eight female researchers injected mice with ketamine, they saw the same results: mice injected by women did not respond to the drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Georgiou and her colleagues repeated the experiments with other antidepressants, but the researchers’ sex didn’t seem to matter. She and Gould suspect &lt;span&gt;that the antidepressant effect&lt;/span&gt; is the result of a specific interaction between ketamine and the male odour in the mouse brain .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But other evidence suggests that the sex of the researcher can affect other types of behavioural experiment, not just those involving ketamine. A 2014 paper&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/news/sex-matters-in-experiments-on-party-drug-in-mice-1.23022#b1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Nature Methods&lt;/em&gt; found that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2014.15106&quot;&gt;mice were more stressed&lt;/a&gt; and less likely to respond to pain when handled by a male researcher. And behavioural neuroscientist Silvana Chiavegatto of the University of São Paulo in Brazil, who was at Georgiou's SfN presentation, says that she has seen the same phenomenon in her lab, where she studies depression but doesn’t use ketamine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rethinking the model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think it’s really fascinating, with wide implications for our field,” says Adrienne Betz, a behavioural neuroscientist at Quinnipiac University in Hamden, Connecticut. But she cautions that the results are preliminary, and it remains to be seen whether the effect is specific to ketamine and to mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others disagree about the potential implications. Hundreds of papers with female experimenters demonstrate the effects of antidepressants — including ketamine — in mice, says Lisa Monteggia, a neuroscientist at the University of Texas Southwestern in Dallas. Other factors, such as whether the researcher is stressed when he or she injects the mice, might affect the animals’ behaviour, she says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gould and Georgiou say that their results don’t necessarily invalidate previous studies; they simply show that ketamine experiments in their lab work only when men inject the mice. There is overwhelming evidence that ketamine is a powerful antidepressant in humans. Gould doubts that the sex of the person administering the drug affects how well it works in a depressed patient, but it's never been tested.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He adds that the findings suggest that researchers studying drugs' effects on mouse behaviour should report the sex of the experimenter in their publications to ensure that other labs can replicate the results. “There are a number of factors that influence replicability and are unrecognized — this is one of them,” Gould says. “For us, it is an inconvenient truth.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 23:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dbcooper</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Sex matters in experiments on party drug — in mice</og:title>
<og:description>Ketamine lifts rodents' mood only if administered by male researchers.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.nature.com/news/sex-matters-in-experiments-on-party-drug-in-mice-1.23022</og:url>
<og:image>http://www.nature.com/polopoly_fs/7.47732.1510951473!/image/2017_11_17_ON_ketaminemice_WEB_GETTY.jpg_gen/derivatives/nature_homepage/2017_11_17_ON_ketaminemice_WEB_GETTY.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.nature.com/news/sex-matters-in-experiments-on-party-drug-in-mice-1.23022</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>User experience design for APIs</title>
<link>https://blog.keras.io/user-experience-design-for-apis.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.keras.io/user-experience-design-for-apis.html</guid>
<description>&lt;footer class=&quot;post-info&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr class=&quot;published&quot; title=&quot;2017-11-21T00:00:00+01:00&quot;&gt;Tue 21 November 2017&lt;/abbr&gt;
&lt;address class=&quot;vcard author&quot;&gt;By &lt;a class=&quot;url fn&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fchollet&quot;&gt;Francois Chollet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.keras.io/category/essays.html&quot;&gt;Essays&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing code is rarely just a private affair between you and your computer. Code is not just meant for machines; it has human users. It is meant to be read by people, used by other developers, maintained and built upon. Developers who produce better code, in greater quantity, when they are kept happy and productive, working with tools they love. Developers who unfortunately are often being let down by their tools, and left cursing at obscure error messages, wondering why that stupid library doesn't do what they thought it would. Our tools have great potential to cause us pain, especially in a field as complex as software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User experience (UX) should be central in application programming interface (API) design. A well-designed API, making complicated tasks feel easy, will probably prevent a lot more pain in this world than a brilliant new design for a bedside lamp ever would. So why does API UX design so often feel like an afterthought, compared to even furniture design? Why is there a profound lack of design culture among developers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;keep the user in mind&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.keras.io/img/api-design/api-design-stock-photo.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of it is simply empathic distance. While you're writing code alone in front of your computer, future users are a distant thought, an abstract notion. It's only when you start sitting down next to your users and watch them struggle with your API that you start to realize that UX matters. And, let's face it, most API developers never do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem is what I would call &quot;smart engineer syndrome&quot;. Programmers tend to assume that end users have sufficient background and context -- because themselves do. But in fact, end users know a tiny fraction of what you know about your own API and its implementation. Besides, smart engineers tend to overcomplicate what they build, because they can easily handle complexity. If you aren't exceptionally bright, or if you are impatient, that fact puts a hard limit on how complicated your software can be -- past a certain level, you simply won't be able to get it to work, so you'll just quit and start over with a cleaner approach. But smart, patient people? They can just deal with the complexity, and they build increasingly ugly Frankenstein monsters, that somehow still walk. This results in the worst kind of API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last issue is that some developers force themselves to stick with user-hostile tools, because they perceive the extra difficulty as a badge of honor, and consider thoughtfully-designed tools to be &quot;for the n00bs&quot;. This is an attitude I see a lot in the more toxic parts of the deep learning community, where most things tend to be fashion-driven and superficial. But ultimately, this masochistic posturing is self-defeating. In the long run, good design wins, because it makes its adepts more productive and more impactful, thus spreading faster than user-hostile undesign. Good design is infectious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most things, API design is not complicated, it just involves following a few basic rules. They all derive from a founding principle: &lt;strong&gt;you should care about your users.&lt;/strong&gt; All of them. Not just the smart ones, not just the experts. Keep the user in focus at all times. Yes, including those befuddled first-time users with limited context and little patience. &lt;strong&gt;Every design decision should be made with the user in mind.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my three rules for API design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1 - Deliberately design end-to-end user workflows.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most API developers focus on atomic methods rather than holistic workflows. They let users figure out end-to-end workflows through evolutionary happenstance, given the basic primitives they provided. The resulting user experience is often one long chain of hacks that route around technical constraints that were invisible at the level of individual methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid this, start by listing the most common workflows that your API will be involved in. The use cases that most people will care about. Actually go through them yourself, and take notes. Better yet: watch a new user go through them, and identify pain points. Ruthlessly iron out those pain points. In particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your workflows should closely map to domain-specific notions that users care about.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are designing an API for cooking burgers, it should probably feature unsurprising objects such as &quot;patty&quot;, &quot;cheese&quot;, &quot;bun&quot;, &quot;grill&quot;, etc. And if you are designing a deep learning API, then your core data structures and their methods should closely map to the concepts used by people familiar with the field: models/networks, layers, activations, optimizers, losses, epochs, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ideally, no API element should deal with implementation details.&lt;/strong&gt; You do not want the average user to deal with &quot;primary_frame_fn&quot;, &quot;defaultGradeLevel&quot;, &quot;graph_hook&quot;, &quot;shardedVariableFactory&quot;, or &quot;hash_scope&quot;, because these are not concepts from the underlying problem domain, they are highly specific concepts that come from your internal implementation choices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deliberately design the user onboarding process.&lt;/strong&gt; How are complete newcomers going to find out the best way to solve their use case with your tool? Have an answer ready. Make sure your onboarding material closely maps to what your users care about: &lt;em&gt;don't teach newcomers how your API is implemented, teach them how they can use it to solve their own problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2 - Reduce cognitive load for your users.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end-to-end workflows you design, always strive to reduce the mental effort that your users have to invest to understand and remember how things work. The less effort and focus you require from your users, the more they can invest in solving their actual problems -- instead of trying to figure out how to use this or that method. In particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use consistent naming and code patterns.&lt;/strong&gt; Your API naming conventions should be internally consistent (If you usually denote counts via the &lt;code&gt;num_*&lt;/code&gt; prefix, don't switch to &lt;code&gt;n_*&lt;/code&gt; in some places), but also consistent with widely recognized external standards. For instance, if you are designing an API for numerical computation in Python, it should not glaringly clash with the Numpy API, which everyone uses. A user-hostile API would arbitrarily use &lt;code&gt;keepdim&lt;/code&gt; where Numpy uses &lt;code&gt;keepdims&lt;/code&gt;, would use &lt;code&gt;dim&lt;/code&gt; where Numpy uses &lt;code&gt;axis&lt;/code&gt;, etc. And an especially poorly-designed API would just randomly alternate between &lt;code&gt;axis&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;dim&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;dims&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;axes&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;axis_i&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;dim_i&lt;/code&gt;, for the same concept.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduce as few new concepts as possible.&lt;/strong&gt; It's not just that additional data structures require more effort in order to learn about their methods and properties, it's that they multiply the number of &lt;strong&gt;mental models&lt;/strong&gt; that are necessary to grok your API. Ideally, you should only need a single universal mental model from which everything flows (in Keras, that's the &lt;code&gt;Layer&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Model&lt;/code&gt;). Definitely avoid having more than 2-3 mental models underlying your workflows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strike a balance between the number of different classes/functions you have, and the parameterization of these classes/functions.&lt;/strong&gt; Having a different class/function for every user action induces high cognitive load, but so does parameter proliferation -- you don't want 35 keyword arguments in a class constructor. Such a balance can be achieved by making your data structures modular and composable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automate what can be automated.&lt;/strong&gt; Strive to reduce the number of user actions required in your workflows. Identify often-repeated code blocks in user-written code, and provide utilities to abstract them away. For instance, in a deep learning API, you should provide automated shape inference instead of requiring users to do mental math to compute expected input shapes in all of their layers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have clear documentation, with lots of examples.&lt;/strong&gt; The best way to communicate to the user how to solve a problem is not to talk about the solution, it is to &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt; the solution. Make sure to have concise and readable code examples available for every feature in your API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The litmus test I use to tell whether an API is well-designed is the following:&lt;/strong&gt; if a new user goes through the workflow for their use case on day one (following the documentation or a tutorial), and they come back the next day to solve the same problem in a slightly different context, will they be able to follow their workflow &lt;em&gt;without looking up the documentation/tutorial&lt;/em&gt;? Will they be able to remember their workflow in one shot? &lt;em&gt;A good API is one where the cognitive load of most workflows is so low that it can be learned in one shot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This litmus test also gives you a way to quantify how good or bad an API is, by counting the number of times the average user needs to look up information about a workflow in order to master it. The worst workflows are those that can never be fully remembered, and require following a lengthy tutorial every single time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3 - Provide helpful feedback to your users.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good design is interactive. It should be possible to use a good API while only minimally relying on documentation and tutorials -- by simply trying things that seem intuitive, and acting upon the feedback you get back from the API. In particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catch user errors early and anticipate common mistakes.&lt;/strong&gt; Do user input validation as soon as possible. Actively keep track of common mistakes that people make, and either solve them by simplifying your API, adding targeted error messages for these mistakes, or having a &quot;solutions to common issues&quot; page in your docs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a place where users can ask questions.&lt;/strong&gt; How else are you going to keep track of existing pain points you need to fix?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide detailed feedback messages upon user error.&lt;/strong&gt; A good error message should answer: &lt;em&gt;what happened, in what context? What did the software expect? How can the user fix it?&lt;/em&gt; They should be contextual, informative, and actionable. Every error message that transparently provides the user with the solution to their problem means one less support ticket, multiplied by how many times users run into the same issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;6.4223300970874&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;i want to murder whoever is responsible for this incredibly descriptive error:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unable to determine [Unknown Property]. Please specify an [Unknown Property]&lt;/p&gt;
— loren schmidt (@lorenschmidt) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lorenschmidt/status/929083642919444480?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 10, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In Python, the following would be an extremely bad error message:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ne&quot;&gt;AssertionError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'1 != 3'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(in general, always use &lt;code&gt;ValueError&lt;/code&gt; and avoid &lt;code&gt;assert&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ne&quot;&gt;ValueError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Invalid target shape (600, 1).'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The following is better, but still not sufficient, because it does not tell the user &lt;em&gt;what they passed&lt;/em&gt;, and does not quite say &lt;em&gt;how to fix it&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ne&quot;&gt;ValueError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'categorical_crossentropy requires target.shape[1] == classes'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Now, here's a good example, that says what was passed, what was expected, and how to fix the issue:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ne&quot;&gt;ValueError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'''You are passing a target array of shape (600, 1) while using as loss `categorical_crossentropy`.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;`categorical_crossentropy` expects targets to be binary matrices (1s and 0s) of shape (samples, classes).&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;If your targets are integer classes, you can convert them to the expected format via:&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;from keras.utils import to_categorical&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;y_binary = to_categorical(y_int)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Alternatively, you can use the loss function `sparse_categorical_crossentropy` instead, which does expect integer targets.'''&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good error messages improve the productivity and the mood of your users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;4.5428571428571&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fchollet?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@fchollet&lt;/a&gt; It's my first time using Keras and I think this is the nicest error message I've ever received! It solved the problem too! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/N7n1tRBjrt&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/N7n1tRBjrt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Henry Dashwood (@hcndashwood) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hcndashwood/status/928696266623737857?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 9, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all fairly simple principles, and following them will allow you to build APIs that people love to use. In turn, more people will start using your software, and you will achieve a greater impact in your field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always remember: software is for humans, not just for machines. Keep the user in mind at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fchollet&quot;&gt;@fchollet&lt;/a&gt;, November 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 22:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fchollet</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.keras.io/user-experience-design-for-apis.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber Paid Hackers to Delete Stolen Data on 57M People</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-21/uber-concealed-cyberattack-that-exposed-57-million-people-s-data</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-21/uber-concealed-cyberattack-that-exposed-57-million-people-s-data</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hackers stole the personal data of 57 million customers and drivers from &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/0084207D:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Uber Technologies Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, a massive breach that the company concealed for more than a year. This week, the ride-hailing firm ousted its chief security officer and one of his deputies for their roles in keeping the hack under wraps, which included a $100,000 payment to the attackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compromised data from the October 2016 attack included names, email addresses and phone numbers of 50 million Uber riders around the world, the company told Bloomberg on Tuesday. The personal information of about 7 million drivers was accessed as well, including some 600,000 U.S. driver’s license numbers. No Social Security numbers, credit card information, trip location details or other data were taken, Uber said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“None of this should have happened, and I will not make excuses for it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the time of the incident, Uber was negotiating with U.S. regulators investigating separate claims of privacy violations. Uber now says it had a legal obligation to report the hack to regulators and to drivers whose license numbers were taken. Instead, the company paid hackers to delete the data and keep the breach quiet. Uber said it believes the information was never used but declined to disclose the identities of the attackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-318224074&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/its78tLvDyzQ/v0/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/its78tLvDyzQ/v0/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dara Khosrowshahi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Matthew Lloyd/Bloomberg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“None of this should have happened, and I will not make excuses for it,” Dara Khosrowshahi, who took over as chief executive officer in September, said in an emailed statement. “We are changing the way we do business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-10-11/uber-pushed-the-limits-of-the-law-now-comes-the-reckoning&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read more: Uber Pushed the Limits of the Law. Now Comes the Reckoning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Uber’s disclosure Tuesday, New York Attorney General Eric Schneiderman launched an investigation into the hack, his spokeswoman Amy Spitalnick said. The company was also &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-22/uber-sued-for-negligence-after-disclosing-massive-data-breach&quot; title=&quot;Uber Sued for Negligence After Disclosing Massive Data Breach&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sued for negligence&lt;/a&gt; over the breach by a customer seeking class-action status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hackers have successfully infiltrated numerous companies in recent years. The Uber breach, while large, is dwarfed by those at Yahoo, MySpace, Target Corp., &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/ANTM:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Anthem Inc.&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/EFX:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Equifax Inc.&lt;/a&gt; What’s more alarming are the extreme measures Uber took to hide the attack. The breach is the latest scandal Khosrowshahi inherits from his predecessor, &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/billionaires/id/17502115&quot; title=&quot;Billionaire Profile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Travis Kalanick&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-tout-type=&quot;story&quot;&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/gadfly/articles/2017-11-21/uber-cyberattack-travis-kalanick-needs-to-explain-his-role&quot; title=&quot;Click for full story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read more: Gadfly’s Shira Ovide says Kalanick must speak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-tout-type=&quot;quicktake&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quicktake/internet-security&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;quicktake&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;news-tout-title&quot;&gt;Quicktake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;news-tout-content&quot;&gt;Cybersecurity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalanick, Uber’s co-founder and former CEO, learned of the hack in November 2016, a month after it took place, the company said. Uber had just settled a lawsuit with the New York attorney general over data security disclosures and was in the process of negotiating with the &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/13362Z:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Federal Trade Commission&lt;/a&gt; over the handling of consumer data. Kalanick declined to comment on the hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Sullivan, the outgoing security chief, spearheaded the response to the hack last year, a spokesman told Bloomberg. Sullivan, a onetime federal prosecutor who joined Uber in 2015 from &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/FB:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Facebook Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, has been at the center of much of the decision-making that has &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-10-11/uber-pushed-the-limits-of-the-law-now-comes-the-reckoning&quot; title=&quot;Uber Pushed the Limits of the Law. Now Comes the Reckoning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;come back to bite Uber&lt;/a&gt; this year. Bloomberg reported last month that the board commissioned an investigation into the activities of Sullivan’s security team. This project, conducted by an outside law firm, discovered the hack and the failure to disclose, Uber said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the hack went down: Two attackers accessed a private GitHub coding site used by Uber software engineers and then used login credentials they obtained there to access data stored on an Amazon Web Services account that handled computing tasks for the company. From there, the hackers discovered an archive of rider and driver information. Later, they emailed Uber asking for money, according to the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A patchwork of state and federal laws require companies to alert people and government agencies when sensitive data breaches occur. Uber said it was obligated to report the hack of driver’s license information and failed to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At the time of the incident, we took immediate steps to secure the data and shut down further unauthorized access by the individuals,” Khosrowshahi said. “We also implemented security measures to restrict access to and strengthen controls on our cloud-based storage accounts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber has earned a reputation for flouting regulations in areas where it has operated since its founding in 2009. The U.S. has opened at least five criminal probes into possible bribes, illicit software, questionable pricing schemes and theft of a competitor’s intellectual property, people familiar with the matters have said. The San Francisco-based company also faces dozens of civil suits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.K. regulators including the National Crime Agency are &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-22/uber-hack-raises-huge-concerns-with-u-k-data-regulator&quot; title=&quot;Uber Is Facing Yet Another Irate U.K. Regulator After Hack (1)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;also looking into the scale&lt;/a&gt; of the breach. London and other governments have previously taken steps toward banning the service, citing what they say is reckless behavior by Uber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In January 2016, the New York attorney general fined Uber $20,000 for failing to promptly disclose an earlier data breach in 2014. After last year’s cyberattack, the company was negotiating with the FTC on a privacy settlement even as it haggled with the hackers on containing the breach, Uber said. The company finally agreed to the FTC settlement three months ago, without admitting wrongdoing and before telling the agency about last year’s attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new CEO said his goal is to change Uber’s ways. Uber said it informed New York’s attorney general and the FTC about the October 2016 hack for the first time on Tuesday. Khosrowshahi asked for the resignation of Sullivan and fired Craig Clark, a senior lawyer who reported to Sullivan. The men didn’t immediately respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Khosrowshahi said in his emailed statement: “While I can’t erase the past, I can commit on behalf of every Uber employee that we will learn from our mistakes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company said its investigation found that Salle Yoo, the outgoing chief legal officer who has been scrutinized for her responses to other matters, hadn’t been told about the incident. Her replacement, Tony West, will &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-10-27/uber-hires-legal-chief-from-pepsi-to-handle-mounting-pressure&quot; title=&quot;Uber Hires Legal Chief From Pepsi Amid Mounting Pressure (1)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;start at Uber&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday and has been briefed on the cyberattack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-314752669&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i1Erh0XOlvtg/v14/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i1Erh0XOlvtg/v14/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travis Kalanick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalanick was &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-06-21/uber-ceo-kalanick-relinquishes-power-after-an-investor-mutiny&quot; title=&quot;Uber CEO Kalanick Relinquishes Power After Investor Mutiny (3)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ousted&lt;/a&gt; as CEO in June under pressure from investors, who said he put the company at legal risk. He remains on the board and recently filled two seats he controlled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber said it has hired Matt Olsen, a former general counsel at the National Security Agency and director of the National Counterterrorism Center, as an adviser. He will help the company restructure its security teams. Uber hired Mandiant, a cybersecurity firm owned by &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/FEYE:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;FireEye Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, to investigate the hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company plans to release a &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/newsroom/2016-data-incident/&quot; title=&quot;Uber statement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; to customers saying it has seen “no evidence of fraud or misuse tied to the incident.” Uber said it will provide drivers whose licenses were compromised with free credit protection monitoring and identity theft protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Erik Larson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 22:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<og:description>Hackers stole the personal data of 57 million customers and drivers from Uber Technologies Inc., a massive breach that the company concealed for more than a year. This week, the ride-hailing firm ousted its chief security officer and one of his deputies for their roles in keeping the hack under wraps, which included a $100,000 payment to the attackers.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iAY_gIX_taEE/v0/1200x813.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Uber Paid Hackers to Delete Stolen Data on 57 Million People</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-21/uber-concealed-cyberattack-that-exposed-57-million-people-s-data</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-21/uber-concealed-cyberattack-that-exposed-57-million-people-s-data</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I&amp;#039;m Testifying to Congress about Data Breaches – What Should I Say?</title>
<link>https://www.troyhunt.com/im-testifying-in-front-of-congress-in-washington-dc-about-data-breaches-what-should-i-say/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.troyhunt.com/im-testifying-in-front-of-congress-in-washington-dc-about-data-breaches-what-should-i-say/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There's a title I never expected to write! But it's exactly what it sounds like and on Thursday next week, I'll be up in front of US congress on the other side of the world &lt;a href=&quot;https://energycommerce.house.gov/hearings/identity-verification-post-breach-world/&quot;&gt;testifying about the impact of data breaches&lt;/a&gt;. It's an amazing opportunity to influence decision makers at the highest levels of government and frankly, I don't want to stuff it up which is why I'm asking the question - what should I say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a bit more context, I've been chatting with folks from &lt;a href=&quot;https://energycommerce.house.gov/&quot;&gt;the House Energy and Commerce Committee&lt;/a&gt; for a while now about the mechanics of data breaches. Obviously, the work I've been doing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/&quot;&gt;Have I Been Pwned&lt;/a&gt; (HIBP) has given me a heap of insight into this specific area of infosec over the last 4 years and the folks from DC felt my views on things might be helpful. That was all great and I was happy to share my thoughts from the other side of the world. Then, a few weeks ago, they reached out and per the title of this post, said &quot;Hey, how about testifying in front of congress in Washington DC?&quot; Uh, you know I'm Australian, right? And yes, they knew of my funny accent and the fact that I was on the other side of the world but now, here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hearing is actually to look at the current challenges facing identity verification and obviously the prevalence of data breaches is having a pretty serious impact on that. For example, if your bank verifies that you are indeed who you say you are by asking you for your date of birth yet that's appeared in a data breach, how sound is it as a knowledge-based authentication (KBA) attribute? That might have worked years ago when we had these small, isolated silos of information that were relatively self-contained, but fast forward to &quot;The Age of the Data Breach&quot; and things are rather different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanics of the hearing essentially work like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I'll submit a written testimony that's a few thousand words long a couple of days before the hearing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the day of the hearing, I'll read a 5-minute oral testimony&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two other expert witnesses (specialising in other areas of identity verification) will also read 5-minute testimonies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Congressmen and congresswomen will ask us questions relating to our testimonies for a couple of hours after that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of this process is completely transparent and open to the public: my written testimony will be made available publicly 48 hours before the hearing (I'll re-post it on this blog too), the whole things will be broadcast live on the day and members of the public can attend in person if they wish (ping me if you're in the area and plan on coming). It'll also all be recorded and available for viewing later on. If you're interested in what a congressional hearing looks like, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/sxsecpNWwkE?t=1528&quot;&gt;this hearing on the opioid crisis&lt;/a&gt; (deep link to when expert witnesses are introduced). There's a lot of folks in suits, which is just one of many things I'm having to adapt to given my existing professional attire consists entirely of jeans and black t-shirts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've already drafted up both my written statement and oral testimony but since I have a few days before I need to submit anything, I really wanted to reach out to the community and share a very broad overview of what I have planned. Many of the people who read this blog have had first-hand experience with data breaches themselves either by having their personal info exposed, working for a company that's been breached, sending me data they've seen circulating or in some cases even being, well, let's call them &quot;person 0&quot; to have seen the breach. I'd love to know what &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think is important for the folks in Washington to hear, keeping in mind this all has to be pretty high level. Let me share a broad overview of my key points (most of which you'll have seen me comment on before), then I'd love your comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data breach vectors:&lt;/strong&gt; There's malicious hacking which people most frequently think of, but there's also the growing prevalence of exposed DBs and backups. The former is frequently due to well-known vulnerabilities and sloppy coding, the latter is usually misconfigured environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data breaches can take years to discover:&lt;/strong&gt; Particularly in 2016 and 2017, we've seen incidents from many years earlier suddenly emerging. Extending that observation, we simply have no idea how many other incidents have already occurred and are yet to come to light.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We've created a perfect storm of data exposure:&lt;/strong&gt; Easily accessible cloud services at a very low price point combined with an explosion in the number of online services collecting data plus the emergence of IoT thrown in as well means a rapidly increasing attack surface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data maximisation is the norm:&lt;/strong&gt; Services want to collect as much data as they can from users for all sorts of reasons beyond what's necessary for the function of the service. It's also data that doesn't get purged; sign up to a forum now and give them your date of birth (because you know, they might want to send you a birthday message) and that data will still be there a decade from now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaches are &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; extensively redistributed:&lt;/strong&gt; It still blows me away how rampant this is. Obviously, there's distribution for commercial purposes (BTC in exchange for data), but there's also an &lt;em&gt;enormously&lt;/em&gt; active trading scene where people (often kids), are just swapping data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The immutability of exposed data attributes:&lt;/strong&gt; The problem with KBA is the assumption that knowledge alone can be used for verification. When we're talking about &quot;static&quot; KBA (that is knowledge that doesn't change), when your mother's maiden name is leaked you're going to have a hard time of it because you can't change that like you can a password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The irrevocability of exposed data:&lt;/strong&gt; This speaks to the question I so frequently hear: &quot;Can you remove my data from the internet?&quot; No, it's near on impossible and once that data starts spreading, the data breach genie never goes back into the bottle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The power of OSINT data:&lt;/strong&gt; I want to make a really firm point here that whilst data breaches are terrible and they're leaking a lot of our info, we've also become pretty good at doing it ourselves. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_intelligence&quot;&gt;Open source intelligence&lt;/a&gt; data is all over the place, especially due to social media and the very attributes we so frequently share are the ones being used for KBA (&quot;Happy birthda... ah crap&quot;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aggregation of multiple sources compounds the problem:&lt;/strong&gt; When I look at data loaded into HIBP, I frequently see multiple different data points on the same individual exposed in different breaches. When you aggregate these together, you get a much richer data set on the individual, especially once combined with that OSINT data as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The resultant impact on KBA:&lt;/strong&gt; All of the above culminates in the feasibility of KBA no longer being what it once was. What worked in the 90's simply doesn't translate to an era in which so much of our data is exposed so extensively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, I've decided not to mention specific data breaches but rather to focus on the patterns we're seeing in the industry. If I'm asked for examples then there's certainly no shortage to choose from, but I felt it was better to focus on the patterns rather than specific organisations' shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's what's been going on in my world and come next week, I'll be sitting there on the other side of the world in the most formal environment I've ever been in talking to very important people and saying &quot;pwned&quot; a lot. It's an amazing opportunity to position infosec and data breaches in front of lawmakers and it's one I want to make the most of. Please do share your thoughts in the comments below and help me ensure the right issues get the airtime they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 20:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ajedi32</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>I'm Testifying in Front of Congress in Washington DC about Data Breaches - What Should I Say?</og:title>
<og:description>There's a title I never expected to write! But it's exactly what it sounds like and on Thursday next week, I'll be up in front of US congress on the other side of the world testifying about the impact of data breaches. It's an amazing opportunity to influence decision makers</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.troyhunt.com/im-testifying-in-front-of-congress-in-washington-dc-about-data-breaches-what-should-i-say/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.troyhunt.com/content/images/2017/11/US-Capitol.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.troyhunt.com/im-testifying-in-front-of-congress-in-washington-dc-about-data-breaches-what-should-i-say/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Man Who Has Lived Alone on an Island for 28 Years</title>
<link>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/travel/destinations/europe/italy/photos-of-life-alone-on-a-paradise-island/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nationalgeographic.com/travel/destinations/europe/italy/photos-of-life-alone-on-a-paradise-island/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seventy-eight-year-old Mauro Morandi often walks along the rocky shores of Budelli Island and looks out over the disconsolate sea, feeling dwarfed by the phantom forces that tug and twist the tides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We think we are giants that can dominate the Earth, but we’re just mosquitos,” Morandi says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1989 on a stretch of water between Sardinia and Corsica, with a crippled engine and anchor adrift, Morandi’s catamaran was gripped by these same inexorable forces and carried to the shores of Budelli Island. When he learned that its caretaker was retiring from his post in two days, Morandi—long disenchanted with society—sold the catamaran and took his place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has lived alone on the island for the past 28 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;34.053412462908&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parks.it/parco.nazionale.arcip.maddalena/Eindex.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Maddalena Archipelago National Park&lt;/a&gt; is comprised of seven islands, and Budelli is considered the most beautiful among them for its &lt;em&gt;Spiaggia Rosa&lt;/em&gt;, or Pink Beach. The rose-colored sand derives its unusual hue from microscopic fragments of corals and shells, which have been slowly reduced to powder by the relentless shifting of the waves&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early nineties, Spiaggia Rosa was dubbed a place of “high natural value” by the Italian government. The beach was closed off to protect its fragile ecosystem, and only certain areas remain accesible to visitors. The island rapidly went from hosting thousands of tourists per day to a single heartbeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;37.219730941704&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, after a three-year &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/europe/italy/10473357/Italy-wants-its-island-back-will-pay-2.5-million-for-Budelli.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;legal battle&lt;/a&gt; between a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalgeographic.com/travel/destinations/oceania/new-zealand/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;New Zealand&lt;/a&gt; businessman and the Italian government for ownership of the land, a court ruled that Budelli belonged to Maddalena National Park. The same year, the park challenged Morandi’s right to live on the island—and the public responded. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/facciamo-in-modo-che-mauro-il-custode-eremita-di-budelli-possa-continuare-a-vivere-l%C3%AC-glgalletti&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;petition&lt;/a&gt; protesting his eviction garnered more than 18,000 signatures, effectively pressuring local politicians to delay his expulsion indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;promo section relatedContentList&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;related-content-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;related-content-list__title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You Might Also Like&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I will never leave,&quot; Morandi says. &quot;I hope to die here and be cremated and have my ashes scattered in the wind.” He believes all life is eventually reunited with the Earth—that we are all part of the same energy. The Stoics of ancient Greece called this &lt;em&gt;sympatheia&lt;/em&gt;, the feeling that the universe is an indivisible, unified living organism endlessly in flux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conviction in our interconnectedness propels Morandi to remain on the island without compensation. Every day he collects wayward plastic that washes up on the beach and tangles with the delicate flora and fauna. Despite his aversion to people, he guards Budelli’s shores with fervor and educates summertime visitors about the ecosystem and how to protect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m not a botanist or a biologist,” Morandi says. “Yes, I know names of plants and animals, but my work is much different than this. To be able to care for a plant is a technical task—I try to make people understand [why] the plant needs to live.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morandi believes that teaching people how to see beauty will save the world from exploitation more effectively than scientific &lt;span&gt;minutiae&lt;/span&gt;. “I would like people to understand that we must try not to look at beauty, but feel beauty with our eyes closed,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winters on Budelli are particularly beautiful. Morandi endures long stretches of time—upwards of 20 days—without any human contact. He finds solace in the quiet introspection it affords him, and often sits on the beach with nothing but the operatic sounds of the wind and waves to punctuate the silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m sort of in prison here,” he says. “But it’s a prison that I chose for myself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morandi passes the time with creative pursuits. He fashions juniper wood into sculptures, finding faces hidden in their nebulous forms. He reads zealously and meditates on the wisdom of Greek philosophers and literary prodigies. He takes pictures of the island, marveling at how it changes from hour to hour, season to season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not unusual for people who spend extensive periods of time alone. Scientists have long posited that solitude generates creativity, as evidenced by scores of artists, poets, and philosophers throughout the ages who produced their greatest works in seclusion from society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;40&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits of solitude may not be universal. “Solitude can be stressful for members of technologically advanced societies who have been trained to believe that aloneness is to be avoided,” explains Pete Suedfeld in &lt;em&gt;Loneliness: A Sourcebook of Current Theory, Research and Therapy&lt;/em&gt;. However, there are still cultures around the world in which solitary life remains a venerated tradition. Buddhist monasticism, for example, encourages spiritual devotion and scholarly pursuit above seeking bodily pleasures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;35.339317773788&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But amidst rapid globalization, humans' ability to experience true solitude is perhaps a thing of the past. In response to increasing development of the region, an internet company established a Wi-Fi connection on Budelli, connecting Morandi and his beloved piece of paradise to the world through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/8isola/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;. Embracing this new form of communication is his concession on behalf of a larger purpose—to facilitate a bond between people and nature by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/mauro.dabudelli/posts/1794931617416122&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;exposing them to its beauty&lt;/a&gt;. A bond Morandi hopes will motivate people to care for the withering planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Love is an absolute consequence of beauty and vice versa,” Morandi says. “When you love a person deeply you see him or her as beautiful, but not because you see them as physically beautiful … you empathize with them, you’ve become a part of her and she’s become a part of you. It’s the same thing with nature.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parbase smartbody section text&quot; readability=&quot;25.955555555556&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Michele Ardu is a photographer based in London. Follow him on Instagram &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/michelearduphoto/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@michelearduphoto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;UniversalVideo section&quot; readability=&quot;9.0532178217822&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;media__caption--text&quot; readability=&quot;13.341584158416&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;headline&quot; class=&quot;media__caption--title&quot;&gt;Related: He Spent 40 Years Alone in the Woods, and Now Scientists Love Him&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;For more than 40 years, billy barr has lived in a small cabin in Gothic, Colorado, recording data about the snowpack to pass the time. In doing so, he has inadvertently provided scientists with a treasure trove of climate change data. This film is part of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://video.nationalgeographic.com/video/short-film-showcase&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Short Film Showcase&lt;/a&gt;; any views expressed are those of the filmmakers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 20:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fern12</dc:creator>
<og:title>Meet the Man Who Has Lived Alone on This Island for 28 Years</og:title>
<og:description>Mauro Morandi's failing catamaran was carried to Budelli Island nearly three decades ago by chance. He never left.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/travel/destinations/europe/italy/photos-of-life-alone-on-a-paradise-island/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/content/dam/travel/2017-digital/alone-on-paradie-island/mauro-dusk-budelli-island-italy.ngsversion.1502371832642.adapt.1900.1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/travel/destinations/europe/italy/photos-of-life-alone-on-a-paradise-island/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>HQ CEO: If You Run This Profile, We’ll Fire Our Host</title>
<link>https://www.thedailybeast.com/ceo-of-hq-the-hottest-app-going-if-you-run-this-profile-well-fire-our-host</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thedailybeast.com/ceo-of-hq-the-hottest-app-going-if-you-run-this-profile-well-fire-our-host</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Every day, hundreds of thousands of people all over the world fire up their smartphones and log onto HQ, a live trivia app that has attracted enormous online buzz and been called &lt;a href=&quot;https://theoutline.com/post/2492/hq-trivia-interactive-tv-uncanny&quot;&gt;the “Future of TV”&lt;/a&gt; in the past week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The co-founder and CEO of the app, however, threatened in a tirade to fire its star host simply for speaking to press on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HQ Trivia allows users across the globe to tune in and participate in twice-per-day live trivia shows where they have the chance to win real cash. The app was founded by Rus Yusupov and Colin Kroll, who co-created Vine in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since its launch over the summer it has become a cultural force. Over 170,000 people waited in the game’s lobby to play HQ on Sunday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the heart of the app is a cult figure named Scott, who hosts the majority of shows. Scott Rogowsky has become the default face of the app, and while other hosts sometimes fill in, Scott is undoubtedly the favorite. It’s Scott’s face that is plastered all over HQ’s press materials, after all. Fans call him “Quiz Daddy” and on the few days when he doesn’t host HQ Trivia, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tommy_penner/status/931252002138607616&quot;&gt;people beg for his return&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everyone needs 15 minutes of Scott in their lives,” one fan &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AndMucc/status/932683798059409410&quot;&gt;recently tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. “If you don’t like Scott from HQ we can’t be friends,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dropkickpikachu/status/930166020085633025&quot;&gt;said another&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of his status as a rising celeb, The Daily Beast reached out to Rogowsky on Monday to write a lighthearted profile on his career and how his life has changed post-HQ fame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott agreed to the interview and chatted with The Daily Beast on Monday afternoon. The Daily Beast simultaneously reached out to the HQ public relations email account and Yusupov, one of HQ’s founders, letting him know of our plans to write a story about the show’s host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several hours later, we received an email from Yusupov stating that HQ was “not making Scott available to discuss his involvement with HQ with the media/press.” The reporter informed Yusupov that we had already interviewed Scott and that the story was nearing publication, but encouraged him to call us with any concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s when things went off the rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yusupov, the CEO of HQ, called the reporter’s cellphone and immediately raised his voice. He said that we were “completely unauthorized” to write about Scott or HQ without his approval and that if we wrote any type of piece about Scott, he would lose his job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yusupov continued to threaten Scott’s job, even after The Daily Beast explained that the story was framed around Scott’s daily life and that he revealed no corporate information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineNewsletter&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineNewsletter__main&quot; readability=&quot;30.323325635104&quot;&gt;
&lt;form class=&quot;InlineNewsletter__form&quot; readability=&quot;-0.90491803278689&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get The Beast In Your Inbox!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;InlineNewsletter__content&quot; readability=&quot;28.065789473684&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineNewsletter__list&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineNewsletterItem InlineNewsletterItem--checked&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineNewsletterItem__title-and-description&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;InlineNewsletterItem__title&quot;&gt;Daily Digest&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;InlineNewsletterItem__description&quot;&gt;Start and finish your day with the top stories from The Daily Beast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineNewsletterItem InlineNewsletterItem--checked&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineNewsletterItem__title-and-description&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;InlineNewsletterItem__title&quot;&gt;Cheat Sheet&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;InlineNewsletterItem__description&quot;&gt;A speedy, smart summary of all the news you need to know (and nothing you don't).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;Button InlineNewsletter__submit-button&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineNewsletter__final&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank You!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are now subscribed to the Daily Digest and Cheat Sheet. We will not share your email with anyone for any reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’re putting Scott’s job in jeopardy. Is that what you want?” Yusupov said. “Scott could lose his job.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Please read me your story word for word,” Yusupov said. “Or you can email it to me.” Although The Daily Beast does not typically share the contents of our pieces, the reporter shared quotes from Rogowsky, which were non-confrontational and shared no company secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yusupov’s objections began with the line, “Scott said that despite the attention, he’s still able to walk down the street and order his favorite salad from Sweetgreen without being accosted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He cannot say that!” Yusupov shouted. “We do not have a brand deal with Sweetgreen! Under no circumstances can he say that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asked to confirm that Rogowsky can’t say he personally enjoys eating at Sweetgreen, Yusupov said “he cannot say that,” inaccurately claiming that Scott had disclosed private company information by revealing his preference for a salad chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When The Daily Beast read Yusupov a quote from Rogowsky saying “I can make people happy and give them the trivia they so desperately love and want. It’s been so great to build this community,” Yusupov implored the reporter to “take that out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked for clarification, Yusupov replied that Rogowsky was absolutely not allowed to say that he “enjoys making people happy and giving them the trivia they want.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He cannot say that people want trivia,” said Yusupov, the founder of the HQ Trivia app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s highly unprofessional. Highly unprofessional of you to reach out to one of our contract employees without my permission and without going through proper press channels,” Yusupov said, revealing previously undisclosed information that Scott himself is not a full-time HQ employee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yusupov said that he would approve The Daily Beast to write an article all about Scott’s life, but that we were “not allowed” to include any mention of HQ or his role in HQ (which is public), or he could be terminated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is ridiculous,” Yusupov said. “If you reached out to an Apple engineer and they gave you information about the new iPhone, would you run it? No, because you’d have to go through proper press channels.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yusupov was repeatedly reassured that Scott had not revealed a single piece of classified information about HQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a back and forth wherein Yusupov told The Daily Beast its reporter would never be allowed to talk to Rogowsky again, the co-founder nervously stated that the conversation was off the record, something he had not stated before that point and a precondition The Daily Beast had never agreed to. The phone call ended shortly thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;***&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Daily Beast’s chat with Rogowsky himself was considerably less combative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogowsky said he had planned to move to Los Angeles this fall and had even given up his Brooklyn apartment when he landed his big break with HQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he got the opportunity to interview for the the job of host he thought, “What the hell? Why not? I figured I’m not going to pass on this thing that could be the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogowsky was no stranger to being in front of audiences—although none were as big as HQ’s. He started doing standup in 2005 back when he was in college and moved to Brooklyn shortly afterward to pursue a career in comedy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He eventually realized that life as a traditional comedian wasn’t quite for him, so he began doing live shows at the Upright Citizens Brigade theatre. He also began making YouTube videos and one of them, a Super Bowl parody, went viral in 2009. Rogowsky said that it opened his eyes in terms of the power of online video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s when I pivoted to video,” he said. He began making more videos for corporate clients and eventually producing web shows. He even did a stint at The Onion as a contributing headline writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But nothing Rogowsky has done before captivated an audience on the scale of his HQ hosting gig. In the past six months, he has become an A-list celebrity in the eyes of fans of the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I travel everywhere by helicopter now,” Rogowsky joked. “Nolita to Soho? I’m taking a chopper. No, to be honest I’m still the same person I was before. I have gotten more Twitter followers, though.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogowsky said that shortly after the app began to launch in beta he was eating with a friend when a man approached him. “He goes, ‘You’re Scott from HQ, right?’ I was like, ‘How the hell?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since that summer encounter he’s had a woman ask him for a selfie while he was retrieving money from an ATM. Others have shouted his name on the street. Several HQ fans even dressed up as Rogowsky for Halloween.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That was probably the craziest moment,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most hectic encounters Rogowsky has had with fans was when he visited a friend at a local WeWork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s where you get mobbed,” he said. “It’s all the startup and app-type guys, so they’re big fans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike other corners of the internet, the HQ community is extremely positive, a stark contrast to the defensive secretiveness of its founder. Fans can socialize prior to and throughout the live shows via an open chat log on the bottom of the screen. With tens of thousands of players signed in at once, the chat messages can fly by, but nearly all messages are positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some root for popular players or ask Scott for special birthday shout outs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I feel like HQ has been a force for good and it’s brought together this amazing community. I would love to see the first people to get married from HQ. Maybe they’ll meet in the chat and name their first child Scott,” said Rogowsky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The internet was supposed to bring people together, but it’s created big divisions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;***&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When The Daily Beast called Yusupov back a day later letting him know that the story was being reframed around his comments, Yusupov brought Rogowsky onto the phone call and falsely claimed that he never threatened to fire him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My feeling was that it was unethical and that you were compromising the app,” Yusupov said to Rogowsky while on the phone with The Daily Beast. “Now they want to reframe the story as me threatening to fire you. Do you think that’s a good idea?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yusupov then said that the two were actually in long-term contract negotiations and that he never had plans to fire him. “He and I are working on a media plan,” Yusupov said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want to fire Scott. Scott is our guy.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 20:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<og:title>CEO of HQ, the Hottest App Going: If You Run This Profile, We’ll Fire Our Host</og:title>
<og:description>The trivia app has become a sensation on the app store and a darling for media prognosticators. Its CEO threatened to fire its star host for talking to us about salad.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.thedailybeast.com/ceo-of-hq-the-hottest-app-going-if-you-run-this-profile-well-fire-our-host</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://img.thedailybeast.com/image/upload/v1511295051/171120-hq-app-tease_lv9ii5.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thedailybeast.com/ceo-of-hq-the-hottest-app-going-if-you-run-this-profile-well-fire-our-host</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>