<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>A friend of mine died and I didn&amp;#039;t know because of algorithms</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/Hellchick/status/942863353403150336</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/Hellchick/status/942863353403150336</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Hellchick/status/942863353403150336&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/Hellchick/status/942863353403150336&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15956811&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15956811&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 460&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 313&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>emsy</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/Hellchick/status/942863353403150336</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Update: Looking Glass Add-On</title>
<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/update-looking-glass-add/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/update-looking-glass-add/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We didn’t think hard enough about how our actions would affect the community, and we’re sorry for letting you down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How we got here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the year Firefox has enjoyed a growing relationship with the Mr. Robot television show and, as part of this relationship, we developed an unpaid collaboration to engage our users and viewers of the show in a new way: Fans could use Firefox to solve a puzzle as part of the alternate reality game (ARG) associated with the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did it work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fans of the show enabled this game in Firefox by turning on the “Looking Glass” add-on effect via preferences setting. When enabled, and the user navigated to Mr. Robot’s ARG page, a clue necessary to advance the puzzle would be revealed.  When enabled, the add-on would also invert text from a list of words related to the shows themes, throughout the web for a few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of giving users the choice to install this add-on, we initially pushed an update to Firefox that installed the “Looking Glass” add-on for English speaking users. This add-on was installed and set to ‘OFF’ and made no changes in the user experience unless it was explicitly turned on by a user, but it was added. Even when turned on no user data was collected or shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rollout did not meet the standards to which we hold ourselves causing concern that was surfaced through our Firefox community. We received feedback regarding the transparency of the rollout and the processes that govern our auto-install mechanism for add-ons. In response we immediately started our internal review, updated the add-on with a better description and began the process to move the Mr. Robot &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/looking-glass/&quot;&gt;Looking Glass tie-in&lt;/a&gt; to the add-ons site as a regular WebExtension. We also shared the source in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/mozilla/addon-wr&quot;&gt;public repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To our community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re sorry for the confusion and for letting down members of our community. While there was no intention or mechanism to collect or share your data or private information and The Looking Glass was an opt-in and user activated promotion, we should have given users the choice to install this add-on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being thorough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recognize that real engagement means listening to feedback. We took immediate actions to correct this, and we are conducting a formal internal review to ensure our technical, legal and communications processes and policies are updated for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We take seriously our responsibility to provide a trusted, secure platform for your online life and will always work to maintain the trust of our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re doing a post-mortem and are going to make changes to our processes. These will be public and we will link to a public list of process changes, likely mid-January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Jascha Kaykas-Wolff, Chief Marketing Officer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 23:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/update-looking-glass-add</og:url>
<og:title>Update: Looking Glass Add-on – The Firefox Frontier</og:title>
<og:description>We didn't think hard enough about how our actions would affect the community, and we're sorry for letting you down. How we got here Over the course of the year ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/files/2017/12/Screen-Shot-2017-12-18-at-2.39.25-PM.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/update-looking-glass-add/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Older Adults&amp;#039; Forgetfulness Tied to Faulty Brain Rhythms in Sleep</title>
<link>http://npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/12/18/571120472/older-adults-forgetfulness-tied-to-faulty-brain-rhythms-in-sleep</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/12/18/571120472/older-adults-forgetfulness-tied-to-faulty-brain-rhythms-in-sleep</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res571192311&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/12/15/sleeping-memory-1-976da945e7c287d447d0c659a5313338eb74d798-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/12/15/sleeping-memory-1-976da945e7c287d447d0c659a5313338eb74d798-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As people age they may forget more because their brain waves get out of sync, new research finds. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;PhotoAlto/Frederic Cirou/Getty Images&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;PhotoAlto/Frederic Cirou/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/12/15/sleeping-memory-1-976da945e7c287d447d0c659a5313338eb74d798-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;As people age they may forget more because their brain waves get out of sync, new research finds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;PhotoAlto/Frederic Cirou/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Older brains may forget more because they lose their rhythm at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During deep sleep, older people have less coordination between two brain waves that are important to saving new memories, a team reports in the journal &lt;em&gt;Neuron.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's like a drummer that's perhaps just one beat off the rhythm,&quot; says &lt;a href=&quot;http://psychology.berkeley.edu/people/matthew-p-walker&quot;&gt;Matt Walker&lt;/a&gt;, one of the paper's authors and a professor of neuroscience and psychology at the University of California, Berkeley. &quot;The aging brain just doesn't seem to be able to synchronize its brain waves effectively.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cell.com/neuron/fulltext/S0896-6273(17)31073-5&quot;&gt;finding&lt;/a&gt; appears to answer a long-standing question about how aging can affect memory even in people who do not have Alzheimer's or some other brain disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is the first paper that actually found a cellular mechanism that might be affected during aging and therefore be responsible for a lack of memory consolidation during sleep,&quot; says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.surrey.ac.uk/biochemical/People/162236/&quot;&gt;Julie Seibt&lt;/a&gt;, a lecturer in sleep and plasticity at the University of Surrey in the U.K. Seibt was not involved in the new study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To confirm the finding, though, researchers will have to show that it's possible to cause memory problems in a young brain by disrupting these rhythms, Seibt says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-mobilebackfill-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study was the result of an effort to understand how the sleeping brain turns short-term memories into memories that can last a lifetime, says Walker, the author of the book &lt;em&gt;Why We Sleep&lt;/em&gt;. &quot;What is it about sleep that seems to perform this elegant trick of cementing new facts into the neural architecture of the brain?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out, Walker and a team of scientists had 20 young adults learn 120 pairs of words. &quot;Then we put electrodes on their head and we had them sleep,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The electrodes let researchers monitor the electrical waves produced by the brain during deep sleep. They focused on the interaction between slow waves, which occur every second or so, and faster waves called sleep spindles, which occur more than 12 times a second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning the volunteers took a test to see how many word pairs they could still remember. And it turned out their performance was determined by how well their slow waves and spindles had synchronized during deep sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;When those two brain waves were perfectly coinciding, that's when you seem to get this fantastic transfer of memory within the brain from short term vulnerable storage sites to these more permanent, safe, long-term storage sites,&quot; Walker says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the team repeated the experiment with 32 people in their 60s and 70s. Their brain waves were less synchronized during deep sleep. They also remembered fewer word pairs the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, just like with young people, performance on the memory test was determined by how well their brain waves kept the beat, says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humboldt-foundation.de/pls/web/pub_hn_query.humboldtianer_details?p_lang=en&amp;amp;p_externe_id=7000283753&quot;&gt;Randolph Helfrich&lt;/a&gt;, an author of the new study and a postdoctoral fellow at UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If you're like 50 milliseconds too early, 50 milliseconds too late, then the storing mechanism actually doesn't work.&quot; Helfrich says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team also found a likely reason for the lack of coordination associated with aging: atrophy of an area of the brain involved in producing deep sleep. People with more atrophy had less rhythm in the brain, Walker says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's discouraging because atrophy in this area of the brain is a normal consequence of aging, Walker says, and can be much worse in people with Alzheimer's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the study also suggests that it's possible to improve an impaired memory by re-synchronizing brain rhythms during sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to do this would be by applying electrical or magnetic pulses through the scalp. &quot;The idea is to boost those brain waves and bring them back together,&quot; Helfrich says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walker already has plans to test this approach to synchronizing brain waves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;What we're going to try and do is act like a metronome and in doing so see if we can actually salvage aspects of learning and memory in older adults and those with dementia,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 21:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jaytaylor</dc:creator>
<og:title>Older Adults' Forgetfulness Tied To Faulty Brain Rhythms In Sleep</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/12/18/571120472/older-adults-forgetfulness-tied-to-faulty-brain-rhythms-in-sleep</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>As people get older, brain waves that occur during deep sleep become less synchronized. This appears to disrupt a system that saves new memories.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/12/15/sleeping-memory-1_wide-98a25786eb582fef09f4ef2770b5c9aac90e1d64.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/12/18/571120472/older-adults-forgetfulness-tied-to-faulty-brain-rhythms-in-sleep</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ten years of professional blogging – what I’ve learned</title>
<link>http://andrewchen.co/professional-blogging/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://andrewchen.co/professional-blogging/</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;1/ After 10+ years of publishing professional writing at &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/ddc2F89IIV&quot;&gt;https://t.co/ddc2F89IIV&lt;/a&gt;, I have a couple opinions on how to get your stuff read&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Andrew Chen (@andrewchen) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/andrewchen/status/890076892698750976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 26, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building your personal bat signal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I want to cross-pollinate a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/andrewchen/status/890076892698750976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;amp;ref_url=http%3A%2F%2Fandrewchen.co%2F%3Fp%3D4182&quot;&gt;tweetstorm&lt;/a&gt; on lessons I’ve learned from a decade of professional writing. In a way, it’s a followup to some more general life lessons from &lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/10-years/&quot;&gt;10 years of living in the Bay Area&lt;/a&gt;. Writing has been enormously impactful from a professional standpoint, and I continue to recommend to everyone – especially folks who are new to the Bay Area – to do it as a way to send out the “bat signal” on their aspirations, ideas, and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s awesome, but insanely hard to get started. Of course, everyone knows the mechanics of setting up a blog – but the hard part is finding your voice, figuring out topics that are interesting for other folks to read, and building a long-term habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The lessons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Without further ado, here are a few opinions I’ve developed up along the way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Titles are 80% of the work, but you write it as the very last thing. It has to be a compelling opinion or important learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s always room for high-quality thoughts/opinions. Venn diagram of people w/ knowledge and those we can communicate is tiny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing is the most scalable professional networking activity – stay home, don’t go to events/conferences, and just put ideas down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think of your writing on the same timescale as your career. Write on a multi-decade timeframe. This means, don’t just pub on Quora/Medium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on writing freq over anything else. Schedule it. Don’t worry about building an immediate audience. Focus on the intrinsic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To develop the habit, put a calendar reminder each Sunday for 2 hours. Forced myself to stare at a blank text box and put something down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of my writing comes from talking/reading deciding I strongly agree or disagree. These opinions become titles. Titles become essays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People are often obsessed with needing to write original ideas. Forget it. You’re a journalist with a day job in the tech industry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An email subscriber is worth 100x twitter or LinkedIn followers or whatever other stuff is out there. An email = a real channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started writing while working at a VC. They asked, “Why give away ideas? That’s your edge.” Ironic that VCs blog/tweet all day now ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing ideas, learnings, opinions, for years &amp;amp; years is a great way to give. And you’ll figure out how to capture value later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;But let’s talk about each one of these in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The lessons, but with more detail!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titles are 80% of the work, but you write it as the very last thing. It has to be an compelling opinion or important learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titles are often written as a vague pre-thought, but in fact, it’s the most important creative decision you’ll make. Titles are the text that’ll be featured prominently in every tweet, Facebook share, and link – and people will refer to it by name. Titles are best when they can pass the “naked share” test – imagine some text that’s so compelling that even if it’s not linked to anything, people will want to share it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best example of this in my work is “&lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/how-to-be-a-growth-hacker-an-airbnbcraigslist-case-study/&quot;&gt;Growth Hacker is the new VP Marketing&lt;/a&gt;” which started out as a tweet with 20+ shares, and then was developed into an essay afterward. To pass the naked share test, this means a title should be an opinion on its own. Or be a factoid (like push notifs being 40%+ CTR) that’s fascinating and shareable. Or if that’s just too hard, the common “curiosity gap” pattern of a listicle can work too. Just avoid vague titles like “Here are my thoughts on XYZ.” No one cares. As a result, in the course of my work, I often write a placeholder title, write the essay, and then at the very end, spend a good chunk of time iterating on titles until there’s a good one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s always room for high-quality thoughts/opinions. Venn diagram of people w/ knowledge and those we can communicate is tiny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might think that there are too many blogs on tech, startups, whatever. There’s always room though, when you think of the whitespace as &lt;strong&gt;Knowledge x Communication x Medium&lt;/strong&gt;. People with real knowledge are busy, especially when that knowledge is under a huge amount of demand. And even when an expert can poke their heads up and do something besides executing their craft, they often can’t communicate! It’s hard to make professional content – often dry, boring, technical – into something that’s compelling and accessible to a wide audience. And furthermore, I’d add the medium into the mix as a third dimension, which is the idea that the knowledge can be shared via video, long-form essays, podcasts, presentation decks, etc. Even when there are experts writing long-form content about cryptocurrencies, let’s say, there’s still room in the market for a highly visual version. Just figure out the whitespace and dive in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is the most scalable professional networking activity – stay home, don’t go to events/conferences, and just put ideas down&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first moved to the Bay Area, I was spending at least one afternoon/evening a week at a launch party, a conference. Plus hours and hours of 1:1s as I was meeting a ton of people. After an entire year of hard work, I had met something like 1000 new people for one-off conversations. But it took hundreds of hours. At the same time, I was dedicating about the same amount of time to writing, but quickly unlocked 5,000+ people, and started reaching into their inboxes on a weekly basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at conferences is the worst time suck. You spend hours prepping a deck, speak to a group of perhaps a few hundred people, and retain very few them in any meaningful relationship. It can feel good to be recognized, but at the same time, it just can’t compare to writing a piece of content that lives forever. I’m still getting traffic – and email feedback – on essays I wrote ten years ago, which is insane! But that’s the power of scale – nothing can beat content as a bat signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of your writing on the same timescale as your career. Write on a multi-decade timeframe. This means, don’t just pub on Quora/Medium&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building your network, your audience, and your ideas will be something you’ll want to do over your entire career. Likely a multi-decade thing that will last longer than any individual publishing startup. &lt;strong&gt;That’s why I refuse to write on Medium or Quora&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead, I prefer to run open source software that I can move around, prioritize building my email list (more on that later) and try to keep regular backups. I used to write on Blogger and watched them slowly stop maintaining the platform after the Google acquisition. Then I switched to Typepad, only to watch the same thing happen. I learned my lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on writing freq over anything else. Schedule it. Don’t worry about building an immediate audience. Focus on the intrinsic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get it- the activation energy to start publishing your professional ideas and thoughts are high. Nevertheless, because initially no one will read your work, the key is just to get started. Your initial topics and format should be whatever you can do easily and maintain some sort of frequency. Maybe that’s 500 words a month on a new product you’ve tried, and whether you hate or it not. Just get started, find out what you like, and you’ll have a lot of time to figure out the intersection of what you want to write, and what others want to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To develop the habit, put a calendar reminder each Sunday for 2 hours. Forced myself to stare at a blank text box and put something down&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several years in, writing remains hard. It’s something that still – to this day – requires time to be set aside. I turn off the music, stop checking email, and write over a few hours to crank something out. Some parts get easier, but the core activity stays difficult. Since starting a normal job (haha) it’s gotten harder to write on Sunday evenings, since that’s when the work email starts. But a good chunk of the writing on this blog happened over Sunday evenings, a few times a month, blocked out with no distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my writing comes from talking/reading deciding I strongly agree or disagree. These opinions become titles. Titles become essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lively lunch/dinner discussion where a provocative opinion is blurted out – say, that cryptocurrencies are going to be widely adopted and ultimately cause a global recession – I usually write it down. If it’s fun and memorable, it’s an easy thing to write 3-4 supporting points as paragraphs, and turn into an essay later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are often obsessed with needing to write original ideas. Forget it. You’re a journalist with a day job in the tech industry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking of yourself as a journalist that’s covering interesting ideas, trends, products, and everything that’s happening around you leads to much better/stronger content. It means you can write often and build on others’ ideas, without feeling like everything has to be completely new. Just as startup ideas are rarely new, but rather twists on older ideas, the same goes for your observations and ideas on tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An email subscriber is worth 100x twitter or LinkedIn followers or whatever other stuff is out there. An email = a real channel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a professional audience, at least, email is the only KPI I care about. Nothing has more engagement. And importantly, to a previous point, it’s independent/decentralized and will clearly be around in a decade – it’s hard to say that about any of these other subscriber metrics. Given that, I focus on my blog’s UI on collecting emails – both on the homepage, at the bottom of essays, plus those annoying popups that are (unfortunately) super effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing while working at a VC. They asked, “Why give away ideas? That’s your edge.” Ironic that VCs blog/tweet all day now ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took a long time for VCs to figure out how to market themselves and their ideas :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishing ideas, learnings, opinions, for years &amp;amp; years is a great way to give. And you’ll figure out how to capture value later&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first year of writing, I had an audience of hundreds, including friends/colleagues from Seattle, my sister, etc. It wouldn’t be until a year later that I figured out it was a helpful asset when you’re going out and trying to raise money for a startup! And years after that, to help get your company acquired. And a great launching pad for market research and side projects too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating is the thing – writing is a subset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For me, writing on this blog has been a real gamechanger in terms of building relationships, a professional reputation, etc. But it’s just one potential method of creating and putting content out there. Maybe your version of this is through videos, photography, or podcasts. Or maybe you’re a developer and want to keep shipping open source projects. All of it can work. The important part is just to start giving out your knowledge and ideas – and over time, to build that into a platform for other activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just get started and I doubt you’ll regret it. And to those who’ve been reading my work for the last decade, thank you! I appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS. Bonus lessons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To close, I’ll point you to some bonus ideas from an old essay, &lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/how-to-start-a-professional-blog-10-tips-for-new-bloggers/&quot;&gt;How to start a professional blog: 10 tips for new bloggers&lt;/a&gt;, written when I was just starting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Carpet bomb a key area and stake out mindshare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take time to find your voice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay consistent on your blog format and topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just show up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go deep on your topic of expertise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meatspace and the blogosphere are tightly connected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embrace the universal reader acquisition strategies for blogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with new topics with brainstorms, news headlines, and notes-to-self&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at your analytics every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t overdo it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/how-to-start-a-professional-blog-10-tips-for-new-bloggers/&quot;&gt;More details here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;PS. Get new updates/analysis on tech and startups&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write a high-quality, weekly newsletter covering what's happening in Silicon Valley, focused on startups, marketing, and mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 19:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hispanic</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>10 years of professional blogging - what I've learned</og:title>
<og:description>1/ After 10+ years of publishing professional writing at https://t.co/ddc2F89IIV, I have a couple opinions on how to get your stuff read — Andrew Chen (@andrewchen) July 26, 2017 Building your personal bat signal I want to cross-pollinate a tweetstorm on lessons I’ve learned from a decade of professional writing. In a way, it’s a followup …</og:description>
<og:url>http://andrewchen.co/professional-blogging/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://andrewchen.co/professional-blogging/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Abandoned rape kits identify over 800 serial rapists in one Michigan county</title>
<link>https://www.freep.com/story/opinion/columnists/nancy-kaffer/2017/12/17/rape-kit-detroit/953083001/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.freep.com/story/opinion/columnists/nancy-kaffer/2017/12/17/rape-kit-detroit/953083001/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;module-position-QgCNbswtaxk&quot; class=&quot;story-asset video-playlist-asset&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery pluto-video-gallery video-gallery story-video-gallery inline-story-video-gallery&quot; data-carousel-rotate=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-viewport pluto-video-gallery-viewport video-gallery-viewport viewport&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slides video-gallery-slides&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slide video-gallery-slide slide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-ui-pluto-video story-video gallery-video playlistsmallattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;108642180&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-pluto-still&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/dfaad63804b3c07962d3d34e4992bad290f76588/r=522/https/media.gannett-cdn.com/35547428001/35547428001_5682390057001_5682368154001-vs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;522px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; class=&quot;ui-pluto-still-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/freep/uscp-web-static-2991.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-description video-gallery-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ellipsis-data-grouped&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-gallery-title&quot;&gt;TODAY'S TOP STORIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-inline-video-title&quot;&gt;The Detroit Club is reopening in January 2018 | 0:57&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;vgm-video-description&quot;&gt;The newly renovated Detroit Club will reopen Jan. 12 after closing four years ago. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Wochit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slide video-gallery-slide slide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-ui-pluto-video story-video gallery-video playlistsmallattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;108712666&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-pluto-still&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/2eb9ea9beccdaa92a66bc00818389fa6cab18bd5/c=0-401-5623-3578&amp;amp;r=1280x720&amp;amp;r=522/local/-/media/2017/12/17/USATODAY/USATODAY/636491327446756255-EPA-USA-ATLANTA-AIRPORT-POWER-OUTAGE.2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;522px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; class=&quot;ui-pluto-still-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/freep/uscp-web-static-2991.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-description video-gallery-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ellipsis-data-grouped&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-gallery-title&quot;&gt;TODAY'S TOP STORIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-inline-video-title&quot;&gt;Atlanta airport power back on, passengers angry | 1:38&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;vgm-video-description&quot;&gt;Georgia Power announced early Monday that power is fully restored to Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta International, the world's busiest airport. More than 1,000 flights were ground on Sunday, stranding many passengers in planes and dark terminals. (Dec. 18) &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slide video-gallery-slide slide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-ui-pluto-video story-video gallery-video playlistsmallattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;108611058&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-pluto-still&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/dfaad63804b3c07962d3d34e4992bad290f76588/r=522/https/media.gannett-cdn.com/35547428001/35547428001_5680609014001_5680601029001-vs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;522px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; class=&quot;ui-pluto-still-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/freep/uscp-web-static-2991.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-description video-gallery-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ellipsis-data-grouped&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-gallery-title&quot;&gt;TODAY'S TOP STORIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-inline-video-title&quot;&gt;How candy is made at Sydney Bogg | 1:14&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;vgm-video-description&quot;&gt;The Sydney Bogg's Sweet Essentials in Berkley, with about seven employees, is much smaller than the Detroit factory and everything is handmade. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Wochit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slide video-gallery-slide slide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-ui-pluto-video story-video gallery-video playlistsmallattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;108629152&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-pluto-still&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/dfaad63804b3c07962d3d34e4992bad290f76588/r=522/https/media.gannett-cdn.com/35547428001/35547428001_5682039862001_5682023885001-vs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;522px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; class=&quot;ui-pluto-still-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/freep/uscp-web-static-2991.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-description video-gallery-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ellipsis-data-grouped&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-gallery-title&quot;&gt;TODAY'S TOP STORIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-inline-video-title&quot;&gt;Eminem reveals new album collaborations | 0:48&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;vgm-video-description&quot;&gt;Eminem took to social media on Tuesday to reveal his much-anticipated tracklist for his newest album, &quot;Revival.&quot; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Wochit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slide video-gallery-slide slide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-ui-pluto-video story-video gallery-video playlistsmallattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;108639098&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-pluto-still&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/dfaad63804b3c07962d3d34e4992bad290f76588/r=522/https/media.gannett-cdn.com/35547428001/35547428001_5682320559001_5682306399001-vs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;522px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; class=&quot;ui-pluto-still-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/freep/uscp-web-static-2991.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-description video-gallery-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ellipsis-data-grouped&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-gallery-title&quot;&gt;TODAY'S TOP STORIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-inline-video-title&quot;&gt;Builder's home in Oakland Township is huge | 0:47&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;vgm-video-description&quot;&gt;This is what you get when a large, successful builder creates his own house and hires the architect of some of Michigan’s flashiest mansions. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Wochit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slide video-gallery-slide slide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-ui-pluto-video story-video gallery-video playlistsmallattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;108660332&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-pluto-still&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/4a1325b15a7e6e9b6b6fbc20b6063652a318d982/c=0-307-2996-2000&amp;amp;r=1280x720&amp;amp;r=522/local/-/media/2017/01/13/USATODAY/USATODAY/636199202443980848-CDC-HEADQUARTERS-ATLANTA.JPG&quot; width=&quot;522px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; class=&quot;ui-pluto-still-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/freep/uscp-web-static-2991.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-description video-gallery-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ellipsis-data-grouped&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-gallery-title&quot;&gt;TODAY'S TOP STORIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-inline-video-title&quot;&gt;Report: CDC analysts must avoid using 7 words | 0:48&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;vgm-video-description&quot;&gt;According to The Washington Post, senior officials at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recently released a 'no no' list with 7 specific words including 'transgender' and 'fetus.' Some leaders in the scientific community are outraged. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Wochit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slide video-gallery-slide slide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-ui-pluto-video story-video gallery-video playlistsmallattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;108613758&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-pluto-still&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/dfaad63804b3c07962d3d34e4992bad290f76588/r=522/https/media.gannett-cdn.com/35547428001/35547428001_5680684193001_5680685918001-vs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;522px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; class=&quot;ui-pluto-still-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/freep/uscp-web-static-2991.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-description video-gallery-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ellipsis-data-grouped&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-gallery-title&quot;&gt;TODAY'S TOP STORIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-inline-video-title&quot;&gt;Detroit sees record sales year for $1M-plus homes | 0:53&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;vgm-video-description&quot;&gt;Four mansions and a penthouse condo sold for $1 million or more in 2017. J.C. Reindl, Detroit Free Press &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Wochit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slide video-gallery-slide slide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-ui-pluto-video story-video gallery-video playlistsmallattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;108641194&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-pluto-still&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/dfaad63804b3c07962d3d34e4992bad290f76588/r=522/https/media.gannett-cdn.com/29906170001/29906170001_5682365070001_5682364741001-vs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;522px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; class=&quot;ui-pluto-still-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/freep/uscp-web-static-2991.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-description video-gallery-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ellipsis-data-grouped&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-gallery-title&quot;&gt;TODAY'S TOP STORIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-inline-video-title&quot;&gt;Interesting Christmas facts you might want to know | 0:52&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;vgm-video-description&quot;&gt;Christmas is right around the corner! And with the merry holiday comes a lot of fun facts that we bet some of you didn’t know, according to the Mirror. Buzz60's Natasha Abellard has the story. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Buzz60&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slide video-gallery-slide slide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-ui-pluto-video story-video gallery-video playlistsmallattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;108655010&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-pluto-still&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/dfaad63804b3c07962d3d34e4992bad290f76588/r=522/https/media.gannett-cdn.com/35547428001/35547428001_5683644039001_5683608823001-vs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;522px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; class=&quot;ui-pluto-still-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/freep/uscp-web-static-2991.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-description video-gallery-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ellipsis-data-grouped&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-gallery-title&quot;&gt;TODAY'S TOP STORIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-inline-video-title&quot;&gt;Couple spreads Christmas spirit, one crisp $100 bill at a time | 0:47&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;vgm-video-description&quot;&gt;These two metro Detroit secret Santas have given away about $150,000 of their own money to unsuspecting recipients in the past 10 years. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Detroit Free Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-slide video-gallery-slide slide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-ui-pluto-video story-video gallery-video playlistsmallattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;108570942&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-pluto-still&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/dfaad63804b3c07962d3d34e4992bad290f76588/r=522/https/media.gannett-cdn.com/35547428001/35547428001_5679147839001_5679147991001-vs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;522px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; class=&quot;ui-pluto-still-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/freep/uscp-web-static-2991.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-description video-gallery-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ellipsis-data-grouped&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-gallery-title&quot;&gt;TODAY'S TOP STORIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gallery-description-title vgm-inline-video-title&quot;&gt;Pregnant at 18 with cancer: Mom's risky choice for life | 0:46&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;vgm-video-description&quot;&gt;Loretta was pregnant. Then she was diagnosed with cancer. She made a choice. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Georgea Kovanis, Detroit Free Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;carousel-nav gallery-nav gallery-nav-prev video-gallery-nav prev carousel-prev js-pvg-prev&quot; rel=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;Last Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;carousel-nav gallery-nav gallery-nav-next video-gallery-nav next carousel-next js-pvg-next gallery-nav-active&quot; rel=&quot;next&quot;&gt;Next Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;module-position-QgCNbswzYWk&quot; class=&quot;story-asset story-metadata-asset&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-metadata-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;module-position-QgCNbqMJEcc&quot; class=&quot;storymetadata-bucket expandable-photo-module story-expandable-photo-module&quot;&gt;&lt;aside itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; class=&quot;single-photo expandable-collapsed&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expand-img-horiz&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/acee7baffad301fd63083b38643c55310fa51900/c=160-0-2241-1561&amp;amp;r=x404&amp;amp;c=534x401/local/-/media/DetroitFreePress/2015/01/06/B9315751071Z.1_20150106153548_000_G149JQRKQ.1-0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DFP kaffer rape kits.JPG&quot; data-mycapture-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/media/DetroitFreePress/2015/01/06/B9315751071Z.1_20150106153548_000_G149JQRKQ.1-0.jpg&quot; data-mycapture-sm-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/bbc213789cfb6d3206e96d950d59a353d8035069/r=500x325/local/-/media/DetroitFreePress/2015/01/06/B9315751071Z.1_20150106153548_000_G149JQRKQ.1-0.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mycapture-small-btn mycapture-btn-with-text mycapture-expandable-photo-btn-small js-mycapture-btn-small&quot;&gt;Buy Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-credit-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cutline js-caption&quot;&gt;Wayne County Prosecutor Kym Worthy holds up an example of a rape test kit at a press conference at the Atheneum Suite Hotel in Detroit Tuesday Jan. 6, 2015. The Michigan Women's Foundation and the Detroit Crime Commission are helping the prosecutor’s office raise $10 million to test and investigate 11,000 rape kits found in a Detroit police storage unit five years ago. Mandi Wright/Detroit Free Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Photo: Detroit Free Press)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mycapture-btn mycapture-btn-with-text mycapture-expandable-photo-btn-large js-mycapture-btn&quot;&gt;Buy Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;speakable-p-1 p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ten thousand rape kits tested. One hundred twenty-seven convictions won, 1,947 cases investigated, 817 serial rapists identified. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;speakable-p-2 p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's been a long eight years for Wayne County Prosecutor Kym Worthy. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;In 2009, 11,341 untested sexual assault kits — the results of an hours-long process that collects evidence from the body of a rape victim — were found during a routine tour of a Detroit police storage warehouse, some dating back to 1984. Worthy and her team started the long and laborious process of testing those kits, investigating the crimes, and prosecuting the perpetrators — and launching &lt;a href=&quot;http://enoughsaiddetroit.org/index.html&quot;&gt;Enough SAID&lt;/a&gt;, an effort to raise the money to complete the work. It's a reversal of a decades-long &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freep.com/story/opinion/columnists/nancy-kaffer/2015/06/20/rape-kits/29013941/&quot;&gt;miscarriage of justice&lt;/a&gt;. This month, Worthy spoke to the Free Press about the work done thus far — and the long road ahead. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; One of the most astounding findings here is that you've identified 817 serial rapists. That's 817 people who attacked more than one person — and crimes that could possibly have been prevented if those people had been caught. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; This is how I try to put it in context for people: There are estimated to be 400,000 untested rape kits in the country. In one city, in one county, in one state, we had 11,341. That means a couple of things: Number one, this problem is a lot more pervasive than people could ever have imagined. Number two, (that's) on top of the very low rate that people report in the first place. That means there is much more sexual assault going on, that it's much more pervasive than people think. I think nationally the number is about 20% of rapes that are reported, and when you get to the prosecution stage it's very, very little ...  that's very sobering, very sad and very pathetic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; In terms of the 817 identified serial rapists who strike between 10 and 15 times —&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; A rapist rapes on average seven to 11 times before they're caught. ... Of our set of 817 ... over 50 of them have 10 to 15 hits apiece. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kaffer:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freep.com/story/opinion/columnists/nancy-kaffer/2015/06/20/rape-kits/29013941/&quot;&gt;How Detroit cop culture hindered rape investigations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; So how should that inform law enforcement, prosecutors' understanding of how to prevent, investigate, prosecute these crimes? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; I'm not sure that I have an answer to that. All I can say from my perspective, even if that wasn't true, we should take these cases seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Testing kits, identifying perpetrators and prosecuting them is part of the work. But you're also working hard to change the system, to ensure that this can't happen again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; We had to do a number of things ... when we first started, we knew we didn't want to be in this place five, 10 years down the road. I don't anticipate we're going to be done with these cases — investigating, prosecuting — for another three years or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;There has be a (sexual assault kit) protocol, and there is now in the Detroit Police Department ... Police officers do not make that decision, they just all go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;We started off with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freep.com/story/news/local/michigan/detroit/2015/06/08/detroit-ups-rape-kit/28683789/&quot;&gt;an 18-month pilot program with UPS&lt;/a&gt;. We knew that if you could track a package, when you order something online, you ought to be able to track a rape kit in your own state. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Legislation that was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.michigan.gov/snyder/0,4668,7-277--331838--,00.html&quot;&gt;signed by Gov. Rick Snyder in 2014&lt;/a&gt; ... created ... standards for when kits get to the lab — 14 days to take it to the lab and 90 days to turn it around, assuming lab has the resources. And that's statewide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;The other huge change that we made here in Wayne County ... is the training. Training officers on how you're supposed to treat victims ... about the neurobiology of trauma. When a potential victim comes into the police department and is laughing or has a flat affect, it doesn't mean they weren't raped. We reviewed many many police reports where the officers dismissed (victims) because they didn't act the way they thought they should act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;exclude-from-newsgate&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freep.com/story/news/politics/2017/11/09/michigan-budget-rape-kit-tracking/849685001/&quot;&gt;Snyder OKs budget bill that funds rape kit tracking system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;exclude-from-newsgate&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freep.com/story/news/columnists/rochelle-riley/2017/04/20/riley-womens-campaign-ends-rape-kit-campaign-final-plea/100615254/&quot;&gt;Women's group makes final push to test abandoned rape kits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; All the things you were talking about, the better tracking system, the new guidelines for when rape kits get tested ... in the National Institute of Justice report on the backlog (by Michigan State University Professor Rebecca Campbell), the big takeaway there was that too often, officers didn't believe victims, and had used disbelief as a way to triage their workload. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; They just closed cases, even cases where I think they believed the victim ... They closed cases because the women had worked as prostitutes or had mental illness issues or had substance abuse. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freep.com/story/opinion/columnists/nancy-kaffer/2015/06/20/rape-kits/29013941/&quot;&gt;Didn't believe them, didn't care&lt;/a&gt;, and this was one issue that led to the backlog of these kits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; That's something we look for in certain victims — when the victim is a teenage boy of color, or a woman who has been raped, we want them to be perfect. They can't have had a drink or have worked as a prostitute, and if they have, there's a mindset that makes them almost ineligible to be a victim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; One of the reasons we have these untested rape kits ... and I can use Detroit as an example, 86% of our victims in these untested kits are people of color. You're not going to find too many blond-haired, blue eyed white women ... Because their kits are treated differently, their cases are solved. That's just the way it is in this country. If you're a person of color, if you're a different economic class, then your case across the board, across the board, not just sexual assault — they're treated differently. And that's just the truth. People may not want to admit it, but I've seen it throughout my career and I know it's true ... It's just true. ... Race is at the center of this in many ways as well, unfortunately, we know that across the criminal justice system. ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;The training aspect is a huge aspect that can turn around this issue. If we cannot treat our sexual assault victims right, especially if justice has been denied to them for so many years, we certainly want to be able to treat our current survivors properly. As you well know, culture change is the hardest kind of change to make. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Eight years into this now with the rape kits, looking back over this time, what stands out to you the most? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; The number of serial rapists. The fact that when you get these kits tested, it can help exonerate someone, potentially. Some of these cases had already been tried. What I talk about all the time, is just in our kits, in one state, in one city, they have tentacles to crime scenes in 39 other states. And finally, the fact that once these hits get into CODIS (the FBI's Combined DNA Index System database), law enforcement can solve more than just sexual assault. They can solve homicide, can solve breaking and entering, because the crimes in other states we're talking about are not just sexual assault. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;We had many jurisdictions across the states — and you can go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://endthebacklog.org/&quot;&gt;endthebacklog.org&lt;/a&gt; — that have found these kits and are not doing anything. They're saying it didn't happen on our watch ... I don't know how anybody can look at this problem square in the face and say that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;No one would be saying this, and you wouldn't even have to ask that question, if we were talking about homicides. You may not have the resources, may not be able to tackle all of these cold cases, but given the resources ... no one turns their back on a cold case homicide. So we wouldn't even have this discussion ... but because it's sexual assault, for whatever reason, it's very easy for some folks to sweep this under the rug. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; If you arrest someone for homicide, let's say the wrong person gets arrested, no one tries to convince the people there wasn't a homicide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; They might say it was the wrong guy, or we can't find the person who did it, but no one says there wasn't a murder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Sexual assault is the neglected child of the family ... it was very, very difficult to get this off the ground. Thankfully, it's not like that now. Cities that are finding these rape kits in their jurisdictions are finding a myriad of resources they can go to, they have a protocol as a result of our project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; You're getting more support from the county, but you still have to supplement this work with outside funds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; (Wayne County Executive) Warren Evans and the Wayne County Commission have given $1 million for the second year in a row, so they have spent $2 million. (Under a previous administration the attitude was) only if we can get outside funding should we be doing it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Which is part of that crazy attitude, that somehow this is an optional crime. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KW:&lt;/strong&gt; I don't understand that. Everybody has a mother. A sister, a wife or a partner, or aunt or or some female that they are close to. And men, too. This happens to men. We have men in our project. We have some children. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Do you feel like in this moment we're having as a culture, do you think that's going to help with not seeing it is a crime, or not being sure it was really a crime?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KW:&lt;/strong&gt; I hope so. I hope so. I remain optimistic. If I didn't remain optimistic and hopeful, I couldn't do this job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article-print-url&quot;&gt;Read or Share this story: http://on.freep.com/2AGYDgX&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 18:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MilnerRoute</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/79db0a6e6309390fa997d4f0be9a244ec513cb5c/c=0-106-2400-1456&amp;r=x803&amp;c=1600x800/local/-/media/DetroitFreePress/2015/01/06/B9315751071Z.1_20150106153548_000_G149JQRKQ.1-0.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Kaffer: 8 years into tests of abandoned rape kits, Worthy works for justice</og:title>
<og:description>Freep columnist Nancy Kaffer talks to Wayne County Prosecutor Kym Worthy about the progress of testing 11,000 rape kits abandoned in Detroit.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.freep.com/story/opinion/columnists/nancy-kaffer/2017/12/17/rape-kit-detroit/953083001/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.freep.com/story/opinion/columnists/nancy-kaffer/2017/12/17/rape-kit-detroit/953083001/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Design of a silicon quantum computer chip</title>
<link>https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/news/science-tech/complete-design-silicon-quantum-computer-chip-unveiled</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/news/science-tech/complete-design-silicon-quantum-computer-chip-unveiled</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A reimagining of today’s computer chips by Australian and Dutch engineers shows how a quantum computer can be manufactured – using mostly standard silicon technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research teams all over the world are exploring different ways to design a working computing chip that can integrate quantum interactions. Now, UNSW engineers believe they have cracked the problem, reimagining the silicon microprocessors we know to create a complete design for a quantum computer chip that can be manufactured using mostly standard industry processes and components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new chip design, published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/em&gt;, details a novel architecture that allows quantum calculations to be performed using existing semiconductor components, known as CMOS (complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor) – the basis for all modern chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was devised by &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.unsw.edu.au/people/scientia-professor-andrew-dzurak&quot;&gt;Andrew Dzurak&lt;/a&gt;, director of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anff-nsw.org/&quot;&gt;Australian National Fabrication Facility&lt;/a&gt; at the University of New South Wales (UNSW), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://qutech.nl/person/menno-veldhorst/&quot;&gt;Menno Veldhorst&lt;/a&gt;, lead author of the paper who was a research fellow at UNSW when the conceptual work was done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-atom-wrapper type-image context-full_width&quot; contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-drop-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ds-1col scald-atom view-mode-full_width clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width/public/thumbnails/image/01_dzurak_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=WKVknmpX&quot; width=&quot;563&quot; height=&quot;396&quot; alt=&quot;01_dzurak_veldhorst.jpg&quot; title=&quot;01_dzurak_veldhorst.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__2x/public/thumbnails/image/01_dzurak_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=UsXrUHXu 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__800/public/thumbnails/image/01_dzurak_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=SWTdI3Uk 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__800_2x/public/thumbnails/image/01_dzurak_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=3v-lGbve 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__600/public/thumbnails/image/01_dzurak_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=rd_Vg4uP 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__600_2x/public/thumbnails/image/01_dzurak_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=t4gm0MkX 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__450/public/thumbnails/image/01_dzurak_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=khISWgOG 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__450_2x/public/thumbnails/image/01_dzurak_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=eZXspb5_ 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width/public/thumbnails/image/01_dzurak_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=WKVknmpX 563w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 801px) 563px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-scald-caption&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prof Andrew Dzurak and Dr Menno Veldhorst explain their new design. (Photo: Grant Turner)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We often think of landing on the Moon as humanity’s greatest technological marvel,” said Dzurak, who is also a Program Leader at Australia’s famed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cqc2t.org/&quot;&gt;Centre of Excellence for Quantum Computation and Communication Technology&lt;/a&gt; (CQC2T). “But creating a microprocessor chip with a billion operating devices integrated together to work like a symphony – that you can carry in your pocket! – is an astounding technical achievement, and one that’s revolutionised modern life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With quantum computing, we are on the verge of another technological leap that could be as deep and transformative. But a complete engineering design to realise this on a single chip has been elusive. I think what we have developed at UNSW now makes that possible. And most importantly, it can be made in a modern semiconductor manufacturing plant,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veldhorst, now a team leader in quantum technology at &lt;a href=&quot;https://qutech.nl/&quot;&gt;QuTech&lt;/a&gt; – a collaboration between Delft University of Technology and TNO, the Netherlands Organisation for Applied Scientific Research – said the power of the new design is that, for the first time, it charts a conceivable engineering pathway toward creating &lt;em&gt;millions&lt;/em&gt; of quantum bits, or qubits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-atom-wrapper type-video context-full_width&quot; contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-drop-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;yt-efJBkSj9koo&quot; class=&quot;yt-player&quot; width=&quot;563px&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/efJBkSj9koo?enablejsapi=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-scald-caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNSW engineers have reimagined the modern semiconductor to create the world’s first complete design for quantum computer chip using mostly standard industry components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Remarkable as they are, today’s computer chips cannot harness the quantum effects needed to solve the really important problems that quantum computers will. To solve problems that address major global challenges – like climate change or complex diseases like cancer – it’s generally accepted we will need &lt;em&gt;millions&lt;/em&gt; of qubits working in tandem. To do that, we will need to pack qubits together and integrate them, like we do with modern microprocessor chips. That’s what this new design aims to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our design incorporates conventional silicon transistor switches to ‘turn on’ operations between qubits in a vast two-dimensional array, using a grid-based ‘word’ and ‘bit’ select protocol similar to that used to select bits in a conventional computer memory chip,” he added. “By selecting electrodes above a qubit, we can control a qubit’s spin, which stores the quantum binary code of a 0 or 1. And by selecting electrodes between the qubits, two-qubit logic interactions, or calculations, can be performed between qubits.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quantum computer exponentially expands the vocabulary of binary code used in modern computers by using two spooky principles of quantum physics – namely, ‘entanglement’ and ‘superposition’. Qubits can store a 0, a 1, or an arbitrary combination of 0 and 1 at the same time. And just as a quantum computer can store multiple values at once, so it can process them simultaneously, doing multiple operations at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would allow a universal quantum computer to be millions of times faster than any conventional computer when solving a range of important problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-atom-wrapper type-image context-full_width&quot; contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-drop-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ds-1col scald-atom view-mode-full_width clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width/public/thumbnails/image/04_veldhorst_dzurak_1.jpg?itok=AeLeog8w&quot; width=&quot;563&quot; height=&quot;396&quot; alt=&quot;04_veldhorst_dzurak.jpg&quot; title=&quot;04_veldhorst_dzurak.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__2x/public/thumbnails/image/04_veldhorst_dzurak_1.jpg?itok=dLstCtOC 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__800/public/thumbnails/image/04_veldhorst_dzurak_1.jpg?itok=wxEVSt_S 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__800_2x/public/thumbnails/image/04_veldhorst_dzurak_1.jpg?itok=bSqZdPeW 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__600/public/thumbnails/image/04_veldhorst_dzurak_1.jpg?itok=IfD75tNK 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__600_2x/public/thumbnails/image/04_veldhorst_dzurak_1.jpg?itok=l12Az0c- 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__450/public/thumbnails/image/04_veldhorst_dzurak_1.jpg?itok=RACHKryt 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__450_2x/public/thumbnails/image/04_veldhorst_dzurak_1.jpg?itok=7v6o_YQL 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width/public/thumbnails/image/04_veldhorst_dzurak_1.jpg?itok=AeLeog8w 563w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 801px) 563px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-scald-caption&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Menno Veldhorst and Prof Andrew Dzurak with some of the instruments they used to test concepts for their design while at the Centre of Excellence for Quantum Computation and Communication Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to solve complex problems, a useful universal quantum computer will need a large number of qubits, possibly millions, because all types of qubits we know are fragile, and even tiny errors can be quickly amplified into wrong answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So we need to use error-correcting codes which employ multiple qubits to store a single piece of data,” said Dzurak. “Our chip blueprint incorporates a new type of error-correcting code designed specifically for spin qubits, and involves a sophisticated protocol of operations across the millions of qubits. It’s the first attempt to integrate into a single chip all of the conventional silicon circuitry needed to control and read the millions of qubits needed for quantum computing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We expect that there will still be modifications required to this design as we move towards manufacture, but all of the key components that are needed for quantum computing are here in one chip. And that’s what will be needed if we are to make quantum computers a workhorse for calculations that are well beyond today’s computers,” Dzurak added. “It shows how to integrate the millions of qubits needed to realise the true promise of quantum computing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building such a universal quantum computer has been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.afr.com/technology/quantum-computing-is-the-next-space-race-says-telstras-hugh-bradlow-20161130-gt0swy&quot;&gt;called the ‘space race of the 21st century’&lt;/a&gt;. For a range of calculations, they will be much faster than existing computers, and for some challenging problems they could find solutions in days, maybe even hours, when today’s best supercomputers would take millions of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-atom-wrapper type-image context-full_width&quot; contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-drop-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ds-1col scald-atom view-mode-full_width clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width/public/thumbnails/image/14_silicon_spinqubits_chip_2.png?itok=F1kObHa8&quot; width=&quot;563&quot; height=&quot;397&quot; alt=&quot;14_silicon_spinqubits_chip.png&quot; title=&quot;14_silicon_spinqubits_chip.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__2x/public/thumbnails/image/14_silicon_spinqubits_chip_2.png?itok=hR9CghY6 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__800/public/thumbnails/image/14_silicon_spinqubits_chip_2.png?itok=9_i-R4oL 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__800_2x/public/thumbnails/image/14_silicon_spinqubits_chip_2.png?itok=haILyZDw 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__600/public/thumbnails/image/14_silicon_spinqubits_chip_2.png?itok=XnYtg9Pl 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__600_2x/public/thumbnails/image/14_silicon_spinqubits_chip_2.png?itok=g1QeOpaH 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__450/public/thumbnails/image/14_silicon_spinqubits_chip_2.png?itok=O7cHOHPn 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__450_2x/public/thumbnails/image/14_silicon_spinqubits_chip_2.png?itok=IYluzQGY 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width/public/thumbnails/image/14_silicon_spinqubits_chip_2.png?itok=F1kObHa8 563w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 801px) 563px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-scald-caption&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artist's impression of the architecture of a silicon CMOS chip for a spin-based quantum computer; above is mostly standard CMOS components, and below the quantum bits in operation. (Illustration: Tony Melov)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are at least five major quantum computing approaches being explored worldwide: silicon spin qubits, ion traps, superconducting loops, diamond vacancies and topological qubits; UNSW’s design is based on silicon spin qubits. The main problem with all of these approaches is that there is no clear pathway to scaling the number of quantum bits up to the millions needed without the computer becoming huge a system requiring bulky supporting equipment and costly infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why UNSW’s new design is so exciting: relying on its silicon spin qubit approach – which already mimics much of the solid-state devices in silicon that are the heart of the US$380 billion global semiconductor industry – it shows how to dovetail spin qubit error correcting code into existing chip designs, enabling true universal quantum computation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike almost every other major group elsewhere, CQC2T’s quantum computing effort is obsessively focused on creating solid-state devices in silicon, from which all of the world’s computer chips are made. And they’re not just creating ornate designs to show off how many qubits can be packed together, but aiming to build qubits that could one day be easily fabricated – and scaled up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s kind of swept under the carpet a bit, but for large-scale quantum computing, we are going to need millions of qubits,” said Dzurak. “Here, we show a way that spin qubits can be scaled up massively. And that’s the key.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-atom-wrapper type-image context-full_width&quot; contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-drop-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ds-1col scald-atom view-mode-full_width clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width/public/thumbnails/image/09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=tgwTFkKE&quot; width=&quot;563&quot; height=&quot;397&quot; alt=&quot;09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst.jpg&quot; title=&quot;09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__2x/public/thumbnails/image/09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=NsVBeGqJ 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__800/public/thumbnails/image/09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=CZvghTTu 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__800_2x/public/thumbnails/image/09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=PJWVLbFB 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__600/public/thumbnails/image/09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=1LyvUdx4 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__600_2x/public/thumbnails/image/09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=NhkcUgCt 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__450/public/thumbnails/image/09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=sYqh-l8T 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__450_2x/public/thumbnails/image/09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=wYgdN6Lp 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width/public/thumbnails/image/09_rosie_hicks_andrew_dzurak_menno_veldhorst_1.jpg?itok=tgwTFkKE 563w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 801px) 563px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-scald-caption&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANFF CEO Rosie Hicks, Prof Andrew Dzurak and Dr Menno Veldhorst describe their concept for the two-quibit logic gate at a news conference in 2015, when they first began to work on the architecture of the new silicon quantum chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design is a leap forward in silicon spin qubits; it was only two years ago, in a paper in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;, that Dzurak and Veldhorst showed, for the first time, how quantum logic calculations could be done in a real silicon device, with the creation of a two-qubit logic gate – the central building block of a quantum computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Those were the first baby steps, the first demonstrations of how to turn this radical quantum computing concept into a practical device using components that underpin all modern computing,” said Mark Hoffman, UNSW’s Dean of Engineering. “Our team now has a blueprint for scaling that up dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’ve been testing elements of this design in the lab, with very positive results. We just need to keep building on that – which is still a hell of a challenge, but the groundwork is there, and it’s very encouraging. It will still take great engineering to bring quantum computing to commercial reality, but clearly the work we see from this extraordinary team at CQC2T puts Australia in the driver’s seat,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other CQC2T researchers involved in the design published in the &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/em&gt; paper were Henry Yang and Gertjan Eenink, the latter of whom has since joined Veldhorst at QuTech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-atom-wrapper type-image context-full_width&quot; contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-drop-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ds-1col scald-atom view-mode-full_width clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width/public/thumbnails/image/10_unsw-anff_labs_hr_1.jpeg?itok=aKVU6LiD&quot; width=&quot;563&quot; height=&quot;396&quot; alt=&quot;10_unsw-anff_labs_hr.jpeg&quot; title=&quot;10_unsw-anff_labs_hr.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__2x/public/thumbnails/image/10_unsw-anff_labs_hr_1.jpeg?itok=0eg_BtXQ 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__800/public/thumbnails/image/10_unsw-anff_labs_hr_1.jpeg?itok=-_cPD_y2 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__800_2x/public/thumbnails/image/10_unsw-anff_labs_hr_1.jpeg?itok=7bBRtliA 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__600/public/thumbnails/image/10_unsw-anff_labs_hr_1.jpeg?itok=dqo6JDp8 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__600_2x/public/thumbnails/image/10_unsw-anff_labs_hr_1.jpeg?itok=QQcO-Luu 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__450/public/thumbnails/image/10_unsw-anff_labs_hr_1.jpeg?itok=jRbd4UIX 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width__450_2x/public/thumbnails/image/10_unsw-anff_labs_hr_1.jpeg?itok=jQVa1UsS 563w, https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/sites/default/files/styles/full_width/public/thumbnails/image/10_unsw-anff_labs_hr_1.jpeg?itok=aKVU6LiD 563w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 801px) 563px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-scald-caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Australian National Fabrication Facility (ANFF) at UNSW, where the qubits are manufactured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UNSW team has struck a A$83 million deal between UNSW, Telstra, Commonwealth Bank and the Australian and New South Wales governments to develop, by 2022, a 10-qubit prototype silicon quantum integrated circuit – the first step in building the world’s first quantum computer in silicon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August, the partners launched Silicon Quantum Computing Pty Ltd, Australia’s first quantum computing company, to advance the development and commercialisation of the team’s unique technologies. The NSW Government pledged A$8.7 million, UNSW A$25 million, the Commonwealth Bank A$14 million, Telstra A$10 million and the Australian Government A$25 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;VIDEO, STILLS AND BACKGROUND AVAILABLE&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/sh/gab5s0r0nfii2v0/AAB2CkSOi6un2LZ0mYPb8xECa?dl=0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STILLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Pictures of Dzurak and Veldhorst, plus illustrations of the complete quantum computer chip. (Photos: Grant Turner/UNSW, Illustrations: Tony Melov/UNSW)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/sh/l2dimskfs9v1tzw/AAADw6Qcav4BYMlBShRWT_yKa?dl=0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BACKGROUNDERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: How UNSW’s ‘silicon spin qubit’ design compares with other approaches; plus a free 3,000-word feature article on the UNSW effort (Creative Commons).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/vhl06yxg0w4a8ap/Silicon%20CMOS%20architecture%20for%20a%20spin-based%20quantum%20computer_NatureComms_15Dec2017.pdf?dl=0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCIENTIFIC PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Original paper in &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/em&gt;, “Silicon CMOS architecture for a spin-based quantum computer”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BACKGROUND ON UNSW’S FACULTY OF ENGINEERING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNSW’s Faculty of Engineering is the powerhouse of engineering research in Australia, comprising of nine schools and 42 research centres. It is ranked in the world’s top 50 engineering faculties. It is home to Australia’s largest cohort of engineering undergraduate, postgraduate, domestic and international students. UNSW is ranked #1 in Australia for producing millionaires (#33 globally) and ranked #1 in Australia for graduates who create technology start-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BACKGROUND ON CQC2T&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Centre for Quantum Computation and Communication Technology (CQC2T) is the world’s largest team working to create a universal quantum computing ecosystem. CQC2T leads the world in the race to build a quantum computer in silicon, and undertakes world-class research in optical quantum computing, quantum communication, quantum interconnects and other quantum technologies. The centre is headquartered at UNSW and comprises more than 200 researchers from nine of Australia’s top research institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 17:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>breck</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/news/science-tech/complete-design-silicon-quantum-computer-chip-unveiled</og:url>
<og:title>Complete design of a silicon quantum computer chip unveiled</og:title>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/news/science-tech/complete-design-silicon-quantum-computer-chip-unveiled</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Oh shit, git: Getting myself out of bad situations</title>
<link>http://ohshitgit.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://ohshitgit.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Oh, shit, git!&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;lolz&quot; content=&quot;My git site brings all the mansplainers to the yard.&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Montserrat|Source+Sans+Pro&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/prism.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; href=&quot;favicon-32x32.png&quot; sizes=&quot;32x32&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; href=&quot;favicon-16x16.png&quot; sizes=&quot;16x16&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;max-width&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;64.088458880442&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;bottom-lined spaced&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git is hard: screwing up is easy, and figuring out how to fix your mistakes is fucking impossible. Git documentation has this chicken and egg problem where you can't search for how to get yourself out of a mess, unless you &lt;em&gt;already know the name of the thing you need to know about&lt;/em&gt; in order to fix your problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are some bad situations I've gotten myself into, and how I eventually got myself out of them &lt;em&gt;in plain english&lt;/em&gt;*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;11.142857142857&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
            git reflog
            # you will see a list of every thing you've done in git, across all branches!
            # each one has an index HEAD@{index}
            # find the one before you broke everything
            git reset HEAD@{index}
            # magic time machine
           &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use this to get back stuff you accidentally deleted, or just to remove some stuff you tried that broke the repo, or to recover after a bad merge, or just to go back to a time when things actually worked. I use &lt;code&gt;reflog&lt;/code&gt; A LOT. Mega hat tip to the many many many many many people who suggested adding it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
                # make your change
                git add . # or add individual files
                git commit --amend
                # follow prompts to change or keep the commit message
                # now your last commit contains that change!
            &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This usually happens to me if I commit, then run tests/linters... and FML, I didn't put a space after the equals sign. You could also make the change as a new commit and then do &lt;code&gt;rebase -i&lt;/code&gt; in order to squash them both together, but this is about a million times faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;2.6666666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
                git commit --amend
                # follow prompts to change the commit message
            &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stupid commit message formatting requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;9.2556634304207&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
                # create a new branch from the current state of master
                git branch some-new-branch-name
                # remove the commit from the master branch
                git reset HEAD~ --hard
                git checkout some-new-branch-name
                # your commit lives in this branch now :)
            &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: this doesn't work if you've already pushed to origin, and if you tried other things first, you might need to &lt;code&gt;git reset HEAD@{number}&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;HEAD~&lt;/code&gt;. Infinite sadness. Also, many many many people suggested an awesome way to make this shorter that I didn't know myself. Thank you all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;10.9875&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
                # undo the last commit, but leave the changes available
                git reset HEAD~ --soft
                git stash
                # move to the correct branch
                git checkout name-of-the-correct-branch
                git stash pop
                git add . # or add individual files
                git commit -m &quot;your message here&quot;
                # now your changes are on the correct branch
            &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have suggested using cherry-pick for this situation too, so take your pick on whatever one makes the most sense to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
                git checkout name-of-the-correct-branch
                # grab the last commit to master
                git cherry-pick master
                # delete it from master
                git checkout master
                git reset HEAD~ --hard
            &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;5.7294520547945&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;git diff --staged&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git won't do a diff of files that have been &lt;code&gt;add&lt;/code&gt;-ed to your staging area without this flag. File under ¯\_(ツ)_/¯ (yes, this is a feature, not a bug, but it's baffling and non-obvious the first time it happens to you!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;4.0555555555556&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;
                cd ..
                sudo rm -r fucking-git-repo-dir
                git clone https://some.github.url/fucking-git-repo-dir.git
                cd fucking-git-repo-dir
            &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/viaz66&quot;&gt;@viaz66&lt;/a&gt; for this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;spaced centered&quot; readability=&quot;20.585846867749&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;top-lined bottom-lined&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;*Disclaimer: I am not, nor do I even remotely claim to be, an expert at git. This site is not intended to be an exhaustive reference, nor is it a beginner's tutorial. And yes, there are other ways to do these same things with more theoretical purity or whatever, but I've come to these steps through trial and error and lots of swearing and table flipping, and I had this crazy idea to share them with a healthy dose of levity and profanity. Take it or leave it as you will! Also, the response has been so overwhelming, I haven't had a chance to sort through submission emails &amp;amp; tweets. SOON.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;flattr-note&quot;&gt;Did this site help you &quot;git&quot; out of a mess? Why not donate a little to help cover hosting costs? THANK YOU!&lt;/small&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;What's your &quot;Oh shit, git&quot; moment? Share them with me:&lt;br/&gt;Katie at ohshitgit.com or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ohshitgit&quot;&gt;@ohshitgit&lt;/a&gt;. (I'm also &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ksylor&quot;&gt;@ksylor&lt;/a&gt;, but that's mostly for stupid jokes about my kids)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 14:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adishaporwal</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://ohshitgit.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A plan to rescue the Web from the Internet</title>
<link>https://staltz.com/a-plan-to-rescue-the-web-from-the-internet.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://staltz.com/a-plan-to-rescue-the-web-from-the-internet.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;centered&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;A plan to rescue the Web from the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;18 Dec 2017&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My previous article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/the-web-began-dying-in-2014-heres-how.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Web began dying in 2014, here’s how&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, raised much more awareness than I thought it would. Many people found it to be an insightful analysis of the Web under the control of tech giants, but the article ended without providing anything positive to hold on to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually have hope for the Web. There are legimately viable ways of preserving freedom on the Web while taking the platform forward and keeping it competitive against proprietary alternatives from tech giants. But it can only happen if the Web takes a courageous step towards its next level. If it stays in its current form, the Web has little chance of being relevant while America’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/14/technology/net-neutrality-repeal-vote.html&quot;&gt;FCC kills Net Neutrality rules&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/10/drms-dead-canary-how-we-just-lost-web-what-we-learned-it-and-what-we-need-do-next&quot;&gt;W3C favors DRM&lt;/a&gt;, and tech giants build their Web-less vision of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community of peer-to-peer technologists has brought to the world several revolutionary technologies: USENET, Napster, BitTorrent, Kazaa, Skype, Bitcoin, Ethereum, and actually even the Web itself. Once again, we can turn to this community to seek digital solutions that defend freedom. Many months ago &lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/my-last-day-and-my-first-day.html&quot;&gt;I quit my job&lt;/a&gt; in order to join a group of peer-to-peer programmers and help build technology that can rescue our digital freedoms. I want to share with you our plan, which in short is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build the mobile mesh Web that works with or without Internet access, to reach 4 billion people currently offline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain this plan, we need to realize that the Web can be independent from the Internet. The core weaknesses of the Internet have to be recognized, and how exactly they were exploited by middlemen businesses. The problem we are solving is both social and technical, so the solution must be a harmony of these two. Finally, all the tools and opportunities we need to supersede them are already in our hands: smartphones, peer-to-peer protocols, and mesh networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rise-of-closed-cyberspaces&quot;&gt;The rise of closed cyberspaces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web is an open cyberspace, a digital context where society can happen, where no single organization, company, or government has the final word on what is allowed or forbidden. It is also an access point to other cyberspaces. Every time you “sign in” with an account on a website, you are entering a closed cyberspace. These cyberspaces are hosted by servers owned by the company or organization behind that website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most closed cyberspaces don’t threaten the Web’s role as a public space. A school’s &lt;em&gt;intranet&lt;/em&gt; is a closed cyberspace, and so is a private discussion forum or a company’s internal discussion platform. Most people will understand how it is necessary for those cyberspaces to be &lt;strong&gt;closed&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;controlled&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real threat comes with giant closed cyberspaces that disguise themselves as public spaces. Facebook, for instance. Many of its users think of it as a neutral public space where society comes together, and in fact Facebook often efficiently carries out that role. It is, nevertheless, closed and controlled. It started as one of those justifiably closed cyberspaces: it was a private community of Harvard students. With its explosive growth, though, it had to quickly evolve to encompass all types of social structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Facebook was growing on the Web, Apple launched the iPhone in 2007, and the world was revolutionized by smartphones after that. Zuckerberg saw the mobile &lt;em&gt;megatrend&lt;/em&gt; before many others did, and as early as &lt;a href=&quot;https://gigaom.com/2009/02/10/why-facebooks-future-is-mobile/&quot;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt; there was a Facebook mobile app with explosive growth. Facebook began re-imagining itself as a platform independent from the Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to December 2016, and 94% of all Facebook monthly active users access the blue closed cyberspace routinely through mobile apps (divide &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/277958/number-of-mobile-active-facebook-users-worldwide/&quot;&gt;mobile MAU&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/264810/number-of-monthly-active-facebook-users-worldwide/&quot;&gt;MAU&lt;/a&gt;), while 62% access it &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; from mobile (divide &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/281600/number-of-mobile-only-facebook-users/&quot;&gt;mobile-only MAU&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/264810/number-of-monthly-active-facebook-users-worldwide/&quot;&gt;MAU&lt;/a&gt;). As a result, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2017/02/01/facebooks-entire-business-relies-on-people-using-it-on-their-phones.html&quot;&gt;84% of FB’s revenue&lt;/a&gt; comes from mobile advertising. As an extrapolation of this data, their mobile-only users likely comprise today (December 2017) between 70% – 79% of all their users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/facebook-mobile-stats.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/facebook-mobile-stats.png&quot; alt=&quot;Facebook mobile stats&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Sources: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/264810/number-of-monthly-active-facebook-users-worldwide/&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/277958/number-of-mobile-active-facebook-users-worldwide/&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/281600/number-of-mobile-only-facebook-users/&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are large enough numbers to admit that the open Web is already rather irrelevant to Zuckerberg’s products. By now, Facebook, Messenger, Instagram, and WhatsApp are arguably &lt;strong&gt;non-Web closed cyberspaces&lt;/strong&gt; of comparable scale to the Web (users of FB products are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/617136/digital-population-worldwide/&quot;&gt;roughly 2/3 of all Internet users&lt;/a&gt;). Facebook even has &lt;a href=&quot;https://amp.theguardian.com/uk-news/2015/jan/31/british-army-facebook-warriors-77th-brigade&quot;&gt;its own concept of cyberwarfare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It competes with the Web in many use cases that people want from a public cyberspace: sharing notes and images, engaging with communities, doing business, marketing services and products, and organizing events. Similarly, this argument can also be made for YouTube. In fact, any closed cyberspace that grows too much could become a threat to the open Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the question: is it fundamentally inevitable that a closed cyberspace will use the open cyberspace to eventually outgrow it? I would answer: no. The Web only got to this current situation because of &lt;strong&gt;fundamental flaws in the Internet’s architecture which rigged the system&lt;/strong&gt;. Closed cyberspaces thrive because they have artificially imposed incentives to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;technical-flaws-that-supported-middlemen-businesses&quot;&gt;Technical flaws that supported middlemen businesses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet that supports the Web (as well as other applications such as email, Skype, WhatsApp, online mobile apps) is a technical marvel, but it shares similarities with some archaic systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way data travels through the Internet is quite similar to how the postal system works. Each recipient needs a unique address. On the Internet, these are the so-called “IP addresses”, which are simply numbers given to each computer. A computer may be assigned the number 198.153.192.40, where the first part 198 refers to a specific region in the USA, and the other numbers help specify which particular computer in that region is the recipient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the problem with IP addresses: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv4_address_exhaustion&quot;&gt;there aren’t enough of them&lt;/a&gt;. When the Internet was being planned, it was initially a system of military and university networks. They did not account for the massive popular adoption of the Internet that made it mainstream in business, commerce, and for inter-personal communication. Imagine if there could only be a limited number of mailboxes in the postal system – that is virtually what occured to the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/ipv4_address_map.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/ipv4_address_map.gif&quot; alt=&quot;IPv4 address map&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a quick solution to this, though: a mechanism called Network Address Translation (NAT). Jargon aside, it’s a simple idea: one computer gets a real IP address and acts as an intermediate for other computers which do not have real IP addresses. Imagine that your neighborhood would share a single mailbox, then one person would be responsible for sorting and forwarding each received mail to the correct final destination. That is what NAT accomplishes for Internet addresses, and it is commonly deployed on local routers, such as the box you might have installed in your home or office. The advent of NAT routers also allowed for that intermediate computer to become a guardian and protect other computers from some dangers of the open Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also meant that some computers were first-class citizens on the Internet, while other computers were subordinates. In addition, the scarcity of IP addresses caused them to be considered valuable assets, and so it became a business opportunity. IP addresses are being sold so that some computers can become first-class citizens on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems easy to solve this problem, though: just provide more IP addresses, since they are after all just artificial resources. That is what &lt;em&gt;IP version 6&lt;/em&gt; is all about, and its purpose is to make sure there would always be enough addresses for everyone (the limit is more than a trillion trillions). However, IPv6 was declared ready for use in 1998 – two decades ago – but its adoption among organizations around the world is still just &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2010/09/there-is-no-plan-b-why-the-ipv4-to-ipv6-transition-will-be-ugly/&quot;&gt;catching up&lt;/a&gt;, because it demands teaching every Internet-connected machine to understand and utilize the new types of addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn’t enough economic incentives for IPv6, though, since the information industry has made its nest in massive systems that assume IPv4 plus NAT. Companies that sell IPv4 addresses see little benefit in adopting IPv6 and companies that depend on IPv4 + NAT systems prefer to avoid the risks associated with disturbing the infrastructures that power their always-online businesses. Even if all the computers started using IPv6, too many programs were built with NAT in mind, which could reveal many security vulnerabilities when exposed to a world without NAT. In other words, the Internet economy simply isn’t ready for a scenario where IPv6 is used everywhere and NAT is abandoned. We are stuck with what we have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, the Internet has allowed intermediate computers to rule. These are like parasites that have grown too large to remove without killing the host. The technical flaw that favored intermediate computers prefigured a world where middlemen business models thrive. Google and Facebook connect consumers with advertisement publishers, and charge fees for each ad. Amazon is a middleman business as well: it connects retailers with consumers, and takes a cut on transactions. Many popular ‘sharing economy’ startups and services are also middlemen: Airbnb, Uber, Kickstarter, Patreon, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to imagine how things could be different, yet the incentives for these businesses to exist were artificially erected. It is not fundamentally necessary to have any intermediate company profiting whenever a person reads news from their friends, rents an apartment from a stranger, or orders a ride from a driver. This is why it is important to analyze technical systems from an economical and societal perspective: because early design decisions foreshadow certain social orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can – and urgently must – provide alternative ways of digitally supporting popular use cases for Web services. It is possible to escape middlemen businesses by decreasing reliance on the infrastructure that plugs their systems together: wires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-internet-on-a-leash&quot;&gt;The Internet, on a leash&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The physical foundation of the Internet is a global network of thick bundles of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.extremetech.com/computing/96827-the-secret-world-of-submarine-cables&quot;&gt;privately-owned fiber optic undersea cables&lt;/a&gt; spanning oceans to connect all the continents together. Undersea communication cables exist since the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Submarine_communications_cable&quot;&gt;1850s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/undersea-cable.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/undersea-cable.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Undersea cables&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Source: Reuters/Landov)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These cables follow a hierarchical layout: continents are connected to other continents, countries connected to countries, and within those countries, different companies (Internet Service Providers, ISPs) have to agree with their local government in order to plug into that network of cables. This well organized hierarchy is the only way the wired Internet can be feasible. Otherwise, a grassroots wired internet would be a true mess of cables. Countries and organizations also manage the distribution of IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the Internet is praised as the technology that ushered us into a new era, the information age, it is just a fancy way of transfering data from computer A to computer B. It is highly efficient in transferring data globally at almost instantenous speeds, but it is nevertheless much like a USB cable that connects your computer to an external hard drive. In fact, transfer speeds are almost always better through USB cables than through the Internet. The real benefit of the Internet is instant globalization through the fact that it makes all computers in the world &lt;em&gt;seem like&lt;/em&gt; they are in the same room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global real-time economy enabled by &lt;em&gt;the wirenet&lt;/em&gt; is a historical achievement with permanent implications to humanity. That said, often we engage with apps that have no need for global connectivity. For instance, staying in contact with friends in the same city – a naive but likely the most popular use case for technology – requires no connections to countries on the other side of the planet. Yet we overutilize the global tangle of inter-connected cables to run proprietary and foreign (often American) apps which deliver messages that travel around the world just to reach a colleague nearby. This has opened our lives and our nations to digital colonialism from surveillance capitalism corporations (pick your favorite Silicon Valley company) married to three-letter intelligence agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What could be the alternative? So much of our digital lives depend on technologies that are out of our reach, physically, legally, and economically. Gladly, technology itself has recently provided the first building blocks that can be put together to create a new cyberspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;untapped-opportunities&quot;&gt;Untapped opportunities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological innovation is quick to introduce amazing things such as smartphones, 4G connectivity, cryptocurrencies, and digital social networks. None of these existed when the Internet was being planned. Yet all of them rely on the very old idea (from the 19th century) of telecom companies, not as a fundamental requirement, but due to lack of alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a thought experiment, how would the Next Internet look like if it were reinvented using all the accumulated knowledge from the last 3 decades of global cyberspaces? There are three promising things that can enable a reinvented Internet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The people-centered Web&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile mesh networks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 billion people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Web is classically a location-centered cyberspace. When you access the Web, you visit locations (URLs, like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wikipedia.org&lt;/code&gt;) that contain content. You often don’t see the people who created that content, but they are implicitly assumed to be there. The problem with location-centered content – prefigured by the way HTTP was designed – is that it’s not easy to archive for posteriority. An image hosted through some link may be there today, but maybe not tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novel peer-to-peer protocols such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://datproject.org/&quot;&gt;Dat&lt;/a&gt; help replace HTTP and make the Web a content-centered cyberspace. This way the link to an image can be something like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;QaPdNnDWRLF1b&lt;/code&gt; – a so-called &lt;em&gt;hash&lt;/em&gt; of the image, summarizing it – instead of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mywebsite.com/pic.jpeg&lt;/code&gt; so that even if &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mywebsite.com&lt;/code&gt; servers are removed, you can still get the image by fetching it from any computer that has stored &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;QaPdNnDWRLF1b&lt;/code&gt;. If you don’t like the unreadable code, you can just use a link shortener like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bit.ly&lt;/code&gt; to create a shortcut to the unreadable code. This way, even if your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bit.ly&lt;/code&gt; short link disappears, the content can still be recovered from the crowd of online computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browsers can be made to work like that, and although it’s a small tweak to how the Web works, it has massive effects on social structures in cyberspace. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://beakerbrowser.com/&quot;&gt;Beaker Browser&lt;/a&gt; is the best demonstration of that, which you can easily install and start using today. It allows your browser to directly share content with other people’s Beaker installations, without intermediate servers (like YouTube servers, Medium, blogs, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These above mentioned technologies fix the Web by making it truly content-centered instead of location-centered. That said, the Web is good at putting content on stage, while keeping content authors in the backstage. While there are many use cases where it’s desirable to de-emphasize people, such as anonymous reports, crowd-sourced encyclopedias, and cat videos, in the recent years we have discovered a game-changing way of structuring cyberspaces: the Social Web, where content orbits the author like planets orbit a star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes sense for a cyberspace, a digital context for people to engage with each other, to be people-centered. Websites in the social realm took a daring approach of making &lt;em&gt;You&lt;/em&gt; a location: the URL &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/andrestaltz&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;twitter.com/andrestaltz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; means that this content &lt;em&gt;is a person&lt;/em&gt;. In fact, one of the earliest large social networks was named &lt;em&gt;Myspace&lt;/em&gt;, emphasizing the location and its association with a person. We all have experienced how revolutionary this concept has been, and how it has pervasively reached to many corners of the Web: you can sign in with a Facebook account or insert blog comments using your Facebook profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/people-centered-web.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/people-centered-web.png&quot; alt=&quot;Three types of Web arrangements&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have experience with some of the intricacies of the social Web, we can reinvent it to put people first without intermediate companies. The peer-to-peer protocol &lt;a href=&quot;http://scuttlebutt.nz/&quot;&gt;Secure Scuttlebutt&lt;/a&gt; (SSB) does that, designed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://coolguy.website/writing/the-future-will-be-technical/index.html&quot;&gt;diversity-first principles&lt;/a&gt; that prefigure (hopefully) social structures with freedom, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P5K18XssVBg&quot;&gt;subjectivity&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FEU632_Em3g&quot;&gt;political structures that can prevent capitalistic monopolies&lt;/a&gt;. SSB was envisioned and created by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2017/05/meet-the-counterantidisintermediationists/527553/&quot;&gt;a nomad programmer&lt;/a&gt; who had unreliable Internet connection and wanted to enable social networks for &lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/an-off-grid-social-network.html&quot;&gt;off-grid lifestyles&lt;/a&gt;. A growing community of pioneers and programmers are using SSB on a daily basis as their main social network. I really hope you click through all those links and explore SSB in more depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mix of off-grid lifestyles with digital social networks is unusual, because we tend to associate technology with dependency on the &lt;em&gt;Grid&lt;/em&gt; for energy and Internet connectivity. However, to create an alternative to the Grid, we need to look for technologies that provide &lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/layers-of-the-internet-economy.html&quot;&gt;energy and connectivity&lt;/a&gt; without the Grid. Solar panels provide the former and are a staple of the off-grid sustainability movement known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://solarpunks.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Solarpunks&lt;/a&gt;. To provide the latter, we can use wireless technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cables gave birth to the information age, but wireless gave us wings to go untethered. And today, digital society gets together &lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/desktop-vs-mobile-2.jpg&quot;&gt;through smartphones more than it does through desktop computers&lt;/a&gt;. While smartphones enable us to easily share files directly to other devices – without intermediates – using Bluetooth or Apple’s AirDrop, we don’t transfer data through that as compulsively as we do through cables. Wireless technology exists today as a mere extension of the wired world, but it could be so much more than that. It could be, in fact, the opposite: wires as a mere extension of the wireless world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably haven’t heard of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_ad_hoc_network&quot;&gt;mobile ad-hoc networks&lt;/a&gt; (MANETs), also known as &lt;em&gt;meshes&lt;/em&gt;. One of the reasons for their lack of popularity is that meshes would &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smart_phone_ad_hoc_network#Threats_to_telcos&quot;&gt;threaten the business of telecom operators&lt;/a&gt;, so there is little incentive from the establishment to develop and deliver mobile ad-hoc networks to you. A MANET is like AirDrop, but automatically and seamlessly connects to devices around you and delivers data in multiple hops between those devices. Even if Bluetooth connections can only reach a few meters, after multiple jumps, you can connect to devices a few kilometers away. Information literally spreads through the air to a mesh of devices in a region. It is propelled even more by the fact that mobile devices are moving around, doing half of the work of transporting data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the primary reason why MANETs are underappreciated is that they do not yet provide data transfer speeds comparable to those in the wirenet. A MANET upholds principles like freedom from fixed intermediate organizations, but it is simply too slow for transfer-intensive use cases like streaming video or instant messaging. Their adoption would feel like a step backwards to the early days of the Web when speeds were measured in a few Kilobits per second, not the usual Megabits per second you are used to in developed countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesh networks are nevertheless still promising, for two facts. First, the technology is evolving, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/multipeerconnectivity&quot;&gt;Apple MultipeerConnectivity&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.bluetooth.com/introducing-bluetooth-mesh-networking&quot;&gt;Bluetooth Mesh&lt;/a&gt; as a few cutting-edge examples. Novel protocols are being developed that envision &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjdelisle/cjdns&quot;&gt;IPv6 without ISPs&lt;/a&gt;, ideal for meshes. Second, because many developing countries do not yet have Internet access. This accounts for 4 billion people, out of the total 7.6 billion, with currently zero bits per second of transfer speeds. Even if it seems like the Internet encompasses the whole world, it still barely reaches 45% of the planet. Some may have Internet connectivity, but it’s intermittent or not consistently speedy. For people with intermittent or unexistent connectivity, ISP-free mesh networks with moderate but consistent speeds become quite attractive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/InternetPenetrationWorldMap.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://staltz.com/img/InternetPenetrationWorldMap.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Internet penetration world map&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;strong&gt;Internet users in 2015 as a percentage of a country’s population&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_number_of_Internet_users#/media/File:InternetPenetrationWorldMap.svg&quot;&gt;Jeff Ogden (W163)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook and Google are desperate for getting an early grip of those 4 billion people, e.g. through &lt;a href=&quot;http://internet.org/&quot;&gt;Internet.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.company/loon/&quot;&gt;Project Loon&lt;/a&gt;. However, because their middlemen businesses are tethered to the Internet, all of these projects require the old hierarchical structures of ISPs and cables. Their businesses and modus operandi are inherently infrastructure-heavy. The difficulties are several: balloons cannot reliably cover all the regions, local ISPs or local governments may be corrupt, and any other wired infrastructure project takes years or decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exciting part is that we can actually beat the tech giants at this game by simply giving local and regional connectivity to people in developing countries. With mobile apps that are built mesh-first, the smartphones would make up self-organizing self-healing MANETs. Frankly, this is quite easy to do, if we are willing to gift mobile devices without expecting anything back, unlike tech giants. It won’t be an easy fight, though, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xCZOGZf_Pnc&quot;&gt;Facebook is working hard to build a compromise&lt;/a&gt; that still gives them the middleman upper hand. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-f8-ten-year-roadmap-2016-4&quot;&gt;Zuckerberg’s 10-year roadmap&lt;/a&gt; puts connectivity projects in the long-term spectrum (5–10 years). That’s basically our deadline, we need to get grassroots meshes in Africa before that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mobile apps for meshes would have to be best suited for the particular limitations of (current) MANET technologies. Video streaming and instant messaging are not the first options, but lightweight websites in content-addressed style (like in the Beaker Browser with Dat) and text-first social news feeds are applications that can be realistically delivered in the short term. Such apps don’t even require constant connection to other devices in the mesh. For text-based social news feeds, it suffices to occasionally sync the latest news with other devices whenever they are in range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the mobile apps themselves can be deployed through MANETs, and I have already developed an “app store” mobile app that fits that use case, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/staltz/dat-installer&quot;&gt;Dat Installer&lt;/a&gt;. My main project at the moment is to build a mesh-friendly &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/staltz/mmmmm-mobile/&quot;&gt;social network mobile app running on SSB&lt;/a&gt;. It is important to highlight that while these apps are built for meshes, they know how to ‘surf’ the Internet and utilize it as a fallback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When talking about decentralized peer-to-peer protocols in 2017, it is imperative to mention blockchains and cryptocurrencies. These are great innovations and directly tackle &lt;em&gt;intermediate organizations&lt;/em&gt; (mostly banks) as a problem, much like IPFS, Dat, and SSB. On the other hand, most blockchain protocols were designed with high Internet speeds, powerful hardware, and global connectivity in mind. What most of these innovations share in common is the accomplishment of a distributed global database where no single actor is to be trusted above the others. There are legitimately useful use cases of this, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://jeremyrand.github.io/namecoin.org/&quot;&gt;decentralized Web domain registration&lt;/a&gt;. On the other hand, requiring global consensus, high Internet speeds, and powerful hardware makes it difficult to utilize blochchains for mesh networks in developing countries. Alternative not-quite-blockchain experiments like &lt;a href=&quot;https://iota.org/&quot;&gt;IOTA&lt;/a&gt; might change this, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-plan&quot;&gt;The plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While growing local mesh networks for-charity in developing countries is the proposed strategy, how is it connected to a plan for countering the tech oligarchy in developed countries? In Internet-less regions there is potential for scaling quickly, and through that we can spawn a new industry around peer-to-peer wireless mesh networks. If this industry grows, it can also support meshes in the developed world. Scaling fast is important to make meshes more than just niche projects by a few enthusiasts, but instead become a thriving ecosystem. The mega-projects listed below are a plan to rescue the Web from the Internet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next year or two:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Developers improve peer-to-peer protocols that support the content-centered Web (IPFS, Dat) and the people-centered Web (SSB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers and hardware manufacturers write open protocols for mesh networking (comparable to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/multipeerconnectivity&quot;&gt;MultipeerConnectivity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjdelisle/cjdns&quot;&gt;CJDNS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://opengarden.com/&quot;&gt;Open Garden&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers bring peer-to-peer protocols to smartphones and build mobile apps that use those&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web enthusiasts and archivers help migrate content from the old Web to the new protocols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware startups compete in the market for regional mesh networks (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://gotenna.com/&quot;&gt;goTenna&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beartooth.com/&quot;&gt;Beartooth&lt;/a&gt;, and others)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In two years or more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Smartphone manufacturers sell mesh-first mobile devices for the developing world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers work with regional communities to localize mesh mobile apps (note the possibility of forking open source projects and customizing them to different cultures)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charitable organizations or companies offer mesh-first smartphones for free (or subsidized and cheap) to people in developing nations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mesh-based cyberspaces start to thrive in some countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similar mesh cyberspaces in the developed world also gain relevance, specially in countries with unfair ISPs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In six years or more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ecosystem of wireless mesh networks expands from regional “airnets” to national airnets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National airnets are weaved together through a global mesh of satellites (much like &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/599g4b/bitcoin-now-comes-from-satellites-in-space&quot;&gt;Blockstream&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the global airnet competitive with the wirenet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a result of having competition between the two, we can hope to fix the overutilization of the wirenet and the underutilization of airnets, bringing balance to the wire-versus-air dichotomy, providing choice in how data should travel in each case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choice is freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you liked this article, consider sharing &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?original_referer=https%3A%2F%2Fstaltz.com%2Fa-plan-to-rescue-the-web-from-the-internet.html&amp;amp;text=A%20plan%20to%20rescue%20the%20Web%20from%20the%20Internet&amp;amp;tw_p=tweetbutton&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstaltz.com%2Fa-plan-to-rescue-the-web-from-the-internet.html&amp;amp;via=andrestaltz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;tweeting&quot;&gt;(tweeting)&lt;/a&gt; it to your followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;verify-in-keybase&quot;&gt;You can make sure that the author wrote this post by copy-pasting &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/staltz/staltz.com/master/signed_posts/2017-12-18-a-plan-to-rescue-the-web-from-the-internet.md.asc&quot;&gt;this signature&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;a href=&quot;https://keybase.io/verify&quot;&gt;this Keybase page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 12:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>staltz</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://staltz.com/a-plan-to-rescue-the-web-from-the-internet.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mining Bitcoin with pencil and paper: 0.67 hashes per day (2014)</title>
<link>http://www.righto.com/2014/09/mining-bitcoin-with-pencil-and-paper.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.righto.com/2014/09/mining-bitcoin-with-pencil-and-paper.html</guid>
<description>

I decided to see how practical it would be to mine Bitcoin with pencil and paper. It turns out that the SHA-256 algorithm used for mining is pretty simple and can in fact be done by hand. Not surprisingly, the process is extremely slow compared to hardware mining and is entirely impractical. But performing the algorithm manually is a good way to understand exactly how it works.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://static.righto.com/images/bitcoin/mine_pencil_1-s800.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A pencil-and-paper round of SHA-256&quot; class=&quot;hilite2&quot; src=&quot;http://static.righto.com/images/bitcoin/mine_pencil_1-w500.png&quot; title=&quot;A pencil-and-paper round of SHA-256&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;A pencil-and-paper round of SHA-256&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The mining process&lt;/h2&gt;
Bitcoin mining is a key part of the security of the Bitcoin system. The idea is that Bitcoin miners group a bunch of Bitcoin transactions into a block, then repeatedly perform a cryptographic operation called hashing zillions of times until someone finds a special extremely rare hash value. At this point, the block has been mined and becomes part of the Bitcoin block chain. The hashing task itself doesn't accomplish anything useful in itself, but because finding a successful block is so difficult, it ensures that no individual has the resources to take over the Bitcoin system. For more details on mining, see my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2014/02/bitcoin-mining-hard-way-algorithms.html&quot;&gt;Bitcoin mining article&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;A cryptographic hash function takes a block of input data and creates a smaller, unpredictable output. The hash function is designed so there's no &quot;short cut&quot; to get the desired output - you just have to keep hashing blocks until you find one by brute force that works. For Bitcoin, the hash function is a function called &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SHA-2&quot;&gt;SHA-256&lt;/a&gt;. To provide additional security, Bitcoin applies the SHA-256 function twice, a process known as double-SHA-256.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Bitcoin, a successful hash is one that starts with enough zeros.&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2014/09/mining-bitcoin-with-pencil-and-paper.html#ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Just as it is rare to find a phone number or license plate ending in multiple zeros, it is rare to find a hash starting with multiple zeros. But Bitcoin is exponentially harder. Currently, a successful hash must start with approximately 17 zeros, so only one out of 1.4x10&lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt; hashes will be successful. In other words, finding a successful hash is harder than finding a particular grain of sand out of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/blogs/krulwich/2012/09/17/161096233/which-is-greater-the-number-of-sand-grains-on-earth-or-stars-in-the-sky&quot;&gt;all the grains of sand on Earth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following diagram shows a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blockexplorer.com/b/286819&quot;&gt;block&lt;/a&gt; in the Bitcoin blockchain along with its hash. The yellow bytes are hashed to generate the block hash. In this case, the resulting hash starts with enough zeros so mining was successful. However, the hash will almost always be unsuccessful. In that case, the miner changes the nonce value or other block contents and tries again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://static.righto.com/images/bitcoin/block_diagram_ghash.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Structure of a Bitcoin block&quot; class=&quot;hilite2&quot; src=&quot;http://static.righto.com/images/bitcoin/block_diagram_ghash-w550.png&quot; title=&quot;Structure of a Bitcoin block&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;Structure of a Bitcoin block&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The SHA-256 hash algorithm used by Bitcoin&lt;/h2&gt;
The SHA-256 hash algorithm takes input blocks of 512 bits (i.e. 64 bytes), combines the data cryptographically, and generates a 256-bit (32 byte) output. The SHA-256 algorithm consists of a relatively simple round repeated 64 times. The diagram below shows one round, which takes eight 4-byte inputs, A through H, performs a few operations, and generates new values of A through H.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://static.righto.com/images/bitcoin/SHA_2.svg.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;SHA-256 round, from Wikipedia&quot; class=&quot;hilite2&quot; src=&quot;http://static.righto.com/images/bitcoin/SHA_2.svg-w400.png&quot; title=&quot;SHA-256 round, from Wikipedia&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;One round of the SHA-256 algorithm showing the 8 input blocks A-H, the processing steps, and the new blocks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:SHA-2.svg#mediaviewer/File:SHA-2.svg&quot;&gt;Diagram&lt;/a&gt; created by kockmeyer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blue boxes mix up the values in non-linear ways that are hard to analyze cryptographically. Since the algorithm uses several different functions, discovering an attack is harder. (If you could figure out a mathematical shortcut to generate successful hashes, you could take over Bitcoin mining.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Ma&lt;/em&gt; majority box looks at the bits of A, B, and C. For each position, if the majority of the bits are 0, it outputs 0. Otherwise it outputs 1. That is, for each position in A, B, and C, look at the number of 1 bits. If it is zero or one, output 0. If it is two or three, output 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Σ0&lt;/em&gt; box rotates the bits of A to form three rotated versions, and then sums them together modulo 2. In other words, if the number of 1 bits is odd, the sum is 1; otherwise, it is 0. The three values in the sum are A rotated right by 2 bits, 13 bits, and 22 bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Ch&lt;/em&gt; &quot;choose&quot; box chooses output bits based on the value of input E. If a bit of E is 1, the output bit is the corresponding bit of F. If a bit of E is 0, the output bit is the corresponding bit of G. In this way, the bits of F and G are shuffled together based on the value of E.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next box &lt;em&gt;Σ1&lt;/em&gt; rotates and sums the bits of E, similar to &lt;em&gt;Σ0&lt;/em&gt; except the shifts are 6, 11, and 25 bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The red boxes perform 32-bit addition, generating new values for A and E. The input &lt;em&gt;W&lt;sub&gt;t&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is based on the input data, slightly processed. (This is where the input block gets fed into the algorithm.) The input &lt;em&gt;K&lt;sub&gt;t&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a constant defined for each round.&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2014/09/mining-bitcoin-with-pencil-and-paper.html#ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As can be seen from the diagram above, only A and E are changed in a round. The other values pass through unchanged, with the old A value becoming the new B value, the old B value becoming the new C value and so forth. Although each round of SHA-256 doesn't change the data much, after 64 rounds the input data will be completely scrambled.&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2014/09/mining-bitcoin-with-pencil-and-paper.html#ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Manual mining&lt;/h2&gt;
The video below shows how the SHA-256 hashing steps described above can be performed with pencil and paper. I perform the first round of hashing to mine a block. Completing this round took me 16 minutes, 45 seconds.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/y3dqhixzGVo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain what's on the paper: I've written each block A through H in hex on a separate row and put the binary value below. The &lt;em&gt;maj&lt;/em&gt; operation appears below C, and the shifts and &lt;em&gt;Σ0&lt;/em&gt; appear above row A. Likewise, the &lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt; operation appears below G, and the shifts and &lt;em&gt;Σ1&lt;/em&gt; above E. In the lower right, a bunch of terms are added together, corresponding to the first three red sum boxes. In the upper right, this sum is used to generate the new A value, and in the middle right, this sum is used to generate the new E value. These steps all correspond to the diagram and discussion above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also manually performed another hash round, the last round to finish hashing the Bitcoin block. In the image below, the hash result is highlighted in yellow. The zeroes in this hash show that it is a successful hash. Note that the zeroes are at the end of the hash. The reason is that Bitcoin inconveniently reverses all the bytes generated by SHA-256.&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2014/09/mining-bitcoin-with-pencil-and-paper.html#ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://static.righto.com/images/bitcoin/mine_pencil_2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Last pencil-and-paper round of SHA-256, showing a successfully-mined Bitcoin block.&quot; class=&quot;hilite2&quot; src=&quot;http://static.righto.com/images/bitcoin/mine_pencil_2-w500.png&quot; title=&quot;Last pencil-and-paper round of SHA-256, showing a successfully-mined Bitcoin block.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;Last pencil-and-paper round of SHA-256, showing a successfully-mined Bitcoin block.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What this means for mining hardware&lt;/h2&gt;
Each step of SHA-256 is very easy to implement in digital logic - simple Boolean operations and 32-bit addition. (If you've studied electronics, you can probably visualize the circuits already.) For this reason, custom ASIC chips can implement the SHA-256 algorithm very efficiently in hardware, putting hundreds of rounds on a chip in parallel. The image below shows a mining chip that runs at 2-3 billion hashes/second; &lt;a href=&quot;http://zeptobars.ru/en/read/bitfury-bitcoin-mining-chip&quot;&gt;Zeptobars&lt;/a&gt; has more photos.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zeptobars.ru/en/read/bitfury-bitcoin-mining-chip&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The silicon die inside a Bitfury ASIC chip. This chip mines Bitcoin at 2-3 Ghash/second. Image from http://zeptobars.ru/en/read/bitfury-bitcoin-mining-chip (CC BY 3.0 license)&quot; class=&quot;hilite2&quot; src=&quot;http://static.righto.com/images/bitcoin/bitfury_die-s350.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The silicon die inside a Bitfury ASIC chip. This chip mines Bitcoin at 2-3 Ghash/second. Image from http://zeptobars.ru/en/read/bitfury-bitcoin-mining-chip (CC BY 3.0 license)&quot; width=&quot;350&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;The silicon die inside a Bitfury ASIC chip. This chip mines Bitcoin at 2-3 Ghash/second. Image from &lt;a href=&quot;http://zeptobars.ru/en/read/bitfury-bitcoin-mining-chip&quot;&gt;Zeptobars&lt;/a&gt;. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY 3.0&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, Litecoin, Dogecoin, and similar altcoins use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrypt&quot;&gt;scrypt&lt;/a&gt; hash algorithm, which is intentionally designed to be difficult to implement in hardware. It stores 1024 different hash values into memory, and then combines them in unpredictable ways to get the final result. As a result, much more circuitry and memory is required for scrypt than for SHA-256 hashes. You can see the impact by looking at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.topbitcoinmininghardware.com/&quot;&gt;mining hardware&lt;/a&gt;, which is thousands of times slower for scrypt (Litecoin, etc) than for SHA-256 (Bitcoin).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
The SHA-256 algorithm is surprisingly simple, easy enough to do by hand. (The elliptic curve algorithm for signing Bitcoin transactions would be very painful to do by hand since it has lots of multiplication of 32-byte integers.) Doing one round of SHA-256 by hand took me 16 minutes, 45 seconds. At this rate, hashing a full Bitcoin block (128 rounds)&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2014/09/mining-bitcoin-with-pencil-and-paper.html#ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; would take 1.49 days, for a hash rate of 0.67 hashes per day (although I would probably get faster with practice). In comparison, current Bitcoin mining hardware does several terahashes per second, about a quintillion times faster than my manual hashing. Needless to say, manual Bitcoin mining is not at all practical.&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2014/09/mining-bitcoin-with-pencil-and-paper.html#ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reddit reader &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/2hpegd/mining_bitcoin_with_pencil_and_paper_067_hashes/ckurfv4&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; about my energy consumption. There's not much physical exertion, so assuming a resting metabolic rate of 1500kcal/day, manual hashing works out to almost 10 megajoules/hash. A typical energy consumption for mining hardware is 1000 megahashes/joule. So I'm less energy efficient by a factor of 10^16, or 10 quadrillion. The next question is the energy cost. A cheap source of food energy is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mymoneyblog.com/what-does-200-calories-cost-the-economics-of-obesity.html&quot;&gt;donuts&lt;/a&gt; at $0.23 for 200 kcalories. Electricity here is $0.15/kilowatt-hour, which is cheaper by a factor of 6.7 - closer than I expected. Thus my energy cost per hash is about 67 quadrillion times that of mining hardware. It's clear I'm not going to make my fortune off manual mining, and I haven't even included the cost of all the paper and pencils I'll need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 edit: My Bitcoin mining on paper system is part of the book &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2kGdqBA&quot;&gt;The Objects That Power the Global Economy&lt;/a&gt;, so take a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kenshirriff&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to find out about my latest blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
[1] It's not exactly the number of zeros at the start of the hash that matters. To be precise, the hash must be less than a particular value that depends on the current Bitcoin &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Difficulty&quot;&gt;difficulty level&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;[2] The source of the constants used in SHA-256 is interesting. The NSA designed the SHA-256 algorithm and picked the values for these constants, so how do you know they didn't pick special values that let them break the hash? To avoid suspicion, the initial hash values come from the square roots of the first 8 primes, and the &lt;em&gt;K&lt;sub&gt;t&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; values come from the cube roots of the first 64 primes. Since these constants come from a simple formula, you can trust that the NSA didn't do anything shady (at least with the constants).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Unfortunately the SHA-256 hash works on a block of 512 bits, but the Bitcoin block header is more than 512 bits. Thus, a second set of 64 SHA-256 hash rounds is required on the second half of the Bitcoin block. Next, Bitcoin uses &lt;em&gt;double-SHA-256&lt;/em&gt;, so a second application of SHA-256 (64 rounds) is done to the result. Adding this up, hashing an arbitrary Bitcoin block takes 192 rounds in total. However there is a shortcut. Mining involves hashing the same block over and over, just changing the &lt;em&gt;nonce&lt;/em&gt; which appears in the second half of the block. Thus, mining can reuse the result of hashing the first 512 bits, and hashing a Bitcoin block typically only requires 128 rounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] Obviously I didn't just have incredible good fortune to end up with a successful hash. I started the hashing process with a block that had already been successfully mined. In particular I used the one displayed earlier in this article, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blockexplorer.com/b/286819&quot;&gt;#286819&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5] Another problem with manual mining is new blocks are mined about every 10 minutes, so even if I did succeed in mining a block, it would be totally obsolete (orphaned) by the time I finished.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 10:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dvt</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.righto.com/2014/09/mining-bitcoin-with-pencil-and-paper.html</og:url>
<og:title>Mining Bitcoin with pencil and paper: 0.67 hashes per day</og:title>
<og:description>This article is now available in Russian: Майним Bitcoin с помощью бумаги и ручки . I decided to see how practical it would be to mine Bit...</og:description>
<og:image>https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/l9ExaHvjqEnSAjeyb3zz4Q9VJt4saWo1jmI-14fOENo2HlXg4TdIebp6SxIJlCkXKRxaiingmmgnPZe34zEN9cjnkct6UcqSs7tNnokybwvGpAZ6H0KqTg=w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.righto.com/2014/09/mining-bitcoin-with-pencil-and-paper.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Groups funded by the Koch brothers are campaigning against municipal broadband</title>
<link>https://www.wired.com/story/koch-brothers-are-cities-new-obstacle-to-building-broadband</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.com/story/koch-brothers-are-cities-new-obstacle-to-building-broadband</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;The three Republican&lt;/span&gt; commissioners now in power at the FCC &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-takes-action-restore-internet-freedom&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;voted&lt;/a&gt; this week to erase the agency's legal authority over high-speed Internet providers. They claim that competition will protect consumers, that the commission shouldn't interfere in the &quot;dynamic internet ecosystem,&quot; and that they are &quot;protecting internet freedom.&quot; Now that the vote is done, the agency has little to do but mess around with spectrum allocations. The mega-utility of the 21st century officially has no regulator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inset-left-component&quot; readability=&quot;7.1450381679389&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;inset-left&quot; class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot;&gt;WIRED Opinion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 name=&quot;inset-left&quot; class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;inset-left&quot; class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/scrawford&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Susan Crawford&lt;/a&gt; is a professor at Harvard Law School and the author of &lt;em&gt;The Responsive City&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Captive Audience&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, fed up with federal apathy and sick of being held back by lousy internet access controlled by local cable monopolies, scrappy cities around the US are working hard to find ways to get cheap, world-class fiber-optic connectivity. It’s always been an uphill climb, as the “incumbents”—giant carriers like Comcast, Verizon, and AT&amp;amp;T—are constantly working behind the scenes to block competition. (Recently, Comcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://muninetworks.org/content/totals-are-comcast-spends-900k-fort-collins-election&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;spent nearly $1 million&lt;/a&gt; opposing a municipal-fiber vote in Fort Collins, Colorado. The company did not prevail, I’m happy to report.) But now there’s an additional obstacle: Powerful right-wing billionaires have joined the fight against municipal fiber efforts, using their deep pockets to fund efforts to block even the most commonsense of plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad news for internet access—the Koch brothers are fighting low-cost open fiber nets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look what happened in Louisville, Kentucky. It's a city of about 750,000, the largest in the state. Earlier this year, the city noticed that the state of Kentucky was funding a &quot;middle mile&quot; fiber network designed to connect the state’s 120 counties and provide cheaper connectivity for municipal buildings—&lt;a href=&quot;https://kentuckywired.ky.gov/SiteCollectionDocuments/KYW%20Quick%20Facts%205.3.17.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;KentuckyWired&lt;/a&gt;. As part of the project, Louisville—also known as Jefferson County—would be able to run 100 miles of fiber alongside the state network for just the cost of materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That seemed like a great deal to Louisville. The city estimated that if it installed fiber for city use from scratch, it would cost $15 million. With the KentuckyWired offer, the same project would cost just $5.4 million—with half of that amount dedicated to placing fiber nodes in West Louisville, a struggling, de facto segregated area of concentrated poverty, poor health outcomes, and general economic distress.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The public benefits of jumping on the KentuckyWired offer would be substantial: Not only would West Louisville get a chance at better access for its homes and businesses, but the city could install fiber-controlled traffic signals, create better and cheaper connectivity for public-safety agencies, and ship data around inexpensively to improve its operations. In a nutshell, the city would build the infrastructure and lease capacity to private internet-service providers. &quot;We were looking at this as our smart city foundation,&quot; Grace Simrall, Louisville's chief of civic innovation, says. At least half of the new fiber capacity would be reserved for open access leases, to encourage last-mile retail providers to wire homes and businesses. All for just the cost of the fiber lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed to be a no-brainer. “I can't think of a more sensible plan,&quot; Simrall says. &quot;I just didn't think that we were going to face opposition on this. We thought surely people would understand that this was a way for us to leapfrog where we were for a fraction of the cost.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when Simrall and her colleagues went to talk to members of the Louisville Metro Council in May, they found that interest groups, including the cable trade association in Kentucky and something called the Taxpayers Protection Alliance, had been there already. Suddenly, the city's eminently sensible plan was in trouble. &quot;The cable trade association in Kentucky was very vocal about how they thought that this was a waste of taxpayer money and had just spoken to numerous council members on the record about that,&quot; Simrall says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Simrall and the city found out that the Washington, DC-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectingtaxpayers.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Taxpayers Protection Alliance&lt;/a&gt; had been posting frequently on social media opposing Louisville's fiber plan. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/protectaxpayers/status/861702144302489600&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Typical tweet&lt;/a&gt;: “Google suspended its fiber efforts in many cities due to cost - now wants Louisville taxpayers to foot the $5.4M bill.” The Louisville plan had nothing to do with Google.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's when Simrall learned who had joined the forces determined to block Louisville from spending a dime on fiber for the city's use: Charles and David Koch, the brothers backing environment-hostile fossil fuels and funding politicians who dole out goodies to the super-rich. &quot;It's widely known that they [the Taxpayers Protection Alliance] receive a lot of funding from the Koch brothers,&quot; Simrall says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;inset-left-component inset-left-component--article&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;inset-left-component--article__list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;inset-left&quot; class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__post&quot; readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__description&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Susan Crawford&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__title&quot;&gt;San Francisco Just Took a Huge Step Toward Internet Utopia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__post&quot; readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__description&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Susan Crawford&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__title&quot;&gt;These Cities have Brightened their Future with Dark Fiber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__post&quot; readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__description&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Klint Finley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__title&quot;&gt;Want Real Choice in Broadband? Make These 3 Things Happen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The connection between the TPA and the Koch brothers emerged from investigative reporting by &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/graphics/koch&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ProPublica&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediamatters.org/research/2015/07/31/media-disclosure-guide-here-are-the-industry-fu/204708&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt;. This work has revealed that the Taxpayers Protection Alliance is a front advocacy group, part of a network of dark-money organizations supported in part by the Koch brothers. (The funding seems not to come from the Koch family directly but instead is funneled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.energyandpolicy.org/renewable-energy-state-policy-attacks-report-2015/taxpayer-protection-alliance/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;through other Koch-funded groups&lt;/a&gt;.) TPA’s most recent IRS filing shows it received about half a million dollars in contributions in 2016, but the sources of these contributions are blacked out. Tax-exempt organizations are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/charities-non-profits/public-disclosure-and-availability-of-exempt-organizations-returns-and-applications-contributors-identities-not-subject-to-disclosure&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;not required&lt;/a&gt; to disclose the names of their donors publicly. David Williams, TPA’s president, told the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courier-journal.com/story/news/politics/metro-government/2017/06/08/koch-group-among-those-against-citys-5-4-m-broadband-network-plan/379718001/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Louisville Courier-Journal&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year that the group receives funding from “a lot of different sources,&quot; including groups affiliated with the Koch brothers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/charities-non-profits/public-disclosure-and-availability-of-exempt-organizations-returns-and-applications-contributors-identities-not-subject-to-disclosure&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the TPA blog&lt;/a&gt; shows that the organization fights municipal fiber as part of its general anti-government and pro-private-sector activities, claiming that “taxpayer-funded broadband is a waste of money.” This week’s post, not surprisingly, congratulates the FCC on rolling back net neutrality regulations that TPA believes were “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectingtaxpayers.org/blog/a/view/taxpayers-protection-alliance-congratulates-federal-communications-commission-rollback-of-obama-era-regulations&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hurting taxpayers&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That made the Louisville fiber project a battle between those trying to help the city and outside money trying to preserve the status quo. With little time before the council vote in mid-June, and facing the prospect that the city would lose forever the opportunity to participate in KentuckyWired at cost, Simrall and her office swung into action. They patiently explained the economic and operational benefits of the city plan to council members and the public, creating a useful &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/louisville-metro-opi2/kentucky-wired-we-need-your-support-4573225b686a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;infographic&lt;/a&gt; to sum up the story. They urged residents to call council members. Simrall had come from the civic tech community in Louisville, and contacted everyone she knew. &quot;Everybody said, 'This is complete common sense,'&quot; Simrall says. On June 8, Louisville Mayor Greg Fischer &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/louisvillemayor/status/872895310661652481&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Tell your council member to back #KyWired and stop the Kochs from meddling in Louisville's progress.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that month, there were two dramatic public meetings on the city's budget for the fiber project. The first vote went along party lines, with Republicans voting against any city involvement in fiber. Simrall and her team kept fighting, and managed to convince some Republicans that the city plan made a lot of sense—especially the Republicans from districts that have suffered from digital redlining by incumbents. In the end, at the final budget hearing, the council voted unanimously to approve the request. &quot;It was really quite a thrilling thing,&quot; Simrall says.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, the Koch-funded campaign backfired. It helped fire up some council members who might not have understood the importance of city fiber; once they knew the Koch brothers were against it, the city's plan got their attention. &quot;That felt pretty good,&quot; Simrall says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Koch brothers were willing to throw money at opposing an incremental, cheap effort to string fiber alongside an existing state network plan, just imagine what they'll be capable of around more ambitious local efforts. There is a major onslaught looming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simrall doesn't think the Kochs actually care about fiber. &quot;It's all their way of opposing particular municipal or state efforts,&quot; Simrall says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scary thing is that the TPA message can be effective to a public that doesn't understand the importance of fiber and can be easily swayed by claims that internet access should be handled solely by the private sector. The same kinds of Koch-like scare-points were rolled out when the unregulated private sector was solely in charge of electricity 100 years ago. But, as Simrall points out, &quot;At this point, who would go to a city that doesn't have electric utilities? Who would go to a city that doesn't have water, or access to highways? Fiber is that type of infrastructure plan.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t matter to the funders of groups like TPA. No matter how limited the government involvement is, they're going to go after it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 05:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>xbmcuser</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Koch Brothers Are Cities' New Obstacle to Building Broadband</og:title>
<og:description>The Taxpayers Protection Alliance, backed in part by the Koch brothers, tried to kill a municipal fiber-optic project to deliver high-speed internet access in Louisville.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.wired.com/photos/5a3475242db63c66d81116a5/191:100/pass/Koch-Louisville-156763236.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.wired.com/story/koch-brothers-are-cities-new-obstacle-to-building-broadband/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.com/story/koch-brothers-are-cities-new-obstacle-to-building-broadband/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>