<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Gears</title>
<link>https://ciechanow.ski/gears/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ciechanow.ski/gears/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;February 12, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been fascinated by mechanical gears. There is something captivating about the way their teeth come together to create a fluid, unified motion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog post I’d like to look at these simple machines up close. I’ll explain how gears affect the properties of rotational motion and how the shape of their teeth is way more sophisticated than it may initially seem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movement is important in this article so most of the visualizations are animated – you can play and pause them by &lt;span class=&quot;click_word&quot;&gt;clicking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tap_word&quot;&gt;tapping&lt;/span&gt; on the button in their bottom left corner. By default the animations are &lt;span id=&quot;global_animate_on&quot;&gt;enabled, but if you find them distracting, or you want to save power, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://ciechanow.ski/gears/#&quot; class=&quot;link_button&quot; onclick=&quot;global_animate(false);return false;&quot;&gt;globally pause&lt;/a&gt; all animations, just make sure to unpause them as needed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;global_animate_off&quot; class=&quot;hidden&quot;&gt;disabled, but if you’d prefer to have things moving as you read you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://ciechanow.ski/gears/#&quot; class=&quot;link_button&quot; onclick=&quot;global_animate(true);return false;&quot;&gt;globally unpause&lt;/a&gt; them and see all the objects in their rotating glory.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a hot summer day you might have enjoyed a cool breeze from a desk fan. Let’s take a closer look at this device. In the demonstration below you can control the fan’s speed using a slider:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The speed of a rotating fan is a different kind of speed than that of a car – it describes how quickly a fan &lt;em&gt;rotates&lt;/em&gt;. To distinguish that rotating movement from a simple linear motion we use the term &lt;em&gt;angular velocity&lt;/em&gt;. Angular velocity describes how quickly an object rotates relative to some point. For mechanical devices like fans that point often corresponds to the center of a shaft on which the spinning part is mounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angular velocity can be expressed in many units. In physics and math the most popular ones are &lt;em&gt;degrees per second&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;fainter&quot;&gt;(°/s)&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;em&gt;radians per second&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;fainter&quot;&gt;(rad/s)&lt;/span&gt; – they express the change in object’s angle of rotation per unit of time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In engineering it’s more common to use the unit of &lt;em&gt;revolutions per minute&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;rpm&lt;/em&gt; for short. Older spinning hard drives rotated at 5,400 rpm while an internal combustion engine of an idling car may keep running at around 800 rpm. Almost by definition, the second hand of a clock rotates at 1 rpm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of °/s, rad/s, and rpm are equivalent – they’re just one multiplication by a constant factor away from each other. Given the engineering nature of this article I’ll stick to rpm, but I’ll often skip the units completely since they won’t be essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Propeller-like shapes are exciting to look at, but they obscure some basic features of the rotational motion that we’ll explore. Over the next few paragraphs we’ll look at a more basic shape – a disc attached to a shaft. In the demonstration below you can control its angular velocity with a slider:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The small triangular indicator is there to help visualize the current orientation of the disc. I’ve also painted six points on its surface. You may have already noticed that some of those points move more than the others even though the entire disc has the same angular velocity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s investigate what’s going on by controlling the time back and forth with a slider. As the disc rotates the points leave a trace of the path they followed:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At the bottom part of the simulation you can see the flattened arcs of the paths traced by the six points. Notably, as the disc rotates the distances traveled by the points further away from the center are larger than those of the points closer to the center. Coincidentally, the triangular pattern of the flattened out arcs is also a simple way to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cut-the-knot.org/Curriculum/Geometry/RABH.shtml&quot;&gt;derive&lt;/a&gt; the area of a circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All paths are traversed in the same amount of time, but their lengths differ signaling that the points have different &lt;em&gt;velocity&lt;/em&gt;. Notice that we’re talking about a different kind of velocity now. The disc and all the points on it have the same &lt;em&gt;angular&lt;/em&gt; velocity, but different points at different radii have different &lt;em&gt;linear&lt;/em&gt; velocities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the demonstration below you can observe how the arrows, which represent the linear velocities of the six points, change depending on the disc’s angular velocity and the points’ distances from the center:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The instantaneous linear velocity &lt;strong&gt;v&lt;/strong&gt; of a point on a rotating object depends on the distance &lt;strong&gt;r&lt;/strong&gt; to the center of rotation and the angular velocity &lt;strong&gt;ω&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v = ω · r&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A linear velocity of a point rotating around the center of rotation is perpendicular to the direction towards the center. As a side note, observe that while the linear velocity vector constantly changes its &lt;em&gt;direction&lt;/em&gt; due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khanacademy.org/science/physics/centripetal-force-and-gravitation/centripetal-acceleration-tutoria/a/what-is-centripetal-acceleration&quot;&gt;centripetal acceleration&lt;/a&gt;, its &lt;em&gt;magnitude&lt;/em&gt; remains the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we’ve been looking at just a single rotating disc, but let’s try to complicate things a little by adding a second disc to our setup. I’ll place it so that the side surfaces of the discs are pressing against each other. In the demonstration below the &lt;em&gt;driving&lt;/em&gt; yellow disc is powered by some engine, which I’ve indicated using a rotating arrow near the shaft. You can observe what happens to the green disc that isn’t powered by anything:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two discs aren’t perfectly slick, their surfaces have some roughness to them which creates friction when the sides touch. That friction at the contact point between two discs is making them temporarily stick to each other. This causes the right circle to be “dragged” along for the ride. At some point the curvature of the discs pulls the connection apart, but as that happens new points on the surfaces of the discs are coming into contact again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observe how the two discs rotate in different directions – as one turns clockwise the other one rotates counterclockwise. Moreover, due to sticking at the point of contact the velocities of the side surfaces of both discs are the same. All the points on those sides trace the same arcs in the same period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that simple scenario as the driving disc completed a full turn, so did the driven disc. Things become more interesting when the discs have &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; radii. Let’s look at the paths that two points on the surfaces of these discs trace:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Since the linear velocities of the points are the same, the paths end up having the same length. However, this causes the bigger disc to rotate by fewer degrees since its circumference is larger. In this configuration, when a small disc does a full turn the big one does &lt;em&gt;half&lt;/em&gt; a turn. The &lt;em&gt;angular&lt;/em&gt; velocity of the right disc is &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can reach the same conclusion by looking at the velocity of the “sticking” point. The linear velocity &lt;strong&gt;v&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as seen by the &lt;strong&gt;in&lt;/strong&gt;put disc is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt; = ω&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt; · r&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the linear velocity &lt;strong&gt;v&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the &lt;strong&gt;out&lt;/strong&gt;put disc is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt; = ω&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt; · r&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these velocities are the same we can simply equate them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt; · r&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt; = ω&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt; · r&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finally derive that the angular velocity of the output disc is proportional to the angular velocity of the input disc:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The smaller the input disc, the smaller the output angular velocity, and the smaller the output disc, the &lt;em&gt;larger&lt;/em&gt; its angular velocity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the demonstration below the left driving disc always rotates with the same angular velocity, but the angular velocity of the right disc is affected by the ratio of radii of the two wheels:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The speed of the driven green disc can change quite drastically depending on the ratio of the radii. We’ve devised a very simple mechanism that allows us to modify the angular velocity from one shaft to another. However, it’s not all this contraption is doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time you tighten a nut with a wrench try to see how the force needed to move it depends on the point at which you apply the force. The demonstration below shows roughly how big of a force would be needed:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The further away from the nut you press the lesser the force needed and the easier it becomes to tighten the nut. If you don’t have a wrench and a nut handy, you can try to open a door by pressing it very close to the hinge. It’s much harder to do compared to pushing the door near the handle – the capability to turn is much smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This turning effect of a force is called &lt;em&gt;torque&lt;/em&gt; and it depends on both the applied force &lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt; and the length of the lever arm &lt;strong&gt;r&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;r · F&lt;sub&gt;t&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the little &lt;sub&gt;&lt;strong&gt;t&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; subscript next to the force – it represents the &lt;em&gt;tangential&lt;/em&gt; component of the force. In the demonstration below you can control the angle of the applied &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gray&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; force, however, only the &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tangential component that is perpendicular to the arm ends up counting towards the torque:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Notice how the magnitude of torque increases and decreases as the force rotates. When the force starts pushing the wrench in the opposite direction the torque changes sign because it also changes the clockwiseness of the rotation of the wrench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alternative way to look at the tangential component is to find a circle that is tangent to the line of force and use its radius &lt;strong&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;t&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as the basis for the torque calculation:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As such, torque can also be expressed using this form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;t&lt;/sub&gt; · F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both approaches to look at this problem are equivalent as they ultimately end up being described by the same equation in which &lt;strong&gt;α&lt;/strong&gt; represents the angle between the force and the arm:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;r · F · sin(α)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far we’ve discussed how a force acting on a perpendicular arm creates a torque. However, if a torque is already present on a shaft, e.g. exerted by an engine or a crank, then that torque will apply a force at a distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the demonstration below a disc has a spool attached to it on which a rope is wound. The disc has a constant input torque, but as the radius of the spool changes so does the force with which the rope is pulled:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When two friction discs are working together the driving one drags the driven one with some force, so let’s see how the torque is affected by the interaction between two discs. A torque &lt;strong&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on an &lt;strong&gt;in&lt;/strong&gt;put shaft causes the disc to exert force &lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt; at a distance &lt;strong&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That very same force acts on the &lt;strong&gt;out&lt;/strong&gt;put disc at a distance &lt;strong&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can equate the two:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finally derive that the output torque is proportional to the input torque:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s compare the equation for the output torque with the equation for the output angular velocity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that the ratios of the radii are inverted. We can now see how the torque and angular velocity are affected in an actual disc setup. In the simulation below you can control the ratio of radii of the two discs. The right disc has a spool with a rope attached to it. Since the spool is attached to the disc the torque and the angular velocity are transferred directly to it:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Notice that when the yellow &lt;em&gt;driving&lt;/em&gt; gear gets smaller the torque on the output disc increases and as a result so does the force with which the rope is pulled. On the other hand, as the &lt;em&gt;driven&lt;/em&gt; gear gets smaller its angular velocity increases and so does the linear velocity of the rope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using two discs of different radii we can use a single engine to drive the input and have vastly different outcomes at the output. Depending on the use case we may want to sacrifice some speed to be able to pull the rope with a lot of force, or prioritize the output velocity at the cost of a weaker pulling capability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The friction discs systems we played with so far work perfectly in idealized scenarios, but in practice they’re quite flawed. As soon as the two discs are not in a close contact due to vibration, wear on the touching surfaces, or even manufacturing imprecision, they’ll start slipping. The assumption about the sticking contact point breaks and the mechanism no longer transfers angular velocity and torque as needed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This problem can be solved by ensuring that the driving wheel physically &lt;em&gt;pushes&lt;/em&gt; the driven wheel. This is where gears come in. Because the teeth of two &lt;em&gt;meshed&lt;/em&gt; gears are interlocked with each other, the driving gear ends up pressing directly against the driven gear:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at an example of two gears of different sizes meshing with each other. Naturally, for two gears to be compatible their teeth have to be of the same size – the distance between two subsequent teeth known as &lt;em&gt;circular pitch&lt;/em&gt; has to be the same. In the demonstration below each gear has its circular pitches marked with short arc segments. Notice down below that those arcs flattened out have the same length:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A full circular set of colorful segments forms a so-called &lt;em&gt;pitch circle&lt;/em&gt;. A pitch circle represents an idealized circle that is in contact with the other gear’s pitch circle. They both correspond to the simple friction-based disc systems we’ve already discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pitch circles let us look past the complexity of the interlocking gears by reducing their form to the familiar teethless discs on which we can used the radius-based equations. However, using the size of gear’s radii or diameter is cumbersome, especially since the pitch circle isn’t visible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, it’s more common to refer to gears by using their number of teeth &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt; and the size of those teeth. In the United States the term &lt;em&gt;diametral pitch&lt;/em&gt; is used to define the teeth size, it is obtained by dividing the number of teeth &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt; by the diameter &lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt; of the pitch circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;diametral pitch&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other countries a similar, but inverted ratio called &lt;em&gt;module&lt;/em&gt; is used instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;module&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;d&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both diametral pitch and module effectively define the &lt;em&gt;size&lt;/em&gt; of the teeth. Since those parameters in the two matching gears have to be the same we can equate them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;d&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;d&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just a simple transformation we can derive that the ratio of the number of teeth is equivalent to the ratio of the diameters, or the radii, of the pitch circles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;d&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;d&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result we can talk about a transmission system using number of teeth on the meshing gears instead of specifying their diameters or radii:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the demonstration below you can adjust the &lt;em&gt;diametral pitch&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. the size of the teeth of the two meshed gears to see that the constant ratio of the numbers of teeth indeed maintains the constant ratio of angular velocity:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So far I’ve conveniently avoided describing the details of the shape of the teeth of a gear, but it’s actually one of the most important aspects of a gear system. Before we take a closer look at the profile of a tooth we have to discuss the concept of a &lt;em&gt;tangent&lt;/em&gt; to a curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tangent&quot;&gt;tangent&lt;/a&gt; can be described in a few different ways, but one of the most intuitive ones is to imagine three beads sliding on said curve. The red bead symbolizes a point of the curve at which we want to find the tangency. The two blue beads neighbor the red bead at its sides:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the blue beads get closer and closer to the red bead, the line spanned through their centers approaches the line of tangency at that red point. The tangent line shows the local “straight ahead” direction on the curve. In the limit, the imaginary beads completely overlap and the tangent locally touches the curve at just a &lt;em&gt;single&lt;/em&gt; point which explains the origin of the word – in Latin &lt;em&gt;tangere&lt;/em&gt; means “to touch”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A closely related concept to a tangent line is a &lt;em&gt;normal&lt;/em&gt; line which is perpendicular to the tangent at that point. In the demonstration below you can see the &lt;span class=&quot;dotted&quot;&gt;dotted&lt;/span&gt; normal and the &lt;span&gt;solid&lt;/span&gt; tangent lines of two curves:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When two curves &lt;a href=&quot;https://ciechanow.ski/gears/#&quot; class=&quot;link_button&quot; onclick=&quot;gears_curve_touch();return false;&quot;&gt;touch&lt;/a&gt; at a single point their lines of tangency, and thus normals, are the same. If it wasn’t the case then a line of tangency of one curve would intersect the other curve in more than one place and the shapes would be overlapping instead of meeting at just a singular location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This observation is important when we consider the point of contact between two teeth. Let’s see it up close:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;black&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; point represents a &lt;em&gt;pitch point&lt;/em&gt; – a point at which the two pitch circles of the gears touch. The &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; point represents the point of contact between two teeth – notice how it moves across the surfaces of the teeth. The &lt;span&gt;solid&lt;/span&gt; line shows the tangent line of the outline of two teeth at the point of contact and the normal is represented by the &lt;span class=&quot;dotted&quot;&gt;dotted&lt;/span&gt; line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only useful component of the contact force between the two gears will be acting in the direction of that normal – that’s the pushing force which I depicted using the black arrow. You may wonder if the fact that the direction of the force in the previous demonstration is tilted matters. After all, it may affect the transfer of torque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at this problem in a little more detail. Since transmission features of gears are ultimately decided by their pitch circles we can simplify the situation by analyzing the effective pitch circles of the teeth-less discs when the force changes direction:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When we discussed torque we already observed that when the force changes direction the radius of the circle tangent to that force also changes. However, the radii of &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; discs are scaled by the same factor of &lt;strong&gt;cos(α)&lt;/strong&gt;, where &lt;strong&gt;α&lt;/strong&gt; is the &lt;em&gt;pressure angle&lt;/em&gt; controlled by the slider in the simulation above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;out&lt;/sub&gt;·cos(α)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;in&lt;/sub&gt;·cos(α)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In effect, the cosine factors cancel out and the constant ratio of torque transfer is maintained. In the example above the line of force always passed through the black pitch point in the center. In the simulation below you can witness what happens to the effective circle radii when the line of force does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; go through the pitch point:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As you can see, if the acting force doesn’t lie on the line through the pitch point one of the circles effectively grows while the other one effectively shrinks. The constant torque ratio is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; maintained since the ratio of the effective radii also changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very similar line of thinking can be done for the rate of change of angular velocity. A point of contact between two gears has some linear velocity related to the rotational motion of the discs. Since the two teeth remain in contact, the components of the velocities in the direction of the normal have to be the same, otherwise the teeth would separate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here the reasoning is equivalent to our analysis of forces – if you’re interested you can follow a &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng-resources.uncc.edu/unccengkit/mechanical/gears/law-of-gearing/&quot;&gt;more rigorous derivation&lt;/a&gt; that I found. The final conclusions for both angular velocity and torque are the same and our discussion of the surface normals helps us define the &lt;em&gt;law of gearing&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure a constant ratio of angular velocity and torque modification the surface normals of teeth at all points of contact have to go through the pitch point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as that condition is met, the tooth profiles can be arbitrary. However, in practice a very specific curve is used to define the shape of a gear’s teeth. Let’s see how it’s created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tooth shape we’re looking for should ensure that its normal at any point of meshing will point at the pitch point. We could let the normal change direction over time, but to make things simpler we can just define a single line on which all normals will lie. We could look at this setup through equations, but thankfully a much more pleasant approach exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll take two discs, wrap a string around them, and we’ll nail that string to the discs’ sides so that it follows their movement. Let’s see what happens when we put a little perpendicular &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; marker on that string and start unwinding it from one disc and winding it onto another. I attached a piece of paper to the underside of the yellow disc so that we can see the trail left by the marker as the disc rotates:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The straight part of the string represents the normal – that’s the direction in which the pushing force will act. For the force to act in this way the tangent of the curve should be &lt;em&gt;perpendicular&lt;/em&gt; to the string at all times. However, that’s exactly what the red marker does – at every point of the curve it is perpendicular to the string, and thus it’s perpendicular to the normal. The trail left on the paper is precisely the curve we were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can look at this same situation from a point of view of the single disc, by unwinding a string with a marker from its surface:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The shape we’ve created is called an &lt;em&gt;involute&lt;/em&gt;. At every point of the curve its normal is tangent to the generating circle precisely because the taut string &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; that normal. If the teeth of two matching gears have an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Involute&quot;&gt;involute&lt;/a&gt; profile they meet the requirements of the law of gearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shape of involute of the teeth in a gear is generated by the gear’s &lt;em&gt;base circle&lt;/em&gt;, which is &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt; than its pitch circle. The smaller size of the base circle results in a non-zero pressure angle, the most commonly used value is 20°. As we’ve seen this is perfectly fine since due to the shape of the involute the force is directed through the pitch point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the demonstration below you can see how a shape of teeth of an &lt;em&gt;idealized&lt;/em&gt; gear is formed:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The shape starts at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ciechanow.ski/gears/#&quot; class=&quot;link_button&quot; onclick=&quot;gears_dedendum();return false;&quot;&gt;dedendum circle&lt;/a&gt; which defines the bottom outline of the teeth roots. From here the teeth grow radially in &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;blue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; straight lines – these areas of the teeth are never in contact with the teeth of the other gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ciechanow.ski/gears/#&quot; class=&quot;link_button&quot; onclick=&quot;gears_base();return false;&quot;&gt;base circle&lt;/a&gt; is reached, the &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; involute shape begins – from every side an imaginary string is being unwound. The magic marker at the end of the string passes through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ciechanow.ski/gears/#&quot; class=&quot;link_button&quot; onclick=&quot;gears_pitch();return false;&quot;&gt;pitch circle&lt;/a&gt;, which corresponds to the idealized friction disc, only to end at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ciechanow.ski/gears/#&quot; class=&quot;link_button&quot; onclick=&quot;gears_addendum();return false;&quot;&gt;addendum circle&lt;/a&gt; which defines the outline of the teeth tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, the bottom part of the tooth would join the dedendum circle with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fillet_(mechanics)&quot;&gt;fillet&lt;/a&gt; to avoid stress concentration and its shape would be heavily influenced by the way a gear is manufactured. The widths of the teeth would also be slightly narrower to allow some &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Backlash_(engineering)&quot;&gt;backlash&lt;/a&gt; to prevent jamming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s interesting about involute gears is that even for the same size of teeth, as measured by diametral pitch or module, the shape of a tooth of a given gear strongly depends on the gear’s radius. In the simulation below the &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;green&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; line shows the pitch circle, the &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; line shows the base circle of the involute, and the slider controls the radius of the gear:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Two matching involute gears with different number of teeth, and thus different radii, will have slightly &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; shapes of teeth. In the limit, when the radius of a gear is infinite, the involute becomes a straight line. A segment of a gear with infinite radius is called a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rack_and_pinion&quot;&gt;rack&lt;/a&gt;. That linear gear is commonly found in a steering mechanism of a car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The involute has another practical property – it maintains the constant transmission ratio even when pitch circles of the two gears aren’t in perfect positions. This allows for some inaccuracies in the placement of the two shafts driving the gears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to many useful properties the involute is the most commonly used tooth profile, however, some applications make use of non-involute gears. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tec-science.com/mechanical-power-transmission/cycloidal-gear/meshing-of-cycloidal-gears/&quot;&gt;cycloidal&lt;/a&gt; gears are used in clocks and watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see what happens when we add a third gear to the system:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Firstly, notice that introduction of the third gear has reversed the direction of the output shaft – it now rotates in the same direction as the first. Let’s calculate how the second blue gear has affected the angular velocity of the third green gear. We can express the final angular velocity of the third gear as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also know that the angular velocity of the second gear depends on the first one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The substitution yields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When three gears are connected like that the number of teeth of the middle, so-called &lt;em&gt;idler&lt;/em&gt; gear, doesn’t matter for the angular velocity and torque of the output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can create a multi gear system in another way. In the demonstration below the red and blue gears are fixed together and they both rotate with their shaft at the same angular velocity:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Let’s peek at the equations of the pairs of meshing gears. The fourth green gear is driven by the third red gear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the second blue gear is driven by the first yellow gear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, however, angular velocities of the third and second gear are the same:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; = ω&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we end up with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;ω&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar logic applies for equations of torque transfer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac_lhs&quot;&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span class=&quot;gear_frac&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_symbol&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;gear_div_bottom&quot;&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this configuration all four gears participate in the final ratio of adjustment. A multi stage transmission enables a significant reduction in size of the assembly – a single stage setup with 4:1 reduction like in the example above would have to be both wider &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; much taller. Additionally, with multiple stages a machine can change the gearing ratios relatively easily like it happens in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wCu9W9xNwtI&quot;&gt;manual transmission gearbox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you never plan to design a functional set of gears, it may be worth knowing how &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to design one. In the demonstration below you can see what happens when the three gears are meshing with each other – the mechanism gets jammed:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;By moving the blue gear slightly to the left we can see that the yellow gear wants to rotate it clockwise, however, by placing the blue gear to the right we can see that the green gear wants to rotate it counterclockwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the “three jammed gears” pitfall is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lockhaven.edu/~dsimanek/whoops.htm#gears&quot;&gt;quite common&lt;/a&gt; in graphics design. However, if you try really hard and have an access to a 3D printer, you may actually be able to pull off at least &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Mf0JpTI_gg&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; version&lt;/a&gt; of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC5NO8MgTQKHAWXp6z8Xl7yQ&quot;&gt;This Old Tony&lt;/a&gt; is an amazing YouTube channel devoted to machining and metal working. Tony’s video on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qVN2jrn4Kuo&quot;&gt;gears and gear cutting&lt;/a&gt; is informative &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; entertaining at the same time. His quirky sense of humor certainly adds a great value to the thorough explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For joyful torture tests of LEGO parts I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UClsFdM0HzTdF1JYoraQ0aUw&quot;&gt;Brick Experiment Channel&lt;/a&gt;. The video collection showcases capabilities of plastic LEGO gears to increase &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s3BsDF6UjCQ&quot;&gt;angular velocity&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pvE83NfbZ8g&quot;&gt;torque&lt;/a&gt; to ridiculous levels – the author managed to coerce a basic battery-powered LEGO motor to lift 100 kg of weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post I’ve only talked about the simple &lt;em&gt;spur&lt;/em&gt; gears. As usual, you can read about some other &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gear#Types&quot;&gt;kinds of gears&lt;/a&gt; on Wikipedia. The entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gear&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; is quite thorough and includes this &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gear#/media/File:Interactive_gears_in_the_hind_legs_of_Issus_coleoptratus_from_Cambridge_gears-3.jpg&quot;&gt;wonderful image&lt;/a&gt; of natural gears found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Issus_coleoptratus&quot;&gt;some planthoppers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tec-science.com/category/mechanical-power-transmission/&quot;&gt;tec-science&lt;/a&gt; is a great resource on various engineering concepts. The series on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tec-science.com/category/mechanical-power-transmission/&quot;&gt;mechanical power transmission&lt;/a&gt; dives deeper into the topics I’ve discussed here. I particularly like that the site’s articles often include high quality &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tec-science.com/mechanical-power-transmission/gear-types/cylindrical-gears/&quot;&gt;3D renders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The considerations behind real world gears are much more complicated than what I’ve presented. The physical world is messy – the gears aren’t perfectly rigid, they thermally expand during operation, and their surfaces wear over time. All of these factors have to be accounted for in the domain of engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all that, under the murky waters of physical reality, the idealized mathematical principles of gears are still there. I’ve hopefully shown you that gears aren’t just some discs with teeth – there is a lot of mathematical ingenuity in their design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 17:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>robert-boehnke</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ciechanow.ski/gears/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Decentralized Naming and Certificate Authority</title>
<link>https://handshake.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://handshake.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;INTERNET NAME TRANSFERS USING COINS TO PREVENT SYBIL ATTACKS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Handshake is a piece of software (and a loose consensus on agreement of the software itself). This software's primary function is for people to come to agreement on names and cryptographic keys authorized to represent that names in a decentralized way. To do this in a decentralized way, we need to prevent a single party from claiming all the names. Therefore, a unit of account is needed to prevent that single party from claiming all names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Handshake uses a coin system for name registration. The Handshake coin (HNS) is the mechanism by which participants transfer, register, and update internet names. The community will be able to initiate auctions and place bids for top-level domains using HNS or trade their HNS as they see fit, with differing value per name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, Handshake allocates the majority of its initial coins towards the FOSS community with absolutely no obligation attached, as it is this community most relevant with decentralized software and tools. The goal of the initial design was to account for all possible stakeholders. &lt;a href=&quot;https://handshake.org/grant-sponsors&quot;&gt;More info&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Handshake's incentive design assumptions relies upon Metcalfe's Law (Beckstrom's Law, etc.). While Bitcoin's value is derived from it being a costly store of value, Handshake's value is derived from its network of users. Metcalfe's Law asserts that an increase in userbase increases the value of the network (sub)exponentially. This means that allocation of value to potential developers and users of this system be a benefit to everyone, with network effect derived benefiting all users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 17:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>LinuxBender</dc:creator>
<og:title>Handshake</og:title>
<og:description>Decentralized certificate authority and naming</og:description>
<og:url>https://handshake.org</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.handshake.org/images/landing/logo-dark.svg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://handshake.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GitHub CLI is now in beta</title>
<link>https://github.blog/2020-02-12-supercharge-your-command-line-experience-github-cli-is-now-in-beta/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.blog/2020-02-12-supercharge-your-command-line-experience-github-cli-is-now-in-beta/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We’re introducing an easier and more seamless way to work with GitHub from the command line—&lt;a href=&quot;https://cli.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub CLI&lt;/a&gt;, now in beta. Millions of developers rely on GitHub to make building software more fun and collaborative, and &lt;code&gt;gh&lt;/code&gt; brings the GitHub experience right to your terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install GitHub CLI today on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cli/cli#installation-and-upgrading&quot;&gt;macOS, Windows, and Linux&lt;/a&gt;, and there’s more to come as we iterate on your feedback from the beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-you-use-github-cli&quot;&gt;How can you use GitHub CLI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started with issues and pull requests because many developers use them every day. Check out a few examples of how &lt;code&gt;gh&lt;/code&gt; can improve your experience when contributing to an open source project and learn more from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cli.github.com/manual/&quot;&gt;manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;filter-lists-to-your-needs&quot;&gt;Filter lists to your needs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find an open source project you want to contribute to and clone the repository. And then, to see where maintainers want community contributions, use &lt;code&gt;gh&lt;/code&gt; to filter the issues to only show those with help wanted labels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/user-images.githubusercontent.com/10404068/74261509-3677d700-4cb0-11ea-9b20-6dbda4a15b04.png?ssl=1&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;quickly-view-the-details&quot;&gt;Quickly view the details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find an issue describing a bug that seems like something you can fix, and use &lt;code&gt;gh&lt;/code&gt; to quickly open it in the browser to get all the details you need to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/user-images.githubusercontent.com/10404068/74261507-3677d700-4cb0-11ea-9871-d4fe5ff797ba.png?ssl=1&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-a-pull-request&quot;&gt;Create a pull request&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a branch, make several commits to fix the bug described in the issue, and use &lt;code&gt;gh&lt;/code&gt; to create a pull request to share your contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/user-images.githubusercontent.com/10404068/74261506-35df4080-4cb0-11ea-9285-c41583009e6c.png?ssl=1&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using GitHub CLI to create pull requests, it also automatically creates a fork when you don’t already have one, and it pushes your branch and creates your pull request to get your change merged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;view-the-status-of-your-work&quot;&gt;View the status of your work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a quick snapshot the next morning of what happened since you created your pull request. &lt;code&gt;gh&lt;/code&gt; shows the review and check status of your pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/user-images.githubusercontent.com/10404068/74261502-34ae1380-4cb0-11ea-8baf-cf8248f1b222.png?ssl=1&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;easily-check-out-pull-requests&quot;&gt;Easily check out pull requests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the maintainers reviewed your pull request and requested changes. You probably switched branches since then, so use &lt;code&gt;gh&lt;/code&gt; to checkout the pull request branch. We never remember the right commands either!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/user-images.githubusercontent.com/10404068/74261497-32e45000-4cb0-11ea-9218-3d6a5b0fd892.png?ssl=1&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make the changes, push them, and soon enough the pull request is merged—congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;help-shape-github-cli&quot;&gt;Help shape GitHub CLI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you’ll love the foundation we’ve built with pull requests and issues. And we’re even more excited about the future as we explore what it looks like to build a truly delightful experience with GitHub on the command line. As GitHub CLI continues to make it even more seamless to contribute to projects on GitHub, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_RQBNCOU0RM&quot;&gt;sky’s the limit&lt;/a&gt; on what we can achieve together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can’t wait to hear about your experience with GitHub CLI, and we’d love your feedback. Create an issue in our &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/cli/cli&quot;&gt;open source repository&lt;/a&gt; or provide feedback in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/umxd3h31c7aMQFKG7&quot;&gt;google form&lt;/a&gt;. What commands feel like you can’t live without them? What’s clunky or missing? Let us know so we can make GitHub CLI even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cli.github.com&quot;&gt;Learn more about GitHub CLI beta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 17:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>twapi</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Supercharge your command line experience: GitHub CLI is now in beta - The GitHub Blog</og:title>
<og:description>We want your feedback about GitHub’s new command line tool that makes it easier to work with GitHub and reduce friction for many of your common workflows.</og:description>
<og:url>https://github.blog/2020-02-12-supercharge-your-command-line-experience-github-cli-is-now-in-beta/</og:url>
<og:image>https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/social-card.png?fit=1200%2C630</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.blog/2020-02-12-supercharge-your-command-line-experience-github-cli-is-now-in-beta/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Simple Analytics hits $4k MRR and shares its numbers</title>
<link>https://simpleanalytics.com/open</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://simpleanalytics.com/open</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;42.407480314961&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple Analytics is an Open Startup™, which means it operates fully transparent and shares its metrics, including revenue, costs, users and &lt;a href=&quot;https://simpleanalytics.com/simpleanalytics.com&quot;&gt;traffic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Profit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the start we shared our current MRR. Since October 2019 we added a more detailed monthly report on our expenses as on our revenue. This gives you a better understanding of our business. While MRR is great for having a fast comparable measurement, we found our detailed profit chart to be a better match for our long term vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;52.797193877551&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Current monthly recurring revenue (MRR)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-0&quot;&gt;~&lt;strong&gt;$4k&lt;/strong&gt; with 322 paying customers (ARR $48.6k)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-help text-small mt-0&quot;&gt;Last updated 6 minutes ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details readability=&quot;13.85079928952&quot;&gt;What is MRR?
&lt;p&gt;At any given time, you can calculate MRR by summing the monthly-normalized amounts of &lt;strong&gt;all active subscriptions&lt;/strong&gt; at that time. For example, an annual subscription for $1,200 only counts $100 towards your MRR. Things get more complicated once you consider discounts, tax, trials, delinquency, cancellations, and metered billing. The reason we've chosen active subscriptions (rather than summing your invoices, for instance) is because MRR is a forward looking metric that is distinct from the immediate cash flow you're about to receive &lt;span class=&quot;text-help text-small&quot;&gt;(source &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.stripe.com/questions/billing-analytics#how-do-you-calculate-mrr&quot;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;details readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;Node.js code to calculate MRR from Stripe
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;hljs hljs-block hljs-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; stripe = &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-built_in&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'stripe'&lt;/span&gt;)(process.env.STRIPE_SECRET)
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; amount = &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;await&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; subscription &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; stripe.subscriptions.list({ &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-attr&quot;&gt;status&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'active'&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-attr&quot;&gt;limit&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt; })) {
  &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; { plan, discount } = subscription
  &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (discount) {
    &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; { duration, amount_off } = discount.coupon
    &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (duration === &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'forever'&lt;/span&gt;) amount -= amount_off
  }
  &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (plan.interval === &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'year'&lt;/span&gt;) amount += (plan.amount / &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;)
  &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (plan.interval === &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'month'&lt;/span&gt;) amount += plan.amount
}
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; mrr = amount / &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-number&quot;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-built_in&quot;&gt;console.log&lt;/span&gt;(mrr)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Page views&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is an analytics company if they don't show their page views. We calculate all page views from all our customers and show this in the graph below. If you scroll down you will also see a graph with our own page views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Customers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total of page views of all our customers combined since July 18th, 2019. They had 16M page views in the last 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32.338345864662&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Page views of simpleanalytics.com&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our own website has &lt;span id=&quot;pageviews&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt; page views in the last month. &lt;a href=&quot;https://simpleanalytics.com/simpleanalytics.com&quot;&gt;See our stats&lt;/a&gt; in our public dashboard. As a customer you're able to make your dashboard public as well. Or you can share it with others via email access without making it public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 15:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AdriaanvRossum</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://simpleanalytics.com/open</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>US says it can prove Huawei has backdoor access to mobile-phone networks</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/02/us-gave-allies-evidence-that-huawei-can-snoop-on-phone-networks-wsj-says/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/02/us-gave-allies-evidence-that-huawei-can-snoop-on-phone-networks-wsj-says/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/huawei-800x533.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Giant Huawei logo onstage.&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; class=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;138 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/02/us-gave-allies-evidence-that-huawei-can-snoop-on-phone-networks-wsj-says/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;138 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/02/us-gave-allies-evidence-that-huawei-can-snoop-on-phone-networks-wsj-says/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;220&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 138 posters participating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;US officials say they have evidence that Huawei has backdoor access to mobile-phone networks around the world, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-officials-say-huawei-can-covertly-access-telecom-networks-11581452256&quot;&gt;according to a Wall Street Journal article&lt;/a&gt; published today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have evidence that Huawei has the capability secretly to access sensitive and personal information in systems it maintains and sells around the world,&quot; US National Security Adviser Robert O'Brien told the Journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States has long claimed that Huawei can secretly access networks through the networking gear it sells to telcos, but the goverment previously &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-believes-it-doesnt-need-to-show-proof-huawei-is-a-spy-threat-11548288297&quot;&gt;argued&lt;/a&gt; that it doesn't need to show any proof. US officials still are not providing such evidence publicly but have begun sharing their intelligence with other countries, the Journal report said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Journal wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US kept the intelligence highly classified until late last year, when American officials provided details to allies including the UK and Germany, according to officials from the three countries. That was a tactical turnabout by the US, which in the past had argued that it didn't need to produce hard evidence of the threat it says Huawei poses to nations' security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US has been sharing this evidence at the same time the Trump administration &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-germany-usa-huawei/merkels-conservatives-set-to-stop-short-of-huawei-5g-ban-in-germany-idUSKBN205146&quot;&gt;tries&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-britain-usa-huawei-trump/trump-apoplectic-with-uks-johnson-over-huawei-decision-ft-idUSKBN2002R2&quot;&gt;convince allies&lt;/a&gt; to get Huawei gear out of their networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US officials said they have been aware of Huawei's backdoor access &quot;since observing it in 2009 in early 4G equipment,&quot; the Journal wrote. However, the US officials quoted by the Journal &quot;declined to say whether the US has observed Huawei using this access.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Backdoors designed for law enforcement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telecom-equipment makers who sell products to carriers &quot;are required by law to build into their hardware ways for authorities to access the networks for lawful purposes,&quot; but they &quot;are also required to build equipment in such a way that the manufacturer can't get access without the consent of the network operator,&quot; the Journal wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US officials say that Huawei has violated these laws, which are enforced in multiple countries, the Journal wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US officials say Huawei has built equipment that secretly preserves the manufacturer's ability to access networks through these interfaces without the carriers' knowledge. The officials didn't provide details of where they believe Huawei is able [to] access networks. Other manufacturers don't have the same ability, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One US official told the Journal that &quot;Huawei does not disclose this covert access to its local customers, or the host nation national-security agencies.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Huawei says it’s not spying&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei disputed the latest allegations, as it has done in the past, saying it &quot;has never and will never do anything that would compromise or endanger the security of networks and data of its clients.&quot; Huawei also said that the United States made its latest accusations &quot;without providing any kind of concrete evidence.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;No Huawei employee is allowed to access the network without an explicit approval from the network operator,&quot; a Huawei official said, according to the Journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US government has been moving to reduce the amount of Huawei and ZTE equipment in telecom networks. The Federal Communications Commission &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/11/fcc-bans-huawei-and-zte-gear-in-us-funded-broadband-projects/&quot;&gt;voted unanimously&lt;/a&gt; in November to ban Huawei and ZTE gear in projects paid for by the FCC's Universal Service Fund (USF). FCC Chairman Ajit Pai said at the time that Huawei and ZTE &quot;have close ties to China's Communist government and military apparatus&quot; and &quot;are subject to Chinese laws broadly obligating them to cooperate with any request from the country's intelligence services and to keep those requests secret.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ban is expected to hit small carriers the hardest, as Huawei has appealed to small network operators by selling low-cost gear. By contrast, big telcos like AT&amp;amp;T &quot;have long steered clear of Huawei,&quot; a March 2018 Wall Street Journal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/caught-between-two-superpowers-the-small-town-cable-guy-1522152000&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; said.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 15:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ssully</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/02/us-gave-allies-evidence-that-huawei-can-snoop-on-phone-networks-wsj-says/</og:url>
<og:title>US says it can prove Huawei has backdoor access to mobile-phone networks</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/huawei-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>US hasn't made evidence public but reportedly shared it with UK and Germany.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/02/us-gave-allies-evidence-that-huawei-can-snoop-on-phone-networks-wsj-says/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SoundCloud raises $75M from SiriusXM</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/11/music-streaming-pioneer-soundcloud-raises-75m-from-pandora-owner-siriusxm</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/11/music-streaming-pioneer-soundcloud-raises-75m-from-pandora-owner-siriusxm</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://soundcloud.com&quot;&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;, the music streaming company that has been described as the “YouTube of audio” because of its profusion of user-generated content, has some big, strategic investment news today. The company has &lt;a href=&quot;https://press.soundcloud.com/186276-soundcloud-announces-75-million-investment-from-sirius-xm-holdings-inc&quot;&gt;raised $75 million in funding&lt;/a&gt; from satellite radio giant SiriusXM, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/24/siriusxm-to-acquire-pandora-for-3-5-billion/&quot;&gt;owner&lt;/a&gt; of streaming giant &lt;a href=&quot;http://pandora.com&quot;&gt;Pandora&lt;/a&gt;, which has an &lt;a href=&quot;https://press.soundcloud.com/168977-soundcloud-selects-pandora-as-ad-sales-partner-in-the-u-s&quot;&gt;ad partnership with SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funding will be used towards product development and launching new services, the companies said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re asking what the valuation is with this round and will update when and if we hear more. According to PitchBook, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/soundcloud&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;soundcloud&quot;&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt; was last &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/52923-70/company/profile&quot;&gt;valued at $500 million&lt;/a&gt; back in 2017. SiriusXM describes the deal as a minority investment that is related to the ad partnership in which Pandora resells SoundCloud’s inventory on its programmatic platform. Together the two serve an audience of 100 million unique listeners in the US, the company said, and SoundCloud hit a forward revenue run-rate of $200 million for the first time in the fourth quarter of 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deal with SiriusXM is a positive development for SoundCloud and could represent a reversal of fortunes for the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally founded in Berlin in 2007 — one of the early movers in music streaming startups that also saw the rise of Spotify — SoundCloud has seen some significant ups and downs in its life. Reportedly once an acquisition target for &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2014/05/19/twitter-soundcloud/&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and later &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/08/spotify-soundcloud-deal-dead/&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, the company never quite converted those talks into deals, in part because of the asking price and the overhang of licensing issues and related business models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, as an independent startup — and despite its surge of viral popularity and obvious street cred with a long roster of creatives using the platform to try out new things and send their songs and other sound-based work into the world — the SoundCloud of yesterday never really managed to surmount the licensing and larger monetisation issues that all streaming companies face, despite raising a hefty $404 million in funding before today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close to running out of money at one point, it &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/06/soundcloud-the-youtube-for-audio-cuts-173-jobs-closes-san-francisco-london-offices/&quot;&gt;restructured, laying people off&lt;/a&gt;, with one founder, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/08/11/soundcloud-saved/&quot;&gt;Alex Ljung&lt;/a&gt;, stepping down as CEO as it raised emergency funding (he is still chairman), and the other co-founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/24/soundcloud-co-founder-and-chief-product-officer-eric-wahlforss-is-leaving/&quot;&gt;Eric Wahlforss&lt;/a&gt; leaving last year. It’s been a much quieter business in recent years as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even as it has laid low, it has continued to grow, and this deal is evidence that it’s definitely not done for yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“SoundCloud’s three consecutive years of strong financial performance directly reflect the success of our creator-led growth strategy,” said Kerry Trainor, current CEO of SoundCloud, in a statement. “We have an exciting roadmap focused on deepening the connections between creators and listeners that fuel creator discovery, career growth and the evolution of music culture on SoundCloud. We’ve built a great relationship with SiriusXM through our highly successful Pandora ad sales agreement, and their investment gives us added capital flexibility to accelerate our vision and take advantage of strategic opportunities as they arise.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a tempting thought to wonder if this could convert into an acquisition of SoundCloud by SiriusXM. Indeed, it does provide a complement to Pandora and potentially fills a gap both for international audience — over 200 million tracks from 25 million creators with listeners in 190 countries — and also more original content. Those who have used the platform to debut original music include Billie Eilish, Post Malone, Bad Bunny, Khalid and Lil Tecca.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“SoundCloud’s unique platform serves a vital role in today’s music ecosystem where new artists are discovered and build their fan base, and established artists experiment and connect directly with their fans in highly effective ways,” said Jim Meyer, Chief Executive Officer of SiriusXM, in a statement. “We admire SoundCloud’s loyal and growing audience, its offering for creators, and its reputation and popularity in global music communities. We believe this is another opportunity to continue creating value for SiriusXM stockholders by investing in expanding digital audio platforms.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No word on any exits in today’s announcement, of course, but what we can see is that SoundCloud has bought more time, and has more strategic buy-in now, for its future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 12:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>theomega</dc:creator>
<og:title>Music streaming pioneer SoundCloud raises $75M from Pandora owner SiriusXM – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>SoundCloud, the music streaming company that has been described as the “YouTube of audio” because of its profusion of user-generated content, has some big, strategic investment news today. The company has raised $75 million in funding from satellite radio giant SiriusXM, owner of stream…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/soundcloud.jpg?w=750</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2020/02/11/music-streaming-pioneer-soundcloud-raises-75m-from-pandora-owner-siriusxm/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/11/music-streaming-pioneer-soundcloud-raises-75m-from-pandora-owner-siriusxm/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>No person who was born blind has ever been diagnosed with schizophrenia</title>
<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/939qbz/people-born-blind-are-mysteriously-protected-from-schizophrenia</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/939qbz/people-born-blind-are-mysteriously-protected-from-schizophrenia</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;article__text--dropcap&quot;&gt;It was something Tom Pollak had heard whispers about—an odd factoid, referred to now and again, usually with bewilderment: No person who was born blind has ever been diagnosed with schizophrenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past 60-some years, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00624/full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;scientists&lt;/a&gt; around the world have been writing about this mystery. They've analyzed past studies, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/030698778090119X?via%3Dihub&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;combed the wards&lt;/a&gt; of psychiatric hospitals, and looked through agencies that treat blind people, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/behavioral-and-brain-sciences/article/no-blind-schizophrenics-are-nmdareceptor-dynamics-involved/82ECC286052AC80FAA4215F103817378&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;trying to find&lt;/a&gt; a case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time goes on, larger data sets have emerged: In 2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0920996418304055#!&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a study&lt;/a&gt; led by a researcher named Vera Morgan at the University of Western Australia looked at nearly half a million children born between 1980 and 2001 and strengthened this negative association. Pollak, a psychiatrist and researcher at King's College London, remembered checking in the mental health facility where he works after learning about it; he too was unable to find a single patient with congenital blindness who had schizophrenia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These findings suggest that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; about congenital blindness may protect a person from schizophrenia. This is especially surprising, since congenital blindness often results from infections, brain trauma, or genetic mutation—all factors that are independently associated with greater risk of psychotic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More strangely, vision loss at other periods of life is associated with higher risks of schizophrenia and psychotic symptoms. Even in healthy people, blocking vision for just a few days can bring about hallucinations. And the connections between vision abnormalities and schizophrenia have become more deeply established in recent years—visual abnormalities are being found before a person has any psychotic symptoms, sometimes predicting who will develop schizophrenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=&quot; alt=&quot;pull quote&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1581364692513-Screen-Shot-2020-02-10-at-122933-PM.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the whispered-about fact persists: Being born blind, and perhaps specific types of congenital blindness, shield from the very disorders vision loss can encourage later in life. A myriad of theories exist as to why—from the blind brain's neuroplasticity to how vision plays an important role in building our model of the world (and what happens when that process goes wrong). Select researchers believe that the ties between vision and psychotic symptoms indicate there's something new to learn here. Could it be that within this narrowly-defined phenomenon there are clues for what causes schizophrenia, how to predict who will develop it, and potentially how to treat it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__text--dropcap&quot;&gt;In 2004, 13 healthy people were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15179062&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blindfolded&lt;/a&gt; for 96 hours, and 10 of them reported having visual hallucinations between their first and second day in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One subject, a 29-year-old woman, saw a green face with big eyes when she was standing in front of where she knew there was a mirror—though she couldn’t see it. Another 24-year-old man, by the end of the second day, was having difficulty walking because of all the hallucinations that appeared to be in his way. He reported seeing &quot;mounds of pebbles, or small stones...and between them was running a small stream of water.&quot; By the end of the study, he reported seeing &quot;ornate buildings of white-green marble&quot; and &quot;cartoon-like figures.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've known for a long time about the link between vision loss and hallucination. Charles Bonnet syndrome, first described in 1760, is a disorder in which people lose their vision and then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rnib.org.uk/eye-health/eye-conditions/charles-bonnet-syndrome-cbs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;start to experience&lt;/a&gt; hallucinations. These kinds of mental conjurings don't necessarily come with mental illness, though people with schizophrenia have been regularly shown to also have issues with their sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having unusual eye movements, problems with the retinas, unusual blink rates, and other visual aberrations makes it more likely for a person to be diagnosed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/01/25/new-findings-lend-confidence-to-the-idea-that-cortical-blindness-eliminates-the-risk-of-developing-schizophrenia/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;schizophrenia.&lt;/a&gt; One &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4850085/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; found that those vision problems start &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; a person has their first psychotic episodes, not after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet this association falls away among people born without sight. Pollak and Phil Corlett, an associate professor of psychiatry and psychology at Yale University, have a theory about why—which they published late &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/schizophreniabulletin/advance-article/doi/10.1093/schbul/sbz098/5585677&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; in the journal &lt;em&gt;Schizophrenia Bulletin.&lt;/em&gt; It's rooted in the hypothesis that one of our brain's most important jobs is to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantamagazine.org/to-make-sense-of-the-present-brains-may-predict-the-future-20180710/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;make predictions&lt;/a&gt; about the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Watch more from VICE:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This view of the brain argues that rather than perceiving the world around us in real time, our brains create a model of what’s out there, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/9k7mva/a-third-of-gluten-free-foods-in-us-restaurants-contain-gluten&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;predict&lt;/a&gt; and simulate what we experience, and then compare our predictions to what’s actually happening—using any errors to update or change the model in our minds. The accuracy of your past predictions are crucial for the accuracy of your overall model—it's what you're comparing new inputs to, and how you're making any adjustments.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where vision comes in. Vision gives us a lot of information about the world around us, and is an important sense that helps link together other sensory cues, like sound and touch, Pollak said. If the way a person sees the world is off, it can make it harder to predict, correct errors, and build a model of the world that makes sense. And when people have problems with their vision, the brain has to make more predictions to explain them. On the other hand, if you couldn’t see anything, you wouldn’t build up those false representations of the world around you—which could lead to problems in thinking later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might help researchers explain all those issues in vision and sensory processing early in life seen in people with schizophrenia. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://ajp.psychiatryonline.org/doi/abs/10.1176/ajp.147.8.1052?journalCode=ajp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a 2006 study&lt;/a&gt; by Elaine Walker at Emory University, she analyzed home movies of people diagnosed with schizophrenia when they were children. A lot of the children were more clumsy in the videos, like dropping a ball more frequently during catch, stumbling more often, or tilting to the left side. It suggests there's some sort of disconnect with the way they’re sensing and interacting with the world. When children of mothers who have schizophrenia &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1600-0447.2005.00584.x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;show visual dysfunction&lt;/a&gt; when they’re young, it can predict if they develop schizophrenia when they’re older. Children who end up with schizophrenia, both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0920996405003737?via%3Dihub&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;with and without&lt;/a&gt; a family history, have more problems with their eyes compared to children who develop non-psychotic diseases or other mental illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person who was born blind doesn't have the visual inputs to help shape their model of the world. They have to build it with their other senses—a model of the world that Pollak and Corlett argue could be more stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The idea we’re trying to get at is, there must be something different in the representation and the stability of the internal world in congenitally blind people,” Pollak said. “And that stability, in a way, is keeping itself protective against the kind of mistakes and false inferences that you get in schizophrenia and psychotic disorders.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__text--dropcap&quot;&gt;The hallucinations, delusions, and bizarre behavior in people with schizophrenia are well known. But Steve Silverstein, a psychiatrist at the University of Rochester, said that he and others view those symptoms as side effects, not the cause of the disease. Actually, schizophrenia could be more rooted in cognitive deficits—disturbances in perception, attention, memory, language, or learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 2010, Silverstein read &lt;em&gt;Blind Vision—&lt;/em&gt;a book by scientists Zaira Cattaneo and Tomaso Vecchi, on the cognitive abilities and experiences of blind people. “I was struck by how many of the compensations that the brain seems to make, or the skills that blind people develop, seem to be the exact opposite of what you find in schizophrenia,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silverstein doesn’t disagree with Pollak and Corlett’s predictive brain theory, but thinks that the answer may be more far-reaching: that prediction is just one way a congenitally blind person's brain has advantages over a schizophrenic brain. He thinks that being blind strengthens the brain in various ways—and in the very same ways that it is weakened when someone has schizophrenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=&quot; alt=&quot;pull quote&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1581364666943-Screen-Shot-2020-02-10-at-123030-PM.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To take one example, there’s something called &lt;em&gt;selective attention&lt;/em&gt; when it comes to listening, which is the ability to stay attentive to one source of auditory information—say, when you’re at a party and listening to one person without letting the sounds from the rest of the room distract you. In a lab setting, researchers test selective attention by playing one noise into your left ear and a different one into your right, asking you to pay attention to one and not the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People with schizophrenia have been shown to have problems with selective attention, Silverstein said, and meanwhile people who were born blind are better at this task than sighted people. When compared to sighted people, congenitally blind people are also better at hearing different pitches, telling pitches apart, and telling where sounds come from. People with schizophrenia are the opposite: They usually have difficulty with listening accuracy, and process speech abnormally. Not being able to properly figure out where sounds are coming from could lead to someone thinking that their own voice is coming from somewhere else, and contribute to delusional thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a compelling list that goes on and on: Blind people are better than sighted ones on reaction time to both sound and touch; schizophrenia patients show deficits in these areas. Blind people have better working memories, and people with schizophrenia can have impairments in memory. Congenitally blind people are also impervious to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3338767/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the rubber hand illusion&lt;/a&gt;, when a person feels like an inanimate object is part of their own body (the experiment is typically done using a rubber hand). It could mean that blind people have more stability when it comes to their bodily representation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I would say there are probably about 20 ways that people who are born blind are better, on average, than people in the general population,” Silverstein said. “And it’s in those same areas where people with schizophrenia tend to have more cognitive problems.” (He's even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/files/Articles/40106/fpsyg-03-00624-r2/image_m/fpsyg-03-00624-t001.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;made a chart&lt;/a&gt;, published in one of his papers.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;If you're born blind, your brain basically from an early age takes over the visual part of the brain to do other things,&quot; Silverstein said. &quot;And that's thought to be the reason why some of these auditory, attentional, and body-representation skills are a little more developed in people who were born blind than other people.&quot; Another result of blindness is that brain regions are talking to each other more, in ways they don’t in sighted people—some brain-imaging studies have seen that. People with schizophrenia, meanwhile, tend to have many fewer of these connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__text--dropcap&quot;&gt;A concrete explanation for why congenital blindness protects from schizophrenia is still up for grabs—whether the protection comes from predicting the world, having a more connected brain, or relying on other senses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot that needs to be fleshed out. For example, there is more than one kind of congenital blindness. &lt;em&gt;Cortical&lt;/em&gt; blindness is caused by an issue in the part of the brain that processes vision, whereas &lt;em&gt;peripheral&lt;/em&gt; blindness is a problem in the eyes instead—but the visual part of the brain is okay. While there are still no reported cases of people with congenital cortical blindness, there might be a few people who were born blind with peripheral blindness who did develop schizophrenia. (Some of the cases are several decades old, or the person has other serious diseases, so saying for sure is tough.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=&quot; alt=&quot;pull quote&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1581364641400-Screen-Shot-2020-02-10-at-123206-PM.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congenital blindness doesn’t seem to protect against any other mental illness, so it’s not a safeguard overall. Congenitally blind people have been reported to have had eating disorders and arachnophobia—a person can have those disorders without ever having seen their bodies or a spider). And if a person is born both deaf &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; blind, it doesn’t seem to offer protection either—that comes with higher risks for psychosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a disease called Usher syndrome, in which people are born deaf and lose their vision early in childhood; it’s been associated with schizophrenia and psychosis. Silverstein said that it’s unclear why adding deafness to the mix removes the protection that blindness seems to offer. “One possibility is that blindness by itself presents a surmountable challenge to cope with the environment and thereby fosters compensatory sensory, perceptual, and cognitive changes that lead to a surprisingly high level of functioning,” Silverstain wrote in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00624/full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a 2013 paper.&lt;/a&gt; “Deafblindness, on the other hand, may so seriously restrict the opportunity for environmental interaction that it also stunts the development of cognitively based coping strategies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the end, it's this extreme specificity that's most intriguing. It could lead to a different approach to thinking about psychosis, Corlett said. The development of the visual system could be looked at more closely, along with people’s visual predictions. It could open up some basic research avenues to help gain more fundamental understanding of schizophrenia: “What's the relationship between those really basic visual perceptual mechanisms and the onset of symptoms?” Corlett asked. We've made very little progress in our understanding of psychosis in particular, but also in psychiatry more broadly, in terms of how these symptoms are created in the brain. I think anything that gives us inspiration, anything that might give us a bit of leverage is really, really welcomed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the U.S., work with schizophrenia patients has been heavily focused on cognitive tasks, like memory, Corlett said, but maybe cognitive training should include more focus on sensory factors and perception. Perhaps early visual training, along with cognitive training, could potentially help. And instead of a blood test, perhaps one day there could be an eye test for people to assess if they’re at high risk for psychosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing to consider, which Silverstein has written about, is having people at risk for schizophrenia increase their reliance on their non-vision senses, to see if that enhances their functioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's not a novel approach: to go looking for where a disease &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; exist, in order to learn something more about it. In the 1980s and 1990s, there were people who were commonly exposed to HIV, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://aidsinfo.nih.gov/news/310/scientists-confirm-natural-resistance-to-hiv-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;never developed&lt;/a&gt; AIDS. Studying &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fredhutch.org/en/news/center-news/2015/12/HIV-super-survivors.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;those people&lt;/a&gt; led to a deeper understanding of risks, and what protective factors they may have had. It was a long-standing medical mystery that people with sickle-cell anemia were somehow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/sickle-cell-mystery-solved-1.9342&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;protected from getting malaria&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/health/la-xpm-2011-nov-25-la-sci-sickle-cell-malaria-20111126-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;same gene&lt;/a&gt; that causes abnormal red blood cells in sickle cell anemia is protective against malaria—offering a window into how malaria works in the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be difficult to study, especially for rare diseases, where you have to wait for natural cases to arise. But it can be a unique place for clues. “I often joke that it’d be interesting to study people like Keith Richards or Ozzy Osbourne: Why they haven't been ravaged by opiate addiction in the same way or similar addiction,” Corlett said. “ &lt;em&gt;What is it about these people that led them not to manifest illnesses?&lt;/em&gt; has been traditionally a very useful way of exploring what it means to be at risk and what it means to have pathophysiology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With schizophrenia and blindness, Silverstein said we’re not there yet, and probably not close. That said, he doesn’t think that we should ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At this point, I don’t think I’d go so far as to say it's promising,” Silverstein said. “The word I’d use is intriguing. “In some ways, this is one of the most interesting observations in a long time in schizophrenia research. Because it’s the only thing that seems to be protective against schizophrenia. I think there’s something here and this should be looked into much more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/page/sign-up-for-the-vice-newsletter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sign up for our newsletter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;to get the best of VICE delivered to your inbox daily.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Shayla Love on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shayla__love&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 09:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>SZJX</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>People Born Blind Are Mysteriously Protected From Schizophrenia</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5e41919fc62ac8009d1eb73f/lede/1581370327161-Nobody-born-blind-has-ever-been-diagnosed-with-schizophrenia_LK.jpeg?crop=1xw:1xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/939qbz/people-born-blind-are-mysteriously-protected-from-schizophrenia</og:url>
<og:description>The possible explanations could help us better understand the condition.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/939qbz/people-born-blind-are-mysteriously-protected-from-schizophrenia</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rotary Cellphone</title>
<link>http://justine-haupt.com/rotarycellphone/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://justine-haupt.com/rotarycellphone/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;85.909497500658&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Rotary Cellphone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://justine-haupt.com/rotarycellphone/RotaryCell1.JPG&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why a rotary cellphone? Because in a finicky, annoying, touchscreen world of hyperconnected people using phones they have no control over or understanding of, I wanted something that would be entirely mine, personal, and absolutely tactile,while also giving me an excuse for not texting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The point isn't to be anachronistic. It's to show that it's possible to have a perfectly usable phone that goes as far from having a touchscreen as I can imagine, and which in some ways may actually be &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; functional. More functional how? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Real, removable antenna with an SMA connector. Receptions is excellent, and if I really want to I could always attach a directional antenna.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I want a phone I don't have to navigate through menus to get to the phone &quot;application&quot;. That's bullshit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I want to call my husband, I can do so by pressing a single dedicated physical key which is dediated to him. No menus. The point isn't to use the rotary dial every single time I want to make a call, which would get tiresome for daily use. The people I call most often are stored, and if I have to dial a new number, or do something like set the volume, then I can use the fun and satisfying-to-use rotary dial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nearlt instantaneous, high resolution of signal strength and battery level. No signal metering lag, and my LED bargraph gives 10 increments of resolution instead of just 4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ePaper display is bistatic, meaning it doesn't take any energy to display a fixed message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I want to change something about the phones behavior, I just do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The power switch is an actual slide switch. No holding down a stupid button to make it turn off and not being sure it really is turning off or what.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So it's not just a show-and-tell piece... My intent is to use it as my primary phone. It fits in a pocket.; It's reasonably compact; calling the people I most often call is &lt;em&gt;faster&lt;/em&gt; than with my old phone, and the battery lasts almost 24 hours.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Technical overview:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rotary mechanism comes from a particular style of Trimline telephone. Trimline phones had a more compact rotary dial than the standard Bell system phones, making it a good choice when keeping the final device as compact as possible is paramount. There are a couple other instances of rotary cell phones floating around the internet, one of which has what looks like a custom tiny rotary dial that needs a stylus to dial, but I wanted this to have a recognizably-classic rotary dial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main board uses the ATmega2560V microcontroller with an 8MHz external resonator. It's programmed as an Arduino Mega2560. Although the cell tranceiver is an Adafruit FONA 3G, this doesn't use the FONA Arduino libraries. Instead the mainboard code sends serial commands (&quot;AT commands&quot;) directly to the FONA over a software serial link. The ePaper display is the Adafruit 2.13&quot; Flexible Monochrome eInk display using Jean-Marc Zingg's GxEPD2 library. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The board was fabbed by pcbway.com in China but was populated by hand (including the .5mm pitch  footprint for the ATmega chip).  Had to do some odd things to make everything fit perfectly in the casing (slanted header for FONA module, slanted eInk Friend daughterboard, blah blah).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to make this it would be a good idea to send me an email for notes that I haven't had a chance to document yet. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code is an ongoing work. Functionality as of this writing is limited, but it makes and receieves calls reliably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open source. All design files (KiCad, Arduino code, mecanical STLs) available &lt;a href=&quot;http://justine-haupt.com/designfiles&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Project Progression:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally I was intent on making this a quick and dirty project. I laid everything out flat to make a proof of principle phone and used an Arduino Micro as the controller:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://justine-haupt.com/rotarycellphone/RotaryCellphone_proof_of_principle.JPG&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I thought I'd just stuff it into a 3D printed enclosure. Let's call this v1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://justine-haupt.com/rotarycellphone/RotaryCellphone_v1.JPG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this proved hopelessly delicate. Couldn't open it to fix something without breaking something else. OK, I guess a board layout is warranted. Did that and came up with v2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://justine-haupt.com/rotarycellphone/RotaryCellphone_v2_Innards_Top.JPG&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://justine-haupt.com/rotarycellphone/RotaryCellphone_v2_1.JPG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://justine-haupt.com/rotarycellphone/RotaryCellphone_v2_2.JPG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://justine-haupt.com/rotarycellphone/RotaryCellphone_v2_3.JPG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 07:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nallerooth</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://justine-haupt.com/rotarycellphone/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Let&amp;#039;s Encrypt: an automated certificate authority to encrypt the entire web</title>
<link>https://blog.acolyer.org/2020/02/12/lets-encrypt-an-automated-certificate-authority-to-encrypt-the-entire-web/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.acolyer.org/2020/02/12/lets-encrypt-an-automated-certificate-authority-to-encrypt-the-entire-web/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-jetpack-markdown&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jhalderm.com/pub/papers/letsencrypt-ccs19.pdf&quot;&gt;Let’s encrypt: an automated certificate authority to encrypt the entire web&lt;/a&gt;, Aas et al., CCS’19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper tells the story of Let’s Encrypt, from it’s early beginnings in 2012/13 all the way to becoming the world’s largest HTTPS Certificate Authority (CA) today – accounting for more currently valid certificates than all other browser-trusted CAs combined. Beyond the functionality that Let’s Encrypt provides, the story stands out to me for two key ingredients. Firstly, whereas normally we trade-off between security and ease-of-use, Let’s Encrypt made the web more secure &lt;em&gt;through&lt;/em&gt; ease-of-use. Secondly, Let’s Encrypt managed to find a sustainable funding model for a combination of an open source project and free online service, as compared to the more normal pattern which sadly seems to involve running a small number of beneficent maintainers into the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it’s launch in December 2015, Let’s Encrypt has steadily grown to become the largest CA in the Web PKI by certificates issued and the fourth largest known CA by Firefox Beta TLS full handshakes. As of January 21, 2019, the CA had issued a total of 538M certificates for 223M unique FQDNs… Let’s Encrypt has been responsible for significant growth in HTTPS deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the majority of HTTPS sites use Let’s Encrypt and it’s the fastest growing CA, but it’s usage is still rarer among the largest sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://adriancolyer.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/lets-encrypt-fig4.jpeg?w=640&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s Encrypt’s service is fully automated end-to-end (a key part of being able to make it free), and hence Let’s Encrypt only offers &lt;em&gt;domain validated&lt;/em&gt; (DV) certificates (verifying that the requestor has control over the domain). 83% of the Alexa Top 100 sites currently use &lt;em&gt;organization validation&lt;/em&gt; (OV) or &lt;em&gt;extended validation&lt;/em&gt; (EV) certificates (validating public business registration documents) – which require manual verification of identity documents. However, web users don’t really understand the difference between DV, OV and EV certificates, and Firefox, Chrome, and Safari no longer have unique indicators for the validation levels, so perhaps it’s only a matter of time before Let’s Encrypt takes over the largest sites too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason that Let’s Encrypt has experienced rapid growth is that its service has been integrated by hosting and CDN providers in order to automatically provision certificates for their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a model for others to follow, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://caddyserver.com/&quot;&gt;Caddy web server&lt;/a&gt; will automatically provision Let’s Encrypt certificates. Apache and Nginx remain the most popular Let’s Encrypt using web servers deployed in the wild though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://adriancolyer.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/lets-encrypt-table-5.jpeg?w=520&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, even though Let’s Encrypt’s certificates have much shorter lifetimes (90 days) than those typically issued by other CAs (more accurately, &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; Let’s Encrypt’s certificates have much shorter lifetimes), sites using Let’s Encrypt certificates are much less likely to to serve expired certificates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;In the beginnning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we started work on Let’s Encrypt, the two most commonly voiced criticisms about the Web PKI were that (a) it was too difficult for server operators to use, and (b) it wasn’t secure anyway. Let’s Encrypt was intended to take aim directly at the first complaint…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, the average price for a one-year single-domain certificate from the five largest CAs was $178, and for a wildcard certificate it was ​$766. Navigating the SSL marketplace was difficult and confusing. It’s interesting to note that even though Let’s Encrypt’s certificates are free, the introduction of a free alternative to the marketplace seems to have done very little to reduce prices at the other CAs. That’s not what I would have predicted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://adriancolyer.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/lets-encrypt-table-1.jpeg?w=520&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, Alex Halderman (University of Michigan) and Peter Eckersley (EFF) were leading a group to develop a protocol for automatically issuing and renewing certificates. Independently, Josh Aas and Eric Rescorla were leading a team at Mozilla to create a free and automated certificate authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The groups learned of each other’s efforts, and joined forces in May 2013. That month, they formed the Internet Security Research Group (ISRG), a nonprofit corporation, to be the legal entity operating Let’s Encrypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s Encrypt was publically announced on November 18th 2014, and began providing service to the public on Decemmber 3rd 2015. To bootstrap trust, ISRG executed a cross-signing agreement with IdenTrust (a root authority trusted by Mozilla, Apple, and Microsoft). ISRG subsequently established its own root trust anchor which was accepted into all major browser and platform root programs as of August 2018. From July this year Let’s Encrypt will default to issuing certificates with a trust chain leading to the ISRG root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Internet Security Research Group&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ISRG’s budget is on the order of $3M per annum. Staffing is the biggest expense, with 13 full-time employees as of May 2019: six SREs, three software developers, and four admin staff. The board contains ten directors, with representation form public benefit entities, educational institutions, and major financial contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, ISRG was funded almost entirely through large donations from technology companies. In late 2014, it secured financial commitments from Akamai, Cisco, EFF, and Mozilla, allowing the organization to purchase equipment, secure hosting contracts, and pay initial staff. Today, ISRG has more diverse funding sources; in 2018 it received 83% of its funding from corporate sponsors, 14% from grants and major gifts, and 3% from individual giving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The ACME protocol&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Automated Certificate Management Environment&lt;/em&gt; (ACME) protocol was a central element in the formation of Let’s Encrypt (now standardised an RFC 8555). It automates the entire relationship between a CA and a certificate applicant, with a typical interaction proceeding as shown in the figure below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://adriancolyer.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/lets-encrypt-fig-2.jpeg?w=520&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACME includes an extensible challenge mechanism for identifier validation. Let’s Encrypt currently supports three challenge types, including the ‘HTTP challenge’ which requires the application to serve a CA-provided random value at a specific HTTP URL at the domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, all validation methods that rely on empirical validation of control (as all of the above do) are vulnerable to network-layer attacks on the validation process, such as BGP hijacking to reroute validation requests. The ACME RFC discusses these risks in detail, and suggests some mitigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Boulder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ACME protocol on its own doesn’t do anything unless there’s a trusted entity serving it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/letsencrypt/boulder&quot;&gt;Boulder&lt;/a&gt; is the open-source CA software stack that powers Let’s Encrypt’s operations. Boulder handles the three main functions required of a CA:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Issuing certificates via ACME&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submitting pre-certificates and certificates to Certificate Transparency logs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publication of certificate revocation status via &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_Certificate_Status_Protocol&quot;&gt;OCSP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://adriancolyer.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/lets-encrypt-fig-3.jpeg?w=640&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://adriancolyer.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/lets-encrypt-fig-3.jpeg&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boulder is built with six key design principles in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimal logic&lt;/strong&gt;, in order to make it easier to verify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimal data&lt;/strong&gt; collection (public key, optional contact email address, and access logs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full automation&lt;/strong&gt; with no facility for human operators to manually create certificates or make one-off policy exceptions. &quot;&lt;em&gt;Locking out humans prevents errors that have led to misissuance by other CAs&lt;/em&gt;.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Functional isolation&lt;/strong&gt; via a small number of limited-purpose components communication through well-defined APIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational isolation&lt;/strong&gt; with no access to data centres and adminstration performed remotely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous availability&lt;/strong&gt; via the facility to run multiple redundant instances of each function in parallel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Clients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the client side, the EFF created an ACME client called &lt;a href=&quot;https://certbot.eff.org/&quot;&gt;Certbot&lt;/a&gt;, which is used by 50% of Let’s Encrypt clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most other clients, Certbot aims to fully automate secure HTTPS deployment, rather than simply procuring a certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lessons for improving the security of an ecosystem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s Encrypt succeeded by combining ease-of-use with a great price (free). This was only possible through automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automation is necessary to have a free CA and free certificates make automation practical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to issue millions of certificates and keep the cost-per-certificate down, automation is the only possible route. Automation also lowers the administrative costs making the ISRG possible to run on a limited budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full end-to-end operation is hard to achieve if payments are involved, so free certificates are another key piece of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last piece of the puzzle is that Let’s Encypt supports &lt;em&gt;gradual deployment&lt;/em&gt; throughout the Web ecosystem. By issuing ordinary WebPKI certificates with cross-signatures, Let’s Encrypts certificates were immediately valid in nearly any browser. In contrast, efforts such as the DNS Authentication of Named Entities (DANE) have stalled: in order to use DANE, both clients and servers have to change, but neither side has an incentive to do so until the other has (a classic marketplace bootstrapping issue).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The last word&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that in the near future, clients will start using HTTPS as the default web transport. Eventually, we may marvel that there was ever a time when Web traffic traveled over the Internet as plaintext.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-23592848-9585-5e449ff0efd47&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20190321#blog_id=23592848&amp;amp;post_id=9585&amp;amp;origin=adriancolyer.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=23592848-9585-5e449ff0efd47&amp;amp;domain=blog.acolyer.org&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-23592848-9585-5e449ff0efd47&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 06:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>godelmachine</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Let's Encrypt: an automated certificate authority to encrypt the entire web</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.acolyer.org/2020/02/12/lets-encrypt-an-automated-certificate-authority-to-encrypt-the-entire-web/</og:url>
<og:description>Let’s encrypt: an automated certificate authority to encrypt the entire web, Aas et al., CCS’19 This paper tells the story of Let’s Encrypt, from it’s early beginnings in 20…</og:description>
<og:image>https://adriancolyer.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/lets-encrypt-fig-3.jpeg?w=640</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.acolyer.org/2020/02/12/lets-encrypt-an-automated-certificate-authority-to-encrypt-the-entire-web/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Becoming a high performing software developer working from your bedroom</title>
<link>https://zephony.com/remote-software-developer-productivity</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://zephony.com/remote-software-developer-productivity</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://zephony.com/remote-software-developer-productivity&quot;&gt;https://zephony.com/remote-software-developer-productivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22306337&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22306337&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 525&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 271&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 06:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kevinpaladin</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://zephony.com/remote-software-developer-productivity</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>