<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Microsoft and GitHub team up to take Git virtual file system to macOS, Linux</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/11/microsoft-and-github-team-up-to-take-git-virtual-file-system-to-macos-linux/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/11/microsoft-and-github-team-up-to-take-git-virtual-file-system-to-macos-linux/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/git-branching.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;53 posters participating, including story author.&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/11/microsoft-and-github-team-up-to-take-git-virtual-file-system-to-macos-linux/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;82&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the more surprising stories of the past year was Microsoft's announcement that it was going to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/02/microsoft-hosts-the-windows-source-in-a-monstrous-300gb-git-repository/&quot;&gt;Git version control system for Windows development&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft had to modify Git to handle the demands of Windows development but said that it wanted to get these modifications accepted upstream and integrated into the standard Git client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That plan appears to be going well. Yesterday, the company announced that &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/devops/2017/11/15/updates-to-gvfs/&quot;&gt;GitHub was adopting its modifications&lt;/a&gt; and that the two would be working together to bring suitable clients to macOS and Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft wanted to move to Git because of Git's features, like its easy branching and its popularity among developers. But the transition faced three problems. Git wasn't designed for such vast numbers of developers—more than 3,000 actively working on the codebase. Also, Git wasn't designed for a codebase that was so large, either in terms of the number of files and version history for each file, or in terms of sheer size, coming in at more than 300GB. When using standard Git, working with the source repository was unacceptably slow. Common operations (such as checking which files have been modified) would take multiple minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company's solution was to develop Git Virtual File System (GVFS). With GVFS, a local replica of a Git repository is virtualized such that it contains metadata and only the source code files that have been explicitly retrieved. By eliminating the need to replicate &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; file (and, hence, check &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; file for modifications), both the disk footprint of the repository and the speed of working with it were greatly improved. Microsoft modified Git to handle this virtual file system. The client was altered so that it didn't needlessly try to access files that weren't available locally and a new transfer protocol was added for selectively retrieving individual files from a remote repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internally, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/05/90-of-windows-devs-now-using-git-creating-1760-windows-builds-per-day/&quot;&gt;proved successful&lt;/a&gt;, with Windows development being substantially migrated to Git in May of this year. But what of the broader Git community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft says that, so far, about half of its modifications have been accepted upstream, with upstream Git developers broadly approving of the approach the company has taken to improve the software's scaling. Redmond also says that it has been willing to make changes to its approach to satisfy the demands of upstream Git. The biggest complexity is that Git has a very conservative approach to compatibility, requiring that repositories remain compatible across versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub's interest and involvement is motivated by the company's desire to address the needs of enterprise customers. The open source, free GitHub hosting doesn't need the scaling work Microsoft has done—obviously, if someone is using standard Git, today then standard Git must be good enough for their development process. But on the paid, enterprise side, the situation can be a little different. Certain industries have large repositories that pose problems with Git; for example, game repositories are often physically large not because they have millions of files and decades of history, but because of their large number of graphics and other assets. The scaling improvements that Microsoft has made to Git are useful for this kind of large repository, too. As such, having the same family of improvements available in GitHub will enable the company to better serve these communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft itself has had similar demands from enterprise; the company told us that Siemens wanted to move away from the Team Foundation Server version control &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visualstudio.com/team-services/git/&quot;&gt;to using Git instead&lt;/a&gt;. But it'll only be able to do this once the scaling improvements had been made; right now, TFS version control scales better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the name would imply, GVFS requires a file system driver to work. The Windows division worked with the engineering team to add features to Windows to make this efficient. The intent is to eventually make this capability into a supported, extensible API and, at some point, move systems such as the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/06/onedrive-done-right-is-back-and-now-it-works-properly/&quot;&gt;OneDrive placeholders&lt;/a&gt; to use the same API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and GitHub are also working to bring similar capabilities to other platforms, with macOS coming first, and later Linux. The obvious way to do this on both systems is to use FUSE, an infrastructure for building file systems that run in user mode rather than kernel mode (desirable because user-mode development is easier and safer than kernel mode). However, the companies have discovered that FUSE isn't fast enough for this—a lesson Dropbox also learned when developing a similar capability, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/04/dropboxs-project-infinite-shows-all-your-files-locally-without-using-any-disk-space/&quot;&gt;Project Infinite&lt;/a&gt;. Currently, the companies believe that tapping into a macOS extensibility mechanism called Kauth (or KAuth) will be the best way forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 17:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dmmalam</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/11/microsoft-and-github-team-up-to-take-git-virtual-file-system-to-macos-linux/</og:url>
<og:title>Microsoft and GitHub team up to take Git virtual file system to macOS, Linux</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/git-branching-760x380.png</og:image>
<og:description>Microsoft isn't the only company that's interested in scaling Git.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/11/microsoft-and-github-team-up-to-take-git-virtual-file-system-to-macos-linux/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is software development really a dead-end job after age 35-40?</title>
<link>https://www.quora.com/Is-software-development-really-a-dead-end-job-after-age-35-40/answer/Jeff-Nelson-32?share=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.quora.com/Is-software-development-really-a-dead-end-job-after-age-35-40/answer/Jeff-Nelson-32?share=1</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;I think you are asking about 3 different questions and should perhaps rewrite the question. Let's break it down, thusly:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Is Agism a problem in Software Development individual contributor careers?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Should you steer your career toward management roles instead of individual career roles?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Is Software Development individual contributor career a dead end job?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Each of these is thoroughly answered here on Quora in other questions with details broken down as outlined above, so I'm going to just discuss each point briefly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;On agism, I don't think anyone can deny there is a certain amount of agism in the industry. You can just look at the median age of new hires of just about every Silicon Valley company. I suspect many, if not most, have median hiring ages well below 30. However, that doesn't necessarily mean there are official corporate policies not to hire candidates above a certain age, race, sex,Sexual preference, or other characteristics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;The reasons why agism exists in the tech industry are multifold and don't require some collusion not to hire older employees. For one, many companies find it easiest to use new college graduates of top schools (the MITs and Stanfords, etc) as a primary pool for recruiting. New graduates are cheap. They have a consistent quality. They are untrammelled by experiences at other companies. They are a clean slate, so it's somewhat easier to teach them corporate culture, software methodology, best practices, and to fit in with other predominantly new grad hires at a startup.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;I don't think that anyone in Silicon Valley would argue, though, that if you have a candidate with 3 years of solid programming experience in a relevant technology - plus also graduated with a prestigious degree - isn't also a good candidate, possibly a better candidate. In fact, I'd go so far as to say there isn't a number N, where a candidate with N years of relevant experience is better than a candidate with N+1 years of experience, all other factors being equal and the skills and experience being relevant and targeted at the business the company is doing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;The myth that the technology changes too fast for engineers to stay relevant may have been true at one time, but the core technologies on which the web is built have been around for many decades. The C programming language emerged way back in the late 1970s, over 40 years ago. The Javascript language, such as it is, emerged for the first time in 1997, about 20 years ago. That means we have engineers walking around, nearing retirement age, whose entire career has been focused on C and running Unix servers, for decades and decades. There are very few engineers of that quality, with that much experience, though, and I doubt anyone would try to claim that to 22 year old who just graduated is necessarily better than a 60 year old, who has spent 40+ years working in these technologies. Those types of engineers are few and far between, of course.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Consquently, to the other point in the question, I don't believe software engineering is a dead end career. I would say that it does tend to plateau after a certain number of years in terms of salary growth. Part of the reason for that is simply that engineers are essentially a human commodity. Unless you are a very special engineer, indeed, you can always be replaced by someone else. I think that helps keep software engineering salaries somewhat low compared to other competitive industries. However, I can almost guarantee you that demand for software engineers will exceed the supply of new graduates or others in the candidate pool, so you'll always have a job. You might not receive those fat 10% exponential raises every year, like you do for your first 2 or 3 years, though.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Finally, to your point about whether management is a better option, I'd ask why consider only that option? There are certainly any number of career paths you can take. You can transition to another area of engineering. For example, many software engineers who don't enjoy creating product move to other roles, sometimes in the same company, such as Operations, Product Management, Project Management, QA, or something even less technical like Sales or Executive positions. I also have friends who have changed careers entirely, such as going into full time teaching.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Let me conclude by saying that I, for one, do appreciate it when I'm working with managers who have a solid background in engineering, preferably software engineering with technologies relevant to the company, so please don't rush into engineering management as a career path. For those of us who might have to deal with you in the future, get 5 or 6 years of good solid engineering as an individual contributor under your belt. Learn how the industry works as a contributor. Only then, consider moving your career in a management direction. You wouldn't hire a florist to build the Brooklyn Bridge. Don't hire any engineering manager who hasn't paid his dues as an engineer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 17:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbanffy</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.quora.com/Is-software-development-really-a-dead-end-job-after-age-35-40/answer/Jeff-Nelson-32?share=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Orcas have learned how to drown great white sharks</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/blog/2017/nov/16/orca-whales-vs-great-white-sharks-in-a-battle-of-the-apex-predators-who-wins?CMP=fb_gu</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/science/blog/2017/nov/16/orca-whales-vs-great-white-sharks-in-a-battle-of-the-apex-predators-who-wins?CMP=fb_gu</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The great white shark, &lt;em&gt;Carcharodon carcharias&lt;/em&gt;, is considered the most voracious apex predator in temperate marine ecosystems worldwide, playing a key role in controlling ecosystem dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, it is difficult to imagine a great white as prey. And yet, earlier this year the carcasses of five great whites washed ashore along South Africa’s Western Cape province. Ranging in size from 2.7 metres (9ft) to 4.9 metres (16ft), the two females and three males all had one thing in common: holes puncturing the muscle wall between the pectoral fins. Strangest of all, their livers were missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-3 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bite marks inflicted, together with confirmed sightings indicate that orcas, &lt;em&gt;Orcinus orca&lt;/em&gt;, were responsible for this precisely-targeted predation. Although the opening scene from Jaws II immediately springs to mind, in which an orca washes up with huge bite marks on it, the reality has turned out to be the exact opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Orcas are apex predators whose diet is often geographic or population specific&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/b339572204f03729bbdd7c34133b4ebfd21e27d1/0_110_5216_3129/master/5216.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=80daf17b3d00444f60c01a92e2e53692&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Orcas are apex predators whose diet is often geographic or population specific. Photograph: Martin Ruegner/Getty Images/age fotostock RM
&lt;p&gt;When comparing these two apex predators alongside each other, the stats read like a game of Top Trumps. Max length: great white 6.4 metres, orca 9.6 metres; max weight: great white 2,268kg, orca 9,000kg; burst swim speed: great white 45km/h, orca 48km/h. On paper, at least, it does seem that orcas have the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diet of orcas is often geographic or population specific. Those populations predating in South African waters have been documented targeting smaller shark species for their livers. Cow sharks, blues and makos caught on longlines have had their livers removed by orcas, alongside the brains of the billfish also caught. Cow shark carcasses without livers have also washed ashore near Cape Town, and again, this followed nearby orca sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With no doubt that orcas are using highly specialised hunting strategies to target the liver; the real question is: why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shark livers are large, typically accounting for 5% or more of a shark’s total body weight. They are oil rich, with a principal component, squalene, serving as an energy store and providing buoyancy in the absence of the swim-bladder found in teleosts (bony fish).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-3 | 2&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analysis of white shark livers in particular shows an extremely high total lipid content, dominated by triacylglycerols (&amp;gt;93%). This results in an energy density that is higher than whale blubber. For the sharks this serves as an energy storage unit to fuel migrations, growth and reproduction (Pethybridge et al 2014). For the orcas this is like eating a deep fried Mars Bar with added vitamins. Generally speaking, livers contain vitamin C, vitamin B12, folate, vitamin B6, niacin, riboflavin, vitamin A, iron, sodium and of course fat, carbohydrate and protein energy sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the attraction of this delicacy to the orca is clear, how exactly does an orca go about removing a great white shark’s liver? The evidence we have shows that it is done with some precision – the shark carcasses were not obliterated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;The examination of one of the great whites beginsThe incision under the pectoral fin was made by the orca.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/f2bf88249379baefd8e10973919a95dbc048d33b/0_0_3987_2392/master/3987.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=5550026826f394ff835fcbedc5964c2d&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

The examination of one of the great whites begins. The incision under the pectoral fin was made by the orca. Photograph: Dyer Island Conservation Trust, Michelle Wcisel
&lt;p&gt;During a 1997 encounter off the Farrallon Islands off the coast of San Francisco, a group of whale watchers witnessed an orca ramming into the side of a great white shark, momentarily stunning it and allowing the orca to flip it over and holding it in place (ventral/belly up) for around 15 minutes, after which the orca began consuming its prey, much to the surprise of the whale watchers on board. A similar incident was captured on film off Costa Rica in 2014 – this time the orca’s prey was a tiger shark. And it’s not just sharks; orcas have been observed doing the same to stingrays too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-3 | 3&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;What the orcas were exploiting to their own advantage is a curious phenomenon known as “tonic immobility” (TI). This is a natural state of paralysis, which occurs when elasmobranchs are positioned ventral side up in the water column. For certain species of shark like the great white, which is unable to pump water across its gills unless it keeps swimming, the consequence of being maintained within this ‘tonic’ state for too long is final. Effectively, the orcas have learned how to drown their prey whilst minimising their own predatory exertion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T I is a reflex that is characterised by a catatonic state and total loss of muscle tone – it equates to at least stage IIb of anaesthesia (loss of consciousness to automatic respiration, as shown by McFarland, 1959). It has been observed and documented for a variety of terrestrial species, but in the aquatic environment it is usually associated with elasmobranchs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Sub-adult lemon shark held in tonic immobility for hook removal.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/b28a71cd8e2e45ca62e5ec3237742ca2e58e1254/72_0_1450_870/master/1450.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=275abca76b8bf3a863aff0fe884ad249&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Sub-adult lemon shark held in tonic immobility for hook removal. Photograph: Lauren Smith
&lt;p&gt;Researchers often use this reflex to help with the surgical implantation of acoustic tags. The rapid induction and recovery of the animals optimises the surgical procedure, which is particularly desirable during what are often complex field work conditions (Kessel &amp;amp; Hussey 2015).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helpful to researchers and predatory orcas it may be, but the evolutionary benefit to those elasmobranchs exhibiting TI is less certain. It may serve as a defence strategy, but the advantage of sharks being able to “play dead” is not clear. An alternative theory suggests that TI may be related to mating, with males using it as a technique to temporarily immobilise the female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the primary use of TI is in the wild for elasmobranchs, orcas are known to exploit this to aid their predation. The sharks however, also learn, and sightings of great whites off the South African coastline rapidly declined whilst the orcas were in the area. Once the orcas moved on, the great whites slowly began to return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pethybridge HR, Parrish CC, Bruce BD, Young JW, Nichols PD. 2014. &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0097877&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Lipid, Fatty Acid and Energy Density Profiles of White Sharks: Insights into the Feeding Ecology and Ecophysiology of a Complex Top Predator&lt;/a&gt;. PLoS ONE 5: e97877.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessel, ST, Hussey, NE. 2015. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nrcresearchpress.com/doi/10.1139/cjfas-2015-0136#.Wg1yBRO0NHc&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Tonic immobility as an anaesthetic for elasmobranchs during surgical implantation procedures.&lt;/a&gt; Canadian Journal of Fisheries and Aquaculture Science. 72. 1-5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McFarland, WN. 1959. A study of the effects of anaesthetics on the behaviour and physiology of fishes. Publication of the Institute of Marine Science, University of Texas at Austin, 6: 23–55.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This headline on this piece was edited on 16 November to correct an error made by a subeditor – orcas, technically speaking, are the largest dolphins and not whales .&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 16:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>walkingolof</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/science/blog/2017/nov/16/orca-whales-vs-great-white-sharks-in-a-battle-of-the-apex-predators-who-wins</og:url>
<og:description>It’s difficult to imagine the voracious great white shark as prey. Could orcas really be overpowering them and removing their livers?</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/18b002b97b654e8c1ea7966625fe42527321edda/0_357_5350_3210/master/5350.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxNi8wNS8yNS9vdmVybGF5LWxvZ28tMTIwMC05MF9vcHQucG5n&amp;s=796b420b4563c2adf0f7b69507439c5a</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Orcas vs great white sharks: in a battle of the apex predators who wins?</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/science/blog/2017/nov/16/orca-whales-vs-great-white-sharks-in-a-battle-of-the-apex-predators-who-wins?CMP=fb_gu</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Germany bans children&amp;#039;s smartwatches</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-42030109</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-42030109</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Smartwatches&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef-1.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/CCB0/production/_98800425_mediaitem98356800.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;NCC&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The German telecoms regulator urged parents to destroy children's smartwatches
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;A German regulator has banned the sale of smartwatches aimed at children, describing them as spying devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It had previously banned an internet-connected doll called, My Friend Cayla, for similar reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telecoms regulator the Federal Network Agency urged parents who had such watches to destroy them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One expert said the decision could be a &quot;game-changer&quot; for internet-connected devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Poorly secured smart devices often allow for privacy invasion. That is really concerning when it comes to kids' GPS tracking watches - the very watches that are supposed to help keep them safe,&quot; said Ken Munro, a security expert at Pen Test Partners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;There is a shocking lack of regulation of the 'internet of things', which allows lax manufacturers to sell us dangerously insecure smart products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Using privacy regulation to ban such devices is a game-changer, stopping these manufacturers playing fast and loose with our kids' security,&quot; he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement, the agency said it had already taken action against several firms offering such watches on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Via an app, parents can use such children's watches to listen unnoticed to the child's environment and they are to be regarded as an unauthorised transmitting system,&quot; said Jochen Homann, president of the Federal Network Agency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;According to our research, parents' watches are also used to listen to teachers in the classroom.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The agency also asked schools to &quot;pay more attention&quot; to such watches among students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Tracking children&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such watches - which are sold by a large number of providers in Germany - are generally aimed at children between the ages of five and 12.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most are equipped with a Sim card and a limited telephony function and are set up and controlled via an app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In October, the Norwegian Consumer Council (NCC) reported that 'some children's watches - including Gator and GPS for kids - had flaws such as transmitting and storing data without encryption.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It meant that strangers, using basic hacking techniques, could track children as they moved or make a child appear to be in a completely different location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is not clear whether the German decision to ban such devices was based on the privacy issues associated with them or wider security flaws that have been uncovered by NCC and others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both firms said that they had resolved the security issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finn Myrstad, head of digital policy at the NCC said: &quot;This ban sends a strong signal to makers of products aimed at children that they need to be safer.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He called for Europe-wide measures to increase the security of such devices.&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 16:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>watbe</dc:creator>
<og:title>Germany bans children's smartwatches</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Telecoms regulator says kids' smartwatches are spying devices and are to be banned under German law.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-42030109</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/cpsprodpb/CCB0/production/_98800425_mediaitem98356800.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-42030109</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Brave expands Basic Attention Token platform to YouTube</title>
<link>https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular&quot; data-padding=&quot;0px|0px|49.3906px|0px&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; et_pb_row et_pb_row_0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text et_pb_module et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_text_0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;YouTube creators can now earn BAT for their content&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text et_pb_module et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_text_1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With today’s release of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/download/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Brave browser 0.19.95&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; for the desktop, audiences can use the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/faq-payments/#what-is-brave-payments&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Brave Payments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;system to reward their favorite YouTube creators with Basic Attention Tokens (BAT).   YouTube viewers can either distribute contributions based on the time they spend viewing material or by “pinning” a set amount for a particular channel. Previously, the BAT could only be distributed on a domain-by-domain basis.    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Brave browser provides an ad-free YouTube video experience. It also enables a direct monetary relationship between the content creator and their audience. Compensation for YouTube creators no longer needs to be based on vague rules or mercurial algorithms, as users can decide who to compensate. This new ability will especially benefit YouTube creators who have under 10,000 lifetime views, as they&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/6/15209220/youtube-partner-program-rule-change-monetize-ads-10000-views&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;do not receive ad revenue from YouTube&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Previously, YouTube creators could not be listed as individual publishers in Brave Payments. This change allows BAT contributions to flow directly into their wallets. The Brave browser determines the YouTube creator name from a YouTube video, no matter what site embeds it. It then displays it in the Brave Payments list, enabling the user to donate back on a monthly basis. Once a user enables Brave Payments, donations are done automatically and anonymously.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In order to verify YouTube creators with our Brave Payments system, we use the OAuth standard. Once the creator’s email is confirmed by our system, they are asked to verify their YouTube channel by connecting via Google; in turn, Google confirms with our&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://publishers.basicattentiontoken.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;publisher site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;that the creator has authenticated as an authorized owner of that channel, without revealing their credentials.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After the YouTube creator completes this verification process and opens an account with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://uphold.com/signup&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Uphold&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, they are eligible to start collecting monthly BAT contributions&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;from their audience. BAT contributions are automatically converted to fiat and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;may then be transferred to the creator’s bank account.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We look forward to seeing a new category of content creators on YouTube get rewarded via BAT. We plan on extending BAT to additional user-generated content platforms so that more creators can benefit from audience support, and anticipate seeing BAT’s utility grow as it supports more creators and publishers in our digital advertising and services platform.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et-waypoint et_pb_image et_pb_animation_left et_pb_image_0 et_always_center_on_mobile&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/images/Brave_Payments_Youtube-1.png&quot; class=&quot;et_pb_lightbox_image&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/images/Brave_Payments_Youtube-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text et_pb_module et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_text_2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brave Payments Log-In Screen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et-waypoint et_pb_image et_pb_animation_left et_pb_image_1 et_always_center_on_mobile&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/images/image3_1.png&quot; class=&quot;et_pb_lightbox_image&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/images/image3_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text et_pb_module et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_text_3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brave Payments Publisher Dashboard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et-waypoint et_pb_image et_pb_animation_left et_pb_image_2 et_always_center_on_mobile&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/images/image1.png&quot; class=&quot;et_pb_lightbox_image&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/images/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_section et_pb_section_2 et_pb_with_background et_section_regular&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; et_pb_row et_pb_row_1 et_pb_equal_columns et_pb_row_fullwidth&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_1_3 et_pb_column_1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et-waypoint et_pb_image et_pb_animation_left et_pb_image_3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/fonts/BAT_icon.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_1_3 et_pb_column_2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text et_pb_module et_pb_bg_layout_dark et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_text_4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Basic Attention Token is the new token for the digital advertising industry. It pays publishers for their content and users for their attention, while providing advertisers with more in return for their ads.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 14:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Helloworldboy</dc:creator>
<og:title>Brave expands Basic Attention Token platform to YouTube</og:title>
<og:url>https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Brave expands Basic Attention Token platform to YouTube</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://basicattentiontoken.org/brave-expands-basic-attention-token-platform-to-youtube/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Paradise Papers: How Ridiculously Easy It Is for the Rich to Avoid Taxes</title>
<link>https://rantt.com/the-paradise-papers-how-ridiculously-easy-it-is-for-the-rich-to-avoid-taxes-15b082cffb68</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://rantt.com/the-paradise-papers-how-ridiculously-easy-it-is-for-the-rich-to-avoid-taxes-15b082cffb68</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;fc2a&quot; id=&quot;fc2a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf--hasDropCapModel graf--hasDropCap graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;graf-dropCap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he revelations in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icij.org/investigations/paradise-papers/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.icij.org/investigations/paradise-papers/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Paradise Papers&lt;/a&gt; followed quickly on the release of the Panama Papers (English majors please note the allusion to the Pentagon Papers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4bfa&quot; id=&quot;4bfa&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Both of these Papers were revealed by an organization with the cumbersome name of The International Consortium of Independent Journals (ICIJ) — a group in need of a new name and a publicity agent. That name gives the impression of some mining cartel intent on keeping up the price of gold and diamonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;27a6&quot; id=&quot;27a6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;To the contrary, it is a group of dedicated journalists who recognized that they could not honestly report on tax evasion when they were working for mainstream media. The media barons and major advertisers are prime users of the tax evasion system. So these journalists gave up successful and lucrative careers to dedicate themselves to exposing offshore tax fraud. The Panama and Paradise Papers are a tribute to their courage, sacrifice, and dedication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bf5a&quot; id=&quot;bf5a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;However, the mainstream media uses the press tactic of ‘burying the lede’ by focusing on political leaders or corporate use of loopholes to the exclusion of a more serious underlying problem: &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;the billions of dollars that the 1% do not pay in taxes so that we bear the burden of maintaining the upkeep of the country and its growing debt.&lt;/strong&gt; Of course, everybody hates paying taxes. The super wealthy are no different in attitude, only in means. They can afford the ways to avoid paying taxes. In 2012, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.taxjustice.net/cms/upload/pdf/Price_of_Offshore_Revisited_120722.pdf&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.taxjustice.net/cms/upload/pdf/Price_of_Offshore_Revisited_120722.pdf&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tax Justice Network&lt;/a&gt; estimated that between $21 trillion and $32 trillion — the size of the U.S. and Japanese economies combined — was hidden in secrecy jurisdictions. If the tax evaded by wealthy individuals was collected, it would likely cover most of the annual deficit in each of the G7 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1dc0&quot; id=&quot;1dc0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;However, most reporting has obscured the tax fraud aspect, the most outrageous aspect of the disclosure. There are two types of these schemes: one is evasion, i.e. tax fraud, by which individuals do not pay taxes. At least &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icij.org/blog/2017/814/paradise-papers-queen-ross-global-reactions/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+GlobalMuckraker+%28The+Global+Muckraker%29&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.icij.org/blog/2017/814/paradise-papers-queen-ross-global-reactions/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+GlobalMuckraker+%28The+Global+Muckraker%29&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;31,000 of the individual&lt;/a&gt; and corporate clients included in the Paradise Paper records are U.S. citizens or have U.S. addresses, more than from any other country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;af1b&quot; id=&quot;af1b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The other scheme is tax avoidance, by which large corporations use government-provided loopholes and willful blindness to reduce their taxes paid by pretending to have made sales or expenses in low tax jurisdictions and reduce tax liability in the US. Apple and Amazon are examples that have been in the news for the avoidance type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;766b&quot; id=&quot;766b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In this article, I’m going to focus just on how wealthy individuals elude the tax man, how easy it is to do, and how easy it would be to stop it if the politicians of either party had the will to do it. That would mean, of course going against the wishes of their wealthy campaign donors. The corporate avoidance schemes will come in a later article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ec00&quot; id=&quot;ec00&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;You, the average taxpayer, probably pay about 20% to 30% of your annual income to your government in the form of income taxes. So, as you drive down an upscale street, lined with sixteen-room mansions set back on professionally landscaped lawns, you might be forgiven for thinking that they must be paying a whopping load of taxes. But that is not the case. That guy may be paying little or no taxes — they could be paying less than you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;724f&quot; id=&quot;724f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;While you and I might think that paying taxes is the price of living in a wonderful country, the 1% thinks differently. To them, dodging taxes is essential to wealth preservation. Taxation is tyranny.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*kMPXZMV75DxXyR2e.jpg&quot; data-width=&quot;347&quot; data-height=&quot;460&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*kMPXZMV75DxXyR2e.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c9e6&quot; id=&quot;c9e6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;As flamboyant New York business tycoon Leona Helmsley famously said to her maid:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;eb8c&quot; id=&quot;eb8c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We don’t pay taxes. Only the little people pay taxes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0221&quot; id=&quot;0221&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote&quot;&gt;During the First World War, when the governments introduced income taxes, the intent was to tax the wealthy more than lower-income residents. Today, however, the reverse is true. Thanks to complexity and loopholes in the tax rules, combined with a double standard in enforcement, the middle class pays far more taxes than some in the moneyed class. As well, the Income Tax Act has perfected the technique of appearing to do one thing while doing the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;716&quot; data-height=&quot;13&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;8441&quot; id=&quot;8441&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Featured Petition&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*b9_uk5r7hx4U52iw9PFtsQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;409&quot; data-height=&quot;6&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*b9_uk5r7hx4U52iw9PFtsQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;b1ee&quot; id=&quot;b1ee&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Do-It-Yourself Tax Evasion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5bff&quot; id=&quot;5bff&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Say you have a million or two to hide from the greedy Taxman. No problem: it’s a one-stop-shop process. The components will fall into place with the efficiency of a high-tech assembly line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;81ec&quot; id=&quot;81ec&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;First off, you have to find an offshore service provider. If you can flash sufficient cash, your local banker will put you in touch with such a provider. Or your lawyer or accountant might make a recommendation. There are many websites that blatantly offer thinly disguised tax evasion, but why take a risk of a public source when there are so many local advisers nearby operating in the shadows. Regardless, you will have at least eighty tried and thoroughly tested secrecy jurisdictions around the globe from which to choose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0396&quot; id=&quot;0396&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Let’s say you choose the Cayman Islands for your bank account. This British Overseas Territory encompasses three islands in the Western Caribbean, the largest of which is Grand Cayman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*LzCwZA07x3CNLpWx.gif&quot; data-width=&quot;322&quot; data-height=&quot;353&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*LzCwZA07x3CNLpWx.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;07ba&quot; id=&quot;07ba&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;BTW: the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.financialsecrecyindex.com&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.financialsecrecyindex.com&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt; — because of overseas territories like the Cayman Islands, the British Virgin Islands and so on — is a much larger secrecy jurisdiction than Switzerland.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8e72&quot; id=&quot;8e72&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;If you choose to visit the Caymans while you attend to the paperwork, it’s not a bad vacation stay. A day of deep-sea fishing is a common perk for opening an account. If it’s your first time, I suggest you make a pilgrimage stop at the Ugland House in George Town on Grand Cayman Island, the registered office for thousands of global companies. It is said to be the base for launching the Cayman Islands into one of the most famous offshore banking centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;13ac&quot; id=&quot;13ac&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In the Caymans, your service provider, a local law firm, will offer a choice of cookie cutter plans with layers of trusts and corporations in other secrecy jurisdictions, which will make it impossible for the tax man to pin down who actually owns the account. An economy option is adequate for most purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;01c4&quot; id=&quot;01c4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Your service provider will engage a f&lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.thestar.com/panama-papers/canada-signatures-for-sale/&quot; data-href=&quot;http://projects.thestar.com/panama-papers/canada-signatures-for-sale/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rontman&lt;/a&gt;. They do a high volume so their charges may be as low as $100. Their name — and their name alone — will appear on any documents related to the account. These guys do this for a living. They will not reside in the same country as you so as not to be subject to your country’s taxman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;566b&quot; id=&quot;566b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The Paradise Papers disclosed some new examples of this practice. An out-of-the-way small &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/06/world/bank-of-utah-leonid-mikhelson.html&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/06/world/bank-of-utah-leonid-mikhelson.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Utah bank&lt;/a&gt; acted as such a frontman so Russians and other foreigners could register their private jets appearing to be Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7aad&quot; id=&quot;7aad&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The next step is to establish a trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*b9_uk5r7hx4U52iw9PFtsQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;409&quot; data-height=&quot;6&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*b9_uk5r7hx4U52iw9PFtsQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;5b55&quot; id=&quot;5b55&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The Three Secret Documents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f227&quot; id=&quot;f227&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;A trust is essential because it is never publically registered. They can be created just like a contract, even on the back of a napkin. Most trusts in tax plans are drafted by lawyers and are kept on encrypted computer files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9cf6&quot; id=&quot;9cf6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The trust gives rise to a split in ownership. A mother may create a trust by putting $1 million savings bonds in trust for her two minor children appointing her lawyer as trustee with directions to pay the income to the children until they reach 25 and then pay the principal (corpus) to them then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bcaf&quot; id=&quot;bcaf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;The trustee is the legal owner.&lt;/strong&gt; He has the sole right to deal with the trust asset such as receive the interest and pay it out according to the terms of the trust and has sole control of the trust. The children are the beneficial owners. On these terms, the mother no longer has any control in law over the funds. Thus we have two classes of people who can legally claim the title owner: trustee and beneficial owner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*mS8vj51RE4k2TrIt.jpg&quot; data-width=&quot;400&quot; data-height=&quot;494&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*mS8vj51RE4k2TrIt.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c4df&quot; id=&quot;c4df&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;In tax evasion schemes, the trustee is the nominee noted above, you are the beneficial owner. The nominee then signs a power of attorney giving sole rights over the trust back to you. The power of attorney need not be registered either — secret document number two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;71c4&quot; id=&quot;71c4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The trust as yet has no assets. The asset will eventually be shares in a corporation to be incorporated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;710d&quot; id=&quot;710d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Next, we have the very helpful rule that corporate registrations in the US (and other G20 countries) only require disclosure of directors but never shareholders. The nominee’s name will appear on the corporate registration as director. As a double-blind, the shares are issued by the lawyer in the nominee’s name and subject to the secret power of attorney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*b9_uk5r7hx4U52iw9PFtsQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;409&quot; data-height=&quot;6&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*b9_uk5r7hx4U52iw9PFtsQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;f0b9&quot; id=&quot;f0b9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Tax Plan Continued&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9d96&quot; id=&quot;9d96&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;To establish your trust, I recommend you use the Seychelles Islands, way in the middle of the Indian Ocean. And, yes, experienced island lawyers are included in your package. Another plus, the Seychelles refuse to enforce foreign court orders. They don’t depend on foreign trade, but are economically self-sufficient from tourism — and selling tax relief. Your taxman cannot get a court order for disclosure enforced in the Seychelles. You have an impenetrable second firewall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4189&quot; id=&quot;4189&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Another perk, if you visit: the Seychelles are a favorite playground of celebrities of all types, movie, sports what have you. They combine holidaying with tax evading.You might get to share a beach with your favorite popstar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9474&quot; id=&quot;9474&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;You must now select a jurisdiction for the corporation that will apparently own the trust — be its “legal” owner. I suggest returning to the Caribbean and the lovely British Virgin Islands. Like the Caymans, this archipelago of four main islands and numerous small ones is a British Overseas Territory. The BVI &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icij.org/investigations/offshore/british-virgin-islands-forbidden-city/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.icij.org/investigations/offshore/british-virgin-islands-forbidden-city/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;contains&lt;/a&gt; as much as 40% of all offshore corporations worldwide and financial services — along with tourism — drive its economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*wUmjHl1r7BHDE2AN.png&quot; data-width=&quot;720&quot; data-height=&quot;478&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;0*wUmjHl1r7BHDE2AN.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*wUmjHl1r7BHDE2AN.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2a70&quot; id=&quot;2a70&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The Chinese respectfully call it the “New Forbidden City.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9ba6&quot; id=&quot;9ba6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Your BVI lawyers will assign you an ocean-blue, four-inch by four-inch mailbox in one of the many long rows found in the centre of Tortola, the main island, for the bargain rate of $22 a month. The BVI creed declares the islands are the true defenders of democracy. They provide the ultimate freedom of choice: the freedom not to pay taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;14ae&quot; id=&quot;14ae&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As an extra precaution, your lawyer will use another law firm to register the corporation. Only its name will be shown on public record as the owner’s lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fe4e&quot; id=&quot;fe4e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Now you have an impenetrable package. An account in the Caymans, owned by a secret trust that resides in the Sechelles, holding shares in a corporation incorporated in the British Virgin Islands by your nominee who has executed a secret power of attorney giving you full control. Your name as beneficial owner never appears on public records but is kept safe in the files of your service provider, which is often a global bank, and your offshore lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;faba&quot; id=&quot;faba&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;All are in secrecy jurisdictions. The only public document is the corporate registration. If the government does get an order to disclose the director’s name publicly, that registration would be by your frontman in some foreign country who is not a taxpayer of your country. The trust and power of attorney remain in the lawyer’s file. You, the beneficial owner, are never exposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9708&quot; id=&quot;9708&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Only a bank employee whistleblower or a hacker could pierce this plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;46d7&quot; id=&quot;46d7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A note to remember: The Cayman Islands were pirate headquarters in the early days of North American exploration. You’ve heard of its most famous resident, Captain Morgan. Makes you believe in reincarnation, doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5e8c&quot; id=&quot;5e8c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;My personal favorite plan of action for getting the money into your new secret piggy bank is the phony lawsuit. Your frontman sues you declaring you ran him down in the Caymans in a rented car. Because you were drinking and driving, your rental insurance was canceled. You, not your insurer, have to pay the victim. The phony plaintiff claims he is a 30-year-old banker with a promising future now rendered a quadriplegic. As luck would have it, just the day before the accident, he was accepted on full scholarship to Harvard Medical School where he planned to start a second career. It’s a multi-million dollar personal injury claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fd30&quot; id=&quot;fd30&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;All the usual lawsuit documents are prepared so it appears legit. You write a check in full settlement of the lawsuit. For the cost of a courier, you move the money to the Caribbean. Your nominee deposits it in your Caymans account. You can now use the money without trace outside of the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*b9_uk5r7hx4U52iw9PFtsQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;409&quot; data-height=&quot;6&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*b9_uk5r7hx4U52iw9PFtsQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;1486&quot; id=&quot;1486&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Bringing It All Home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;978e&quot; id=&quot;978e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;So, how do you get the money back home? You’ve seen the crude movie methods of cash in false-bottomed suitcases or taped to your body, or diamonds set in a cheap necklace. Such methods are not particularly effective, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b567&quot; id=&quot;b567&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Take the case of California rapper Snoop Dogg. In the summer of 2015, Snoop Dog &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/08/01/us-italy-snoopdogg-idUSKCN0Q637W20150801#bdxhO7VZ4xmRSQm9.97&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/08/01/us-italy-snoopdogg-idUSKCN0Q637W20150801#bdxhO7VZ4xmRSQm9.97&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tried&lt;/a&gt; to sneak $422,000 in cash through an Italian airport in his Louis Vuitton luggage. He was stopped by the police. In the European Union, and in many other jurisdictions carrying more than €10,000 in cash triggers anti-money laundering laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*IbdtjdTvXFW2bN8k.jpg&quot; data-width=&quot;800&quot; data-height=&quot;532&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;0*IbdtjdTvXFW2bN8k.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*IbdtjdTvXFW2bN8k.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/techcrunch/20984123694/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/techcrunch/20984123694/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;686d&quot; id=&quot;686d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Snoop Dogg’s agent explained that it was a minor administrative infraction in not declaring amounts more than €10,000 on leaving, a mere misunderstanding. But the leaving is not the issue. Snoop Dogg earned the funds legally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b417&quot; id=&quot;b417&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The question is why did he take the risk of carrying so much cash when he could have transferred the amount through a bank with the click of a mouse? Did he not want a record of the cash? What would Snoop Dogg do with the cash earned in a foreign country for which there was no record? Would he declare it on his US tax return? None of the reporters who cover the celebrity beat asked those questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;722a&quot; id=&quot;722a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The truth is you don’t have to use these movie-cliché methods. Creative methods abound. Of the many artful ways there is a morbid one worthy of the evil genius of Sherlock Holmes’s nemesis, Moriarty. It’s the phony insurance policy issued by a mailbox foreign insurance company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5d79&quot; id=&quot;5d79&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;There are multitudes of banks and insurance in the Caribbean islands that are no more than an address on a mailbox. You can incorporate them with the same ease as incorporating a company in the US. The cost is a bit more. Last time I saw one, it was $75,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;716f&quot; id=&quot;716f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This scheme revolves around the fact that an insurance policy payout is not taxable in the hands of the named beneficiary. So, how do you put it to work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;83a8&quot; id=&quot;83a8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;You must know someone living in your home country who is dying; everyone does. Perhaps a relative. Say you take out an insurance policy on dear Uncle Joe’s life. This is illegal in most countries, but this is not with a real insurance company. This phony company exists only to facilitate this type of tax evasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9e89&quot; id=&quot;9e89&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;When your Uncle Joe dies, the insurer pays. The cash goes into your bank account tax-free. How can the taxman prove otherwise? You have a policy and Uncle Joe’s valid death certificate issued by your own government. The money is home free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c172&quot; id=&quot;c172&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;If the phony insurance policy is too gruesome for you, you can find something more appealing in the summaries of the multitude of methods on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/businesses/small-businesses-self-employed/abusive-offshore-tax-avoidance-schemes-talking-points&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/businesses/small-businesses-self-employed/abusive-offshore-tax-avoidance-schemes-talking-points&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IRS website.&lt;/a&gt; A simple workaround would be to get a credit card from a foreign bank and pay it off through your secret bank account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2ffb&quot; id=&quot;2ffb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;If you’re not the DIY type, there are service providers. In a report for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scmp.com/business/article/1565727/fatca-regime-may-have-unintended-consequences-financial-system&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.scmp.com/business/article/1565727/fatca-regime-may-have-unintended-consequences-financial-system&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;South China News&lt;/a&gt;, Peter Guy tells of one. For a modest 22% commission, the service will deliver suitcases of cash to New York or Vancouver. Guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*b9_uk5r7hx4U52iw9PFtsQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;409&quot; data-height=&quot;6&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*b9_uk5r7hx4U52iw9PFtsQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a908&quot; id=&quot;a908&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Offshore secrecy jurisdictions are no longer reserved for the 1%. The innovative wealth-management industry has brought offshore within the means of the upscale. Do an internet search. You can set up an offshore account in any of the eighty or so secrecy jurisdictions for as little as $1,500. Beware: this is trickle-up marketing — to get you in the door. To achieve true anonymity, you will need more of the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a262&quot; id=&quot;a262&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As increasing affordability will permit tax evasion to spread, our deficit will grow in parallel. It’s impossible to really estimate how much this tax evasion by the superrich costs a country. &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/rampage/wp/2016/08/31/could-reducing-tax-cheating-close-the-deficit/?utm_term=.799f9ff1abe8&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/rampage/wp/2016/08/31/could-reducing-tax-cheating-close-the-deficit/?utm_term=.799f9ff1abe8&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; estimated that for 2016 the budget deficit was $590 billion and estimated tax evasion was $600 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;eaa2&quot; id=&quot;eaa2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;It’s easy to do and easy to stop&lt;/strong&gt;. Just require that everyone who applies for incorporation discloses under oath who the ultimate beneficial owner of the shares is, and either that there is no trust anywhere in the ownership chain or a declaration revealing who the beneficiaries of the trust are. This could fit on one page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;625f&quot; id=&quot;625f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Sounds like a motherhood issue for any politician. Curious how none are picking it up and no newspaper is waging a campaign against tax evasion by the super-rich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;716&quot; data-height=&quot;13&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;94d4&quot; id=&quot;94d4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Featured Petition&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;716&quot; data-height=&quot;13&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/ranttnews&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/ranttnews&quot; class=&quot;graf-imageAnchor&quot; data-action=&quot;image-link&quot; data-action-observe-only=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*JTzWvC0h-qkSUzXhKl36CA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1586&quot; data-height=&quot;777&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*JTzWvC0h-qkSUzXhKl36CA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;ea3b&quot; id=&quot;ea3b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pullquote graf-after--figure&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to help support projects like these, please consider helping us fund our operation by joining our community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;a2bf&quot; id=&quot;a2bf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--pullquote&quot;&gt;What We’re Offering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1cda&quot; id=&quot;1cda&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;$3 — Make A Difference!&lt;/strong&gt; Support Independent Journalism, get exclusive posts, and become a founding member of Rantt, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9ce6&quot; id=&quot;9ce6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;$10 — Join The Team!&lt;/strong&gt; 24/7 access to Rantt’s #Newsroom on Slack. Here you’ll be able to spectate &amp;amp; speak with the writers, editors, and founders as we discuss news and current events in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;23ab&quot; id=&quot;23ab&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;$20 — Get Published!&lt;/strong&gt; Work one-on-one with your own personal Rantt Editor to develop and write stories that you’d like to see published on our site. You come up with the story and we’ll make sure it’s Rantt ready in no time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2258&quot; id=&quot;2258&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;To see more of our offerings, check out our&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/ranttnews&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/ranttnews&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Patreon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;b4e5&quot; id=&quot;b4e5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://me.dm/r-7hZndQ0dQl?source=email-anon_abf705ef3afa--publication.newsletter&quot; data-href=&quot;http://me.dm/r-7hZndQ0dQl?source=email-anon_abf705ef3afa--publication.newsletter&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--h3-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JOIN US&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;6a40&quot; id=&quot;6a40&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--mixtapeEmbed&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Thanks again for everything. We love and appreciate you!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8061&quot; id=&quot;8061&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;02e6&quot; id=&quot;02e6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;The Rantt Team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f058&quot; id=&quot;f058&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Stay in the know and subscribe to our newsletter by following us on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://rantt.com&quot; data-href=&quot;https://rantt.com&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Rantt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;924f&quot; id=&quot;924f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RanttNews&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RanttNews&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;@RanttNews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7a40&quot; id=&quot;7a40&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Join us on Facebook:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/RanttNews/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/RanttNews/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;/RanttNews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;716&quot; data-height=&quot;13&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*Ww_KFCtvh6-_eEtVuZjWsg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 14:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>obi1kenobi</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Paradise Papers: How Ridiculously Easy It Is For The Rich To Avoid Taxes</og:title>
<og:url>https://rantt.com/the-paradise-papers-how-ridiculously-easy-it-is-for-the-rich-to-avoid-taxes-15b082cffb68</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*KVlAUiIkVcksKr47JOJZyw.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>A little too easy…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://rantt.com/the-paradise-papers-how-ridiculously-easy-it-is-for-the-rich-to-avoid-taxes-15b082cffb68?gi=7d05e3128877</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Walking away from $30,000 of DJI bounty money [pdf]</title>
<link>https://regmedia.co.uk/2017/11/16/whyiwalkedfrom3k.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://regmedia.co.uk/2017/11/16/whyiwalkedfrom3k.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2017/11/16/whyiwalkedfrom3k.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 11:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>druml</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Paradise Papers: How Ridiculously Easy It Is For The Rich To Avoid Taxes</og:title>
<og:url>https://rantt.com/the-paradise-papers-how-ridiculously-easy-it-is-for-the-rich-to-avoid-taxes-15b082cffb68</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*KVlAUiIkVcksKr47JOJZyw.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>A little too easy…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://regmedia.co.uk/2017/11/16/whyiwalkedfrom3k.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft Has Manually Patched Their Equation Editor Executable</title>
<link>https://0patch.blogspot.com/2017/11/did-microsoft-just-manually-patch-their.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://0patch.blogspot.com/2017/11/did-microsoft-just-manually-patch-their.html</guid>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;And They Did an Absolutely Stellar Job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;by Mitja Kolsek, the 0patch Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;A Pretty Old Executable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recent Patch Tuesday brought, among other things, a new version of &quot;old&quot; Equation Editor, which introduced a &lt;a href=&quot;https://portal.msrc.microsoft.com/en-US/security-guidance/advisory/CVE-2017-11882&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fix for a buffer overflow issue&lt;/a&gt; reported by &lt;a href=&quot;https://embedi.com/blog/skeleton-closet-ms-office-vulnerability-you-didnt-know-about&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Embedi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &quot;old&quot; Equation Editor is an &lt;em&gt;ancient&lt;/em&gt; component of Microsoft Office (Office now uses an integrated Equation Editor), which is confirmed by looking at the properties of the unpatched &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Enhu0lS8YnQ/Wg13751nRQI/AAAAAAAAAL4/23BAV5T2qf0ziKcOL5yJENLvZH7wr-_NwCLcBGAs/s1600/Equation_editor_properties.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;628&quot; data-original-width=&quot;552&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Enhu0lS8YnQ/Wg13751nRQI/AAAAAAAAAL4/23BAV5T2qf0ziKcOL5yJENLvZH7wr-_NwCLcBGAs/s640/Equation_editor_properties.png&quot; width=&quot;561&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can see that &lt;em&gt;File version&lt;/em&gt; is 2000.11.9.0 (implying being built in 2000), while &lt;em&gt;Date modified&lt;/em&gt; is in 2003, which matches the time of its signature (signing modifies the file as the signature is attached to it.) Furthermore, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/desktop/ms680547(v=vs.85).aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;TimeDateStamp&lt;/em&gt; in its PE header&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span&gt;3A0ACEBF&lt;/span&gt;), which the compiler writes into the executable module when building it, indicates that the file was built on November 9, 2000 - exactly matching the date in the above version number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jCGvXVbNrIs/Wg2esj3Sv-I/AAAAAAAAAMI/UJuomV8JoE441wVNodpr8HqjZcNdwZEAACLcBGAs/s1600/Equation_editor_timestamp.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;227&quot; data-original-width=&quot;636&quot; height=&quot;227&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jCGvXVbNrIs/Wg2esj3Sv-I/AAAAAAAAAMI/UJuomV8JoE441wVNodpr8HqjZcNdwZEAACLcBGAs/s640/Equation_editor_timestamp.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;We're therefore safe to claim that the vulnerable &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt; has been with us since 2000. That's 17 years, which is a pretty respectable life span for software!&lt;p&gt;So now a vulnerability was reported in this executable and Microsoft spawned their fixing procedure: they reproduced the issue using Embedi's proof-of-concept, confirmed it, took the source code, fixed the issue in the source code, re-built &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt;, and distributed the fixed version to Office users, who now see version 2017.8.14.0 under its properties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At least that's how it &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; work for most other vulnerabilities. But something was different here. For some reason, Microsoft didn't fix this issue in the source code - but rather by manually patching the binary executable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manually Patching an EXE?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Really, quite literally, some pretty skilled Microsoft employee or contractor reverse engineered our friend &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt;, located the flawed code, and corrected it by manually overwriting existing instructions with better ones (making sure to only use the space previously occupied by original instructions).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do we know that? Well, have you ever met a C/C++ compiler that would put all functions in a 500+ KB executable on &lt;strong&gt;exactly the same address in the module&lt;/strong&gt; after rebuilding a modified source code, especially when these modifications changed the amount of code in several functions?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To clarify, let's look at BinDiff results between the fixed (2017.8.14.0, &quot;primary&quot;) and vulnerable version (2000.11.9.0, &quot;secondary&quot;) of &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ifCAOWoNy9M/Wg2madMZOiI/AAAAAAAAAM0/A7EayU-hO-ccnTJpABWZUQVxTHb_TsQ0ACLcBGAs/s1600/Equation_Editor_diff_matched_functions.PNG&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;495&quot; data-original-width=&quot;657&quot; height=&quot;482&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ifCAOWoNy9M/Wg2madMZOiI/AAAAAAAAAM0/A7EayU-hO-ccnTJpABWZUQVxTHb_TsQ0ACLcBGAs/s640/Equation_Editor_diff_matched_functions.PNG&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're diffing binaries a lot, you'll notice something highly peculiar: All &lt;em&gt;EA primary&lt;/em&gt; values are identical to &lt;em&gt;EA secondary&lt;/em&gt; values of matched functions. Even the matched but obviously different functions listed at the bottom are at the same address in both &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt; versions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we already &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/0patch/status/930803478930345984&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;noted on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft modified five functions in &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt;, namely the bottom-most five functions listed on the above image. Let's look at the most-modified one first, the one at address &lt;span&gt;4164FA&lt;/span&gt;. The patched version is on the left, the vulnerable one on the right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-nDogtRmbob8/Wg22vFYPkNI/AAAAAAAAANE/xKeWoIeUqasm2bB7Nurr-Dzt484jg8m2wCLcBGAs/s1600/Equation_Editor_diff_patched_function.PNG&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1143&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;456&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-nDogtRmbob8/Wg22vFYPkNI/AAAAAAAAANE/xKeWoIeUqasm2bB7Nurr-Dzt484jg8m2wCLcBGAs/s640/Equation_Editor_diff_patched_function.PNG&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This function takes a pointer to the destination buffer and copies characters, one by one in a loop, from user-supplied string to this buffer. It is also the very function that Embedi found to be vulnerable in their research; namely, there was no check whether the destination buffer was large enough for the user-supplied string, and a too-long font name provided through the Equation object could cause a buffer overflow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft's fix introduced an additional parameter to this function, specifying the destination buffer length. The original logic of the character-copying loop was then modified so that the loop ends not only when the source string end is reached, but also when the destination buffer length is reached - preventing buffer overflow. In addition, the copied string in the destination buffer is zero-terminated after copying, in case the destination buffer length was reached (which would leave the string unterminated).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's look at the code in its text form (again, patched function on left, vulnerable on right):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-2jBHdAeUQK0/Wg3BqTo3xyI/AAAAAAAAANU/HmcA89oqR8AQk0EFI-y_NjaDqXI9DJZZQCLcBGAs/s1600/Patched_function_code_diff.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;627&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-2jBHdAeUQK0/Wg3BqTo3xyI/AAAAAAAAANU/HmcA89oqR8AQk0EFI-y_NjaDqXI9DJZZQCLcBGAs/s640/Patched_function_code_diff.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
As you can see, whoever patched this function not only added a check for buffer length in it, but also managed to make the function 14 bytes shorter (and padded the resulting gap before the adjacent function with &lt;span&gt;0xCC&lt;/span&gt; bytes for style points :). Impressive.&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patching The Callers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving on. If the patched function got an additional parameter, all those calling it would have to change as well, right? There are exactly two callers of this function, at addresses &lt;span&gt;43B418&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span&gt;4181FA&lt;/span&gt;, and in the patched version they both have a &lt;span&gt;push&lt;/span&gt; instruction added before the call to specify the length of their buffers, &lt;span&gt;0x100&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span&gt;0x1F4&lt;/span&gt; respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, a &lt;span&gt;push&lt;/span&gt; instruction with a 32-bit literal operand takes 5 bytes. In order to add this instruction to these two functions while staying within the tight space of the original code (whose logic must also remain intact), the patcher did the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For function at address &lt;span&gt;43B418&lt;/span&gt;, the patched function temporarily stores some value - which it will need later on - in &lt;span&gt;ebx&lt;/span&gt; instead of a local stack-based variable, which releases enough bytes for injecting the &lt;span&gt;push&lt;/span&gt; call. (By the way, addievidence of manual patching is that while the local variable is no longer used, space for it is still made on the stack; otherwise &lt;span&gt;sub esp, 0x10C&lt;/span&gt; would turn into &lt;span&gt;sub esp, 0x108&lt;/span&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-YWFtQxdtQrc/Wg3HcZfc89I/AAAAAAAAANk/4MaiGXbVAN0v2fYM5l03319nzV1dAY0wgCLcBGAs/s1600/Equation_Editor_diff_43B418.PNG&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;595&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1101&quot; height=&quot;344&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-YWFtQxdtQrc/Wg3HcZfc89I/AAAAAAAAANk/4MaiGXbVAN0v2fYM5l03319nzV1dAY0wgCLcBGAs/s640/Equation_Editor_diff_43B418.PNG&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the other caller, function at address &lt;span&gt;4181FA&lt;/span&gt;, the patched function mysteriously has the &lt;span&gt;push&lt;/span&gt; instruction injected without any other modifications to the code that would introduce the needed extra space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-a83KyPafDf4/Wg3Kg3iLw0I/AAAAAAAAANw/6JlDMhGZPvkJu6GAnQmUuMeTIZCpL6D5wCLcBGAs/s1600/Equation_Editor_diff_4181FA.PNG&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1254&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-a83KyPafDf4/Wg3Kg3iLw0I/AAAAAAAAANw/6JlDMhGZPvkJu6GAnQmUuMeTIZCpL6D5wCLcBGAs/s640/Equation_Editor_diff_4181FA.PNG&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;As you can see on the above image, the &lt;span&gt;push&lt;/span&gt; instruction is injected at the beginning of the yellow block, and all original instructions in that block are pushed down 5 bytes. But why does this not overwrite 5 bytes of the original code somewhere else? It's as if there were 5 or more unused bytes already in existence just after this block of code that the patcher could safely overwrite.&lt;p&gt;To solve this mystery, let's look at the code in its text form.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3oBrhl4rZhM/Wg3OL-9df-I/AAAAAAAAAN8/9yhIbEiD-ko1jsMkQpcHpUWc8SY9-MzXwCLcBGAs/s1600/4181FA_code_diff.PNG&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;312&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;124&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3oBrhl4rZhM/Wg3OL-9df-I/AAAAAAAAAN8/9yhIbEiD-ko1jsMkQpcHpUWc8SY9-MzXwCLcBGAs/s640/4181FA_code_diff.PNG&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Surprise, the vulnerable version actually had an extra &lt;span&gt;jmp loc_418318&lt;/span&gt; instruction at the end of the modified code block. How convenient! This allows the code in this block to be moved down 5 bytes, making space for the &lt;span&gt;push&lt;/span&gt; instruction at the top.&lt;p&gt;Coincidence? Perhaps, but it looks an awful lot like this code block got manually modified before in the past, whereby it got shortened for 5 bytes and its last instruction (&lt;span&gt;jmp loc_418318&lt;/span&gt;) was left there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Security Checks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What we've covered so far was related to Embedi's published research and CVE-2017-11882. Their described buffer overflow would now be prevented by checking for the destination buffer length. But the new version of &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt; has two additional modified functions at addresses &lt;span&gt;41160F&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span&gt;4219F0&lt;/span&gt;. Let's have a look at them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the patched executable, these two functions got a bunch of injected boundary checks for copying to what appear to be &lt;span&gt;0x20&lt;/span&gt;-byte buffers. These checks all look the same: &lt;span&gt;ecx&lt;/span&gt; (which is the counter for copying) is compared to &lt;span&gt;0x21&lt;/span&gt;; if it's greater than or equal to that, &lt;span&gt;ecx&lt;/span&gt; gets set to &lt;span&gt;0x20&lt;/span&gt;. All these checks are injected right before inlined &lt;span&gt;memcpy&lt;/span&gt; operations. Let's look at one of them to see how the patcher made room for the additional instructions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Qg9fbwOlIxs/Wg4d_6aZJAI/AAAAAAAAAOM/vZfGowBNtfMHWIin4QZgDdk4t-I6kGvGACLcBGAs/s1600/Equation_Editor_diff_41160F.PNG&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;877&quot; data-original-width=&quot;911&quot; height=&quot;616&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Qg9fbwOlIxs/Wg4d_6aZJAI/AAAAAAAAAOM/vZfGowBNtfMHWIin4QZgDdk4t-I6kGvGACLcBGAs/s640/Equation_Editor_diff_41160F.PNG&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;As shown on the above image, a check is injected before the inlined &lt;span&gt;memcpy&lt;/span&gt; code. Note that in 32-bit code, &lt;span&gt;memcpy&lt;/span&gt; is typically implemented by first copying blocks of 4 bytes using the &lt;span&gt;movsd&lt;/span&gt; (move double word) instruction, while any remaining bytes are then copied using &lt;span&gt;movsb&lt;/span&gt; (move byte). This is efficient in terms of performance, but whoever was patching this noticed that some space can be freed by only using &lt;span&gt;movsb&lt;/span&gt;, and perhaps sacrificing a nanosecond or two. After doing so, the code remained logically identical but now there was space for injecting the check before it, as well as for zero-terminating the copied string. Again, an impressive and clever hack (and there was still an extra byte to spare - notice the &lt;span&gt;nop&lt;/span&gt;?)&lt;p&gt;There are six such length checks in two modified functions, and since they don't seem to be related to fixing CVE-2017-11882, we believe that Microsoft noticed some additional attack vectors that could also cause a buffer overflow and decided to proactively patch them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Touches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After patching the vulnerable code and effectively manually building a new version of Equation Editor, the patcher also corrected the version number of &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt; to 2017.8.14.0, and the &lt;em&gt;TimeDateStamp&lt;/em&gt; in the PE header to August 14, 2017 (hex value &lt;span&gt;5991FA38&lt;/span&gt;) - which is just 10 days after Microsoft acknowledged receipt of Embedi's report. (Note however that due to the manual nature of setting these values it's possible that code has been modified after that date.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maintaining a software product in its binary form instead of rebuilding it from modified source code is hard. We can only speculate as to why Microsoft used the binary patching approach, but being binary patchers ourselves we think they did a stellar job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This old Equation Editor is now under the spotlight, and many researchers are likely to start fuzzing it for additional vulnerabilities. If any are found, we'll probably see additional rounds of manual binary patches in &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt;. While Office has had a new Equation Editor integrated since at least version 2007, Microsoft can't simply remove &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt; (the old Equation Editor) from Office as there are probably tons of old documents out there containing equations in this old format, which would then become un-editable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now how would we micropatch CVE-2017-11882 with 0patch? It would actually be much easier: we wouldn't have to shrink existing code to make room for the injected one, because 0patch makes sure that we get all the space we need. So we wouldn't have to come up with clever hacks like de-optimizing &lt;span&gt;memcpy&lt;/span&gt; or finding an alternative place to temporarily store a value for later use. This freedom and flexibility makes developing an in-memory micropatch much easier and quicker than in-file patching, and we believe software vendors like Microsoft could benefit greatly from using in-memory micropatching for fixing critical vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh by the way, Microsoft also updated Office's &lt;span&gt;wwlib.dll&lt;/span&gt; this Patch Tuesday, prompting us to port our &lt;a href=&quot;https://0patch.blogspot.com/2017/10/0patching-office-dde-ddeauto.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DDE / DDEAUTO patches&lt;/a&gt; to these new versions. 0patch Agent running on your computer will automatically download and apply these new patches without interrupting you. If you don't have 0patch Agent installed yet, we have good news for you: IT'S FREE! Just &lt;a href=&quot;http://0patch.com/download.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;, install and register, and you're all set. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mkolsek&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@mkolsek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/0patch&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@0patch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;P.S.: If you happen to know the person(s) who did the binary patching of &lt;span&gt;EQNEDT32.EXE&lt;/span&gt;, please send them a link to this blog post. We'd like them to know how much we admire their work. Thanks! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 10:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dielel</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://0patch.blogspot.com/2017/11/did-microsoft-just-manually-patch-their.html</og:url>
<og:title>Did Microsoft Just Manually Patch Their Equation Editor Executable? Why Yes, Yes They Did. (CVE-2017-11882)</og:title>
<og:description>And They Did an Absolutely Stellar Job by Mitja Kolsek, the 0patch Team A Pretty Old Executable The recent Patch Tuesday brought, am...</og:description>
<og:image>https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Enhu0lS8YnQ/Wg13751nRQI/AAAAAAAAAL4/23BAV5T2qf0ziKcOL5yJENLvZH7wr-_NwCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/Equation_editor_properties.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://0patch.blogspot.com/2017/11/did-microsoft-just-manually-patch-their.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla Roadster</title>
<link>https://www.tesla.com/roadster/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.tesla.com/roadster/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/roadster/&quot;&gt;https://www.tesla.com/roadster/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15719262&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15719262&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 1187&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 687&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 05:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>franl</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.tesla.com/</og:url>
<og:title>Roadster | Tesla</og:title>
<og:image>https://www.tesla.com/sites/default/files/images/software_update.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.tesla.com/roadster/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Speed up your Python using Rust</title>
<link>https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2017/11/16/speed-python-using-rust/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2017/11/16/speed-python-using-rust/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2017/11/16/speed-python-using-rust/&quot;&gt;https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2017/11/16/speed-python-using-rust/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15719254&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15719254&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 265&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 90&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 05:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jD91mZM2</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2017/11/16/speed-python-using-rust/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>