<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>SubEthaEdit 5 is now free and open source</title>
<link>https://rant.monkeydom.de/posts/2018/11/28/see-is-back</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://rant.monkeydom.de/posts/2018/11/28/see-is-back</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new version 5 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://subethaedit.net&quot;&gt;SubEthaEdit&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Design_Awards#2003&quot;&gt;Apple Design Award winning&lt;/a&gt; text editor for macOS, is now available free of charge in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://subethaedit.net/appstore&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt; and as &lt;a href=&quot;https://subethaedit.net/SubEthaEdit.zip&quot;&gt;direct download&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/subethaedit/SubEthaEdit&quot;&gt;complete source code&lt;/a&gt; with history going back 15 years is also available under the MIT License.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release fills me with great pride and joy. SubEthaEdit always has a special place in my heart. It is where my journey as a developer in the Apple ecosystem started. I owe it the position I am in today. This connection is why I'm taking the time to maintain it again and try to lead it towards a long lasting future. Therefore I think it is worthwhile looking at how everything came together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started with the initial set of peers at our university at the end of 2002: Ulrich Bauer, Martin Ott, &lt;a href=&quot;https://martin.pittenauer.com&quot;&gt;Martin Pittenauer&lt;/a&gt; and me. As university students we wanted to build something real. So we searched for a project to grow into a fully grown app. Motivated by the Apple Design Awards competition, we challenged ourselves with a fitting deadline to do submit an entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point in time there weren't many good native text editors on the platform, so doing a general purpose text editor was always an aspiration of mine. I had recently switched from my old &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RiscPC&quot;&gt;Acorn RiscPC&lt;/a&gt; over to the Mac, and was really missing my then beloved &lt;a href=&quot;http://stronged.iconbar.com&quot;&gt;StrongEd&lt;/a&gt; (fair warning that website is quite a sight, as sadly most of the RiscOS ecosystem is and almost always was in terms of style).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was playing around with the existing text editors, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/&quot;&gt;BBEdit&lt;/a&gt; really wasn't for me (and at this time very Carbon, and as such looked dated and did not integrate too smoothly into the new OS X). Personally I went with MacroMedia's Dreamweaver as the least bad option for my web development work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily one of us dug up an old &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/220876978_High-Latency_Low-Bandwidth_Windowing_in_the_Jupiter_Collaboration_System&quot;&gt;Xerox Parc Paper&lt;/a&gt; that showed how latency free live collaboration can be done. At that time it fit perfectly with the newly released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q892647&quot;&gt;Bonjour&lt;/a&gt; technology to allow for networking without configuration between Macs. That was super exciting and we quickly got to a point where we could see this technology as viable and so we went on to build our application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was with great joy that we submitted our freely available work, then named &lt;strong&gt;Hydra&lt;/strong&gt;, to the awards, and with even more joy that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Design_Awards#2003&quot;&gt;we won&lt;/a&gt; in the student category we applied in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Design_Awards#2003&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rant.monkeydom.de/assets/posts/ADA2003.svg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rant.monkeydom.de/assets/posts/ADA2003.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time we didn't charge any money for it. Only at the end of our university careers, the three remaining of us started out our luck as &lt;a href=&quot;https://codingmonkeys.de&quot;&gt;TheCodingMonkeys&lt;/a&gt; to live the dream of a Mac indie studio. We all started out doing this part time, the transition from free software to paid shareware did not support more than one person at that time. And while it was fantastic to see SubEthaEdit being used in conferences all over the world, the financial aspects weren't looking great for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marketing wise we shoehorned ourselves into the collaborative aspects, and failed to communicate the fact that SubEthaEdit was a great general purpose text editor of its own right. Worse, the commercial start of SubEthaEdit was overshadowed by the then not yet released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q2297533&quot;&gt;TextMate&lt;/a&gt;. This was mainly based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q719413&quot;&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/a&gt;'s well deserved hype of the initial &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gzj723LkRJY&quot;&gt;ruby on rails videos&lt;/a&gt; featuring it. So we lost the race for the second most popular text editor on the platform (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/&quot;&gt;BBEdit&lt;/a&gt; still got the first place because of Mac users loyalty and steady development), and therefore the commercial success too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was at this point that we began struggling a little. While we had enough success to sustain one person, we were not on track to support more than that. Developing and maintaining SubEthaEdit easily consumed most of our time though. It is by that fact, that we all had still day jobs. And while we dabbled in other product ideas (one of the bigger ones a more creative writing based collaboration tool codenamed 'Fenchurch') we didn't get to produce any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rant.monkeydom.de/assets/posts/SEE5-Fenchurch.png&quot; width=&quot;243&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fenchurch prototype mockup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead we got another lucky break. The great folks at &lt;a href=&quot;https://panic.com&quot;&gt;Panic&lt;/a&gt; were planning their then secret &lt;a href=&quot;https://panic.com/coda&quot;&gt;Coda&lt;/a&gt;, and were looking for something they could base their editing engine on. And that influx of financial support was what enabled us to become a real working company. We are forever grateful to &lt;a href=&quot;https://panic.com&quot;&gt;Panic&lt;/a&gt; for this, as they essentially gave us this opportunity. This was the point in time when Martin Ott, our third co-founder left us, and we started venturing to build &lt;a href=&quot;https://carcassonneapp.com&quot;&gt;Carcassonne&lt;/a&gt; for iOS. Another project of mine that was very close to my heart. I have been a board game geek from my early teens on, and joining this with my professional world was just a fantastic opportunity. It also gave me the opportunity to do real production work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.erlang.org&quot;&gt;Erlang&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of Carcassonne also had a somewhat unfortunate side effect for us: With still no real viable long term business story for SubEthaEdit it moved more and more on the back burner. We still maintained it and brought it up to the App Store eventually, but sadly it couldn't prove its financial viability. A big shout out goes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ellduin&quot;&gt;Lisa Brodner&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/merrysuperstar&quot;&gt;Michael Ehrmann&lt;/a&gt;, who took the bulk of the work to create the 4.x releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while it served us well, even for our own development – SubEthaEdit was our main editor to develop it, in the times of Project Builder with external editor support – it did not plant roots in any specific community. And with Xcode slowly getting better, moving to the single window layout only and providing all the Project aware metadata we couldn't, even our own top use case went away. However, we are still very fond of it and use it for all things scripting and of course text creation and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forwarding to 4 years ago, I left TheCodingMonkeys to try my luck in the US working for UIKit at Apple while Martin Pittenauer took over the company. It was with both surprise and delight that I experienced how SubEthaEdit still resonated with many of my colleagues there. Even with the success of Carcassonne, SubEthaEdit seemed to have been the product that was part of many of their pasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now that I'm back to a more independent life I feel that SubEthaEdit deserves a future. Although I'm not rejoining TheCodingMonkeys, we are on good terms and we were able to make an arrangement that hopefully proves beneficial to everyone. From today on SubEthaEdit will be free and open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What was the focus for this release?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bring the code base into a state that builds fine and fully supports macOS Mojave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a nice repository with as much history as possible, both for reference and educational purposes &lt;em&gt;(Fun fact: SubEthaEdit started out in Subversion, had a long time in Mercurial and very much later moved on to git)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update and or remove dependent libraries, support current Mojave features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get into shape for dual App Store and Website download releases, so contributions can have a quick turnaround time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the dependency on the Website for system integration, e.g. the see tool and authorization scripts are now part of the distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;What are my hopes for the future?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Attract contributors to ensure a long term thriving ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The free availability both in and out of the App Store should reduce the barrier to entry to the collaborative use cases in education, pair programming, etc, leading to good bug reports and use cases that are worth investing some future development in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for more languages, modes and contributions thereof&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Longevity of SubEthaEdit as a product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I hope you all share and enjoy this release, file bug reports, enhancement requests and contribute the scripts, modes and styles you make.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 11:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>schwuk</dc:creator>
<og:title>rant-dom: SubEthaEdit 5 – Now free and open source!</og:title>
<og:image>https://rant.monkeydom.de/assets/square1024.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://rant.monkeydom.de/posts/2018/11/28/see-is-back</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>South Koreans lock themselves up to escape prison of daily life</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-southkorea-prisonstay-idUSKCN1NS0JB</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-southkorea-prisonstay-idUSKCN1NS0JB</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;HONGCHEON, South Korea (Reuters) - For most people, prison is a place to escape from. For South Koreans in need of a break from the demands of everyday life, a day in a faux jail is the escape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This prison gives me a sense of freedom,” said Park Hye-ri, a 28-year-old office worker who paid $90 to spend 24 hours locked up in a mock prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2013, the “Prison Inside Me” facility in northeast Hongcheon has hosted more than 2,000 inmates, many of them stressed office workers and students seeking relief from South Korea’s demanding work and academic culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was too busy,” said Park as she sat in a 5-sq-m (54-sq-foot) cell. “I shouldn’t be here right now, given the work I need to do. But I decided to pause and look back at myself for a better life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(To see accompanying package, click on &lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/2qZ4D1a&quot;&gt;reut.rs/2qZ4D1a&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prison rules are strict. No talking with other inmates. No mobile phones or clocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clients get a blue prison uniform, a yoga mat, tea set, a pen and notebook. They sleep on the floor. There is a small toilet inside the room, but no mirror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The menu includes steamed sweet potato and a banana shake for dinner, and rice porridge for breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-founder Noh Ji-Hyang said the mock prison was inspired by her husband, a prosecutor who often put in 100-hour work weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He said he would rather go into solitary confinement for a week to take a rest and feel better,” she said. “That was the beginning.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A downturn in South Korea’s high-tech, export-driven economy has intensified a hyper-competitive school and work environment that experts say adds to a high incidence of stress and suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Koreans worked 2,024 hours on average in 2017, the third longest after Mexico and Costa Rica, in a survey of 36 member countries in the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_container Slideshow_small Slideshow_standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_preview-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20181123&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1327839504&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEEAM0EI&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;Slideshow_count&quot;&gt;(27 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help people work less and earn more, the government has raised the minimum wage and cut the legal cap on working hours to 52 per week from 68. But the policies could backfire and put at risk more jobs than they create, economists say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noh said some customers are wary of spending 24 or 48 hours in a prison cell, until they try it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“After a stay in the prison, people say, ‘This is not a prison, the real prison is where we return to,’” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by Minwoo Park and Yijin Kim; Editing by Josh Smith and Darren Schuettler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 21:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jacobbudin</dc:creator>
<og:title>South Koreans lock themselves up to escape prison of daily life</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-southkorea-prisonstay-idUSKCN1NS0JB</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>For most people, prison is a place to escape from. For South Koreans in need of ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20181123&amp;t=2&amp;i=1327839504&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEEAM0EI</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-southkorea-prisonstay-idUSKCN1NS0JB</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AWS Ground Station – Ingest and Process Data from Orbiting Satellites</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-ground-station-ingest-and-process-data-from-orbiting-satellites/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-ground-station-ingest-and-process-data-from-orbiting-satellites/</guid>
<description>&lt;table id=&quot;amazon-polly-audio-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;amazon-polly-audio-tab&quot;&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;amazon-polly-by-tab&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/polly/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://a0.awsstatic.com/aws-blog/images/Voiced_by_Amazon_Polly_EN.png&quot; width=&quot;554&quot; height=&quot;56&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2018/gs_sat_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Not an actual satellite&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; height=&quot;470&quot;/&gt;Did you know that there are currently thousands of satellites orbiting the Earth? I certainly did not, and would have guessed a few hundred at most. Today, high school and college students design, fabricate, and launch nano-, pico-, and even femto-satellites such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CubeSat&quot;&gt;CubeSats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PocketQube&quot;&gt;PocketQubes&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://femtosat.asu.edu/&quot;&gt;SunCubes&lt;/a&gt;. On the commercial side, organizations of any size can now launch satellites for Earth observation, communication, media distribution, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of these satellites collect a lot of data, and that’s where things get even more interesting. While it is now relatively cheap to get a satellite into &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Low_Earth_orbit&quot;&gt;Low Earth Orbit&lt;/a&gt; (LEO) or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medium_Earth_orbit&quot;&gt;Medium Earth Orbit&lt;/a&gt; (MEO) and only slightly more expensive to achieve a more distant &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geostationary_orbit&quot;&gt;Geostationary Orbit&lt;/a&gt;, getting that data back to Earth is still more difficult than it should be. Large-scale satellite operators often build and run their own ground stations at a cost of up to one million dollars or more each; smaller operators enter into inflexible long-term contracts to make use of existing ground stations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the challenges that I reviewed above may remind you of those early, pre-cloud days when you had to build and run your own data center. That changed when we &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/amazon_ec2_beta/&quot;&gt;launched Amazon EC2&lt;/a&gt; back in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing AWS Ground Station&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Today I would like to tell you about &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Ground Station&lt;/span&gt;. Amazon EC2 made compute power accessible on a cost-effective, pay-as-you-go basis. &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Ground Station&lt;/span&gt; does the same for satellite ground stations. Instead of building your own ground station or entering in to a long-term contract, you can make use of &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Ground Station&lt;/span&gt; on an as-needed, pay-as-you-go basis. You can get access to a ground station on short notice in order to handle a special event: severe weather, a natural disaster, or something more positive such as a sporting event. If you need access to a ground station on a regular basis to capture Earth observations or distribute content world-wide, you can reserve capacity ahead of time and pay even less. &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Ground Station&lt;/span&gt; is a fully managed service. You don’t need to build or maintain antennas, and can focus on your work or research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re starting out with a pair of ground stations today, and will have 12 in operation by mid-2019. Each ground station is associated with a particular AWS Region; the raw analog data from the satellite is processed by our modem digitizer into a data stream (in what is formally known as VITA 49 baseband or VITA 49 RF over IP data streams) and routed to an EC2 instance that is responsible for doing the signal processing to turn it into a byte stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the data is in digital form, you have a host of streaming, processing, analytics, and storage options. Here’s a starter list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streaming&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/streams/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon Kinesis Data Streams&lt;/a&gt; to capture, process, and store data streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processing&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/rekognition/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon Rekognition&lt;/a&gt; for image analysis; &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/sagemaker/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon SageMaker&lt;/a&gt; to build, train, and deploy ML models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytics / Reporting&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon Redshift&lt;/a&gt; to store processed data in structured data warehouse form; &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/athena&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon Athena&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://quicksight.aws&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon QuickSight&lt;/a&gt; for queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/s3/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)&lt;/a&gt; to store data in object form, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/glacier/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon Glacier&lt;/a&gt; for long-term archival storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your entire workflow, from the ground stations all the way through to processing, storage, reporting, and delivery, can now be done on elastic, pay-as-you-go infrastructure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS Ground Station in Action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I did not have an actual satellite to test with, so the &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Ground Station&lt;/span&gt; team created an imaginary one in my account! When you are ready to make use of &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Ground Station&lt;/span&gt;, we’ll need your satellite’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satellite_Catalog_Number&quot;&gt;NORAD ID&lt;/a&gt;, information about your FCC license, and your AWS account number so that we can associate it with your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I open the Ground Station Console and click &lt;strong&gt;Reserve contacts now&lt;/strong&gt; to get started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2018/gs_main_2.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;605&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to reserve a contact (an upcoming time when my satellite will be in the optimal position to transmit to the ground station I choose). I choose a ground station from the menu:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2018/gs_pick_a_gs_3.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;333&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can filter based on status (&lt;strong&gt;Available&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Scheduled&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;Completed&lt;/strong&gt;) and on a time range:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2018/gs_filter_3.png&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;330&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can see the contacts, pick one that meets my requirements, select it, and click &lt;strong&gt;Reserve Contact&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2018/gs_contacts_3.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;336&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I confirm my contact on the next page, and click &lt;strong&gt;Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2018/gs_reserve_5.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;366&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I can filter the &lt;strong&gt;Contacts&lt;/strong&gt; list to show all of my upcoming reservations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2018/gs_my_reservations_4.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;430&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my contact has been reserved, I make sure that my EC2 instances will be running in the AWS Region associated with the ground station at least 15 minutes ahead of the start time. The instance responsible for the signal processing connects to an Elastic Network Interface (ENI), uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rtlogic.com/products/datadefender&quot;&gt;DataDefender&lt;/a&gt; to manage the data transfer, and routes the data to a software modem such as qRadio to convert it to digital form (we’ll provide customers with a CloudFormation template that will create the ENI and do all of the other setup work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things to Know&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here are a couple of things you should know about &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Ground Station&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access&lt;/strong&gt; – Due to the nature of this service, access is not self-serve. You will need to communicate with our team in order to register your satellite(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ground Stations&lt;/strong&gt; – As I mentioned earlier, we are launching today with 2 ground stations, and will have a total of 12 in operation by 2019. We will monitor utilization and demand, and will build additional stations and antennas as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing&lt;/strong&gt; – Pricing is per-minute of downlink time, with an option to pre-pay for blocks of minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffbarr&quot;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 20:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>leef</dc:creator>
<og:title>AWS Ground Station – Ingest and Process Data from Orbiting Satellites | Amazon Web Services</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-ground-station-ingest-and-process-data-from-orbiting-satellites/</og:url>
<og:description>Did you know that there are currently thousands of satellites orbiting the Earth? I certainly did not, and would have guessed a few hundred at most. Today, high school and college students design, fabricate, and launch nano-, pico-, and even femto-satellites such as CubeSats, PocketQubes, and SunCubes. On the commercial side, organizations of any size […]</og:description>
<og:image>https://d2908q01vomqb2.cloudfront.net/da4b9237bacccdf19c0760cab7aec4a8359010b0/2018/11/20/gs_main_2.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-ground-station-ingest-and-process-data-from-orbiting-satellites/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>China Expands Research Funding, Luring U.S. Scientists and Students</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/11/27/669645323/china-expands-research-funding-luring-u-s-scientists-and-students</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/11/27/669645323/china-expands-research-funding-luring-u-s-scientists-and-students</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res671024161&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/26/gettyimages-635868542-465b54f89cf3a6fad134d0b5e571546b7dc059af-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/26/gettyimages-635868542-465b54f89cf3a6fad134d0b5e571546b7dc059af-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tianjin, in northern China, is home to Tianjin University, an international research center that recently hired an American to lead its school of pharmaceutical science and technology. He recruits students from all over the world, he says, and the program's classes are taught in English. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Prisma Bildagentur/UIG/Getty Images&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Prisma Bildagentur/UIG/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/26/gettyimages-635868542-465b54f89cf3a6fad134d0b5e571546b7dc059af-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Tianjin, in northern China, is home to Tianjin University, an international research center that recently hired an American to lead its school of pharmaceutical science and technology. He recruits students from all over the world, he says, and the program's classes are taught in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Prisma Bildagentur/UIG/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tju.edu.cn/english/news/latest/201808/t20180815_308749.htm&quot;&gt;Jay Siegel&lt;/a&gt; was up for a new challenge. Siegel was a tenured professor of chemistry at the University of California, San Diego, but he took a job at the University of Zurich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;When I first moved, people said, 'Oh, you're crazy to leave San Diego; it's a paradise. Why would you go to Europe? Blah, blah blah,' &quot;recalls Siegel. &quot;And after 10 years people were saying, 'Oh, man, that was the smartest thing you ever did. Zurich is wonderful.' &quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he told his friends he was moving to China. &quot;And again, people said 'What? Are you crazy?' &quot; Siegel says. But he thinks they'll soon realize he again made the smart choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res670978494&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage670752865&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/11/26/670752865/chinese-scientist-says-hes-first-to-genetically-edit-babies&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2018\/11\/26\/670752865\/chinese-scientist-says-hes-first-to-genetically-edit-babies&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/26/ap_18330076454211_sq-de5140383fccfbc45472fc9113637f608ca4d5c0-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/26/ap_18330076454211_sq-de5140383fccfbc45472fc9113637f608ca4d5c0-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Chinese Scientist Says He's First To Create Genetically Modified Babies Using CRISPR&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past decade or so, China has been expanding its commitment to scientific research, and it shows. Chinese researchers now produce &lt;a href=&quot;https://nsf.gov/statistics/2018/nsb20181/report/sections/overview/research-publications&quot;&gt;more scientific publications&lt;/a&gt; than U.S. scientists do, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__www.nber.org_papers_w24829&amp;amp;d=DwIEAg&amp;amp;c=E2nBno7hEddFhl23N5nD1Q&amp;amp;r=Z0zpjFSQtaEO1zgUOSHxGw&amp;amp;m=z_RiWjKcMRUzCCO493_5jjct0ujrKaPWSYktYT8Q0nI&amp;amp;s=ihnFYBNsgsMNiTsDTfiIRI8bzL1_zMxTUh9IO-cJGgk&amp;amp;e=&quot;&gt;global ratings&lt;/a&gt; of Chinese universities are rising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five years ago &lt;a href=&quot;http://chem.sci.ehime-u.ac.jp/~poc26/files/2015_Siegel_Short_Bio.pdf&quot;&gt;Siegel&lt;/a&gt; became dean of the school of pharmaceutical science and technology at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tju.edu.cn/english/&quot;&gt;Tianjin University&lt;/a&gt;. He says the university president recruited him to build an undergraduate program that would attract students from all over — not just China. Siegel says the program is taught entirely in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;They get a bachelor's degree that is every bit recognized around the world&quot; says Siegel. &quot;Our graduates go on to do master's and Ph.D. degrees at Harvard, Princeton — at any of the universities around the world.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's another aspect of getting a pharmaceutical science degree at Tianjin that Siegel expects students from throughout the world to find particularly attractive: The Chinese government plans to offer scholarships to cover the cost for students who enroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;They'd walk out debt-free,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siegel says this is all part of China's effort to attract international scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res670982906&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage654339389&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2018/10/07/654339389/china-makes-a-big-play-in-silicon-valley&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/2018\/10\/07\/654339389\/china-makes-a-big-play-in-silicon-valley&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/10/04/china-tech-angelahsieh_sq-08ae91ba5039a215b84140d5359583c32b39762b-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/10/04/china-tech-angelahsieh_sq-08ae91ba5039a215b84140d5359583c32b39762b-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;China Makes A Big Play In Silicon Valley&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We've hired from Brazil; Mexico; the United States,&quot; he says. &quot;We have people from Germany; from the U.K. From Korea — from all over.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of those hires is chemist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.olsonlaboratory.com/mark-a-olson.html&quot;&gt;Mark Olson&lt;/a&gt;. Though he had a faculty job at Texas A&amp;amp;M, Olson says he was ready for a new challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res671014615&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image medium&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/26/olsen-edited_vert-61971cff9db0df5c5893480f609e7cf7692f75eb-s800-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/26/olsen-edited_vert-61971cff9db0df5c5893480f609e7cf7692f75eb-s800.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemist Mark Olson was on the faculty at Texas A&amp;amp;M before taking a university job in Tianjin. The move's been good for his research and for his children, he says. &quot;To show them that, 'Hey, on the other side of the planet, this is what life is like.' &quot; &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Joe Palca/NPR&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Joe Palca/NPR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/26/olsen-edited_vert-61971cff9db0df5c5893480f609e7cf7692f75eb-s1400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Chemist Mark Olson was on the faculty at Texas A&amp;amp;M before taking a university job in Tianjin. The move's been good for his research and for his children, he says. &quot;To show them that, 'Hey, on the other side of the planet, this is what life is like.' &quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Joe Palca/NPR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I'm actually born and raised in South Texas — in Corpus Christi,&quot; he says. &quot;I come from a Hispanic family.&quot; Being in China has been good for his science, Olson says, but there's another reason he's happy he made the move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's good for the kids,&quot; he says. He's got three now — and a fourth on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;To show them that the world is round [has been good],&quot; Olson says. &quot;To show them that, 'Hey, on the other side of the planet, this is what life is like.' And it's been very fulfilling.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another colleague in the chemistry department, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tju.edu.cn/pharm/chinese/xydt/tzgg/201605/P020160531647477798569.pdf&quot;&gt;Jon Antilla&lt;/a&gt;, was at the University of South Florida when he first came to Tianjin University as a visiting faculty member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res670972277&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside aria-label=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;bucket&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We've had no political restrictions. I know that people talk about them being out there, and I've heard rumors of things. But, for us personally, I would have to say no, I've not had that experience.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;Jay Siegel, dean of pharmaceutical science and technology, Tianjin University, China&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Now I've become full-time here,&quot; Antilla says, &quot;giving up my position with tenure in U.S. just to come here.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were several reasons he made the move. One, he has a Chinese wife who was enthusiastic about the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, Antilla says, he was attracted by the research climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You really have a lot of freedom here, actually, to pursue your science,&quot; Antilla says. &quot;The grant funding is easier to get, and that frees you up to think more.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's no question that the amount of money available for research in China is going up. The country has made it clear it plans to be a global leader in high-tech manufacturing. China created the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.1000plan.org/en/&quot;&gt;Thousand Talents Plan&lt;/a&gt; to attract top researchers from around the world. Both Antilla and Olson get support under the plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China's ambitions have prompted great concern in the Trump Administration. The worry is that China might be eroding America's technology advantage — not just by support for research, but also by theft of scientific ideas and corporate espionage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, for now, those concerns are not preventing scientists who are interested in moving to China from doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;A lot of people who live here are drawn to China for some reason, and I wasn't,&quot; says &lt;a href=&quot;http://kiaa.pku.edu.cn/faculty/gregory-j-herczeg&quot;&gt;Greg Herczeg&lt;/a&gt;, an astronomer at the Kavli Institute for Astronomy and Astrophysics at Peking University &quot;But I thought it would be an interesting thing to do&quot; he says, &quot;to move to China for a few years and experience a different culture. And I've stayed for the past seven years now.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herczeg took a faculty position at the institute after completing postdoctoral stints at the California Institute of Technology and in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China has the largest radio telescope in the world, Herczeg notes, and is planning to build several new telescopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I think this is a great place to build a career,&quot; he says. &quot;It's given me an interesting platform — let me work with interesting students.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res670983753&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage638987483&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2018/10/09/638987483/in-pakistan-learning-chinese-is-cool-and-seen-as-a-path-to-prosperity&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/2018\/10\/09\/638987483\/in-pakistan-learning-chinese-is-cool-and-seen-as-a-path-to-prosperity&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/09/11/mandarin-student-pakistan-14_sq-6a35b4b5e608d14656c9511c77bf749c818de4a3-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/09/11/mandarin-student-pakistan-14_sq-6a35b4b5e608d14656c9511c77bf749c818de4a3-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;In Pakistan, Learning Chinese Is Cool — And Seen As A Path To Prosperity&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in China does have some drawbacks. There are restrictions on the Internet, making it difficult to reach certain websites. And though English is spoken on university campuses, it's not spoken throughout most of the country, posing a problem for many foreign visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's more, free speech in China isn't the same concept as it is in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Herczeg says there's one thing he has not experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;There's no interference politically on the science,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a feeling echoed by Tianjin University's Siegel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We've had no political restrictions,&quot; says Siegel. &quot;I know that people talk about them being out there, and I've heard rumors of things. But, for us personally, I would have to say no, I've not had that experience.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siegel thinks he knows why he and his American colleagues have been left alone to do their research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Chinese have this interesting phrase that says, 'The foreign monk speaks more easily to God,' &quot; Siegel says. &quot;So when you are a foreigner here, you may get away with things that other people don't get away with. Although, in contrast, they also have the phrase that, 'The foreign dragon can never defeat the local snake.' And I think these are two good pieces of advice wherever you go in the world. That, indeed, when you are a guest there are certain things that will be allowed you that aren't allowed to everyone else.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the influence of guests may be modest when their opinions don't fit with a country's intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flow of researchers abandoning labs in the United States for academic positions in China is still more trickle than flood. But China is working hard to make itself an attractive destination for top international scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 19:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<og:title>China Expands Research Funding, Luring U.S. Scientists And Students</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/11/27/669645323/china-expands-research-funding-luring-u-s-scientists-and-students</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>In a quest to rapidly advance its scientific depth and breadth, China is recruiting scientists from around the world. Some from the U.S. say the greater funding for school and research is freeing.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/26/gettyimages-635868542_wide-7ed2983c0f07961401dad9f4159efa79cf9b8a42.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/11/27/669645323/china-expands-research-funding-luring-u-s-scientists-and-students</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to balance full-time work with creative projects</title>
<link>https://thecreativeindependent.com/guides/how-to-balance-full-time-work-with-creative-projects/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thecreativeindependent.com/guides/how-to-balance-full-time-work-with-creative-projects/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-honest-about-your-9-to-5&quot;&gt;Be honest about your 9 to 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your day job matters a lot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really does! The average person will spend over 90,000 hours, or about a third of their lives, at work. With another third of our hours spent sleeping, the time we actually have for “living” seems modest at best. If you’re holding down an unfulfilling 9-5 with the primary ambitions of supporting yourself and your creative work (versus building a career in that area), ideally this job should provide you with at least one of three things: more time, more resources, or a skill set that will help you be successful in your creative endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you contemplate what type of day job might make sense for you, consider the feelings you’ll want to have after completing a shift, or after heading out from the office. Probably “drained, grumpy, and sick of everyone” are not feelings that are on your list. So think about it: &lt;em&gt;What type of work or situations might you seek out that wouldn’t leave you in a bad mood after working?&lt;/em&gt; By spending some time brainstorming about the job that could be a nice complement to your personality and side projects, you’ll put yourself in a better position to find the right type of gig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before returning to teaching, I held an office job in NYC that left me deeply unfulfilled. My frustration and uncertainty about what to do about it translated to me generally being a grump around others. This disgruntled attitude also affected my relationship with friends, partners, and family. When it came time to write a song, article, or even do trivial tasks, I approached them with the same aversion I had to my job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have patience and enjoy the ride&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the right gig to nicely balance with your personality and creative work isn’t going to happen overnight. As you work towards finding the right role, pause and reflect on your thoughts and emotions whenever possible. In each type of positions, ask yourself: &lt;em&gt;Were there new trends in your behavior? Did you notice an uptick in your creative work and productivity outside of your 9-5?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you think about what type of day job might make sense for you, a simple exercise to try starts with taking inventory of your skills and passions. Write them down. Go for quantity here: &lt;em&gt;What are you good at? What comes naturally?&lt;/em&gt; Anything goes. Then look for patterns or themes. You may even group your skills into categories including “things I love doing,” “things I get paid the most for doing,” ”skills I want to improve,” or “skills I haven’t used in a long time, but would like to use again.” Identifying patterns will enable you to honor and recognize the expertise you already possess, and can help you find employment that complements not only you as a person, but your creative practice as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you do the above exercise, you should also be honest with your intentions, and even name them. &lt;em&gt;Would you like a job that makes you lots of money? Expands your network? Gets you working with your hands?&lt;/em&gt; Trust your brain and your body—you’ll thank yourself when you’ve landed the right job that’s actually helping you get what you want (not just what you think you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; want), and are also able to have time and energy to produce creative work you’re proud of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://tci-assets.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/HowNotToBurnOut-Day%20Job%20Revised.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-comfy-with-sacrifice-and-boundaries&quot;&gt;Get comfy with sacrifice and boundaries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Say “no” with confidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose to really focus on creative work while continuing to have a full-time day job, chances are you’ll be sacrificing time for friends, family, partners, and all the other ways you could be spending your days. Growing accustomed to missing out takes time, but learning to say “no” to things—even when you truly wish you could do those things—is an indispensable tool for maintaining focus and productivity with your art. While many people have an intuitive desire to please others, re-framing how, when, and why we say “no” can create fewer distractions, protect your time, and even shift your own perception of the importance and value of your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back on the first few years I lived in Brooklyn, it is remarkable how little work I produced as I fell victim to saying “yes” to everything—to every show, every party, every coffee, every beer. It can be a hard pill to swallow, but overcommitting will ultimately hurt you, your relationships, and/or your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few ways to make saying “no” part of your creative practice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;13.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teach people to understand that you may very well say “no” to their invitations.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of assuming that everyone expects you to say yes, flip the narrative. Experiment with making “no” a real option for you. Start small—say “no” to an invitation for drinks, or to a “quick phone call” that may actually completely interrupt your work flow. Once saying “no” becomes a real option, you’ll find yourself being able to do it with relative ease, and without feeling guilty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change “I can’t” to “I don’t.”&lt;/strong&gt; Having some personal ground rules and boundaries for yourself can go a long way. Where “I can’t” comes off as uncertain, “I don’t” implies confidence in your routine. For example, try saying “I don’t go out on Sunday nights, because I always use that time to write,” instead of “I can’t make it tonight, maybe next time!” Using “I don’t” will make it easier to stick to resolutions and increase the consistency of your creative routines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get rid of the guilt.&lt;/strong&gt; This might be the hardest thing to get used to (it certainly has been for me). Remember that saying “no” to friends and opportunities does not mean you’re doing something wrong; rather, it’s completely your right to decide how you spend your time. Examine your guilt, but don’t let it consume you. Most of the time you’ll find it’s not rooted in reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important reminder:&lt;/strong&gt; Saying “yes” is also always an option! If you find that you’re denying yourself experiences that you deeply enjoy just for the sake of working, you may need to re-assess your strategy. Use “no” with purpose, and make saying “yes” something that you can really get excited about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://tci-assets.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/HowNotToBurnOut-GoodHabits%20Revised.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-management-and-organization&quot;&gt;Time management and organization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build good habits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daily routines play a huge role in our creative successes (and failures). Chances are they’ll change repeatedly until you establish habits that are meaningful and attainable given the individual obstacles that tend to arise in your life each day. Personally, I’ve found creative routines to work most effectively when viewed as a place to start, rather than as a set of rules that can never be broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the creative people I know come from two schools of thought: those who don’t work until inspiration strikes, and those who write, record, paint, or create even when inspiration is nowhere to be found. As someone who identifies with the latter, the following are habits that should support anyone looking to consistently flex their creative muscles. Honestly, the hardest part is just getting started—but once you start putting in the time, inspiration inevitably comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;17.888005530591&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify peak creative hours.&lt;/strong&gt; Pick a window where distractions are minimal and your energy tends to be highest. Finding your ideal time block and sticking to it (without beating yourself up if you miss a day) is a great way to establish a creative routine. As an educator, I operate full-steam ahead from around 7am–2pm. After that, I find my energy waning. I’ve learned that other than occasional short bursts of energy after dinner, I tend to reserve my creative work for weekend mornings after I’ve exercised, meditated, and eaten a large meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7.7721518987342&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Done” is better than “perfect.”&lt;/strong&gt; Watching highly creative friends fail to finish a promising project always makes me sad. Regardless of whether or not you ever plan to publish the work, it’s important to make every effort to see your work through. Even if your only goal is to create the seeds for creative work, that counts—having a “stash” of ideas to pull from (&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/people/musician-and-producer-big-boi-on-using-your-time-wisely/&quot;&gt;as Big Boi advises&lt;/a&gt;) can be super helpful when you think you’ve hit a wall. And, on days where it feels like nothing is coming to you, it’s refreshing to scroll through your journal, notes, or sketchpad and know your creative well hasn’t run dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change your environment.&lt;/strong&gt; The environment you make your work in impacts the quality and quantity of your work. If your creative space doesn’t support your goals and habits, it becomes increasingly difficult to make progress. A simple environment change you can make is to have whatever tools you need to create visible at all times. When you walk into your space, they should be staring you down. When I go downstairs in our apartment and all of my recording gear is set up, it’s rare that I don’t at least come up with one idea. If I come back from a show and leave my guitar and pedals packed away, it takes longer for me to get back in a groove of practicing and making demos. Pay attention to the barriers you create to getting started. Visiting other artists’ spaces to get ideas for how to re-arrange your desk, furniture, or equipment can also work wonders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start small and build slowly.&lt;/strong&gt; Whenever I would hear about guitarists I admire who practice for multiple hours a day uninterrupted, I’d get frustrated—I couldn’t imagine having that much extra time in a day. Then I realized I was going about it all wrong. I chose instead to start with a version of the habit that was easy: practicing for 10 minutes a day. The next day, I went up to 15 minutes, and kept going until I was at the hour mark. Building on a habit on a small scale helped me comprehend that I actually could find the time in my day to put in the work. By only increasing the habit by small increments, the progress felt meaningful and manageable. I was also completely focused on playing and not on any one particular outcome. Remember the long game. You can chip away at creative work and over time, it will add up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://tci-assets.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/HowNotToBurnOut-SayNo%20Revised.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-realistic&quot;&gt;Be realistic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Read this section while &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x4OTnortXpc&quot;&gt;listening to Cat Power’s “Nothin’ But Time (feat. Iggy Pop)&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have more time than you think. Seriously. For someone who has never had a singular vision of what I should be doing with my life, accepting this was a big step towards putting goals in perspective and accepting that my curiosity for music, writing, and education could all be explored. Renowned rock climber, musician, poet, and writer Pat Ament describes just this in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://aquariumdrunkard.com/2018/02/21/song-by-pat-ament-2018-reissue/&quot;&gt;2017 &lt;em&gt;Aquarium Drunkard&lt;/em&gt; interview&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s like love. There is no end to the amount of love one can have. You can love multiple people at the same time, your mother and father, your friends, your girlfriend—but it’s the same with our pursuits. There is more than enough time in life to do more than one thing,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ament also describes society’s need to categorize one another. “People are curious and like to define and understand a person. If one is good at a certain endeavor, people around him will reject any effort he makes to be good at another separate endeavor.” For those currently exploring a multitude of creative paths, keep on pressin’ on. You ain’t got nothin’ but time, and it ain’t got nothin’ on you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To counter that, be realistic about your productivity. If your aim to increase your proficiency starts to make you feel crazy, you may slowly be entering the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johnshopkinshealthreview.com/issues/spring-summer-2016/articles/the-cult-of-busy&quot;&gt;cult of busy&lt;/a&gt;. Are you actually having fun making your work, or has it become a box to check off a list? Try not to let your goals take ownership of your own well-being. A creative goal that served you a year ago may simply be out of sync with where you’re at now. Don’t forget to ask yourself “why” you’re doing what you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://tci-assets.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/HowNotToBurnOut-DoNothing%20Revised.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-easy-on-yourself&quot;&gt;Go easy on yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do nothing, be mindful, and get moving&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitting still is difficult for many people, and it always has been for me. I tend to punish myself for wasting any part of a day, and it’s rare that I’ll allow myself to just be. Even when physically sick, I retreat to the comfort of my to-do list. Vacations create a sense of urgency for me: I must see and do as much as possible when traveling to a new place. Sound familiar to anyone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only recently have I become more comfortable with letting my mind be still. Reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chroniclebooks.com/titles/on-doing-nothing.html&quot;&gt;Roman Muradov’s illustrated book “On Doing Nothing”&lt;/a&gt; was a game changer for me. Through the lens of various artists, writers, and philosophers, Muradov argues that doing nothing is both easily achievable and essential to leading an enjoyable and creative life. While boredom can be debilitating at work, it certainly has its place in creativity. Our hyperactivity can often be a mirage, convincing us we’re being productive as we ascribe false status to our actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downtime restores both drive and creativity, and provides a blank slate. It also gives your unconscious a chance to stimulate thought. Without time for reflection, we run the risk of psychological burnout. The following activities can yield surprisingly major results before, during, or after doing creative work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take a walk, drive, bus, train, or subway ride without a destination in mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat without doing anything else simultaneously—notice what sensations your body gets from the food you’re putting in your body. Chew slowly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a quiet place to sit alone and listen to natural sounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take three of the deepest breaths you’ve taken all day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years I filled every quiet moment with noise. Now, it’s the opposite. I look forward to moments of silence and tend to think/work best with ambient or instrumental music, especially when writing. If you’re looking to increase focus, an app I highly recommend looking into is called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.numerogroup.com/products/environments&quot;&gt;Environments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Released by archival record label The Numero Group, &lt;em&gt;Environments&lt;/em&gt; is an ambient sound app based on extended field recordings made in the 1960s and ‘70s by musicologist Irv Teibel. Sounds include country streams, gentle rain, and a wordless choir. Bandcamp also does a fantastic ambient music roundup each month. Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://daily.bandcamp.com/2017/02/17/music-for-relaxation-a-meditation-journey/&quot;&gt;Music for Relaxation&lt;/a&gt; feature is a great place to start. In addition, Sydney’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://longformeditions.bandcamp.com/&quot;&gt;Longform Editions&lt;/a&gt; curate an ongoing series of pieces of substantial length designed for immersive listening experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If zoning out and slowing down aren’t quite doing the trick, never discount the power of getting your heart rate up. The benefits of regular exercise are endless, and often you just need to find the right type of sport or activity that fits your needs and personality. As a teacher, I interact with adults and children non-stop, and it gets to be exhausting. Because of that, I couldn’t imagine leaving my job and then participating in any sort of group sport where I had to interact with more people. Instead, running fits the bill perfectly. I enjoy it for its low cost, the minor barriers required to get started, and its solitude. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.harukimurakami.com/book/what-i-talk-about-when-i-talk-about-running-a-memoir/&quot;&gt;Haruki Murakami’s book devoted to the sport&lt;/a&gt; outlines the clear connection between his work as a novelist and long-distance running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a freelancer who works predominantly alone, you may be looking for some human interaction. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-exercise-that-helps-mental-health-most-1534777677&quot;&gt;The Wall Street Journal recently reported&lt;/a&gt; that team sports, followed by cycling (either stationary or on the road), are the best exercises to support mental health. &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.stanford.edu/2014/04/24/walking-vs-sitting-042414/&quot;&gt;Studies&lt;/a&gt; have shown that even walking for significant portions of time can improve cognitive efforts associated with creativity. Regardless of which exercise best suits you, try to build up a habit. Again, start small and build slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get support, let go, and move on&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After relocating to Portland, Oregon from New York City, I was reminded how valuable having a trusted support system can be. Leaving New York meant leaving family, established friend groups, and creative communities behind. However, I was also reminded of the excitement and fear associated with being a new person in town, and the work you must do to nurture new relationships and build a community around yourself. It’s still a work in progress, but after a year living in Portland, I am relieved to have found people I can rely on for encouragement, feedback, and motivation. Wherever you are, even if you prefer to work alone, don’t underestimate the importance of being vulnerable, open, and honest with others. In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6lyZd0JZCK0&quot;&gt;words of the Staple Singers&lt;/a&gt;, “reach out, touch a hand, make a friend if you can.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of letting go and moving on when something isn’t working out, I can’t say I do either of these well, but would be remiss not to address their value. When I launched &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.singlesclub.fm/issues/&quot;&gt;Singles Club&lt;/a&gt;—a subscription-based record club and music journal—with my best friend in 2013, I believed in the project so much that I refused to accept that it wasn’t a sustainable model. It tied together many of my interests and skill sets, so when it came time to put the project on indefinite hiatus, I took it as a failure on my part. I told myself if I just promoted our releases harder, or secured investment/sponsorship opportunities, that it could have continued. Now, I know that’s probably not true. Moving on was challenging, but I am proud of the cultural artifact we left in the universe. It taught me to stop putting so much weight on specific projects, and that sometimes letting go is the best thing you can do to move forward and prevent burnout—both spiritually and creatively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-summary&quot;&gt;In summary…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding balance between full-time and creative work is a process. Most of the time, you’ll probably feel slightly off center. That’s more than okay. Be kind to yourself throughout your highest and lowest points. Admit when you’re having a hard time, and then shout it from the rooftops when you’ve had a breakthrough. Share, lift, and shine light on the work of others you admire. Protect your time and your vision, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MfBN4kASuw8&quot;&gt;keep your name clean&lt;/a&gt;. Be grateful. You are who you’re supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 17:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cookingoils</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://tci-assets.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/balancecreativeandwork-guide-social.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>How to balance full-time work with creative projects</og:title>
<og:description>A guide to finding the right day job, protecting your time, and building creative habits by Jeffrey Silverstein. Illustrated by Sunny Eckerle.</og:description>
<og:url>https://thecreativeindependent.com/guides/how-to-balance-full-time-work-with-creative-projects/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thecreativeindependent.com/guides/how-to-balance-full-time-work-with-creative-projects/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust 2018 survey results</title>
<link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2018/11/27/Rust-survey-2018.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.rust-lang.org/2018/11/27/Rust-survey-2018.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Another year means another Rust survey, and this year marks Rust’s third annual survey. This year, the survey launched for the first time in multiple languages. In total &lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; languages, in addition to English, were covered. The results from non-English languages totalled &lt;em&gt;25% of all responses&lt;/em&gt; and helped pushed the number of responses to a new record of &lt;strong&gt;5991 responses&lt;/strong&gt;. Before we begin the analysis, we just want to give a big “thank you!” to all the people who took the time to respond and give us your thoughts. It’s because of your help that Rust will continue to improve year after year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/1-Do_you_use_Rust.png&quot; alt=&quot;Do you use Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite having an increase in the number of responses, this year also saw an increase in the percentage of Rust users. Up from last year’s 66.9% Rust users, this year nearly three-quarters of responses were from Rust users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-with-rust&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time with Rust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/4-How_long_have_you_worked_in_Rust.png&quot; alt=&quot;How long have you worked in Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re seeing a steady stream of new users into Rust. At the time of the survey, ~23% of Rust users had been using it for 3 months or less. Likewise, nearly a quarter of the users have used Rust for at least 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/5-How_long_did_it_take_to_be_productive.png&quot; alt=&quot;How long did it take to be productive&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 40% of Rust users felt productive in Rust in less than a month of use, and over 70% felt productive in their first year. Unfortunately, there is a noticeable struggle among users, as over 22% do not yet feel productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/5a-How_long_have_you_been_unproductive.png&quot; alt=&quot;How long have you been unproductive&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking closer at these users who feel unproductive in Rust, only about 25% are in their first month of use. The challenge here is to find ways to help bridge users to productivity so they don’t get stuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-do-you-use-rust&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much do you use Rust?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/6-Size_of_summed_Rust_projects.png&quot; alt=&quot;Size of summed Rust projects&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust projects are continuing to trend to larger sizes, with larger overall investments. Medium to large investments in Rust (those totally over 10k and 100k lines of code respectively) have grown from 8.9% in 2016, to 16% in 2017, to &lt;strong&gt;23%&lt;/strong&gt; this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/7-How_often_use_Rust.png&quot; alt=&quot;How often do you use Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also seen a growth in Rust regular usage. Up from 17.5% last year, Rust daily usage is now nearly a quarter of users. In total, Rust weekly total usage has risen from 60.8% to 66.4%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-expertise&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rust expertise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/8-How_you_rate_your_Rust_expertise.png&quot; alt=&quot;How would you rate your Rust expertise&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than being a simple curve, Rust expertise has two peaks: one around a “3”, and another at “7”, showing that users tend to see themselves as just above beginner or experienced without necessarily being expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/9-How_difficult_are_Rust_concepts.png&quot; alt=&quot;How difficult are Rust concepts&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust users generally felt that Enums and Cargo were largely easy concepts; followed by Iterators, Modules, and Traits. More challenging concepts of Trait Bounds and Unsafe came next. Lastly, the most challenging concepts were Macros, Ownership &amp;amp; Borrowing, and Lifetimes. These challenges match closely to feedback we’ve heard in years past and continue to be a focus of continued productivity improvements like NLL and the continued macro system improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/22-Programming_language_familiarity.png&quot; alt=&quot;What programming languages are you familiar with&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humorously, we see that Rust isn’t actually the top programming language that users were familiar with. Instead, it pulled in a 2nd place behind Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/10-Which_Rust_version.png&quot; alt=&quot;Which Rust version do you use&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re seeing similar numbers in users of the current stable release since last year. Perhaps surprisingly, we’re continuing to see a rise in the number of users who use the Nightly compiler in their workflow. For the second year in a row, Nightly usage has continued to rise, and is now over 56% (up from 51.6% of last year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asked why they used nightly, people responded with a broad range of reasons including: access to 2018 edition, asm, async/await, clippy, embedded development, rocket, NLL, proc macros, and wasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/11-Has_upgrading_compiler_broken_you.png&quot; alt=&quot;Has upgrading the compiler broken your code&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The percentage of people who see a breakage during a routine compiler update has stayed the same since last year, with 7.4% saying they’ve experienced breakage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/12-If_so_how_much_work_to_fix.png&quot; alt=&quot;If so how much work to fix it&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breakages generally leaned to requiring minor fixes, though some reported having moderate or major fixes to upgrade to the next stable compiler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/13-Preferred_install_method.png&quot; alt=&quot;Preferred install method&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We again see a strong showing for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rustup&lt;/code&gt;, which continues to hold at 90% of Rust installs. Linux distros follow as a distant second at 17%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/14-Tool-experience.png&quot; alt=&quot;Experience with Rust tools&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rustfmt&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rustdoc&lt;/code&gt; had a strong show, with lots of positive support. Following these is the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;clippy&lt;/code&gt; tool – despite having fewer users, its users enjoy the tool. The IDE support tools &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Rust Language Server&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;racer&lt;/code&gt; had positive support but unfortunately, of the tools surveyed, generated a few more dislike votes and comments. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bindgen&lt;/code&gt; tool has relatively small userbase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-workflow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rust workflow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/15-Platform_developing_on.png&quot; alt=&quot;Which platform are you developing on&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux continues to be a powerhouse among Rust developers, holding on to roughly 80% of Rust developers. Windows usage has grown slightly from 31% last year to 34% this year, its second year in a row of growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/16-Platforms_targeting.png&quot; alt=&quot;Which platforms are you developing for&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux and Windows continued to show strongly as targets for Rust applications. Other platforms held largely the same as last year, with one exception: WebAssembly. The new technology has showed impressive growth, nearly doubling from last year’s 13% to this year’s 24%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/17-Editors.png&quot; alt=&quot;What editors do you use&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim, the front-runner in editors for two years has now finally been bested by VSCode, which grew from 33.8% of Rust developers to 44.4% this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-at-work&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rust at work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/18-Rust_at_work.png&quot; alt=&quot;Do you use Rust at work&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust continues is slow-and-steady growth in the workplace. We’re now seeing year-over-year growth of full-time and part-time Rust, growing from last year’s 4.4% full-time and 16.6% part-time to this year’s &lt;strong&gt;8.9% full-time&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;21.2% part-time&lt;/strong&gt;, a doubling of full-time Rust commercial use. In total, Rust commercial use grew from 21% to just over 30% of Rust users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/19-Company_evaluate_Rust.png&quot; alt=&quot;Is your company evaluating Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more room for Rust to grow into more companies, over a third of which users report aren’t currently looking into evaluating Rust in the coming year. When paired with the survey data that said that nearly half of non-users needed the company support, this shows the need for further company outreach or more company-focused information about Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;feeling-welcome&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feeling welcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/23-Do_you_feel_welcome.png&quot; alt=&quot;Do you feel welcome in the Rust community&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important part of the Rust community efforts are ensuring that the Rust project is a welcoming place for its users. New users should feel encouraged to explore, share ideas, and generally be themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asked, both current Rust users and non-users largely felt welcome, though over a quarter of responses weren’t sure. There was also some regional variation in these responses. For example, responses on the Russian version of the survey showed double the percent of unwelcome feelings at 4%. Mainland China showed even more at 8%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a challenge here to help Rust communities worldwide feel like they are part of what makes Rust unique, as Rust continues to grow a strong presence in more areas of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/24-Underrepresented.png&quot; alt=&quot;Are you underrepresented in tech&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of people in Rust who self-identify as being part of a group underrepresented in technology is growing slowly year-over-year. The survey also highlights some challenges, as the number of women is still lower than the industry average of women in programming fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big part of a welcoming Rust community is reaching out to non-users as well. As we have in years past, we again asked the reasons why people weren’t using Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/2-How_long_before_you_stopped.png&quot; alt=&quot;How long before you stopped&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who stopped using Rust, just over 50% stopped using Rust in less than a month. Likewise, roughly 50% of people who left Rust managed to use it for more than a month before stopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2018-11-RustSurvey/3-Why_not_using_Rust.png&quot; alt=&quot;Why are you not using Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many non-users responded that they did want to learn Rust, but there were factors that slowed them down. First among these is that the companies the responders work for do not themselves use Rust. Nearly one half of the non-users were blocked by the lack of company support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, 1 in 4 non-users were slowed by the feeling of Rust being too intimidating or complicated. The work towards improving Rust IDE support has helped (down from 25% to 16%), though we still see a strong push towards even better IDE support among non-users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve done in past years, we asked for your comments in where Rust can improve. This year, we see some familiar themes as well as some new ones in this feedback. The top ten themes this year are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;the need for better library support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a more improved IDE experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the need for broader adoption of Rust generally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a richer ecosystem of tools and support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an improved learning curve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the need for important language features and crates to be stable and supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for async programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for GUI development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved compile times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;New this year is the rising need to &lt;strong&gt;support GUI development&lt;/strong&gt;, showing that Rust continues to grow not only on the server, but that people are feeling the need to stretch into application development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Improve Rust marketing. Many people don’t know about it”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments remind us that while Rust may be well-known in some circles, it still has room to grow and in many tech circles Rust may not yet be well-known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Keeping a focus on adoption/tutorials/books/novice experience will pay dividends in the years to come.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to outreach, a broader set of documentation would in turn help reach a broader audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Stability and maturity of developer tools, make it easier to get a working setup and to debug applications”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people commented on the IDE support, pointing out not only instability or inaccuracy in the RLS, but also the need for a much stronger IDE story that covered more areas, like easier debugging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The maturity of the ecosystem and libraries. Have a good ecosystem of “standard” libraries is key for the future of the language”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common theme continues to be the need to push libraries to completion and grow the set of “standard” libraries that users can use. Some comments point out this isn’t the fault of maintainers, who are already working hard to write and publish the crates, but that generally more companies need to get involved and offer commercial support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ergonomics and discoverability of “putting it together” documentation”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people pointed out that ergonomics goes hand in hand with richer documentation, seeing that these aren’t separate concepts but rather challenges that should be tackled together in a unified approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-forward&quot;&gt;Looking forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year saw the strongest survey yet. Not only was it the largest community survey, it was the first to cover languages outside of English. Rust continues to grow steadily, and with it, both its strengths and challenges are introduced to a broader audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to using your feedback in planning for 2019, and we’re excited to see where we can take Rust next.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 17:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steveklabnik</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2018/11/27/Rust-survey-2018.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dropping Acid</title>
<link>https://logicmag.io/06-dropping-acid/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://logicmag.io/06-dropping-acid/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;by-shuja-haider&quot;&gt;by Shuja Haider&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the 1980s, musicians in Chicago built a new genre out of obsolete machinery. Listeners lost their minds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://logicmag.io/content/images/2018/11/shuja-2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;small&gt;A Roland TB-303 synthesizer. Photograph by Alexandre Dulaunoy.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The author has assembled a playlist to accompany this piece. You can listen to it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/user/1268025173/playlist/06iuSLZoVwaSWCqJvmlCC6?si=8JeX53rHQu6hXdRKDa5bsA&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This piece appears in&lt;/em&gt; Logic'&lt;em&gt;s upcoming sixth issue, &quot;Play.&quot; To receive the issue when it comes out, &lt;a href=&quot;https://logicmag.io/subscribe&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; or pre-order it in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.logicmag.io&quot;&gt;store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Muzic Box was open on Tuesdays, Thursdays, and Saturdays, staying closed on Wednesdays and Fridays only to give Chicago’s competing disco club, the Power Plant, a chance to draw a crowd a couple nights a week. If you were a young, gay person of color in the Windy City during the early 1980s, there was no better place to be. The Muzic Box was a sanctuary, free from the judgment of a still-restrictive society that, in the days of panic over an increasingly visible queer culture, inhibited the sense of celebratory pride sorely needed by the local gay community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the Muzic Box’s four walls, dancers were welcomed in the embrace of an idea. As the attention of the mass audience shifted away from disco, and “Disco Sucks” rallies were held at Chicago’s Comiskey Park stadium, these clubs were the only place to hear the music of the future. The songs on rotation in the Muzic Box may not have been categorized in the same bin at the record store, but they all shared invigorating rhythms and futuristic tonalities that suggested a new genre cutting through those established categories. The fearless explorer breaking through the boundaries between them was Ron Hardy, a virtuoso who mixed records together in a spontaneous collage style inspired by New York disco DJs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardy had begun playing at the club in 1982, when it was called The Warehouse, and remained the resident DJ until it closed in 1987. His predecessor Frankie Knuckles first brought the disco DJing style, with its aim of creating a seamless landscape of rhythm, to Chicago from his hometown of New York. However, in spite of its East Coast origins, this approach to mixing music—and the approach to producing music that these DJs would eventually create—took flight in the Midwest. To this day, it bears the abbreviated name of the club where it began its international ascendance. The music had gotten so popular by the mid-1980s that Chicago record stores started giving the records that got played at The Warehouse their own bin, labeled “house music.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was on a night in 1985—whether it was Tuesday, Thursday, or Saturday is lost to history—that Earl “Spanky” Smith and Nathaniel Pierre Jones entered the Muzic Box with a reel-to-reel tape, containing a track that they had just recorded in Smith’s bedroom. Hardy would sometimes switch from vinyl to a tape reel to play productions by local amateurs, in order to keep up with the developing sound of the genre. House DJs had already begun making inroads into production, thanks to the availability of cheap synthesizers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith and Jones recount the evening they debuted their new track in a documentary for the British broadcaster Channel 4 on house music called &lt;em&gt;Pump Up the Volume&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pierre&lt;/strong&gt;: We thought, if anybody would be daring enough to play this, it would be Ron Hardy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spanky&lt;/strong&gt;: He ended up playing it four times that night. First time he played it, people didn’t really know how to react to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pierre&lt;/strong&gt;: He played it again, people was looking like “Hm. It’s early, I guess he playing some crazy stuff.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spanky&lt;/strong&gt;: The fourth time, &lt;em&gt;they lost they mind&lt;/em&gt;. That was the birth of acid, right there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new era began that night. The track didn’t bother with song form, melodic development, harmony, or lyrical content; it was an investigation of the infinite permutations of sound itself. Winding through a pounding, jittery beat, an atonal three-note motif wriggled and thrashed, as though trying to escape, for more than twelve minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It did not sound like it had been produced by a musical instrument. Nor did it sound like a pop song, with its structure more akin to minimalist experimental music. Disco had already been moving in this direction, emphasizing texture over song. But this dispensed with the song altogether. It took a forward-thinking listener to see its promise, in 1985, as a potential dancefloor hit. Fortunately, Ron Hardy was precisely that kind of listener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The producers had called their composition “In Your Mind,” but that may have been too limiting—listeners had &lt;em&gt;lost&lt;/em&gt; their minds upon hearing it. The track was not an object for contemplation, but a shockwave that affected the body. Either because of its fluid yet abrasive texture, or because of its tonal similarity to the guitars of psychedelic rock, or because some dancers at the Muzic Box were so blown away that they thought someone had spiked their drinks with LSD, the record became known as “Acid Trax.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hPd_Mzuz_Uc?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global phenomenon of rave music would eventually derive everything from “Acid Trax,” which was released as a 12-inch record in 1987 under the name Phuture. A subgenre of house music adopted its name: “acid house,” which would also become the label that rave music went by upon its earliest appearances in Europe. Acid’s abstract quality brought the futuristic nature of house music to the forefront, influencing the concurrent development of techno in Detroit and catalyzing the emergence of drum and bass in England. Today, aspects of EDM are uncannily similar to acid house as it was heard thirty years ago in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made “Acid Trax” so revolutionary was not just its structure or its sound, but its use of the technology that produced it. Jazz, funk, disco, and even rock and roll had emphasized timbre and spontaneity as much as melody and narrative, in the struggle over centuries to adapt traditional musical practices to new languages and new tools. “Acid Trax,” however, did not derive its complex sound from overblown horns or bent strings—or even distorted amplifiers. It was made almost entirely with one instrument or, more accurately, one machine: the Roland TB-303, which generated sound waves from scratch. Then bought for next to nothing at a pawn shop, the 303 has since entered into legend, and now commands thousands of dollars on eBay. Even today, producers of underground dance music try to capture the sonic force it holds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the writer Kodwo Eshun’s description, the machine itself shares authorship of “Acid Trax.” “Acid is an accident,” he suggests, “in which the TB-303 bass synthesizer uses Phuture to reproduce itself, to multiply the dimensions of electronic sound, to open up a nomadology of texturhythms, rhythmelodies.” The story of acid house begins in a factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;transistor-rhythm&quot;&gt;Transistor Rhythm&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While house music’s sonic textures drew from both African-American music’s corporeal funk and European synth pop’s electronic sheen, it only crystallized as a genre and production practice after some help from Japanese technology. The Roland Corporation, founded by Ikutaro Kakehashi in Osaka in 1972, unknowingly provided the final ingredients for the futuristic dance music that would emerge in America over the next few decades. In 1980, Roland’s TR-808 Rhythm Composer, the “TR” designating “Transistor Rhythm,” became one of the first synthesized drum machines to become available to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early synthesizers were as complicated—and as large—as electronic manufacturing technology. But Roland’s instruments were appearing in a new context. Before the widespread extension of electrical power to residential areas in the 1920s, machinery under capitalism had been an instrument of labor. In Marx’s “Fragment on Machines,” he remarked on the place of technology in the capitalist mode of production:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nature builds no machines, no locomotives, railways, electric telegraphs, self-acting mules etc. These are products of human industry: natural material transformed into organs of the human will over nature, or of human participation in nature. They are organs of the human brain, created by the human hand: the power of knowledge, objectified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the twentieth century, consumer electronics dispersed scientific knowledge further still. Beyond being a tool that workers used in the factory, electrical machinery became present in the home. Automation took on a presence in everyday life as well as within the means of production. The amplification of sound was inextricably linked to this process, with the development and distribution of electricity tied from its origin to telephone communication and radio broadcasting. By the mid-twentieth century, most homes had radios, making their operation familiar to a far broader population than expert telegraphers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mold of consumer devices like the portable stereo, the TR-808 was built for home use. Its target audience was musicians who needed accompaniment for practice sessions, and its interface more closely resembled a stereo than a circuit board. In the late 1970s, however, the TR-808 began to migrate from the home to the recording studio. It started to appear on pop records—Marvin Gaye’s “Sexual Healing” is a famous example—many of which may have been played by Knuckles or Hardy during their expansive DJ sets. Its rigid, aggressive drum sound may have driven professional musicians crazy, but its mathematically precise rhythmic divisions were perfect for DJ mixing, a process of matching up beats by adjusting the speed of rotation on turntables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1982, Roland engineer Tadao Kikumoto designed a new machine as a supplement to the TR-808: TB-303, the initials standing for “Transistor Bass.” For $400, the 303 could be used as a supplement to Roland’s drum machines, giving a solitary musician in a domestic setting the experience of playing with a band. “Electric” is not to be confused with “electronic”—while a bass guitar amplifies sound that is produced acoustically, the 303 was triggered by a voltage-controlled oscillator cued by a one-octave keyboard, with knobs and switches to manipulate the timbre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A traditional instrument like a bass guitar makes waves. What fluctuates in these waves, in the case of acoustic instruments, is the air surrounding a vibration in or around part of the instrument’s material body. When two frequencies occur simultaneously, they affect the shape of the wave, creating the effect that musicians call timbre—the &lt;em&gt;character&lt;/em&gt; of sound that differentiates separate instruments playing the same note. While a pure sine wave creates a tone so pure as to sound lifeless, the sound produced by any instrument is complex, with a fundamental tone altered by harmonic overtones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early electronic synthesizer broke the relationship between the shape and substance of a physical object and the sound it produced, allowing for the formation of a waveform through a mathematical formula instead. There are two kinds of complex tones that formed the palette of electronic synthesizers like the 303: square and triangle. The square wave produces only odd-numbered harmonics of the fundamental tone, with a sound comparable to a clarinet. Though the wave looks like a square, it is in fact produced by a series of sine waves, embedded like a fractal set. The sawtooth wave produces both odd and even harmonics, making it sound something like a violin. The triangle wave resembles the square wave, but with less complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 303 had six knobs, reading TUNING, CUT OFF FREQ, RESONANCE, ENV MOD, DECAY, and ACCENT, controlling the parameters of the sound’s tone and articulation. This was not a conventional instrument like a clarinet or a violin, but more like a manufacturing tool, the kind that was being used on the increasingly automated assembly lines of the industrial factories then dominating the economy of the American Midwest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As robotic instruments were incorporated into the manufacturing process, labor became oriented towards their operation and maintenance, rather than hand assembly. In a concert hall, an instrument is to be played; on a shop floor, it is to be worked on. The 303’s interface blurs the distinction: while it holds a portion of a piano’s keyboard, its primary mechanism is operated by means of knobs and buttons. Like a robotic arm, it is programmed as much as it is played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;machine-music&quot;&gt;Machine Music&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TB-303 didn’t sell. It may have been because the advent of sampling technology made it possible to reproduce recordings of other instruments directly. Or it may just have been, according to Peter Shapiro in &lt;em&gt;The Wire&lt;/em&gt;, because Roland accidentally forgot to ship out manuals to English-speaking countries. Either way, the machine was devastatingly unpopular for its intended purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 1980s, a handful of inventive pop musicians did begin to feature the 303’s unrealistic sound as a novelty. Still, the machine lapsed out of production in 1984—a year before the arrival of “Acid Trax” heralded the invention of acid house. Earl “Spanky” Smith bought one at a secondhand music store for $40—sans manual—knowing it was what Jesse Saunders had used for “On and On,” the earliest foray into house music production in Chicago. He programmed a beat into his Roland drum machine and called his friend Pierre:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spanky&lt;/strong&gt;: Well basically, we started using the 303 just to try to make bass lines, because when we first started making music, it sucked. So I made this rhythm…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pierre&lt;/strong&gt;:…and it’s just playing straight, and he said, “I can’t figure out how to work this thing,” and he’s still doing this weird sound. “I don’t know how to program it,” he said, “maybe you could figure out how to program it, ‘cause it ain’t come with a book.” So instead of trying to program it, I just started turning knobs. I was like, “&lt;em&gt;woo-ooo-ooo-ooo&lt;/em&gt;.” And he was like, “What you doing?” And I’m like, “I don’t know, I’m turning these knobs!” And he said, “Keep doing that!” So we was just sitting there for thirty, forty minutes, just turning knobs, going “I like that, I &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 1988 interview, veteran Chicago house DJ Farley “Jackmaster” Funk explained  that before “Acid Trax,” the TB-303 was “an obsolete, old-fashioned piece of technology that no one had ever thought of using that way before.” House DJs had already begun to resist the conventional distinction between production and consumption in consumer society by turning the playing of records into the playing &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt; music as a creative process. Pierre and Spanky extended this intervention in a way that called for a redefinition of musical sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the TB-303 was built to emulate an electric bass, its real-world referent was specified. If you were to imagine a visual representation, you might picture someone playing the instrument, albeit one that looked a bit weird. But by playing the 303 itself, through manipulation of its electronic interface, Pierre transformed his virtual instrument as the track progressed. The image would have to exist in an amorphous dream logic, as though the instrument were a shape-shifting mutant: a violin, then a trumpet, then a flute, then a timpani, until it could no longer be associated with a recognizable correlate. As Pierre &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thefader.com/2014/08/04/back-to-the-phuture-dj-pierre-on-inventing-acid-and-why-edm-fans-need-to-learn-their-history&quot;&gt;put&lt;/a&gt; it in &lt;em&gt;The Fader&lt;/em&gt;, while the 303 “was supposed to be copying a bass guitar, [the way we used it] doesn’t sound like any previous sound you’ve ever heard before. And you can only describe it as being acid.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Acid Trax,” with its extended texture, was truly a &lt;em&gt;track&lt;/em&gt; rather than a song. In fact, it was more than one; &lt;em&gt;trax&lt;/em&gt;, in the plural, its name also describing every succeeding installment in the genre it created. In the late 1980s and early 90s, acid house spread like a virus. New records proliferated—not just by Phuture, but by other local producers like Adonis, Lil Louis, Mike Dunn, and the teenage prodigy Armando. Armando’s 1987 classic “Land of Confusion” epitomizes Kodwo Eshun’s contention that the 303 was a collaborator in the production of acid house. Its composition was described by Mike Dunn in Chicago’s &lt;em&gt;5 Magazine&lt;/em&gt; as based on the machine’s settings. “If you take the batteries out for a minute and put them back in,” he recalled, “that’s the first bassline that will come up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the 1980s, the style had become influential not only in Chicago but in Detroit, where a similar kind of dance music, called techno, had been emerging. Juan Atkins, the founder of techno, had begun to fuse the experimental qualities of funk and progressive rock with the rhythmic structure of contemporary dance music. His friend and collaborator Derrick May, after taking frequent trips across I-94 to visit his mother, had been “baptised” at The Warehouse. May established a link between the cities, even buying Frankie Knuckles’s TR-909, the successor to the TR-808, to produce his own records. Techno emphasized the space-age qualities of synthesized sound over the disco and gospel influences that characterized house. But if a line separates the sound of the two genres, acid house sits directly on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;sonic-synthesis&quot;&gt;Sonic Synthesis&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acid house’s dissociation of sound from physical presence is now a fact of our sonic environment. For those who came of age after its emergence, acid has permanently altered our relationship to aural experience. Tones that might previously have been limited to sound effects in science-fiction cinema, intended as &lt;em&gt;representation&lt;/em&gt; of alien objects, we now hear as musical in themselves. “For some, I guess, ‘synthesize’ means ‘duplicate,’” Juan Atkins &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2002/05/blackbox/&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;. “But for me, ‘synthesize’ is synonymous with ‘create.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, contemporary pop music has fully incorporated acid house’s sonic range, if not its production method. Producers used it as a starting point for the sound of R&amp;amp;B and hip-hop in the new millennium—in 2000, Timbaland’s backing track for Aaliyah’s “Try Again” used a TB-303 for its bass line, inspiring countless producers to imitate the sound on other synthesizers and computers. For his part, Pierre sees something prophetic in the name that he and Earl Smith chose for their work: Phuture. “Twenty-six years later and acid is still going strong,” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dummymag.com/lists/the-10-best-acid-house-tracks-according-to-dj-pierre&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; in 2011. “You can see the proof of this when platinum-selling groups and artists like LMFAO and Skrillex are putting ‘acid’ in their songs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But while the &lt;em&gt;sound&lt;/em&gt; of acid has become incorporated into the output of what Adorno and Horkheimer called the “culture industry,” the act of its creation was a rupture of the equivalence that term assumes. Acid house was born in a space &lt;em&gt;between&lt;/em&gt; the cultural and the industrial, between social life and the relations of production. It is here that we find not only art, but political action. Acid house relocates industrial sabotage from the factory to a domestic setting, allowing for creative acts that expanded the consumer sphere of the disco community to the practice of house music &lt;em&gt;production&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, acid house fits into the spectrum of an ongoing struggle. In his 1963 book &lt;em&gt;Blues People&lt;/em&gt;, Amiri Baraka traced the origin of jazz to the use, by African-American musicians in the nineteenth century, of unfamiliar tools. These musicians, lacking formal training, “developed an instrumental technique and music of their own, a music that relied heavily on the non-European vocal tradition of blues.” The result was a musical practice that used European instruments to achieve “the altered timbral qualities and diverse vibrato effects of African music.” On a guitar or trumpet, a fretboard or valve system provides an interface for producing tones corresponding to the chromatic scale of Western harmony. But through physical intervention, they can be made to deviate from that limited use. Acid house directs this intervention towards consumer devices, drawing altered timbres and vibrato effects from &lt;em&gt;machinery&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This practice disrupts the presumption of autonomy between the spheres of art, consumer society, and industrial production—a presumption that was also investigated in Marx’s critique of capitalism. Italian political theorist Paolo Virno, in his essay “Virtuosity and Revolution,” shows that Marx had already addressed cultural production in his notes for &lt;em&gt;Capital&lt;/em&gt;. Marx distinguished between two kinds of intellectual labor: “commodities which exist separately from the producer,” like paintings or books, and those in which “the product is not separable from the act of producing,” like the performing arts. As Virno argues, within the context of the service work that dominates advanced economies, “activity-without-a-finished-work moves from being a special and problematic case to becoming the prototype of waged labor in general.” The artist is in the same category as the service worker, in other words: “virtuosic activity comes across as universal servile labor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this light, an artistic practice in itself does not escape the boundaries of the capitalist mode of production, which has included service work and the dissemination of cultural phenomena since the days of the printing press. Speaking to &lt;em&gt;The Fader&lt;/em&gt;, Pierre pointed out that the sound of the TB-303 itself has now become subject to imitation by an arm of the culture industry. “I think since people have made all these clones of the 303,” he says, “to me that’s just like other manufacturers making bass guitars or lead guitars, or pianos.” To his ears, much of the electronic music that has followed simply repeats an old formula: “Even dubstep, as crazy as that stuff sounds, has sounds that are connected to a previous instrument—it’s still copying something in some kind of way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real legacy of acid house may not reside in its sound, but in its method. Acid shows us a new way to relate to the machinery that increasingly populates our everyday lives, one that shifts our experience from the passive mode of consumerism into the realm of creative activity. The knowledge we share as operators of this machinery has the potential, as Virno puts it, to “affirm itself as an autonomous public sphere,” but only “if it cuts the linkage that binds it to the production of commodities and wage labor.” Acid house teaches us that the potential for a radical practice of culture may not lie in making a certain kind of sound, but in something more fundamental: not doing what it says in the manual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shuja Haider is an editor at&lt;/em&gt; Viewpoint Magazine &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Popula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This piece appears in&lt;/em&gt; Logic'&lt;em&gt;s upcoming sixth issue, &quot;Play.&quot; To receive the issue when it comes out, &lt;a href=&quot;https://logicmag.io/subscribe&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; or pre-order it in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.logicmag.io&quot;&gt;store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://logicmag.io/06-play/&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; Back to the Table of Contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 16:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wglb</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Dropping Acid</og:title>
<og:description>In the 1980s, musicians in Chicago built a new genre out of obsolete machinery. Listeners lost their minds.</og:description>
<og:url>https://logicmag.io/06-dropping-acid/</og:url>
<og:image>https://logicmag.io/content/images/2018/11/shuja-2-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://logicmag.io/06-dropping-acid/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>NIST&amp;#039;s answer to “Do you need a blockchain?”</title>
<link>https://imgur.com/a/RlUj9Ed</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://imgur.com/a/RlUj9Ed</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/a/RlUj9Ed&quot;&gt;https://imgur.com/a/RlUj9Ed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18543454&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18543454&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 347&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 163&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 16:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alanfranzoni</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://imgur.com/a/RlUj9Ed</og:url>
<og:title>NIST's answer to &quot;Do you need a blockchain?&quot;</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.imgur.com/rw8cb1P.jpg?fb</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>From NIST Blockchain Technology Overview: https://www.nist.gov/publications/blockchain-technology-overview</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://imgur.com/a/RlUj9Ed</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fortran is still a thing</title>
<link>https://wordsandbuttons.online/fortran_is_still_a_thing.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://wordsandbuttons.online/fortran_is_still_a_thing.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2017 NASA announced a code optimization competition only to cancel it shortly after. The rules were simple. There is a Navier-Stokes equations solver used to model aerodynamics, and basically, the one who makes it run the fastest on the Pleiades supercomputer wins the first prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few caveats though. The applicant had to be a US citizen at least 18 years of age, and the code to optimize had to be in Fortran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortran is not the most popular language in the programmer’s community. Many believe that it’s complex and outdated. Programming in Fortran is perceived like riding a horse-driven carriage to work. Fortran? Isn’t it something that Amish do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thought that the competition will never start due to the lack of applicants. In fact, it was cancelled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.herox.com/HPFCC/updates&quot;&gt;for the exact opposite reason&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quoting NASA's Press Release: &lt;em&gt;«The extremely high number of applicants, more than 1,800, coupled with the difficulty in satisfying the extensive vetting requirements to control the public distribution of the software made it unlikely we would achieve the challenge’s original objectives in a timely manner.»&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/90/Pleiades_supercomputer.jpg/1024px-Pleiades_supercomputer.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortran is not, of course, outdated, and it’s not at all complex. In fact, it has grown into these myths exactly because it is that good at what it does. It was designed to make number-crunching easy and efficient. Its users are scientists and engineers; not computer scientists and software engineers, but the real ones. And when engineers have a tool for the problem, they solve the problem with the tool. The problem comes first, not the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s how the complexity myth has started. Most of the code you see in Fortran is indeed complex. But this is because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) the problem behind it is complex;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) the code was written by domain specialists and not programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortran is simple enough for domain specialist to write bad code and achieve good results with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as for the outdatedness, the current Fortran standard is Fortran 2008. The next one is 2018 and it is expected to arrive anytime soon. Fortran is constantly being modernized one little step after another. The biggest holding factor here is its mission. It must remain simple for real engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the modern Fortran already has modules, objects, generics and built-in support for parallel computing. Foot shooting area grows steadily to meet the fiats of the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It stll excels in the good old structured programming. It has features that mainstream C-like languages lack. For instance, it can exit or continue a loop from a nested loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table readability=&quot;2.139175257732&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4175257731959&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;6.8453608247423&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span&gt;rows&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;The first one is the number to start, the second – to finish. In Fortran elements are accesible via 1..n indexing, not 0..n-1 as in C. The loop goes through all the 10 numbers from 1 to 10.&quot;&gt; = 1, 10&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;columns&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;The first one is the number to start, the second – to finish. In Fortran elements are accesible via 1..n indexing, not 0..n-1 as in C. The loop goes through all the 10 numbers from 1 to 10.&quot;&gt; = 1, 10&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;) = 0.) &lt;span&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;rows&lt;/span&gt;
    ...
  &lt;span&gt;enddo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;columns&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;enddo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;rows&lt;/span&gt;
    
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;If has &lt;em&gt;case&lt;/em&gt; statement with ranges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table readability=&quot;4.080223880597&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.240671641791&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;10.880597014925&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span&gt;integer&lt;/span&gt; :: &lt;span&gt;temp_c&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span&gt;! Temperature in Celsius!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span&gt;temp_c&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;span&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; (:-1)
  &lt;span&gt;write&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;The tuple denotes two things: the unit number, like the file handle in C; and the format specifier. Asterisks mean that they are both default.&quot;&gt;(*,*)&lt;/a&gt; 'Below freezing'
&lt;span&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; (0)
  &lt;span&gt;write&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;The tuple denotes two things: the unit number, like the file handle in C; and the format specifier. Asterisks mean that they are both default.&quot;&gt;(*,*)&lt;/a&gt; 'Freezing point'
&lt;span&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; (1:20)
  &lt;span&gt;write&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;The tuple denotes two things: the unit number, like the file handle in C; and the format specifier. Asterisks mean that they are both default.&quot;&gt;(*,*)&lt;/a&gt; 'It is cool'
&lt;span&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; (21:33)
  &lt;span&gt;write&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;The tuple denotes two things: the unit number, like the file handle in C; and the format specifier. Asterisks mean that they are both default.&quot;&gt;(*,*)&lt;/a&gt; 'It is warm'
&lt;span&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; (34:)
 &lt;span&gt;write&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;The tuple denotes two things: the unit number, like the file handle in C; and the format specifier. Asterisks mean that they are both default.&quot;&gt;(*,*)&lt;/a&gt; 'This is Texas!'
&lt;span&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;select&lt;/span&gt;
    
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it can use an array of indexes to access another array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table readability=&quot;5.1036036036036&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.310810810811&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;12.990990990991&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span&gt;real&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;dimension&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;This is the array dimensions. One dimensional array is just a special case. In Fortran multidimensional arrays in arbitrary ranges are first class citizens. (0:4, 2:6, 5) is a valid 5x5x5 array.&quot;&gt;(5) &lt;/a&gt;:: &lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; = [ 2, 4, 6, 8, 10 ]
&lt;span&gt;integer&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;dimension&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;This is the array dimensions. One dimensional array is just a special case. In Fortran multidimensional arrays in arbitrary ranges are first class citizens. (0:4, 2:6, 5) is a valid 5x5x5 array.&quot;&gt;(2) &lt;/a&gt;:: &lt;span&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; = [ 2, 4 ]

&lt;span&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;This is the format specifier. Asterisk means 'default'.&quot;&gt; *, &lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;)   &lt;span&gt;! prints 4. 8.&lt;/span&gt;
    
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a brief &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tacc.utexas.edu/documents/13601/162125/fortran_class.pdf&quot;&gt;introduction into modern Fortran&lt;/a&gt; by Lars Koesterke. If you think Fortran hasn’t changed since the 60s, please look through it. You might get surprised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Fortran is not complex and it’s not outdated. Now how come it went underground in the modern world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer here is actually the same as for “where do old programmers go?” They mostly stay in business, but according to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2014/06/20/MyLawn.html&quot;&gt;Martin’s lawn&lt;/a&gt;, as the number of programmers doubles every five years, they get vastly outnumbered by the younger folks. They just dissolve in a mass. But this is endemic for software industry only. Fortran users are mostly the real engineers and their numbers don’t grow exponentially. There is more or less the same amount of Fortran users, old and young, as it was some 30 or 40 years ago when Fortran was at its peak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, it has been at its peak all that time. It’s the world around that has gone crazy. Languages come and go, paradigms ripe and rot, the whole software business is a part of fashion industry now. But when you want your plane to fly, you still need to do the maths with your trusty Fortran. That’s the beauty of the things that work; they don’t have to change much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 15:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zeveb</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://wordsandbuttons.online/fortran_is_still_a_thing.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We are Google employees – Google must drop Dragonfly</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@googlersagainstdragonfly/we-are-google-employees-google-must-drop-dragonfly-4c8a30c5e5eb</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@googlersagainstdragonfly/we-are-google-employees-google-must-drop-dragonfly-4c8a30c5e5eb</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;3f83&quot; id=&quot;3f83&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;We are Google employees and we join&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2018/11/google-must-not-capitulate-to-chinas-censorship-demands/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2018/11/google-must-not-capitulate-to-chinas-censorship-demands/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;in calling on Google to cancel project Dragonfly&lt;/strong&gt;, Google’s effort to create &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/08/01/google-china-search-engine-censorship/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/08/01/google-china-search-engine-censorship/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a censored search&lt;/a&gt; engine for the Chinese market that &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/09/14/google-china-prototype-links-searches-to-phone-numbers/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/09/14/google-china-prototype-links-searches-to-phone-numbers/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;enables state surveillance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a878&quot; id=&quot;a878&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We are among thousands of employees who have raised our voices for months. International &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hrw.org/news/2018/08/28/open-letter-google-reported-plans-launch-censored-search-engine-china&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.hrw.org/news/2018/08/28/open-letter-google-reported-plans-launch-censored-search-engine-china&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;human rights&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2018/08/open-letter-to-google-on-reported-plans-to-launch-a-censored-search-engine-in-china/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2018/08/open-letter-to-google-on-reported-plans-to-launch-a-censored-search-engine-in-china/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;organizations&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/08/17/internal-meeting-reveals-how-google-bosses-misled-staff-on-their-china-censorship-plan-here-are-the-questions-they-must-answer/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/08/17/internal-meeting-reveals-how-google-bosses-misled-staff-on-their-china-censorship-plan-here-are-the-questions-they-must-answer/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;investigative reporters&lt;/a&gt; have also sounded the alarm, emphasizing serious human rights concerns and repeatedly calling on Google to cancel the project. So far, our leadership’s response has been unsatisfactory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;73b4&quot; id=&quot;73b4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Our opposition to Dragonfly is not about China: we object to technologies that aid the powerful in oppressing the vulnerable, wherever they may be.&lt;/strong&gt; The Chinese government certainly isn’t alone in its readiness to stifle freedom of expression, and to use surveillance to repress dissent. Dragonfly in China would establish a dangerous precedent at a volatile political moment, one that would make it harder for Google to deny other countries similar concessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;13b7&quot; id=&quot;13b7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Our company’s decision comes as the Chinese government is openly expanding &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/08/business/china-surveillance-technology.html&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/08/business/china-surveillance-technology.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;its surveillance powers&lt;/a&gt; and tools of population control. Many of these rely on advanced technologies, and combine online activity, personal records, and mass monitoring to track and profile citizens. Reports are already showing who bears the cost, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/briefing/2018/05/31/china-has-turned-xinjiang-into-a-police-state-like-no-other&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/briefing/2018/05/31/china-has-turned-xinjiang-into-a-police-state-like-no-other&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Uyghurs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2017/07/27/why-is-beijing-afraid-of-chinese-feminists/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.28c481d65315&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2017/07/27/why-is-beijing-afraid-of-chinese-feminists/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.28c481d65315&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;women’s rights advocates&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/11/world/asia/china-student-activists.html&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/11/world/asia/china-student-activists.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;students&lt;/a&gt;. Providing the Chinese government with ready access to user data, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/2167240/chinese-police-get-power-inspect-internet-service-providers&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/2167240/chinese-police-get-power-inspect-internet-service-providers&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;required by Chinese law&lt;/a&gt;, would make Google complicit in oppression and human rights abuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;21f7&quot; id=&quot;21f7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Dragonfly would also enable censorship and government-directed disinformation, and destabilize the ground truth on which popular deliberation and dissent rely. Given the Chinese government’s reported suppression of dissident voices, such controls would likely be used to silence marginalized people, and favor information that promotes government interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a2ee&quot; id=&quot;a2ee&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Many of us accepted employment at Google with the company’s values in mind, including its &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicpolicy.googleblog.com/2010/03/new-approach-to-china-update.html&quot; data-href=&quot;https://publicpolicy.googleblog.com/2010/03/new-approach-to-china-update.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;previous position&lt;/a&gt; on Chinese censorship and surveillance, and an understanding that Google was a company willing to place its values above its profits. After a year of disappointments including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/04/technology/google-letter-ceo-pentagon-project.html&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/04/technology/google-letter-ceo-pentagon-project.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Project Maven&lt;/a&gt;, Dragonfly, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/25/technology/google-sexual-harassment-andy-rubin.html&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/25/technology/google-sexual-harassment-andy-rubin.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google’s support for abusers&lt;/a&gt;, we no longer believe this is the case. This is why we’re taking a stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9593&quot; id=&quot;9593&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We join with Amnesty International in demanding that Google cancel Dragonfly. We also demand that leadership commit to &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/heres-the-letter-1-400-google-workers-sent-leadership-i-1828393599&quot; data-href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/heres-the-letter-1-400-google-workers-sent-leadership-i-1828393599&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;transparency, clear communication, and real accountability&lt;/a&gt;. Google is too powerful not to be held accountable. We deserve to know what we’re building and we deserve a say in these significant decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;51b6&quot; id=&quot;51b6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Signed,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3a6b&quot; id=&quot;3a6b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Rebecca Ackermann, UX Designer&lt;br/&gt;Ammar Aijazi, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Owain G. Ainsworth, Senior Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ange Albertini, Security Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alejandro Alderman, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;David H. Alexander, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sarah Allen, Technical Lead/Manager&lt;br/&gt;Randy Almand, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Abdulmajid Alnouri, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alon Altman, Senior Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Nina-Marie Amadeo, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Andrés Ambrois, Senior Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Christopher Anderson, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ryan Anderson, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Allison Andrews, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jamie Andrews, Software Engineer, Tools and Infrastructure&lt;br/&gt;Olivier Ansaldi, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Wesley Aptekar-Cassels, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Guillaume Aubian, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Arianna Avanzini, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Eva Bacon, Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Daniel Bali, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Janos Barbero, Software engineer&lt;br/&gt;Eric Barndollar, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ivan Baroni, Analytical Lead&lt;br/&gt;Pierre-Alexandre Bastarache Roberge, Software Developer&lt;br/&gt;Laetitia Baudoin, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Daniel Bauman, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Pinal Bavishi, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;David Bendebury, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Luca Bigliardi, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Steven Bills, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Max Bittker, Software Engineer &lt;br/&gt;Ryan Biwer, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Naomi Black, Technical Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Donald S. Black, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Adam Blackburn Norberg, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Penny Blackwell, Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Bryan Blatt, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Dan Boger, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Benoit Boissinot, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Peter Boothe, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;David Bort, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Randall Bosetti, Senior Staff Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Pierre Bourdon, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jen Bourey, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jeff Bowden, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Keith Brady, Staff Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Matthew Braithwaite, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Gordon Brander, Designer&lt;br/&gt;Shawn Brenneman, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Michael Bringle, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Chad Brubaker, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Christian Brunschen, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Colm Buckley, Engineering Director&lt;br/&gt;Liza Burakova, Security Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Bri Burr, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Toby Burress, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jason Cahoon, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Francis Carr, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Erik Carter, Art Director&lt;br/&gt;Mike Castle, Release Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Mike Castner, Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;John Cater, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Bruno Cauet, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Clay Caviness, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Rodrigo Chandia, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Craig Chasseur, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;David Chess, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sergio Clemente Filho, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Isaac Clerencia, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Marc Cohen, Staff Developer Advocate&lt;br/&gt;Travis Collins, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Marie Collins, Business Analyst&lt;br/&gt;Mike Conley, Senior Technical Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Patrick Conner, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ollie Cook, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Brett Cooley, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jim Coursey, Sound Designer&lt;br/&gt;Paul Cowan, Site Reliability Manager&lt;br/&gt;Charles Crissman, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;James Crooks, Software Engineer, Site Reliability&lt;br/&gt;Stryder Crown, Custom Solutions Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Cian Cullinan, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Aleksandra Culver, Senior Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Marco Cunha, Strategic Cloud Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Silas Cutler, Security Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Fergal Daly, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Philip Davis, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Michael De Rosa, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Josh Deprez, Senior Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Aloke Desai, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Damien Desfontaines, Privacy Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Susan Dickey, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Kate Donahue, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Giles Douglas, Senior Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Don Dresser, Technical Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Karel Driesen, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Grégoire Duchêne, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Paul Duke, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Thai Duong, Information Security Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Bobby Dygert, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Z Edens, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Julia Edholm, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ben Eggers, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Abraham Egnor, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Todd Eisenberger, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Joshua Emele, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alexandre Emelianov, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Burcin Erocal, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Gabriel Ewing, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Michael Falgoust, UX Researcher&lt;br/&gt;Nick Felt, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Mark Fickett, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sean Finney, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Paul Fisher, Senior software engineer&lt;br/&gt;Liz Fong-Jones, Staff Developer Advocate&lt;br/&gt;Roman Franchuk, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Gustavo Franco, Site Reliability Manager&lt;br/&gt;Amr Gaber, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Cory Gagliardi, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Gianni Gambetti, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Antonio Garcia, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Matthew Garrett, Staff Security Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Nicole Gfroerer, Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Dan Glick, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Lynne Goerner, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Beth Goldberg, Research Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Brian Goldman, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Boaz Goldstein, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Pedro Gonnet, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ian Gorham, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ian Gowen, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Reilly Grant, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sachith Gullapalli, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Andrew Gunsch, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Bruce Hahne, Technical Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Jaakko Häme, Technical Specialist&lt;br/&gt;Logan Hanks, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Shawn Hannah, Technical Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Mila Hardt, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alyssa Haroldsen, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Gautam Hathi, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Toby Hawker, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Will Hayworth, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Anna Henrichs, Data Analyst&lt;br/&gt;Andy Herrman, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Johnicholas Hines, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Andrew Ho, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Paul Hobbs, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sarah Hodne, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Aidan Holloway-Bidwell, Software Engineer in Tools and Infrastructure&lt;br/&gt;Tyler Holsclaw, IT Resident&lt;br/&gt;Aaron Homer, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Dan Hope, UX Writer&lt;br/&gt;Hollee Hord, Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Waldemar Horwat, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Kuan-Yu Hsiao, Google Ads Program Manager &lt;br/&gt;David B Huang, Strategy &amp;amp; Operations Associate&lt;br/&gt;Sebastian Hubbard, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Brady Hunsaker, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Eric Hustvedt, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Simon Ilyushchenko, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Kelli Ireland, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Dan Irwin, Senior Test Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Pavel Ivanov, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Michał Jabczyński, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Keith Jackson, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Bartosz Janiak, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Phoebe Jenkins, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Brandon Jewett-Hall, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Hongming Jin, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Tim Johnson, Sr. Security Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Patrick Jones, Technical Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Brandon Jones, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Abi Jones, Senior Interaction Designer&lt;br/&gt;Mike Jurney, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Max Kaehn, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alex Kahn, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Tom Karlo, Senior Product Manager&lt;br/&gt;Kris Kennaway, Staff Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Gabriel Kerneis, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Peter Kerzum, Swe / Sre&lt;br/&gt;Andrea Kilpatrick, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Zu Kim, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alex Kim, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Nathan Kiner, Product Analyst&lt;br/&gt;Jamie Kinney, Cloud Solutions Architect&lt;br/&gt;Kathi R. Kitner, Staff UXR/Anthropologist &lt;br/&gt;Kasey Klimes, UX Researcher&lt;br/&gt;Irene Knapp, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Thomas Koch, Technical Solutions Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Greg Kochanski, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Hanna Kollo, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Kris Kooi, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Marcin Kowalczyk, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Gabe Krabbe, Senior Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Thomas Kreeger, Systems Administrator&lt;br/&gt;Natarajan Krishnaswami, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ryuho Kudo, Test Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Mikhail Kulemin, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Matthew Kulukundis, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Vineet Kumar, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jeremy Kun, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Yuri Kunde Schlesner, Software Engineer, Site Reliability Engineering&lt;br/&gt;Adrien Kunysz, Systems Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Aysha Kureishi, Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Victoria Lai, Analytical lead&lt;br/&gt;Aimee Langmaid, Senior Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Pierre-François Laquerre, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Marcos Lara-Reinhold, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Robin Lassonde, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sage LaTorra, Senior Test Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Reuven Lazarus, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Antoine Leblanc, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alice Lemieux, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jonathan Lepage, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jack Ley, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Tom Li, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Joshua Liebow-Feeser, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Samuel Lijin, Software Engineer, Tools and Infrastructure&lt;br/&gt;Lu Liu, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Miguel Lourenco, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Christopher Lu, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Viet-Tam Luu, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Emily Maier, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jake Marcus, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Brian Marete, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Orion Martin, Software Engineer Tools and Infrastructure&lt;br/&gt;Michael Martin, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Robin Martinjak, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Geoff Matters, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Brian McBarron, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ted McCarthy, User Researcher&lt;br/&gt;Jason McGibbon, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Colin McMillen, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Miguel Mendez, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Kwasi Mensah, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Emily Metcalfe, Security Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Remoun Metyas, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Henning Meyer, Senior Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Dean Michael Berris, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Robert L Miller, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Damien Miller, Staff Information Security Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Peter Milley, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Bryan C. Mills, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Phillips Mitchell, Vendor Manager&lt;br/&gt;Dominic Mitchell, Software Engineer in Tools &amp;amp; Infrastructure&lt;br/&gt;Jessa Mittleman, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Laura Mo, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Steven Monacelli, Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;David Morell, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sven Mueller, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Cristina Munoz, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Bert Muthalaly, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Aditi Nagaraj, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Dan Nanas, Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Max Nash, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Maajid Nazrulla, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Christopher Neffshade, Data Scientist&lt;br/&gt;John Nesky, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Rob Neuhaus, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ned Nguyen, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Chris Niekel, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ben Niemann, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;André Nogueira, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Mike Nonemacher, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Peter Nuttall, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Robert Obryk, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Andrew Olsen, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;John Olson, Software Engineering Manager&lt;br/&gt;Kjetil Ørbekk, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ayla Ounce, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Chris Palmer, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;John Panzer, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Stephanie Parker, Policy Specialist&lt;br/&gt;Kathrin Paschen, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Vanja Pejovic, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;John Phillpot, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Anthony Polito, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ian Post, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Michael Powell, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Joshua Pratt, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alessandro Preite Martinez, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Xavid Pretzer, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Vikas Pydah, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Dante Qin, Corporate Operations Engineer&lt;br/&gt;David Quinn, Data Scientist&lt;br/&gt;Sverre Rabbelier, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jesper Ramsgaard, UX researcher&lt;br/&gt;Burton Rast, UX Design Lead&lt;br/&gt;Connor Regan, Product Marketing Manager, Hardware&lt;br/&gt;Tom Renn, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Joe Richey, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Owen Rodley, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jacqueline Rogoff, Software Engineer Tools and Infrastructure&lt;br/&gt;Natasha Ross, Executive Business Partner&lt;br/&gt;Robert Rossney, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Michael Safyan, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Yuzu Saijo, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Eric Salo, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Mike Samuel, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sheldon Sandbekkhaug, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Michael K. Sanders, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Aprotim Sanyal, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Michael Saunders, Product Manager&lt;br/&gt;Christopher Schmidt, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Tim Schuster, Data Analyst&lt;br/&gt;Erty Seidohl, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Yash Sekhon, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alexey Semenko, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ali Shah, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Thomas Sharp, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Adam Shaw, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Kimos Shehata, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Martin Shelton, UX Researcher&lt;br/&gt;Andrew Sherman, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Michael Shields, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Matthew Siegler, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Austin Sims, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Joëlle Skaf, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sophie Smithburg, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sara Smollett, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Shawn Smout, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jacob Smullyan, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Derek Snyder, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Matthew Sperry, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Kyle Spiers, Security Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Venkatesh Srinivas, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Joshua Steadmon, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Andrew Stebbins, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ben Stewart, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alec Story, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Stevie Strickland, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Murali Suriar, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Brian Swetland, Senior Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Huseyin Tasbent, Account Manager&lt;br/&gt;Mohammad Tayseer, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jennifer Thakar, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Daniel Thornburgh, Software Engineer in Tools and Infrastructure&lt;br/&gt;Arthur Tilley, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Finbarr Timbers, Research Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Spencer Tofts, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Anton Tolchanov, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Valentin Tolmer, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jonathan Tomer, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Omer Torok, Account Manager&lt;br/&gt;Taylor Trimble, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Seth Troisi, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Philip Tucker, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Zora Tung, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;David Turner, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jakub Turski, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Rose Valle, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Filippo Valsorda, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jan Van Bruggen, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;JC van Winkel, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Andrei Vancea, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Arne Vansteenkiste, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Pascal Varet, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Sandeep Vijayasekar, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Salim Virji, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Joel Votaw, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Ryan Waldman, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Rachel Walker, User Experience Researcher&lt;br/&gt;Adrienne Walker, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Shawn Wallace, Engineering Manager&lt;br/&gt;Ann Wallace, Cloud Security Consultant&lt;br/&gt;Jazbel Wang, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Paul Wankadia, Systems Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Peter Ward, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Michael Weatherford, Test Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Chris Weisiger, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Natalie Weizenbaum, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Guillaume Wenzek, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Drew Weymouth, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Colin Whitmarsh, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Meredith Whittaker, Google Open Research Lead&lt;br/&gt;Rachel Wiens, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Kimberly Wilber, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jamie Wilkinson, Senior Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Lori Williams, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jon Wilson, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Titus Winters, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;John Wohn, Cloud Program Manager&lt;br/&gt;Ryan Wolf, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Benjamin Wolf, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Mark Womack, Staff Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;James Woodyatt, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;David Worsham, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Edmund Wright, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Huajie Wu, Software Engineer, Tools and Infrastructure&lt;br/&gt;Juerg Wullschleger, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Kuo-Hsin Yang, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jeffrey Yasskin, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;D. L. Yonge-Mallo, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Tony Young, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Tariq Yusuf, Privacy Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Joel Zacharias, Senior Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Alexandre Zani, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Susanna Zaraysky, Content Strategist, Material Design&lt;br/&gt;Daria Zenkova, Site Reliability Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Jean Zheng, Senior Staff Technology Manager&lt;br/&gt;Bonnie Zhou, Software Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Augustin Zidek, Research Engineer&lt;br/&gt;Miriam Zimmerman, Software Engineer &lt;br/&gt;Elsa Zuckerman, Software Engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1ebd&quot; id=&quot;1ebd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;*We will be updating this post with additional signatures as they come in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 15:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>daveowei</dc:creator>
<og:title>We are Google employees. Google must drop Dragonfly.</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@googlersagainstdragonfly/we-are-google-employees-google-must-drop-dragonfly-4c8a30c5e5eb</og:url>
<og:description>We are Google employees and we join Amnesty International in calling on Google to cancel project Dragonfly, Google’s effort to create a…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@googlersagainstdragonfly/we-are-google-employees-google-must-drop-dragonfly-4c8a30c5e5eb</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>