<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Unilever threatens to pull its ads from Facebook and Google over &amp;#039;toxic content&amp;#039;</title>
<link>http://www.latimes.com/business/technology/la-fi-tn-unilever-ads-google-facebook-20180212-story.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.latimes.com/business/technology/la-fi-tn-unilever-ads-google-facebook-20180212-story.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Fake news, racism, sexism, terrorists spreading messages of hate, toxic content directed at children — parts of the internet we have ended up with is a million miles from where we thought it would take us,&quot; Weed said in a speech at the Interactive Advertising Bureau's Leadership Meeting in Palm Desert. &quot;It is in the digital media industry's interest to listen and act on this.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 21:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CodeSheikh</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.latimes.com/business/technology/la-fi-tn-unilever-ads-google-facebook-20180212-story.html</og:url>
<og:title>Giant advertiser Unilever threatens to pull its ads from Facebook and Google over 'toxic content'</og:title>
<og:image>http://www.latimes.com/resizer/hGLerXivX6W9HsE2UpIhs6dHSHY=/1200x0/www.trbimg.com/img-5a8224f9/turbine/la-fi-tn-unilever-ads-google-facebook-20180212</og:image>
<og:description>Unilever, one of the world's largest advertisers, is threatening to pull its ads from social sites such as Facebook and YouTube if the tech companies don't do more to minimize divisive content on their platforms. Unilever brands include Dove, Lipton, Axe and Ben &amp; Jerry's.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.latimes.com/business/technology/la-fi-tn-unilever-ads-google-facebook-20180212-story.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Picture of a Single Atom Wins Science Photo Contest</title>
<link>https://petapixel.com/2018/02/12/picture-single-atom-wins-science-photo-contest/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://petapixel.com/2018/02/12/picture-single-atom-wins-science-photo-contest/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/02/singleatomhead-800x800.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-303326&quot; srcset=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/02/singleatomhead-800x800.jpg 800w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/02/singleatomhead-100x100.jpg 100w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/02/singleatomhead-320x320.jpg 320w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/02/singleatomhead.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A remarkable photo of a single atom trapped by electric fields has just been awarded the top prize in a well-known science photography competition. The photo is titled “Single Atom in an Ion Trap” and was shot by David Nadlinger of the University of Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council (EPSRC) in the UK &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epsrc.ac.uk/newsevents/news/single-trapped-atom-captures-science-photography-competitions-top-prize/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;follow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;today announced&lt;/a&gt; the winning photos of its national science photography competition. Nadlinger’s grand prize photo shows an atom as a speck of light between two metal electrodes placed about 2mm (0.078in) apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/02/cropatom-800x603.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;603&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-303327&quot; srcset=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/02/cropatom-800x603.jpg 800w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/02/cropatom-320x241.jpg 320w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/02/cropatom.jpg 1184w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;A crop of the winning photo that shows the single atom being suspended at the center of the frame.
&lt;p&gt;The caption reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the center of the picture, a small bright dot is visible – a single positively-charged strontium atom. It is held nearly motionless by electric fields emanating from the metal electrodes surrounding it. […] When illuminated by a laser of the right blue-violet color, the atom absorbs and re-emits light particles sufficiently quickly for an ordinary camera to capture it in a long exposure photograph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture was taken through a window of the ultra-high vacuum chamber that houses the trap. Laser-cooled atomic ions provide a pristine platform for exploring and harnessing the unique properties of quantum physics. They are used to construct extremely accurate clocks or, as in this research, as building blocks for future quantum computers, which could tackle problems that stymie even today’s largest supercomputers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The idea of being able to see a single atom with the naked eye had struck me as a wonderfully direct and visceral bridge between the miniscule quantum world and our macroscopic reality,” Nadlinger tells EPSRC. “A back-of-the-envelope calculation showed the numbers to be on my side, and when I set off to the lab with camera and tripods one quiet Sunday afternoon, I was rewarded with this particular picture of a small, pale blue dot.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photo was captured on August 7th, 2017, using a Canon 5D Mark II DSLR, a Canon EF 50mm f/1.8 lens, extension tubes, and two flash units with color gels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image credits:&lt;/strong&gt; Photograph and crop by David Nadlinger, courtesy EPSRC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 21:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gokhan</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Picture of a Single Atom Wins Science Photo Contest</og:title>
<og:description>A remarkable photo of a single atom trapped by electric fields has just been awarded the top prize in a well-known science photography competition. The pho</og:description>
<og:url>https://petapixel.com/2018/02/12/picture-single-atom-wins-science-photo-contest/</og:url>
<og:image>https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/02/singleatomfeat.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://petapixel.com/2018/02/12/picture-single-atom-wins-science-photo-contest/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>German court rules Facebook use of personal data illegal</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-germany-facebook/german-court-rules-facebook-use-of-personal-data-illegal-idUSKBN1FW1FI?il=0</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-germany-facebook/german-court-rules-facebook-use-of-personal-data-illegal-idUSKBN1FW1FI?il=0</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;MegaArticleBody_first-p_2htdt&quot;&gt;BERLIN (Reuters) - A German consumer rights group said on Monday that a court had found Facebook’s use of personal data to be illegal because the U.S. social media platform did not adequately secure the informed consent of its users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The verdict, from a Berlin regional court, comes as Big Tech faces increasing scrutiny in Germany over its handling of sensitive personal data that enables it to micro-target online advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Federation of German Consumer Organisations (vzvb) said that Facebook’s default settings and some of its terms of service were in breach of consumer law, and that the court had found parts of the consent to data usage to be invalid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Facebook hides default settings that are not privacy-friendly in its privacy center and does not provide sufficient information about it when users register,” said Heiko Duenkel, litigation policy officer at the vzvb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“This does not meet the requirement for informed consent.” The vzvb posted a copy of the ruling on its website. A court spokesperson confirmed that a judgment had been handed down but declined further comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FACEBOOK TO APPEAL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook said it would appeal, even though several aspects of the court judgment had been in its favor. In a statement, it said it had already made significant changes to its terms of service and data protection guidelines since the case was first brought in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“We are working hard to ensure that our guidelines are clear and easy to understand, and that the services offered by Facebook are in full accordance with the law,” Facebook said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Further, Facebook would in the meantime update its data protection guidelines and its terms of service so that they comply with new European Union-wide rules that are due to enter force in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook, which counts more than 2 billion users worldwide, already faces scrutiny from Germany’s competition authorities over its handling of its users’ personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Federal Cartel Office, in an interim update on an investigation into Facebook, said in December that it objected to the way the company gains access to third-party data when an account is opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;This includes tapping information from its own WhatsApp and Instagram products - as well as how it tracks which sites its users access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;One concern highlighted by the consumer rights group was that, in Facebook’s app for smartphones, a service was pre-activated that revealed the user’s location to the person they were chatting to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Also, in the privacy settings, ticks were already placed in boxes that allowed search engines to link to the user’s timeline, meaning that anyone would be able quickly and easily to find a user’s profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“The judges ruled that all five of the default settings on Facebook that vzvb complained about are invalid,” the group said in a statement, adding that several other of Facebook’s terms of use were found to be illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container_28wm1&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution_o4ojT&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content_27_rw&quot;&gt;Writing by Douglas Busvine; Editing by Susan Fenton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer_1gqgJ&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle_7sKLj&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 20:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>HoppedUpMenace</dc:creator>
<og:title>German court rules Facebook use of personal data illegal</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-germany-facebook/german-court-rules-facebook-use-of-personal-data-illegal-idUSKBN1FW1FI</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>A German consumer rights group said on Monday that a court had found Facebook's use of personal data to be illegal because the U.S. social media platform did not adequately secure the informed consent of its users.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20180212&amp;t=2&amp;i=1230704407&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEE1B11E</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-germany-facebook/german-court-rules-facebook-use-of-personal-data-illegal-idUSKBN1FW1FI?il=0</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SpaceX&amp;#039;s Falcon Heavy center booster lacked ignition fluid to re-light engines</title>
<link>http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-spacex-falcon-heavy-core-20180212-story.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-spacex-falcon-heavy-core-20180212-story.html</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-spacex-falcon-heavy-core-20180212-story.html&quot;&gt;http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-spacex-falcon-heavy-core-20180212-story.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16361610&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16361610&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 208&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 158&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 20:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-spacex-falcon-heavy-core-20180212-story.html</og:url>
<og:title>SpaceX's Falcon Heavy center booster lacked enough ignition fluid to light engines, land on platform, Musk says</og:title>
<og:image>http://www.latimes.com/resizer/pZAhQhz8yDJ4DgjA6ejypyrPmzc=/1200x0/www.trbimg.com/img-5a81eb57/turbine/la-fi-spacex-falcon-heavy-core-20180212</og:image>
<og:description>SpaceX Chief Executive Elon Musk said the Falcon Heavy's center core didn't have enough ignition fluid to light the rocket's outer two engines to land on the floating sea platform.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-spacex-falcon-heavy-core-20180212-story.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hidden work when launching a SaaS</title>
<link>https://workshop.kwoosh.com/post/the-hidden-work-when-launching-a-saas.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://workshop.kwoosh.com/post/the-hidden-work-when-launching-a-saas.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve built and sold software for the Mac and iOS. Those products all had simple billing systems. On the Mac, I just plugged in a framework eSellerate and added a couple of hooks in my software to integrate. eSellerate handled all of the billing, taxes and so forth. This let me focus 100% on my product, and then tack the part that allowed customers to pay me. For the service they charged around 10 or 12%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On iOS (and later on the Mac) it was further simplified by Apple handling everything via the AppStore. This was a huge benefit because no work is required by the developer. They can focus 100% on the app, at least as far as payments are concerned, and it costs 30% of the app price. However, they lose the ability to communicate with their customers, unless they build out forms in their app to collect that information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these cases are all one-time sale purchases. Send an email on purchase and you’re finished. Using something like eSellerate or the AppStore and it’s all done for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a SaaS, you need to handle all of that yourself. You need to handle payments, and invoices and everything inbetween.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s when I realized we hadn’t addressed that part of the application yet. We had built in a Sign Up screen to create accounts, but not the 90% required to make it usable by actual customers. It’s easy to forget all of this extra work exists until you start thinking through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. What are the next actions you want a customer to perform (i.e. Sign Up) b. If you were a customer who just performed an action (Signed up) what sort of communications might you expect and when might you expect them c. What kinds of documents might you need to procure to pay for the app e.g. an invoice to send to your boss to authorize the credit card payment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the “hidden”work, work outside of our main app, we needed to complete was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create an account and start a trial with our payment provider when customer account created&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charge sales tax for users in Texas
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Which means we needed to know &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; our customer lives, so building out a form, database table, and workflow to allows users to display and edit their address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synced with our payment provider and update sales tax accordingly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As Kwoosh licensed per-user, sync their subscription when a user is added or removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display a list of invoices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a view to display a single invoice
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pull in event information e.g. when was this invoice created, when was it paid, and display it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure the breadcrumbs make sense for the context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welcome Email drafting, screenshot production, and coding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it didn’t seem like a lot at first glance the amount of work on a non-core feature to make it right is quite large. While I’m happy with the backend, our invoice display needs a bit more work. As this is our workshop, our place for show and tell, I present you with our Work in Progress Invoice screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.kwoosh.com/workshop/images/2018/02/12/invoice.png&quot; alt=&quot;The first version of the Kwoosh invoice.&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;—jvd&lt;/span&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 18:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mijustin</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://assets.kwoosh.com/workshop/images/opengraph.png</og:image>
<og:title>The hidden work when launching a SaaS — The Workshop @Kwoosh</og:title>
<og:description>I’ve built and sold software for the Mac and iOS. Those products all had simple billing systems. On the Mac, I just plugged in a framework eSellerate and add...</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://workshop.kwoosh.com/post/the-hidden-work-when-launching-a-saas.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook lost around 2.8M U.S. users under 25 last year</title>
<link>https://www.recode.net/2018/2/12/16998750/facebooks-teen-users-decline-instagram-snap-emarketer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.recode.net/2018/2/12/16998750/facebooks-teen-users-decline-instagram-snap-emarketer</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;HTwdlH&quot;&gt;Facebook is losing young users even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2017/8/21/16181348/teenagers-millennials-users-facebook-instagram-snapchat-emarketer&quot;&gt;quicker than expected&lt;/a&gt;, according to new estimates by eMarketer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;XB8TWi&quot;&gt;The digital measurement firm predicted last year that Facebook would see a 3.4 percent drop in 12- to 17-year-old users in the U.S. in 2017, the first time it had predicted a drop in usage for any age group on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ueIzlc&quot;&gt;The reality: The number of U.S. Facebook users in the 12- to 17-year-old demographic declined by 9.9 percent in 2017, eMarketer found, or about 1.4 million total users. That’s almost three times the decline expected. There were roughly 12.1 million U.S. Facebook users in the 12- to 17-year-old demographic by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;r7mNbg&quot;&gt;There are likely multiple reasons for the decline. Facebook has been losing its “cool” factor for years, and young people have more options than ever for staying in touch with friends and family. Facebook also serves as a digital record keeper — but many young people don’t seem to care about saving their life online, at least not publicly. That explains why Snapchat and Instagram, which offer features for sharing photos and videos that disappear, are growing in popularity among this demographic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5OZbsd&quot;&gt;Overall, eMarketer found Facebook lost about 2.8 million U.S. users under 25 last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;O5SHmc&quot;&gt;And Facebook’s 2018 doesn’t look much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;EBW4dJ&quot;&gt;The research firm released Facebook usage estimates for 2018 on Monday, and expects that Facebook will lose about 2.1 million users in the U.S. under the age of 25 this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;49hTZY&quot;&gt;EMarketer predicts that Facebook will see a decline in usage among all three age groups for people under 25:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;nkyWTr&quot;&gt;A 9.3 percent drop for Facebook users under 11 years old. (Reminder: Facebook’s terms of service require that users must be 13 years old in order to create an account, though it’s easy to get around that.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;rgIFIU&quot;&gt;A 5.6 percent decline in users between 12 and 17 years old.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;aTcfZb&quot;&gt;A 5.8 percent decline in users between 18 and 24 years old. This is the first time eMarketer has ever predicted a year-over-year decline in usage for this age group, though it has happened before. In 2016, Facebook’s user base for 18- to 24-year-olds fell by 1.5 percent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;ks8FrI&quot;&gt;Take the numbers with a grain of salt — eMarketer is an outside research firm so it doesn’t have the full picture that, say, Facebook has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;DHB3QS&quot;&gt;But the fact that eMarketer is predicting declines across the board is a bad sign for Facebook regardless. Young people offer a good barometer for what is popular, but more importantly for Facebook, losing out on the next generation of internet users in the U.S. is troubling for the company’s long-term dominance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;HVFZeh&quot;&gt;The good news for Facebook is that, despite the expected decline in younger users, eMarketer believes Facebook’s overall U.S. audience will continue to grow for the next few years. More importantly, perhaps, eMarketer expects Facebook-owned Instagram to grow significantly. The research firm believes Instagram’s U.S. user base will grow by 13 percent this year, to almost 105 million people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;WwMF1b&quot;&gt;That’s even better than Snapchat’s expected growth — eMarketer believes it will grow its U.S. audience by 9 percent in 2018. That would give Snapchat about 86.5 million users by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;p-entry-hr&quot; id=&quot;CkYHGR&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;1yP08n&quot; readability=&quot;1.4192307692308&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 17:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rblion</dc:creator>
<og:description>That’s according to research firm eMarketer.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8xKQJQQ_akEGH-LH9TkbE06t7Ic=/0x0:5472x2865/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/8829581/GettyImages_642714816.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Facebook lost around 2.8 million U.S. users under 25 last year. 2018 won’t be much better.</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.recode.net/2018/2/12/16998750/facebooks-teen-users-decline-instagram-snap-emarketer</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.recode.net/2018/2/12/16998750/facebooks-teen-users-decline-instagram-snap-emarketer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Long, Slow Decline of BitTorrent (2017)</title>
<link>https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/2017/06/01/the-long-slow-decline-of-bittorrent/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/2017/06/01/the-long-slow-decline-of-bittorrent/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-26020&quot; src=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bittorrent-06-535x535-250x250.png&quot; alt=&quot;BitTorrent Logo&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bittorrent-06-535x535-250x250.png 250w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bittorrent-06-535x535-150x150.png 150w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bittorrent-06-535x535-420x420.png 420w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bittorrent-06-535x535.png 535w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 250px) 100vw, 250px&quot;/&gt;In 2006 BitTorrent, or specifically peer-to-peer (P2P) file sharing. was king.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/bittorrent-the-one-third-of-all-internet-traffic-myth/&quot;&gt;In a study from January of that year&lt;/a&gt;, P2P traffic accounted for over 70% of all internet traffic. Though, at that time, BitTorrent shared the file sharing crown with other networks, it quickly moved to become the number one file sharing protocol, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.ucsb.edu/~almeroth/classes/W10.290F/papers/ipoque-internet-study-08-09.pdf&quot;&gt;a title it would hold decisively by 2008&lt;/a&gt;, in part &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/uncategorized/2008/04/bittorrent-use-soars-as-mpaa-fights-on-against-p2p-sites/&quot;&gt;due to an incredible period of growth in late 2007/early 2008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, even by then cracks were showing in the P2P armor. By late 2007, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businesswire.com/portal/site/google/index.jsp?ndmViewId=news_view&amp;amp;newsId=20070618005912&amp;amp;newsLang=en&quot;&gt;web traffic had overtaken p2p traffic&lt;/a&gt;. This was largely because of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/3355565/YouTubes-meteoric-rise-clips-with-everything.html&quot;&gt;the meteoric rise of YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2011, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2011/05/netflix-traffic/&quot;&gt;P2P had fallen to under 19% in North America&lt;/a&gt; and was beaten by Netflix during peak times. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/bittorrent-file-sharing-p2p-download-upload-downloading-uploading/&quot;&gt;By 2013 that traffic was down to just 7.39 percent&lt;/a&gt; and represented a drop not just in percentage, but actual traffic. In 2015, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bgr.com/2016/01/21/netflix-downloads-bittorrent-piracy/&quot;&gt;it was estimated to be 3 percent&lt;/a&gt;, a percentage that put it on par with Hulu, the fourth most popular video streaming site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this shift has been most acutely felt in North America. Studies have found it to also be on the decline elsewhere, &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/bittorrent-traffic-share-drops-to-new-low-150918/&quot;&gt;including Europe and Asia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This decreased prominence reached a peak in May of this year when pirates threatened to leak episode of Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;Orange is the New Black&lt;/em&gt; before their slated release. Their demand for ransom was balked at the they posted the files on BitTorrent sites with almost no impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raises a simple question: What’s eating away at BitTorrent? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2017-05-02/why-netflix-is-winning-the-online-piracy-wars&quot;&gt;Why is BitTorrent the only kind of internet traffic not growing nor expected to grow&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand we have to look at all of the variables at play and understand how BitTorrent is under assault from all sides and why piracy may never be the same.&lt;span id=&quot;more-25961&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Cause 1: Better Legitimate Alternatives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-10363&quot; src=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/netflix-logo-normal-300x108.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of Netflix Logo&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;108&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/netflix-logo-normal-300x108.jpg 300w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/netflix-logo-normal.jpg 346w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;When the decline of BitTorrent and P2P file sharing is raised the credit is usually given largely to legitimate alternatives such as Netflix, Hulu and Amazon Prime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is supported by the numbers as well. Netflix, YouTube, Amazon Video, iTunes and Hulu combine to make up well over 60% of all peak internet traffic in North America. That’s 20 times the estimated size of BitTorrent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most convincing of all, the rise of Netflix as a traffic largely mirrors BitTorrent’s fall. This makes it clear that, as users were firing up Netflix, they were doing so at the expense of P2P file sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, when a month of unlimited streaming comes costs less than a lunch, people snap it up. Even more so when the library of content is sound and the ease/reliability of streaming is very high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt that Netflix and its competitors have played a significant role in the downfall of BitTorrent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Cause 2: Streaming Piracy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-26021&quot; src=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/banner-sbs-11-300x169.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kodi Logo&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;169&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/banner-sbs-11-300x169.png 300w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/banner-sbs-11-700x394.png 700w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/banner-sbs-11-696x392.png 696w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/banner-sbs-11-1068x601.png 1068w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/banner-sbs-11-747x420.png 747w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/banner-sbs-11-560x315.png 560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;However, legitimate streaming services wasn’t the only destination that former BitTorrent users went to. Many leapt onto pirate streaming services, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/illegal-streaming-is-dominating-online-piracy-2016-8&quot;&gt;which made up 74% of all visits to pirated film sites last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like their legitimate counterparts, pirate streaming sites offer greater convenience and security than BitTorrent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, that security is two-fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, it includes security from viruses and other malware that’s common on &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5261046/beware-of-viruses-in-office-2010-bittorrent-builds&quot;&gt;BitTorrent downloads&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/mac-bittorrent-client-transmission-gets-infected-with-m-1785957214&quot;&gt;BitTorrent software&lt;/a&gt;. Second, it protects against &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2011/05/biggest-bittorrent-case/&quot;&gt;legal threats filed against BitTorrent users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the risk of using BitTorrent is small, especially if done intelligently, streaming sites are seen as far safer because they don’t (or at least shouldn’t) download anything to the computer or require the user to re-share the content, greatly expanding their potential legal liability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Streaming pirate sites are more convenient than BitTorrent, especially when a permanent download isn’t useful, and tools such as Kodi boxes make it even easier. &lt;a href=&quot;https://kodi.tv/article/selling-pirate-boxes-now-illegal-eu-dev-journal&quot;&gt;So much so that they are actively being targeted for bans&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Cause 3: Enforcement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-26022&quot; src=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/dollar-941246_640-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Money Image&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/dollar-941246_640-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/dollar-941246_640-80x60.jpg 80w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/dollar-941246_640-265x198.jpg 265w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/dollar-941246_640-560x420.jpg 560w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/dollar-941246_640.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;The role of copyright enforcement in the decline of P2P file sharing is a hotly-debated one. Some headline-grabbing steps such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2014/11/04/police-finally-arrest-the-third-and-final-founder-of-the-pirate-bay/&quot;&gt;the arrest of the founders of The Pirate Bay&lt;/a&gt; did little to blunt piracy or even shutter the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in recent years anti-piracy efforts have instead focused on a more subdued approach, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/apr/02/infringing-websites-list-anti-piracy&quot;&gt;one that’s commonly referred to as “follow the money”&lt;/a&gt;. This approach works to discourage advertising and other partners, such as hosts and domain registrars, from working with pirate sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While arrests still do happen, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.co.uk/article/kat-alleged-founder-arrested&quot;&gt;such as the 2016 arrests of the alleged founders of Kickass Torrents&lt;/a&gt;, other sites shut down spontaneously, &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/extratorrent-shuts-down-for-good-170517/&quot;&gt;such as the recent closure of Extratorrents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it’s hard to know for certain, the call for donations to save the ExtraTorrent’s release group makes it clear that money was at least part of the reason. That, in turn, is likely due to a combination dwindling ad revenue and increasing expenses associated with running a pirate site in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/meganomics-the-future-of-follow-the-money-copyright-enforcement-120124/&quot;&gt;A survey of pirate sites by Torrentfreak&lt;/a&gt; found that, even with large sites, many were either barely breaking even or were even losing money, making them vulnerable this approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though some BitTorrent sites make it work, it’s getting more and more difficult to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Cause 4: Demographics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-26023&quot; src=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/danbo-2006935_640-300x170.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Parents Image&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;170&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/danbo-2006935_640-300x170.jpg 300w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/danbo-2006935_640-560x318.jpg 560w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/danbo-2006935_640.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;The peak for P2P piracy was, by most accounts, between 2003 and 2006. At the same time, piracy demographics skew heavily to a younger audience &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2011/11/its-official-america-a-land-of-young-casual-pirates/&quot;&gt;with 18-29 year olds being significantly more likely to pirate than the adult population at large&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, more than a decade later, the people who were heavy into P2P piracy are no longer in the traditional demographic for piracy. Though people of all ages pirate, the older one gets the less likely they are to pirate and the less they are likely to take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the new generation, they didn’t grow up with Napster (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Napster&quot;&gt;which is celebrating its 18th birthday today&lt;/a&gt;) or with BitTorrent. They grew up with iTunes, YouTube and Netflix. They’re much more likely to have access to paid services, use legitimate portals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, young people have greater access to legitimate services than they did 10 years ago and, when they do pirate, they’re going to turn more to streaming pirate sites rather than BitTorrent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, the convenience of Netflix and Spotify set the bar for what they wan’t out of their content, whether they get it legitimately or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, generation BitTorrent grew up and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csmonitor.com/2003/1216/p11s01-legn.html&quot;&gt;left the dorm room&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Cause 5: VPN Usage&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-20719&quot; src=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/640px-Virtual_Private_Network_overview.svg-300x212.png&quot; alt=&quot;VPN Diagram&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;212&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/640px-Virtual_Private_Network_overview.svg-300x212.png 300w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/640px-Virtual_Private_Network_overview.svg-550x388.png 550w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/640px-Virtual_Private_Network_overview.svg-100x70.png 100w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/640px-Virtual_Private_Network_overview.svg-595x420.png 595w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/640px-Virtual_Private_Network_overview.svg-610x431.png 610w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/640px-Virtual_Private_Network_overview.svg-560x396.png 560w, https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/640px-Virtual_Private_Network_overview.svg.png 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;Finally, there’s one other possibility for why BitTorrent and P2P traffic seems to be falling out of favor: It’s harder to track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though there are no hard numbers, it’s been widely reported that VPN usage has been increasing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kitguru.net/gaming/security-software/jon-martindale/uk-vpn-usage-explodes-as-digital-economy-bill-progresses/&quot;&gt;Whether it’s due to anti-piracy efforts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/2017/06/01/the-long-slow-decline-of-bittorrent/atwtxsuuezdw.html&quot; rel=&quot;file&quot; id=&quot;wxsfqqredfwxadtxszwwxztsswczbaraze&quot;&gt;vxrautvqyyvb&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2016/11/17/trump-win-drives-more-people-to-online-privacy-tools-including-vpn-and-encrypted-messaging/&quot;&gt;political changes&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://nordvpn.com/blog/vpn-popularity-increasing-due-to-privacy-fears/&quot;&gt;privacy concerns&lt;/a&gt;, by all accounts VPN usage is growing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/2017/04/05/how-the-privacy-debate-could-reshape-the-internet/&quot;&gt;and it could change the internet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real problem here is that there’s no way to know just how much of VPN traffic is growing or how much of it is BitTorrent. Though different traffic studies look at the internet from different vantage points, some simply would not be able to see VPN-obscured BitTorrent traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, it’s unlikely that VPN usage accounts for the drop in interest in BitTorrent, but it may mean the gains aren’t quite as drastic as some studies indicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For BitTorrent and P2P file sharing in general, the heyday has passed. If you’re a BitTorrent site operator, the halcyon days of the early 2000s are not coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, there will always be P2P piracy on the internet. Most predictions call for P2P traffic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2017-05-02/why-netflix-is-winning-the-online-piracy-wars&quot;&gt;to remain flat over the next few years&lt;/a&gt;. But that flatness is against the backdrop of an anticipated explosion in other types of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a percentage of traffic, P2P will, almost certainly, continue to dwindle until it’s less and less significant. Some pockets of the world will hold out longer than others, but the global trend is clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean that piracy is over and done (even P2P piracy) or that there aren’t problems with the legitimate services we have today. Creators can’t quite celebrate yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, something that seemed impossible 10 years ago has come to fruition, BitTorrent is no longer the dominant force on the internet. It’s not even the largest service for video nor is it even in the top 3 providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet is now dominated by legitimate choices for video streaming.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 16:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/decline-589-sized.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Long, Slow Decline of BitTorrent - Plagiarism Today</og:title>
<og:description>BitTorrent used to dominate not just piracy, but the internet. Now, it's barely noticed in traffic studies. What happened to the platform?</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/2017/06/01/the-long-slow-decline-of-bittorrent/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.plagiarismtoday.com/2017/06/01/the-long-slow-decline-of-bittorrent/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lessons from Optics, the Other Deep Learning</title>
<link>http://www.argmin.net/2018/01/25/optics/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.argmin.net/2018/01/25/optics/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Would you say deep learning is mature enough to be taught in high schools?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s why I ask. Some time ago, I received an email from a product manager at a very large company. I love sharing personal emails publicly, so I’ll post it here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/email.png&quot; alt=&quot;BUT HER EMAILS&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat on this email for days. I couldn’t come up with a constructive answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, I wanted to reply that maybe her engineers &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/vgg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pipelines. The source of all prosperity and misery&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re an engineer, you’re given this net, and you’re asked to make it work better on a dataset. You might presume each of these layers is there for a reason. But as a field, we don’t yet have a common language to express these reasons. The way we teach deep learning is very different from the way we teach other technical disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I got into optics. In optics, you also build stacks of components that process inputs. Here’s a camera lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/lens.png&quot; alt=&quot;My eyes hurt&quot; width=&quot;460px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To design something like this, you start with basic stackup, usually named after the famous person who invented it, you simulate it to determine how it falls short of your requirements, then insert additional components to correct the shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You then run the system through a numerical optimizer to tune its parameters, like the shape of the surfaces, their locations, and their inclinations, to maximize some design objective. Then you simulate, again, modify, optimize, and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like with a deep net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the 36 elements in the stackup is deliberately inserted to correct an aberration of some kind. This requires a very clear mental model for what each component does to the light that passes through it. That mental model is usually in terms of an action, like refraction, reflection, diffraction, dispersion, or wavefront correction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/refraction.gif&quot; alt=&quot;refraction&quot; width=&quot;90px&quot; height=&quot;90px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/reflection.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;reflection&quot; width=&quot;90px&quot; height=&quot;90px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/diffraction.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;diffraction&quot; width=&quot;90px&quot; height=&quot;90px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/dispersion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dispersion&quot; width=&quot;110px&quot; height=&quot;90px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/wavefront-correction.png&quot; alt=&quot;wavefront correction&quot; width=&quot;110px&quot; height=&quot;90px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don’t fear this design process. Each year, the US graduates hundreds of optical engineers who go on to design lenses that work. And they’re not scared of their job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not because optics is easy. It’s because the mental models in optics are organized well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern optics is taught in layers of abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/abstractions.png&quot; alt=&quot;Absractions all the way down&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the simplest layer, at the top, is ray optics. Ray optics is a simplification of wave optics, where the rays represent the normal vectors of the wavefronts in wave optics. Wave optics is an approximate solution to Maxwell’s equations. And Maxwell’s equations can be derived from quantum physics, which I don’t actually understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each layer is derived from the layer below it, by making simplifying assumptions. As such, each layer can explain a more sophisticated set of phenomena than the layer above it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/optics-scorecard.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alchemy up top, science at the bottom&quot; width=&quot;650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend most of my time designing systems at the top four levels of abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how we teach optics today. But these theories weren’t always organized in a stack like this. Until a hundred years ago, some of these theories co-existed in a conflicting state. Practitioners relied on folkloric theories of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/galileo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;And yet it magnifies&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That didn’t stop Galileo from building a pretty good telescope nearly a hundred years before Newton formalized ray optics. Galileo had a good enough mental model of light to build a telescope that could magnify 10x. But his understanding wasn’t good enough to correct chromatic aberrations, or to get a wide field of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before these theories of light were unified in stack of abstractions, each theory had to start with a fundamental concept of light from the ground up. This involves making up a fresh set of unrealistic assumptions. Newton’s ray optics modeled light as a spray of particles that could be attracted to, or repelled from, solid matter. Huygens modeled light as a longitudinal pressure wave through a mystical medium called “ether”. He modeled light like sound. Maxwell also assumed light propagates through ether. You can still see the remnant of this in the names of the coefficients in Maxwell’s equations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;silly-models-yes-but-quantitative-and-predictive&quot;&gt;Silly Models, yes. But quantitative, and Predictive.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As silly as these assumptions may sound today, these models were quantitative and they had predictive power. You could plug numbers into them and get numerical predictions out. That’s tremendously useful to an engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;seeking-a-modular-language-for-deep-learning-to-describe-the-action-of-each-layer&quot;&gt;Seeking: A modular language for deep learning to describe the action of each layer.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be easier to design deep nets if we could talk about the action of each of its layers the way we talk about the action of an optical element on the light that passes through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talk about convolutional layers as running matched filters against their inputs, and the subsequent nonlinearities as pooling. This is a relatively low-level description, akin to describing the action of a lens in terms of Maxwell’s equations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe there are higher level abstractions to rely on, in terms of a quantity that is modified as it passes through the layers of a net, akin to the action of lens in terms of how it bends rays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it would be nice if this abstraction were quantitative so you could plug numbers into a formula to run back-of-the-envelope analyses to help you design your network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;were-far-from-this-kind-of-language-lets-start-with-something-simpler&quot;&gt;We’re far from this kind of language. Let’s start with something simpler.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I’m getting carried away with fantasies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with something simpler. We have lots of mental models of how deep net training works. I’ve collected a sampling of phenomena worth explaining. Let’s see how well these mental models explain these phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get too far, I admit that this exercise is doomed. Optics had 300 years to do this. I spent a Saturday afternoon on it. In exchange I’m just reporting my findings in a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;phenomenon-a-random-initializer-for-sgd-is-good-enough-but-small-numerical-errors-thereafter-or-bad-step-sizes-break-sgd&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phenomenon:&lt;/em&gt; A random initializer for SGD is good enough. But small numerical errors thereafter, or bad step sizes, break SGD.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some practitioners have observed that small changes in how gradients are accumulated can result in vastly different performance on the test set. This comes up for example, when you train with a GPU instead of a CPU (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/2226&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/2732&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think this is a legitimate observation that’s worth explaining?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or do you think this a spurious observation, and it’s probably untrue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe you think there is something wrong with this observation, like it’s logically self-contradictory in some way, or it’s a malformed claim?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sentiments are mixed, I’m sure, but let me record this as a phenomenon and move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;phenomenon-shallow-local-minima-generalize-better-than-sharp-ones&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phenomenon:&lt;/em&gt; Shallow local minima generalize better than sharp ones.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This claim is fashionable. Some people insist it’s true (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1609.04836&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1611.01838&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1704.04289&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1710.06451&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;), and others, including myself, believe that it can’t be true on logical grounds. Others have refuted the claim on empirical grounds (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1703.04933&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;). Yet others have offered refined variants of this claim (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1706.08947&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;). Confusion remains (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/beenwrekt/status/941005520420225025&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll note that this phenomenon might be disputed, but record it nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;phenomenon-inserting-batch-norm-layers-speeds-up-sgd&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phenomenon:&lt;/em&gt; Inserting Batch Norm layers speeds up SGD.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That batchnorm works is mostly undisputed. I offer only one redoubtable exception (&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyus.joshuawise.com/batchnorm.pdf&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;)), and record this as a phenomenon with no reservation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;phenomenon-sgd-is-successful-despite-many-local-optima-and-saddle-points&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phenomenon:&lt;/em&gt; SGD is successful despite many local optima and saddle points.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several claims packed in this one. It is often claimed that the training loss surface of deep learning is rife with saddle points and local minima (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1712.04741&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;). In addition, it is variously claimed either that gradient descent can traverse these hazards (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1412.6544&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;), or that it need not traverse these hazards to produce a solution that generalizes well (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1712.04741&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;). It is also just as often claimed that the loss surface of deep models is altogether benign (&lt;a href=&quot;http://openaccess.thecvf.com/content_cvpr_2017/html/Haeffele_Global_Optimality_in_CVPR_2017_paper.html&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll record this a phenomenon, begrudgingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;phenomenon-dropout-works-better-than-other-randomization-strategies&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phenomenon:&lt;/em&gt; Dropout works better than other randomization strategies.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how to categorize the class of dropout-like things, so I’m calling them “randomization strategies”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded with apologies and without discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;phenomenon-deep-nets-can-memorize-random-labels-and-yet-they-generalize&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phenomenon:&lt;/em&gt; Deep nets can memorize random labels, and yet, they generalize.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evidence is plain (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1611.03530&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;), witnessed and supported by dear friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded as a phenomenon despite the conflict of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;explications&quot;&gt;Explications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve gathered some phenomena. From the papers I cited above, I’ve also gathered theories that I think have the best chance of explaining these phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s see how we fare:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.argmin.net/assets/optics/deeplearning-scorecard.png&quot; alt=&quot;You're fired&quot; width=&quot;650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons to not get excited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we couldn’t agree on some of the observations we were trying to explain in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I couldn’t organize the explanations into a hierarchy of abstractions. What made optics easy to learn isn’t at all manifest here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, I suspect some of the theories I’m quoting from the papers aren’t true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-point&quot;&gt;My Point&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a mass influx of newcomers to our field and we’re equipping them with little more than folklore and pre-trained deep nets, then asking them to innovate. We can barely agree on the phenomena that we should be explaining away. I think we’re far from teaching this stuff in high schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we get there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if we could provide mental models, at various layers of abstraction, of the action of the layers of a deep net. What could be our equivalent of refraction, dispersion, and diffraction? Maybe you already think in terms of these actions, but we just haven’t standardized our language around these concepts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s gather a set of phenomena that we all agree on. We could then try to explain them away. What is our equivalent of Newton Rings, the Kerr effect, or the Faraday effect?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small group of colleagues and I have started a massive empirical effort to catalogue mental models that are ambient in our field, to formalize them, and to then validate them with experiments. It’s a lot of work. I think it’s the first step to developing a layered mental model of deep learning that you could teach in high schools. If you want to chat about this project or to help out, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/beenwrekt/status/956621165161779200&quot;&gt;tweet me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 15:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mxwsn</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Lessons from Optics, The Other Deep Learning</og:title>
<og:description>Musings on systems, information, learning, and optimization.</og:description>
<og:url>http://benjamin-recht.github.io/2018/01/25/optics/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.argmin.net/2018/01/25/optics/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cloud TPUs in Beta</title>
<link>https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/02/Cloud-TPU-machine-learning-accelerators-now-available-in-beta.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/02/Cloud-TPU-machine-learning-accelerators-now-available-in-beta.html</guid>
<description></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 14:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>saeta</dc:creator>
<og:title>Cloud TPU machine learning accelerators now available in beta</og:title>
<og:url>https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/02/Cloud-TPU-machine-learning-accelerators-now-available-in-beta.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-PTPDiXQlxpQ/WoE1egCCWiI/AAAAAAAAFBc/upPx57HXKu4Ld7ieL25RWPw2_dJle9QCwCLcBGAs/s640/cloud-tpu-beta.png</og:image>
<og:description>By John Barrus, Product Manager for Cloud TPUs, Google Cloud and Zak Stone, Product Manager for TensorFlow and Cloud TPUs, Google Brain Team...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/02/Cloud-TPU-machine-learning-accelerators-now-available-in-beta.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My professional opinion as a blockchain researcher: I don’t see the point (yet)</title>
<link>https://jmkorhonen.net/2018/01/12/my-professional-opinion-as-a-blockchain-researcher-i-dont-see-the-point/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jmkorhonen.net/2018/01/12/my-professional-opinion-as-a-blockchain-researcher-i-dont-see-the-point/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the last 15 months researching the implications and possibilities of blockchains and related “distributed trust technologies” from a business and societal point of view. Sadly, I have to say that I don’t quite get the hype, as much as I’d love to believe in a technological revolution that democratises the world economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: &lt;/strong&gt;I’ve edited this text a bit to be clear that I’m talking about &lt;em&gt;public &lt;/em&gt;blockchains. &lt;em&gt;Private&lt;/em&gt; blockchains are a different matter, and they will have applications in e.g. automating many transactions. That said, the effects are hardly revolutionary, at least in the short term.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it stands, public blockchain is very much a kludgy solution looking for non-existent problem, namely lack of trusted intermediaries in finance and accounting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for this central value proposition of blockchain, there is no lack of trusted enough intermediaries in the financial/accounting sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very few people outside so-called crypto-anarchist community are opposed to trusted intermediaries as a matter of principle, and outside this (admittedly vocal) minority and those who for their own personal reasons want to believe in this scheme, I seriously doubt there is going to be a huge market of people who are willing to pay a premium (in time, effort or actual valuables) just for the sake of avoiding one sort of intermediary, only to trust the transactions to a code that may or may not be transparently accounted for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For who among us can honestly say “yes, I am capable of reviewing the code behind blockchain applications I’m using and I have personally done so to make sure I’m not being scammed?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can the people who are now willing to trust their savings to blockchain technologies  be sure that the code and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/blockchain-reconnaissance/segwit2x-proves-that-blockchain-doesnt-make-politics-obsolete-831432cd16c3&quot;&gt;its underlying governance structures&lt;/a&gt; (that is, how it is being developed and modified) are in any way better than at least nominally democratically governed systems – with at least some possibility for recourse if things go sour – they want to replace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, it all seems another gold craze, stoked not only by the usual crowd of techno-babblers keen on latching on the latest buzzword, but also by certified wingnuts from the long-discredited hyper-libertarian Austrian school of economics, kept buoyant by half-baked comparisons to “unreliable” “paper money” (which is nevertheless very effectively backed by the government’s universal tendency to require said paper money for taxes, not to mention the inconvenient fact that if societal trust erodes sufficiently for paper money to lose its value, it’s highly unlikely an arbitrary string of ones and zeros in an arbitrary hard disk somewhere would fare much better), spotty comparisons of current economic system &lt;a href=&quot;https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Inflation&quot;&gt;to few exceptions where hyperinflation was allowed to run rampant&lt;/a&gt;, and perhaps most of all, by simple wishes that the persons currently propping up the belief in blockchains will not be the last ones who are blinded by the latest buzzword and get-rich-quick scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please do not get me wrong. I believe that in the long run, crypto-enabled distributed trust technologies could possibly have significant role in enabling micropayments and microinvestments, effectively by reducing transaction costs related to distribution and bookkeeping. There may also be some &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/blockchain-reconnaissance/are-blockchains-the-3d-printing-of-trust-services-8408458cf38a&quot;&gt;very interesting applications in governance and organisation of human work,&lt;/a&gt; and these initiatives ought to be followed more closely. Furthermore, private, permissioned blockchains are already quite useful for e.g. automating transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the crypto-enthusiastic community loudly ignores that 1) there are absolutely no reasons the current banking system couldn’t reduce its own transaction costs enough to compete very effectively in these lucrative sectors, and 2) the bog standard public blockchain with its Proof of Work scheme (e.g. how Bitcoin burns electricity) is certainly not going to cut transaction costs enough, as throughput rates are simply not even within two orders of magnitude from what is needed. Case in point: a &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.bitcoin.com/miami-bitcoin-conference-stops-accepting-bitcoin-due-to-fees-and-congestion/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin developer conference just announced it won’t be accepting Bitcoin as a means of payment, because it’s too slow and the transaction fees are too high. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we will inevitably end up with some variation of Proof of Stake protocol – where we will simply have to trust some users more than others – just because Proof of Work, where we don’t have to know or trust other users, is absolutely ridiculous waste of resources and will always have trouble scaling up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, for example, how &lt;a href=&quot;https://getacryp.com/blockchain-vs-tangle-dag/&quot;&gt;Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) “tangles”&lt;/a&gt; are proposed to work. And once we go down that route, it will become increasingly hard to avoid asking the question: since distributed computing in this sort of record-keeping is always going to be less efficient than centralised computing, what are the precise reasons we should not go the whole route and designate certain nodes as … trusted intermediaries?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we’ll end up with what is basically a buzzword-enhanced database solution with some redundancy and consensus algorithms built in. These are not new, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paxos_(computer_science)&quot;&gt;PAXOS consensus algorithms debuted in 1989&lt;/a&gt; – and there are Reasons why they haven’t been used very much. Namely, performance, and the fact that there is no pressing problem these would solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crypto applications will certainly be useful for verification of various things (again, these are not exactly new ideas) and I could foresee a micropayment and &lt;a href=&quot;https://valuecraft.coop&quot;&gt;alternative finance systems&lt;/a&gt; that could well take off, provided the backbone is something else than blockchain as it is. (My money at the moment would be on DAGs, as both Bitcoin and Ethereum still seem to have grave problems scaling up – but it’s even more likely that someone will come up with something better than current DAGs.) This could develop into a microinvestment vehicle of some sort, and unlocking the investment potential of the world’s poor could well make some people very, very wealthy indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are also Reasons why such “penny stocks” have been regulated everywhere for decades if not centuries: they have &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; been fantastic vehicles for scamming the credulous. Cryptography is not some magic free lunch that totally changes the rules in investing and finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to call me a luddite or whatever. It’s just that I’ve been studying the possibilities of blockchains for business for over a year now, and while it is certainly possible that I simply lack the imagination (or chutzpah) necessary for bold proclamations, I just don’t see the possibilities the marketers seem to see.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice to all those who are interested in blockchain systems is this: think very carefully whether the problem you are interested in solving will truly be easier to solve, or can be solved better, by distributing the database to the users of the database. If the answer is yes, and &lt;em&gt;if &lt;/em&gt;you can also remain fairly confident that the solution will not infringe on privacy or financial regulation, and &lt;em&gt;if &lt;/em&gt;you have money to spare, then by all means go ahead and experiment with blockchain technologies – though keep in mind that at this stage, everything is so rudimentary that systems will have to be built from scratch (not a good idea, usually) and that technologies can change abruptly. At this moment, there are already some fairly well established private blockchains, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting things are more likely to appear in the smart contracts field, and technologies like blockchain are almost certainly going to be used both to enhance existing systems and to develop new kinds of services that are still hard to envision in detail. Some interesting developments that may point a direction to the future include automating some aspects of insurance markets, such as automating claims processing in more straightforward cases (e.g. when a flight is cancelled and customers need to be refunded) or even selling of insurances automatically based on mutually shared financial data. However, these technologies are still very much immature, and while early adopters could potentially benefit, the risks are also significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very good reads on the topic are becoming more numerous than it is possible to keep track of, but here are some of the best ones I’ve come across lately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prestonbyrne.com/2017/12/08/bitcoin_ponzi/&quot;&gt;Preston Byrne: The Problem with Calling Bitcoin a “Ponzi Scheme”&lt;/a&gt; (“This is no pyramid scheme – our model is the trapezoid!”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prestonbyrne.com/2017/09/01/the-bear-case-for-crypto/amp/&quot;&gt;Preston Byrne: The bear case for crypto, part I (the other parts are good too)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webb-site.com/articles/bitcoinponzi.asp&quot;&gt;Webb Reports: Bitcoin: The world’s first decentralized Ponzi scheme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/matt_levine/status/951147744772743168&quot;&gt;Someone wants to create “legally binding agreements” for consensual sex, and store them in … blockchain, because of course they would. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2017/10/27/biz_quadruples_value_over_night_by_adding_blockchain_to_name/&quot;&gt;One company found its valuation quadruple simply by adding “blockchain” to its name. No bubbles here, nossiree!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-08/bitcoin-resumes-drop-as-asian-regulation-demand-concerns-linger&quot;&gt;Governments are finally beginning to do something, and it doesn’t bode well for the prices of cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-official sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-15258697-1883-5a829b5c63d9d&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20180212#blog_id=15258697&amp;amp;post_id=1883&amp;amp;origin=jmkorhonen.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=15258697-1883-5a829b5c63d9d&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-15258697-1883-5a829b5c63d9d&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ericdanielski</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>My professional opinion as a blockchain researcher: I don’t see the point (yet)</og:title>
<og:url>https://jmkorhonen.net/2018/01/12/my-professional-opinion-as-a-blockchain-researcher-i-dont-see-the-point/</og:url>
<og:description>I’ve spent the last 15 months researching the implications and possibilities of blockchains and related “distributed trust technologies” from a business and societal point of view…</og:description>
<og:image>https://jmkorhonen.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/cropped-ci-270-1.gif?w=200</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jmkorhonen.net/2018/01/12/my-professional-opinion-as-a-blockchain-researcher-i-dont-see-the-point/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>