<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Cloud Storage for $2 per TB per month</title>
<link>https://blog.sia.tech/cloud-storage-for-2-tb-mo-8a34043e93bb</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.sia.tech/cloud-storage-for-2-tb-mo-8a34043e93bb</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;4.7&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;el&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;n em en eo ep&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o n&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.sia.tech/@davidvorick?source=post_page-----8a34043e93bb----------------------&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;David Vorick&quot; class=&quot;r eq er es&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/96/96/1*VyyA44ch6zcB8qyyPpql6A.png&quot; width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;48&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;8d5f&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;One of the frequent claims of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sia.tech&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Sia&lt;/a&gt; network is that over the long term, storage will be cheaper than $2 / TB / Mo, assuming that storage economics do not change. Though we’ve claimed this many times, we’ve never published a detailed model explaining where this number comes from. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e6c7&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;For the purposes of this model, we are going to be assuming an endgame where Sia has substantially outgrown all of the latent / unused storage in the world, where the only way Sia can continue to grow is by having new datacenters established for the sole purpose of profiting from selling data to the Sia network. You can follow along with the math using &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1hGc-DHftI5c9zgJuyfKpQZJPQJfam_TN2tK8qxCzeg4/edit?usp=sharing&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;this spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;2022&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj ik hl il hn im hp in hr io ht dl&quot;&gt;One of the key ways that the Sia network distinguishes itself from traditional cloud storage is its datacenter architecture and requirements. The Sia network only expects hosts to have a 95–98% uptime. Despite this, the Sia network is able to achieve 99.9999% uptime for files. This is because each piece of data on the Sia network is stored on many hosts, requiring only a subset of them to be online in order for the file to remain available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ef23&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;Today, data is typically stored on the Sia network with a 10-of-30 redundancy scheme. This means that there’s a 3x overhead, and that as long as &lt;strong class=&quot;hi ip&quot;&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; 10 hosts are online, the file itself is still retrievable. Once the Sia network is more mature, we will likely be switching to 64-of-96 hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9d08&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;If we assume that the 30 hosts go offline independently, and each host has a 95% chance of being online over a given time interval, the equation to determine the probability that a file is unavailable looks &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolframalpha.com/input/?i=sum+of+%2830+choose+x%29+*+0.95%5Ex+*+%281-0.95%29%5E%2830-x%29%2C+from+1+to+10&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;like this,&lt;/a&gt; giving a result of 10^-19, or 18 nines of uptime. Practically speaking host failures are not truly independent and you have to account for black swan situations like world war three. The true reality is that no system actually hits 18 nines of uptime (nor 11 nines of reliability).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2a49&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;Amazingly, even though 64-of-96 is only 1.5x redundancy, exactly half of the total copies of 10-of-30, the uptime equation has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolframalpha.com/input/?i=sum+of+%2896+choose+x%29+*+0.95%5Ex+*+%281-0.95%29%5E%2896-x%29%2C+from+1+to+64&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;a nearly identical result&lt;/a&gt; — 17 nines of uptime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1f12&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;In Sia’s endgame, 1.5x redundancy is the number that is most likely to be used in production contexts, so that is the number we are going to be using when we model the long term cost of storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;f742&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj ik hl il hn im hp in hr io ht dl&quot;&gt;An efficient storage rig is going to need the following parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;a4f6&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht iq ir is&quot;&gt;32x 6 TB HDD: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/HGST-7-2K-SATA-Drive-Model/dp/B07XQRBJGZ/ref=sr_1_10?keywords=6tb+internal+hdd+HGST&amp;amp;qid=1583310365&amp;amp;refinements=p_n_condition-type%3A2224371011&amp;amp;rnid=2224369011&amp;amp;s=pc&amp;amp;sr=1-10&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;$4160&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;c3fd&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj it hl iu hn iv hp iw hr ix ht iq ir is&quot;&gt;1x Mobo with 8 SATA slots: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newegg.com/asrock-x570-phantom-gaming-4/p/N82E16813157884?Item=N82E16813157884&amp;amp;Description=mobo&amp;amp;cm_re=mobo-_-13-157-884-_-Product&amp;amp;quicklink=true&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;$150&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;7dec&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj it hl iu hn iv hp iw hr ix ht iq ir is&quot;&gt;8x 4 way SATA data splitters: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/CableDeconn-SFF-8087-Degrees-Target-H0304/dp/B00XBE4DGO/ref=sr_1_2?keywords=sata+data+splitter&amp;amp;qid=1583311218&amp;amp;s=electronics&amp;amp;sr=1-2&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;$50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;c580&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj it hl iu hn iv hp iw hr ix ht iq ir is&quot;&gt;1x CPU 4 cores: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newegg.com/amd-ryzen-3-1200/p/N82E16819113446?Description=ryzen%203&amp;amp;cm_re=ryzen_3-_-19-113-446-_-Product&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;$95&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;defd&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj it hl iu hn iv hp iw hr ix ht iq ir is&quot;&gt;32 GB RAM: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newegg.com/corsair-32gb-288-pin-ddr4-sdram/p/N82E16820233894?Description=DDR4%2032%20GB&amp;amp;cm_re=DDR4_32_GB-_-20-233-894-_-Product&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;$140&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;c76d&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj it hl iu hn iv hp iw hr ix ht iq ir is&quot;&gt;1x PSU with 8 SATA cables: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newegg.com/amd-ryzen-3-1200/p/N82E16819113446?Item=9SIA4YU9XA2202&amp;amp;Description=AM4%20CPU&amp;amp;cm_re=AM4_CPU-_-19-113-446-_-Product&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;$80&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;66dc&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj it hl iu hn iv hp iw hr ix ht iq ir is&quot;&gt;8x SATA power splitters: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/StarTech-com-Power-Splitter-Adapter-PYO4SATA/dp/B0086OGN9E/ref=sr_1_4?keywords=sata+power+splitter&amp;amp;qid=1583313496&amp;amp;sr=8-4&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;$50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;538f&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj it hl iu hn iv hp iw hr ix ht iq ir is&quot;&gt;16x Stackable HDD cage: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newegg.com/phanteks-ph-hddkt-03-stackable-3-5-hdd-bracket/p/N82E16817972005?Description=HDD%20cage&amp;amp;cm_re=HDD_cage-_-17-972-005-_-Product&amp;amp;quicklink=true&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;$160&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;f6e9&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj it hl iu hn iv hp iw hr ix ht iq ir is&quot;&gt;Bare shelf: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Safco-Products-Compartment-Organization-Compartments/dp/B001E2573S/ref=sr_1_15?keywords=multi%2Bcompartment%2Bshelf&amp;amp;qid=1583315170&amp;amp;sr=8-15&amp;amp;th=1&quot; class=&quot;cp fx hu hv hw hx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;$60&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;d48a&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;What’s going here is we’re buying 32 HDDs, and then finding a low cost way to put them together. This is a technique that was championed by the Bitcoin mining industry, with unprecedented levels of corner cutting, bitcoin mining farms were able to get prices to be absurdly low. We can employ the same strategies here. With 95% uptime requirements, we don’t need to splurge on expensive parts like a full computer tower. The mobo selected above supports 48 gbps in data transfer, which means we still end up with over 1gbps per HDD even though we are doing a ton of splitting. It also turns out that 32 HDDs only consume 200w, so the 750w PSU we picked is more than sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3f55&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;In total, we’re spending $4945 to get a rig with 192 TB, or about $26/TB. And this is all paying consumer prices. This rig was assembled using consumer parts, when buying a large number of rigs at scale, a datacenter should be able to get much better pricing. So we will be using a rig cost of $4500 in our spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p id=&quot;5cb7&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;Often times for datacenter buildout, you budget around $1mm per megawatt in costs, or about $1 per watt. These rigs are going to consume about 400w each (6 watts per HDD, 65 for the CPU, 70 for RAM and mobo, and then loss from the PSU and datacenter PUE). In total, that means budgeting about $500 in capex for datacenter buildout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;659c&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;Another cost that needs to be considered is networking equipment. If we’re assuming that you can fit about 8 machines per rack, and you need $2,000 of networking equipment in the datacenter per rack, you get $250 per rig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9dce&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;Finally, everything is going to have to be assembled and constructed. Including screws and such, each rig has in the ballpark of 400 parts. That means about 2 hours of labor per rig. We’ll call that $50, bringing our total buildout expenses to $800 per rig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;9824&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj ik hl il hn im hp in hr io ht dl&quot;&gt;The whole purpose of understanding capex for the purposes of a profitable datacenter build is to model depreciation. We need to understand how much value we are losing on our hardware every year that the datacenter is in operation. Hard drives last on average about 7 years. Hard drives also go down in price over time, meaning that you lose value a little faster than hard drives break. For this example, we are going to assume a 15% depreciation rate on our storage rigs, and a 5% depreciation on our build-out. That means our total depreciation costs are $785 per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f94b&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;Investors putting money into datacenter buildout are going to expect to make more revenue than just operational costs and depreciation costs. I think a reasonable profit expectation for a datacenter built to support a mature Sia ecosystem is around 10%, because the risk of building storage for a mature platform should be relatively low. Earlier in the life of the Sia network, risk may be higher, therefore profit requirements may be higher. At 10% profit expectation, the rigs will need to earn $570 per year in profit to be considered a good investment.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p id=&quot;1bcc&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;Our rig takes up about 2 square feet. The shelf that I linked should actually be able to hold about 3 of these rigs, and should be able to stack 3 or more of these shelves together. If you account for leaving space for airflow and aisles, you end up with about 1 square foot per rig, meaning a 2,000 square foot datacenter can hold 200,000 TB. The cost of rent is going to be negligible compared to other expenses, and is therefore excluded. Electricity aside, utilities should be approximately negligible as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;62df&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;If we assume a PSU efficiency of 93% (this is easily attained at datacenters) and a PUE of 1.4 (generally attainable for this type of setup), you get about 400w per rig. Mining farms often have electricity costs at low as 4 cents, but Sia datacenters are restricted by the fact that they need to have access to good network connections, so we will budget 10 cents per kilowatt hour for electricity. At 500 watts per rig, this comes out to $450 per year in electricity expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5cfb&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;On Sia, bandwidth is priced separately, renters pay for upload bandwidth and download bandwidth independently from storage, which means that we can exclude all ISP costs from this equation. Those expenses are covered as renters utilize the bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b19c&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;Typical datacenters often have multiple redundant power agreements, backup power setups, batteries, etc, so that they can maintain 99.99% uptime. They will also have technical staff at the datacenter 24/7 to react quickly to any failures or outages. None of these things are required when your uptime target is 95%, and therefore this is a huge set of costs we can ignore when designing Sia datacenters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;51c9&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;Sia datacenters will however need at least a bit of maintenance. For a 32 HDD system, you expect about 5 drives to fail per year. This takes time to repair and you will need on-site staff (just not 24/7). To account for these costs, we will budget $50 per year per rig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f168&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;All told, we are at about $1850 per year in expected revenue. This combines the depreciation costs, the electricity costs, the utility costs, and the profit requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;5be0&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj ik hl il hn im hp in hr io ht dl&quot;&gt;A mature datacenter should be able to maintain a utilization of 90% or more by purchasing equipment on an as-needed basis. Assuming that a datacenter does achieve 90% utilization, a 192 TB storage rig is going to need to earn all of its revenue on only 172 TB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;011f&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;Something that is unique to the Sia network is collateral lockup. When hosting someone’s data, you need to lock up collateral to retain that data. When storing 172 TB of data, a host should expect to have about 6 months worth of revenue locked up. At a 10% profit expectation, that comes down to losing about 1 month worth of revenue to capital expenses per year on actively used storage. So really, we should only be counting 11 months of revenue, as that 12th month is going to pay for our collateral lockup expenses. We compute the collateral expenses as a number of months lost because it can be computed independently of other values this way and simplifies the math.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a895&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;The final expense is the siafund fee. All storage on the network incurs a roughly 10% fee, which means the renter is going to be paying more than the host is earning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;bcac&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj ik hl il hn im hp in hr io ht dl&quot;&gt;With a total revenue requirement of about $1750, an effective utilization of about 172 TB, and an effective earnings period of 11 months, we compute that the host needs to be earning about 90 cents per TB per month in revenue for an investment to make sense. Accounting for siafund fees, the renter needs to pay about $1.00 per TB per month. And then accounting for 1.5x redundancy, the final cost of redundant storage is about &lt;strong class=&quot;hi ip&quot;&gt;$1.50 per TB per month&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;34f3&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;This is possible because the Sia network is designed so that datacenters can take shortcuts while building. The traditional model for the cloud assumes that datacenters need to be ultra high reliability, and often also assumes certain performance requirements on the internal network and servers of the datacenter. Sia is much more relaxed, everything needs to happen on the order of milliseconds as opposed to microseconds, and is perfectly comfortable with datacenters and storage rigs that have over a day of downtime per month on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1bd6&quot; class=&quot;hg hh dt at hi b hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht dl&quot;&gt;More to the point, as a whole the Sia network has been carefully designed to be optimal as a decentralized system. Many of the fundamental design choices for Sia had to be different to achieve decentralization, and we have been able to leverage the strengths and weaknesses of these requirements to create something entirely new, and ultimately far superior to the traditional cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 19:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>beedrillzzzzz</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Cloud Storage for $2 / TB / Mo</og:title>
<og:description>Explore the model that shows why Sia storage will stay below $2/TB/Mo for the long term.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.sia.tech/cloud-storage-for-2-tb-mo-8a34043e93bb</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/max/1200/1*RwOb3-L7repKtbZAKYzLYw.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.sia.tech/cloud-storage-for-2-tb-mo-8a34043e93bb?gi=c11717bfe435</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The EARN IT act is an attack on end-to-end encryption</title>
<link>https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2020/03/06/earn-it-is-an-attack-on-encryption/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2020/03/06/earn-it-is-an-attack-on-encryption/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday a bipartisan group of U.S. Senators introduced a new bill called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/5/21162983/congress-senate-earn-it-act-lindsey-graham-richard-blumenthal-section-230-encryption-bill-proposed&quot;&gt;EARN IT&lt;/a&gt; act. On its face, the bill seems like a bit of inside baseball having to do with legal liability for information service providers. In reality, it represents a sophisticated and direct governmental attack on the right of Americans to communicate privately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t stress how dangerous this bill is, though others have &lt;a href=&quot;http://cyberlaw.stanford.edu/blog/2020/03/earn-it-act-here-surprise-it%E2%80%99s-still-bad-news&quot;&gt;tried&lt;/a&gt;. In this post I’m going to try to do my best to explain why it scares me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;“Going Dark”, and the background behind EARN IT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, the U.S. Department of Justice and the FBI have been pursuing an aggressive campaign to eliminate end-to-end encryption services. This is a category that includes text messaging systems like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/privacy/features/&quot;&gt;Apple’s iMessage&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whatsapp.com/&quot;&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://telegram.org/&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;. Those services protect your data by encrypting it, and ensuring that the keys are only available to you and the person you’re communicating with. That means your provider, the person who hacks your provider, and (inadvertently) the FBI, are all left in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fbi.gov/services/operational-technology/going-dark&quot;&gt;anti-encryption campaign&lt;/a&gt; has not been very successful. There are basically two reasons for this. First, people &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; communicating privately. If there’s anything we’ve learned over the past few years, it’s that the world is &lt;em&gt;not a safe place&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;for your private information&lt;/em&gt;. You don’t have to be worried about the NSA spying on you to be worried that some hacker will steal your messages or email. In fact, this kind of hack occurs so routinely that there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/&quot;&gt;popular website&lt;/a&gt; you can use to check if your accounts have been compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason that the government has failed to win hearts and minds is that providers like Facebook and Google and Microsoft also care very much about encryption. While some firms (*cough* Facebook and Google) do like to collect your data, even those companies are starting to realize that they hold way too much of it. This presents a  risk for them, and increasingly it’s producing a backlash from their own customers. Companies like Facebook are realizing that if they can encrypt some of that data — such that they no longer have access to it — then they can make their customers happier and safer at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governments have tried to navigate this impasse by asking for “exceptional access” systems. These are basically “backdoors” in cyrptographic systems that would allow providers to occasionally access user data with a warrant, but only when a specific criminal act has occurred. This is an exceptionally hard problem to get right, and many experts have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schneier.com/academic/paperfiles/paper-keys-under-doormats-CSAIL.pdf&quot;&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; about why this is. But as hard as that problem is, it’s nothing compared to what EARN IT is asking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is EARN IT, and how is it an attack on encryption?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the Department of Justice has largely failed in its mission to convince the public that tech firms should stop using end-to-end encryption, it’s decided to try a different tack. Instead of demanding that tech firms provide access to messages &lt;em&gt;only in serious criminal circumstances and with a warrant,&lt;/em&gt; the DoJ and backers in Congress have decided to leverage concern around the distribution of child pornography, also known as child sexual abuse material, or CSAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be a bit more blunt about this than I usually would be, but only because I think the following statement is accurate. The real goal here is to make it financially impossible for providers to deploy encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let me be clear: the existence of CSAM is despicable, and represents a real problem for many providers. To address it, many file sharing and messaging services voluntarily perform scanning for these types of media. This involves checking images and videos against a database of known “photo hashes” and sending a report to an organization called NCMEC when one is found. NCMEC then passes these reports on to local authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;End-to-end encryption systems make CSAM scanning more challenging: this is because photo scanning systems are essentially a form of mass surveillance — one that’s deployed for a good cause — and end-to-end encryption is explicitly designed to prevent mass surveillance. So photo scanning while also allowing encryption is a fundamentally hard problem, one that providers &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2019/12/08/on-client-side-media-scanning/&quot;&gt;don’t yet know how to solve&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this brings us to EARN IT. The new bill, out of Lindsey Graham’s Judiciary committee, is designed to force providers to either solve the encryption-while-scanning problem, or stop using encryption entirely. And given that we don’t yet know how to solve the problem — and the techniques to do it are basically at the &lt;em&gt;research&lt;/em&gt; stage of R&amp;amp;D —  it’s likely that “stop using encryption” is really the preferred goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EARN IT works by revoking a type of liability called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/cda230&quot;&gt;Section 230&lt;/a&gt; that makes it possible for providers to operate on the Internet, by preventing the provider for being held responsible for what their customers do on a platform like Facebook. The new bill would make it financially impossible for providers like WhatsApp and Apple to operate services unless they conduct “best practices” for scanning their systems for CSAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there are no “best practices” in existence, and the techniques for doing this while preserving privacy are completely unknown, the bill creates a government-appointed committee that will tell technology providers what technology they have to use. The specific nature of the committee is byzantine and described within the bill itself. Needless to say, the makeup of the committee, which can include as few as zero data security experts, ensures that end-to-end encryption will almost certainly not be considered a best practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in short: this bill is a backdoor way to allow the government to ban encryption on commercial services. And even more beautifully: it doesn’t come out and actually &lt;em&gt;ban&lt;/em&gt; the use of encryption, it just makes encryption commercially infeasible for major providers to deploy, ensuring that they’ll go bankrupt if they try to disobey this committee’s recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the kind of bill you’d come up with if you knew the thing you wanted to do was unconstitutional and highly unpopular, and you basically didn’t care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;So why is EARN IT a terrible idea?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, we’re shockingly bad at keeping computer systems secure. This has expensive, trillion dollar costs to our economy, More than that, our failure to manage the security of data has intangible costs for our ability to function as a working society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a handful of promising technologies that could solve this problem. End-to-end encryption happens to be one of those. It is, in fact, &lt;em&gt;the single most promising&lt;/em&gt; technology that we have to prevent hacking, loss of data, and all of the harm that can &lt;a href=&quot;https://money.cnn.com/2015/07/02/technology/revenge-porn-hacker-charlie-evens/index.html&quot;&gt;befall vulnerable people because of it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now the technology for securing our infrastructure isn’t mature enough that we can appoint a government-appointed committee to dictate what sorts of tech it’s “ok” for  firms to provide. Maybe some day we’ll be there, but we’re years from the point where we can protect your data and also have Washington DC deciding what technology we can use to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that yes, some technologies, like CSAM scanning, will have to be re-imagined and in some cases their effectiveness will be reduced. But tech firms have been aggressive about developing this technology on their own (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/using-ai-help-organizations-detect-and-report-child-sexual-abuse-material-online/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for some of the advanced work Google has been doing using Machine Learning), and they will continue to do so. The tech industry has many problems, in many areas. But it doesn’t need Senators to tell it how to do this specific job, because people in California have kids too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you support the goals of EARN IT, remember: if the U.S. Senate &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; decide to tell Silicon Valley how to do their job — at the point of a liability gun — you can bet the industry will revert to doing the &lt;em&gt;minimum possible.&lt;/em&gt; Why would the tech firms continue to invest in developing more sophisticated and expensive technology in this area, knowing that they could be mandated to deploy any new technology they invent, regardless of the cost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that will be the real outcome of this bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;On cynicism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years there has been a vigorous debate about the value of end-to-end encryption, and the demand for law enforcement to have access to more user data. I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schneier.com/academic/paperfiles/paper-keys-under-doormats-CSAIL.pdf&quot;&gt;participated in this debate,&lt;/a&gt; and while I’ve disagreed with many on the other side of it, I’ve always fundamentally &lt;em&gt;respected&lt;/em&gt; their position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EARN IT turns all of this on its head. It’s extremely difficult to believe that this bill stems from an honest consideration of the rights of child victims, and that this legislation is anything other than a direct attack on the use of end-to-end encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope is that the Internet community and civil society will treat this proposal with the seriousness it deserves, and that we’ll see Senators rally behind a bill that actually protects children from abuse, rather than using those issues as a cynical attempt to bring about a “backdoor ban” on encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 17:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jmsflknr</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>EARN IT is a direct attack on end-to-end encryption</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2020/03/06/earn-it-is-an-attack-on-encryption/</og:url>
<og:description>Yesterday a bipartisan group of U.S. Senators introduced a new bill called the EARN IT act. On its face, the bill seems like a bit of inside baseball having to do with legal liability for informati…</og:description>
<og:image>https://matthewdgreen.files.wordpress.com/2020/03/static.politico.com_.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2020/03/06/earn-it-is-an-attack-on-encryption/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Not being an asshole will make you more money</title>
<link>https://www.atlassquats.com/post/not-being-an-asshole-will-make-you-more-money</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.atlassquats.com/post/not-being-an-asshole-will-make-you-more-money</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;All too often in the course of building my business, I bump into the existence of countless assholes. From dealing with aggressive and manipulative salesmen to investors offering term sheets a monkey wouldn't be dumb enough to sign. It frankly sucks. Sucks hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;I really don't understand why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;So many people are straight assholes in business. Especially the more you climb the ladder. As my bootstrapped business reached $3M ARR, a wave of no-name investors approached us. Some of the term sheets more than insulted me. They sought to take control of the company without any payout for the co-founders or employees. They just wanted to capitalize a company they'd now own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;I don't understand why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;Now, I'll speak negatively of them whenever I'm asked. Hell, I'll shit talk them just in case someone runs into them. How do they ever plan to build a long term business if only idiots would accept their deal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;Let's make it simple. If you try to make money from someone's detriment, you're only hurting yourself. It's a short term play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;Smart successful people do not want to work with people they cannot trust. It's not worth it. The world's too big. You'll only ever whittle away your reputation until you're surrounded by mirrors of yourself. It's not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;When you form a partnership with someone, you should sincerely believe the other person is benefiting. It should be fair. You both should make money. You should both want to continue the partnership. Relationships and reputations last much longer than your shitty new sales tool or your underwater fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;I am not a nice person. I do not pretend to be. When I form deals, everyone makes money. Or at least, my attempts were sincere and I always share in the downside. Not everyone feels this way. Most certainly don't act it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;In business, there is a strong incentive to push risk away from yourself and onto others while retaining as much of the upside as possible. Different people have different lines and perspectives on fairness. Some people view it as a simple game. They seek to selfishly maximize their outcome with as little risk as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;The problem in business is that there is always risk. Most businesses operating now did not exist 150 years ago. The ones now probably won't make it another 50. Risk is everywhere. You can't avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;You can be smarter. You can work harder. You can lower that risk considerably through sheer will. But it stops at a point. At some point, the temptation to pass risk onto others creeps in. Enter Finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;Almost every single company more than 6 months old enters into financial agreements with other companies. Whether it's an investment or it's simple terms on purchasing inputs, companies engage in financial agreements all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;A financial agreement can generally be viewed as an investment of sorts. For example, let's say your company buys t-shirts, puts a logo on it and sells it through a website. If the company you buy t-shirts from offers 30-day net terms, you may able to grow your business faster with less money tied up in inventory and the t-shirt manufacturer gets to sell more t-shirts too. If you go bankrupt, both you and the t-shirt manufacturer suffer somewhat proportionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;All good business deals share this trait. They expose both parties to upside and downside somewhat fairly given expected and possible outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;An evil business deal does the opposite. It seeks to offload risk while retaining reward. Sometimes a particularly evil person will come along and pretend to present an opportunity when in reality, they're looking to steal part of the investment. These are the worst people. Stay away from them at all costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;In general, I'd ask you to talk with yourself honestly and see what kind of deals you're making. Do they generally benefit both parties?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;You should. You should work nonstop to ensure it does. Once you build a reputation for making your partners more money, success will come easier and easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;Ever wonder why some people raise a $5M seed with an idea scribbled on a napkin? Generally, these people have a reputation for positive returns for all involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;XzvDs _208Ie tFDi5 blog-post-text-font blog-post-text-color _2QAo- _25MYV _6RI6N tFDi5&quot;&gt;What's your reputation?&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 16:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dumbfoundded</dc:creator>
<og:title>Not being an asshole will make you more money</og:title>
<og:description>All too often in the course of building my business, I bump into the existence of countless assholes. From dealing with aggressive and manipulative salesmen to investors offering term sheets a monkey wouldn't be dumb enough to sign. It frankly sucks. Sucks hard. I really don't understand why. So many people are straigh</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.atlassquats.com/post/not-being-an-asshole-will-make-you-more-money</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.atlassquats.com/post/not-being-an-asshole-will-make-you-more-money</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 months in and $1k MRR: my biggest mistakes so far</title>
<link>https://lunchbag.ca/lunch-money-mistakes/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lunchbag.ca/lunch-money-mistakes/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Written on &lt;time datetime=&quot;2020-02-17 16:00:00 +0000 UTC&quot;&gt;February 17, 2020&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick introduction: 👋 Hi, I’m Jen! I’m the founder, chief budgeter, engineer &amp;amp; designer behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://lunchmoney.app&quot;&gt;Lunch Money&lt;/a&gt;, a personal finance and budgeting web app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been 6 months since the official launch of Lunch Money and I’ve been sharing milestones, both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiehackers.com/product/lunch-money/mentioned-in-techcrunch-and-macrumors--LzBQz1KY0MspKE8mloW&quot;&gt;big&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiehackers.com/product/lunch-money/shipped-a-boatload-of-new-features-improvements--LtvscbLRqs2xCBWNLIr&quot;&gt;small&lt;/a&gt;. But that’s hardly the full picture. While I like the idea of sharing highlights regularly to keep morale up, I thought it would be a good time to reflect and start a periodic series on the biggest mistakes I’ve made (so far).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20811287&quot;&gt;launched via Show HN&lt;/a&gt; on Hacker News in late August 2019. Readers upheld Lunch Money’s standing on the front page for nearly 24 hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About an hour into the launch, I started to get notifications and emails that users couldn’t connect their accounts via Plaid, our third-party banking importer. In a state of panic, I spammed their support channel and the two friends I know who worked there, crying for help. That is until I realized that it was my own dumb fault because I accidentally left my Plaid environment set to development which only supported 100 connected accounts. My free test accounts which I had been diligently rationing up until this point had been depleted and Plaid was rightfully denying any new connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tip&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson learned: Have tests in place to check critical environment variables are properly set before deploying to production&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lunchbag.ca/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202020-02-18%20at%208.23.37%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A simple test could have saved me a ton of headache&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I ran into issues with a third-party email service provider, Sendgrid. I was using Sendgrid to send confirmation emails to new users as they signed up for Lunch Money. The issue was twofold which I discovered while prematurely celebrating the first fix. I had hit my 100 emails per day limit due to being on the free plan, so I quickly upgraded to a paid plan only to find out that Sendgrid was also rate-limiting me! Thankfully, this was quickly resolved through their responsive support chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tip&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lessons learned: Ensure your current plans with third-party services you depend on are sufficient, and monitor usage on launch day to catch issues before they arise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: Lunch Money’s launch was by-and-large unplanned and accidental. If you want to read the “full story” of the launch, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiehackers.com/product/lunch-money/got-on-front-page-of-hacker-news-today--LnVqxbaYPHu7vsPBx39&quot;&gt;check out the Indie Hackers post&lt;/a&gt; I had written at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started Lunch Money as a web app since that is the platform I’m most comfortable with and can iterate quickest on. I like the idea of having more screen real estate for a proper user interface and I also have a lot more experience (and fun!) designing and coding for web apps over mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, at the back of my mind I always felt that I would need to have a mobile app. Who would use a new budgeting app if it was not mobile-first? Who even owns a laptop or desktop computer anymore?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a fully-functioning web app that was mobile responsive, but I had also fully convinced myself that no one would take my app seriously because it wasn’t available natively on iOS or Android. Though I wasn’t going to let this be a barrier to launching, I ended up pricing my product low enough as compensation for the fact. I was also a bit overzealous in my copy. I had a line that promised a mobile app was coming soon and I even called it the “pre-mobile launch”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lunchbag.ca/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202020-02-18%20at%208.26.10%20PM-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Way too much attention on the lack of a mobile app 🤦‍♀️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After launching, I realized through user feedback that a mobile app was not the dealbreaker I hyped it up to be. Of course, there were a few users who made it clear they would only subscribe once a mobile version was available, but there were way more people who were just excited about the potential of Lunch Money itself. It became obvious that I should focus on continuing to develop the core product rather than halting progress in favour of spawning a half-baked version on a new platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tip&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson learned: Don't assume what is and isn't important to your users. Focus on an MVP and wait for feedback.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back now, it was the right decision to hold off on a mobile app. Keeping parity with both web and mobile while iterating regularly on the product would have been nearly impossible. The web version changed so quickly with many features having been completely re-written in the last 6 months. That would have taken more than twice the time if I also had to consider the mobile app whose update cycles are at the mercy of Apple and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lunchbag.ca/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202020-02-18%20at%2011.26.11%20PM-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Embracing the fact that we’re a web app!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that Lunch Money will never have a mobile app. I’m still working on rounding out core features and as the product approaches stability, I’ll spend time thinking seriously about a mobile app. Whether that involves hiring a contractor, outsourcing the development or encouraging users to build their own via our developer API is still up in the air!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, I priced Lunch Money initially to overcompensate for the lack of a mobile app. At launch, the product was offered at $3/month or $29/year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was getting feedback over the next few weeks that my pricing was too low! If your users are telling you your price is too low, it’s even lower than you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of 4 weeks, I experimented with pricing. I raised my price every time I came out with a new major feature, which, at that time, was happening on a weekly basis. These are core features to the product today, such as CSV import (+$2/month) and the Query Tool (+$1/month). My pricing basically went from $3/month to $5/month to $6/month and finally $8/month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At $8/month, there was a noticeable drop in signups. But that by itself was not the issue as it was compounded by my next mistake..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At launch time, we were offering a 45-day free trial. The idea was to allow users the experience of a whole monthly budgeting cycle to assess Lunch Money. Also, YNAB, who I perceived to be my biggest competitor, was offering a 38-day free trial so I thought that with a longer trial and lower price, Lunch Money would be more appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I could have been right about that, it wasn’t worth the painfully long sales cycle that came with offering a 45-day free trial PLUS the option for a whopping two week trial extension. Major facepalm. At the longest, users were not going to convert until 2 months after initially signing up. This made assessing product-market fit an unnecessarily long process. Also, very few users opted to extend the trial after 45 days which was unsurprising– if a user is still on the fence at day 45, they probably won’t be subscribing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lunchbag.ca/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202020-02-18%20at%208.39.31%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Fully prepared to give away a 2 week trial extension on top of a 45 day free trial… 🤦‍♀️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, at the advice of a friend much smarter than me, I decided to shorten the free trial length to 14 days. Even though I now ran the risk of users not having enough time to assess the product, I felt the shorter trial might instill some urgency in users, and I was still offering the option for a 1 week trial extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tip&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson learned: Be aware of the difficulties in offering too long of a free trial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth mentioning now that this realization and the realization that I was charging too little happened in parallel so I actually ended up increasing the pricing to $8/month AND decreasing the free trial length to 14 days on the same day. Yes, I changed two very important variables at the same time. My sign ups dropped drastically and I had no way of knowing if it was because I was charging too high or my trial length was too short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/fQMmw06EWWRP9fvhWv/giphy.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My two inner selves when I realized what I’d done&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tip&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson learned: If you are testing major changes, do not change two variables at the same time. (Duh!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The recovery:&lt;/strong&gt; I ended up sticking with the shorter trial length and offering a discount off the $8/month pricing which was determined to be too high. I’d like to eventually get Lunch Money to a point where it is worth $8/month and until then, I’m offering lifetime percentage discounts. I started off with a 30% discount for Cyber Week which had great reception. Afterwards, I lowered the discount to 20% off which amounts to $6.40/month. Based on the rate of new signups and a user feedback survey I sent out a few weeks ago, I’m confident the current trial length and monthly price are both reasonable for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a month and a half, we didn’t have an About page. I wasn’t sure how Lunch Money would be perceived if people found out there was a singular engineer behind a personal finance app. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lunchbag.ca/lunch-money&quot;&gt;I wrote an article on my personal blog&lt;/a&gt; that would link Lunch Money to me, but it would only be discoverable by those eager enough to read the origin story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some initial feedback, I decided to implement an &lt;a href=&quot;https://lunchmoney.app/about&quot;&gt;About page&lt;/a&gt; and start sending a welcome email to new users introducing myself as the one-woman team behind the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center readability=&quot;0.72857142857143&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;3.6428571428571&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Let’s not be strangers anymore 👋 We finally have an About page! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/koZiMSAM3o&quot;&gt;https://t.co/koZiMSAM3o&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Lunch Money (@LunchbagLabs) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LunchbagLabs/status/1180518703487733766?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 5, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now regularly get emails back from users letting me know that they find my story inspiring, or that they love the fact that an indie developer is behind the product! 🥰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center readability=&quot;2.2987616099071&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;7.3560371517028&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;My mind is kind of blown that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lunchbag?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@lunchbag&lt;/a&gt; made Lunch Money on her own &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; she’s the support staff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The unbelievable thing is that Lunch Money is truly better than Mint and YNAB. I’ve never been able to keep using budgeting software because they’re so bad. Not anymore!&lt;/p&gt;
— Eric Windmill (@ericwindmill) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ericwindmill/status/1226992389627072512?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tip&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson learned: People care about the narrative behind your product, so don't be afraid to tell your story!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I sent out a user survey recently and 20% of responses cited me as an indie developer as a reason why they love Lunch Money. All of this was incredibly heartwarming and I learned to embrace my story more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lunchbag.ca/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202020-02-18%20at%2011.03.35%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;So much ❤️ from our users!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to report that despite all these bumps in the road (and many more that didn’t make the cut for this post!), &lt;a href=&quot;https://lunchmoney.app&quot;&gt;Lunch Money&lt;/a&gt; is still alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I never thought that any one of these mistakes would be the downfall of Lunch Money but I’m sure in the moment, each one felt like the dumbest thing I could have possibly done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/9jObH9PkVPTyM/giphy-downsized.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My overdramatic self reacting to my mistakes as they happen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole journey is a learning process and I’m grateful to be able to share mine transparently. It’s important to not only celebrate the highs and stay humble, but also face the lows and forgive yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure there are many more mistakes to be made on the horizon and I look forward to writing and laughing about them in another 6 months!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 15:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jnfr</dc:creator>
<og:title>The biggest mistakes I've made with Lunch Money (so far)</og:title>
<og:description>It's been 6 months since the official launch of Lunch Money and I've been sharing milestones, both big and small. But that's hardly the full picture.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://lunchbag.ca/lunch-money-mistakes/</og:url>
<og:image>https://lunchbag.ca/uploads/ogimage-blog-biggest-mistake-2.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lunchbag.ca/lunch-money-mistakes/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>DuckDuckGo is good enough for regular use</title>
<link>https://www.bitlog.com/2020/03/06/duckduckgo-is-good-enough-for-regular-use/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bitlog.com/2020/03/06/duckduckgo-is-good-enough-for-regular-use/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Google recently launched a desktop redesign. The favicon and URL breadcrumbs were turned into a header for organic search results. Ads had the same design, but were identified using the string “Ad” instead of the favicon. This design wasn’t new. Google’s mobile web search has served this design &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/22/18635774/google-mobile-search-redesign-favicons-website-names&quot;&gt;since May 2019&lt;/a&gt;. But users and regulators complained that the desktop version blurred the distinction between ads and organic results. Google reverted the change a few weeks later, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/searchliaison/status/1220768238490939394&quot;&gt;citing the backlash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I experienced &lt;a href=&quot;https://uxdesign.cc/design-psychology-change-aversion-cbc10066c41f&quot;&gt;change aversion&lt;/a&gt; when I tried the redesign. Change aversion is a simple idea: users react negatively to new experiences, but they stop caring as new experiences become normal. Anyways, looking at the Google redesign gave me change aversion. I knew that I wouldn’t care about it within a few days. But I decided to put it to good use: I would try &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;. If it was time for Google to experiment, then it was time for me to experiment. I had wanted to try it for a while. This finally gave me the activation energy to switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DuckDuckGo’s premise is simple. They do not collect or share personal information. They log searches, but they promise that these logs are not linked to personally identifiable information. Their search engine results seemingly come from Bing, but they claim to have their own crawler and hundreds of other sources on top of that. They do customize the results a little: geo-searches like &lt;span&gt;bars near my location&lt;/span&gt; give me results from my home city of New York. But search results aren’t personalized. I’ve always wondered how good the results would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, here are the guidelines that I set for my experiment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcworld.com/article/249158/how_to_change_your_browsers_default_search_engine.html&quot;&gt;switch all of my browser’s default search engines&lt;/a&gt; to DuckDuckGo across all of my devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would use DuckDuckGo for at least a month. This would give me enough time to learn some of its strengths and weaknesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would not use any DuckDuckGo poweruser features unless I could guess that they existed. I wanted to understand the out-of-the-box experience on the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I could use the &lt;span&gt;!g&lt;/span&gt; operator to search Google if DuckDuckGo failed. Some will point out that this violates the previous rule. But as soon as a discussion changes to DuckDuckGo usage, people can’t WAIT to talk about how often they use &lt;span&gt;!g&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span&gt;g!&lt;/span&gt;. Do you need an example? I discussed it in this paragraph and tried to blame it on other people. I’m serious: people can’t talk about DuckDuckGo without talking about &lt;span&gt;!g&lt;/span&gt;. It’s the law. So I know about it and I will use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven’t tried a new search engine since I tried Bing in 2009. It was time to find out how good DuckDuckGo is in 2020. What was the biggest difference that I found?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google is the king of low-intent searches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has a structured understanding of many domains. This is a difficult moat for other search engines to cross. This is evident when comparing low-intent searches. These are searches with an ambiguous purpose. The subject is broad and it’s not clear what the user wanted. The user might not even “want” anything except to kill five minutes before a meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s try a low-intent search. Type &lt;span&gt;harry potter&lt;/span&gt; into Google. In response, Google throws everything at the wall to see what sticks. In addition to the organic links, Google serves me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A panel on the right with a ton of metadata. This includes oddly-specific structured data like “&lt;strong&gt;Sport&lt;/strong&gt;: Quidditch”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list of five of the seven books in the series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fantasy books from five related searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A news panel containing three articles about Harry Potter actors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;span&gt;harry potter&lt;/span&gt; Google Maps search, centered on the New York area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A “People also ask” panel with four questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A link to three Harry Potter-related YouTube videos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three recent tweets from @HarryPotterFilm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A panel with 7 “Fantasy book series” results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A panel with 7 “Kids book series” results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 other search strings related to &lt;span&gt;harry potter&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This makes sense: what did I want when I searched for &lt;span&gt;harry potter&lt;/span&gt;? Google can’t know. So Google returns information from many domains to attempt to satisfy the query. Google returns so much information that something will be close enough. This is a huge competitive advantage. They can serve good results for bad searches by covering as many domains as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a departure from how search used to work. When I was in grade school, I was taught how to craft search queries. Someone herded us into a library and explained how to pick effective keywords, quote text, use operators like AND or OR, etc. These days are dead. None of this matters on Google. If you want to know showtimes for “Harry Potter and the Cursed Child,” a search for &lt;span&gt;harry potter&lt;/span&gt; will get you close enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison, DuckDuckGo’s results for &lt;span&gt;harry potter&lt;/span&gt; are relaxing. It serves a small knowledge panel to the right and three recent news articles at the top, some organic links, and nothing else. It’s much easier to scan this page. It’s a more relaxed vibe. But if I actually wanted something, it likely wouldn’t be on this page. You can make the argument that I got what I deserved: I didn’t clearly communicate what I wanted, and therefore I didn’t get it. But Google has trained everyone that broad queries are effective. It feels like magic. It’s not. It’s the result of years of developing a structured understanding of the world and crafting ways to surface the structure. And it’s something that potential competitors will need to come to terms with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t personally miss most of Google’s result panels. Especially the panels that highlight information snippets. It’s easy to find these. Searching &lt;span&gt;microsoft word justify text&lt;/span&gt; provides me a snippet from Microsoft’s Office’s support page explaining what to click or type to justify text. I’ve learned not to trust information in these panels without reading the source they came from. Google seems to cite this information uncritically. I’ve found enough oversimplified knowledge panel answers that I’ve stopped reading most of them. Recently, I was chatting with a Googler who works on these. I asked them if I was wrong to feel this way. And they replied, “I trust them, but I’ve read enough bug reports and user feedback that I don’t blame you.” So my position is wrong, but not very wrong. I’ll take that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of Google’s panels are great. I miss them. I haven’t found anything better than Google’s stock panel for quickly looking at after-hours stock movements. Searching Google for &lt;span&gt;goog stock&lt;/span&gt; will show you this panel. I miss you buddy. I hope you’re doing well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it stresses me out when Google returns many panels in a search. I’m sure that each is a marginal gain for Google. But I don’t like how Google feels as a result. I’m continually glad to see just 10 links on DuckDuckGo, even if this means that I’m not getting what I wanted. This has been training me to craft more specific searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DuckDuckGo is good enough&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s move away from Google’s competitive advantages. How does DuckDuckGo perform for most of my search traffic? DuckDuckGo does a good job. I haven’t found a reason to switch back to Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I combed through my browser’s history of DuckDuckGo searches. I compared it to my Google search history. When I fell back to Google, I often didn’t find what I wanted on Google either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my searches relate to my job, which means that most of my searches are technical queries. DuckDuckGo serves good results for my searches. I’ll admit that I’m a paranoid searcher: I reformat error strings, remove identifiers that are unique to my code, and remove quotes before searching. I’m not sure how well DuckDuckGo would handle copy/pasted error strings with lots of quotes and unique identifiers. This means that I don’t know if DuckDuckGo handles all technical searches well. But it does a good job for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many domains where Google outperforms DuckDuckGo. Product search and local search are some examples. I recently made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundproofliving.com/make-diy-soundproof-window-plug/&quot;&gt;window plug&lt;/a&gt;. It was much easier to find which big-box hardware stores had the materials I need with Google. I also recently bought a pair of ANC headphones. I got much better comparison information starting at Google. Google also shines with sparse results like rare programming error messages. If you’re a programmer, you know what I’m talking about: imagine a Google search page with three results. One is a page in Chinese that has the English error string, one is a forum post that gives you the first hint that you need to solve the problem, and one is the error string in the original source code in Github. DuckDuckGo often returns nothing for these kinds of searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though Google is better for some specific domains, I am confident that DuckDuckGo can find what I need. When it doesn’t, Google often doesn’t help either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample of times when both Google and DuckDuckGo failed me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I tried to write a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/reference/other&quot;&gt;protobuf compiler plugin&lt;/a&gt; using the official PHP protocol buffer bindings. I now believe that writing a protobuf compiler plugin in PHP is impossible due to several arbitrary facts, but I needed to piece this information together myself. My searches sprawled over Google and DuckDuckGo across several days before I concluded that it could not be done and that I could not find a workaround. This isn’t DuckDuckGo or Google’s fault. Some things just don’t have answers online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I often fell back to Google for gif searches. It turns out that I’m bad at finding gifs. Sometimes I get exactly what I want, like searching for &lt;span&gt;gritty turning around&lt;/span&gt;. But I had a lot of trouble finding a string that gave me &lt;a href=&quot;https://video.twimg.com/tweet_video/EQwQKSWUwAEo846.mp4&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. Eventually I found it by remembering a Twitter user that had posted it and scanning their “Media” posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trying to find a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KVrHgCs6fQc&quot;&gt;very specific CS:GO clip&lt;/a&gt; that I had seen on Reddit years ago. I found it via a combination of Reddit search and skimming the bottom of Reddit threads for video links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is &lt;span&gt;australian licorice&lt;/span&gt;? Is it a marketing gimmick? Stores sell it. It’s tasty. But I can’t find an explanation anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of switching to DuckDuckGo because of the Google redesign, I’ll save you the trouble: DuckDuckGo’s inline ads are formatted similarly to the Google redesign that got reverted. If anything, DuckDuckGo’s ads are harder to spot because DuckDuckGo’s (Ad) icon is on the right, while Google’s was on the left where my eyes naturally skim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It turns out that I care about privacy, but I still use Google Analytics on my blog. I haven’t been thinking about digital privacy for long enough to have a consistent and principled opinion. Sorry about that.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back to the original selling point of DuckDuckGo: they don’t track you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reading my DuckDuckGo searches in my browser history for this post. It’s wonderful that all of these searches remained private. Some of them should remain private for stupid reasons. I don’t want anyone to know that I searched for &lt;span&gt;what is the value of a human life&lt;/span&gt; because it makes me sound like a killer robot. Other searches are much more sensitive. One is the name of a medication I’m on. Others are searches about pains and fears that I have. DuckDuckGo allows me to perform these searches without building a profile of me. I’m sure that advertisers pick up the scent as soon as I click a link. But I appreciate the delay. I didn’t think about the traces I left online when I searched on Google. But now that I know I have the choice, I’m actively comforted by reviewing my DuckDuckGo search history and reading everything that they didn’t track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also noticed that many searches show trends. I knew that this was true in theory. But it’s different when you see it in your own search results. A month ago, many of my searches related to vacation planning. But now they don’t anymore. The coronavirus scrapped my plans. But there are many life events that could have also caused this: health reasons, family problems, etc. These are things that ad networks could piece together as I visit sites. It’s possible to imagine even darker versions of this – imagine the months of searches that relate to a pregnancy with a miscarriage. Many companies could profit from a couple going through that process, if they showed the right ads in the right places at the right time. There is a lot of trend information that you just want to keep to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What happens moving forward?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue using DuckDuckGo. I don’t see a reason to switch back to Google. I’m going to continue to fall back using &lt;span&gt;!g&lt;/span&gt; when I need to. I’m going to try to avoid talking about the fallback (but let’s be honest, I just did it again).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still use lots of Google products. I’m not in the process of porting away from any of them. I still use Chrome in addition to Firefox and mobile Safari. Google Docs still holds a place in my heart. Etsy is hosted on GCP and uses Google Apps. Google Photos is still the best place for me to store and share my photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked the exercise of reading a month of my search history. You should do it, too. It became clear that I broadcast lots of information by having these very personal conversations with search engines. I’d like to understand more about the digital traces I leave online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to turn into a digital hermit. But I would like to become more deliberate about the traces that I leave around the internet. Even as a developer, I’m not sure what will happen if I disable third-party cookies across the internet. But I’d like to start reading more about digital privacy to understand what tradeoffs I am making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: I worked at Google from 2010-2015, but did not work on search.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 14:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>braythwayt</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>DuckDuckGo is good enough for regular use | www.bitlog.com</og:title>
<og:description>I haven't tried a new search engine since I tried Bing in 2009. It was time to find out how good DuckDuckGo is in 2020. What was the biggest difference that I found?</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bitlog.com/2020/03/06/duckduckgo-is-good-enough-for-regular-use/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bitlog.com/2020/03/06/duckduckgo-is-good-enough-for-regular-use/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Caffeine boosts problem-solving ability but not creativity, study indicates</title>
<link>https://news.uark.edu/articles/52447/caffeine-boosts-problem-solving-ability-but-not-creativity-study-indicates</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.uark.edu/articles/52447/caffeine-boosts-problem-solving-ability-but-not-creativity-study-indicates</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;articleHead clearfix&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 05, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;storyImagePanel&quot; class=&quot;col-sm-12 col-md-6 pull-right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://campusdata.uark.edu/resources/images/articles/2020-03-04_12-35-16-PMRS73279_9097_Darya_Zabelina-17-Edit-lpr.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;https://campusdata.uark.edu/resources/images/articles/2020-03-04_12-35-16-PMRS73279_9097_Darya_Zabelina-17-Edit-lpr.jpg?width=800&amp;amp;mode=max&quot; alt=&quot;Darya Zabelina&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nwArticleCaption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-right nwPhotoCaption&quot;&gt;Russell Cothren&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darya Zabelina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAYETTEVILLE, Ark. – Caffeine increases the ability to focus and problem solve, but a new study by a University of Arkansas researcher indicates it doesn’t stimulate creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In Western cultures, caffeine is stereotypically associated with creative occupations and lifestyles, from writers and their coffee to programmers and their energy drinks, and there’s more than a kernel of truth to these stereotypes,” wrote Darya Zabelina, assistant professor of psychology and first author of the study recently published in the journal Consciousness and Cognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the cognitive benefits of caffeine — increased alertness, improved vigilance, enhanced focus and improved motor performance — are well established, she said, the stimulant’s affect on creativity is less known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the paper, Zabelina differentiates “convergent” from “divergent” thinking. The former is defined as seeking a specific solution to a problem, for example, the “correct” answer. The latter is characterized by idea generation where a large set of apt, novel or interesting responses would be suitable. Caffeine was shown to improve convergent thinking in the study, while consuming it had no significant impact on divergent thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the study, 80 volunteers were randomly given either a 200mg caffeine pill, equivalent to one strong cup of coffee, or a placebo. They were then tested on standard measures of convergent and divergent thinking, working memory and mood. In addition to the results on creativity, caffeine did not significantly affect working memory, but test subjects who took it did report feeling less sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The 200mg enhanced problem solving significantly, but had no effect on creative thinking,” said Zabelina. “It also didn’t make it worse, so keep drinking your coffee; it won’t interfere with these abilities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the University of Arkansas: The University of Arkansas provides an internationally competitive education for undergraduate and graduate students in more than 200 academic programs. The university contributes new knowledge, economic development, basic and applied research, and creative activity while also providing service to academic and professional disciplines. The Carnegie Foundation classifies the University of Arkansas among fewer than 3% of colleges and universities in America that have the highest level of research activity. U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report ranks the University of Arkansas among its top American public research universities. Founded in 1871, the University of Arkansas comprises 10 colleges and schools and maintains a low student-to-faculty ratio that promotes personal attention and close mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 13:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rajnathani</dc:creator>
<og:title>Caffeine Boosts Problem-Solving Ability but Not Creativity, Study Indicates</og:title>
<og:url>https://news.uark.edu/articles/52447</og:url>
<og:description>While the drug is known to increase focus, alertness and motor skills, its effect on creative thinking had not been studied previously.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://campusdata.uark.edu/resources/images/articles/2020-03-04_12-35-16-PMRS73279_9097_Darya_Zabelina-17-Edit-lpr.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.uark.edu/articles/52447/caffeine-boosts-problem-solving-ability-but-not-creativity-study-indicates</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Study: Low Carb Diet May Prevent, Reverse Age-Related Effects Within the Brain</title>
<link>https://news.stonybrook.edu/newsroom/study-shows-low-carb-diet-may-prevent-reverse-age-related-effects-within-the-brain/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.stonybrook.edu/newsroom/study-shows-low-carb-diet-may-prevent-reverse-age-related-effects-within-the-brain/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The news in brief:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Brain changes associated with aging become visible much earlier than would be expected, in the late 40’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) This is hypothesized to result from neurons’ loss of energy; if so, researchers may have found a way to prevent or reverse these effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) This can be done with diet, by switching neurons’ fuel from glucose to ketones. Ketones have previously been shown to increase the availability of energy to the heart. However, this is the first evidence that a similar benefit may be achieved for the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Study Shows Low Carb Diet May Prevent, Reverse Age-Related Effects Within the Brain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STONY BROOK, NY, March 4, 2020&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; A study using neuroimaging led by Stony Brook University professor and lead author &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stonybrook.edu/commcms/bme/people/l_parodi.php&quot;&gt;Lilianne R. Mujica-Parodi&lt;/a&gt;, PhD, and published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pnas.org/content/early/2020/03/02/1913042117&quot;&gt;PNAS&lt;/a&gt;, reveals that neurobiological changes associated with aging can be seen at a much younger age than would be expected, in the late 40s. However, the study also suggests that this process may be prevented or reversed based on dietary changes that involve minimizing the consumption of simple carbohydrates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-126488 size-medium&quot; title=&quot;Mujica parodi 2020web&quot; src=&quot;https://news.stonybrook.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mujica-parodi-2020web-300x232.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mujica parodi 2020web&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;232&quot; srcset=&quot;https://news.stonybrook.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mujica-parodi-2020web-300x232.jpg 300w, https://news.stonybrook.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mujica-parodi-2020web-768x594.jpg 768w, https://news.stonybrook.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mujica-parodi-2020web-370x286.jpg 370w, https://news.stonybrook.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mujica-parodi-2020web-270x209.jpg 270w, https://news.stonybrook.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mujica-parodi-2020web-740x572.jpg 740w, https://news.stonybrook.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mujica-parodi-2020web.jpg 900w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;Lilianne R. Mujica-Parodi, Ph.D.
&lt;p&gt;To better understand how diet influences brain aging, the research team focused on the presymptomatic period during which prevention may be most effective. In the article titled “Diet modulates brain network stability, a biomarker for brain aging, in young adults,” they showed, using large-scale life span neuroimaging datasets, that functional communication between brain regions destabilizes with age, typically in the late 40’s, and that destabilization correlates with poorer cognition and accelerates with insulin resistance. Targeted experiments then showed this biomarker for brain aging to be reliably modulated with consumption of different fuel sources: glucose decreases, and ketones increase, the stability of brain networks. This effect was replicated across both changes to total diet as well as after drinking a fuel-specific calorie-matched supplement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What we found with these experiments involves both bad and good news,” said Mujica-Parodi, a Professor in the Department of Biomedical Engineering with joint appointments in the College of Engineering &amp;amp; Applied Sciences and Renaissance School of Medicine at Stony Brook University, and a faculty member in &lt;a href=&quot;https://laufercenter.stonybrook.edu/&quot;&gt;the Laufer Center for Physical and Quantitative Biology&lt;/a&gt;. “The bad news is that we see the first signs of brain aging much earlier than was previously thought. However, the good news is that we may be able to prevent or reverse these effects with diet, mitigating the impact of encroaching hypometabolism by exchanging glucose for ketones as fuel for neurons.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the researchers discovered, using neuroimaging of the brain, is that quite early on there is breakdown of communication between brain regions (“network stability”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We think that, as people get older, their brains start to lose the ability to metabolize glucose efficiently, causing neurons to slowly starve, and brain networks to destabilize,” said Mujica-Parodi. “Thus, we tested whether giving the brain a more efficient fuel source, in the form of ketones, either by following a low-carb diet or drinking ketone supplements, could provide the brain with greater energy. Even in younger individuals, this added energy further stabilized brain networks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conduct their experiments, brain network stability was established as a biomarker for aging by using two large-scale brain neuroimaging (fMRI) datasets totaling nearly 1,000 individuals, ages 18 to 88. Destabilization of brain networks was associated with impaired cognition and was accelerated with Type 2 diabetes, an illness that blocks neurons’ ability to effectively metabolize glucose. To identify the mechanism as being specific to energy availability, the researchers then held age constant and scanned an additional 42 adults under the age of 50 years with fMRI. This allowed them to observe directly the impact of glucose and ketones on each individual’s brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brain’s response to diet was tested in two ways. The first was holistic, comparing brain network stability after participants had spent one week on a standard (unrestricted) vs. low carb (for example: meat or fish with salad, but no sugar, grains, rice, starchy vegetables) diet. In a standard diet, the primary fuel metabolized is glucose, whereas in a low-carb diet, the primary fuel metabolized is ketones. However, there might have been other differences between diets driving the observed effects. Therefore, to isolate glucose vs. ketones as the crucial difference between the diets, an independent set of participants was scanned before and after drinking a small dose of glucose on one day, and ketones on the other, where the two fuels were individually weight-dosed and calorically matched. The results replicated, showing that the differences between the diets could be attributed to the type of fuel they provide to the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional findings from the study included the following: Effects of brain aging emerged at age 47, with most rapid degeneration occurring at age 60. Even in younger adults, under age 50, dietary ketosis (whether achieved after one week of dietary change or 30 minutes after drinking ketones) increased overall brain activity and stabilized functional networks. This is thought to be due to the fact that ketones provide greater energy to cells than glucose, even when the fuels are calorically matched. This benefit has previously been shown for the heart, but the current set of experiments provides the first evidence for equivalent effects in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This effect matters because brain aging, and especially dementia, are associated with “hypometabolism,” in which neurons gradually lose the ability to effectively use glucose as fuel. Therefore, if we can increase the amount of energy available to the brain by using a different fuel, the hope is that we can restore the brain to more youthful functioning. In collaboration with Dr. Eva Ratai at Massachusetts General Hospital, we’re currently addressing this question, by now extending our studies to older populations,” said Mujica-Parodi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Additional research with collaborators at Children’s National, under the direction of Dr. Nathan Smith, focuses on discovering the precise mechanisms by which fuel impacts signaling between neurons. Finally, in collaboration with Dr. Ken Dill and Dr. Steven Skiena, at Stony Brook, we’re working on building a comprehensive computational model that can incorporate our understanding of the biology, from individual neurons to whole brains to cognition, as it develops.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research is currently funded under a new $2.5 million National Science Foundation BRAIN Initiative “Frontiers” grants (numbers (NSFECCS1533257 and NSFNCS-FR 1926781) awarded to Stony Brook, as well as by the W. M. Keck Foundation, which originally funded the team in 2017 with a $1 million seed grant designed to jump-start “pioneering discoveries in science, engineering, and medical research.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborators included Stony Brook faculty from the Laufer Center for Physical and Quantitative Biology, Departments of Biomedical Engineering, Applied Mathematics and Statistics, Physics and Astronomy, and Computer Science; and scientists at the Athinoula A. Martinos Center for Biomedical Imaging (Massachusetts General Hospital and Harvard Medical School), Children’s National, the National Institutes of Health, and Oxford University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rp4wp-related-posts rp4wp-related-post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 13:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rajnathani</dc:creator>
<og:title>Study Shows Low Carb Diet May Prevent, Reverse Age-Related Effects Within the Brain | | SBU News</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://news.stonybrook.edu/newsroom/study-shows-low-carb-diet-may-prevent-reverse-age-related-effects-within-the-brain/</og:url>
<og:image>https://news.stonybrook.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mujica-parodi-2020web.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The news in brief: 1) Brain changes associated with aging become visible much earlier than would be expected, in the late 40's. 2) This is hypothesized to result from neurons' loss of energy; if so, researchers may have found a way to prevent or reverse these effects. 3) This can be done with diet, by switching neurons' fuel from glucose to ketones. Ketones have previously been shown to increase the availability of energy to the heart. However, this is the first evidence that a similar benefit may be achieved for the brain. Study Shows Low Carb Diet May Prevent, Reverse Age-Related Effects Within the Brain STONY BROOK, NY, March 4, 2020 – A study using neuroimaging led by Stony Brook University professor and lead author Lilianne R. Mujica-Parodi, PhD, and published in PNAS, reveals that neurobiological changes associated with aging can be seen at a much younger age than would be expected, in the late 40s. However, the study also suggests that this process may be prevented or reversed</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.stonybrook.edu/newsroom/study-shows-low-carb-diet-may-prevent-reverse-age-related-effects-within-the-brain/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who is Facebook&amp;#039;s mysterious “Lan Tim 2”?</title>
<link>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2020/03/who-is-facebooks-mysterious-lan-tim-2/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2020/03/who-is-facebooks-mysterious-lan-tim-2/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook has an interesting feature. It will let you see which companies have associated your off-Facebook activity with your Facebook account. If you visit:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/off_facebook_activity/&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/off_facebook_activity/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;you'll see what companies are snitching on you to Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/AirBnB?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#AirBnB&lt;/a&gt; shares your activity with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Facebook?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Facebook&lt;/a&gt; ?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delete that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Airbnb?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; app, folks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mine didn't even allow me to change its Facebook connection 😡 isn't that against GDPR, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vestager?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Vestager&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dreynders?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@DReynders&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And delete your off-&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Facebook?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Facebook&lt;/a&gt; activity here:&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/9Ccih8wur3&quot;&gt;https://t.co/9Ccih8wur3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HT &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexstamos?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@AlexStamos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/3nZnK6LAi8&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/3nZnK6LAi8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Alice Stollmeyer (@StollmeyerEU) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/StollmeyerEU/status/1222203127585288192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 28, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off-Facebook activity includes information that businesses and organisations share with us about your interactions with them. Interactions are things such as visiting their website or logging in to their app with Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://getfirefox.com&quot;&gt;Firefox web browser&lt;/a&gt;, all my off-FB activity is kept private from Facebook. I don't use FB to sign into things. I also run an ad-blocker. So I expected my &quot;Off Facebook Activity&quot; to be completely blank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Off-Facebook-Activity.png&quot; alt=&quot;Facebook activity page saying they received data from &amp;quot;Lan Tim 2&amp;quot;.&quot; width=&quot;810&quot; height=&quot;304&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-34270&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are Lan Tim 2? And what did I purchase from them? First up, let's check that I'm as paranoid as I think I am...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Blank-apps-and-websites-page.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Blank apps and websites page.&quot; width=&quot;994&quot; height=&quot;402&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-34271&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup! I've connected &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to my FB account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I'm being a dolt. Perhaps I signed in to a store with Facebook without thinking about it? Perhaps it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a legitimate purchase.... And then I saw this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Take a look at your off-Facebook activity and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ClearHistory?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#ClearHistory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything I've seen to date has been through &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Android?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Android&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Facebook?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Facebook&lt;/a&gt; App tracking. I wrote a report on this last year which can be found here &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/xge3h3cSZP&quot;&gt;https://t.co/xge3h3cSZP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Activity: 👇👇👇 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/ELrVkCauhX&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/ELrVkCauhX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Christopher Weatherhead (@CJFWeatherhead) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CJFWeatherhead/status/1222519352764837888?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 29, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't know Christopher - although we appear to have some mutual friends. It strikes me as a bit odd that two random individuals, who are both pretty privacy conscious, would both have made the same mistake which led to a Facebook associated purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I checked through all my credit card statements and emails. I didn't purchase anything around that time, and I couldn't find any reference to the merchant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download your Facebook data as JSON. So I did that. This is all it had about those mystery transactions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/JSON-code.png&quot; alt=&quot;Scrap of JSON which doesn't say much.&quot; width=&quot;322&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-34272&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It's actually a bit more complicated than that&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off-Facebook activity doesn't just mean stuff that happens online. Facebook also does &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/business/help/1142103235885551?id=565900110447546&quot;&gt;offline conversions&lt;/a&gt; which allows advertisers to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/business/help/341425252616329?id=2469097953376494&quot;&gt;match offline activity with online activity.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we use a process called matching to match the hashed information with Facebook profiles so that you can advertise to your customers on Facebook, Instagram and Audience Network. The more information you can provide, the better the match rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose I go to a restaurant, and I booked using my name and phone number. The restaurant sends that data to Facebook to say &quot;Terence Eden ate at this restaurant on this day.&quot; Facebook can then tell if I saw an advert which led me to make a purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good reason to use a disposable phone number for &lt;em&gt;everything!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached out to a friend who worked at Facebook. Obviously they couldn't tell me too much, but here's what I did find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lan Tim 2 supply custom printed apparel. Print your logo on a t-shirt or mug, that sort of thing. They're a &quot;white label&quot; operation. That is, you buy from &quot;Tom's Terrific T-Shirts&quot; but it's Lan Tim 2 who print and supply the final item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had I bought anything like that? I didn't think so. And then, I remembered...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spreadshirt! I'd made some custom printed t-shirts through them. I contacted a few other people who'd seen Lan Tim 2. They'd also used Spreadshirt! And, like me, their last purchase was inconsistent with the data given to Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assume I gave my phone number to Spreadshirt to provide delivery information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is correct, then it looks to me like Spreadshirt took the phone numbers given to it for one reason - and then used them for another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, perhaps I'm wrong, and some dodgy company has been randomly spamming Facebook with fake data?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It goes to show, Facebook's level of transparency of data isn't good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 13:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edent</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Who is Facebook's mysterious &quot;Lan Tim 2&quot;?</og:title>
<og:url>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2020/03/who-is-facebooks-mysterious-lan-tim-2/</og:url>
<og:description>Facebook has an interesting feature. It will let you see which companies have associated your off-Facebook activity with your Facebook account. If you visit: you’ll see what companies are sni…</og:description>
<og:image>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Off-Facebook-Activity.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2020/03/who-is-facebooks-mysterious-lan-tim-2/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Smart Algorithms beat Hardware Acceleration for Large-Scale Deep Learning</title>
<link>https://arxiv.org/abs/1903.03129</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arxiv.org/abs/1903.03129</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;10.702702702703&quot;&gt;(Submitted on 7 Mar 2019 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1903.03129v1&quot;&gt;v1&lt;/a&gt;), last revised 1 Mar 2020 (this version, v2))&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;descriptor&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt; Deep Learning (DL) algorithms are the central focus of modern machine learning systems. As data volumes keep growing, it has become customary to train large neural networks with hundreds of millions of parameters to maintain enough capacity to memorize these volumes and obtain state-of-the-art accuracy. To get around the costly computations associated with large models and data, the community is increasingly investing in specialized hardware for model training. However, specialized hardware is expensive and hard to generalize to a multitude of tasks. The progress on the algorithmic front has failed to demonstrate a direct advantage over powerful hardware such as NVIDIA-V100 GPUs. This paper provides an exception. We propose SLIDE (Sub-LInear Deep learning Engine) that uniquely blends smart randomized algorithms, with multi-core parallelism and workload optimization. Using just a CPU, SLIDE drastically reduces the computations during both training and inference outperforming an optimized implementation of Tensorflow (TF) on the best available GPU. Our evaluations on industry-scale recommendation datasets, with large fully connected architectures, show that training with SLIDE on a 44 core CPU is more than 3.5 times (1 hour vs. 3.5 hours) faster than the same network trained using TF on Tesla V100 at any given accuracy level. On the same CPU hardware, SLIDE is over 10x faster than TF. We provide codes and scripts for reproducibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 09:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rkwasny</dc:creator>
<og:title>SLIDE : In Defense of Smart Algorithms over Hardware Acceleration for Large-Scale Deep Learning Systems</og:title>
<og:url>https://arxiv.org/abs/1903.03129v2</og:url>
<og:description>Deep Learning (DL) algorithms are the central focus of modern machine learning systems. As data volumes keep growing, it has become customary to train large neural networks with hundreds of millions of parameters to maintain enough capacity to memorize these volumes and obtain state-of-the-art accuracy. To get around the costly computations associated with large models and data, the community is increasingly investing in specialized hardware for model training. However, specialized hardware is expensive and hard to generalize to a multitude of tasks. The progress on the algorithmic front has failed to demonstrate a direct advantage over powerful hardware such as NVIDIA-V100 GPUs. This paper provides an exception. We propose SLIDE (Sub-LInear Deep learning Engine) that uniquely blends smart randomized algorithms, with multi-core parallelism and workload optimization. Using just a CPU, SLIDE drastically reduces the computations during both training and inference outperforming an optimized implementation of Tensorflow (TF) on the best available GPU. Our evaluations on industry-scale recommendation datasets, with large fully connected architectures, show that training with SLIDE on a 44 core CPU is more than 3.5 times (1 hour vs. 3.5 hours) faster than the same network trained using TF on Tesla V100 at any given accuracy level. On the same CPU hardware, SLIDE is over 10x faster than TF. We provide codes and scripts for reproducibility.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arxiv.org/abs/1903.03129</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>CLUI: Building a Graphical Command Line</title>
<link>https://blog.repl.it/clui</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.repl.it/clui</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Command line interfaces. Once that was all we had. Then they disappeared, replaced by what we thought was a great advance: GUIs. GUIs were - and still are - valuable, but they fail to scale to the demands of today's systems. So now command line interfaces are back again, hiding under the name of search. Now you see them, now you don't. Now you see them again. And they will get better and better with time: mark my words, that is my prediction for the future of interfaces.” [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don Norman wrote this in 2008. Since then, search has become more powerful and users have grown more dependent on it-- searching for information with context-aware autocomplete is present in almost every popular digital product. Traditional CLIs, however, were never widely adopted by end-users because of their learning curve. Terminals, the primary platform for command-lines, are intimidating and feel like a black box to non-technical people. Also, a text-only interface is limiting-- it only allows actions to take place through language instead of the clicks, taps, and hovers that we’re used to today. Commands and flags often have obscure names, and spelling mistakes can result in cryptic errors, or worse, doing something you didn't intend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all these problems, CLIs are still powerful. The input mechanism is always the same: text. It’s predictable and constant. Adding more commands takes minimal effort from the developer. Users aren’t overwhelmed with information-- you just specify the exact commands you need at any given moment. These benefits, however, come with the tradeoff that commands must be memorized to be efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, GUIs are the most popular user interface paradigm because they address many of the concerns above. They use visual metaphors for everyday objects we are used to: desktops, windows, tabs, buttons, menus, files, and folders. They’re intuitive and offer a small learning curve to perform basic actions, like moving files via drag and drop. It’s faster to recognize an icon than to remember the action’s name. The benefits of GUIs are rooted in both memory recognition, which “...refers to our ability to “recognize” an event or piece of information as being familiar”, and memory recall, which “...designates the retrieval of related details from memory.” [4, 5]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So GUIs are obviously the best UI paradigm ever, right?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably not. Although GUIs might solve some core usability issues that most CLIs present, they &quot;...fail to scale to the demands of today's systems&quot; [2, 3]. The moment you want to add a feature to a GUI, there’s an immediate question about where to put that feature. Should it be in the top right? Bottom left? Nav bar? Behind a tab? In the sidebar? Revealed on hover?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You end up with buttons, panels, and menus competing for space in the UI-- screen real estate. Every pixel becomes more and more valuable for primary features. You don’t need to look very far to see what happens when you need to include dozens of features into a tiny rectangle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.repl.it/images/clui/adobe-premiere.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Adobe Premiere&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Adobe Premiere UI. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=54dUzkzEb-8&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you see the issue here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a reason using simple, lightweight software feels like a breath of fresh air. Professional creative tools like Adobe Premiere are often so packed with features that they become unapproachable, slow, ugly, and unfocused. YouTube is swamped with multi-part tutorials that deter beginners from learning. Power users will show you that their workflows are heavily dependent on keyboard shortcuts, elaborate workspace setups, custom automation tools and plugins, and help/search bars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.repl.it/images/clui/dropdowns.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nested dropdowns&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Are nested dropdowns the 10th circle of hell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a problem with GUIs inherently but rather a symptom of poor product scaling, which can often affect the density of a GUI first. The biggest issue with GUI density is throwing new features into endless submenus, dropdowns, hidden settings pages, or worse, the dreaded “more” button (which currently plagues Repl.it as well). Some apps try to mitigate this UI flood by using progressive disclosure: gradually revealing information to the user over time to avoid cognitive overload and make usage context clearer [6]. But the double-edged sword here is that reducing clutter in a UI can potentially make features harder to discover. A “simple UI” doesn’t necessarily mean it’s simple to use. Simplicity instead should be an emergent property of a well progressively disclosed UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing about bloated GUIs is that they beg for search. Once menus become deeply nested and panels flood your screen, it feels natural to want to search for something. You don’t want to look for what you need; you just want it in front of you immediately. However, the UX of searching to easily navigate through deeply nested menus seems like an afterthought. What if it was the primary way to interact with a tool?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many popular products and services are starting to explore this thought. In a way, voice assistants are one of the closest things we have to a synthesis of GUIs and CLIs. The input is semi-structured natural language (CLI-inspired) but the output can be rich media and interactive controls (GUI-inspired).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.repl.it/images/clui/siri.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Siri&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;When you ask Siri to turn on alarms, iOS will bring up portions of familiar GUI elements to further interact with. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT207512&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also plugins like Runner Pro for Sketch (a UI design tool) that allows you to quickly access information and automate design actions [7].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.repl.it/images/clui/sketch-runner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sketch runner&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Kind of funny that CLI-inspired interfaces are also useful in design tools. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/sketch-app-sources/hello-runner-pro-13ba62cbac35&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Repl.it, where our goal is to build a simple yet powerful programming environment, we run into UI scalability issues every time we have an IDE feature to add. So when it came to building our admin tools, we decided to explore a new UI paradigm. We often need to do simple things like changing single values in the database, so it’s usually easier to connect to the database directly and run some SQL than build new UI for it. But that's both unsafe and excludes anyone unfamiliar with SQL or the CLI. So we asked ourselves, “how can we marry the conciseness of CLIs with approachability of GUIs in the same interface?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few requirements for a CLI to be approachable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should be able to use it with a mouse.&lt;/strong&gt; This may seem contradictory to CLIs as a paradigm since their real power comes from using the keyboard, but being able to click through commands does two things: gives beginners a chance to &quot;level up&quot; to the keyboard and makes the interface more approachable. It also paves the way to make programming environments more accessible via touch and mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It needs to be discoverable.&lt;/strong&gt; That means context-aware autocomplete with clear and concise language providing the right level of detail about a command. The primary issue with discoverability in CLIs is that the commands are invisible. You either need to have memorized the commands already or use some form of documentation to gain access. In CLUI, the commands come to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The output should support rich and interactive media.&lt;/strong&gt; That means that images, gifs, video, graphs, interactive diagrams, buttons, and forms should be able to integrate directly into the CLI experience. ASCII art is fun, but text is only as useful as the information it can convey. Interactive media should be treated as a first class citizen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.repl.it/images/clui/comparison-table.png&quot; alt=&quot;UI Feature Comparisons&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To meet these requirements, we started to build CLUI: an easily extensible interface that blends GUIs and CLIs. On the surface, it’s simple: type in what you want, and get suggestions for commands. When you enter a full command, you get back some UI relevant to what you asked for. But the potential here is much larger than just a CLI with autocomplete and buttons. Eventually, we plan on making all of Repl.it accessible through CLUI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are dozens of features we could have implemented first, we prioritized the three bullets listed above. Keep in mind these are prototypes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Approachability&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.repl.it/images/clui/clui-approachability.gif&quot; alt=&quot;CLUI Approachability&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Being able to click through the commands makes CLUI more approachable to beginners than traditional CLIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Discoverability&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.repl.it/images/clui/clui-discoverability.gif&quot; alt=&quot;CLUI Discoverability&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Autocomplete and fuzzy-search makes commands significantly more discoverable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Interactivity&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.repl.it/images/clui/clui-interactivity.gif&quot; alt=&quot;CLUI Interactivity&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Interactive form elements makes interacting with the output of CLUI commands much more approachable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the unique parts about CLUI is that &lt;strong&gt;any new UI is automatically generated from the data you give it.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that adding features is as simple as adding commands on the backend. It’s an incredibly scalable approach for a small team like ours, and it makes new features much more modular and easier to reason about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a high level, CLUI really operates like a flowchart or a decision tree. You start at the root of the tree and gradually select commands one by one. Once you are done going down the tree (similar to a depth first search), you end up with your complete command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.repl.it/images/clui/command-tree.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Command tree&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Going down the command tree. Disclaimer: these are currently not real commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the tree is hierarchical, you might think that it actually resembles a large dropdown menu. The difference is that search is built directly into its navigation, not just pointing and clicking. One clear improvement that could be made is being able to search for any subcommand without having to specify its parent command first. That way you can access any deeply nested information instantly, similar to spotlight search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a technical level, a CLUI command is conceptually similar to a file path or URL. Since a complete CLUI command is simply a path down the command tree, each potential subcommand is like a portion of a file path or URL. Flags, on the other hand, function like query parameters. CLUI’s resemblance to URL paths means &lt;em&gt;you can send someone a complete, executable CLUI command as a URL.&lt;/em&gt; They’re mapped 1:1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we have a GraphQL backend, we know all the potential fields and arguments a client can use. By using an &lt;a href=&quot;https://graphql.org/learn/introspection/&quot;&gt;introspection&lt;/a&gt; query we generate a tree of commands/sub-commands that map onto their respective resolve functions. Now, to add a new admin command all that's needed is a new field on a GraphQL type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CLUI’s architecture thus makes it easy to create a direct mapping between our data primitives and UI primitives. For example, booleans are mapped to toggles or checkboxes and JSON is mapped to an auto-generated form. That means that we can focus on features of our product in isolation and trust that CLUI will help us manage their complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of our future plans for CLUI include, but aren’t limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unified terminal, REPL, shell, and spotlight search.&lt;/strong&gt; We want to eventually combine all command driven user interfaces together— this includes navigating the website, finding relevant information, action automation, and of course, traditional access to the UNIX shell and any language REPL. Many people are confused by the difference between the REPL and shell, and advanced users are often frustrated when they have to switch contexts and leave one or the other. Making a unified, CLUI driven design pattern across Repl.it will help mitigate both sides of these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End user programming.&lt;/strong&gt; Empowering our users to customize Repl.it and make CLUI work for them is one of our primary goals. You can easily imagine users being able to create aliases/shortcuts for base CLUI commands. For example, &lt;code&gt;repl new python —invite rachel95&lt;/code&gt; could be mapped to &lt;code&gt;lesson with rachel&lt;/code&gt;. The power in this comes from combining these shortcuts together, essentially abstracting away from our standard library of CLUI commands altogether and allowing users to create their own pseudo-languages to command Repl.it. When you extend this concept of user-created shortcuts to include parameterization, suddenly any command acts like a function— and the idea of piping inputs and outputs between commands becomes obvious. Users will be able to share, remix, and plug and play an entire command store’s worth of automation tools and utilities that make Repl.it truly unique to each user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/replit/clui&quot;&gt;open-sourced some of the code&lt;/a&gt; used to build this system. There's also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://repl.it/@moudy/clui-demo&quot;&gt;demo application&lt;/a&gt; that shows how everything works together. Right now, CLUI is offered as an unopinionated library for dealing with trees of commands- so you can bring your own UI and use it anywhere JavaScript runs. For example, we’re going to use CLUI as a base for a Figma plugin to automate parts of our design workflow, similar to Sketch Runner. We’re excited to see what the community (you!) can do with CLUI and your input on its design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, all user interfaces-- command driven or graphical-- are supposed to convey important, actionable information while being imperfect models of how people expect them to behave. There's a constant struggle to figure out how much information to expose, how to expose it, when, where, and why. Although we know that CLUI won’t be a panacea for Repl.it’s UI and UX development going forward, we think it'll help us through many core design scalability problems and hopefully get rid of some dropdown menus along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sources:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jnd.org/ui_breakthrough-command_line_interfaces&quot;&gt;https://jnd.org/ui_breakthrough-command_line_interfaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computerhope.com/issues/ch000619.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.computerhope.com/issues/ch000619.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jnd.org/natural_user_interfaces_are_not_natural/&quot;&gt;https://jnd.org/natural_user_interfaces_are_not_natural/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/recognition-and-recall/&quot;&gt;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/recognition-and-recall/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/ten-usability-heuristics/&quot;&gt;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/ten-usability-heuristics/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_disclosure&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_disclosure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sketchrunner.com/&quot;&gt;https://sketchrunner.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 21:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amasad</dc:creator>
<og:title>CLUI: Building a Graphical Command Line</og:title>
<og:description>&gt; “Command line interfaces. Once that was all we had. Then they disappeared, replaced by what we thought was a great advance: GUIs. GUIs…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>/images/clui-cover.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://blog.repl.it/clui</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.repl.it/clui</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>