<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Mars becomes the 2nd planet that has more computers running Linux than Windows</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/mikko/status/1362763793042972673</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/mikko/status/1362763793042972673</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mikko/status/1362763793042972673&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/mikko/status/1362763793042972673&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26197280&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26197280&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 788&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 211&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 19:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fireball_blaze</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://twitter.com/mikko/status/1362763793042972673</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ultima VIII – How to destroy a gaming franchise in one easy step</title>
<link>https://www.filfre.net/2021/02/ultima-viii-or-how-to-destroy-a-gaming-franchise-in-one-easy-step/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.filfre.net/2021/02/ultima-viii-or-how-to-destroy-a-gaming-franchise-in-one-easy-step/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2021/02/ultima-viii-or-how-to-destroy-a-gaming-franchise-in-one-easy-step/2748-pagan-ultima-viii-dos-front-cover/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4598&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-4598&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2748-pagan-ultima-viii-dos-front-cover-217x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;217&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2748-pagan-ultima-viii-dos-front-cover-217x300.jpg 217w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2748-pagan-ultima-viii-dos-front-cover-741x1024.jpg 741w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2748-pagan-ultima-viii-dos-front-cover-768x1061.jpg 768w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2748-pagan-ultima-viii-dos-front-cover.jpg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 217px) 100vw, 217px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1994, Origin Systems’s &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; series was the most universally lauded franchise in computer gaming. Over the course of seven mainline games and five spinoffs and side stories, the &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; brand had consistently stood for elaborate but doggedly nonlinear plots which seriously engaged with questions of ethics; for the familiar but ever-evolving and ever-welcoming world of Britannia in which most of the games took place; for a merry group of recurring boon companions with whom the Avatar, the player-defined protagonist of the games, adventured each time; for complex rules systems and knotty central mysteries that required brainpower and lots of notepaper rather than reflexes to work through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, for the eighth game in the mainline &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; series, Origin decided to try something just a little bit different. They made a game in which you played a thoughtless jerk moving on rails through a linear series of events; in which you never went to Britannia at all, but stayed instead on a miserable hellhole of a world called Pagan; in which you spent the whole game adventuring alone (after all, who would want to adventure with a jerk like you?); in which the core mechanics were jumping between pedestals like Super Mario and pounding your enemies over the head with your big old hammer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2021/02/ultima-viii-or-how-to-destroy-a-gaming-franchise-in-one-easy-step/u8_5/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4603&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-4603&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_5-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_5-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_5.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tens of thousands of eager &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; fans, some of whom had been buying every installment of the series for ten years or more, rushed home from their local software stores with &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII: Pagan&lt;/em&gt; in their hot little hands. An hour later, they were one and all sitting there scratching their heads and asking themselves what the hell had happened. Had they bought the wrong game entirely? No, it said “Ultima” right there on the box!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past quarter century, &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; fans have continued to ask themselves that same question: what the &lt;em&gt;hell&lt;/em&gt; happened with &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt;? It stands today as one of the most bizarre would-be series continuations in gaming history, such a colossal failure to meet its players’ expectations that, alone and unaided, it killed dead at a stroke the most venerable franchise in computer gaming. No, really: Origin couldn’t have shot &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; in the head more efficiently if they’d tried. And so we ask ourselves again: &lt;em&gt;what the hell&lt;/em&gt; happened? What the hell was Origin thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In seeking to explain the seemingly unexplainable, &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; fans have tended to hew to a simple, naturally appealing narrative that paints Electronic Arts — gaming’s very own Evil Empire — as the unmitigated villain. After &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2019/09/origin-sells-out&quot;&gt;acquiring Origin in late 1992&lt;/a&gt;, so the story goes, EA forced them to abandon all of the long-established principles of &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; in order to reach the mass market of lowest-common-denominator players to which EA aspired. Richard Garriot — a.k.a. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2011/12/lord-british&quot;&gt;“Lord British,”&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2012/02/ultima-part-1&quot;&gt;father of &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2013/05/origin-systems&quot;&gt;co-founder of Origin&lt;/a&gt; — has embraced this explanation with gusto, part and parcel of a perhaps too prevalent tendency with His Lordship to lay his failures at the feet of others. From Garriott’s 2017 memoir:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;48&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality is that EA earns most of its revenue with terrific games like Madden Football. Every year they publish a new edition, which reflects the changes in the NFL. They don’t have to create much that’s new — they just tweak their football-game engine and update the rosters. The rules of football change slowly. At the deadline they wrap it up and release it. The audience is pre-sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, the games we were making could easily take two years or more to create. We released them when we were done. That was not EA’s way of doing business. “Richard,” they told me, “your release of games is incredibly unreliable.” They wanted us to change our development process to meet their deadlines. The game we were developing when we sold Origin was Ultima VIII; EA wanted it on the shelves in time for the following Christmas. This was the first time in my life that the realities of business became more important than the quality of a product. They were adamant: “Richard, you need to cut whatever needs to be cut to get this game done.” So I cut it; I cut it and I cut it and I cut it, and as a result I shipped the most incomplete, dumb, buggy game I’ve ever shipped. I still believe that if we had waited until it was complete, Ultima VIII would have been a great game. We would have been the first to market with a variety of features that eventually proved very popular in other games. But we didn’t wait, and that was my fault. I bowed to the outside pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most distressing was seeing the results of making those cuts on both the game and my team. The team saw past the warts, knew what we were up against, and loved the game for what it was; they appreciated the innovations in it rather than bemoaning what it could have been. But the press, as well as a number of players, didn’t like it at all. The reviews were terrible. All the money I’d been paid had no meaning. I felt awful that I had let down so many people in my effort to be loyal and learn from EA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a lot of people had made serious sacrifices to meet EA’s schedule. Many of our programmers had worked twelve hours a day, seven days a week for ten months. We would bring dinner in for them because we were afraid if they left, they might not come back. The last month or so we gave them every other Sunday off so, as one of them pointed out, they could see their family or do some laundry. The creative joy we’d once shared in developing a game had been replaced by the prosaic demands of running a business. It was hard to believe how much had changed; only a few years earlier our people would happily work all night and love every minute of it, and now we had become a sweatshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least partially as a consequence of that disappointment, management told me, basically, that they didn’t want me making big games like Ultima anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This classic passive-aggressive apology — “I felt awful that I had let down so many people in my effort to be loyal and learn from EA” doesn’t exactly ring out with contrition — isn’t even internally consistent; if the development team loved their game so much, why was Origin’s management forced to devise stratagems to keep them from going home out of the fear that they wouldn’t come back? Nevertheless, it does contain a fair amount of truth alongside its self-serving omissions; one would be foolish to deny that the EA acquisition played a major role in the &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;VIII&lt;/em&gt; debacle. And yet the discussion should perhaps be framed rather differently. It might be more accurate to see Origin’s acquisition by EA and the eventual &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; as mutual symptoms rather than cause and effect, both being the result of Origin trying to negotiate trends that seemed to leave &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; with less and less space to be what it had always been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by looking more closely at the timeline than Garriott deigns to do above. EA and Origin signed the acquisition contract in September of 1992, just five months after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2019/02/ultima-vii&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ultima VII: The Black Gate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; had shipped. &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; would still have been in the early-concept phase at best at that point. When he refers to “the following Christmas” above, Garriott thus presumably means the Christmas of 1993. While this release date may have been a stated aspiration, it’s hard to believe it was a serious one; it would have marked the swiftest turnaround time between two mainline &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; games since the first three of them in the early 1980s. As it was, &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; wouldn’t ship until March of 1994, still in a woefully unfinished state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the story of &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; is more than that of just one more game that was released before its time. Even had all of Origin’s plans for it come off perfectly, it would still have been a radical, seemingly nonsensical departure from everything &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; had been in the past. Multiple sources confirm that it was in fact Richard Garriott himself rather than any soulless suit from EA who decided that the latest installment in Origin’s epic CRPG series ought to become a… &lt;em&gt;platformer&lt;/em&gt;. He was inspired in this not by &lt;em&gt;Super Mario Bros.&lt;/em&gt;, as many fans would later suspect, but rather by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2016/10/how-jordan-mechner-made-a-different-sort-of-interactive-movie-or-the-virtues-of-restraint&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prince of Persia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Broderbund Software’s hugely popular, widely ported, elegantly minimalist, intensely cinematic linear action game. &lt;em&gt;Prince of Persia&lt;/em&gt; was and is a more than worthy game in its own right, but it seems a strange choice indeed to use as inspiration for the latest &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt;. We should try to understand where the choice came from in the context of the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garriott has often joked that he spent the first twelve years of his career making essentially the same game over and over — merely making said game that much bigger and better each time out. If so, then &lt;em&gt;Ultima VII&lt;/em&gt; was the ultimate, if you will, version of that game. Today its reputation is as hallowed as that of any game of its era; it remains a perennial on lists of the best CRPGs of all time. Yet its mixed reception in 1992 rather belies its modern reputation. Many reviewers expressed a certain ennui about the series as a whole, and ordinary gamers seemed less excited by its arrival than they had been by that of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2014/07/ultima-iv&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ultima IV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2016/02/ultima-v&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;V&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2017/04/ultima-vi&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;VI&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2019/01/life-off-the-grid-part-1-making-ultima-underworld&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ultima Underworld&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a more action-oriented spinoff which was created by the outside studio Blue Sky Productions and published by Origin just a month before &lt;em&gt;Ultima VII&lt;/em&gt;, collected more critical praise and, likely most frustratingly of all for the hyper-competitive Garriott, continued to outsell its supposed big brother even after the latter’s release. A survey in the March 1993 issue of &lt;em&gt;Computer Gaming World&lt;/em&gt; magazine is particularly telling: &lt;em&gt;Ultima VII&lt;/em&gt; is rated as the 30th favorite game of the magazine’s readers, while &lt;em&gt;Ultima Underworld&lt;/em&gt; is in a tie for third favorite. Meanwhile Origin’s eighteen-month-old &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/wing-commander-ii&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wing Commander II&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a cinematic action game of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;-style space combat, still sits at number six.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the role of &lt;em&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/em&gt; in all of this should not be neglected. The brainchild of an enthusiastic young Englishman named Chris Roberts, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2017/04/from-squadron-to-wingleader&quot;&gt;the first game in that series&lt;/a&gt; had upon its release in 1990 surprised everyone by handily outselling that same year’s &lt;em&gt;Ultima VI&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/em&gt; franchise had kept on outselling &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; ever since, whilst being faster and easier to make on an installment-by-installment basis.This too could hardly have sat well with Garriott. The House That &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; Built had become The Home of &lt;em&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/em&gt;, and Chris Roberts was now more in demand for interviews than Lord British. The harsh truth was that EA had been far more excited about &lt;em&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/em&gt; than &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; when they decided to acquire Origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken as a whole, all of this must have seemed intensely symbolic of a changing industry. As computers got faster and came to sport higher-fidelity audiovisual capabilities, visceral action titles were taking a bigger and bigger slice of computer-game sales, as evinced not only by the success of &lt;em&gt;Ultima Underworld&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/em&gt; but by other big hits like id Software’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/05/the-shareware-scene-part-3-the-id-boys&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wolfenstein 3D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Onscreen text was out of fashion, as was sprawl and complexity and most of the other traditional markers of an &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt;. Shorter, more focused games of the sort that one could pick up and play &lt;em&gt;quickly&lt;/em&gt; were in. Origin had to keep up with the trends if they hoped to survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, Origin was in an extremely perilous financial state just before the EA acquisition. EA’s deep pockets would allow them to keep pace with spiraling development costs for the time being. But in return, the games they made had to have enough mass-market appeal to recoup their larger budgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, then, was the calculus that went into &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt;, which begins to make the inexplicable at least somewhat more comprehensible. At this juncture in time, epic CRPGs were at literally their lowest ebb in the entire history of computer games. Therefore &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt;, the series that was virtually synonymous with the epic CRPG in the minds of most gamers, needed to become something else. It needed to become simpler and faster-paced, and if it could also jump on the trend toward grittier, more violent ludic aesthetics — I point again to the rise of id Software — so much the better. It may not have been a coincidence that, when &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; eventually shipped, it did so in a box sporting garish orange flames and a huge pentagram — the same general graphics style and even iconography as was seen in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/06/the-shareware-scene-part-4-doom&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DOOM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, id’s latest ultra-violent hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2021/02/ultima-viii-or-how-to-destroy-a-gaming-franchise-in-one-easy-step/u8_1/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4599&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-4599&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_1-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_1.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the flaws in the thought process that led to &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; aren’t hard to identify in retrospect. Games which lack the courage of their own convictions seldom make for good company, any more than do people of the same stripe. The insecure child of a nervous creator who feared the world of gaming was passing him by, &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; could likely never have aspired to be more than competent in a derivative sort of way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest blunder was the decision to slap the &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; name on the thing at all, thereby raising expectations on the part of the franchise’s preexisting fan base which the game was never designed to meet. Ironically, the audience for an &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; was every bit as “pre-sold,” as Garriott puts it above, as the audience for the latest &lt;em&gt;Madden&lt;/em&gt;. And yet one game that fails to meet fan expectations can destroy just such a pre-sold audience really, really quickly, as Garriott was about to prove. (An analogy to the radical change in course of &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; might be a &lt;em&gt;Madden&lt;/em&gt; installment that suddenly decided to become a cerebral stat-based game of football management and strategy instead of an exercise in fast-paced on-the-field action…) It would have been better to announce that &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; was taking a break while Lord British tried something new. But it seems that Garriott identified so strongly with the only line of games he had ever seriously worked on that he couldn’t imagine &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; calling his latest one &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for the conceptual flaws in the project. Alas, its execution would prove even more of a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Garriott’s involvement in the day-to-day work of game development had been decreasing almost year by year, ever since he had first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2016/02/the-road-to-v&quot;&gt;agreed to let other programmers help him&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;em&gt;Ultima V&lt;/em&gt; back in 1986. The &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; project was set up in the same way that the last couple had been: Garriott provided a set of general design goals and approaches along with a plot outline, then dropped in occasionally on the Origin staff who were assigned to the project while they made it all happen. This time the role of project director fell to one Mike McShaffry, who had come to Origin in 1990 to work as a programmer on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/02/the-worlds-of-ultima&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ultima Worlds of Adventure 2: Martian Dreams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, then held the same role on &lt;em&gt;Ultima VII&lt;/em&gt;. Meanwhile the nuts-and-bolts designers of &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; became John Watson and Andrew Morris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of these people were incompetent; all would continue to pursue fruitful careers in the games industry after &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; was behind them. But on this occasion they found themselves in an untenable situation, given neither the time nor the support they needed to make a competent game even of the dubious type for which Garriott was asking. &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; would not employ the talents of Raymond Benson, the accomplished wordsmith who had made &lt;em&gt;Ultima VII&lt;/em&gt;‘s script so exceptionally rich and subtle; he was now gone from the company, driven away like many of his peers by the insanely long hours Origin demanded of their employees. Rather than replacing him with another proper writer, Origin cobbled together a collection of programmers, artists, and designers to provide all of its comparatively scant text, most of them doing double duty with their other roles on the project. After all, it was now the age of multimedia action. How much did mere words really matter anymore?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As 1993 wore on, external events heaped more and more pressure on the team. Chris Roberts’s latest game &lt;em&gt;Strike Commander&lt;/em&gt; appeared in the spring of 1993; it moved his patented &lt;em&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/em&gt; approach into the milieu of a near-future techno-thriller. Everyone confidently expected it to become Roberts’s latest blockbuster hit, EA’s first great dividend on the price of the Origin acquisition. But instead it under-performed relative to expectations; gamers seemed nonplussed by the change in setting, and their computers struggled to meet its high system requirements. Origin would manage to score some successes on a more modest scale in 1993 with other, cheaper &lt;em&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/em&gt; spinoffs and an &lt;em&gt;Ultima VII Part Two&lt;/em&gt;, but their big cannon for the year had shot a dud. It was now up to &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; to put smiles on the faces of EA’s management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all that the EA acquisition certainly was a major factor in the story of &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt;, it’s difficult to say for sure how much of the pressure Origin felt was brought directly to bear by their new corporate parent and how much was merely perceived. As we’ve seen, Richard Garriott hasn’t hesitated to chalk the failure of &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; up to EA’s interference, full stop. Yet the actual EA executives in question have vociferously denied micromanaging the project, insisting on the contrary that it was conceived, created, and finally shipped on terms dictated by no one outside of Origin. Even some Origin employees have admitted that EA handled their new charge with a fairly light touch for the first couple of years; it was only after such disappointments as &lt;em&gt;Strike Commander&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; had convinced them that adult supervision was sorely needed down in Austin that they took a more hands-on approach. In the end, then, we can say for sure only that the appalling state in which &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; was released was down to some gradation in between an earnest desire on Origin’s behalf to please their parent and a stern dictate from said parent to &lt;em&gt;ship it now, or else!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It must be said as well that the reality of crunch time at Origin prior to &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; was somewhat different from the rosy picture which Garriott paints above. The bad-cop counterpart to Garriot the lunch-providing good cop was Dallas Snell, Origin’s hard-driving production manager. The company’s internal newsletters from the early 1990s are littered with complaints about the stresses of crunch time, sometimes accompanied by Snell’s strident but unconvincing attempts to defend the practice on the basis of passion, dedication, and esprit de corps. As a result, Raymond Benson was only one of a steady stream of talented people who came to Origin, stayed there a relatively brief period of time, and then moved on to other parts of the games industry or to other industries entirely, having made the perfectly sensible decision that no job is worth sacrificing one’s health and general well-being for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the crunch that produced &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; was extreme even by Origin’s usual standards, and the stress was undoubtedly compounded by the bad vibe of compromise and trend-chasing that had clung to the project from the start. It didn’t help that Mike McShaffry had never attempted to manage a software-development project of any sort before; he was completely unequipped to bring any semblance of order to all of the frantic effort, as he freely admits today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To a lot of people on the development team, Ultima VIII unfortunately was a very negative development experience. Most of the team who were managing Ultima VIII — myself especially — you know, it was our first really big management task, and so…to say I really screwed it up doesn’t really come close, I don’t think, to the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t just put anybody at the helm of an oil tanker and say, “Take it through the strait!” and not expect something really horrible to happen. And Ultima’s a big ship to steer, and it was unfortunate that I never had the chance to figure out how to manage a team that large. It took me another ten years to really get better at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these factors led to &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; shipping in a state that almost defies critical description; seldom has a game so blatantly unfinished been allowed onto store shelves. The writing is so sparse and unrefined that it often seems like placeholder text, and yet still manages to leave threads dangling and plot holes yawning everywhere; the cloth map that is included in the box bears almost no relation to the world in the game itself, what with so much of the latter having gone missing in action; what’s left of the CRPG mechanics are so broken that it’s possible to max out your character in less than an hour of play; every place in the game looks the same, being all too clearly built from the same handful of pre-rendered graphics (giant mushrooms everywhere for the win!); every single chest in the game explodes, even if it doesn’t contain anything, as if the developers didn’t have time to address each one individually and so just set a global flag somewhere; your unresponsive lunk of a character drowns instantly if he falls into two feet of water. Tellingly, the one part of &lt;em&gt;Ultima VII&lt;/em&gt; that is painstakingly preserved in &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; is its most annoying: an impossible inventory-management system that forces you to spend minutes at a time dragging around tiny overlapping icons just to find anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2021/02/ultima-viii-or-how-to-destroy-a-gaming-franchise-in-one-easy-step/u8_4/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4602&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-4602&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_4-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_4-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_4.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2021/02/ultima-viii-or-how-to-destroy-a-gaming-franchise-in-one-easy-step/u8_3/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4601&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-4601&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_3-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_3-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_3.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But none of that was quite enough to make the original version of &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; worthy of the adjective “unplayable.” What served for that was the absurdly broken jumping system. &lt;em&gt;Super Mario Bros.&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Prince of Persia&lt;/em&gt; had been designed for joypads and joysticks. Seeking to translate those paradigms to a moused-based computer, Origin came up with a relativistic jumping system whereby the length of your leap would be determined by the distance the cursor was from your character when you clicked the mouse, rather than opting for the more intuitive solution whereby you simply pointed at and clicked on a would-be destination to attempt to jump there. McShaffry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;29&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think, for us, it was such a departure from what we were used to. And honestly, a jumping mechanic like what we were trying to do… I think that we just didn’t have enough people on the team who were really hardcore platformer players. Something like Mario, where you have an intuitive feel for what works in a jumping system and what doesn’t work in a jumping system. I certainly hadn’t played a lot of those games until then, and so I honestly didn’t know what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, that’s a case where we should have listened a whole lot more to QA. They were platformers! They played every Nintendo console [game] out there, and they came back to us and said, “Hey, this jumping is kind of busted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think sometimes in product development we’d get on the high horse and go, “It’s not busted; we know what we’re doing.” And in that case… that was a horrible mistake on our part to not listen to them. But hey, we were in our twenties; when you’re in your twenties, you think you’ve got god-like powers and you’re immortal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth, jumping in &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; wasn’t “kind of busted” at all; it was completely, comprehensively busted. Figuring out where any given jump would land you was a black art, thanks to the sloppy mouse cursor and the impossibility of accurately judging depths in the game’s canted isometric view. The only way to get anywhere was to save before each jump and give it a try, then reload and adjust until you got it right. After four or five attempts, you might just manage it if you were lucky. Then you got to rinse and repeat for the next jump, out of what might be a dozen or more in all to get across a single obstacle. In order to fully appreciate the horror of all this, you have to remember that every single save or restore would have taken on the order of 30 seconds back in 1994. And now imagine trying to work through this process when some of the platforms you need to jump from and to are &lt;em&gt;moving&lt;/em&gt;. On release day, &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; really was perilously close to being literally unplayable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_4604&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2021/02/ultima-viii-or-how-to-destroy-a-gaming-franchise-in-one-easy-step/u8lithos/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4604&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-4604&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-4604&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8lithos-300x225.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8lithos-300x225.png 300w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8lithos.png 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-4604&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Oh, my… I’m afraid we’re going to be here a while…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In keeping with a tradition dating back to the early 1980s, Richard Garriott, Mike McShaffry, and several other members of the development team turned up on CompuServe for an online conference with fans just a couple of weeks after the game’s release. These affairs were heavily moderated, and this prevented the outrage that was already percolating through the fan community from being expressed too aggressively. Nevertheless, the developers quickly learned that this meetup was not to be the usual love fest. Instead they got an earful from the fans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;61&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me say that I have been playing Ultimas since I was charmed and amazed by Ultima IV on my Commodore 64. One of the best things about Ultimas was the rich, detailed world and intricate, lengthy storylines. I could look forward to easily over 100 hours with each new Ultima, an excellent value for the money. Ultima VIII, on the other hand, is way too short…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like there were a lot of bugs in Ultima VIII…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought the game was a little rough around the edges, especially the jumping. Since many Ultima players don’t like the heavy arcade element, are you set on keeping Ultima a CRPG/action game?…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of Ultima VII was the large world. I was a little disappointed when I found that the world in Ultima VIII was actually smaller. Will Ultima IX have a larger world and more puzzles that require thinking, as opposed to jumping and running?…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I note with some trepidation your interest/fascination with “action” and “digital speech.” I think that too many game companies are spending too many resources on the latest graphics, sounds, etc., and nowhere near enough on character development and story and interaction. Is the swing to action/arcade a marketing-driven decision, your personal [decision], or [down to] some other reason?…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have noticed a trend toward a single-threaded story line. Any hopes of returning to the original roots with the Ultima IX story line?…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I and a lot of other old Ultima fans saw disappear after Ultima VII was the great ability to interact. Like baking bread, etc., and I would like to know if you plan for this to return in Ultima IX. And will you pay more attention to the plot?…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m concerned about the decline in the Avatar’s principles. I spent two days trying to solve Bane and Vordion without breaking my oath…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am disappointed about the length of Ultima VIII, as others have said. There’s too much running around, and the clues to locations are far too vague…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m disappointed in Ultima VIII. I’ve played every single Ultima, and I feel Ultima VIII is a serious step back from previous Ultimas. I hope you realize that it takes more than glitz and sound to make a good CRPG. Lastly, I really do hope you’ll fix more bugs. I had to reformat my whole hard drive because of Ultima VIII…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we ever going to get various sexes and races of Avatars to choose from again?…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they didn’t know it before, Origin must have realized by the time this conference ended that they had a big, big problem on their hands. The subsequent fan reactions to &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; were and remain far more entertaining than the game itself; few games have inspired as many &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wpui9EKNTzE&quot;&gt;unhinged, poetically profane rants&lt;/a&gt; as this one. Writing in the fannish newsletter &lt;em&gt;Questbusters&lt;/em&gt;, Charles Don Hall struggled to reconcile this awful game with the Lord British cult of personality that so much of hardcore &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; fandom had always been: “My best guess is that Lord British had nothing at all to do with it, and turned development over to soulless drones who were capable of playing the earlier &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt;s but incapable of understanding what made them such great games.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The glossier magazines weren’t quite sure what to do about &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt;. Torn between the need to serve their readerships and Origin’s advertising dollars, they equivocated like crazy, often settling on an “it’s not the game, it’s me” approach: i.e., &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; didn’t much enjoy &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt;, but &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; might.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big exception was &lt;em&gt;Computer Gaming World&lt;/em&gt;, the most long-lived and respected of all the journals, whose status gave it a degree of insulation from the need to chase advertisers. Scorpia, the magazine’s influential adventure-gaming columnist, ripped the game to shreds in her review. I’ll share just a few highlights here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;45&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pagan, the purported Ultima VIII, is unlike any other Ultima you may have played. If you were expecting characterization, rich story, role-playing — you’re expecting it from the wrong game…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game might easily have been called, as a friend of mine put it, “Mario: The Avatar.” If the name “Ultima” wasn’t on the box, you might think you’d picked up the latest Sega or Nintendo game by mistake…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pagan could well be subtitled “School Daze,” as a good 75 percent of it is having the Avatar prove he is worthy to belong to a particular magic organization. “You want to be a Necromancer? First, you must be tested!” “You want to be a Theurgist? First, you must be tested!” “You want to be a Sorcerer? First you must be tested!”…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2021/02/ultima-viii-or-how-to-destroy-a-gaming-franchise-in-one-easy-step/u8_2/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4600&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-4600&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_2-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/u8_2.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story, such as it is, can be summed up as “Homeward-Bound Avatar Wrecks World…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Avatar] lies to become a Necromancer; joins the Theurgists solely to steal an item (thereby negating their spell-casting abilities); betrays a Sorcerer who trusted him (thereby becoming an accessory to murder); kills (in supposed self-defense) the Master of Sorcerers to obtain another needed item; and frees the two bound Titans, so the world is wracked by continual violent storms and lava rain…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Pagan is a disaster, and an embarrassment to Origin, Lord British, and Ultima fans everywhere. It tries to go in two directions at once, and succeeds only in tearing itself apart, failing dismally on all fronts…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of giving a smattering of hints and tips for &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt;, as was her wont with the games she reviewed, Scorpia published an outright walkthrough, in order to “help anyone playing it to finish quickly and move on to better things.” For the following issue, she wrote a detailed retrospective of &lt;em&gt;Ultima IV&lt;/em&gt;, her avowed favorite game of all time, pointing out all the ways in which it was the archetypal &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; — and, by pointed implication, all of the ways in which &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; had failed to live up to its legacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that very same issue, Origin offered an unprecedented mea culpa for &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt;. Having clearly decided that this installment was beyond hope, they tried to save the franchise’s future by throwing it, and to at least some extent its project leader Mike McShaffry, under the bus. Richard Garriott had, he said, “heard the cry of his fans”; he admitted that “the latest game design had moved too close to action gaming and strayed too far from the strengths of the series.” Origin would, they promised, place the rock-steady Warren Spector — the man who had helmed &lt;em&gt;Ultima VI&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Martian Dreams&lt;/em&gt;, and the two &lt;em&gt;Ultima Underworld&lt;/em&gt; games — in charge of &lt;em&gt;Ultima IX&lt;/em&gt;. “If,” Spector pleaded, “we can get some of our followers who were disappointed in &lt;em&gt;Pagan&lt;/em&gt; to try &lt;em&gt;Ultima IX&lt;/em&gt;, we don’t think they’ll be disappointed.” In the meantime, an all-but-complete &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; expansion disk was axed as part of a general desire to forget that the game had ever happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One man, however, could not possibly forget. Mike McShaffry says today that he “felt like persona non grata at Origin because I personally felt like I was being blamed for the mistakes.” After months of ineffectual bad feelings, he finally decided to do something about it. He took all of the &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; code home with him over the Thanksgiving weekend of 1994 and, as he puts it, “fixed the jumping myself,” replacing the weird system of relative leaps with a simple click-here-to-jump-here approach. Despite their wish to flush the whole thing down the memory hole, Origin agreed to put out a patch incorporating this change and a number of other desperately needed quality-of-life improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s this version of &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; that you’ll find hosted on digital storefronts today. It’s definitely a vast improvement over the original, even taking into account the philosophical objection that it turns into a triviality the jumping that was intended to be a major part of the experience. Much respect to Mike McShaffry for making it; if he hadn’t done so, the game’s reputation would be even worse today. Even Scorpia took note of the patch in her column, and was prompted to soften her stance toward the game ever so slightly. (“I can’t guarantee the game will be more fun, but it will certainly be less frustrating.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, it’s quite common to hear today that &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; really wasn’t a bad game at all — that it was merely a bad &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt;, in departing way too radically from that series’s established traditions. Some fuel for this argument is provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/game/crusader-no-remorse&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crusader: No Remorse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/game/crusader-no-regret&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crusader: No Regret&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a pair of science-fiction action games that used the engine developed for &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt;, but were able to do so without the baggage which the &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; name brought with it. Both were well-received upon their release in 1995 and 1996 respectively, and are still fondly remembered in some circles today. Some have gone so far as to claim that the engine influenced &lt;em&gt;Diablo&lt;/em&gt;, Blizzard Entertainment’s 1996 mega-hit of a streamlined, story-light action-CRPG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, to say that McShaffry’s patch makes a &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; game out of &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; strikes me as a leap too far (pun intended). At best, it moves it from unplayable to the lower end of mediocre: the boring environments, uninteresting and/or broken mechanics, poor and sometimes nonexistent writing, and general air of unpleasantness remain unpatched. &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; is not the misunderstood classic that a few thoroughgoing contrarians would have it be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; is best studied not as an exercise in game design in the abstract but as an endlessly illustrative sign of its times, showing what happened when the changes being wrought upon the culture of computer gaming by the likes of &lt;em&gt;Wolfenstein 3D&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;DOOM&lt;/em&gt; — not to mention &lt;em&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/em&gt;! — collided head-on with one of that culture’s traditional standard bearers. In this case, the standard bearer in question would never be the same again. The &lt;em&gt;Ultima IX&lt;/em&gt; which certain factions inside Origin were so eager to make as a way of spitting out the bad taste of &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; would keep getting pushed down in the priority queue after &lt;em&gt;Wing Commander III&lt;/em&gt; appeared in late 1994 and finally provided the big hit which Origin had been looking for ever since the EA acquisition. With that event, &lt;em&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/em&gt;‘s takeover of Origin was complete. It would be over two and a half years before gamers would hear the name of &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; from Origin again in any context, four and a half years before &lt;em&gt;Ultima IX&lt;/em&gt; would appear and promptly disappoint everyone all over again. The glory days of Lord British were over; from this point forward, Richard Garriott’s career in game development would consist of little other than big promises followed by bigger disappointments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt; the books &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/006228665X/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=analogantiqua-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=006228665X&amp;amp;linkId=d5b32176abfc75b070ed9d5266ec0742&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore Create&lt;/em&gt; by Richard Garriott with David Fisher&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0072228881/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=analogantiqua-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0072228881&amp;amp;linkId=74b750b81ff26b1ce7722a93528873d7&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dungeons and Dreamers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Brad King and John Borland; &lt;em&gt;Computer Gaming World&lt;/em&gt; of March 1994, July 1994, August 1994, and May 1995; &lt;em&gt;Electronic Entertainment&lt;/em&gt; of April 1994; &lt;em&gt;Questbusters&lt;/em&gt; 111; &lt;em&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/em&gt; of May/June 1994; &lt;em&gt;PC Zone&lt;/em&gt; of June 1994; &lt;em&gt;Dragon&lt;/em&gt; of August 1994; Origin Systems’s internal newsletter &lt;em&gt;Point of Origin&lt;/em&gt; of December 1993, March 1994, and May 5 1995. Online sources include &lt;a href=&quot;http://sherigranerray.com/?p=13&quot;&gt;Sheri Graner Ray’s memories&lt;/a&gt; of her time at Origin Systems, &lt;a href=&quot;https://v1.escapistmagazine.com/articles/view/video-games/issues/issue_14/87-The-Conquest-of-Origin&quot;&gt;“The Conquest of Origin”&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;em&gt;The Escapist&lt;/em&gt;, and the &lt;em&gt;Ultima Codex&lt;/em&gt; interviews with &lt;a href=&quot;https://ultimacodex.com/interviews/oh-no-not-moonglow-again-an-interview-with-mike-mcshaffry/&quot;&gt;Mike McShaffry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ultimacodex.com/interviews/we-had-a-lot-of-fun-with-the-other-explosives-an-interview-with-jason-ely/&quot;&gt;Jason Ely&lt;/a&gt;. My huge thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/01/a-conversation-with-judith-pintar&quot;&gt;Judith Pintar&lt;/a&gt; for digging up the online CompuServe conference that followed &lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt;‘s release. Note that I’ve heavily edited the excerpts that are included here for grammar, clarity, and brevity; feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/misc/u8ciscnf.txt&quot;&gt;download the full, unedited transcript&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ultima VIII&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gog.com/game/ultima_8_gold_edition&quot;&gt;available as a digital purchase&lt;/a&gt; at GOG.com.)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doppp</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.filfre.net/2021/02/ultima-viii-or-how-to-destroy-a-gaming-franchise-in-one-easy-step/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tauri: An Electron alternative written in Rust</title>
<link>https://tauri.studio/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://tauri.studio/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tauri.studio/&quot;&gt;https://tauri.studio/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26194990&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26194990&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 711&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 310&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>metalwhale</dc:creator>
<og:title>Build smaller, faster, and more secure desktop applications with a web frontend | Tauri Studio</og:title>
<og:description>Tauri is a framework for building tiny, blazing fast binaries for all major desktop platforms. Developers can integrate any front-end framework that compiles to HTML, JS and CSS for building their user interface.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://tauri.studio/en/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Brave Browser leaks your Tor / Onion service requests through DNS</title>
<link>https://ramble.pw/f/privacy/2387/brave-browser-leaks-your-tor-onion-service-requests-through</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ramble.pw/f/privacy/2387/brave-browser-leaks-your-tor-onion-service-requests-through</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Edit: (Since this is gaining traction elsewhere.) I'm not trying to shit on Brave. I'm just wanting to help protect end-users who may use Brave for it's Tor feature to do stuff over Tor that should only be done with the actual Tor browser. If you're using Brave you probably use it because you expect a certain level of privacy/anonymity. Piping .onion requests through DNS where your ISP or DNS provider can see that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; made a request for an .onion site defeats that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also no NetSec expert but you don't have to be to replicate this. I'm just a dude with some websites and projects and I'm not certain I would have taken notice of this if it wasn't reported to me by a partner on another project who witnessed this behavior when monitoring his local requests leaving his network. He'll be doing his own write-up and is more equipped to discuss this in length than me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Testing out something that was noted a week or so ago, and wanting to replicate it for the purpose of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of you know I'm working on an ad, tracker, and other BS blocking VPN service for an unrelated project to this site. Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ramble.pw/f/incoghost&quot;&gt;/f/incoghost&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://incog.host&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;) for more because I try to keep these things separated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, it was reported by a partner that Brave was leaking DNS requests for onion sites and I was able to confirm it at the time. Decided to spin up a VM with Brave and test with this site's Onion service (though it will do this for any .onion)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt; Feb 18 12:02:25: query[A] rambleeeqrhty6s5jgefdfdtc6tfgg4jj6svr4jpgk4wjtg3qshwbaad.onion from 104.244.xx.xxx
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this entry shows (simply) is that the request made for the domain rambleeeqrhty6s5jgefdfdtc6tfgg4jj6svr4jpgk4wjtg3qshwbaad.onion made it to the DNS server and is tagged with the IP of the requester, which in this case is just the test / dev VPN. This shouldn't happen. There isn't any reason for Brave to attempt to resolve a .onion domain through traditional means as it would with a regular clearnet site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially worrisome for those of you who use Brave browser from your normal residential IP and (for whatever reason) use the Tor feature built into the browser to access Tor sites. Your ISP or DNS provider &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; know that a request made to a specific Tor site was made by &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; IP. With Brave, your ISP would know that you accessed &lt;em&gt;somesketchyonionsite.onion&lt;/em&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: If you're going to use Tor, use the Tor Browser and not Brave. The Tor browser itself doesn't leak these requests like Brave does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit: To clarify, the VPN service we're working on is no-logging but during this dev and testing period we're logging DNS requests while we work out the kinks in the blocklists. This has also allowed us to witness .onions being passed through which is a fault of Brave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit 2: Screenshot: &lt;a href=&quot;https://images2.imgbox.com/98/46/1i084PbC_o.png&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://images2.imgbox.com/98/46/1i084PbC_o.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was me loading duckduckgo in a different container, with brave, while live fetching DNS requests made to the DNS server. I blurred out the non-onion requests. (Different VPN test location than in the above example so 209.x.x.x IP instead of the 104.x.x.x one in the original example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;EDIT 2: The mods of /r/privacy won't let this be posted. They say:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we (vastly) prefer the Tor Browser over the Brave one, you'll need a better source than the one you found. Can you find something from a more widely recognized NetSec expert? Something along the lines of Bruce Schneier's blog or something at that level of credibility?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with screenshots is that they can be faked, trivially. There are also a host of approaches that credible writers/reporters do in the NetSec space do before a line of text appears in print. It's this kind of journalism that we have to trust, since we humble Mods don't have the time or resources to vet. So, we'll need something better sourced. Sorry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;19.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are new posts everyday &quot;warning&quot; people of things that aren't legitimate, hence the caution. This is not a &quot;security&quot; subreddit. A moderator's job is to ensure that the subreddit doesn't devolve into conspiracy theories and misinformation. Security announcements should be vetted and confirmed, not independent claims that the mods have no time to independently verify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can post the steps on how to easily replicate this by using pi-hole on their local networks. Anyone is capable of verifying this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great. Please do so on r/brave, r/netsec, r/infosec, and other places where this is both directly relevant and appropriate to seek others confirmation. Once vetted by the community (and republished by professionals), you're welcome to post those official responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/r/brave is private, invite only. I posted on netsec and infosec so we'll see. I guess /r/privacy must love Brave and not allow anything against it since it's so god damned easy to verify this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you have to do to VERIFY that this is happening is A.) Use Brave B.) Go to an Onion site C.) Observe DNS traffic. Install Pi-Hole on a Raspberry Pi or in a Virtual Machine on your desktop and run your DNS requests through it for ease of use and you can verify it. Not sure why they're so hesitant to inform their subscribers of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit 3: Tested on both a Debian 10 and Ubuntu desktop. I'm not esteemed NetSec researcher and I'm not setting up a 100 different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>todsacerdoti</dc:creator>
<og:title>Brave Browser leaks your Tor / Onion service requests through DNS.</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://ramble.pw/f/privacy/2387/brave-browser-leaks-your-tor-onion-service-requests-through</og:url>
<og:image>https://ramble.pw/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ramble.pw/f/privacy/2387/brave-browser-leaks-your-tor-onion-service-requests-through</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook reported fake numbers to advertisers</title>
<link>https://news.yahoo.com/unsealed-court-document-claims-facebook-203236002.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.yahoo.com/unsealed-court-document-claims-facebook-203236002.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;D(ib) Mt(2px) Mb(4px) C($c-fuji-grey-m)&quot;&gt;TipRanks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;C($c-fuji-grey-m) Fw(600) Fz(16px) M(0) Mb(5px) Lh(1.25em) Trs(colorTransition) item-hover-trigger:h_C($titleHoverColor)&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;Td(n) C($inherit) LineClamp(2,45px) D(f) js-content-viewer rapidnofollow&quot; data-uuid=&quot;cc540c3f-3ebd-31d1-aec9-312db9e5ece2&quot; href=&quot;https://news.yahoo.com/3-stocks-flashing-signs-strong-181846997.html&quot; data-ylk=&quot;elm:hdln;itc:0;pos:1;sec:strm;subsec:moreforyou;cpos:24;ct:story;g:cc540c3f-3ebd-31d1-aec9-312db9e5ece2&quot; data-hosted-type=&quot;HOSTED&quot; data-wf-caas-prefetch=&quot;1&quot; data-wf-caas-uuid=&quot;cc540c3f-3ebd-31d1-aec9-312db9e5ece2&quot;&gt;3 Stocks Flashing Signs of Strong Insider Buying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;M(0) C($summaryColor) Fz(14px) Lh(1.43em) LineClamp(3,60px)&quot;&gt;For an individual investor to beat the market, you need an edge. Investing strategies come in different forms and you can rely on several factors to achieve the end goal of strong returns. Be it following analyst ratings, upcoming catalysts or recognizing the latest market moving trends. There is another option: following the signal from those in the know – the corporate insiders. These are the company officers whose positions give them both access to frequently privileged information on business plans and finances and the experience necessary to translate that into smart stock trades. And better yet – they are not wholly free actors. Being responsible to shareholders and Boards of Directors for company profits, these insiders cannot use their inside knowledge for selfish purposes. Which means that following their stock trades, especially of their own companies, can be a viable investment strategy. Fortunately, federal regulations require that the insiders make their inside trades public – to keep the playing field level. To make that search easier, the TipRanks Insiders’ Hot Stocks tool gets the footwork started – identifying stocks that have seen informative moves by insiders, highlighting several common strategies used by the insiders, and collecting the data all in one place. We’ve picked three stocks with recent informative buys to show how the data works for you. Calix, Inc. (CALX) The first stock we're looking at is Calix, a cloud computing tech company. Calix follows a subscription model, offering cloud software, systems, platforms, services, and solutions to the communications industry. Calix’s products give the customers real-time data and data insights into their end-users, allowing them to more efficiently monetize their business and customer interactions. Calix, like many high-tech software platform companies, offers a system that can streamline operations – a vital advantage in today’s expanding remote work climate. The company’s revenues reflect the growth-oriented environment: the top line showed year-over-year growth in each quarter of 2020, with the most recent, Q4, coming in at $170 million being the best of the past two years. EPS, at 37 cents, was up 15% from Q3, and was positive for the second quarter in a row – a feat the company had been unable to achieve over the past two years. With a background like that, it’s no wonder that this stock is seeing insider buying. The most recent purchase is from Board member Donald Listwin, who bought up 20,000 shares, shelling out almost $715,000. 5-star analyst Paul Silverstein, of Cowen, notes that Calix has adopted an age-old strategy for beating the forecasts: “4Q20 fuels our view that near- and long-term earnings power and cash flow continue to be significantly greater than what Street has modeled… we respectfully note that CALX has established a clear pattern of appropriately and admirably taking a highly conservative stance as to risk assessment and, concomitantly, under-promising and over-delivering.” Silverstein clearly likes Calix’s approach, and he rates the stock an Outperform (i.e. Buy). On top of this, the analyst gives the stock a $45 price target, which implies a one-year upside of 23%. (To watch Silverstein’s track record, click here) What does the rest of the Street think? Looking at the consensus breakdown, opinions from other analysts are more spread out. 3 Buys and 2 Holds add up to a Moderate Buy consensus. In addition, the $37.40 average price target indicates a modest upside from current levels. (See CALX stock analysis on TipRanks) DXC Technology Company (DXC) Founded in 2017, in part as a spin-off from Hewlett Packard Enterprises, DXC is a leader in the business-to-business (B2B) IT field. The company’s products allow global companies to run their critical systems and ops efficiently, with security and scalability at a variety of levels. DXC’s enterprise tech enhances performance and competitiveness, and therefore the customer experience. The company has been seeing a dropoff in revenues over the past two years. It saw $19.5 billion in revenues for calendar year 2020, but is on track come in at ~$18 billion for fiscal 2021. The most recent quarter reported, fiscal 3Q21, showed $4.29 billion at the top line, falling 14.6% year over year. However, earnings, at $4.29, were far stronger than the 80-cent and 96-cent losses reported in the previous two quarters. Despite the falling revenues, the company has maintained its dividend, paying out 21 cents per common share over the past year, for a current yield of 3.2%. Looking at the recent insider trades, we see that Board member Raul Fernandez made two purchases this month, buying up 11,443. Fernandez paid nearly $300,00 for the new shares. In a comprehensive review of DXC, RBC analyst Daniel Perlin, rated 5-stars at TipRanks, writes: “We believe that FQ3/21’s results provided proof points that DXC’s transformation is progressing. In terms of customer focus, we note that revenue in the quarter increased 3.1% q/q and 1.7%... the second quarter in a row of sequential improvement…” Perlin went on to list several reasons for his bullish thesis: “1) management succeeding on its strategic plan and achieving its FY22 targets; 2) DXC evolving into an at-scale digital / new technology player, which should help offset declines in traditional solutions; and 3) valuation is attractive relative to peers, especially given potential upside to synergy targets.” Perlin uses these comments to support an Outperform (i.e. Buy) rating on DXC, and a $38 price target that indicates room for a robust 46% upside in the next 12 months. (To watch Perlin’s track record, click here) The Wall Street analysts are taking a range of views on this stock, as shown by the 10 recent reviews – which include 4 Buys and 6 Holds. Added up, it comes out to a Moderate Buy analyst consensus rating. The average price target, at $31, implies a 19% one-year upside from the current trading price of $26.06. (See DXC stock analysis on TipRanks) Northern Oil and Gas (NOG) Last but not least is Northern Oil and Gas, a highly localized hydrocarbon explorer, with assets in the states of Montana and North Dakota, specifically, the Williston Basin. NOG owns a large acreage footprint in the region, holding title to the lands on which developers will drill and complete oil and gas wells. This year, NOG has made two moves to increase its operating capital. The second move was announced on February 8 – an offering of senior notes at 8.125%, due in 2028. Proceeds are to be used to repay various outstanding debts and interest obligations, and then to help fund acquisition of new natural gas assets. The new land acquisitions targeted are in the Appalachian region, and will mark a true expansion for Northern Oil and Gas. The first capital move, however, is more interesting for this current article. On February 4, the company announced that it was putting 12.5 million shares of common stock on the market, at a price of $9.75 per share. Capital raised will be used first to fund the Appalachian Basin land buy, and then to repay debt and fund general operations – these are standard conditions on this type of capital drive. Company Board member Stuart Lasher bought 25,000 shares of NOG just a few days after the public stock offering was announced. The recent bloc of shares was picked up for $243,750. RBC’s Scott Hanold is clearly bullish on this company’s expansion to a new region, writing, “NOG's Appalachian acquisition was strategic by accelerating leverage reduction, balance sheet clean-up, and diversifying its asset and commodity footprints. The move into the Marcellus gas play underpins management's aptitude to focus on generating the best economic returns…” Hanold rates NOG an Outperform (i.e. Buy), and his $15 price target suggests the stock has room for 37% growth this year. (To watch Hanold’s track record, click here) With 4 recent reviews, all Buys, the Strong Buy analyst consensus rating here is unanimous. Northern’s shares are priced at $10.99 and they have an average price target of $14.75, indicating that the stock has a 34% one-year upside potential. (See NOG stock analysis on TipRanks) To find good ideas for stocks trading at attractive valuations, visit TipRanks’ Best Stocks to Buy, a newly launched tool that unites all of TipRanks’ equity insights. Disclaimer: The opinions expressed in this article are solely those of the featured analysts. The content is intended to be used for informational purposes only. It is very important to do your own analysis before making any investment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 14:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>elorant</dc:creator>
<og:title>Unsealed court document claims Facebook 'knew for years' that a metric was inflated and ignored an employee warning to avoid a revenue hit</og:title>
<og:url>https://news.yahoo.com/unsealed-court-document-claims-facebook-203236002.html</og:url>
<og:description>Facebook executives &quot;took steps to conceal the problem&quot; with its inflated Potential Reach metric, the unredacted court document says.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s.yimg.com/uu/api/res/1.2/2ddf.vlAZuyTgpVUaOxCEw--~B/aD0xNTAwO3c9MjAwMDthcHBpZD15dGFjaHlvbg--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/business_insider_articles_888/faab7cc77c8a73be318a4eec4906558c</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.yahoo.com/unsealed-court-document-claims-facebook-203236002.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WhatsApp to move ahead with privacy update despite backlash</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/facebook-whatsapp-privacy-idUSL4N2KP0XY</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/facebook-whatsapp-privacy-idUSL4N2KP0XY</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-byline-container-3H6dy&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Byline-byline-1sVmo ArticleBody-byline-10B7D&quot;&gt;By &lt;span class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__black___2FN-Z TextLabel__serif___3lOpX Byline-author-2BSir&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reuters Staff&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-read-time-and-social-2VOIr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__gray___1V4fk TextLabel__small-all-caps-spaced-out___3O9H4 ReadTime-read-time-1s3CG ArticleBody-read-time-29pGN&quot;&gt;2 Min Read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Feb 18 (Reuters) - Facebook Inc’s WhatsApp said on Thursday it will go ahead with its controversial privacy policy update but will allow users to read it at “their own pace” and will also display a banner providing additional information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The messaging platform laid out fresh terms in January, aimed at increasing business transactions on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The policy update would allow owner Facebook and its subsidiaries collect user data, including their phone number and location, which sparked a global outcry and a rush of new users to competitors Telegram and Signal, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;WhatsApp then moved to delay the new policy launch to May from February and sought to clarify the update was focused on allowing users to message with businesses and would not affect personal conversations, which will continue to have end-to-end encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;In its latest blog post, WhatsApp said it will start reminding users to review and accept updates to keep using the messaging platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“We’ve also included more information to try and address concerns we’re hearing,” it added. (Reporting by Shubham Kalia in Bengaluru; Editing by Krishna Chandra Eluri)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 13:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sidcool</dc:creator>
<og:title>WhatsApp to move ahead with privacy update despite backlash</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook Inc's WhatsApp said on Thursday it will go ahead with its controversial privacy policy update but will allow users to read it at &quot;their own pace&quot; and will also display a banner providing additional information.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s1.reutersmedia.net/resources_v2/images/rcom-default.png?w=800</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/facebook-whatsapp-privacy-idUSL4N2KP0XY</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/facebook-whatsapp-privacy-idUSL4N2KP0XY</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“I will slaughter you”</title>
<link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2021/02/19/i-will-slaughter-you/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2021/02/19/i-will-slaughter-you/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;You might know that I’ve posted funny emails I’ve received on my blog several times in the past. The kind of emails people send me when they experience problems with some device they own (like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2018/02/16/why-is-your-email-in-my-car/&quot; data-type=&quot;post&quot; data-id=&quot;10856&quot;&gt;car&lt;/a&gt;) and they contact me because my email address happens to be visible somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People sometimes say I should get a different email address or use another one in the curl license file, but I’ve truly never had a problem with these emails, as they mostly remind me about the tough challenges the modern technical life bring to people and it gives me insights about what things that run curl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not all of these emails are “funny”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Category: not funny&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I received the following email&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-preformatted&quot;&gt;
From: Al Nocai &amp;lt;[redacted]@icloud.com&amp;gt;
Date: Fri, 19 Feb 2021 03:02:24 -0600
Subject: I will slaughter you
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open source maintainer since over twenty years, I know flame wars and personal attacks and I have a fairly thick skin and I don’t let words get to me easily. It took me a minute to absorb and realize it was actually meant as a direct physical threat. It found its ways through and got to me. This level of aggressiveness is not what I’m prepared for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attached in this email, there were seven images and no text at all. The images all look like screenshots from a phone and the first one is clearly showing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/curl/curl/blob/master/include/curl/multi.h&quot;&gt;source code I wrote&lt;/a&gt; and my copyright line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;295&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-15803&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://daniel.haxx.se/al/&quot;&gt;other images&lt;/a&gt; showed other source code and related build/software info of other components, but I couldn’t spot how they were associated with me in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No explanation, just that subject and the seven images and I was left to draw my own conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I presume the name in the email is made up and the email account is probably a throw-away one. The time zone used in the &lt;code&gt;Date:&lt;/code&gt; string might imply US &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.timeanddate.com/time/zones/cst&quot;&gt;central standard time&lt;/a&gt; but could of course easily be phony as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How I responded&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally I don’t respond to these confused emails because the distance between me and the person writing them is usually almost interplanetary. This time though, it was so far beyond what’s acceptable to me and in any decent society I couldn’t just let it slide. After I took a little pause and walked around my house for a few minutes to cool off, I wrote a really angry reply and sent it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a totally and completely utterly unacceptable email and it hurt me deep in my soul. You should be ashamed and seriously reconsider your manners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what your screenshots are supposed to show, but clearly something somewhere is using code I wrote. Code I have written runs in virtually every Internet connected device on the planet and in most cases the users download and use it without even telling me, for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly you don’t deserve my code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t expect that it will be read or make any difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update below, added after my initial post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Al Nocai’s response&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to my expectations above, he responded. It’s not even worth commenting but for transparency I’ll include it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I do not care. Your bullshit software was an attack vector that cost me a multimillion dollar defense project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your bullshit software has been used to root me and multiple others. I lost over $15k in prototyping alone from bullshit rooting to the charge arbitrators.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have now since October been sandboxed because of your bullshit software so dipshit google kids could grift me trying to get out of the sandbox because they are too piss poor to know shat they are doing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You know what I did to deserve that? I tried to develop a trade route in tech and establish project based learning methodologies to make sure kids aren’t left behind. You know who is all over those god damn files? You are. Its sickening. I got breached in Oct 2020 through federal server hijacking, and I owe a great amount of that to you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ive had to sit and watch as i reported:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;fireeye Oct/2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solarwinds Oct/2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zyxel Modem Breach Oct/2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multiple Sigover attack vectors utilizing favicon XML injection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;JS Stochastic templating utilizing comparison expressions to write to data registers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get strong armed by $50billion companies because i exposed bullshit malware&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And i was rooted and had my important correspondence all rerouted as some sick fuck dismantled my life with the code you have your name plastered all over. I cant even leave the country because of the situation; qas you have so effectively built a code base to shit all over people, I dont give a shit how you feel about this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You built a formula 1 race car and tossed the keys to kids with ego problems. Now i have to deal with Win10 0-days because this garbage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I lost my family, my country my friends, my home and 6 years of work trying to build a better place for posterity. And it has beginnings in that code. That code is used to root and exploit people. That code is used to blackmail people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So no, I don’t feel bad one bit. You knew exactly the utility of what you were building. And you thought it was all a big joke. Im not laughing. I am so far past that point now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;/- Al&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Al continues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nine hours after I first published this blog post , Al replied again with two additional emails. His third and forth emails to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Email 3:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://davidkrider.com/i-will-slaughter-you-daniel-haxx-se/&quot;&gt;https://davidkrider.com/i-will-slaughter-you-daniel-haxx-se/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Step up. You arent scaring me. What led me here? The 5th violent attempt on my life. Apple terms of service? gtfo, thanks for the platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amusingly he has found a blog post about my blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Email 4:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is the project: MOUT Ops Risk Analysis through Wide Band Em Spectrum analysis through different fourier transforms.&lt;br/&gt;You and whoever the fuck david dick rider is, you are a part of this.&lt;br/&gt;Federal server breaches-&lt;br/&gt;Accomplice to attempted murder-&lt;br/&gt;Fraud-&lt;br/&gt;just a few.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have talked to now: FBI FBI Regional, VA, VA OIG, FCC, SEC, NSA, DOH, GSA, DOI, CIA, CFPB, HUD, MS, Convercent, as of today 22 separate local law enforcement agencies calling my ass up and wasting my time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You and dick ridin’ dave are respinsible. I dont give a shit, call the cops. I cuss them out wheb they call and they all go silent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve kept his peculiar formatting and typos. In email 4 there was also a PDF file attached named &lt;code&gt;BustyBabes 4.pdf&lt;/code&gt;. It is apparently a 13 page document about the “NERVEBUS NERVOUS SYSTEM” described in the first paragraph as “NerveBus Nervous System aims to be a general utility platform that provides comprehensive and complex analysis to provide the end user with cohesive, coherent and “real-time” information about the environment it monitors.”. There’s no mention of curl or my name in the document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I don’t know the status of this document I will not share it publicly, but here’s a screenshot of the front page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot_2021-02-20-BustyBabes-4-pdf.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot_2021-02-20-BustyBabes-4-pdf.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-15823&quot; width=&quot;358&quot; height=&quot;462&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This topic on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26192025&quot;&gt;hacker news&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/lnhcrc/i_will_slaughter_you_daniel_stenberg_got_a_quite/&quot;&gt;reddit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have reported the threat to the Swedish police (where I live).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 11:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2021/02/19/i-will-slaughter-you/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to be more productive without forcing yourself</title>
<link>https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-be-productive-without-forcing-yourself</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-be-productive-without-forcing-yourself</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/work_bad_rect.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot; alt=&quot;How to be more productive without forcing yourself&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you could work more and be wildly productive. And the best thing about it? You wouldn’t need to force yourself to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people exactly like that who sit down and work without pushing themselves to do it. They even look forward to working. The good news is that you can learn to do it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people have a negative mindset about work. People see work as an annoyance that keeps them from doing whatever they really want to do. They also think that resting and having nothing to do is an ideal state they’d like to be in forever. This leads to thinking that you need to push yourself to work. You need to use willpower to get yourself to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s simple to understand where this attitude comes from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;People usually want things they don’t have and think that grass is greener on the other side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone talks about how work is hard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In comparison to dead-end or corporate jobs without impact or freedom, neverending leisure looks like paradise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In reality, most people who try to be in this nothing-to-do state for a long time become unhappy, depressed, and bored. Rich people who “made it” report how soon they become restless again. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/StopGaming/&quot;&gt;People who game all the time&lt;/a&gt; realize how empty it feels. Too much leisure isn’t satisfying for long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there is a certain group of people who work a lot and enjoy it. Let’s call this group &lt;em&gt;producers&lt;/em&gt;. By this, we don’t mean workaholics who escape from their whole life by working all the time. Producers have a healthy work-life balance. So what do they do that people who hate work don’t?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, they tend to think about work differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For them, work is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/what-is-a-positive-feedback-loop-and-why-it-matters&quot;&gt;a virtuous cycle of positive feedback loops&lt;/a&gt;. Producers see &lt;strong&gt;work as a source of meaning and satisfaction&lt;/strong&gt;. They see work as something that allows them to savor deserved leisure. They see rest as something that increases their life happiness and fuels their motivation towards work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, their work is usually:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Interesting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meaningful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well-defined&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you check at least 1 or 2 boxes somehow, something magical happens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don’t have to push yourself towards work anymore.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well-defined, meaningful, and especially interesting work is easy to look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-producers often think that these producers are lucky because they stumbled upon work like this. In reality, producers often go a long way to make their work fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to make work more interesting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the crucial factor in whether work gets done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to see any meaning in your work for it to be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the task is totally undefined, complex, and difficult, curiosity can carry you to its completion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how can you develop this curiosity towards work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to give the work a chance to become interesting. How? By combining these 3 steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. Have less exposure towards super fun things&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video games, surfing the internet, porn, alcohol, and drugs etc. make work significantly more difficult. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They establish a certain standard of mental stimulation. Anything that’s not super fun will seem boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/stimulation_standard.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot; alt=&quot;We develop a Stimulation Standard&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, work often falls in the “feels bad” category. In comparison to games or social media, work can feel uninteresting or annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/stimulation_work_distractions.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot; alt=&quot;Switching from distractions to work is hard&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might argue that there are people who work just fine even while drinking alcohol, playing video games etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, consider that there are two types of people: ones who can moderate their consumption and others who can’t. The latter society often describes as addicts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, if you’re addicted to any of the high-dopamine, low-effort activity, please quit it. At least temporarily so you can reestablish a healthy relationship to work. The more experienced we’re about the topic, the more obvious this is. There is no other way than to temporarily quit the addiction. If your vice is gaming, we’ve covered &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/should-i-quit-video-games&quot;&gt;video gaming addiction here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some can have a healthy relationship with, for example, gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, for some people gaming is kryptonite. Here are some signs that super-fun activities have a detrimental effect on your work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;You rush and half-ass everything else in order to get to your super-fun activity. When I (Mat) was addicted to gaming, everything during the day was half-assed so I could finally start playing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You keep postponing or forgetting everything that isn’t urgent in order to get to your super fun activity. You have this book that you want to read but you never get to actually reading it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your orderliness suffers once you start with the super fun activity. Most people who come back to gaming report how their sense of orderliness starts to depreciate rather quickly. Their room gets messy, they start skipping workouts, stop meal-prepping, start eating more junk food, stop organizing their days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the points above describe you, it might be time to quit your super fun activity. At least for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your brain is not constantly hyper-stimulated, it’s easier to find mundane activities like work or tidying more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. Get bored more often&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you get bored, everything else becomes more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t believe us? Try this little experiment. Turn everything off. Set a timer for 15 minutes. Sit on a chair and stare at a wall. Don’t move. Don’t consume any information. Don’t talk. Don’t write anything down. Just stare at the wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except for zen masters, most of us will become restless after a few minutes. Often, our brain starts dreaming and imagining things. For the first few minutes, you might feel alright, thinking about your day. However, after 5 or 10 minutes, you’ll be itching to do something, anything really. Suddenly, creating a website, writing an article, or drawing a picture sounds like more interesting, more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/stimulation_work_boredom.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot; alt=&quot;Switching from boredom to work is easier&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you feel like you never stop scrolling and consume content all the time, schedule a 15 minute boredom window for tomorrow right before you want to start working. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-use-boredom-to-procrastinate-less&quot;&gt;Use boredom strategically.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Dive deep into a topic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s fun when we can connect the dots. When we can draw new connections between ideas, we get a rush. &lt;em&gt;Oh, I can see how this historical event contributed to an uprising…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more connections we can draw within a topic, the more interested we become. This is what curiosity is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take the time to watch a documentary related to what you’re working on, read a book about it, or find a couple relevant articles. You’ll collect more dots to connect. You’ll see how everything fits together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you do feel like watching something or have a free evening, instead of watching random videos or reruns of old TV shows, steer your attention to something related to what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give yourself time to develop an interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to make work more meaningful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to feel motivated when you don't have a personal reason to do something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, “meaningful work” has become something of a buzzword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is trying to find meaning in their work. This can be wasted energy, especially if you work in a corporate or a dead-end job. We say this so you don’t dwell on it and don’t feel frustrated because you can’t figure out how to save the world by doing what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, whatever your work is, you can make it meaningful enough to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you have to study for an exam. You don’t find this particular class enjoyable. If you remind yourself why you chose to take the class and why studying is important for you, you will have an easier time persuading yourself to push through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact is that some things simply need to be done. It's better if you find a compelling and personal reason to do them and get them over with as soon as possible, instead of putting them off forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When something is boring, ask yourself: Why do I need to do this? Find and reinforce the why behind the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to make work well-defined&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a recipe that tells you step-by-step how to cook a meal, it is usually quite easy to follow. You know exactly where to start and how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s creative work, this often isn’t the case. There are no recipes for the work we need to do, or they don’t make the work any easier because the recipe would be too complex to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we often hamper our enthusiasm towards work by ourselves. How often do you find yourself with vague and unhelpful to-dos like “write the essay” or “make a video.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many steps in “make a video” that this vague task definition only causes anxiety and procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We always say that it’s more difficult to start working than to keep working. Therefore we should make starting easier by defining well &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to begin and &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The better you can define how to start working, the easier it’ll be to actually do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, you do this in 3 steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Always define exactly where you’ll start&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means you write down the next physical action to take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you need to write an essay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next physical action is: Open the scientific study and start reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or: Create a document → Create a rough draft in the next 15 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want to start learning coding?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next physical action should be: Open freecodecamp.org → Start solving the first challenge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might sound silly to define the next physical action, but it isn’t. Finding it is easy, and you can do it immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the next physical action you need to take?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. Start with only having to work for 5/15 minutes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably don't feel like creating a 20 slide presentation right now from scratch, and then presenting it in 2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't feel like writing a whole final thesis on a topic you barely know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't feel like running a marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you might feel like looking up a couple pictures or articles for the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or feel like writing a paragraph or two before lunch break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or feel like taking a 1km walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are the small steps along the longer journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often underestimate the power of small steps, but they are essential because they help us get into the right routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you start running a couple miles every other day, you'll get familiar with the routine and then you'll naturally want to start increasing the distance. And eventually, you might get to running a full marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small steps, while they may seem tiny at the moment, are what will gradually lead to completing the longer journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a daunting task, try doing it for 5 or 15 minutes. Everyone can survive that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Your first draft can be sloppy - no expectations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have high expectations of your finished work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to write a great book, not just a good one. Or create a stellar artwork, or start a great business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All those expectations can put more pressure on you than you can bear. More pressure often equals more procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, you can escape those expectations by &lt;em&gt;starting deliberately badly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a chapter of a book by hand, without editing anything - you know that's not going to get published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start designing a poster with a sharpie, instead of the latest high-tech illustrating program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a bad first prototype for a product that you'd never ship to anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you know that you don't have to make the greatest thing ever right from the start, it's much easier to start. And then it's easier to continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you combine these tips, working will become much easier to do. You might even start looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you want to find work more interesting, cut super fun distractions, get bored more often, and give yourself time to develop an interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If possible, look for a meaning in your work. You don’t need to save the world, just think of a couple personal reasons to do what you need to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define exactly how you’ll start. What’s the next physical action you need to take?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apply this today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 10:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vitabenes</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-be-productive-without-forcing-yourself</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/work_bad_rect.png</og:image>
<og:title>How to be more productive without forcing yourself</og:title>
<og:description>Imagine you could work more and be wildly productive. And you wouldn’t need to force yourself to work.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-be-productive-without-forcing-yourself</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber drivers are workers not self employed, Supreme Court rules</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-56123668</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-56123668</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-56123668&quot;&gt;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-56123668&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26191364&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26191364&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 381&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 360&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 10:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BellLabradors</dc:creator>
<og:description>The decision could mean thousands of Uber drivers are set to receive minimum wage and holiday pay.</og:description>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13161/production/_117077187_img_7524.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Uber drivers are workers not self-employed, Supreme Court rules</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-56123668</og:url>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-56123668</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Monolith First (2015)</title>
<link>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/MonolithFirst.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://martinfowler.com/bliki/MonolithFirst.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As I hear stories about teams using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/articles/microservices.html&quot;&gt;microservices architecture&lt;/a&gt;, I've noticed a common pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Almost all the successful microservice stories have started with a monolith that got too big and was broken up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost all the cases where I've heard of a system that was built as a microservice system from scratch, it has ended up in serious trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This pattern has led many of my colleagues to argue that &lt;strong&gt;you shouldn't start a new project with microservices, even if you're sure your application will be big enough to make it worthwhile.&lt;/strong&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fullPhoto&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full-size&quot; src=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/images/microservice-verdict/path.png&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microservices are a useful architecture, but even their advocates say that using them incurs a significant &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/MicroservicePremium.html&quot;&gt;MicroservicePremium&lt;/a&gt;, which means they are only useful with more complex systems. This premium, essentially the cost of managing a suite of services, will slow down a team, favoring a monolith for simpler applications. This leads to a powerful argument for a monolith-first strategy, where you should build a new application as a monolith initially, even if you think it's likely that it will benefit from a microservices architecture later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first reason for this is classic &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/Yagni.html&quot;&gt;Yagni&lt;/a&gt;. When you begin a new application, how sure are you that it will be useful to your users? It may be hard to scale a poorly designed but successful software system, but that's still a better place to be than its inverse. As we're now recognizing, often the best way to find out if a software idea is useful is to build a simplistic version of it and see how well it works out. During this first phase you need to prioritize speed (and thus cycle time for feedback), so the premium of microservices is a drag you should do without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second issue with starting with microservices is that they only work well if you come up with good, stable boundaries between the services - which is essentially the task of drawing up the right set of &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/BoundedContext.html&quot;&gt;BoundedContexts&lt;/a&gt;. Any refactoring of functionality between services is much harder than it is in a monolith. But even experienced architects working in familiar domains have great difficulty getting boundaries right at the beginning. By building a monolith first, you can figure out what the right boundaries are, before a microservices design brushes a layer of treacle over them. It also gives you time to develop the &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/MicroservicePrerequisites.html&quot;&gt;MicroservicePrerequisites&lt;/a&gt; you need for finer-grained services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-card&quot; readability=&quot;26.697969543147&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/microservices&quot;&gt;Microservices Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot; readability=&quot;31.802139037433&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;card-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/microservices/microservices-sq.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
My colleagues and I have been writing about microservices since they first hit the radar of the software world. This guide page has articles on when to use microservices, the practices you should have in place as you begin, how to test them effectively, and how to decompose a monolith.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've heard different ways to execute a monolith-first strategy. The logical way is to design a monolith carefully, paying attention to modularity within the software, both at the API boundaries and how the data is stored. Do this well, and it's a relatively simple matter to make the shift to microservices. However I'd feel much more comfortable with this approach if I'd heard a decent number of stories where it worked out that way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more common approach is to start with a monolith and gradually peel off microservices at the edges. Such an approach can leave a substantial monolith at the heart of the microservices architecture, but with most new development occurring in the microservices while the monolith is relatively quiescent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another common approach is to just replace the monolith entirely. Few people look at this as an approach to be proud of, yet there are advantages to building a monolith as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/SacrificialArchitecture.html&quot;&gt;SacrificialArchitecture&lt;/a&gt;. Don't be afraid of building a monolith that you will discard, particularly if a monolith can get you to market quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another route I've run into is to start with just a couple of coarse-grained services, larger than those you expect to end up with. Use these coarse-grained services to get used to working with multiple services, while enjoying the fact that such coarse granularity reduces the amount of inter-service refactoring you have to do. Then as boundaries stabilize, break down into finer-grained services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the bulk of my contacts lean toward the monolith-first approach, it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/articles/dont-start-monolith.html&quot;&gt;by no means unanimous&lt;/a&gt;. The counter argument says that starting with microservices allows you to get used to the rhythm of developing in a microservice environment. It takes a lot, perhaps too much, discipline to build a monolith in a sufficiently modular way that it can be broken down into microservices easily. By starting with microservices you get everyone used to developing in separate small teams from the beginning, and having teams separated by service boundaries makes it much easier to scale up the development effort when you need to. This is especially viable for system replacements where you have a better chance of coming up with stable-enough boundaries early. Although the evidence is sparse, I feel that you shouldn't start with microservices unless you have reasonable experience of building a microservices system in the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't feel I have enough anecdotes yet to get a firm handle on how to decide whether to use a monolith-first strategy. These are early days in microservices, and there are relatively few anecdotes to learn from. So anybody's advice on these topics must be seen as tentative, however confidently they argue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;furtherReading&quot; readability=&quot;6.4827586206897&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam Newman &lt;a href=&quot;http://samnewman.io/blog/2015/04/07/microservices-for-greenfield/&quot;&gt;describes a case study&lt;/a&gt; of a team considering using microservices on a greenfield project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;
I stole much of this thinking from my coleagues: James Lewis, Sam Newman, Thiyagu Palanisamy, and Evan Bottcher. Stefan Tilkov's comments on an earlier draft played a pivotal role in clarifying my thoughts. Chad Currie created the lovely glyphy dragons. Steven Lowe, Patrick Kua, Jean Robert D'amore, Chelsea Komlo, Ashok Subramanian, Dan Siwiec, Prasanna Pendse, Kief Morris, Chris Ford, and Florian Sellmayr discussed drafts on our internal mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 07:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>asyrafql</dc:creator>
<og:title>bliki: MonolithFirst</og:title>
<og:url>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/MonolithFirst.html</og:url>
<og:description>Going directly to a microservices architecture is risky, so consider building a monolithic system first. Split to microservices when, and if, you need it.</og:description>
<og:image>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/images/microservice-verdict/path.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/MonolithFirst.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>