<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Elon Musk Deletes Own, SpaceX and Tesla Facebook Pages After #deletefacebook</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/23/elon-musk-deletes-own-spacex-and-tesla-facebook-pages-after-deletefacebook/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/23/elon-musk-deletes-own-spacex-and-tesla-facebook-pages-after-deletefacebook/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/person/elon-musk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;person&quot; data-entity=&quot;elon-musk&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt; apparently wasn’t aware that his company SpaceX had a Facebook page. The &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/space-exploration-technologies/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;space-exploration-technologies&quot;&gt;SpaceX&lt;/a&gt; and Tesla CEO has responded to a comment on Twitter calling for him to take down the SpaceX, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/tesla-motors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;tesla-motors&quot;&gt;Tesla&lt;/a&gt; and Elon Musk official pages in support of the #deletefacebook movement by first acknowledging he didn’t know one existed, and then following up with promises that he would indeed take them down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’s done just that, as the &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/space-exploration-technologies/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;space-exploration-technologies&quot;&gt;SpaceX&lt;/a&gt; Facebook page is now gone, after having been live earlier today (as you can see from the screenshot included taken at around 12:10 PM ET).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout alignnone size-full wp-image-1611250&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/screen-shot-2018-03-23-at-12-10-17-pm.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;1066&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of this publishing, going to any of the above pages directs you to a message saying “Sorry, this content isn’t available right now” instead. That’s a quick turnaround, since Musk seems only to have found out these pages existed about 20 minutes prior to his taking them all offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout alignnone size-full wp-image-1611258&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/screen-shot-2018-03-23-at-12-19-54-pm.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;448&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk also responded to another comment on Twitter regarding his own and his companies’ prolific use of Instagram, which is of course owned by Facebook. The prolific entrepreneur &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/977213864969256960&quot;&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt; that Instagram was “borderline,” since FB’s “influence is slowly creeping in,” but it seems like he’s okay with maintaining that presence for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to their deletion, both the SpaceX and Tesla pages had over 2.6 million Likes and Follows, and super high engagement rates. You have to wonder whether Musk’s social media management employees cried a little when these went down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout alignnone size-full wp-image-1611263&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/screen-shot-2018-03-23-at-12-10-24-pm.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;1017&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 16:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>middle1</dc:creator>
<og:title>Elon Musk deletes own, SpaceX and Tesla Facebook pages after #deletefacebook</og:title>
<og:description>Elon Musk apparently wasn’t aware that his company SpaceX had a Facebook page. The SpaceX and Tesla CEO has responded to a comment on Twitter calling for him to take down the SpaceX, Tesla and Elon Musk official pages in support of the #deletefacebook movement by first acknowledging he didn&amp;#…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/489749988.jpg?w=599</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/03/23/elon-musk-deletes-own-spacex-and-tesla-facebook-pages-after-deletefacebook/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/23/elon-musk-deletes-own-spacex-and-tesla-facebook-pages-after-deletefacebook/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Congrats Dropbox</title>
<link>https://blog.ycombinator.com/congratsdropbox/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.ycombinator.com/congratsdropbox/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote Dropbox their first investment check on June 26, 2007. What strikes me as I look at a copy of the check is that Drew and Arash must have been fairly effective at getting all their incorporation paperwork completed. I often had to chase startups well into July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little did I know back then what a momentous check this one would be: that 11 years later, Dropbox would be the first Y Combinator company to go public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could say that Paul, Robert, Trevor and I knew this would be one of the big ones when we interviewed Drew and Arash on April 21, 2007. They were the first interview of the day, at 8:30am. Though it was a long time ago, I remember we all agreed that they seemed good, and it was an easy decision to fund them. Trevor had already looked at the software and was impressed by it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d met Drew the year before. He’d been Adam Smith’s big brother in MIT’s Phi Delta Theta fraternity. Adam was a founder of Xobni, which was in the Summer ’06 batch, and he’d brought Drew with him as a guest to a YC dinner. We also met Drew at YC’s Startup School in California in March 2007. He came to the afterparty at our house and showed us an early prototype of Dropbox. I remember him being likeable, earnest, and very energetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Drew applied to YC, he applied as a single founder. After we invited him to interviews, Paul sent him an email suggesting he’d be better off with a cofounder. By interviews, a few weeks later, he’d found Arash. That worked out well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drew and Arash spent the summer of 2007 writing code. In those days there were a lot of file storage and syncing services, but none of them worked very well. The Dropbox founders were determined from the very beginning to win by making a product that was better than anything else. They used their batchmates, and us, as their guinea pigs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6227.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1459&quot; height=&quot;1094&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1102399&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6227.jpg 1459w, https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6227-300x225.jpg 300w, https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6227-768x576.jpg 768w, https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6227-1024x768.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1459px) 100vw, 1459px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Summer 2007 Y Combinator Batch – Jessica Sitting with Dropbox Cofounder, Arash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had Demo Day at our Cambridge office in August. For the first few years, we remembered each Demo Day by the disaster that happened during it. This was the Demo Day when our air conditioning system broke during a heat wave. We had to rent portable air conditioners, which took up huge amounts of space and did little to cool off our little oven of a building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, Drew gave an excellent pitch. It’s not easy to make file syncing look exciting, but Paul thought of a way: he suggested Drew delete his Demo Day presentation in the middle of giving it, and then recover it from Dropbox and keep going. Usually we don’t suggest gags like this during pitches, but this one made people pay attention. I think even Drew was not 100% sure it would work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1102398&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6169.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1459&quot; height=&quot;1094&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1102398&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6169.jpg 1459w, https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6169-300x225.jpg 300w, https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6169-768x576.jpg 768w, https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6169-1024x768.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1459px) 100vw, 1459px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Drew Presenting at Demo Day in Mountain View. Arash driving the slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dropbox impressed investors in Boston. It just didn’t impress them enough to write a check. We used to do one Demo Day in Boston in the summer, then fly everyone out to Silicon Valley to do another there a week later. So Boston investors had an entire week before any Silicon Valley investors saw Dropbox, and not one of them made a move. I think the party line was that “the space was too crowded.” Drew and Arash presented in our Mountain View Office on August 16, raised money from Sequoia, and moved to San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next year, Drew and Arash continued to improve their product, still using the YC alumni as their early adopters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-23-at-3.59.17-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1944&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1102404&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-23-at-3.59.17-PM.png 1944w, https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-23-at-3.59.17-PM-300x67.png 300w, https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-23-at-3.59.17-PM-768x171.png 768w, https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-23-at-3.59.17-PM-1024x228.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1944px) 100vw, 1944px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Year after year, I’ve seen Drew and Arash grow Dropbox into a bigger and more successful company. And I’ve become prouder and prouder of them as they continue to refine their original vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is a big milestone for YC. When we launched 13 years ago, we never imagined that a company that we’d funded would one day go public. We are so proud of Drew and Arash and the Dropbox team!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 15:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:title>Congrats Dropbox!</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.ycombinator.com/congratsdropbox/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>I wrote Dropbox their first investment check, on June 26, 2007. Little did I know back then what a momentous check this one would be: that 11 years later, Dropbox would be the first Y Combinator company to go public.</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_6227.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.ycombinator.com/congratsdropbox/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Listening for illegal logging chainsaws using TensorFlow</title>
<link>https://www.blog.google/topics/machine-learning/fight-against-illegal-deforestation-tensorflow/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.blog.google/topics/machine-learning/fight-against-illegal-deforestation-tensorflow/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rfcx.org/home.html&quot;&gt;Rainforest Connection&lt;/a&gt; is using technology to protect the rainforest. Founder and CEO Topher White shares how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/&quot;&gt;TensorFlow,&lt;/a&gt; Google’s open-source machine learning framework, aids in their efforts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, growing up in the 80s and 90s, the phrase “Save the Rainforest” was a directive that barely progressed over the years. The appeal was clear, but the threat was abstract and distant. And the solution (if there was one) seemed difficult to grasp. Since then, other worries—even harder to grasp in their immediacy and scope—have come to dominate our conversations: climate change, as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many of us believe that technology has a crucial role to play in fighting climate change, but few are as aware that “Saving the Rainforest” and fighting climate change are nearly one and the same. By the numbers, destruction of forests accounts for nearly one-fifth of all greenhouse gas emissions every year. And in the tropical rainforest deforestation accelerated on the heels of rampant logging—up to 90 percent of which is done illegally and under the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stopping illegal logging and protecting the world’s rainforests may be the fastest, cheapest way for humanity to slow climate change. And who’s best suited to protect the rainforest? The locals and the indigenous tribes that have lived there for generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rainforest Connection is a group of engineers and developers focused on building technology to help locals—like the Tembé tribe from central Amazon—protect their land, and in the process, protect the rest of us from the effects of climate change. Chief Naldo Tembé reached out to me a couple years ago seeking to collaborate on ways technology could help stop illegal loggers from destroying their land. Together, we embarked on an ambitious plan to address this issue using recycled cell phones and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team has built the world’s first scalable, real-time detection and alert system for logging and environmental conservation in the rainforest. Building hardware that will survive in the rainforest is challenging, but we’re using what’s already there: the trees. We’ve hidden modified smartphones powered with solar panels—called “Guardian” devices—in trees in threatened areas, and continuously monitor the sounds of the forest, sending all audio up to our cloud-based servers over the standard, local cell-­phone network.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 14:19:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dgacmu</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The fight against illegal deforestation with TensorFlow</og:title>
<og:description>Rainforest Connection founder and CEO Topher White shares how TensorFlow, Google’s open-source machine learning framework, aids in their efforts.</og:description>
<og:image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/SearchOn_Brazil_1896_1.max-2800x2800.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.blog.google/topics/machine-learning/fight-against-illegal-deforestation-tensorflow/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.blog.google/topics/machine-learning/fight-against-illegal-deforestation-tensorflow/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Police chief said Uber victim “came from the shadows” – don’t believe it</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/03/police-chief-said-uber-victim-came-from-the-shadows-dont-believe-it/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/03/police-chief-said-uber-victim-came-from-the-shadows-dont-believe-it/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kaufman_tempe-800x445.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kaufman_tempe.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;1417&quot; data-width=&quot;2549&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; A frame from Brian Kaufman's video shows the spot where Elaine Herzberg was killed.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Brian Kaufman&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;217 posters participating, including story author.&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/03/police-chief-said-uber-victim-came-from-the-shadows-dont-believe-it/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;619&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday night, an Uber self-driving car &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/03/uber-self-driving-car-hits-and-kills-pedestrian/&quot;&gt;killed 49-year-old Elaine Herzberg&lt;/a&gt; in Tempe, Arizona. A key argument in Uber's defense has been that the road was so dark that even an attentive driver would not have spotted Herzberg in the seconds before the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herzberg &quot;came from the shadows right into the roadway,&quot; Tempe police chief Sylvia Moir &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sfchronicle.com/business/article/Exclusive-Tempe-police-chief-says-early-probe-12765481.php&quot;&gt;told the &lt;em&gt;San Francisco Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Monday. &quot;The driver said it was like a flash.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-22-at-10.34.27-PM-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-22-at-10.34.27-PM.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-22-at-10.34.27-PM-980x470.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-22-at-10.34.27-PM-1440x691.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1280821&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This is one of the first frames of the Uber dashcam video where Elaine Herzberg is visible. Notice that you can faintly see a white sign to the far right of the image. This sign is much more clearly visible in videos taken by YouTubers.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kaufman_tempe-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kaufman_tempe.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kaufman_tempe-980x545.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kaufman_tempe-1440x801.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1280929&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A frame from Brian Kaufman's video shows the spot where Elaine Herzberg was killed.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Brian Kaufman&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/black_tempe-150x150.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/black_tempe.png&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/black_tempe-980x545.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/black_tempe-1440x801.png 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1280967&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A frame from Dana Black's video shows a spot slightly further back (Black's video becomes unfocused at the exact spot corresponding to the other two screenshots).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When police &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/03/video-uber-driver-looks-down-for-seconds-before-fatal-crash/&quot;&gt;released footage from the Uber vehicle's onboard camera&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday, it seemed to somewhat support this view. In the video, Herzberg's feet become visible only about 1.4 seconds before the final frame of the video. Prior to that point, she appears shrouded in shadow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then people in the Tempe area started making their own videos—videos that give a dramatically different impression of that section of roadway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CRW0q8i3u6E?start=0&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Mill Ave. at night.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this nighttime video, posted to YouTube by Brian Kaufman on Wednesday, the scene of the crash can be seen around 0:33. Features at the sides of the road—including curbs, signs, and bushes—are clearly visible. No pedestrians walk into the road during the video, but it seems clear that Herzberg would have been visible much earlier if the Uber video had been taken with this camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1XOVxSCG8u0?start=0&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Mill Ave. at night.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another YouTuber, Dana Black, posted this video. His camera work isn't as good as Kaufman's—the video is blurry and he doesn't hold his camera steady. But his video supports the same basic conclusion. &quot;It's not as dark as that video made it look,&quot; Black says in the video as he drives past the point in the road where Herzberg was hit (around 0:33). &quot;My footage is from my Pixel XL and looks pretty similar to real life,&quot; he writes in the YouTube description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be fair, there are a few other cars on the road in Black's video, which might be adding some illumination. But Kaufman's car appears to be the only vehicle on the road, and visibility is still much better than in Uber's dashcam video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Headlights are supposed to illuminate more than two seconds ahead of the car&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not surprising that the road was actually more brightly lit than the Uber video makes out. Think about it: the Uber car was going 38 miles per hour (61km/h), and people on pitch-black country roads drive faster than that all the time. That would be extremely reckless if—as the video implies—headlights can't illuminate the road two seconds ahead at that speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video implies that the Uber car's headlights had a range under 110 feet (33 meters). For comparison, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iihs.org/iihs/ratings/vehicle/v/volvo/xc90-4-door-suv/2017&quot;&gt;here's a diagram&lt;/a&gt; from the Insurance Institute for Highway Safety showing headlight ratings for the car in question, a Volvo XC90:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-23-at-9.24.48-AM.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot; data-height=&quot;1086&quot; data-width=&quot;1932&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-23-at-9.24.48-AM-640x360.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-23-at-9.24.48-AM-1280x720.png 2x&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;p&gt;IIHS shows the XC90 with a range just under 250 feet (76 meters) with &quot;low beams&quot; on. The car's headlights are rated poorly by the IIHS compared with other cars on the market. Still, 250 feet is more than 4 seconds of illumination for a car driving 38 miles per hour. If the Uber car's headlights really didn't illuminate Herzberg until less than two seconds before the crash, there was something seriously wrong with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more likely explanation is that the Uber vehicle's dashcam was poorly configured for nighttime recording, and so the video gives a misleading impression of how bright the scene was and how much warning the driver had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if it's true that the road were poorly lit, it's not clear if that would exonerate Uber. Uber's cars have lidar and radar sensors in addition to cameras, and those sensors don't require ambient light to function. So the vehicle should have spotted Herzberg even if the road was pitch black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, interior dashcam footage shows the driver looking down for nearly five seconds just before the accident—so she likely would have missed Herzberg no matter how good the illumination on the road was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Originally this story featured a generic IIHS diagram on headlight distance. But after it went up my colleague Jonathan Gitlin pointed me to an XC90-specific diagram. So I replaced the diagram and updated the paragraphs on either side accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 13:12:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>drabiega</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/03/police-chief-said-uber-victim-came-from-the-shadows-dont-believe-it/</og:url>
<og:title>Police chief said Uber victim “came from the shadows”—don’t believe it</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kaufman_tempe-760x380.png</og:image>
<og:description>YouTube videos give a different impression of the site of a deadly Uber crash.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/03/police-chief-said-uber-victim-came-from-the-shadows-dont-believe-it/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>C for All</title>
<link>https://plg.uwaterloo.ca/~cforall/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://plg.uwaterloo.ca/~cforall/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;jumbotron head jumboLocal&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;located at &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;125&quot; alt=&quot;University of Waterloo&quot; src=&quot;https://plg.uwaterloo.ca/~cforall/pic/UWlogo.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huawei.com/en&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;100&quot; alt=&quot;Huawei&quot; src=&quot;https://plg.uwaterloo.ca/~cforall/pic/Huawei_logo.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;CFAManual&quot; href=&quot;https://plg.uwaterloo.ca/~cforall/user.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cfa&quot;&gt;C∀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (C-for-all) is an open-source project with the goal of extending ISO C as a &lt;em&gt;non-object-oriented&lt;/em&gt; programing language. The purpose of the project is to engineer modern language features into C in an evolutionary rather than revolutionary way. &lt;a id=&quot;D&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;D&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;Go&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;Java&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a id=&quot;Rust&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rust_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; are examples of the revolutionary approach for modernizing C, resulting in a new language rather than an extension of C. &lt;a id=&quot;Cpp&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C++&quot;&gt;C++ 17&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;Cobol&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/COBOL&quot;&gt;Cobol 14&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a id=&quot;Fortran&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortran&quot;&gt;Fortran 15&lt;/a&gt; are examples of the evolutionary approach where modern language features are added and problems fixed within the framework of an existing language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to produce a backwards compatible version of C containing modern language features and fixing well known C problems. Without continued development of the language, C will be unable to cope with the needs of modern programming problems and programmers; as a result, it will fade into disuse. Considering the large body of existing C code and programmers, there is significant impetus to ensure C is transformed into a modern programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While C++ had similar goals, it has the disadvantages of multiple legacy design-choices (e.g., object-oriented) that cannot be changed, and active divergence from C in new versions, requiring significant effort and training to incrementally add C++ to a C-based project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;CFAMailingList&quot; href=&quot;https://lists.uwaterloo.ca/mailman/admindb/cforall&quot;&gt;Mailing List&lt;/a&gt; (internal only)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;CFADashboard&quot; href=&quot;http://plg2:8082/dashboard.html&quot;&gt;Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; (internal only)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;CFABugTrac&quot; href=&quot;http://plg2:8083/wiki&quot;&gt;Bug Tracker&lt;/a&gt; (internal only)&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 12:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>etrevino</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://plg.uwaterloo.ca/~cforall/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Medieval peasants got more vacation time than modern workers (2013)</title>
<link>http://blogs.reuters.com/great-debate/2013/08/29/why-a-medieval-peasant-got-more-vacation-time-than-you/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blogs.reuters.com/great-debate/2013/08/29/why-a-medieval-peasant-got-more-vacation-time-than-you/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.reuters.com/great-debate/files/2013/08/beach.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-23360&quot; title=&quot;Caitlin, an Australian tourist, enjoys the sun on a beach of the Croisette in Cannes&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.reuters.com/great-debate/files/2013/08/beach-300x180.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Life for the medieval peasant was certainly no picnic. His life was shadowed by fear of famine, disease and bursts of warfare. His diet and personal hygiene left much to be desired. But despite his reputation as a miserable wretch, you might envy him one thing: his vacations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plowing and harvesting were backbreaking toil, but the peasant enjoyed anywhere from eight weeks to half the year off. The Church, mindful of how to keep a population from rebelling, enforced &lt;a href=&quot;http://history-world.org/peasant.htm&quot;&gt;frequent mandatory holidays&lt;/a&gt;. Weddings, wakes and births might mean a week off quaffing ale to celebrate, and when wandering jugglers or sporting events came to town, the peasant expected time off for entertainment. There were labor-free Sundays, and when the plowing and harvesting seasons were over, the peasant got time to rest, too. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.csail.mit.edu/mac/users/rauch/worktime/hours_workweek.html&quot;&gt;economist Juliet Shor&lt;/a&gt; found that during periods of particularly high wages, such as 14th-century England, peasants might put in no more than 150 days a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the modern American worker? After a year on the job, she gets an average of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bls.gov/news.release/ebs.t05.htm&quot;&gt;eight vacation days&lt;/a&gt; annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t supposed to turn out this way: John Maynard Keynes, one of the founders of modern economics, made a famous &lt;a href=&quot;http://money.howstuffworks.com/five-day-weekend2.htm&quot;&gt;prediction&lt;/a&gt; that by 2030, advanced societies would be wealthy enough that leisure time, rather than work, would characterize national lifestyles. So far, that forecast is not looking good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened? Some cite the victory of the modern eight-hour a day, 40-hour workweek over the punishing 70 or 80 hours a 19th century worker spent toiling as proof that we’re moving in the right direction. But Americans have long since &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/americans-40-hour-work-week-not-enough-2011-6&quot;&gt;kissed the 40-hour workweek goodbye&lt;/a&gt;, and Shor’s examination of work patterns reveals that the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century was an aberration in the history of human labor. When workers fought for the eight-hour workday, they weren’t trying to get something radical and new, but rather to restore what their ancestors had enjoyed before industrial capitalists and the electric lightbulb came on the scene. Go back 200, 300 or 400 years and you find that most people did not work very long hours at all. In addition to relaxing during long holidays, the medieval peasant took his sweet time eating meals, and the day often included time for an afternoon snooze. “The tempo of life was slow, even leisurely; the pace of work relaxed,” notes Shor. “Our ancestors may not have been rich, but they had an abundance of leisure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; century, and the U.S. is the only advanced country with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2012/07/the-only-advanced-country-without-a-national-vacation-policy-its-the-us/259317/&quot;&gt;no national vacation policy whatsoever&lt;/a&gt;. Many American workers must keep on working through public holidays, and vacation days often go unused. Even when we finally carve out a holiday, many of us answer emails and “check in” whether we’re camping with the kids or trying to kick back on the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2012/08/no-vacation-nation-why-dont-americans-know-how-to-take-a-break/260759/&quot;&gt;blame the American worker&lt;/a&gt; for not taking what is her due. But in a period of consistently high unemployment, job insecurity and weak labor unions, employees may feel no choice but to accept the conditions set by the culture and the individual employer. In a world of “at will” employment, where the work contract can be terminated at any time, it’s not easy to raise objections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s true that the New Deal brought back some of the conditions that farm workers and artisans from the Middle Ages took for granted, but since the 1980s things have gone steadily downhill. With secure long-term employment slipping away, people jump from job to job, so seniority no longer offers the benefits of additional days off. The rising trend of hourly and part-time work, stoked by the Great Recession, means that for many, the idea of a guaranteed vacation is a dim memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, this cult of endless toil doesn’t really help the bottom line. &lt;a href=&quot;http://accounting.smartpros.com/x43420.xml&quot;&gt;Study&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lostgarden.com/2008/09/rules-of-productivity-presentation.html&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; shows that overworking reduces productivity. On the other hand, performance increases after a vacation, and workers come back with restored energy and focus. The longer the vacation, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://familiesandwork.org/site/newsroom/releases/2005overwork.html&quot;&gt;more relaxed and energized&lt;/a&gt; people feel upon returning to the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic crises give austerity-minded politicians excuses to talk of decreasing time off, increasing the retirement age and cutting into social insurance programs and safety nets that were supposed to allow us a fate better than working until we drop. In Europe, where workers average 25 to 30 days off per year, politicians like French President Francois Hollande and Greek Prime Minister Antonis Samaras are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-25/hollande-bids-adieu-to-eu-vacation-culture-as-crisis-lingers.html&quot;&gt;sending signals&lt;/a&gt; that the culture of longer vacations is coming to an end. But the belief that shorter vacations bring economic gains doesn’t appear to add up. According to the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) the Greeks, who face a horrible economy, work more hours than any other Europeans. In Germany, an economic powerhouse, workers rank second to last in number of hours worked. Despite more time off, German workers are the eighth most productive in Europe, while the long-toiling Greeks rank 24 out of 25 in productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond burnout, vanishing vacations make our relationships with families and friends suffer. Our health is deteriorating: &lt;a href=&quot;http://familiesandwork.org/site/newsroom/releases/2005overwork.html&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11020089&quot;&gt;higher risk of death&lt;/a&gt; are among the outcomes for our no-vacation nation. Some forward-thinking people have tried to reverse this trend, like progressive economist Robert Reich, who has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketplace.org/topics/economy/commentary/mandatory-extended-vacation-good-economy&quot;&gt;argued in favor&lt;/a&gt; of a mandatory three weeks off for all American workers. Congressman Alan Grayson proposed the Paid Vacation Act of 2009, but alas, the bill didn’t even make it to the floor of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Congress, its members seem to be the only people in America getting as much down time as the medieval peasant. They get &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.policymic.com/articles/38177/want-a-job-with-239-vacation-days-become-a-member-of-congress&quot;&gt;239 days off this year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PHOTO: Caitlin, an Australian tourist, enjoys the sun on a beach of the Croisette during a hot summer day in Cannes July 31, 2013. REUTERS/Eric Gaillard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 11:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fredrikaurdal</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why a medieval peasant got more vacation time than you</og:title>
<og:image>http://blogs.reuters.com/wp-content/themes/reuters_fb_150x150.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://blogs.reuters.com/great-debate/2013/08/29/why-a-medieval-peasant-got-more-vacation-time-than-you/</og:url>
<og:description>John Maynard Keynes, one of the founders of modern economics, made a famous prediction that by 2030, advanced societies would be wealthy enough that leisure time, rather than work, would characterize national lifestyles. So far, that forecast is not looking good.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blogs.reuters.com/great-debate/2013/08/29/why-a-medieval-peasant-got-more-vacation-time-than-you/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Downloaded my Facebook data and it has the call history with my partner’s mother</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/dylanmckaynz/status/976369275324678145</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/dylanmckaynz/status/976369275324678145</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;thanks for your work. I just uninstalled the Messenger app (android). My facebook zip had a bunch (not all, but heaps) of my contacts in that file. I don't have the FB app on phone. Not sure how this was gathered. No metadata, call history. Just contacts. insane.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 10:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bkfh</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/dylanmckaynz/status/976369275324678145</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>With SESTA/FOSTA, lawmakers failed to separate good intentions from bad law</title>
<link>https://www.eff.org//deeplinks/2018/03/how-congress-censored-internet</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eff.org//deeplinks/2018/03/how-congress-censored-internet</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Passing SESTA/FOSTA, Lawmakers Failed to Separate Their Good Intentions from Bad Law&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was a dark day for the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Senate just voted 97-2 to pass the Allow States and Victims to Fight Online Sex Trafficking Act (FOSTA, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/1865&quot;&gt;H.R. 1865&lt;/a&gt;), a bill that silences online speech by forcing Internet platforms to censor their users. As lobbyists and members of Congress applaud themselves for enacting a law tackling the problem of trafficking, let’s be clear: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/10/sex-trafficking-experts-say-sesta-wrong-solution&quot;&gt;Congress just made trafficking victims less safe&lt;/a&gt;, not more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The version of FOSTA that just passed the Senate combined an earlier version of FOSTA (what we call FOSTA 2.0) with the Stop Enabling Sex Traffickers Act (SESTA, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/senate-bill/1693&quot;&gt;S. 1693&lt;/a&gt;). The history of SESTA/FOSTA—a bad bill that turned into a worse bill and then was rushed through votes in both houses of Congress—is a story about Congress’ failure to see that its good intentions can result in bad law. It’s a story of Congress’ failure to listen to the constituents who’d be most affected by the laws it passed. It’s also the story of some players in the tech sector choosing to settle for compromises and half-wins that will put ordinary people in danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silencing Internet Users Doesn’t Make Us Safer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SESTA/FOSTA undermines &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/cda230&quot;&gt;Section 230&lt;/a&gt;, the most important law protecting free speech online. Section 230 protects online platforms from liability for some types of speech by their users. Without Section 230, the Internet would look very different. It’s likely that &lt;a href=&quot;https://230matters.com/letter.html&quot;&gt;many of today’s online platforms would never have formed&lt;/a&gt; or received the investment they needed to grow and scale—the risk of litigation would have simply been too high. Similarly, in absence of Section 230 protections, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.wikimedia.org/2017/11/09/cda-230-principles-wikipedia/&quot;&gt;noncommercial platforms like Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and the Internet Archive likely wouldn’t have been founded given the high level of legal risk involved with hosting third-party content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;The bill is worded so broadly that it could even be used against platform owners that don’t know that their sites are being used for trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/09/stop-sesta-section-230-not-broken&quot;&gt;Section 230 does not shield platforms from liability under federal criminal law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; Section 230 also doesn’t shield platforms across-the-board from liability under civil law: courts have allowed civil claims against online platforms when a platform directly contributed to unlawful speech. Section 230 strikes a careful balance between enabling the pursuit of justice and promoting free speech and innovation online: platforms can be held responsible for their own actions, and can still host user-generated content without fear of broad legal liability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SESTA/FOSTA upends that balance, opening platforms to new criminal and civil liability at the state and federal levels for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/09/stop-sesta-congress-doesnt-understand-how-section-230-works&quot;&gt;their users’ sex trafficking activities&lt;/a&gt;. The platform liability created by new Section 230 carve outs applies &lt;em&gt;retroactively&lt;/em&gt;—meaning the increased liability applies to trafficking that took place before the law passed. &lt;a href=&quot;/files/2018/03/19/doj-sesta.pdf&quot;&gt;The Department of Justice has raised concerns&lt;/a&gt; [.pdf] about this violating the Constitution’s Ex Post Facto Clause, at least for the criminal provisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill also expands existing federal criminal law to target online platforms where sex trafficking content appears. The bill is worded so broadly that it could even be used against platform owners that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/09/stop-sesta-amendments-federal-criminal-sex-trafficking-law-sweep-too-broadly&quot;&gt;don’t know that their sites are being used for trafficking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, SESTA/FOSTA expands federal prostitution law to cover those who use the Internet to “promote or facilitate prostitution.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;The Internet will become a less inclusive place, something that hurts all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to see the impact that this ramp-up in liability will have on online speech: facing the risk of ruinous litigation, online platforms will have little choice but to become much more restrictive in what sorts of discussion—and what sorts of users—they allow, censoring innocent people in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What forms that erasure takes will vary from platform to platform. For some, it will mean increasingly restrictive terms of service—banning sexual content, for example, or advertisements for legal escort services. For others, it will mean &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/03/how-fosta-will-get-hollywood-filters-theyve-long-wanted&quot;&gt;over-reliance on automated filters&lt;/a&gt; to delete borderline posts. No matter what methods platforms use to mitigate their risk, one thing is certain: when platforms choose to err on the side of censorship, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/09/stop-sesta-whose-voices-will-sesta-silence&quot;&gt;marginalized voices are censored disproportionately&lt;/a&gt;. The Internet will become a less inclusive place, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/10/south-dakota-civil-liberties-groups-urge-senator-thune-put-brakes-sesta&quot;&gt;something that hurts all of us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Big Tech Companies Don&lt;strong&gt;’&lt;/strong&gt;t Speak for Users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SESTA/FOSTA supporters boast that their bill has the support of the technology community, but it’s worth considering what they mean by “technology.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/blogs/policy/ibm-letter-sesta-human-trafficking/&quot;&gt;IBM&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.portman.senate.gov/public/index.cfm?p=press-releases&amp;amp;id=197B9C12-C83A-4106-A0C4-DFD0DAB7594B&quot;&gt;Oracle&lt;/a&gt;—companies whose business models don’t heavily rely on Section 230—were quick to jump onboard. Next came the Internet Association, a trade association representing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/11/internet-association-endorses-internet-censorship-bill&quot;&gt;world’s largest Internet companies&lt;/a&gt;, companies that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/09/google-will-survive-sesta-your-startup-might-not&quot;&gt;will certainly be able to survive SESTA&lt;/a&gt; while their smaller competitors struggle to comply with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those tech companies simply don’t speak for the Internet users who will be silenced under the law. And tragically, the people likely to be censored the most are trafficking victims themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SESTA/FOSTA Will Put Trafficking Victims in More Danger&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the SESTA/FOSTA debate, the bills’ proponents provided little to no evidence that increased platform liability would do anything to reduce trafficking. On the other hand, the bills’ opponents have presented a great deal of evidence that &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ericgoldman.org/archives/2017/08/how-section-230-helps-sex-trafficking-victims-and-sesta-would-hurt-them-guest-blog-post.htm&quot;&gt;shutting down platforms where sexual services are advertised exposes trafficking victims to more danger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom Network USA—the largest national network of organizations working to reduce trafficking in their communities—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2017/09/18/sestahearing-freedomnetwork.pdf&quot;&gt;spoke out early to express grave concerns&lt;/a&gt; [.pdf] that removing sexual ads from the Internet would also remove the best chance trafficking victims had of being found and helped by organizations like theirs as well as law enforcement agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reforming [Section 230] to include the threat of civil litigation could deter responsible website administrators from trying to identify and report trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that responsible website administration can make trafficking more visible—which can lead to increased identification. There are many cases of victims being identified online—and little doubt that without this platform, they would have not been identified. Internet sites provide a digital footprint that law enforcement can use to investigate trafficking into the sex trade, and to locate trafficking victims. When websites are shut down, the sex trade is pushed underground and sex trafficking victims are forced into even more dangerous circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom Network was far from alone. Since SESTA was introduced, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/12/internet-censorship-bills-wouldnt-help-catch-sex-traffickers&quot;&gt;many experts have chimed in to point out the danger that SESTA would put all sex workers in&lt;/a&gt;, including those who are being trafficked. Sex workers themselves have spoken out too, explaining how &lt;a href=&quot;https://theslot.jezebel.com/the-senates-anti-sex-trafficking-bill-is-a-disaster-for-1823704879&quot;&gt;online platforms have literally saved their lives&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/09/live-blog-senate-commerce-committee-discusses-sesta&quot;&gt;Why didn’t Congress bring those experts&lt;/a&gt; to its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/10/live-blog-house-discusses-section-230&quot;&gt;deliberations on SESTA/FOSTA&lt;/a&gt; over the past year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we can’t speculate on the agendas of the groups behind SESTA, we can study those same groups’ past advocacy work. Given that history, one could be forgiven for thinking that some of these groups see SESTA as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20170929/01242638309/campaigners-sesta-see-it-as-first-step-to-stomping-out-porn.shtml&quot;&gt;mere stepping stone to banning pornography from the Internet&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://injusticetoday.com/anti-online-trafficking-bills-advance-in-congress-despite-opposition-from-survivors-themselves-e741ea300307&quot;&gt;blurring the legal distinctions&lt;/a&gt; between &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melissagira/status/974304760353427456&quot;&gt;sex work and trafficking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all of Congress’ deliberations on SESTA, no one spoke to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180314/00004839422/sex-workers-survivors-raising-alarm-about-sesta-it-will-literally-put-their-lives-danger.shtml&quot;&gt;the experiences of the sex workers that the bill will push off of the Internet&lt;/a&gt; and onto the dangerous streets. It wasn’t surprising, then, when the House of Representatives presented its “alternative” bill, one that targeted those communities more directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;“Compromise” Bill Raises New Civil Liberties Concerns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/12/amended-version-fosta-would-still-silence-legitimate-speech-online&quot;&gt;the House Judiciary Committee unveiled&lt;/a&gt; its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/1865/text/rh?&quot;&gt;new revision of FOSTA&lt;/a&gt;. FOSTA 2.0 had the same inherent flaw that its predecessor had—attaching more liability to platforms for their users’ speech does nothing to fight the underlying criminal behavior of traffickers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, FOSTA 2.0 was an improvement: the bill was targeted only at platforms that intentionally facilitated prostitution, and so would affect a narrower swath of the Internet. But the damage it would do was much more blunt: it would expand federal prostitution law such that online platforms would have to take down any posts that could potentially be in support of &lt;em&gt;any sex work&lt;/em&gt;, regardless of whether there’s an indication of force or coercion, or whether minors were involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSTA 2.0 didn’t stop there. It criminalized using the Internet to “promote or facilitate” prostitution. Activists who work to reduce harm in the sex work community—by providing health information, for example, or sharing lists of dangerous clients—were rightly worried that prosecutors would attempt to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/40537286/fosta-backlash-how-the-anti-sex-trafficking-bill-could-harm-sex-workers&quot;&gt;use this law to put their work in jeopardy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, a few holdouts in the tech world believed that their best hope of stopping SESTA was to endorse a censorship bill that would do slightly less damage to the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They should have known it was a trap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SESTA/FOSTA: The Worst of Both Worlds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That brings us to last month, when a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/02/fosta-would-be-disaster-online-communities&quot;&gt;new bill combining SESTA and FOSTA&lt;/a&gt; was rushed through congressional procedure and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/02/house-vote-fosta-win-censorship&quot;&gt;overwhelmingly passed the House&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;When the Department of Justice is the group urging Congress not to expand criminal law and Congress does it anyway, something is very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thousands of you picked up your phone and called your senators, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/03/stop-sestafosta-dont-let-congress-censor-internet&quot;&gt;urging them to oppose the new Frankenstein bill&lt;/a&gt;. And you weren’t alone: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/03/dear-leader-mcconnell-dont-pass-fosta&quot;&gt;EFF&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/letter/aclu-vote-recommendation-congress-oppose-h-r-1865-allow-states-and-victims-fight-online-sex&quot;&gt;American Civil Liberties Union&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/blog/its-all-downsides-hybrid-fosta-sesta-hinders-law-enforcement-hurts-victims-and-speakers/&quot;&gt;Center for Democracy and Technology&lt;/a&gt;, and many other experts pleaded with Congress to recognize the dangers to free speech and online communities that the bill presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the Department of Justice wrote a letter &lt;a href=&quot;/files/2018/03/19/doj-sesta.pdf&quot;&gt;urging Congress not to go forward with the hybrid bill&lt;/a&gt; [.pdf]. The DOJ said that the expansion of federal criminal law in SESTA/FOSTA was simply unnecessary, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180227/15314039324/doj-tells-congress-sesta-fosta-will-make-it-more-difficult-to-catch-traffickers-house-votes-it-anyway.shtml&quot;&gt;could possibly undermine criminal investigations&lt;/a&gt;. When the Department of Justice is the group urging Congress not to expand criminal law and Congress does it anyway, something is very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming that the president signs it into law, SESTA/FOSTA is the most significant rollback to date of the protections for online speech in Section 230. We hope that it’s the last, but it may not be. Over the past year, we’ve seen more calls than ever to &lt;a href=&quot;http://foreignpolicy.com/2017/11/13/its-the-beginning-of-the-end-of-the-internets-legal-immunity/&quot;&gt;create new exceptions to Section 230&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, we will continue to fight back against proposals that undermine our right to speak and gather online. We hope you’ll stand with us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 06:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jakeogh</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How Congress Censored the Internet</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/03/how-congress-censored-internet</og:url>
<og:description>In Passing SESTA/FOSTA, Lawmakers Failed to Separate Their Good Intentions from Bad LawToday was a dark day for the Internet.The U.S. Senate just voted 97-2 to pass the Allow States and Victims to Fight Online Sex Trafficking Act (FOSTA, H.R. 1865), a bill that silences online speech by forcing...</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.eff.org/files/congress-action.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eff.org//deeplinks/2018/03/how-congress-censored-internet</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Responsibility Deflected, the CLOUD Act Passes</title>
<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/03/responsibility-deflected-cloud-act-passes</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/03/responsibility-deflected-cloud-act-passes</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE, March 23, 2018: President Donald Trump signed the $1.3 trillion government spending bill—which includes the CLOUD Act—into law Friday morning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People deserve the right to a better process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are the words of Jim McGovern, representative for Massachusetts and member of the House of Representatives Committee on Rules, when, after 8:00 PM EST on Wednesday, he and his colleagues were handed a 2,232-page bill to review and approve for a floor vote by the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the final pages of the bill—meant only to appropriate future government spending—lawmakers snuck in a separate piece of legislation that made no mention of funds, salaries, or budget cuts. Instead, this final, tacked-on piece of legislation will erode privacy protections around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/02/cloud-act-dangerous-expansion-police-snooping-cross-border-data&quot;&gt;This bill is the CLOUD Act&lt;/a&gt;. It was never reviewed or marked up by any committee in either the House or the Senate. It never received a hearing. It was robbed of a stand-alone floor vote because Congressional leadership decided, behind closed doors, to attach this un-vetted, unrelated data bill to the $1.3 trillion government spending bill. Congress has a professional responsibility to listen to the American people’s concerns, to represent their constituents, and to debate the merits and concerns of this proposal amongst themselves, and this week, they failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, the House approved the omnibus government spending bill, with the CLOUD Act attached, in a 256-167 vote. The Senate followed up late that night with a 65-32 vote in favor. All the bill requires now is the president’s signature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake—you spoke up. You emailed your representatives. You told them to protect privacy and to reject the CLOUD Act, including any efforts to attach it to must-pass spending bills. You did your part. It is Congressional leadership—negotiating behind closed doors—who failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this failure, U.S. and foreign police will have new mechanisms to seize data across the globe. Because of this failure, your private emails, your online chats, your Facebook, Google, Flickr photos, your Snapchat videos, your private lives online, your moments shared digitally between only those you trust, will be open to foreign law enforcement without a warrant and with few restrictions on using and sharing your information. Because of this failure, U.S. laws will be bypassed on U.S. soil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we wrote before, the CLOUD Act is a far-reaching, privacy-upending piece of legislation that will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enable foreign police to collect and wiretap people's communications from U.S. companies, without obtaining a U.S. warrant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow foreign nations to demand personal data stored in the United States, without prior review by a judge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the U.S. president to enter &quot;executive agreements&quot; that empower police in foreign nations that have weaker privacy laws than the United States to seize data in the United States while ignoring U.S. privacy laws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow foreign police to collect someone's data without notifying them about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empower U.S. police to grab any data, regardless if it's a U.S. person's or not, no matter where it is stored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, as we wrote before, this is how the CLOUD Act could work in practice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;London investigators want the private Slack messages of a Londoner they suspect of bank fraud. The London police could go directly to Slack, a U.S. company, to request and collect those messages. The London police would not necessarily need prior judicial review for this request. The London police would not be required to notify U.S. law enforcement about this request. The London police would not need a probable cause warrant for this collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predictably, in this request, the London police might also collect Slack messages written by U.S. persons communicating with the Londoner suspected of bank fraud. Those messages could be read, stored, and potentially shared, all without the U.S. person knowing about it. Those messages, if shared with U.S. law enforcement, could be used to criminally charge the U.S. person in a U.S. court, even though a warrant was never issued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bill has large privacy implications both in the U.S. and abroad. It was never given the attention it deserved in Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Rep. McGovern said, the people deserve the right to a better process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 05:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>raleighm</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Responsibility Deflected, the CLOUD Act Passes</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/03/responsibility-deflected-cloud-act-passes</og:url>
<og:description>UPDATE, March 23, 2018: President Donald Trump signed the $1.3 trillion government spending bill—which includes the CLOUD Act—into law Friday morning. “People deserve the right to a better process.”Those are the words of Jim McGovern, representative for Massachusetts and member of the House of...</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.eff.org/files/cloud-leaky.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/03/responsibility-deflected-cloud-act-passes</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My daughter&amp;#039;s disabled. Please don&amp;#039;t look away from her</title>
<link>http://www.latimes.com/opinion/op-ed/la-oe-willingham-how-to-interact-with-a-disabled-child-20180322-story.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.latimes.com/opinion/op-ed/la-oe-willingham-how-to-interact-with-a-disabled-child-20180322-story.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Chances are, you and your children will encounter Esprit or a child who is similarly disabled at a store, or in a park. Your child will be struck by Esprit's appearance. Typical for trisomy-18 kids, her head is small, her eyelids droop and her ears are low-set. Add the wheelchair and the braces on her feet and midsection, and you've got quite a sight. Older children pointedly refrain from staring (usually with a furtive peek or two), but younger children gape uninhibitedly. Embarrassed parents will try to distract their child, or drag him away, probably delivering a &quot;don't stare&quot; lecture once out of sight. But you can't blame a 4-year-old for staring at a child who looks different. His curiosity is natural.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 04:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>helloworld</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.latimes.com/opinion/op-ed/la-oe-willingham-how-to-interact-with-a-disabled-child-20180322-story.html</og:url>
<og:title>My daughter's disabled. Please don't look away from her</og:title>
<og:image>http://www.latimes.com/resizer/ZzEGPiKtOasai8-5-24pceSc-GI=/1200x0/www.trbimg.com/img-5ab2d578/turbine/la-oe-willingham-how-to-interact-with-a-disabled-child-20180322</og:image>
<og:description>As the father of a disabled child, I find myself less concerned with research into her condition and more interested in helping people feel comfortable interacting with her.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.latimes.com/opinion/op-ed/la-oe-willingham-how-to-interact-with-a-disabled-child-20180322-story.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>