<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>WeWork Gets Tax Rebate Meant for Its Small-Business Tenants</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-20/wework-gets-u-k-tax-rebate-meant-for-its-small-business-tenants</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-20/wework-gets-u-k-tax-rebate-meant-for-its-small-business-tenants</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-20/wework-gets-u-k-tax-rebate-meant-for-its-small-business-tenants&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-20/wework-gets-u-k-tax-rebate-meant-for-its-small-business-tenants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20813899&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20813899&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 211&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 72&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 20:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Turukawa</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=63026ce0-c92f-11e9-b515-73be744bf90b&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wOC0yMC93ZXdvcmstZ2V0cy11LWstdGF4LXJlYmF0ZS1tZWFudC1mb3ItaXRzLXNtYWxsLWJ1c2luZXNzLXRlbmFudHM=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Please Add RSS Support to Your Site</title>
<link>https://kevq.uk/please-add-rss-support-to-your-site</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://kevq.uk/please-add-rss-support-to-your-site</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://jlelse.blog&quot;&gt;Jan-Lukas Else's blog&lt;/a&gt;, which contains a tonne of great posts - I'd strongly recommend checking out his blog if you're a techie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was perusing Jan's blog, I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://jlelse.blog/blogroll&quot;&gt;his blogroll&lt;/a&gt;, which includes links to other blogs he finds interesting. Again, that list is well worth checking out as it has some good blogs in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Side note - I was thrilled to see this blog listed on his list, thanks Jan! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went through the list, hoping to find some new feeds to add to my RSS reader. But I was surprised to learn that many of the blogs that Jan had linked to didn't support RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Y U No RSS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to find some of these people on &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosstodon.org&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, so I will be able to consume their new content. However, some people had no obvious way to subscribe, so I will be unlikely to see their new posts in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There aren't many tech people that I know who don't use RSS feeds to consume news and articles, so by not supporting RSS you could be losing readers. I know for most people (myself included) writing content isn't about amassing a huge readership, but that doesn't mean we shouldn't take steps to ensure our content is easy to consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;If you own a blog, please make sure it supports RSS.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, that reminds me, if you want to add the feed for this site to your RSS reader, it's &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/feed&quot;&gt;https://kevq.uk/feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you think of a good reason NOT to use RSS on a website? What am I missing here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 18:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kevq</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://kevq.uk/please-add-rss-support-to-your-site</og:url>
<og:title>Please Add RSS Support To Your Site | Kev Quirk</og:title>
<og:description>There is no real reason to not have RSS support on your blog today. RSS feeds are simple to implement and could stop you losing readers.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://kevq.uk/please-add-rss-support-to-your-site</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Time anxiety: is it too late?</title>
<link>https://nesslabs.com/time-anxiety</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nesslabs.com/time-anxiety</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have always struggled with one thought. The kind of recurring thought that never really leaves you: “It’s too late.” Too late to publish a book, too late to start a company, too late to learn a new language. This is called time anxiety. The number of skills I haven’t acquired and the opportunities I didn’t take because of that very thought are, frankly, infuriating. It’s only recently that I have managed to get over that thought, and, while in my case it is still a daily struggle, I wanted to share some of my strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-style-large&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Men are not prisoners of fate, but only prisoners of their own minds.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Franklin D. Roosevelt.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;strong&gt;death anxiety&lt;/strong&gt; is the fear of running out of time, &lt;strong&gt;time anxiety&lt;/strong&gt; is the fear of wasting your time. It’s an obsession about spending your time in the most meaningful way possible. And when society tells us—or when we interpret signs from society as saying—that it’s too late to achieve a particular goal, we don’t perceive it as meaningful enough. We need—we demand—that what we do with our lives actually matters.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time anxiety can take several forms:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current time anxiety:&lt;/strong&gt; the daily feeling of being rushed that makes us feel overwhelmed and panicky. Some people also experience anxiety attacks because of the day-to-day stress caused by this type of time anxiety.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future time anxiety:&lt;/strong&gt; thoughts about what may or may not happen in the future, which are the cause of worry and “what if” types of internal questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Existential time anxiety:&lt;/strong&gt; the sense of lost time slipping away and never to return, which many people experience in a more acute way when thinking about death.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Alex Lickerman, the author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2ZvvssJ&quot;&gt;The Undefeated Mind: On the Science of Constructing an Indestructible Self&lt;/a&gt;, says that time anxiety stems from some of the following questions: “Am I creating the greatest amount of value with my life that I can? Will I feel, when it comes my time to die, that I spent too much of my time frivolously?”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time anxiety does not necessarily mean that you believe in an outside force that has assigned a purpose to your life, and that you are yet to discover. It just means that your well-being is determined to a large extent by the importance of the value you feel you are creating with your life.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, paradoxically, this over-optimisation may prevent us from creating the most value with our lives. We limit ourselves by always calculating the best potential outcome through our personal &lt;a href=&quot;https://nesslabs.com/fear-of-failure&quot;&gt;perception of possible&lt;/a&gt;. Beating time anxiety means shifting our focus from outcomes to output so we can spend our energy on things we can actually control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/time-anxiety-icon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Time anxiety&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1394&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Beating time anxiety: from outcomes to output&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Tanya J. Peterson, the author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Lppzsf&quot;&gt;The Mindfulness Journal for Anxiety&lt;/a&gt;, it’s important to accept a few truths to be able to feel in control of your daily time and your lifetime. First, time exists and we can’t change that. Time will move forward, and so will we. Accepting these simple yet daunting truths is the first step in reducing time anxiety. Next, you can start implementing some strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And if we continue asking why, like the child we once were, trying to excavate down to our most rudimentary ambition—a time-worn exercise—we’ll eventually find all reasons lead to the same place, to the one core reason for living we’d sought all along, the core reason against which we measure the value of everything we do: to be happy.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Dr. Alex Lickerman, Clinical Psychologist.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While purpose in life is an important factor in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nesslabs.com/psychology-of-happiness&quot;&gt;psychology of happiness&lt;/a&gt;, spending too much mental energy on finding it rather than doing things that make use happy can be anxiety-inducing. Here are three steps you can take to reduce time anxiety while still finding meaning in your day-to-day life:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define what “time well spent” means to you:&lt;/strong&gt; sit down, and think about what really makes your happy and &lt;a href=&quot;https://nesslabs.com/flow&quot;&gt;gets you in the flow&lt;/a&gt;, without overthinking about how feasible the final outcome would be. Just think of your output and how it makes you feel to work on producing it. For example, don’t think about how it would make you happy to publish a book. Ask yourself if you really enjoy writing. Don’t think about how proud you would be to run a marathon. Question whether you like running. Create a short list of activities you really enjoy and that bring value to yourself or to the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make space for these moments:&lt;/strong&gt; this does not mean making time for them. Instead, think of where you will incorporate these moments into your life. Maybe on your way to work. Maybe at home, after the kids are asleep. Or maybe spending time with your kid is the activity you want to make space for. If you happen to have less time than expected, that’s completely fine. It’s more about designing a space dedicated to your “time well spent” activities. As the prolific writer Maria Edgeworth said, “If we take care of the moments, the years will take care of themselves.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cut out time-consuming distractions:&lt;/strong&gt; the moments we spend mindlessly scrolling on social media or watching random videos do contribute to time anxiety. Do a quick audit of your content consumption patterns and try to cut out the amount of time you spend in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://nesslabs.com/creative-input-output&quot;&gt;input rather than output&lt;/a&gt; mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/time-anxiety-icon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Time anxiety&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1394&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said, time anxiety is something I’m still struggling with, and may keep on struggling with for the rest of my life. If that’s something you’re also struggling with, I hope you find these strategies useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator is-style-dots&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Anne-Laure Le Cunff&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/profile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-964&quot; width=&quot;103&quot; height=&quot;103&quot; srcset=&quot;https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/profile.jpg 400w, https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/profile-150x150.jpg 150w, https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/profile-300x300.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 103px) 100vw, 103px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m an ex-Googler, entrepreneur, and part-time neuroscience student at King’s College. If you found this article useful, subscribe to my weekly newsletter about productivity, creativity, learning, and designing engaging products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a thank you for joining the Maker Mind family, you will receive a welcome gift: &lt;em&gt;The Beginner’s Guide to Mindframing&lt;/em&gt;, an actionable 22-page handbook to better set and achieve your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/mindframing-preview.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-995&quot; srcset=&quot;https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/mindframing-preview.png 710w, https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/mindframing-preview-300x190.png 300w, https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/mindframing-preview-600x380.png 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 710px) 100vw, 710px&quot;/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 18:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>anthilemoon</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Time anxiety: is it too late?</og:title>
<og:description>I have always struggled with a thought: it’s too late. Too late to publish a book, to start a company, to learn a new language. This is called time anxiety.</og:description>
<og:url>https://nesslabs.com/time-anxiety</og:url>
<og:image>https://nesslabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/time-anxiety-banner.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nesslabs.com/time-anxiety</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Anthony Levandowski Charged with Theft of Trade Secrets</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/27/technology/google-trade-secrets-levandowski.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/27/technology/google-trade-secrets-levandowski.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;SAN JOSE, Calif. — Anthony Levandowski was once one of Silicon Valley’s most sought after technologists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As a pioneer of self-driving car technology, he became a confidant of Larry Page, a co-founder of Google, and helped develop the search giant’s autonomous vehicles. Uber wooed him to gain an edge in self-driving techniques. Venture capitalists threw their money at him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But on Tuesday, Mr. Levandowski, 39, fell far from that favored stature. Federal prosecutors charged him with 33 counts of theft and attempted theft of trade secrets from Google. At an arraignment in a federal courthouse in San Jose, Calif., a disheveled Mr. Levandowski, dressed in a blue blazer and dark brown pants and accompanied by his parents, posted $2 million bail and was ordered to wear an ankle monitor after prosecutors argued that he was a flight risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/usao-ndca/pr/former-uber-self-driving-car-executive-indicted-alleged-theft-trade-secrets-google&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The criminal indictment&lt;/a&gt; against Mr. Levandowski from the United States Attorney’s Office for the Northern District of California opens a new chapter in a legal battle that has embroiled Google, its self-driving car spinoff Waymo and its rival Uber in the high-stakes contest over autonomous vehicles. The case also highlights Silicon Valley’s no-holds-barred culture, where gaining an edge in new technologies versus competitors can be paramount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It is not uncommon for tech companies, which fiercely guard their intellectual property, to sue former employees or the firms they join after they leave. But criminal charges against a senior executive for theft is unusual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“There have always been disputes between companies — and they have often defined the Valley,” said Margaret O’Mara, a professor at the University of Washington and the author of the new book “The Code: Silicon Valley and the Remaking of America.” “But this is an extreme example. When criminal charges were brought in the past, it has involved pretty large-scale hardware theft operations as well as concern that technology was being shared with foreign adversaries.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;“All of us are free to move from job to job,” said David L. Anderson, United States attorney in the Northern District of California. “What we cannot do is stuff our pockets on the way out the door.”&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/08/27/business/27levandowski2/merlin_159798723_77a4806d-3ab7-417c-88f6-f96118756ac0-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/08/27/business/27levandowski2/merlin_159798723_77a4806d-3ab7-417c-88f6-f96118756ac0-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/08/27/business/27levandowski2/merlin_159798723_77a4806d-3ab7-417c-88f6-f96118756ac0-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/08/27/business/27levandowski2/merlin_159798723_77a4806d-3ab7-417c-88f6-f96118756ac0-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/08/27/business/27levandowski2/merlin_159798723_77a4806d-3ab7-417c-88f6-f96118756ac0-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;“All of us are free to move from job to job,” said David L. Anderson, United States attorney in the Northern District of California. “What we cannot do is stuff our pockets on the way out the door.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jason Henry for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/usao-ndca/press-release/file/1197991/download&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;According to the indictment&lt;/a&gt;, Mr. Levandowski downloaded more than 14,000 files containing critical information about Google’s autonomous-vehicle research before leaving the company in 2016. He then made an unauthorized transfer of the files to his personal laptop, the indictment said. Mr. Levandowski joined Uber later that year when the ride-hailing firm bought his new self-driving trucking start-up, which was called Otto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Some of the files that Mr. Levandowski took from Google included private schematics for proprietary circuit boards and designs for light sensor technology, known as Lidar, which are used in self-driving cars, according to the indictment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The Bay Area has the best and brightest engineers, and they take big risks,” John Bennett, the F.B.I. special agent in charge of the San Francisco Division, said at a news conference on Tuesday. “But Silicon Valley is not the Wild West. The fast-paced and competitive environment does not mean federal laws do not apply.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The United States attorney’s office said the indictment was returned by a federal grand jury on Aug. 15 and unsealed on Tuesday. Mr. Levandowski turned himself in at the federal courthouse in San Jose on Tuesday morning. At his arraignment, he pleaded not guilty to all charges. After he put up $300,000 and his parents and a friend posted their houses as collateral for bail, he was allowed to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Levandowski’s next court date is Sept. 4. If he is convicted, he could face a maximum of 10 years in prison, a $250,000 fine for every count and additional restitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“All of us are free to move from job to job,” said David L. Anderson, United States attorney in the Northern District of California. “What we cannot do is stuff our pockets on the way out the door.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Former Uber chief executive Travis Kalanick leaving federal court in San Francisco last year during the trial over trade secrets with Waymo.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jeff Chiu/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One of Mr. Levandowski’s lawyers, Miles Erlich, said outside the courthouse, “For more than a decade, Anthony Levandowski has been an industry leading innovator in the field of self-driving car and truck technology. And the evidence in this case is going to show conclusively that Anthony did not steal anything. Not from Google, not from anyone. Period.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Uber said in a statement that the company “has cooperated with the government throughout their investigation and will continue to do so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Suzanne Philion, a spokeswoman for Waymo, said it had “always believed competition should be fueled by innovation, and we appreciate the work of the U.S. Attorney’s Office and the F.B.I. on this case.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The indictment follows a settlement between Waymo and Uber in a trade secrets case. In February 2017, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/02/23/technology/google-self-driving-waymo-uber-otto-lawsuit.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Waymo had accused the ride-hailing firm, Mr. Levandowski&lt;/a&gt; and others of stealing self-driving car technology. That case went to trial in San Francisco in February 2018, riveting the tech industry with testimony about the inner workings of technology companies, rivalries among billionaire tech entrepreneurs and the cutthroat competition for engineering talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Four days into the trial, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/09/technology/uber-waymo-lawsuit-driverless.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Uber and Waymo settled&lt;/a&gt;, with Uber agreeing to provide 0.34 percent of its stock to Alphabet, the parent company of Waymo and Google. But Mr. Levandowski’s situation was not resolved by the settlement. The federal judge in the case &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2017/05/googles-fight-uber-takes-turn-criminal/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;referred it to the United States attorney’s office&lt;/a&gt; for a possible criminal inquiry into Mr. Levandowski’s behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Levandowski became known for self-driving technology as a graduate student at the University of California, Berkeley. In 2004, he designed a self-driving motorcycle that was entered in the Pentagon’s first contest for autonomous vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Mr. Levandowski in San Francisco in 2016.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ramin Rahimian for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;At Google, which Mr. Levandowski joined last decade, he ended up leading many aspects of the self-driving program inside the company’s clandestine “Google X” division. Google’s self-driving car unit was later spun off into Waymo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2016, Mr. Levandowski left Google &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/17/technology/want-to-buy-a-self-driving-car-trucks-may-come-first.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;to form Otto&lt;/a&gt;, a self-driving trucking start-up. He took a small army of Google engineers along with him. Otto was &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/19/technology/uber-self-driving-cars-otto-trucks.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;quickly acquired by Uber&lt;/a&gt; for nearly $700 million. The deal was driven by Travis Kalanick, Uber’s chief executive at the time, who had a vision of building a fleet of self-driving robotaxis that would replace Uber’s hundreds of thousands of human drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2017, Waymo sued Uber, Mr. Levandowski and Otto for theft of trade secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Otto and Uber have taken Waymo’s intellectual property so that they could avoid incurring the risk, time and expense of independently developing their own technology,” Waymo said in its suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The relationship between Uber and Mr. Levandowski quickly went south. In the Waymo case, Mr. Levandowski &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/30/technology/uber-waymo-levandowski.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;invoked his Fifth Amendment right to avoid self-incrimination&lt;/a&gt; because, his lawyers said, there was “potential for criminal action.” He was terminated by Uber in May 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Uber regrets ever bringing Anthony Levandowski on board,” one of Uber’s lawyers said during the trial last year. “All Uber has to show for Anthony Levandowski is this lawsuit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Levandowski, who made millions of dollars from his work and through sales of his start-ups, has not stepped back. In December, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/dec/18/controversial-engineer-i-travelled-over-3000-miles-in-a-self-driving-car&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;he gave an interview to The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; about his new self-driving start-up, Pronto.AI, in which he claimed that he built a car that had driven from San Francisco to New York without human intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/pronto-ai/pronto-means-ready-e885bc8ec9e9&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a post on Medium&lt;/a&gt; at the time, Mr. Levandowski criticized the state of the self-driving industry. He also said he had been “painted into a villainous caricature” and was “super excited to be back.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Pronto.AI said in a statement on Tuesday that its technology did not rely on Lidar. It added that Robbie Miller, Pronto’s chief safety officer, would take over as its chief executive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/27/technology/google-trade-secrets-levandowski.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Former Star Google and Uber Engineer Charged With Theft of Trade Secrets</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/08/27/business/27levandowski3/27levandowski3-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Anthony Levandowski, one of Silicon Valley’s foremost technologists on autonomous cars, was charged with theft and attempted theft of trade secrets from Google.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/27/technology/google-trade-secrets-levandowski.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>No More Cheap Shipping for Chinese Sellers</title>
<link>https://sellercentral.amazon.com/forums/t/its-official-no-more-cheap-shipping-for-chinese-sellers/493043</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://sellercentral.amazon.com/forums/t/its-official-no-more-cheap-shipping-for-chinese-sellers/493043</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have contracted negotiated international rates for epacket. We’re based in Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got notification today that all USPS international GEPS contracts will be terminated September 31st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all related to the Universal Postal Union agreement that allows Chinese sellers to ship products to the U.S. for less than it costs us to ship to the same state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The administration has given the UPU an ultimatum, that they: either allow the USPS to set rates for China mail that arrives in the U.S., or the U.S. will officially leave the UPU on October 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, this means as of October 17, no more cheap Chinese shipping. They will have to pay the same domestic rates as us once their e-packets arrive here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is great news for U.S. sellers, especially eBay sellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad news for Wish com, Chinese e-commerce sellers, Ali-express, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(edited out external url)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s great news!&lt;br/&gt;For those who want to read a good summary on what’s going on, google&lt;br/&gt;As U.S. Postage Rates Continue To Rise, The USPS Gives The Chinese A ‘Free Ride’&lt;br/&gt;Then also google&lt;br/&gt;This U.S. Postal Policy Powers Chinese E-Commerce While Hurting U.S. Entrepreneurs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally more of a level playing field.&lt;br/&gt;Usually these things take years to negotiate or undo, but this one was quickly implemented.&lt;br/&gt;Google&lt;br/&gt;The End of Cheap Shipping From China&lt;br/&gt;The White House wants to put an end to low-cost shipping from overseas, a move widely supported among U.S. e-commerce sellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you’ve overlooked is the Chinese government might just subsidise the postage rates. Sure USPS might charge China Post more, but not all (or zero) of that increase might get passed onto their customers in China. No user price increase means no difference, and the Chinese government just subsidises the exports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;quote no-group&quot; data-post=&quot;3&quot; data-topic=&quot;493043&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/G/01/social/giveaway/host/avatar._CB515668827_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;avatar&quot;/&gt; September1999:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese government just subsidises the exports&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yep, true dat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese Gov’t might subsidize the postage costs ( at least temporarily to help with the transition ). I would not be surprised if it was around $5 or so per package, times millions of packages… till now it was subsidized by yours truly and you and the rest of the USA customers who needed to pony up more for domestic shipping so the e-packet from China remains cheap for the shipments originating from China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they don’t subsidize it, this will help Amazon. Amazon is encouraging all the Chinese sellers to ship everything to FBA and the hike in e-packet rates will convince lot of them to go that route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d all like to see the Chinese to pay a fairer rate, but let’s not pretend that this would be the only consequence of the US abandoning the framework that sets rates between us and every other country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;em&gt;Washington Examiner&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;quote no-group&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With America’s exit from the UPU just 14 months away, the nation will be forced to choose one of four likely paths forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One potential option would be for USPS to cede the market to foreign post offices to the private sector. This would make all international mail in the United States behave like the express mail market that operates outside of the terminal dues framework. This change would dramatically increase the cost of sending standard letters both inbound to and outbound from the United States, as well as that of small parcels shipped into the United States from abroad. However, it would also end USPS’s obligations to the international postal system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second option would be for the United States to lay out a set of its own rates for each individual country based on whatever standard it sees fit. Other countries could accept or reject these rates based on how much they value the ability to send mail to the United States. And in this case, they would also set their own rates for Americans to access their postal systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;America negotiating with international postal operators through treaties outside of the UPU would be a third potential outcome. Articles addressing the international mail issues that the United Nations covers could be added onto existing treaties with other countries. If the United States decides to pursue this option, we could see postal issues lumped in with broader issues of trade and even inserted into trade agreements. The need to pass treaties to address postal issues could then become a starting point for new negotiations to liberalize trade more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, the State Department has limited capacity to negotiate and Senate time to vote on a wave of new treaties is as scarce as ever. Moreover, the cost of these negotiations could wipe out a substantial portion of the gains from an international postal order that is more favorable to American shippers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth and most likely outcome is one where the UPU flinches and the world makes concessions that give reason for the United States to remain in the treaty. Rates, especially those on Chinese small parcels, could increase in order to stem complaints from American merchants unfairly disadvantaged by current shipping rates. A UPU response with concessions avoids the need to upend how international mail is sent in the United States, as well as the need to negotiate and vote on a series of new postal treaties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some sellers suffer more from Chinese competitors than they benefit from sales to international customers, but others have a lot to lose if this unfolds in a Brexit-like fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;quote no-group&quot; data-post=&quot;3&quot; data-topic=&quot;493043&quot; data-full=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/G/01/social/giveaway/host/avatar._CB515668827_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;avatar&quot;/&gt; September1999:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you’ve overlooked is the Chinese government might just subsidise the postage rates. Sure USPS might charge China Post more, but not all (or zero) of that increase might get passed onto their customers in China. No user price increase means no difference, and the Chinese government just subsidises the exports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really don’t see that happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our USPS international rep called us last week also. Essentially, the rates the US wants to charge China have already been set. They’re just not telling us due to confidentiality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our rep indiciated that the new rates for China shippers will be on par with what US shippers are charged to ship to China, i.e. the playing field will be leveled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more Shipping a 4 lb. package to the USA for $5. Retail rates from USA to China for the same weight is $70.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Chinese government wants to subsidize hundreds of millions of packages at $65 a package, I say go right ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;quote no-group&quot; data-post=&quot;4&quot; data-topic=&quot;493043&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://d2bvhe78se1grn.cloudfront.net/forums/user_avatar/sellercentral.amazon.com/1709/40/3869_1.png&quot; class=&quot;avatar&quot;/&gt; keyslife:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they don’t subsidize it, this will help Amazon. Amazon is encouraging all the Chinese sellers to ship everything to FBA and the hike in e-packet rates will convince lot of them to go that route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The funny thing is, Amazon has been lobbying FOR the termination of Chinese epacket rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once terminated, Chinese sellers will be forced into FBA, which is good for Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eBay lobbied hard against this. eBay owns no warehouses, and relies on China sellers selling direct via. epacket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how eBay announced their version of FBA starting next year? It’s no coincidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d still like to know how British booksellers can send their books to the US for under $10 when it costs me about $30 to send a book to England. I mean, seriously…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;quote no-group&quot; data-post=&quot;1&quot; data-topic=&quot;493043&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/G/01/social/giveaway/host/avatar._CB515668827_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;avatar&quot;/&gt; Charlie1983:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got notification today that all USPS international GEPS contracts will be terminated &lt;em&gt;September &lt;strong&gt;31st&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;^ Er…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;look up on google&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;they are actively looking to compete in the shipping industry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from the article&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project’s name: Dragon Boat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of that strategy, Bloomberg reported Amazon had plans to take on freight forwarding and brokerage services directly, eliminating a set of middlemen.&lt;br/&gt;…&lt;br/&gt;Among the most important ramifications from Amazon’s vision: small Chinese manufacturer will be able sell to American consumers with no one else than Amazon between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will Amazon provide its services only for Chinese manufacturers selling goods through Amazon? That is the trillion question, but note this: the USAToday says a job posting with Beijing Century Joyo in Shanghai describes the ideal candidate as someone who will help the company in “disrupting the way products are bought, sold and distributed on a global scale.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;quote no-group&quot; data-post=&quot;1&quot; data-topic=&quot;493043&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/G/01/social/giveaway/host/avatar._CB515668827_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;avatar&quot;/&gt; Charlie1983:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tiated international rates for epacket. We’re based in Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got notification today that all USPS international GEPS contracts will be terminated September 31st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all related to the Universal Postal Union agreement that allows Chinese sellers to ship products to the U.S. for less than it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meh about time. Here is Canada I can buy a certain product from china and ship it to Alberta for $35. (The product lands in Ontario and travels through Ontario to Alberta).&lt;br/&gt;But for me to ship that exact same product (Not even buy it) here in Canada Ontario to Alberta it costs $44.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tell me how a Chinese shipper can manufacture and ship a product for less than what it costs me to ship to the province directly beside me? Oh because we subsidize their shipments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was flagged by the community and is temporarily hidden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good news but won’t affect Amazon platform too much since too many Chinese sellers have already learned how to use FBA and black-hat tactics to manipulate Amazon platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;quote no-group&quot; data-post=&quot;13&quot; data-topic=&quot;493043&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://d2bvhe78se1grn.cloudfront.net/forums/user_avatar/sellercentral.amazon.com/1310/40/14200_1.png&quot; class=&quot;avatar&quot;/&gt; left_coast_books:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well Charlie, I would like to know what you had to say about the discrepancy in shipping costs USA v. UK, but you deleted your post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the post I deleted, I gave you my estimate as to how much your competitors were probably paying, then I realized we cannot say due to our USPS non disclosure agreement, which states we cannot share pricing info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I can say is that they are not paying anywhere near what you are paying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do good business internationally, you can probably get a GEPS contract. The minimum threshold volume is not outrageous and they are way more flexible than the requirements they list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: But hold off until this is all resolved, as there’s a 50/50 chance we’re all having our contracts cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But since Amazon itself is going to be doing lots more of the shipping from PRC to USA then the actual costs for shipping has yet to be determined. Since this action should lessen the subsidy the US taxpayers are giving to PRC currently, Yea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sept Only has 30 days… There is no September 31.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When did we add an extra day to September to make it a 31 day month. &lt;img src=&quot;https://sellercentral.amazon.com/forums/images/emoji/twitter/laughing.png?v=6&quot; title=&quot;:laughing:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:laughing:&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sellercentral.amazon.com/forums/images/emoji/twitter/laughing.png?v=6&quot; title=&quot;:laughing:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:laughing:&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sellercentral.amazon.com/forums/images/emoji/twitter/laughing.png?v=6&quot; title=&quot;:laughing:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:laughing:&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally! We might actually be able to MAKE money again on eBay and etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i need my international postage rates to go DOWN, not the rates for the chinese to go up. $23 for an 8 oz package to Europe killed much of my international business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;quote no-group&quot; data-post=&quot;1&quot; data-topic=&quot;493043&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/G/01/social/giveaway/host/avatar._CB515668827_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;avatar&quot;/&gt; Charlie1983:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The administration has given the UPU an ultimatum, that they: either allow the USPS to set rates for China mail that arrives in the U.S., or the U.S. will officially leave the UPU on October 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nothing is official with the current administration until it happens… and even then it is questionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 14:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nkurz</dc:creator>
<og:image>http://sellercentral.amazon.com/forums/images/default-apple-touch-icon.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://sellercentral.amazon.com/forums/t/its-official-no-more-cheap-shipping-for-chinese-sellers/493043?_escaped_fragment_=</og:url>
<og:title>It's Official, No More Cheap Shipping For Chinese Sellers</og:title>
<og:description>We have contracted negotiated international rates for epacket. We’re based in Las Vegas. Got notification today that all USPS international GEPS contracts will be terminated September 31st. This is all related to the Universal Postal Union agreement that allows Chinese sellers to ship products to the U.S. for less than it costs us to ship to the same state. The administration has given the UPU an ultimatum, that they: either allow the USPS to set rates for China mail that arrives in the U.S.,...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://sellercentral.amazon.com/forums/t/its-official-no-more-cheap-shipping-for-chinese-sellers/493043?_escaped_fragment_=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Recommended resources to learn the Linux kernel and OS theory?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20809666</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20809666</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Ask HN: Recommended resources to learn the Linux kernel and OS theory?&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.9445983379501&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.1204986149584&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;20809666&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20809666&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Recommended resources to learn the Linux kernel and OS theory?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.72289156626506&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_20809666&quot;&gt;326 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=non-entity&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;non-entity&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20809666&quot;&gt;10 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_20809666&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=20809666&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D20809666&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Recommended%20resources%20to%20learn%20the%20Linux%20kernel%20and%20OS%20theory%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Recommended%20resources%20to%20learn%20the%20Linux%20kernel%20and%20OS%20theory%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=20809666&amp;amp;auth=46f6ff417c971b37b975c1dbc3513d0255a97ada&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20809666&quot;&gt;77 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;So recently I did a couple of minor patches on the FreeBSD and NetBSD kernels and played with some linux kernel. It was the first time in a a few years, I've been excited about programming.
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I'm still completely lost. It seems that there's so much to learn and every kernel update breaks whatever you just finished writing. I see terms in unfamiliar with and often find myself googling basic OS concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there any recommendations reading materials to get a better grasp on OS theory and / or the Linux / UNIX kernels and programming for them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 14:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>non-entity</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20809666</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Let&amp;#039;s build houses for people, not cars</title>
<link>https://noparkinghere.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://noparkinghere.com</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;07. MOVING FORWARD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;88&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Even the most automobile centered techno-future will have less parking. The double threat of autonomous vehicles and rideshare services makes car ownership obsolete. A system with fewer cars working more hours is far more efficient than the current model of “everyone spends lots of money on a personal vehicle that’s parked 95% of the day.” &lt;mark&gt;The future isn’t parked, it’s constantly moving.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's important to understand that the answers to many of our cities largest problems don't involve glamorous solutions. Dense housing existed thousands of years before the earliest written language. London was building subways in the 1800s. In many cases, building safer pedestrian or cycling infrastructure simply requires painting different lines on the road and installing cheap bollards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cities are organisms that grow and change of their own accord, but we can't look past the fact that every part of a city is built by design. Every parcel in LA is zoned for certain uses, densities, and heights. There exists an archive in LADOTs headquarters of the exact dimensions of every roadway in the City of Los Angeles. People choose what cities look like and how they function, it's not only our responsibility, but also entirely in our power to change city design to be better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Street parking can be converted into micro-mobility lanes, bus lanes, expanded sidewalks, parklets, and bike/scooter corrals. Let’s not only move more people, but also make our streets enjoyable places to be in instead of the fastest possible route through. If it isn’t comfortable for children and the elderly then we are failing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surface lots can be converted into housing, but also community amenities. Lets build more playgrounds and schools and parks. Let's plant more trees to capture carbon, absorb toxins out of the air, and reduce urban heat island effects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Los Angeles has the space, it just needs right priorities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course Los Angeles needs more than parking reform to fix it’s housing, transportation, and environmental challenges, but it’s representative of an unsustainable system. &lt;mark&gt;Los Angeles has 15,700 people living in their vehicles each night because we’ve done a better job building homes for cars instead of people.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parking is simple, we have more than Los Angeles will ever need. There’s absolutely no reason to be building more. &lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;https://noparkinghere.com/pic/FIX_DSC02280.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;imgsrc&quot;&gt;900 parking stalls in a 7-level podium across from the Wilshire/Vermont station.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Santa Monica recently passed what might be the region's most progressive Parking Regulation. But even this only affects a small downtown core area and still requires half a parking space per multi-family unit.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The City of Los Angeles Transit Oriented Communities guidelines passed in 2018 allows developers to build higher, more affordably, and with less parking near rail stations and frequent busses. However only the least common Tier allows units to be built without any parking, and still sets the commercial parking minimum to 40%. All told, only some 2.5 square miles of Los Angeles are eligible for construction with no new residential parking through the TOD guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The City of LA’s Cornfield Arroyo Seco Specific Plan is currently the only zoned area in LA completely residential and commercially parking minimum free. Although not even one square mile, it allows any development to be built without any parking all and should be used as a model for future zoning decisions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Re:Code LA , the city’s project to update zoning code across the city, looks to move towards a more sustainable parking policy: “In summary, the current approach to parking across the city should be reevaluated in light of contemporary development trends. Parking ratios should be more responsive to context and the availability of transit, without significantly impacting surrounding residential areas.” While the above summary reads optimistic, outside of unbundling parking and potential parking maximums around transit stations, the report specifics are generally bullish on parking. It assumes large amounts of new parking will continue to be built, used, and necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parking legislation should be focused on two things; what will get the most housing built the quickest, and what will best prioritize low-carbon solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A proper policy would be similar to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;No universal parking minimums. Developers choose how much parking the market requires.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parking Maximums in Transit Oriented Communities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All new parking garages must be built with a flat floor and a high enough ceiling to allow future conversion into office, studio, or living space.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% of parking spaces must include EV charging, with the rest install ready.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garages must include an equivalent number of bicycle/micro-mobility parking spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 06:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dhritzkiv</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://noparkinghere.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: A clean and minimalist theme for Jekyll</title>
<link>https://github.com/huangyz0918/moving</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/huangyz0918/moving</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://badge.fury.io/rb/moving&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/e4f3d3ae8aea9b32221498c930b19c10a8337ea9/68747470733a2f2f62616467652e667572792e696f2f72622f6d6f76696e672e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Gem Version&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://badge.fury.io/rb/moving.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/huangyz0918/moving&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/4185837a6ba7f0481cd047a7e903b867faebaf25/68747470733a2f2f7472617669732d63692e6f72672f6875616e67797a303931382f6d6f76696e672e7376673f6272616e63683d6d6173746572&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/huangyz0918/moving.svg?branch=master&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/b39a886d652e8a2148958f2fd779124d202be7e1/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f70726f67726573732d646576656c6f70696e672d79656c6c6f772e737667&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/b39a886d652e8a2148958f2fd779124d202be7e1/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f70726f67726573732d646576656c6f70696e672d79656c6c6f772e737667&quot; alt=&quot;progress&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/progress-developing-yellow.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving is a clean and minimalist theme for &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, focuses on pure and efficient writing. &lt;a href=&quot;http://huangyz.name/moving/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;[view demo]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohugo.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; theme, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joway/hugo-theme-yinyang&quot;&gt;YinYang&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/huangyz0918/moving/blob/master/github/banner.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/huangyz0918/moving/raw/master/github/banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to create a new blog using moving. You can follow these steps after setting up the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; environments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clone this repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
git clone https://github.com/huangyz0918/moving.git
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Move into that directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; moving/
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install required gems using &lt;code&gt;bundle&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
bundle install
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the blog in localhost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
jekyll serve
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you successfully run the moving blog, you can modify the theme and add posts by yourself, have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Add Moving to Existing Blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add this line to your Jekyll site's &lt;code&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-ruby&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
gem &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;moving&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And add this line to your Jekyll site's &lt;code&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-yaml&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;theme&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;moving&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then execute:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ bundle
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or install it yourself as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ gem install moving
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deploy to Github Pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚠️ If you want to publish your site in &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Change &lt;code&gt;theme: xxx&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;remote_theme: huangyz0918/moving&lt;/code&gt; then push to your github repo (this is important, or you will get an error from github pages that not support the moving theme). If you want to test your site locally, you can change that to &lt;code&gt;theme: moving&lt;/code&gt; and build again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can modify the &lt;code&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; to custom your blog. An example is if you want to change the back button's text in each post, you can change the &lt;code&gt;back_to&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-yaml&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;Moving &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; The title of the blog&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;author&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;Your Name &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Your name &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;email&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;your-email@domain.com &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; your email shown in the footer&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;http://huangyz.name/moving/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; this is your site's root address.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; this means to ignore newlines until &quot;show_excerpts:&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;  A clean and minimalist theme for Jekyll.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;favicon&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;./favicon.ico&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; set the favicon of the site &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;show_excerpts&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;false &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; set to true to show excerpts on the homepage&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Moving date format&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; refer to https://shopify.github.io/liquid/filters/date/ if you want to customize this&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;moving&lt;/span&gt;:
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;avatar_url&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;https://i.loli.net/2019/08/26/JzCLhDWPEybZr2T.jpg&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; avatar in about page&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;about_you&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;a short description about you. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; short description about you in about page&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;date_format&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;%b %d&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; date format of posts in home page&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;back_to&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;Home&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; In the post page, you have a back button above the title, you can custom the text by yourself.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Build settings&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;theme&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;moving &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; note, please use huangyz0918/moving if you want to publish to Github Pages.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bug reports and pull requests are welcome on GitHub at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/huangyz0918/moving&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This project is intended to be a safe, welcoming space for collaboration, and contributors are expected to adhere to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://contributor-covenant.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Contributor Covenant&lt;/a&gt; code of conduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set up your environment to develop this theme, run &lt;code&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your theme is setup just like a normal Jekyll site! To test your theme, run &lt;code&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; and open your browser at &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:4000&lt;/code&gt;. This starts a Jekyll server using your theme. Add pages, documents, data, etc. like normal to test your theme's contents. As you make modifications to your theme and to your content, your site will regenerate and you should see the changes in the browser after a refresh, just like normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your theme is released, only the files in &lt;code&gt;_layouts&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;_includes&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;_sass&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;assets&lt;/code&gt; tracked with Git will be bundled. To add a custom directory to your theme-gem, please edit the regexp in &lt;code&gt;moving.gemspec&lt;/code&gt; accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme is available as open source under the terms of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 04:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>huangyz0918</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/15646062?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>huangyz0918/moving</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/huangyz0918/moving</og:url>
<og:description>A clean and minimalist theme for Jekyll. Contribute to huangyz0918/moving development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/huangyz0918/moving</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Am the Cheapest Bastard in Indie Games</title>
<link>https://jeff-vogel.blogspot.com/2019/08/i-am-cheapest-bastard-in-indie-games.html?m=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jeff-vogel.blogspot.com/2019/08/i-am-cheapest-bastard-in-indie-games.html?m=1</guid>
<description>&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9-Gdns-Es3M/XWRRO7E4TWI/AAAAAAAABLs/_cq5tUWb_04Ap4p__J44B4ppFvHMFiHWACLcBGAs/s1600/QW%2BSS.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;900&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;157&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9-Gdns-Es3M/XWRRO7E4TWI/AAAAAAAABLs/_cq5tUWb_04Ap4p__J44B4ppFvHMFiHWACLcBGAs/s280/QW%2BSS.jpg&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;A Queen's Wish screenshot. Note that I use game art that I like to look at. This is necessary because I'll be staring at it for years, and I don't want to go mad.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A week ago, I put up a blog post called &lt;a href=&quot;https://jeff-vogel.blogspot.com/2019/08/why-all-of-our-games-look-like-crap.html&quot;&gt;&quot;Why All My Games Look Like Crap.&quot;&lt;/a&gt; It really blew up. A lot of people read it. Some were highly supportive. Others took precious time out of their days to let me know I am a gigantic, gigantic bozo.&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all! When you're trying to get attention for a small indie game, there's no such thing as bad publicity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Basically, my blog post said, &quot;Some people like my art, but I am still super-bad at art. Always have been. Fixing the problem costs time and cash, and I don't have any of either to spare. So that's why our games look bad.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got a lot of questions about this. Good questions. Why can't I afford art direction? How much does art cost? Why don't I do this or that smart thing? So that's why I'm writing this. I want to answer the good questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I am going to say some stuff about making and budgeting video games and why I am a bozo and why I am cursed to be a bozo forever. Along the way, I'm going to explain to you the whole indie games biz, from soup to nuts. If you like indie games, I think you might find how I survive interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You see, I am the cheapest bastard in indie games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CGlnE7_Nzks/XWRRpRdb0KI/AAAAAAAABL0/rcwD-u_3diM3fLv9SdGiapSEhUC_vKPBwCLcBGAs/s1600/big-cat-clipart-of-a-rich-tiger-holding-a-bag-of-money-by-hit-toon-4.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;620&quot; data-original-width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;290&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CGlnE7_Nzks/XWRRpRdb0KI/AAAAAAAABL0/rcwD-u_3diM3fLv9SdGiapSEhUC_vKPBwCLcBGAs/s280/big-cat-clipart-of-a-rich-tiger-holding-a-bag-of-money-by-hit-toon-4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;I don't have this much money. And, please, I beg you, support &lt;a href=&quot;http://bigcatclipart.com/&quot;&gt;bigcatclipart.com&lt;/a&gt; and the good work they do.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I've Been Doing This For 25 Years&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people really get annoyed when I bring this up. It's as if having long experience and a huge body of work gives my words some sort of weight and my advice some value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, it does. Do you realize how few people have turned a good profit for that long in this blood sport business? I am rarer than a unicorn made of bigfoots!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indie games business is hard, one of the toughest there is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Is It So Hard To Make Money In Indie Games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do you think the going rate for the best indie games ever made is?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you guess 'Free'? You're right! Go to the Epic Game Store every week and they'll hand you the best indie games, games way better than mine, for free!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That not enough? Join the Humble Monthly Bundle. For just $12/month, they'll send you 6-7 games every month, plus you can also download over 60(!) games in their &quot;Humble Trove.&quot; They're good games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the competition is intense, and you can never ever match your superiors on price, ie free. That makes for tough business, friend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-IBv08R44oKE/XWRSJefoKxI/AAAAAAAABL8/fL6Cffbmn0s105OdVrAywD69_tqyEkkvACLcBGAs/s1600/celeste.0.jpeg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;800&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;186&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-IBv08R44oKE/XWRSJefoKxI/AAAAAAAABL8/fL6Cffbmn0s105OdVrAywD69_tqyEkkvACLcBGAs/s280/celeste.0.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;Award-winning. Critical darling. Huge hit. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/videos/two-fantastic-epic-games-store-freebies-announced-/2300-6450792/&quot;&gt;Free.&lt;/a&gt; How do you plan to compete?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So How Can You Survive?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simple. You provide something nobody else can ever provide. Something cool and distinctive that people will rather pay money for your game than get someone else's for free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider me. I'm an OK programmer. I'm not good at art and visual stuff, and I haven't been since I was a kid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I can write well. I make good settings and stories, my spelling and grammar are ok, I make addicting game systems, and my systems and stories blend really well. THAT is the product I sell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm in the business of selling Jeff Vogel games. And just like Van Gogh couldn't paint a Renoir, or vice versa, nobody else can make a Jeff Vogel game. Larian Studios is a great company with great resources that makes great products. However, no matter how hard they try, they can never make a game one of my fans will mistake for one of mine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for me, there are people who really like Jeff Vogel games, and only we sell them. So we have a business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, that's not all it takes to stay in business. I can get people to buy my games, sure. But I need to turn a profit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is why I need to be the cheapest bastard in indie games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-AfyC5niox6Y/XWRSk0lNyYI/AAAAAAAABME/ig3q6bVWZKEGRxwHgjDPjn6JlmeYdBpvgCLcBGAs/s1600/a754a1bd-50c0-42cb-a237-10b61315bcbd.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;520&quot; data-original-width=&quot;780&quot; height=&quot;186&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-AfyC5niox6Y/XWRSk0lNyYI/AAAAAAAABME/ig3q6bVWZKEGRxwHgjDPjn6JlmeYdBpvgCLcBGAs/s280/a754a1bd-50c0-42cb-a237-10b61315bcbd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;You can find a dedicated fan base for any imaginable art style. That's indie games, baby!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let's See Some Numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got into this kerfuffle talking about how my games look ugly, and I'll get back to that. First, though, let's look at budgets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our next game is Queen's Wish: The Conqueror. We spent about 20 months on it. For it to have a chance to pay for the time we spent creating it, it needs to make, after Steam and GOG.com and Apple and itch.io and Kickstarter take their cuts, about $200000 US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(It will take years for the game to earn this money, but we'll be earning money from back catalog at the same time, so it evens out.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why that amount? Because that is what long experience has told us we are most likely to get. Low-budget high-text, thinky RPGs don't become giant hits, but we have a loyal audience, so we'll get decent sales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then we take out, say, $60000 for business expenses and insurance. Then we spend X dollars on art (the key factor we are discussing here). We use what is left to pay our salaries (to get baubles like food, clothing, and shelter).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So our earnings for 20 months of hard work is, let's say, $140000 minus art expenses. Keep your eye on the ball.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twenty Months? That's Not Very Long To Write a Game&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No! It's not! Whenever I ship I game, I immediately begin the race against time to write another game before our bank account runs out. Twenty months is actually an unusually long time for us, but Queen's Wish is an all-new games system and engine, so it needs it. I normally need 12-14 months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the way, for people who asked me why I don't just learn to do better art myself, this is why. To learn to do better art, I'd need to spend at least 6-12 months. (To think it takes less is insulting to artists.) I just don't have the time to not be writing games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-D8KHmCKapg0/XWRS1t8ayoI/AAAAAAAABMM/EjzSxjqNfeYGSiAtRbzFkASJ-wUTizEXQCLcBGAs/s1600/shapinghall.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;428&quot; data-original-width=&quot;578&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-D8KHmCKapg0/XWRS1t8ayoI/AAAAAAAABMM/EjzSxjqNfeYGSiAtRbzFkASJ-wUTizEXQCLcBGAs/s280/shapinghall.jpg&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;I made the frames and button background for this interface. It was years before someone say, &quot;Um, Jeff, are you sure this isn't a little too green?&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So Back To Art&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;After I wrote the last blog post, a lot of people wanted to make sure that, &quot;Oh yeah, pal. No matter how bad your art is? It's WAY worse than that.&quot; The most common complaint I got is that there is no unified style and color palette. My art looks like it was cobbled together from like 20 different artists, blended together imperfectly by my nonexistent Photoshop stills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I've got news for you. Our art WAS literally cobbled together from like 20 different artists, blended together imperfectly by my nonexistent Photoshop stills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's the thing. Many people don't notice this. Some notice, but it doesn't bother them. But for skilled artists and people with an eye for this sort of thing, looking at the icons I use makes their faces do this ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ptGM8o1QxDs/XWRTGDjGdBI/AAAAAAAABMU/h1aKDZ7BcQM2lvEa_mk3W6GvuWqXKSINACLcBGAs/s1600/nazi.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;298&quot; data-original-width=&quot;364&quot; height=&quot;228&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ptGM8o1QxDs/XWRTGDjGdBI/AAAAAAAABMU/h1aKDZ7BcQM2lvEa_mk3W6GvuWqXKSINACLcBGAs/s280/nazi.png&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;Hello darkness, my old friend.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sorry about that.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I &quot;Art Direct&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I do what might laughably be called &quot;art design&quot;, my first step is to cobble together any floor/terrain objects that will function. I pull art from old games, from https://opengameart.org/, from sites that license icons for cheap, from anywhere I can get icons that will function. I use Photoshop trickery to make it blend as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I will reach a point where I need stuff that I can't use online resources for, stuff that needs to be custom-made for how I want the game to look. Then I go to freelancers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I pay for bespoke art for terrain types with different looks that need to fit the engine, like tables and statues. Also, for terrain that I have my own unique formats for, like walls and doors and gates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My artists work very hard to make sure the icons they do blend well with each other and look great. They do awesome work. Then I defile it by mixing it in with all the other weird stuff I find. If anything looks bad in my games, blame me! Seriously!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doing the art this way costs around $40000. That leaves $100000 of earnings. For 20 months of work, that's pretty thin, but I'll live with it. I'll make up for it with the next two games in the series, which will take a lot less time to write. (Plus, eventually, remasters. I will be squeezing pennies out of Queen's Wish for literally decades.) So it's fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So that is where the weird mix of styles in my games comes from. Suppose I wanted to have unified art, all one style guide, all one look, everything done from scratch to give the game one pure look. I'm not a total idiot. I know it's possible. This is why I don't do it ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here! Have Some Hard Numbers!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;Queen's Wish is a big game! Five nations and biomes! A surface and underworld! Multiple sets of furniture, all kinds of environments. The game currently has, to make the different regions look distinct and give enough visual variety, well over 1000 terrain icons. (An icon here is defined to be a 48x48 tile. Some terrains require multiple icons. Each wall type, for example, is assembled from 60 icons.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now suppose I do all this from scratch for the game. I need to hire freelancers. So I have to assemble a team of them that work in the desired style, that all make art that blend well, that are available and reliable, that are willing to commit to a job this big, and aren't too expensive. (If you think this is easy, you have a lot to learn. Assembling this team takes a lot of my non-existent time.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I hire Fredrika Freelancer (F.F.) for short. F.F. charges $25/hour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(That’s a really fair price. If you’re paying less, someone else is going to hire her away from you. On the other hand, many freelancers charge $50/hour or more, but F.F. likes me and gives me a break. She probably lives in a country where the U.S. dollar goes farther. If you live in Brooklyn, I can't afford you.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ask F.F. to do, say, a stone pillar, about 20 pixels wide and 70 pixels high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She builds it in her 3-D program. Textures it. Shadows it. Sizes it properly. Renders it. Sends it to me. I request some changes. She makes them. (I'm really easy to work with. I almost never ask for more than one round of changes. Believe it or not, freelancers tend to really like working with me.) I get the art. This probably will take about two hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, if I'm lucky, I get this pillar done for $50. Yay! One terrain type down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;999 more to go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But for Queen's Wish, I want 4 different pillars, to give distinct looks to four different cultures. Suppose on opengameart, I find a set of public domain pillar icons that basically work. They aren't great, but they function. If I download them, I save $200.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;$200!!! That's folding money! You know how much money that is? That's enough money to buy 200 donuts! WITH SPRINKLES!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But That's Not All!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So do a little math and tell me how much money I'll need to shell out to get all 1000 terrain icons done, how much money will be chipped out of my $140000. And then remember that's just terrain! Then I need creature art, and an interface, and portraits, and color paintings, and sfx, and item icons, and ability icons, and ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;RPGs are art-intensive!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you seeing why I go cheap whenever I can? Freelancers charge money because they DESERVE it. They are talented people in a hard job. But they are selling the art ala carte, and I'm too much of a doofus to be able to afford too much of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To art everything being done from scratch with a unified style and a consistent, pleasing color palette and all the other good things artists like, if I'm lucky and get a lot of charity and really scale back what I want, I can easily end up spending $150000. Again, I can't do it myself. I'm a writer, not an artist, and RPGs absolutely need certain sorts of assets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So here is the math: Doing art the cheap bastard way, I spend $40000. Doing it the good way, I spend around $150000. 150000 – 40000 = 110000&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So to justify the extra art cost, I need to sell $110000 more worth of games just to break even. Remember that number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-O4qcf4H_x1k/XWRVHrVMvII/AAAAAAAABMw/ykoiZJt1oXYqxFTxbA4OtRPQQnloG30HwCLcBGAs/s1600/14-185.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;480&quot; data-original-width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;210&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-O4qcf4H_x1k/XWRVHrVMvII/AAAAAAAABMw/ykoiZJt1oXYqxFTxbA4OtRPQQnloG30HwCLcBGAs/s280/14-185.png&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;We should be grateful that indie games have expanded what a game can look like and still break through. It wasn't like this a decade ago. &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Or I Could Hire An Employee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't have to use freelancers, of course. I could hire an artist full-time for 20 months. Suppose I do a big search and find someone whose style I like and who wants to work for me. How much will that count, taking benefits and taxes into account?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many who are unfamiliar with this industry are surprised to find that artists are some of the highest paid people. Good, reliable artists are rare! Check out this site https://www.careerexplorer.com/careers/games-artist/salary/, for salary estimates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I'm lucky enough to find a good artist who wants the job, with bonuses and benefits and so on, I might be able to get him or her for $150000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I'm lucky enough to find a good person, with bonuses and benefits and so on, I might be able to get this person for $150000-180000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(LOL! This is probably way too low, especially if I want the person to live in Seattle so I can work with them face to face, which I do. I will be paying under the median at this rate.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't want to do this. I'm an introvert, and one of the reasons I got into this business was so that I could work alone. But I'll do it. For the Sake Of Art. You, the customer, deserve it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dQw4w9WgXcQ&quot;&gt;I will never let you down!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, my cheap bastard art is $40000. If I hire a full-time art director/artist, I need to increase sales by $110000-140000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where Does the Extra Art-Buying Money Come From, By The Way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So can I even spend the extra $110000+ to begin with?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't have that much cash on hand. Nowhere near. To launch this project, I need to take a bank loan or raid my retirement fund. Then, if I don't break even, I'm in big trouble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OK. I Need To Increase Sales By $110000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know. This blog post is a long slog. Here's the punchline! Remember, most indie games are sold at deep discount now. After the store's cut, I'll probably average about $8 a sale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make that $200000 I think I can earn, I'll need to make about 25000 sales. For an indie game, this is a LOT. But give me a few years and let me luck into a Steam daily deal or a Humble Bundle and I can manage it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But to break even on my all-new art project, to earn that extra $110000, my still very low-budget indie turn-based-retro-word-heavy RPG needs to sell about 40000 copies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That increase may not sound like so much more, but it is a LOT. Ask any indie developer. 40000 copies is a HUGELY aggressive number. (So is 25000, but, again, I have an established fan base. Every sale I get requires more work than the sale before it.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is just to break even. If we don't hit that number? We can easily lose the entire business, poof, all sacrificed for the sake of a nice, unified art style.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that is why I need to be the cheapest bastard in indie games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QwgaJAMMwRY/XWRVvGR0QII/AAAAAAAABNA/P5qQNSuKIqUEtbJQNM8vgEcmFdPABNL2QCLcBGAs/s1600/haters_gonna_hate_3_by_mezkalito4p-d4f3zsw.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;260&quot; data-original-width=&quot;290&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QwgaJAMMwRY/XWRVvGR0QII/AAAAAAAABNA/P5qQNSuKIqUEtbJQNM8vgEcmFdPABNL2QCLcBGAs/s1600/haters_gonna_hate_3_by_mezkalito4p-d4f3zsw.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;All my best art direction is done when my eyes are covered with slices of cucumber.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But ... But ... I Thought Indie Games Made You Rich!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah. Sometimes you get a hit. Then you get a pile of money. Then you hire a bunch of employees and make a real company. Then one of two things happen. You write a new, expensive game and it's a mistake and fails and everything explodes. Or you keep writing good games and grow until GiantMegaCorp gives you hundreds of millions of dollars for your company and you fly free and take a big vacation and buy a Tesla and realize you have no idea what to do with your life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, most indie developers are like most small business owners. We're humble folks scraping by and doing what we can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is why I am writing these too-many words. If you want to have a small business or make a living as a humble artist, I have kind words for you, because I really want you to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Inspirational Ending!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got yelled at a lot for the previous article. It was basically a massive expression of contempt at me for being such a hack that I was content writing such ugly games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(And if you want to get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/cubkxa/why_all_of_our_games_look_like_crap_spiderweb/?st=jzoq993n&amp;amp;sh=cebf255f&quot;&gt;Extremely Mad Online&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/gamedev/comments/ctvicn/why_all_of_our_games_look_like_crap/?st=jzne67gx&amp;amp;sh=43ebcb48&quot;&gt;dunk on me&lt;/a&gt; more, it's cool. Whatever is fun. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8UXircX3VdM&quot;&gt;Shine on, you crazy diamond.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But here’s the thing! If you want to be a game writer, or creator, or small businessperson, you should find my story to be inspiring!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I write games so ugly that I am showered with contempt, and yet I make money! I’ll have a full, lifelong career! If I can have so many flaws and still succeed, you can too!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure out what you are really good at doing. Sell that. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oNJy0h6gIpI&amp;amp;list=PL6SSUza2wNqihtsiQQOVMfrQAn0M0LGx-&amp;amp;index=32&quot;&gt;Make your dream real.&lt;/a&gt; Get it out the door, whatever it takes, whatever corners you have to cut. If you’re better than me (and who isn’t, really), you have a chance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>grawprog</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://jeff-vogel.blogspot.com/2019/08/i-am-cheapest-bastard-in-indie-games.html</og:url>
<og:title>I Am the Cheapest Bastard In Indie Games</og:title>
<og:description>A Queen's Wish screenshot. Note that I use game art that I like to look at. This is necessary because I'll be staring at it for years, and...</og:description>
<og:image>https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9-Gdns-Es3M/XWRRO7E4TWI/AAAAAAAABLs/_cq5tUWb_04Ap4p__J44B4ppFvHMFiHWACLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/QW%2BSS.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jeff-vogel.blogspot.com/2019/08/i-am-cheapest-bastard-in-indie-games.html?m=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Experimental USAF space plane breaks record for orbital spaceflight</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/26/experimental-u-s-air-force-space-plane-breaks-previous-record-for-orbital-spaceflight/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/26/experimental-u-s-air-force-space-plane-breaks-previous-record-for-orbital-spaceflight/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;The Boeing-built X-37B space plane commissioned and operated by the U.S. Air Force has now broken its own record for time spent in space. Its latest mission has lasted 719 days as of today, which is one day longer than its last mission, which ended in 2017, as noted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.space.com/x-37b-military-space-plane-otv5-duration-record.html?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=dlvr.it&quot;&gt;Space.com&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not an overall record, as geocommunications satellites typically have life spans of five years or more, but it’s nonetheless an impressive milestone for this secretive Air Force vehicle, which is all about testing and developing U.S. technologies related to reusable spaceflight and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The X-37B began its current mission in September 2017, when it launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/07/spacex-will-launch-the-us-air-forces-top-secret-x-37b-spaceplane-in-august/&quot;&gt;atop a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket&lt;/a&gt;. The specific details of the spacecraft’s missions are classified, but in addition to apparently spending ever-increasing amounts of time up in space (each successive mission of the space plane has lasted longer), it’s also “operating experiments that can be returned to, and examined, on Earth.” These tests involve tech related to guidance, navigation, thermal protection, high-temperature materials and durability, flight and propulsion systems and more, which is basically not saying much, as that’s just about everything involved in space flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no crew on board operating X-37B, but the vehicle can autonomously descend back through Earth’s atmosphere and land horizontally on a runway, just like the &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/nasa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;nasa&quot;&gt;NASA&lt;/a&gt; Space Shuttle used to do when it was in operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA began the X-37 program in 1999; it was then transferred to &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/darpa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;darpa&quot;&gt;DARPA&lt;/a&gt; and the U.S. Air Force in 2004. The X-37B has flown four times; in total, the first four missions have completed 2,085 days in space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 23:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lil-scamp</dc:creator>
<og:title>Experimental US Air Force space plane breaks previous record for orbital spaceflight – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>The Boeing-built X-37B space plane commissioned and operated by the U.S. Air Force has now broken its own record for time spent in space. Its latest mission has lasted 719 days as of today, which is one day longer than its last mission, which ended in 2017, as noted by Space.com. It’s not an …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/100330-O-1234S-001.jpg?w=594</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/08/26/experimental-u-s-air-force-space-plane-breaks-previous-record-for-orbital-spaceflight/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/26/experimental-u-s-air-force-space-plane-breaks-previous-record-for-orbital-spaceflight/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>