<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Myequifax.com Bypasses Credit Freeze Pin</title>
<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/03/myequifax-com-bypasses-credit-freeze-pin/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/03/myequifax-com-bypasses-credit-freeze-pin/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Most people who have frozen their credit files with &lt;strong&gt;Equifax&lt;/strong&gt; have been issued a numeric Personal Identification Number (PIN) which is supposed to be required before a freeze can be lifted or thawed. Unfortunately, if you don’t already have an account at the credit bureau’s new &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.equifax.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;myEquifax portal&lt;/a&gt;, it may be simple for identity thieves to lift an existing credit freeze at Equifax and bypass the PIN armed with little more than your, name, Social Security number and birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumers in every U.S. state can now freeze their credit files for free with Equifax and two other major bureaus (&lt;strong&gt;Trans Union&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Experian&lt;/strong&gt;). A freeze makes it much harder for identity thieves to open new lines of credit in your name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-46831&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/myequifax.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;594&quot; height=&quot;341&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Equifax’s epic 2017 data breach impacting some 148 million Americans, many people did freeze their credit files at the big three in response. But Equifax has changed a few things since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeking to manage my own credit freeze at equifax.com as I’d done in years past, I was steered toward creating an account at myequifax.com, which I was shocked to find I did previously possess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting an account at myequifax.com was easy. In fact, it was too easy. The portal asked me for an email address and suggested a longish, randomized password, which I accepted. I chose an old email address that I knew wasn’t directly tied to my real-life identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next page asked me enter my SSN and date of birth, and to share a phone number (sharing was optional, so I didn’t). SSN and DOB data is widely available for sale in the cybercrime underground on almost all U.S. citizens. This has been the reality for years, and was so well before Equifax announced its big 2017 breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;myEquifax said it couldn’t verify that my email address belonged to the Brian Krebs at that SSN and DOB. It then asked a series of four security questions — so-called “knowledge-based authentication” or KBA questions designed to see if I can about my recent financial history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the data being asked about in these KBA quizzes is culled from public records, meaning that this information likely is publicly available in some form — either digitally or in-person. Indeed, I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/09/data-broker-giants-hacked-by-id-theft-service/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;long assailed the KBA industry&lt;/a&gt; as creating a false sense of security that is easily bypassed by fraudsters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One potential problem with relying on KBA questions to authenticate consumers online is that so much of the information needed to successfully guess the answers to those multiple-choice questions is now indexed or exposed by search engines, social networks and third-party services online — both criminal and commercial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first three multiple-guess questions myEquifax asked were about loans or debts that I have never owed. Thus, the answer to the first three KBA questions asked was, “none of the above.” The final question asked for the name of our last mortgage company. Again, information that is not hard to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satisfied with my answers, Equifax informed me that yes indeed I was Brian Krebs and that I could now manage my existing freeze with the company. After requesting a thaw, I was brought to a vintage Equifax page that looked nothing like myEquifax’s sunnier new online plumage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_46832&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/equifax-PIN-needed.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-46832&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/equifax-PIN-needed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;596&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Equifax’s site says it will require users requesting changes to an existing credit freeze to have access to their freeze PIN and be ready to supply it. But Equifax never actually asks for the PIN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page informed me that if I previously secured a freeze of my credit file with Equifax and been given a PIN needed to undo that status in any way, that I should be ready to provide said information &lt;em&gt;if I was requesting changes via phone or email. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, &lt;em&gt;credit freezes and thaws requested via myEquifax don’t require users to supply any pre-existing PIN&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine, I said. Let’s do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;myEquifax then asked for the date range requested to thaw my credit freeze. Submit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’ve successfully processed your security freeze request!,” the site declared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also was exclaimed in an email to the random old address I’d used at myEquifax, although the site never once made any attempt to validate that I had access to this inbox, something that could be done by simply sending a confirmation link that needs to be clicked to activate the account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I noticed Equifax added my old mobile number to my account, even though I never supplied this information and was not using this phone when I created the myEquifax account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_46833&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/MYequifax-success.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-46833&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/MYequifax-success.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;599&quot; height=&quot;324&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Successfully unfreezing (temporarily thawing) my credit freeze did not require me to ever supply my previously-issued freeze PIN from Equifax. Anyone who knew the vaguest and most knowable details about me could have done the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;myEquifax.com does not currently seek to verify the account by requesting confirmation via a phone call or text to the phone number associated with the account (also, recall that even providing a phone number was optional).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, I did discover then when I used a different computer and Internet address to try to open up another account under my name, date of birth and SSN, it informed me that a profile already existed for this information. This suggests that signing up at myEquifax is probably a good idea, given that the alternative is more risky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was way too easy to create my account, but I’m not saying everyone will be able to create one online. In testing with several readers over the past 24 hours, myEquifax seems to be returning a lot more error pages at the KBA stage of the process now, prompting people to try again later or make a request via email or phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equifax spokesperson &lt;strong&gt;Nancy Bistritz-Balkan&lt;/strong&gt; said not requiring a PIN for people with existing freezes was by design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With myEquifax, we created an online experience that enables consumers to securely and conveniently manage security freezes and fraud alerts,” Bistritz-Balkan said..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We deployed an experience that embraces both security standards (using a multi-factor and layered approach to verify the consumer’s identity) and reflects specific consumer feedback on managing security freezes and fraud alerts online without the use of a PIN,” she continued. “The account set-up process, which involves the creation of a username and password, relies on both user inputs and other factors to securely establish, verify, and authenticate that the consumer’s identity is connected to the consumer every time.”&lt;span id=&quot;more-46823&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked Bistritz-Balkan what else besides a username and a password the company may have meant by “multi-factor;” I’m still waiting for clarification. But I did not experience anything like multi-factor in setting up or logging into my myEquifax account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may by closer to Equifax’s idea of multi-factor: The company told me that if I still really wanted to use my freeze PIN, I could always call their 800 number (800-349-9960) or make the request via mail. Nevermind that if I’m a bad guy looking to hack others, I’m definitely going to be using the myEquifax Web site — &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the options that make me have to supply a PIN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtually the entire United States population in 2017 became eligible for free credit monitoring from Equifax following its 2017 breach. Credit monitoring can be useful for recovering from identity theft, but consumers should not expect these services to block new account fraud; the most they will likely do in this case is alert you after ID thieves have already opened new accounts in your name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A credit freeze does not impact your ability to use any existing financial accounts you may have, including bank and credit/debit accounts. Nor will it protect you from fraud on those existing accounts. It is mainly a way to minimize the risk that someone may be able to create new accounts in your name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t done so lately, it might a good time to order a free copy of your credit report from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annualcreditreport.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;annualcreditreport.com&lt;/a&gt;. This service entitles each consumer one free copy of their credit report annually from each of the three credit bureaus — either all at once or spread out over the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/09/credit-freezes-are-free-let-the-ice-age-begin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Credit Freezes are Free: Let the Ice Age Begin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/06/plant-your-flag-mark-your-territory/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Plant Your Flag, Mark Your Territory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/09/experian-site-can-give-anyone-your-credit-freeze-pin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Experian Site Can Give Anyone Your Freeze PIN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/03/survey-americans-spent-1-4b-on-credit-freeze-fees-in-wake-of-equifax-breach/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Survey: Americans Spent $1.4B on Credit Freeze Fees in Wake of Equifax Breach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/10/equifax-breach-fallout-your-salary-history/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Equifax Breach Fallout: Your Salary History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/09/data-broker-giants-hacked-by-id-theft-service/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Data Broker Giants Hacked by ID Theft Service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/10/experian-sold-consumer-data-to-id-theft-service/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Experian Sold Access to ID Theft Service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mid-banner&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.akamai.com/us/en/security.jsp?utm_source=krebsonsecurity&amp;amp;utm_medium=display&amp;amp;utm_id=F-MC-44701&amp;amp;utm_campaign=unifiedsecurity_digital_2019&amp;amp;utm_content=unifiedsecurity_global&amp;amp;utm_term=unifiedsecurity_ros&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/b-akamai/15.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/credit-freeze-pin/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;credit freeze PIN&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/experian/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Experian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/freeze-pin-bypass/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;freeze PIN bypass&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/kba/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;KBA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/myequifax-com/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;myEquifax.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/nancy-bistritz-balkan/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Nancy Bistritz-Balkan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/trans-union/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Trans Union&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Friday, March 8th, 2019 at 11:12 am and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/sunshine/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;A Little Sunshine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/latest-warnings/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Latest Warnings&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/security-tools/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Security Tools&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/comingstorm/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;The Coming Storm&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any comments to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/03/myequifax-com-bypasses-credit-freeze-pin/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. You can skip to the end and leave a comment. Pinging is currently not allowed.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 16:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>deanmoriarty</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/03/myequifax-com-bypasses-credit-freeze-pin/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Elizabeth Warren Proposes Breaking Up Tech Giants Like Amazon</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/08/us/politics/elizabeth-warren-amazon.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/08/us/politics/elizabeth-warren-amazon.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Senator Elizabeth Warren, the Massachusetts Democrat who is bidding to be the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/27/us/politics/elizabeth-warren-democrats-policy.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;policy pacesetter in the Democratic presidential primary&lt;/a&gt;, announced another expansive idea on Friday: a regulatory plan aimed at breaking up some of America’s largest tech companies, including Amazon, Google, Apple, and Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The proposal — which comes on the same day Ms. Warren will hold a rally in Long Island City, the Queens neighborhood that was to be home to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/14/nyregion/amazon-hq2-queens.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;a major new Amazon campus&lt;/a&gt; — calls for the appointment of regulators who would “unwind tech mergers that illegally undermine competition,” as well as legislation that would prohibit platforms from both offering a marketplace for commerce and participating in that marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Warren’s plan would also force the rollback of some acquisitions by technological giants, the campaign said, including Facebook’s deals for &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://dealbook.nytimes.com/2014/02/19/facebook-to-buy-messaging-start-up/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://dealbook.nytimes.com/2012/04/09/facebook-buys-instagram-for-1-billion/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/06/16/business/dealbook/amazon-whole-foods.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon’s addition of Whole Foods&lt;/a&gt;, and Google’s purchase of Waze. Companies would be barred from transferring or sharing users’ data with third parties. Dual entities, such as Amazon Marketplace and AmazonBasics, would be split apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;[&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/politics?smid=rd?action=click&amp;amp;module=Intentional&amp;amp;pgtype=Article&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Sign up for our politics newsletter and join our conversation about the 2020 presidential race.&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I want a government that makes sure everybody — even the biggest and most powerful companies in America — plays by the rules,” Ms. Warren said in a morning statement. “To do that, we need to stop this generation of big tech companies from throwing around their political power to shape the rules in their favor and throwing around their economic power to snuff out or buy up every potential competitor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;During a brief interview later in New York, Ms. Warren refused to say whether Gov. Andrew M. Cuomo was right to have offered &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/22/nyregion/amazon-cuomo-gianaris.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;hefty tax incentives&lt;/a&gt; to Amazon in return for the proposed campus in Queens. Boston Mayor Martin J. Walsh, from Ms. Warren’s home state, also offered sizable incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“That’s not the point,” she said. “Before you even get into the question of do you need to change the statutes, there are structural changes you can make in the economy to prevent Amazon from dancing its way across America saying, ‘What will you offer me if I came?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The announcement reverberated on Friday from New York to Silicon Valley. Pressure for elected officials to place additional oversight on mega-tech companies has been building for months, particularly after revelations that companies such as Facebook may have &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/18/technology/facebook-privacy.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;violated customer privacy agreements&lt;/a&gt;. Ms. Warren is also sending a political warning shot across the Democratic primary field, where decisions on how much to embrace or reject Silicon Valley and its wealthy donors could become an important dividing line among candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In the wide-open nomination race, Democrats such as Ms. Warren, Senator Bernie Sanders of Vermont and Senator Amy Klobuchar of Minnesota have expressed a willingness to limit the influence of companies such as Facebook, Google, Apple and Amazon — though Mr. Sanders and Ms. Klobuchar have yet to present clear policy details. Senator Kamala Harris, who represents many of those companies based in her home state of California, has repeatedly &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/10/us/politics/zuckerberg-facebook-senate-hearing.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;pressed executives on consumer privacy&lt;/a&gt; but has stayed away from direct calls to limit their influence. Senator Cory Booker of New Jersey has been &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/08/07/cory-bookers-silicon-valley-friendships-started-at-stanford/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;more willing to embrace the controversial corporations&lt;/a&gt;, who have frequently used their vast resources to lobby politicians of both parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Our technology industry is the envy the world and we need policies that will foster innovation and consumer choice — but we also need stronger enforcement of antitrust law,” said Ro Khanna, the California House Democrat who represents Silicon Valley headquarters of companies such as Apple and eBay. He said blanket statements against big tech companies weren’t helpful, but that each company needs to be “evaluated on a case-by-case basis and afforded due process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;[&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/us/politics/2020-presidential-candidates.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=inline&amp;amp;pgtype=Article&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Check out the Democratic field with our candidate tracker.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Warren’s plan creates two tiers of companies that would fall under the new regulations: those that have an annual global revenue of $25 billion or more, and those with annual revenue of $90 million to $25 billion. The upper tier would be required to “structurally separate” their products from their marketplace. Smaller companies would be subject to regulations but would not be forced to separate themselves from the online marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Warren, who has previously said moving to Boston would have been a “good opportunity” for Amazon, said in a Medium post Friday morning that companies have grown so powerful that they can bully cities and states into showering them with massive taxpayer handouts in exchange for doing business, and can act — in the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/the-big-idea/2018/4/9/17214752/zuckerberg-facebook-power-regulation-data-privacy-control-political-theory-data-breach-king&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;words&lt;/a&gt; of Mark Zuckerberg — “more like a government than a traditional company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This is a refrain she has hit for years, including in a 2016 speech titled “Reigniting Competition in the American Economy.” Last year, she introduced the Accountable Capitalism Act, which seeks to curb shareholder power by forcing corporations to increase worker representation on their governing boards, while also reducing incentives for big companies to pay out shareholders rather than reinvest in businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Matt Stoller, a fellow at the Open Markets Institute in Washington and a former senior adviser to the Senate Budget Committee, said Ms. Warren’s plan was “practical” and “necessary.” He compared big tech companies to the tobacco monopolies of America’s past, which were eventually subjected to antitrust lawsuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“There’s been a traditional sense around the politics of D.C. that these companies are progressive,” Mr. Stoller said. “Their employees give to Democrats, they’re friendly to social liberalism, there’s an idealism to how they talk about the world. That’s been the traditional sense.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“But these companies have the moral frame of Big Tobacco,” he added. “They don’t care.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Carl Szabo, who is vice president at an e-commerce trade association called NetChoice, said he felt Ms. Warren’s plan was unnecessary. He warned that it could lead to weaponization of antitrust laws, as legislators target companies deemed to be their enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Politicizing and weaponizing antitrust law is ripe for abuse,” said Mr. Szabo, who is a professor of privacy law at George Mason University’s law school. “We’ve already seen how politics can inject itself into antitrust reviews, and I don’t think our legislators should be encouraging this precedent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He added that he also felt Ms. Warren is “wrong in her assertion that tech markets lack competition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Never before have consumers and workers had more access to goods, services and opportunities online,” Mr. Szabo said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In the announcement, Ms. Warren’s team included praise from several scholars on internet privacy and technology regulation, including Siva Vaidhyanathan from the University of Virginia and Frank Pasquale of the University of Maryland’s School of Law. For those closely watching the Democratic presidential nomination contest, the announcement was another example of Ms. Warren’s political strategy, which is to appeal to voters based on policy ideas and retail politics, not soaring oration or feel-good messages of unity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In January, Faiz Shakir, then the national political director for the American Civil Liberties Union, said, “Elizabeth Warren is trying to position herself as the ideas candidate of the field, and thus far, in the early going, she’s winning that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Others should start thinking about competing in the arena for new ideas,” Mr. Shakir added. He has since joined Mr. Sanders’s presidential bid as its campaign manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 13:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chadmhorner</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/08/us/politics/elizabeth-warren-amazon.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Elizabeth Warren Proposes Breaking Up Tech Giants Like Amazon and Facebook</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/08/us/politics/08warren/08warren-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The Massachusetts senator, who is running for president, announced a regulatory plan aimed at breaking up large tech companies and “unwind tech mergers that illegally undermine competition.”</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/08/us/politics/elizabeth-warren-amazon.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How random can you be?</title>
<link>https://www.expunctis.com/2019/03/07/Not-so-random.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.expunctis.com/2019/03/07/Not-so-random.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Mar 07, 2019       tags: &lt;em&gt;| &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expunctis.com/tags/js.html&quot;&gt;js&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expunctis.com/tags/visualisation.html&quot;&gt;visualisation&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-random-can-you-be&quot;&gt;How random can you be?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s play a game. You press ← and → as randomly as you can, and I will try to guess your next input. Use your keyboard or the buttons below (on touchscreen devices).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I guess right, I will take $1 from your virtual account. Every time I guess wrong, you’ll get $1.05. If you are as random as you think, you’ll be making virtual dough in no time. Don’t worry, there is no cheating involved. I simply keep track of the patterns you produce and use them to predict your next move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve become tired of watching your virtual money evaporate, press the “randomize” button below, and I will add 10 pseudo-random inputs on your behalf. &lt;strong&gt;On average&lt;/strong&gt; (i.e. not all the time), this is going to earn you some money. Isn’t it ironic that a pseudo-random number generator is more “random” than you are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: I added three custom metrics/events in google analytics to collect statistics on correct guesses after 100, 200 and 500 inputs. If you’d rather not be counted, please load the html file from my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ex-punctis/not-so-random&quot;&gt;github repository&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button id=&quot;randomize&quot; onclick=&quot;randomHelpFunc(event)&quot;&gt;randomize!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;button id=&quot;left&quot; ontouchstart=&quot;captureBtnLeftFunc(event)&quot;&gt;  ←  &lt;/button&gt; &lt;button id=&quot;right&quot; ontouchstart=&quot;captureBtnRightFunc(event)&quot;&gt;  →  &lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;centreContainer&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;log&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start pressing ← and → on your keyboard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(←/→ buttons above on touchscreen devices).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log messages will appear here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does it work exactly? Your fingers tend to repeat certain patterns even if you don’t notice it. The program keeps a database of each possible combination of 5 presses, and two counters are stored under each entry — one is for every zero that follows the combination, and the other one is for all the ones that follow this combination. So every time you press a key, an entry in the database gets updated. To make a prediction, the program needs only to look up the entry corresponding to the last 5 presses and decide by looking at the counters which key press is more likely to follow. The rest is up to Fortuna (velut luna). I’ve run this script with 200 pseudo-random inputs 100,000 times, and found that the distribution of correct guesses is approximately normal with µ=50% and σ=3.5% (this agrees with the binomial estimation, of course). The probability of the program guessing your inputs &amp;gt;57% (µ+2σ) of the time purely by chance is very slim, which suggests that you really aren’t good at making random choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credits:&lt;/strong&gt; I got the idea from PBS Digital Studios Infinite Series on YouTube (a highly recommended channel!). One of the videos linked &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.ischool.berkeley.edu/~nick/aaronson-oracle/&quot;&gt;this demo&lt;/a&gt; which inspired me to experiment with the idea. I didn’t dig deeply, but it seems my implementation (5-grams) ended up the same (or at least very similar). I’ve also tried 3-grams, 4-grams, and adaptive n-grams (n&amp;lt;6), but it seemed they did no better than the current 5-gram model. Although, to be honest, I didn’t have the time to do thorough testing, so I may be wrong. The plot is powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://plot.ly/javascript/&quot;&gt;plotly.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ex-punctis/not-so-random&quot;&gt;github repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;expanded-image-container&quot; class=&quot;expanded-image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;expanded-image-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.expunctis.com/images/icons/x.svg&quot; class=&quot;expanded-img-close-icon icon-animation&quot; onclick=&quot;close_expanded_img()&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 11:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mdp</dc:creator>
<og:title>How random can you be?</og:title>
<og:description>Suppose I asked you to generate a random sequence of ones and zeroes. Every time you add another 1 or 0 to the sequence, I am going to predict your next choice. Do you think you can make your sequence random enough that I fail to guess more than ~50% correct? Read this post to find out. Spoiler — you are not so random.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.expunctis.com/2019/03/07/Not-so-random.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-CA</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.expunctis.com/2019/03/07/Not-so-random.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>List of 30 European Tech Visas and Work Permits</title>
<link>https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wLPGB2BdRxHWbdOXXtKAoCQimY_4RjBjRH8Grv3U0tI/edit#gid=0</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wLPGB2BdRxHWbdOXXtKAoCQimY_4RjBjRH8Grv3U0tI/edit#gid=0</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s1&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;👉👉&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s2 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit SeedTable.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s3&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s4 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weekly, curated newsletter for founders, investors and senior employees in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s5&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s5&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s5&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s5&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s6&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s7&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s8&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s8&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s8&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s9&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s9&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s9&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s9&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s10&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Visa 🛂&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;URL 💻&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Country 🗺️&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Recipient&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Diploma 🗒️&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Family 👪&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Duration 📆&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Renewable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s0&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Cost 💰&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s11 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;freezebar-cell freezebar-horizontal-handle&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Estonia's Work &amp;amp; Residence Permit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.workinestonia.com/working-in-estonia/work-permits/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Estonia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Finland's Work Permite&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.businessfinland.fi/en/do-business-with-finland/work-in-finland/visas-work-permits/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Finland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration of contract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s15&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s16&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€450.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;French Tech Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://medium.com/frenchtech/france-is-going-all-in-to-help-its-startups-win-the-battle-for-global-talent-enter-the-new-french-c33311bc8510&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;France&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;4 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany's Temporary Residence Permit for Employment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://berlinstartupjobs.com/guide-working-in-berlin/types-of-german-work-permits-and-how-to-get-one/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;1 year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Germany's Blue Card&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://berlinstartupjobs.com/guide-working-in-berlin/types-of-german-work-permits-and-how-to-get-one/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;4 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly skilled workers with diploma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;UK Tier 2 Work Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.gov.uk/tier-2-general&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;5 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€610.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Highly-Skilled Migrants&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://ind.nl/en/work/Pages/Highly-skilled-migrant.aspx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Netherlands&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration of contract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€2,638&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salary requirements goes up with age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Denmark's Positive List Regime&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.nyidanmark.dk/en-GB/You-want-to-apply/Work/Positivlisten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Denmark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration of contract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ireland's Highly Skilled Occupations Regime&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://dbei.gov.ie/en/What-We-Do/Workplace-and-Skills/Employment-Permits/Employment-Permit-Eligibility/Highly-Skilled-Eligible-Occupations-List/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Ireland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€1,000.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spain's Residency Visa for Highly Skilled Professionals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.exteriores.gob.es/Consulados/CIUDADDELCABO/en/InformacionParaExtranjeros/Pages/Law-on-Visas-for-Entrepreneurs.aspx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Spain&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Tech Nation Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://technation.io/visa/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;5 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;£456&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only 2000 visas/year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Denmark's Pay Limit Scheme&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.nyidanmark.dk/en-GB/Applying/Work/Pay%20limit%20scheme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Denmark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a job for more than DKK 375,000/year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s18 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ireland General Employment Permit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s19&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;https://techlifeireland.com/moving-to-ireland/immigration-to-ireland/&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Ireland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€1,000.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;€30000 minimum salary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ireland Critical Skills Employment Permit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s19&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;https://dbei.gov.ie/en/What-We-Do/Workplace-and-Skills/Employment-Permits/Permit-Types/Critical-Skills-Employment-Permit/&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Ireland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2 Years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€1,000.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;€30000 minimum salary / Job Offer of 2 years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Israel Long Term Working Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.tel-aviv.gov.il/en/WorkAndStudy/Pages/Work-Visas.aspx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Israel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;63 months&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Norway's Work Immigration Permit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.udi.no/en/want-to-apply/work-immigration/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Norway&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Job offer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Startup Denmark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.startupdenmark.info/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Denmark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No specific funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Estonia Startup Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.startupestonia.ee/visa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Estonia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;1.5 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€80.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Finnish Startup Permit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.businessfinland.fi/en/do-business-with-finland/work-in-finland/startup-permit/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Finland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No specific funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;French Tech Visa for Founders&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://visa.lafrenchtech.com/3/french-tech-visa-for-founders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;France&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;4 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€250.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Ireland Startup Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.citizensinformation.ie/en/employment/types_of_employment/self_employment/coming_to_set_up_a_business_in_ireland.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Ireland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Indefinite&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€75,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Israel's Startup Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.itrade.gov.il/us/israel-to-offer-startup-visa-for-foreign-innovators/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Israel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;5 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Italian Startup Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://italiastartupvisa.mise.gov.it/#ISVhome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Italy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;1 year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;€50000 in funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Startup Visa Lithuania&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://startupvisalithuania.com/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Lithuania&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;1 year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Dutch Startup Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://business.gov.nl/coming-to-the-netherlands/permits-and-visa/startup-visa/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Netherlands&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;1 year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€326.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Self-Employed Persons Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.udi.no/en/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Norway&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;1 year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;30000 NOK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Startup Portugal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://startupportugal.com/startup-visa/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Portugal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potential to generate a turnover of 325,000€/ year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Spanish Startup Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s20 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://extranjeros.mitramiss.gob.es/es/UnidadGrandesEmpresas/ley14_2013/tripticos/triptico-emprender-INGLES.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Spain&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;1 year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€72.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden's Residence Permit for the Self-Employed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.migrationsverket.se/English/Private-individuals/Working-in-Sweden/Self-employment.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Sweden&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;SEK 200,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;UK Entrepreneurial Visa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.gov.uk/tier-1-entrepreneur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 years and 4 months&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s21&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;€1,021.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;£50,000 from UK investors, or £200,000 from any party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Sweden's Work Permit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.migrationsverket.se/English/Private-individuals/Working-in-Sweden/Employed/Work-permit-requirements.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Sweden&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration of contract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEK 13,000 per month&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Startup Latvia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s22 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://startuplatvia.eu/startup-visa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Latvia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Founder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;3 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s17&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within 6 months 30'000 Eur investment, 18 months another 30'000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Austria's Very Highly Qualified Workers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s13 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.migration.gv.at/en/types-of-immigration/permanent-immigration/very-highly-qualified-workers/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Austria&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration of contract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s14 softmerge&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point-based system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s12&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;freezebar-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 11:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gonsanchezs</dc:creator>
<og:title>European Tech Visas &amp; Work Permits 🛂🌐</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wLPGB2BdRxHWbdOXXtKAoCQimY_4RjBjRH8Grv3U0tI/edit?usp=embed_facebook</og:url>
<og:image>https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/5s1KL70hZ2_NeuZiREhHsgjHHjmwefBFOQNlkTd40UAfogMdfTvAaRVEJq9IQrJrv22C0Q=w1200-h630-p</og:image>
<og:description>Sheet1 👉👉,Visit SeedTable.com,Weekly, curated newsletter for founders, investors and senior employees in Europe. Visa 🛂,URL 💻,Country 🗺️,Recipient,Diploma 🗒️,Family 👪,Duration 📆,Renewable,Cost 💰,Requirements Estonia's Work &amp; Residence Permit,https://www.workinestonia.com/working-in-esto...</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wLPGB2BdRxHWbdOXXtKAoCQimY_4RjBjRH8Grv3U0tI/edit</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is It a Duck or a Rabbit? For Google Cloud Vision, Depends on Image Rotation</title>
<link>https://www.reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful/comments/aydqig/is_it_a_duck_or_a_rabbit_for_google_cloud_vision/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful/comments/aydqig/is_it_a_duck_or_a_rabbit_for_google_cloud_vision/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;s1bd5ppi-8 gjbPXG&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s1bd5ppi-10 jmHofS&quot;&gt;13.6m&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s1bd5ppi-11 dAmide&quot; id=&quot;IdCard--Subscribers--undefined--t5_2tk95&quot;&gt;Subscribers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;s1bd5ppi-9 lgpBtg&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s1bd5ppi-10 jmHofS&quot;&gt;6.9k&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s1bd5ppi-11 dAmide&quot; id=&quot;IdCard--CurrentlyViewing--undefined--t5_2tk95&quot;&gt;Online&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s1bd5ppi-13 bczYis&quot;&gt;A place for visual representations of data: Graphs, charts, maps, etc. DataIsBeautiful is for visualizations that effectively convey information. **Aesthetics are an important part of information visualization, but pretty pictures are not the aim of this subreddit.**&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 05:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jpatokal</dc:creator>
<og:title>r/dataisbeautiful - Is it a Duck or a Rabbit? For Google Cloud Vision, it depends how the image is rotated. [OC]</og:title>
<og:type>video</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful/comments/aydqig/is_it_a_duck_or_a_rabbit_for_google_cloud_vision/</og:url>
<og:description>26,888 votes and 550 comments so far on Reddit</og:description>
<og:image>https://external-preview.redd.it/YIWtpSvWAKzvbb-Z4Y4uFyPpgPUgDOY0I8liyEISqpY.png?format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=42046b62747a1f2841159cba7b6eb6e15e66ba7d</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful/comments/aydqig/is_it_a_duck_or_a_rabbit_for_google_cloud_vision/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YC&amp;#039;s latest moonshot bet is a startup building a $380K “flying motorcycle”</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/07/ycs-latest-moonshot-bet-is-a-startup-building-a-380k-flying-motorcycle/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/07/ycs-latest-moonshot-bet-is-a-startup-building-a-380k-flying-motorcycle/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/person/david-mayman&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;person&quot; data-entity=&quot;david-mayman&quot;&gt;David Mayman&lt;/a&gt; has a vision for personal aviation that he’s spent the past dozen years and millions of his personal fortune chasing. He hasn’t accepted the convention that jetpacks were just a misguided fantasy for the future; his company, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetpackaviation.com/&quot;&gt;Jetpack Aviation&lt;/a&gt;, has been building them and he’s been zooming around in publicity-grabbing stunts in a plea to the public that there’s room to dream when it comes to human flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while an eight-person startup aiming to build out a fleet of $380,000 “flying motorcycles” might seem like a tall order, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/y-combinator&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;y-combinator&quot;&gt;Y Combinator,&lt;/a&gt; a top accelerator known for its &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/13/nectome/&quot;&gt;occasionally bizarre bets&lt;/a&gt;, is gambling on the company and its jet engine-obsessed CEO in one of its latest investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube embed breakout embed--video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FneaFcVZyos?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/jetpack&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;jetpack&quot;&gt;Jetpack&lt;/a&gt; Aviation is about to become a very different company. The startup has launched pre-orders this week for the moonshot of moonshots, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jetpackaviation.com/recreational-speeder/&quot;&gt;Speeder&lt;/a&gt;, a personal vertical take-off and landing vehicle with a svelte concept design that looks straight out of Star Wars or Halo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep-pocketed, sci-fi-minded buyers are going to have to fork over $10,000 just to get a spot in the pre-order line for the first vehicles to ship, but the startup’s founder seems to see the campaign as less about the money than it is about the confirmation that there are people interested in planting a stake in his wild company’s future success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think it’s a validation statement for all of us,” Mayman tells TechCrunch. “If you look at how long Tesla took to deliver the Model 3 to customers, I think people understand that this is not something that’s a Kickstarted pre-delivery campaign where at the tail-end of it we’re immediately going to be delivering product.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are gambles and then there are flying motorcycles. This is frankly an atypical startup for YC to fund, but it is also an unconventional business path for Mayman, who has largely been self-financing his jetpack-building obsession for the past 12 years. &lt;span&gt;For the Australian CEO, the YC investment is mainly about gaining access to Silicon Valley’s network of VCs, though he also acknowledges it’s a fair assumption that SF breeds the type of executive that might be interested in pre-ordering something so seemingly outlandish. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I can’t imagine someone not being excited about a flying motorcycle,” YC partner Jared Friedman told TechCrunch in an email. “Jetpack Aviation created the future with Speeder, and I look forward to seeing how this technology transforms the dreaded commute, vacation travel, and everyday errands.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While much of the excitement Mayman has raised for his company’s jetpacks has relied on the spectacle of prototype demos in front of throngs of news networks (Jetpack Aviation has unsurprisingly partnered with Red Bull), the company has yet to build a full-scale prototype of the Speeder, though he says their new round of funding should get them there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1793808&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-1793808&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-1793808&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-6.16.08-PM.png?w=627&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;486&quot; height=&quot;526&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-6.16.08-PM.png 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-6.16.08-PM.png?resize=138,150 138w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-6.16.08-PM.png?resize=277,300 277w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-6.16.08-PM.png?resize=768,833 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-6.16.08-PM.png?resize=627,680 627w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-6.16.08-PM.png?resize=46,50 46w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 486px) 100vw, 486px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-1793808&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Mayman flying a jetpack around the Statue of Liberty in 2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can they actually build this? That’s seems to be a pretty valid question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our conversation, Mayman acknowledges upfront that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Speeder is “at least” two years of development time away from ending up in customer hands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company will have to raise “tens of millions” of dollars to ship this design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are still plenty of unknowns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jetpack Aviation’s current design is more ambitious than most helicopter-shaped concept VTOL vehicles being pursued by companies like Uber, namely due to its relatively sleek design where the human rider is directly above a set of several gimbal-mounted jet engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company claims finished designs will move faster than 150 mph at altitudes up to 15,000 feet. The flight time is still a limiting factor; max flight times for the models are estimated to be around 30 minutes. The company is planning a number of versions, including an ultralight model that complies with some federal regulations and won’t require a pilot’s license, the company says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The startup’s most pertinent problem is creating the autonomous stabilization technologies that will make flying the Speeder effortless and safe. Mayman notes that most VTOL designs look like quadcopters simply because the physics of putting weight directly on top of the thrust system is so challenging. “It’s like trying to balance a pencil on your finger,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His team has been training people to use their jetpacks — now in their 11th design iteration — and say it takes about a week to get potential flyers up-and-running with the particulars of the system. But Mayman says he wants this to be a device that just works, a design concept that made a lot of sense when Steve Jobs was using it to refer to the simplicity of the iPad, but feels a tad more aggressive when presented with the rendered images of someone flying this thing over city centers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube embed breakout embed--video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/URgznwTph6M?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the industry’s existing work around autonomous flight and stabilization for drone aircraft really doesn’t account for Jetpack Aviation’s design, though Mayman says they’ve already made some significant progress with their 1:3 scale prototype. He also notes that the company does have a “less elegant-looking” plan-B design if they determine the centrally clustered jet engines are too much of a stabilization liability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the key for getting a concept like this off the ground and ensuring the company doesn’t miserably fail is being flexible about how this vision matures, Mayman says, noting that they’re approaching the vehicle with multiple designs and multiple considerations for how the regulatory environment for certification shapes up, including work on a separate military version and consideration for designs more focused on emergency response like rapid medical evacuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked whether pre-orderers plunking down $10K might be disappointed by a different-looking product, the founder said that they’ve done enough modeling to know that what they build will fall into a roughly similar design. “It may not look exactly like what we’ve rendered, but I’m confident that it’s still going to be the same sort of concept, a motorcycle or jet-ski size and shape.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is certainly a unique choice for the company to launch its pre-orders already with so much in the air, but it’s fairly apparent that they are looking to emulate Tesla here, and if people with nearly $400K to throw around want to buy a jet-engine jet-ski, then by all means, let the free market do its thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Y Combinator’s $150,000 investment is an early step for the moonshot effort and a vote of confidence that places them on others’ radar. Mayman, for his part, does seem genuinely thrilled about expanding the ambitions of his passion project, even if the road ahead is crowded with obstacles for realizing the vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you don’t start it, you’re never going to get there,” Mayman says. “If our guys weren’t able to wake up every morning saying, ‘Holy shit, this would be freaking amazing if we can build this,’ then it’s sort of not worth doing. We might as well go do something else.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 03:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kristianp</dc:creator>
<og:title>YC’s latest moonshot bet is a startup building a $380K ‘flying motorcycle’</og:title>
<og:description>David Mayman has a vision for personal aviation that he’s spent the past dozen years and millions of his personal fortune chasing. He hasn’t accepted the convention that jetpacks were just a misguided fantasy for the future; his company, Jetpack Aviation, has been building them and he’s been zoomin…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/jetpack-aviation-speeder.jpg?w=712</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/03/07/ycs-latest-moonshot-bet-is-a-startup-building-a-380k-flying-motorcycle/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/07/ycs-latest-moonshot-bet-is-a-startup-building-a-380k-flying-motorcycle/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>800M Email Addresses Leaked Online by Email Verification Service</title>
<link>https://securitydiscovery.com/800-million-emails-leaked-online-by-email-verification-service/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://securitydiscovery.com/800-million-emails-leaked-online-by-email-verification-service/</guid>
<description>
&lt;div class=&quot;image-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1502&quot; height=&quot;1008&quot; src=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-3.58.36-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;attachment-full size-full wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-3.58.36-PM.png 1502w, https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-3.58.36-PM-300x201.png 300w, https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-3.58.36-PM-768x515.png 768w, https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-3.58.36-PM-1024x687.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1502px) 100vw, 1502px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot; data-initials=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;On February 25th, 2019, I discovered a non-password protected 150GB-sized MongoDB instance. This is perhaps the biggest and most comprehensive email database I have ever reported. Upon verification I was shocked at the massive number of emails that were publicly accessible for anyone with an internet connection. Some of data was much more detailed than just the email address and included personally identifiable information (PII).  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This database contained four separate collections of data and combined was an astounding 808,539,939 records. The largest part of it was named ‘mailEmailDatabase’ – and inside it contained three folders:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Emailrecords (count: 798,171,891 records)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;emailWithPhone (count: 4,150,600 records)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;businessLeads (count: 6,217,358 records)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-350&quot; src=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;511&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; srcset=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic3.jpg 692w, https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic3-300x241.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 511px) 100vw, 511px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;‘Emailrecords’ was structured  to include zip / phone / address / gender / email / user IP / DOB:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-348&quot; src=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;665&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; srcset=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic1.jpg 825w, https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic1-300x119.jpg 300w, https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic1-768x305.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 665px) 100vw, 665px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As part of the verification process I  cross-checked a random selection of records with Troy Hunt’s HaveIBeenPwned database. Based on the results, I came to conclusion that this is not just another ‘Collection’ of previously leaked sources but a completely unique set of data. Although, not all records contained the detailed profile information about the email owner, a large amount of records were very detailed. We are still talking about millions of records.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I started to analyze the content in an attempt to identify the owner and responsibly disclose it – even despite the fact that this started to look very much like a spam organization dataset.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In addition to the email databases this unprotected Mongo instance it also uncovered details on the possible owner of the database – a company named ‘Verifications.io’ – which offered the services of ‘Enterprise Email Validation’. Unfortunately, it appears that once emails were uploaded for verification they were also stored in plain text. Once I reported my discovery to Verifications.io the site was taken offline and is currently down at the time of this publication. &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20190227230352/https://verifications.io/&quot;&gt;Here is the archived version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-349&quot; src=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1898&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; srcset=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic2.jpg 1898w, https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic2-300x134.jpg 300w, https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic2-768x342.jpg 768w, https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic2-1024x456.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1898px) 100vw, 1898px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At this point I teamed up with Vinny Troya, owner of NightLion Security with whom I worked on other projects previously and who had a similar experience with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/exactis-database-leak-340-million-records/&quot;&gt;finding the Exactis database&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt; . I also sent a data breach notification email to the company’s support (yes, I decided it is a right thing to do).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-352&quot; src=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;518&quot; height=&quot;409&quot; srcset=&quot;https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic4.jpg 718w, https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/pic4-300x236.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 518px) 100vw, 518px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After researching more about Verifications.io online and comparing the information that was publicly available in the database we have come to the following conclusions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How this all works&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Someone uploads a list of email addresses that they want to validate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Verifications.io has a list of mail servers and internal email accounts that they use to “validate” an email address.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;They do this by literally sending the people an email. If it does not bounce, the email is validated.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;If it bounces, they put it in a bounce list so they can easily validate later on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is the scenario:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Mr. Threat Actor” has a list of 1000 companies that he wants to hack into. He has a bunch of potential users and passwords, but has no idea which ones are real. He could try to log in to a service or system using ALL of those accounts, but that type of brute force attack is very noisy and would likely be identified. Instead, he uploads all of his potential email addresses to a service like&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;verifications.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. The email verification service then sends tens of thousands of emails to validate these users (some real, some not). Each one of the users on the list gets their own spam message saying “hi”. Then the threat actor gets a cleaned, verified, and valid list of users at these companies. Now he knows who works there and who does not, and he can start a more focused phishing or brute forcing campaign.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I know this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The database(s) included email accounts they use for sending mail as well as hundreds of SMTP servers, email, spam traps, keywords to avoid, IP addresses to blacklist, and more. This is why I initially thought they were potentially engaged in spam related activities. It turns out that technically they actually are sending unwanted and unsolicited emails. This is the worst kind of spam because they send millions of completely worthless “hello” emails that no one can understand.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As I mentioned they did act fast and the database was taken down the same day I sent notification email to the company’s support. Ironically, they did reply to my notification. In the response they identified that what I had discovered was public data and not client data, so why close the database and take the site offline if it indeed was “public”? In addition to the email profiles this database also had access details and a user list of (130 records), with names and credentials to access FTP server to upload / download email lists (hosted on the same IP with MongoDB). We can only speculate that this was not meant to be public data.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;You can read more details about this discovery that was featured in: Wired – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/email-marketing-company-809-million-records-exposed-online/&quot;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About author and security researcher:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob Diachenko has over 12 years experience working in corporate/product/internal communications with a strong focus on infosecurity, IT and technology. In the past Bob has worked with top tier media, government agencies, and law enforcement to help secure exposed data. Follow Bob on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MayhemDayOne&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and his blog on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/vdyachenko/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;, Email: bob@securitydiscovery.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;entry-footer&quot;&gt;

&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 23:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tlrobinson</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>800+ Million Emails Leaked Online by Email Verification Service - Security Discovery</og:title>
<og:description>Our Biggest Data Breach Discovery of 2019 a massive 800 million emails leaked online. This data breach uncovered how an email verification service uses spam</og:description>
<og:url>https://securitydiscovery.com/800-million-emails-leaked-online-by-email-verification-service/</og:url>
<og:image>https://securitydiscovery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-06-at-3.58.36-PM.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://securitydiscovery.com/800-million-emails-leaked-online-by-email-verification-service/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to earn your macroeconomics and finance white belt as a software developer</title>
<link>https://notamonadtutorial.com/how-to-earn-your-macroeconomics-and-finance-white-belt-as-a-software-developer-136e7454866f</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://notamonadtutorial.com/how-to-earn-your-macroeconomics-and-finance-white-belt-as-a-software-developer-136e7454866f</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;uiScale uiScale-ui--regular uiScale-caption--regular u-flexCenter u-marginVertical24 u-fontSize15 js-postMetaLockup&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-flex0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link u-baseColor--link avatar&quot; href=&quot;https://notamonadtutorial.com/@unbalancedparen?source=post_header_lockup&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-source=&quot;post_header_lockup&quot; data-action-value=&quot;d257e779bd2c&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; data-user-id=&quot;d257e779bd2c&quot; data-collection-slug=&quot;this-is-not-a-monad-tutorial&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/100/100/1*8CQ8azFtqLAzUYdnx--Vxg.png&quot; class=&quot;avatar-image u-size50x50&quot; alt=&quot;Go to the profile of unbalancedparentheses&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*DqV2jwq55q04VQDnm1lP-A.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;1280&quot; data-height=&quot;720&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*DqV2jwq55q04VQDnm1lP-A.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*DqV2jwq55q04VQDnm1lP-A.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;12ff&quot; id=&quot;12ff&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;I was always interested in economics. However until a few years ago I never really studied finance. Since I decided to change that, I have learnt finance from reading good and bad books, online courses, newspapers, blog posts and online forums and by executing trades. This post sums up and prioritizes the roadmap I recommend taking to learn about finance. Having a deep understanding of macroeconomics is not necessary to learn about finance, even less if you are only looking to manage your own money. However, I highly recommend that you invest some time to understand the basic foundations of how the economy works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ead3&quot; id=&quot;ead3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Andrew Lo, an MIT economist, said that while physics has three laws that explain 99% of the phenomena, finance has 99 laws that explain only 3%. Not only do we not fully understand how the economy works but also there is an endless debate on how it should function. Everyone has values and an ideology even if they don’t tell you. You should keep that in mind while studying economics. In this roadmap I try to recommend the tools easily available and that are a part of the current economic thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8019&quot; id=&quot;8019&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;If you have any comment, question or critique you can find me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unbalancedparen&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unbalancedparen&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/unbalancedparen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;db13&quot; id=&quot;db13&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Basic macroeconomics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4b79&quot; id=&quot;4b79&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;How the economic machine works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ray Dalio, founder of the biggest hedge fund in the world, created this 30 minute video called &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/PHe0bXAIuk0&quot; data-href=&quot;https://youtu.be/PHe0bXAIuk0&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How the Economic machine works&lt;/a&gt;. In this video he shares his template to understand how the the economy works. What is taught in this video is simple but really important. Don’t just watch it, study it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;cd6f&quot; id=&quot;cd6f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;Investopedia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fc29&quot; id=&quot;fc29&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;Dalio’s video connects many concepts like transactions, market, central bank, monetary policy, fiscal policy, debt, collateral, credit, interest rate, inflation, deflation, productivity, economic cycles, deleveraging, recession and depression. If you don’t know what any of these words means or if you have doubts &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/search&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/search&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;search&lt;/a&gt; them. In most cases Investopedia will have simple and more begginner friendly definitions than Wikipedia. Also in general at the end of each article you can view useful examples and related concepts that it are useful to check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;a79b&quot; id=&quot;a79b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1027&quot; id=&quot;1027&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;Some time ago I saw an interview with an old priest that has dedicated his life to keeping the Latin language alive. The interviewer asked him: “Why are you so good at Latin?”. The priest answered: “Do you see where I am sitting on? My butt. You sit on your butt and study Latin as long as I have. You’ll be a master too”. So the general idea is that it takes time master something, but anybody can do it. My biggest recommendation to learn more about economics and finance is to get a subscription for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Economist&lt;/a&gt;. Read the Financial Times every day, specially the Markets and Opinions sections. Read the weekly Economist magazine, especially the Finance and Economics section. It’s like working out, after some time you will see big changes but you won’t be able to see them by doing short-term comparisons. Learning and reading about the financial and economic situation of different countries of the world can be overwhelming at the beginning. Geopolitics is closely related to economics. These three Youtube channels are great for making sense of what you read: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwnKziETDbHJtx78nIkfYug&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwnKziETDbHJtx78nIkfYug&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Caspian Report&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCT3v6vL2H5HK4loLMc8pmCw&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCT3v6vL2H5HK4loLMc8pmCw&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VisualPolitik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCmmPgObSUPw1HL2lq6H4ffA&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCmmPgObSUPw1HL2lq6H4ffA&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Geography Now&lt;/a&gt;. Geography Now is almost exclusively about geography but it is great to watch when you are reading news about a part of the world you don’t know much about. Caspian Report is the most profound of the three and tries to explain the deep structural reasons for what happens in the world. VisualPolitik doesn’t go as deep in the analysis as Caspian Report and has a noticeable political agenda but it is useful too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1022&quot; id=&quot;1022&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;My recommendation is that you avoid at all costs watching TV channels like CNBC or any newspaper that focus only on daily news. We live in a world without flavor, dominated by clickbait news and post-truth politics. Deep, slow to digest, opinionated analyses are hard to come by. I prefer to read anything that makes me think even if it is written by somebody that thinks or has opposite values to mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;8204&quot; id=&quot;8204&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;Macroeconomic courses and books (optional)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;eb45&quot; id=&quot;eb45&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;To better learn the concepts that where mentioned by Ray Dalio’s video you should follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khanacademy.org/economics-finance-domain/macroeconomics&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.khanacademy.org/economics-finance-domain/macroeconomics&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Khan’s Academy Macroeconomics course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;60f1&quot; id=&quot;60f1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I am not a big fan of textbooks since I find them way too schematic, but if you want to advance in the subject you will need to read one. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1753460.Principles_of_Economics&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1753460.Principles_of_Economics&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mankiw’s Principles of Economics&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/367710.Macroeconomics&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/367710.Macroeconomics&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Krugman’s Macroeconomy&lt;/a&gt; are the most basic. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1308531.Macroeconomics&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1308531.Macroeconomics&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Blanchard’s Macroeconomics&lt;/a&gt; is a little bit more advanced. I am giving many options since you will probably find one of the three books at your library. Keep in mind that studying one of this textbooks is not needed to advance in studying finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;ff95&quot; id=&quot;ff95&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Finance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;866b&quot; id=&quot;866b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;Learn basic finance to invest your own money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5420&quot; id=&quot;5420&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;The first thing I recommend that you do is to follow Nobel prize Robert &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/financial-markets-global&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/financial-markets-global&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shiller’s Financial Markets course&lt;/a&gt;. The course covers stocks, bonds, dividends, markets, brokers, exchanges, bubbles and basic financial market history. He explains things in a simple and concise way. With this course you will get a basic understanding of what finance is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;69bc&quot; id=&quot;69bc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The next step on your journey should be to get some practical experience. The best way to do this is to open a brokerage account to invest some of your own money. Fees and safety should be the main considerations when choosing which broker to use. Also your nationality and where you live are big factors when choosing a broker. I had good experiences with Interactive Brokers, Saxo Bank and DEGIRO. Robinhood is a new player that you should check out too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5903&quot; id=&quot;5903&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After opening your brokerage account you should decide what you want to invest in. The first book I recommend reading is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1119024927/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1119024927&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=aweaofcomsen-20&amp;amp;linkId=33NCCDPJIVOFUTL5&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1119024927/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1119024927&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=aweaofcomsen-20&amp;amp;linkId=33NCCDPJIVOFUTL5&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Wealth of Common Sense&lt;/a&gt;. It is a very good book that explains how to create a simple framework to decide how to invest for the long term. A more dry and profound book to read that is pretty similar to the previous one is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Random-Walk-Down-Wall-Street/dp/1324002182&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Random-Walk-Down-Wall-Street/dp/1324002182&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Random Walk Down Wall Street&lt;/a&gt;. It is an excellent critique to the so-called technical analysis and it sums up the different investigations that have shown that humans are not rational investors. It is a good book that demonstrates that for the retail investors the best thing to do is to put their money in passive, low-fee investment vehicles instead of paying a money manager that charges a lot and doesn’t even deliver market returns. My biggest issue with the book it is that it adheres way too strongly to the Efficient Market Hypothesis (EMH). Eugene Fama, another Nobel prize and one of the most important EMH adherents, said that &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;“In an efficient market, at any point in time, the actual price of a security will be a good estimate of its intrinsic value”&lt;/em&gt;. That means that in general there is no free money laying around or that getting above-average returns is really difficult. That is correct especially for the retail and individual investor. However as you will see in the advanced part of this roadmap I recommend books that are critical of this theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5a52&quot; id=&quot;5a52&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Two great books that explain more complex investment strategies are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25029029&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25029029&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Global Asset Allocation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21518331-global-value&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21518331-global-value&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Global Value&lt;/a&gt;. The Global Asset Allocation shows how diversifying your portfolio outside bonds and stocks can be useful. Global Value Allocation shows how investing in countries that are cheap, measured by fundamentals like the Price/Earnings ratio, gets your great returns in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f1ff&quot; id=&quot;f1ff&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;With Shiller’s course and these four books plus your broker account you should be perfectly able to invest your money in an intelligent way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;1ee5&quot; id=&quot;1ee5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Financial theory and derivatives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;16c7&quot; id=&quot;16c7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;At the beginning, learning about futures, swaps, options or derivatives can be overwhelming. Before stepping into more technical grounds I recommend that you read about the history of hedge funds with their successes and failures to understand what they did and how. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/more-money-than-god-sebastian-mallaby/1100257890&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/more-money-than-god-sebastian-mallaby/1100257890&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;More Money Than God: Hedge Funds and the Making of A New Elite&lt;/a&gt; by Mallaby does just that. A quote from the book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;6f58&quot; id=&quot;6f58&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Weymar looked to his teachers for help in refining his mathematical and computing skills, he was unimpressed by their efficient-market theories. “I thought random walk was bullshit,” he said later. “The whole idea that an individual can’t make serious money with a competitive edge over the rest of the market is wacko.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;22ea&quot; id=&quot;22ea&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;As you can see, this book goes in the opposite direction than A Random Walk Down Wall Street. The success of the main protagonists depends on finding market inefficiencies, they are not believers in efficient market hypothesis. Thanks to a hedge fund called Quantopian that provides data, a development platform and education, you can write your own investment algorithms and backtest them to find this type of small market inefficiencies. Their free &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantopian.com/lectures&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.quantopian.com/lectures&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lectures&lt;/a&gt; are a great resource that you should follow if you know how to code in Python and if you have some knowledge in probability and statistics. They will introduce you to futures, the Capital Asset Pricing Model, alpha and beta, factors, means reversion, pairs trading and long-short strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f6ab&quot; id=&quot;f6ab&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After following these lectures it is time to move on into learning about options. Options are difficult because you are leveraged, they react non-linearly to volatility changes, time plays a huge factor in their pricing and their payoff function can be convex or concave (if you don’t understand what these words mean don’t worry). You can be right about your bet but still lose money and the other way around. They are a counter-intuitive beast. You can create a strategy with options that looses money 99% of the time and still make enough money on the 1% case to recover everything that was lost and more. There are two books I have used to understand options. The first book I have read is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/100827.Options_Futures_and_Other_Derivatives&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/100827.Options_Futures_and_Other_Derivatives&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Options, Futures and Other Derivatives by John Hul&lt;/a&gt;. It is a textbook that explains all the moving parts of a trade that involves derivatives. A good thing about the book is that is has quite a few exercises after each chapter so that you can double-check you really understood what you have read. Since it was difficult for me to grasp everything I have read from Hul’s book, I decided to read a second book called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/119373.Option_Volatility_Pricing&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/119373.Option_Volatility_Pricing&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Option Volatility &amp;amp; Pricing: Advanced Trading Strategies and Techniques&lt;/a&gt; that was written by Natenberg. The tone of the book felt like it was written by a practitioner. It was easier to digest. Hul’s book seemed a little bit more advance and I think it is better to read Natenberg book first and Hul’s book afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;68da&quot; id=&quot;68da&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After learning the theory you should do some paper trading and real trading with options and futures before moving on. Now it is time to switch from the technical side of things to learning more about the history of financial theory and its critics. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/665134.The_Mis_Behavior_of_Markets&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/665134.The_Mis_Behavior_of_Markets&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Misbehavior of Markets: A Fractal View of Financial Turbulence by Mandelbrot&lt;/a&gt; is a book that summarizes the history of modern financial theory. After that, it shows that modern financial theory doesn’t take into account big market moves that happen more frequently that what the theory predicts. At the end of the book Mandelbrot proposes other ways of modelling financial markets. I found the critique more interesting than the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bdcc&quot; id=&quot;bdcc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13530973-antifragile&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13530973-antifragile&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Antifragile by Taleb&lt;/a&gt; is a book that summarizes many ideas that Taleb wrote in Fooled by Randomness and The Black Swan. Similar to what Mandelbrot wrote, Taleb proposes that unpredictable events are far more frequent and influential than most models take into account. Therefore, we should build anything, including our financial strategies, in a manner that benefits from chaos rather than try to avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e71d&quot; id=&quot;e71d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After learning about the tools at your disposal and the dangers involved in trading with options it is time to learn how to really trade volatility. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24945749-trading-volatility&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24945749-trading-volatility&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trading Volatility by Bennett&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5404804-volatility-trading&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5404804-volatility-trading&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Volatility Trading by Euan Sinclair&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/31867439-the-volatility-smile&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/31867439-the-volatility-smile&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Volatility Smile by Emanuel Derman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/204689.Dynamic_Hedging&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/204689.Dynamic_Hedging&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dynamic Hedging by Nassim Taleb&lt;/a&gt; are the best books in the area. I have only studied the first two. The last two are more complex and I have only done superficially and rapid lecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;c0dd&quot; id=&quot;c0dd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Other skills&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;58de&quot; id=&quot;58de&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;At some point you need to learn more about financial accounting. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUkh9m2BorqnKWu0g5ZUps_CbQ-JGtbI9&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUkh9m2BorqnKWu0g5ZUps_CbQ-JGtbI9&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Aswath Damodaran has a great course&lt;/a&gt; about companies valuation that I recommend that you follow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;db69&quot; id=&quot;db69&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The modern monetary system can not be separated from the financial markets. This was deeply visible in the last financial crisis. It is important to understand how the banking and monetary system works from a practical point of view. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/money-banking&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/money-banking&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mehrling’s course&lt;/a&gt; is a great introduction to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;259e&quot; id=&quot;259e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;At last, probability and statistics are the best tools we have to assess an work with risk. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12042357-think-stats&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12042357-think-stats&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thinks Stats&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://camdavidsonpilon.github.io/Probabilistic-Programming-and-Bayesian-Methods-for-Hackers/#contents&quot; data-href=&quot;http://camdavidsonpilon.github.io/Probabilistic-Programming-and-Bayesian-Methods-for-Hackers/#contents&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Probabilistic Programming &amp;amp; Bayesian Methods for Hackers&lt;/a&gt; are the best practical books I can recommend to quickly learn probability and statistics. If you want to start the trip that goes down the rabbit hole I recommend that you do &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/statistics&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/statistics&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Statistics with R Specialization by Duke&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 22:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>andrenth</dc:creator>
<og:title>How to earn your Macroeconomics and Finance white belt (as a software developer)</og:title>
<og:url>https://notamonadtutorial.com/how-to-earn-your-macroeconomics-and-finance-white-belt-as-a-software-developer-136e7454866f</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*DqV2jwq55q04VQDnm1lP-A.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>I was always interested in economics. However until a few years ago I never really studied finance. Since I decided to change that, I have…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://notamonadtutorial.com/how-to-earn-your-macroeconomics-and-finance-white-belt-as-a-software-developer-136e7454866f?gi=2d28888f328c</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber Not Criminally Liable in Death of Woman Hit by Self-Driving Car</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/2019/03/06/700801945/uber-not-criminally-liable-in-death-of-woman-hit-by-self-driving-car-says-prosec</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/2019/03/06/700801945/uber-not-criminally-liable-in-death-of-woman-hit-by-self-driving-car-says-prosec</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res700811089&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/03/06/ap_18144485254712-d2b0f98802ea1f83666ea3a8d8e016c5449ea4d5-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/03/06/ap_18144485254712-d2b0f98802ea1f83666ea3a8d8e016c5449ea4d5-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video still from a mounted camera captures the moment before a self-driving Uber SUV fatally struck a woman in Tempe, Ariz., last March. A Yavapai County prosecutor found that Uber is not criminally liable for the crash. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Tempe Police Department /AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Tempe Police Department /AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/03/06/ap_18144485254712-d2b0f98802ea1f83666ea3a8d8e016c5449ea4d5-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A video still from a mounted camera captures the moment before a self-driving Uber SUV fatally struck a woman in Tempe, Ariz., last March. A Yavapai County prosecutor found that Uber is not criminally liable for the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Tempe Police Department /AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated at 3:15 p.m. ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Arizona prosecutor has determined that Uber is not criminally liable in the death of a Tempe woman who was struck by a self-driving test car last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;After a very thorough review of all the evidence presented, this Office has determined that there is no basis for criminal liability for the Uber corporation arising from this matter,&quot; the Yavapai County Attorney's Office wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.documentcloud.org/documents/5759641/UberCrashYavapaiRuling03052019.pdf&quot;&gt;in a letter&lt;/a&gt; to the Maricopa County Attorney's Office. Tempe is in Maricopa County, but Yavapai County took the case due to a potential conflict of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elaine Herzberg, 49, was walking a bicycle across the road at night when she was fatally struck by a Volvo SUV outfitted with an Uber self-driving system in March 2018. The car had a human operator behind the wheel but was in computer control mode at the time of the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res700816615&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage614200117&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/05/24/614200117/ntsb-uber-self-driving-car-had-disabled-emergency-brake-system-before-fatal-cras&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/thetwo-way\/2018\/05\/24\/614200117\/ntsb-uber-self-driving-car-had-disabled-emergency-brake-system-before-fatal-cras&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/05/24/ap_18078673473478_sq-0ab70472ec7989937bd9769a31db464f9bf91126-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/05/24/ap_18078673473478_sq-0ab70472ec7989937bd9769a31db464f9bf91126-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;NTSB: Uber Self-Driving Car Had Disabled Emergency Brake System Before Fatal Crash&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the six seconds before impact, the self-driving system classified the pedestrian as an unknown object, then as a vehicle, and then as a bicycle, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ntsb.gov/investigations/AccidentReports/Reports/HWY18MH010-prelim.pdf&quot;&gt;a preliminary report&lt;/a&gt; from the National Transportation Safety Board explained. While the system identified that an emergency braking maneuver was needed to mitigate a collision, the system was set up to not activate emergency braking when under computer control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, the car's system relied on the human operator to intervene as needed. &quot;The system is not designed to alert the operator,&quot; the report notes. The driver swerved less than a second before the crash and did not brake until after impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;res700831151&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage595941015&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/03/21/595941015/police-in-arizona-release-dashcam-video-of-fatal-crash-involving-self-driving-ca&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/thetwo-way\/2018\/03\/21\/595941015\/police-in-arizona-release-dashcam-video-of-fatal-crash-involving-self-driving-ca&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/21/ap_18081019249634_sq-c7be3dd2ec629914322ed50c2a20a0e0e9717970-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/21/ap_18081019249634_sq-c7be3dd2ec629914322ed50c2a20a0e0e9717970-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Police In Arizona Release Dashcam Video Of Fatal Crash Involving Self-Driving Car &quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Arizona Republic&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.azcentral.com/story/news/local/tempe-breaking/2018/06/21/uber-self-driving-car-crash-tempe-police-elaine-herzberg/724344002/&quot;&gt;has reported&lt;/a&gt; that the driver, 44-year-old Rafaela Vasquez, was streaming the television show &lt;em&gt;The Voice&lt;/em&gt; in the vehicle in the minutes before the crash. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/03/21/595941015/police-in-arizona-release-dashcam-video-of-fatal-crash-involving-self-driving-ca&quot;&gt;Video from a camera inside the car&lt;/a&gt; shows Vasquez looking down immediately before the crash, glancing up at the road from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vasquez could face charges of manslaughter. The prosecutor's letter recommends expert analysis of the collision video that would show what the driver &quot;would or should have seen that night given the vehicle's speed, lighting conditions, and other relevant factors.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber, which declined to comment for this story, could still be sued in civil court and be forced to pay damages. The government could also potentially pursue criminal charges against managers or employees of Uber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res700816839&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage595115055&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/03/20/595115055/arizona-governor-helped-make-state-wild-west-for-driverless-cars&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/thetwo-way\/2018\/03\/20\/595115055\/arizona-governor-helped-make-state-wild-west-for-driverless-cars&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/20/ap_18078639838919_sq-b45b1ee246f71462202ac98b3f66efe7fae35a99-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/03/20/ap_18078639838919_sq-b45b1ee246f71462202ac98b3f66efe7fae35a99-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Arizona Governor Helped Make State 'Wild West' For Driverless Cars&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herzberg's family &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/03/29/597850303/uber-reaches-settlement-with-family-of-arizona-woman-killed-by-driverless-car&quot;&gt;reached a settlement&lt;/a&gt; with the company shortly after the crash. Her husband and daughter have also sued the city of Tempe, alleging that a brick pathway that crosses the landscaping was designed for people to cross at the accident site, the &lt;em&gt;Republic&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.azcentral.com/story/news/local/tempe/2019/03/05/no-criminal-charges-uber-fatal-tempe-crash-tempe-police-further-investigate-driver/3071369002/&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. The city has since torn out the pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bryant Walker Smith, a University of South Carolina law professor whose research focuses on automated driving systems, suggests not reading too much into the prosecutor's letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's not necessarily exculpatory — it doesn't exonerate Uber or put the company's conduct then or now beyond criticism,&quot; he writes in an email to NPR. &quot;And I'm not sure it tells us much about the criminal, much less civil, liability of automated driving developers in future incidents.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith says he hopes the NTSB's final report on the crash will illuminate more about the crash. &quot;And I would still like to see Uber publicly apologize and explain what specifically went wrong,&quot; he says. &quot;Companies should earn our trust in part by being candid about their failures as well as their successes.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 22:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>abhisuri97</dc:creator>
<og:title>Uber Not Criminally Liable In Death Of Woman Hit By Self-Driving Car, Prosecutor Says</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/2019/03/06/700801945/uber-not-criminally-liable-in-death-of-woman-hit-by-self-driving-car-says-prosec</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The woman was walking a bicycle across the road when she was fatally struck by the SUV. The car had a human operator behind the wheel but was in computer control mode at the time of the crash.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/03/06/ap_18144485254712_wide-4e820754e11d19d12b30dcf6d5ca28dab938384f.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/2019/03/06/700801945/uber-not-criminally-liable-in-death-of-woman-hit-by-self-driving-car-says-prosec</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stop Wasting Connections, Use HTTP Keep-Alive</title>
<link>https://lob.com/blog/use-http-keep-alive</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lob.com/blog/use-http-keep-alive</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;With the proliferation of third-party APIs and microservice architectures, modern web servers can make as many outgoing HTTP requests as the number of incoming HTTP requests they serve. A typical web application can interact with third-party APIs to handle payment processing, send email, track analytics, dispatch text messages, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lob.com/products/address-verification&quot;&gt;verify mailing addresses&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://lob.com/products/print-mail/postcards&quot;&gt;even deliver physical mail&lt;/a&gt;. A server can also rely on internal APIs to fetch account information, start asynchronous processes, or perform complex searches. Programs that initiate a high volume of outgoing HTTP requests must minimize the overhead of each in order to remain performant and optimize resource utilization.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to minimize HTTP overhead is to reuse connections with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_persistent_connection&quot;&gt;HTTP Keep-Alive&lt;/a&gt;. This feature is commonly enabled by default for many HTTP clients. These clients will maintain a pool of connections—each connection initializes once and handles multiple requests until the connection is closed. Reusing a connection avoids the overhead of making a DNS lookup, establishing a connection, and performing an SSL handshake. However, not all HTTP clients, including the default client of Node.js, enable HTTP Keep-Alive.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Lob’s backend services is heavily dependent on internal and external APIs to verify addresses, dispatch webhooks, start AWS Lambda executions, and more. This Node.js server has a handful of endpoints that make several outgoing HTTP requests per incoming request. Enabling connection reuse for these outgoing requests led to a 50% increase in maximum inbound request throughput, significantly reduced CPU usage, and lowered response latencies. It also eliminated sporadic DNS lookup errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance Benefits of HTTP Keep-Alive&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a benchmark validates the performance benefits of HTTP Keep-alive. The following chart displays the total time taken to make 1000 GET requests for both non-reused and reused connections with a varying number of requests made concurrently. It shows that for all levels of tested concurrency, reusing connections reduces the total run time by a factor of roughly 3.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/Cjpzj6oH6bC-X9dEZ-kBAqpvQVErZ2yLhUBMZaN04d6lf2_45rP5iM-X0py8nfkXyx_ErMJg-ew-Eq_ejgxy80yLcO93Uo4g0ZxsU1juicDBclvcSEgV0g4LQ1D4eWeA2k4jHYY3&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another observed benefit of reusing HTTP connections is reduced CPU utilization. On Mac OS X, this reduction manifests in the Node process itself and in a process named mDNSResponder, an operating system service responsible for resolving DNS. Running &lt;code&gt;top -stats pid,command,cpu | grep -E &quot;(mDNSResponder|node)\s&quot;&lt;/code&gt; during both benchmarks shows the contrast in CPU usage.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Without Connection Reuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;crayon-5c83025a8d5db055775169&quot; class=&quot;crayon-syntax crayon-theme-github crayon-font-monospace crayon-os-pc print-yes notranslate&quot; data-settings=&quot; minimize scroll-mouseover&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;crayon-main&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;crayon-table&quot; readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;crayon-row&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;crayon-nums&quot; data-settings=&quot;show&quot;&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;crayon-code&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;crayon-pre&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-e&quot;&gt;PID    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-e&quot;&gt;Process          &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-v&quot;&gt;CPU&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;crayon-o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-cn&quot;&gt;63702&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-h&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-i&quot;&gt;node&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-h&quot;&gt;            &lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;crayon-cn&quot;&gt;24.2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-cn&quot;&gt;231&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-h&quot;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-i&quot;&gt;mDNSResponder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-h&quot;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-cn&quot;&gt;6.5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With Connection Reuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;crayon-5c83025a8d5e5049268863&quot; class=&quot;crayon-syntax crayon-theme-github crayon-font-monospace crayon-os-pc print-yes notranslate&quot; data-settings=&quot; minimize scroll-mouseover&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;crayon-main&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;crayon-table&quot; readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;crayon-row&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;crayon-nums&quot; data-settings=&quot;show&quot;&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;crayon-code&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;crayon-pre&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-e&quot;&gt;PID    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-e&quot;&gt;Process          &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-v&quot;&gt;CPU&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;crayon-o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-cn&quot;&gt;63823&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-h&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-i&quot;&gt;node&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-h&quot;&gt;            &lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;crayon-cn&quot;&gt;9.7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-cn&quot;&gt;231&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-h&quot;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-i&quot;&gt;mDNSResponder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-h&quot;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;crayon-cn&quot;&gt;0.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspecting the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brendangregg.com/FlameGraphs/cpuflamegraphs.html&quot;&gt;flamegraph&lt;/a&gt; of the benchmark script without connection reuse reveals the reason for increased CPU utilization in Node. A large percentage of CPU time is spent on establishing connections and performing SSL handshakes. For example, the flame fragment below shows that 14% of measured CPU ticks occurred while creating a socket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/pW86iSS-6_UDIC6PiICGF9kEjlbHyz8iopPK830wMvI-i6xENhtVdZv14mm2yJAr9LsjaENKOIWJmNbh220eVnlFaaEemft09w3ZbIjuwIsxf0QJdhmzkmPIjtpsin0FY92C6rfd&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that initiating connections also incurs overhead for HTTP servers. Therefore, reusing connections also reduces overhead for servers handling these requests.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flamegraphs of each benchmark are available to explore: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mgartner.github.io/node-keep-alive-benchmark/docs/keep-alive-off.html&quot;&gt;flamegraph without connection reuse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mgartner.github.io/node-keep-alive-benchmark/docs/keep-alive-on.html&quot;&gt;flamegraph with connection reuse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benchmarking scripts are documented in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mgartner/node-keep-alive-benchmark&quot;&gt;node-keep-alive-benchmark&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reduced DNS Errors&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reusing connections also eliminated a set of DNS errors that occurred sporadically within our service. When connections are not reused, a new connection is initialized for each outgoing request. In Node, this initialization includes a DNS lookup to determine the IP of the domain to send the request to. A high volume of DNS lookups can lead to sporadic errors of the form &lt;strong&gt;Error: getaddrinfo ENOTFOUND&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on several issues in the Node repository (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nodejs/node-v0.x-archive/issues/7729&quot;&gt;nodejs/node-v0.x-archive#7729&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nodejs/node-v0.x-archive/issues/5488&quot;&gt;nodejs/node-v0.x-archive#5488&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nodejs/node/issues/5436&quot;&gt;nodejs/node#5436&lt;/a&gt;) this error can occur when a DNS server fail to respond, perhaps due to it rate-limiting requests. Reducing DNS lookups can reduce or eliminate these errors.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tips when Reusing Connections&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Check Your Timeouts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, reusing connections can lead to hard-to-debug issues. Problems can arise when a client assumes that a connection is alive and well, only to discover that, upon sending a request, the server has terminated the connection. In Node, this problem surfaces as an &lt;strong&gt;Error: socket hang up&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mitigate this, check the idle socket timeouts of both the client and the server. This value represents how long a connection will be kept alive when no data is sent or received. Make sure that the idle socket timeout of the client is shorter than that of the server. This should ensure that the client closes a connection before the server, preventing the client from sending a request down an unknowingly dead connection.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don’t Use Node’s Default HTTP Agents&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Node services, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/node-modules/agentkeepalive&quot;&gt;agentkeepalive&lt;/a&gt; library provides HTTP and HTTPS agents that enable connection reuse by default. These agents also have other sensible defaults that the standard libraries agents do not.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connection reuse should provide significant performance improvements to services written in any language that are making numerous outgoing HTTP requests. Some HTTP clients enable this behavior by default, but not all. Some widely used languages and libraries do not enable HTTP Keep-Alive by default, such as Node, so be sure to check the documentation and source code.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, Lob is hiring! If you are interested in joining a growing company that fosters curiosity, diligence, and collaboration, we’d love to hear from you. Check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://lob.com/careers&quot;&gt;careers page&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 20:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mgartner</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://lob.com/blog/use-http-keep-alive/</og:url>
<og:title>Stop Wasting Connections, Use HTTP Keep-Alive</og:title>
<og:image>https://wp.lob.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/cable-cat-5e-colorful-47079-1024x683.jpg</og:image>
<og:description> With the proliferation of third-party APIs and microservice architectures, modern web servers can make as many outgoing HTTP requests as the number of incoming HTTP requests they serve. A typical web application can interact with third-party APIs to handle payment processing, send ...</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lob.com/blog/use-http-keep-alive</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>