<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Hijack of Amazon’s domain service used to reroute web traffic for two hours</title>
<link>https://doublepulsar.com/hijack-of-amazons-internet-domain-service-used-to-reroute-web-traffic-for-two-hours-unnoticed-3a6f0dda6a6f</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://doublepulsar.com/hijack-of-amazons-internet-domain-service-used-to-reroute-web-traffic-for-two-hours-unnoticed-3a6f0dda6a6f</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;d5b0&quot; id=&quot;d5b0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Between 11am until 1pm UTC today, DNS traffic — the phone book of the internet, routing you to your favourite websites — was hijacked by an unknown actor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*-eV5KvjGyHqRMEmsc2YZ5w.png&quot; data-width=&quot;497&quot; data-height=&quot;486&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*-eV5KvjGyHqRMEmsc2YZ5w.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7d30&quot; id=&quot;7d30&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The attackers used BGP — a key protocol used for routing internet traffic around the world — to reroute traffic to Amazon’s Route 53 service, the largest commercial cloud provider who count major websites such as Twitter.com as customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8bc2&quot; id=&quot;8bc2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;They re-routed DNS traffic using a man in the middle attack using a server at Equinix in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c01e&quot; id=&quot;c01e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;From there, they served traffic for over two hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*lRhC-FlKHnBHp7NUdu7kyQ@2x.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;1988&quot; data-height=&quot;1386&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*lRhC-FlKHnBHp7NUdu7kyQ@2x.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*lRhC-FlKHnBHp7NUdu7kyQ@2x.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3fb1&quot; id=&quot;3fb1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure graf--trailing&quot;&gt;This would allow them to intercept traffic globally across the internet to Amazon Route 53 customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 17:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<og:title>Hijack of Amazon’s internet domain service used to reroute web traffic for two hours unnoticed</og:title>
<og:url>https://doublepulsar.com/hijack-of-amazons-internet-domain-service-used-to-reroute-web-traffic-for-two-hours-unnoticed-3a6f0dda6a6f</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*-eV5KvjGyHqRMEmsc2YZ5w.png</og:image>
<og:description>Between 11am until 1pm UTC today, DNS traffic — the phone book of the internet, routing you to your favourite websites — was hijacked by…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://doublepulsar.com/hijack-of-amazons-internet-domain-service-used-to-reroute-web-traffic-for-two-hours-unnoticed-3a6f0dda6a6f?gi=9b6f9e9f10a2</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Patent Review System Upheld by U.S. Supreme Court</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-24/patent-death-squad-system-upheld-by-u-s-supreme-court</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-24/patent-death-squad-system-upheld-by-u-s-supreme-court</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court upheld an administrative review system that has helped Google Inc., Apple Inc. and other companies invalidate hundreds of issued patents.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The justices, &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/16-712_87ad.pdf&quot; title=&quot;link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;voting&lt;/a&gt; 7-2, said Tuesday a U.S. Patent and Trademark Office review board that critics call a patent &quot;death squad&quot; wasn’t unconstitutionally wielding powers that belong to the courts.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Silicon Valley companies have used the system as a less-expensive way to ward off demands for royalties, particularly from patent owners derided as &quot;trolls&quot; because they don’t use their patents to make products. Drugmakers and independent inventors complain that it unfairly upends what they thought were established property rights.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;“It came down to this: Is the patent office fixing its own mistakes or is the government taking property?” said Wayne Stacy, a patent lawyer with Baker Botts. “They came down on the side of the patent office fixing its own mistakes.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The ruling caused shares to drop in companies whose main source of revenue -- their patents -- are under threat from challenges. VirnetX Holding Corp., which is trying to protect almost $1 billion in damages it won against Apple, dropped as much as 12 percent and closed down 8.5 percent. The patent office has said its patents are invalid in a case currently before an appeals court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court’s ruling “will reassure, if not embolden, patent challengers,” said Christopher Bruno, a patent lawyer with Schiff Hardin. Patent owners are likely to turn their focus to asking courts to scrutinize some of the procedures used by the board, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;‘Public Rights’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drugmakers, research companies and independent inventors &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-09-20/apple-likes-the-patent-death-squad-allergan-pays-to-avoid-it&quot; title=&quot;Apple Likes the Patent ‘Death Squad.’ Allergan Avoids It (1)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;criticized&lt;/a&gt; the Patent Trial and Appeal Board, saying its rules unfairly lean toward challengers and make it harder to fend off competitors and protect their ideas from copycats. Congress set up the system in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justice Clarence Thomas wrote the court’s majority opinion, rejecting contentions that issued patents are the type of rights that must be adjudicated only in the federal courts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The decision to grant a patent is a matter involving public rights -- specifically, the grant of a public franchise,&quot; Thomas wrote. The review system &quot;is simply a reconsideration of that grant, and Congress has permissibly reserved the PTO’s authority to conduct that reconsideration.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ruling addressed only whether the reviews are constitutional and doesn’t limit arguments in other contexts that patents are property, Thomas wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s common sense -- we trust them to make these decisions in the first place,” said lawyer Andrew Pincus of Mayer Brown, who submitted legal arguments on behalf of BSA - The Software Alliance. “There are costs to having patents that are overbroad or shouldn’t have been granted. We want to do as much as we can to make sure the experts got it right.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;‘Give a Gift’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Justice John Roberts and Justice Neil Gorsuch dissented. “Just because you give a gift doesn’t mean you forever enjoy the right to reclaim it,” Gorsuch wrote for the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court also issued a ruling Tuesday in a separate case involving proceedings at the patent review board. In that 5-4 &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/16-969_f2qg.pdf&quot; title=&quot;link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;decision&lt;/a&gt;, Gorsuch wrote for the court that the board must issue final written decisions on all parts of a patent that are questioned in a challenge, even if the board decides to review only some of them. The effect will force patent owners’ challenges filed at the agency to be more targeted, because they aren’t allowed to raise issues decided by the review board if they go to court later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the reviews began in 2012, more than 7,000 petitions have been filed, primarily on computer and high-tech patents. Former patent office Director Michelle Lee said changes have been made to the process to make it more fair and clear, and more are being considered by the agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said the reviews were “never a death squad” that critics called it, and were set up as a lower-cost alternative to litigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The review system was created in response to business complaints about what they considered abusive patent litigation. Other court rulings and changes in how lawsuits are filed have made it easier for accused infringers to fend off lawsuits and demand payment for legal costs when they win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;‘All a Balance’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People could disagree about the numbers or the cost, but it was an issue clearly faced by a number of companies,” Lee said. “Most abusive patent litigation, that there was a lot of concern about, has been mitigated. At the same time, we want to make sure patent owners and inventors have enough incentive. It’s all a balance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Oil States decision was called a “disgrace” by members of U.S. Inventor, a group of independent inventors that protested outside the Supreme Court when arguments were heard in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Inventors, aspiring inventors, and patriots of all kinds are devastated by today’s Supreme Court ruling,” said Josh Malone, inventor of the Bunch O Balloons toy who has seen his patents challenged at the agency and &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/terminal/OZSQVY6TTDS1&quot; title=&quot;Retailers Lose Water Balloon Battle in Texas Courtroom&quot; class=&quot;terminal-news-story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;upheld&lt;/a&gt; in court. “Now if a big corporation wants your patents or your land, they only need to convince their friends in the administrative tribunal or city council to do the job. No judge, no jury, no America.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul Fucito, a spokesman for the patent office, said it is “carefully considering the Supreme Court’s decisions and determining their impact on various proceedings at the PTAB.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pharmaceutical Research and Manufacturers of America, which represents the biggest drugmakers, said the two decisions show that the system needs refinement, either through the agency or Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade group for biotechnology firms said some aspects of the decision upholding the review system are “encouraging.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Supreme Court did not accept the government’s devaluing theory that patents are little more than government benefits that can be awarded and reclaimed by administrators,” said Hans Sauer, deputy general counsel for the Biotechnology Innovation Organization. “The court signals that a patent owner’s settled, investment-backed expectations continue to be important, and that it is not irrelevant if patent owners have built businesses, and staked their livelihoods, in reliance on a patent that was examined and issued by the Patent Office.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United for Patent Reform, which represents retailers, automakers like Ford Motor Co. and General Motors Co. and some tech companies including Google and Facebook Inc., said the review procedures “strengthen our patent system and improve overall patent quality.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This ruling will help ensure that American inventors and businesses can focus on building products and creating jobs rather than paying to fend off abusive litigation,” the group said in a &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.unitedforpatentreform.com/files/ipr-supreme-3-24-18-final134413536.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Statement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEEE-USA, a trade group for engineers, computer and technology professionals, said the reviews hurt small businesses and start-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This decision highlights the need for Congress to repair damage done to our intellectual property system,” Maura Moran, former vice president of government relations for the group, said in a &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://ieeeusa.org/release-04-24-19/&quot; title=&quot;Statement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cases are Oil States v. Greene’s Energy Group, 16-712, and SAS Institute Inc. v. Iancu, 16-969.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 14:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jackfoxy</dc:creator>
<og:description>The U.S. Supreme Court upheld an administrative review system that has helped Google Inc., Apple Inc. and other companies invalidate hundreds of issued patents.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i5_vEuCT6bKM/v0/1200x800.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Patent ‘Death Squad’ System Upheld by U.S. Supreme Court</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-24/patent-death-squad-system-upheld-by-u-s-supreme-court</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-24/patent-death-squad-system-upheld-by-u-s-supreme-court</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dumber phone</title>
<link>https://nomasters.io/posts/dumber-phone/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nomasters.io/posts/dumber-phone/</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less is exponentially more – Rob Pike&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart phones are useful, but they are also &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2017/11/30/health/smartphone-addiction-study/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;incredibly addictive&lt;/a&gt;, and that addiction is at the epicenter of Silicon Valley’s effort to grab an ever increasing percentage of our minds. In that a substance or behavior controls us, it becomes our master, and that just won’t do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the humor of it, lets use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webmd.com/mental-health/addiction/signs-of-drug-addiction#1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this webMD post&lt;/a&gt; and only slightly modify key signature behaviors outlined to describe smart phone usage addiction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You keep using your phone after it’s no longer needed to solve a problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You spend more and more of your time on your phone to get the same effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You feel strange when you don’t have your phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can’t stop yourself from using your phone, even if you don’t want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have a hard time giving yourself limits. You might say you’ll only use “so much” but then can’t stop and end up using twice that amount. Or you use it more often than you meant to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’ve begun having trouble doing normal daily things without your phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You drive or do other dangerous things (like use heavy machines) while you are on your phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You borrow money to pay for your phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You hide some phone use or the effect it is having on you from others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The smart phone represent something quite unique when it comes to the human mind. It opens an always on, always connected portal to a large assortment of variable reward machines. Pick your poison: email, stock trackers, social media, news feeds, link aggregators; list goes on and on. But despite all of the tooling and potential it provides, it introduces an entire swath of repetitive behavior modification that isn’t appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its a strange mix of variable reward pocket casino and surveillance capitalism that hooks us. The pocket casino’s price to play is your attention and it pays out a seemingly never ending supply of dopamine to your brain. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffingtonpost.com/connie-bennett/the-rats-who-preferred-su_b_712254.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hijacking of our pleasure sensors&lt;/a&gt; does really strange things to our brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it didn’t feel good to share your personal details with facebook, you wouldn’t do it. So facebook works hard to make it feel good. And when it feels good and you come back for more, you start behaving in ways you wouldn’t have otherwise acted. You come back for the likes, you craft updates in your mind when you aren’t even on facebook and you walk around your life thinking about ways to engage with facebook. In exchange for you dopamine fix, facebook packages up your behaviors linked to your stated and unstated profile data and sells it to the highest bidder (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cambridge_Analytica&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an audience who is also hoping to further alter your behavior&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this isn’t a post about facebook right? This is a post about smart phones. Yep. I’m just picking on Facebook for effect. Facebook might provide the fix, the smart phone is the delivery method. With its portability, push notifications, and proximity sensory organs, it acts like no other device in our lives. To continue the arguments from my earlier post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nomasters.io/posts/nonparticipation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;nonparticipation&lt;/a&gt; we can choose to opt out. But does this mean we go back to feature phones? Is that a viable option? How about no phone at all? &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=i+got+rid+of+my+smart+phone&amp;amp;t=ffnt&amp;amp;ia=web&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;There are plenty of folks who have reached this conclusion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though going completely “phoneless” is interesting to me, I wanted to explore another option: dumbing down the smart phone. Can we leverage the aspects of smart phones that are amazing, while minizing the addictive aspects? What if we could make our phones so boring we just look at them we we have to? What if we could strip out most, if not all of the dopamine inducing features and leave the phone in a state that is useful but boring. This is what I’ve been experimenting with for the last month and this is what I’d like to outline here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-one-cut-out-the-entertainment&quot;&gt;step one - cut out the entertainment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;no games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no video streaming apps (youtube, netflix, hulu, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no social media apps (facebook, twitter, instagram, snap, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no news aggregations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you “kill time” with the app, delete it. These are obvious and probably the most painful for most. The most successful of these are designing addiction into their services (mention fortnite to a fourteen year old and see how this goes). If you must use some of these, use them on your computer. I’d been off all social media for a while, for me it was Youtube. I’ve got probably 30+ channels I subscribe to and I wasted more time than I’d like to admit “keeping track” on my phone. Instead I spend deliberate “youtube channel time” once per day and leave it at that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-two-move-variable-reward-apps-to-a-folder&quot;&gt;step two - move variable reward apps to a folder.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my home screen I have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Units Conversion tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio Books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interval training Timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translation tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an “everything else” folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boring right? The purpose here is to leave utility apps that don’t cause dopamine response on the home screen while moving all other apps into a folder, which requires a bit more effort to get to. This means any chat app, calendar, email, etc. Move these “one folder deeper” into your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-three-turn-on-do-not-disturb&quot;&gt;step three - turn on Do Not Disturb&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I schedule my phone to be in Do Not Disturb between 9PM and 6AM. This is also automatically set while driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-four-turn-off-unnecessary-notifications&quot;&gt;step four - turn off unnecessary notifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;turn off all lock screen notifications (this is better for privacy anyway)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turn off vibrate and sound notifications, I leave badges for important things like messaging apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turn off notifications for apps that really don’t need it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the day, its time to purge the notification insanity. Go through your notifications settings for each app on the phone and set it to the minimum level possible. For me this means that I turned of email notifications including badges. I also put my email app in a folder outlined in step two, so that if I do want to check email or send email on my phone, I can, but it is inconvenient and gives me no information when I open my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work in tech and I understand that being “on-call” can be a nonstarter for some. I’d keep those tools in the “necessary notifications”. I used to be on call all the time and feel very fortunate that I’m not in that spot anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there you go, a dumber, much less interesting phone. This is still a work in progress for me, but this is where I am right now. Overall its been really interesting to watch me transition from mindlessly unlock my phone and poke around to forgetting about my phone for relatively long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup will cause you to be less responsive on chats and email, but that’s sort of the point. Your phone shouldn’t dictate to you what you focus your attention on, and the behavior it cultivates in keeping you “always ready” is unhealthy and spills over into parts of our lives that aren’t serving us well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a phrase I’ve been using recently in describing things like nonparticipation and dumber phones which is that I’m trying to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;turn down the volume&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of stimulants and reward centers. This is part of a hypothesis that pleasure seeking behaviors physiologically block your brains ability to be content. There is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34237719-the-hacking-of-the-american-mind&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;modern science&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zen_Mind,_Beginner%27s_Mind&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ancient wisdom&lt;/a&gt; that seem to support this and anecdotally I concur.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 14:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jstanley</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nomasters.io/posts/dumber-phone/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Watch Stanford CS Lectures Together</title>
<link>https://www.classroomies.com/?4</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.classroomies.com/?4</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I'm Karim, founder of Classroomies. Classroomies is a 24/7 broadcast of pre-recorded Stanford lectures on the topics of Startups, Computer Science &amp;amp; Business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🎓 What's it about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I became addicted to online lectures from universities like Stanford, Harvard &amp;amp; MIT after getting my engineering &amp;amp; art degree in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In all honesty, I've learned more from those Youtube videos than from my teachers when I was still in school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The one thing I do miss from offline-universities are the discussions with fellow classmates. For me, that's where the magic happened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's why I've built Classroomies - Bringing the social interactions of a real university / campus to online educational content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Classroomies is an experiment (still in beta), exploring a better format for online classes, aiming to enable likeminded people to connect &amp;amp; discuss the intellectual material at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;☕ How can I contact you?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to send me an &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:karim@jibly.com&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or say hi on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jibly&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;💻 Product Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Currently works only on Desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works best in Chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li/&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 13:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>___karim</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.classroomies.com/?4</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Things I Learned from a Job Hunt for a Senior Engineering Role</title>
<link>http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/jobhound/2018/04/24/ten-things-i-learned-from-a-job-hunt-for-a-senior-engineering-role.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/jobhound/2018/04/24/ten-things-i-learned-from-a-job-hunt-for-a-senior-engineering-role.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I recently went on a search for a new full time gig and I learned that today’s job search is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; what it used to be. Here’s the quick summary of what I learned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The job search takes much, much longer than it used to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No one believes that anyone can actually code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding Tests Can Trip Up Even Good Engineers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensive homework is now normal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every company’s “process” is different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outsourced hiring “services” are very much in vogue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies Really Want to Know Your Salary; Don’t tell Them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interviews Matter Much, Much More to You Than to the Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Age discrimination really exists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’ll never really know why you weren’t hired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In terms of full disclosure, at the end of this article, I’m going to pitch you on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jobhound.io&quot;&gt;new tool&lt;/a&gt; I built for managing your personal job hunt, but don’t worry, it’s &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; to use. I found the job hunt process so &lt;strong&gt;absolutely distasteful&lt;/strong&gt; that the only way I could get through it was to actually create some software based on what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s just a bit about myself so you can understand my job search. I’m a senior software guy who’s still writing code after all these years. My platform is generally Ruby / Rails and my &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/resume.html&quot;&gt;resume&lt;/a&gt; is here in case you care. I’ve been a consultant for the last few years and I wanted to get back to a full time gig in a senior engineering role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the stats from my job search:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Total Jobs Applied For: &lt;strong&gt;82&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total Jobs Where You Got an HR Interview &lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total Jobs Where You Got a Technical Interview: &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total Jobs Where You Got an Onsite Interview: &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total Job Offers: &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in high tech a long time and other than the few really bad times, the general rule in high tech hiring has been “fill an engineering slot as fast as possible”. The industry may talk a good game about culture fit but other than a few firms, it always has been about quickly putting bodies in seats. That is absolutely no longer the case. HR departments now seem to be focused on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Initially getting a large number of candidates to review as the first step (and nothing, even when you seem to be a perfect requirement match, happens until they get that large group of candidates).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marching the entire group of candidates, step by step, through their entire process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Putting as many barriers in place before hiring anyone. I discuss this more below under process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just so you’re aware, the HR departments will not own up to the process taking longer than ever. They will spin you a song and a dance about how quickly things are going to progress and it just isn’t true. My two observations in this area are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Companies today, despite what they might say, are pickier about candidates than ever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies are less willing to hire than I’ve ever seen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;One helpful thing I did during my job hunt was track everything so I actually had dates all along. Here’s an example of what I commonly saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;2/5 was my initial application to Company W&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3/1 was when I completed my homework project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3/2 was when I got scheduled for an onsite interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3/23 was when I found out that I didn’t get it (two weeks after my onsite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s almost two months start to finish! And today that job remains on the company’s web site – they still haven’t hired anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general thing that I saw from everyone that I talked to is that no one actually believes that anyone can code. At every stage in the interview process, you’re going to need to &lt;strong&gt;prove&lt;/strong&gt; that your resume isn’t a lie and that you can actually do what you say you can. I find this ludicrous because it is like interviewing an attorney and then saying to him “Please prove that you can cite a Supreme Court precedent”. When did an entire industry of people get pre-judged as lying? Don’t we exist in a country where the default assumption is innocence not guilt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extremely common thing that you’re going to find as part of a job search are coding tests and I’d urge you NOT to take them lightly. These coding tests tend to bear &lt;strong&gt;no resemblance&lt;/strong&gt; to anything you’ll do in the work place and even good engineers can get tripped up by them. I found that part way through my job search I had to buckle down, hit the books and start practicing on different coding tests to get my scores up. Once upon a time I would have said that any engineer should be able to pass a coding test but that’s just not true. The longer you are in industry, I would argue the less likely you may be to pass a coding test. I suspect I could have done much better on a coding test fresh out of college when my “test taking skills” were actually something I used. Now? The last test I passed was for a driver’s license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; You should note that since most tests come from an outsourced service like Codility, you can google for practice questions, sample exams and more. And I’d strongly encourage you to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t underestimate coding tests at all. I did and it was to my disadvantage. You really, really need to practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a hiring manager, I’ve given homework assignments to weed out candidates from the pack but I always kept it reasonable, just a few hours in length. I’ve now regularly seen homework assignments ranging from 8 hours to “spend a week on this and really show us what you can do”. Over on &lt;a href=&quot;https://work.qz.com/1254663/job-interviews-for-programmers-now-often-come-with-days-of-unpaid-homework/&quot;&gt;QZ&lt;/a&gt; there is an excellent article about this along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16874015&quot;&gt;984 comments on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;. And yes that’s a huge amount of comments on any one topic since the current amount of comments on the top 30 items on Hacker News is &lt;strong&gt;53&lt;/strong&gt; comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be aware that your coding submission will be judged all kinds of ways, often unfairly. For one application I built, I was told “you didn’t allow for proper performance given a 500x increase in data”. This came after being specifically told “use no technologies other than the database itself” (it was a search application). And what good engineer allows for an arbitrary 500x increase? That is massive, unnecessary over engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; One thing that I did do to stand out from the crowd for almost all my homework assignments was to record a screencast talking through my work and illustrating what I thought were the best points. I had several interviewers tell me that “thank you; I’ve never seen that before”. This gets the interviewer past any issues with getting code installed / setup, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should comment that even though I don’t like the trend towards homework, I vastly prefer it to coding tests. You shouldn’t think, however, that just because you passed the homework assignment, you won’t face a whiteboard challenge - every place I did a home assignment for, I also got a whiteboard challenge, sometimes multiple ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It used to be that getting a coding job boiled down to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Send in resume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HR Screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical Interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was a pretty standard process and I saw (and hired) a lot of people with this approach. Apparently though times change and now the “process” is all over the map. One of the most useful things I learned to ask companies early on was “Please explain your hiring process to me” and then I wrote it down for each company. This let me know “for company X, the process is”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;HR Screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding Test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical Interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pair Programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical Interview with the Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onsite Interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;What you’re going to find is that while there are common elements (currently homework) in the hiring process, everyone’s process is different. If you know what a company cares about then you can start to get ready before it happens. For example, if you know in advance that you have a coding test in front of you, this lets you know that you may need to study. If an HR person says to me “Oh and we administer a coding test” then my first response is “I’ve taken a bunch of those, which one do you use?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that really surprised me was how many companies rely on outsourced hiring services. I saw this all over the place from companies that sent me a link to a coding test, often &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codility.com/&quot;&gt;Codility&lt;/a&gt;, to “personality assessment” tools, often &lt;a href=&quot;http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/jobhound/2018/04/24/www.predictiveindex.com&quot;&gt;Predictive Index&lt;/a&gt;. I suppose this is the natural evolution of SAAS companies into the hiring space. When I was recruiting, in years past, my HR department always strongly warned me against administering coding tests on the grounds of legal issues / fairness. Now that these are outsourced, I suspect that HR departments aren’t concerned at all about legal issues since they come from a vendor not themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that you’ll find is that these outsourced assessment services are being stuck into the hiring process at &lt;strong&gt;ANY&lt;/strong&gt; point in the process. I’ve seen things ranging from HR screen to initial technical interview to coding test to send in a resume and get a personality test fired back at you before you ever talk to a human being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I started my job search, I was lucky enough to read Josh Doody’s fabulous book &lt;a href=&quot;https://fearlesssalarynegotiation.com/&quot;&gt;Fearless Salary Negotiation&lt;/a&gt; and the best thing I got from it was “Never disclose your current salary or expectations”. I never disclosed it but I found HR people absolutely relentless on this point. I finally said to one California company “You do realize that legally you can’t ask me that” and they shamelessly replied “Yes I can; you aren’t in California”. And you’ll find that there are web forms which require you to fill it in (I always put in a minimal, crazy number like 1234).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and if you haven’t read Josh’s book then I strongly encourage you to do so. It is a short but fantastic read. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fearless-Salary-Negotiation-step-step/dp/0692568689/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1524566767&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=fearless+salary+negotiation&quot;&gt;Here’s an Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately it is entirely true that any given interview matters far more &lt;strong&gt;to you&lt;/strong&gt; than it does &lt;strong&gt;to the company&lt;/strong&gt; that is interviewing you. Any candidate has only a relatively small number of jobs they can even apply for where as the company has all of the Internet applying (this is particularly true if the company is any good). I couldn’t even count how many interviews companies missed, were late on, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: I recently turned 50 and I’m still a hands on engineer who writes code just about every single day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One very surprising thing to me was just how much I discovered that age discrimination in high tech hiring is real. There were all too many times when jobs that I was an absolute perfect match for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I never got an interview at all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was mysteriously ghosted midway though the process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got all the way to the end, nailed everything perfectly and then never found out why I didn’t get it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is one of those things that you never can prove and no one will ever own up to I do think that is very, very real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that there are lots of actually good reasons why companies don’t want to tell you why you weren’t hired but this remains my single biggest issue with today’s job hunt. I can understand that you can’t tell everyone why they didn’t get hired but when you get to the end point and pass all these hurdles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;HR Screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding Test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical Interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pair Programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical Interview with the Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onsite Interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You would think that more information than “We all really liked you but we went in a different direction” could be said. I saw this repeatedly on jobs that I got all the way to the end point on. How is a candidate ever supposed to improve themselves when the company will not tell you why you didn’t get the job?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result of all this was that while I did end up with a full time job, I also ended up creating a new &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; product, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jobhound.io&quot;&gt;Job Hound&lt;/a&gt; to make applying for tech jobs (generally programming) easier. Job Hound is a job application tracking system and it puts the job application firmly in charge of the process. I built it because after I had applied for about 15 jobs, I had no idea where I was in the process and I couldn’t give my wife a decent answer about my progress because I simply had no idea. Job Hound isn’t a SAAS product, it is 100% free and I’d encourage you to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jobhound.io&quot;&gt;My new free product is Job Hound: Make applying for tech jobs suck less! Sign Up Today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also here is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/job-hound&quot;&gt;Job Hound on Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt; in case you want to toss me an upvote. Thanks in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t underestimate these changes to the hiring process and their impact on the industry as a whole. Here’s how I see things changing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decreased job mobility&lt;/strong&gt;. If jobs are harder to get then engineers will be less willing to change roles than they have been in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lower salaries&lt;/strong&gt;. Generally speaking the easiest way to get a raise as an engineer is to leave your job. If jobs are harder to get then less people will leave and that will drive salaries down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less Cross Pollination of Ideas&lt;/strong&gt;. While companies may not like job mobility, I would argue that on the whole it has been good for high tech in general. By engineers moving freely across companies, we’ve seen a great dissemination of engineering techniques and approaches. If engineers lose job mobility then that will absolutely change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given how high tech has been such a tool for job creation over the past few decades, I really don’t like the implication of these trends but I do see them as very, very real.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 13:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fuzzygroup</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://fuzzyblog.io/blog/jobhound/2018/04/24/ten-things-i-learned-from-a-job-hunt-for-a-senior-engineering-role.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Startup says it wants to fight poverty, but a food stamp giant is blocking it</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/23/technology/start-up-fight-poverty-food-stamp-giant-blocking-it.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/23/technology/start-up-fight-poverty-food-stamp-giant-blocking-it.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;252&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2590&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-6&quot;&gt;The fight over the app is now affecting people like Brianna LaBelle, 25, of Augusta, Me., who has two young sons. She has used Propel’s app to create shopping lists, track food purchases and budget. “I love it,” she said. “It’s very handy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;317&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2907&quot;&gt;But in February, when Ms. LaBelle tried to check her food stamps balance, she got a message that access to her information was “currently unavailable to the residents of Maine.” That interruption, she said, lasted for nearly a month, in which she also lost the timesaving and meal-planning convenience of the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;379&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3286&quot;&gt;Propel, Mr. Chen insisted, has tried to explain its business to state governments and to food stamp contractors. The Propel app is a digital “skin” that works on top of the websites of food stamp contractors, like Conduent. A user taps the app, which is known as FreshEBT, to look up the amount left in the account. On average, users check their balances seven times a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;328&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3614&quot;&gt;Conduent, in another twist, has begun competing with the start-up. The business services outsourcer, which has $6 billion in yearly revenue, introduced its own smartphone app last year. Conduent’s entry, ConnectEBT, has significantly fewer reviews and lower ratings on the Google and Apple app stores than Propel’s FreshEBT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/23/technology/start-up-fight-poverty-food-stamp-giant-blocking-it.html#story-continues-7&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;327&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3941&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-7&quot;&gt;Conduent’s app is available in Utah, South Carolina and Oklahoma, and offers only basic information on account balances and purchases. But the company said it was beginning a broader rollout this year, and would provide “more features and functions” as it gets states’ approval as a regulated contractor, unlike Propel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;174&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4115&quot;&gt;Propel’s predicament is magnified because the food-stamp system’s technology, like many government tech services, is outsourced to a relatively small number of companies.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;273&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4388&quot;&gt;“It’s an oligopoly game, so there’s often not much choice, competition or innovation,” said Josh Miller, who oversaw the development of digital products in the Obama White House. He added that the volume of data requests from Propel is “tiny” in internet terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;161&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4549&quot;&gt;Propel’s early success suggests there is opportunity for innovation in the low-income market, no matter how the start-up’s wrangling with Conduent turns out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;430&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4979&quot;&gt;Propel is a fledgling company, with only 11 employees, two of them former food-stamp recipients. Mr. Chen, 30, is not one of them. His family emigrated from China when he was 4, and he attended Stanford University on a full scholarship, based on need. Propel has raised $5.2 million from investors like Andreessen Horowitz, a Silicon Valley venture capital firm, and Omidyar Network, which funds start-ups focused on social goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/23/technology/start-up-fight-poverty-food-stamp-giant-blocking-it.html#story-continues-8&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 07:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dredmorbius</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/23/technology/start-up-fight-poverty-food-stamp-giant-blocking-it.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>This Start-Up Says It Wants to Fight Poverty. A Food Stamp Giant Is Blocking It.</og:title>
<og:description>Propel was begun to bring convenience and new services to food stamp recipients. A big government contractor is getting in the way.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/04/20/business/00PROPEL-1/00PROPEL-1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/23/technology/start-up-fight-poverty-food-stamp-giant-blocking-it.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Intuitive Linear Algebra and 3D Geometry</title>
<link>https://intuitive-math.club</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://intuitive-math.club</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;HomePage__ImageBanner-chcxXb ixjnVq&quot; data-reactid=&quot;211&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://intuitive-math.club/static/intuitive-math-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Intuitive Math Banner Logo&quot; data-reactid=&quot;212&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;213&quot;&gt;This is a math primer that is a little different. It is written using technologies such as React and WebGL with animated explanations of fields like Linear Algebra and Geometry designed to help you develop a visual intuition for what is going on. More fields will be added as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;222&quot;&gt;The visualizations are partially interactive. They are done on sine-wave interpolations by default, but if a value is shown below the visualisation, in some cases, you can manually adjust it by dragging it from side to side, or just double-clicking and editing it. Animation will stop for that value as soon as you edit it, and you can undo the stopped animation by clicking the close button:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;226&quot;&gt;Note that due to the limit on the number of concurrently running WebGL contexts implemented by most browsers, I have tried to use some smarts to disable contexts when they are not fully in view. So far, I have tested that this worked on Chrome and Firefox Quantum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 data-reactid=&quot;227&quot;&gt;Why did you write this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;228&quot;&gt;I mainly wrote this to help me consolidate my own notes on the subjects since I personally have a hard time instantly developing an intuition for math. And without the intuition, I have a hard time applying math to problems because I will not know what the tools are actually for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 data-reactid=&quot;229&quot;&gt;Corrections, Errata&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;230&quot;&gt;Given that I am not an expert in this area, its possible that I probably got something wrong. If you notice something that seems odd, you can reach me at s AT polysquare DOT org. Or, the code is open source, so you can just submit a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/smspillaz/intuitive-math&quot; data-reactid=&quot;233&quot;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 03:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>smspillaz</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://intuitive-math.club/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scientists plan huge European AI hub to compete with US</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2018/apr/23/scientists-plan-huge-european-ai-hub-to-compete-with-us</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/science/2018/apr/23/scientists-plan-huge-european-ai-hub-to-compete-with-us</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Leading scientists have drawn up plans for a vast multinational European institute devoted to world-class artificial intelligence (AI) research in a desperate bid to nurture and retain top talent in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/europe-news&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new institute would be set up for similar reasons as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/2012/jul/04/higgs-boson-cern-scientists-discover&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Cern&lt;/a&gt;, the particle physics lab near Geneva, which was created after the second world war to rebuild European physics and reverse the brain drain of the brightest and best scientists to the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Named the European Lab for Learning and Intelligent Systems, or Ellis, the proposed AI institute would have major centres in a handful of countries, the UK included, with each employing hundreds of computer engineers, mathematicians and other scientists with the express aim of keeping Europe at the forefront of AI research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ellis-open-letter.eu/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; that urges governments to act, the scientists describe how Europe has not kept up with the US and China, where the vast majority of leading AI firms and universities are based. The letter adds that while a few “research hotspots” still exist in Europe, “virtually all of the top people in those places are continuously being pursued for recruitment by US companies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extent of the hiring frenzy and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/2017/nov/02/big-tech-firms-google-ai-hiring-frenzy-brain-drain-uk-universities&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;damaging impact it is having on British universities&lt;/a&gt; was revealed in a Guardian investigation last year. It found that PhD students had left their studies for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/2017/nov/01/cant-compete-universities-losing-best-ai-scientists&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;six-figure salaries&lt;/a&gt; at US tech firms. Meanwhile, some universities had been hit so hard that they had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/2017/nov/02/big-tech-firms-google-ai-hiring-frenzy-brain-drain-uk-universities&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;lost an entire generation&lt;/a&gt; of talented young researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The letter, signed by scientists in the UK, France, Germany, Switzerland, Israel and the Netherlands, calls for work on the new institute to start this year. Under the proposal, participating countries would fund the institute as an intergovernmental organisation. The same approach is used to fund the European Molecular Biology Lab, which has a major centre in Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;4a4b5894-522c-40cb-ac52-2eddf91d87fb&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;qanda&quot; class=&quot;atom atom--snippet atom--snippet--qanda&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;atom--snippet__label&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;atom--snippet__headline&quot;&gt;What is AI?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;atom__button atom__button--large atom__button--rounded atom--snippet__handle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;is-on&quot;&gt; Show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;is-off&quot;&gt; Hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence has various definitions, but in general it means a program that uses data to build a model of some aspect of the world. This model is then used to make informed decisions and predictions about future events. The technology is used widely, to provide speech and face recognition, language translation, and personal recommendations on music, film and shopping sites. In the future, it could deliver driverless cars, smart personal assistants, and intelligent energy grids. AI has the potential to make organisations more effective and efficient, but the technology raises serious issues of ethics, governance, privacy and law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;atom--snippet__footer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was this helpful?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__ack&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;Thank you for your feedback.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Something needs to be done and it needs to be done now,” said Zoubin Ghahramani, professor of information engineering at Cambridge University and chief scientist at Uber. “It would provide Europe with centres of mass where we would have not 10 researchers but hundreds with expertise from different countries.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghahramani, one of the most influential AI researchers in Britain, joined Uber after the San Francisco-based firm bought Geometric Intelligence, an AI startup he co-founded with a New York University psychologist some years ago. Despite the move, which exemplifies the problems Europe now faces, he has driven the UK’s involvement in the proposal for the new lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is of such importance to Europe it would be a terrible mistake not to do something major,” he said. “If we don’t act in this area, both European universities and European industry will start to drift downwards.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The institute’s stated mission is to ensure that the best AI research is performed in Europe, a goal that would drive jobs and economies and also give the region’s scientists a voice in shaping how AI changes the world, the scientists believe. Those who work at the institute would have the freedom to work with industry and launch startup companies based on the breakthroughs they make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Private and public investment in AI have soared on the back of breakthroughs in the field over the past few decades, but the US and China have firmly taken the lead. The technology has such potential that its impact on society is widely expected to be as profound as the industrial revolution.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first steps in building the institute are expected to begin with a collaboration between France and Germany with other nations joining later. Ultimately, each local lab would become a $100m facility with an annual budget of $30m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential for AI to have a dramatic impact on lives, by taking decisions in areas from healthcare and policing to defence and transport, has led to serious questions over who writes the rules on how AI is used.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Europe steps back and watches AI research from the sidelines, it will have little say in shaping its future, Ghahramani said. “The regulatory environment for technology is often led by the people who control the technology,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major supporter of the institute, Bernard Schölkopf, director at the Max Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems in Tübingen, Germany, said: “Europe has a unique academic research tradition, so we have managed to keep up for a number of years. But the US and China have recognised the strategic importance of this field and no single European country is a match for this.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 02:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>charlysl</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/science/2018/apr/23/scientists-plan-huge-european-ai-hub-to-compete-with-us</og:url>
<og:description>Exclusive: In an open letter, the scientists say the proposed Ellis institute is essential to avoid brain drain to big tech firms</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a63e298378c39cd4a568f8ab2af229d9b814a8c1/99_0_5563_3338/master/5563.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=5153526768968044667c3f364efe2a5f</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Scientists plan huge European AI hub to compete with US</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2018/apr/23/scientists-plan-huge-european-ai-hub-to-compete-with-us</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins X: a CI/CD solution for cloud applications on Kubernetes</title>
<link>https://jenkins.io/blog/2018/03/19/introducing-jenkins-x/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jenkins.io/blog/2018/03/19/introducing-jenkins-x/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;content-top&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;post-attrs&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;submitted&quot;&gt;Published on 2018-03-19 by &lt;a href=&quot;https://jenkins.io/blog/2018/03/19/introducing-jenkins-x/#about-the-author&quot;&gt;James Strachan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;8.6523605150215&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to share and invite the community to join us on a project we’ve been thinking about over the last few months called &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io&quot;&gt;Jenkins X&lt;/a&gt; which extends the Jenkins ecosystem to solve the problem of automating CI/CD in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot; readability=&quot;31.397415185784&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last few years have seen massive changes in the software industry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;4.3194842406877&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;use of immutable container images for distributing software which are smaller, easier to work with and lead to cheaper infrastructure costs than VMs alone (approx 20% less on average)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1.8913043478261&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; has become the defacto way of installing, upgrading, operating and managing containers at scale on any public or hybrid cloud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;0.95670995670996&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0.91452991452991&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 is the year all the major public clouds, operating system vendors and PaaS offerings support &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; natively&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we now have an open source industry standard for distributing, installing and managing applications on any cloud!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;increased adoption of microservices and cloud native applications leading to massive increase in the number of components which require CI/CD along with increased release frequency&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;improvements in DevOps practices coming from the community such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://puppet.com/blog/2017-state-devops-report-here&quot;&gt;State of DevOps Report&lt;/a&gt; which show the approach of high performing teams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;increasingly many businesses now realise that to compete you have to deliver value quickly via software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;teams need to become high performing if the business is to succeed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this adds up to an increased demand for teams to have a solution for cloud native CI/CD with lots of automation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;introducing-jenkins-x&quot;&gt;Introducing Jenkins X&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot; readability=&quot;32.291169451074&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;8.5929648241206&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jenkins.io/images/jenkins-x/logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Jenkins X Logo&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io&quot;&gt;Jenkins X&lt;/a&gt; is a project which rethinks how developers should interact with CI/CD in the cloud with a focus on making development teams productive through automation, tooling and DevOps best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;6.34375&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io&quot;&gt;Jenkins X&lt;/a&gt; is open source and we invite you to give us feedback and to contribute to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot; readability=&quot;18.751994198695&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-the-big-deal&quot;&gt;Whats the big deal?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years Jenkins has been capable of doing pretty much anything in the CI/CD space; the challenge has always been figuring out how to get the right plugins, configuration and code to work together in your &lt;code&gt;Jenkinsfile&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;11.316455696203&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me the big deal about Jenkins X is as a developer you can type one command &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/developing/create-spring/&quot;&gt;jx create&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/developing/import/&quot;&gt;jx import&lt;/a&gt; and get your source code, git repository and application created, automatically built and deployed to Kubernetes on each Pull Request or git push with full CI/CD complete with Environments and Promotion via GitOps!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers and teams don’t have to spend time figuring out how to package software as docker images, create the Kubernetes YAML to run their application on kubernetes, create Preview environments or even learn how to implement CI/CD pipelines with declarative pipeline-as-code &lt;code&gt;Jenkinsfiles&lt;/code&gt;. It’s all automated for you out of the box! So you can focus instead on delivering value!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Jenkins X doesn’t hide anything. If you do want to hack the &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Jenkinsfile&lt;/code&gt; or Helm charts for your apps or their environments then go right ahead - those are all available versioned in git with the rest of your source code with full CI/CD on it all. GitOps FTW!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenkins X automates CI/CD and DevOps best practices for you - so you can become a faster performing team! Let your butler do more work for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot; readability=&quot;17.090909090909&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kPes3rvT1UM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;jenkins-x-features&quot;&gt;Jenkins X Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot; readability=&quot;28.836164043082&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now lets walk through the features of Jenkins X that we showed in the demo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot; readability=&quot;8.7846202935546&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;automated-ci-cd-pipelines&quot;&gt;Automated CI/CD Pipelines&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;0.48387096774194&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-0.94805194805195&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;get a Pipeline automatically setup for you that implements best practice CI/CD features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;0.46621621621622&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;creates a &lt;code&gt;Jenkinsfile&lt;/code&gt; for defining the CI/CD pipelines through declarative pipeline-as-code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;creates a &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; for packaging the application up as an immutable container image (for applications which generate images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-0.74025974025974&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;creates a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.helm.sh/developing_charts/#charts&quot;&gt;Helm chart&lt;/a&gt; for deploying and running your application on &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ensures your code is in a git repository (e.g. GitHub) with the necessary webhooks to trigger the Jenkins CI/CD pipelines on push events&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;triggers the first release pipeline to promote your application to your teams &lt;em&gt;Staging&lt;/em&gt; Environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then on each Pull Request:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a CI pipeline is triggered to build your application and run all the tests ensuring you keep the master branch in a ready to release state&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;your Pull Request is deployed to a Preview Environment (more on this later)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a Pull Request is merged to the master branch the Release pipeline is triggered to create a new release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;1.4582366589327&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a new semantic version number is generated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the source code is modified for the new version (e.g. &lt;em&gt;pom.xml&lt;/em&gt; files get their &lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; elements modified) and then tagged in git&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;new versioned artifacts are published including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;docker image, helm chart and any language specific artifacts (e.g. &lt;em&gt;pom.xml&lt;/em&gt; and jar files for Java, npm packages for node or binaries for go etc)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-0.8125&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the new version is promoted to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/about/features/#environments&quot;&gt;Environments&lt;/a&gt; (more on this later)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot; readability=&quot;13.278527607362&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;environment-promotion-via-gitops&quot;&gt;Environment Promotion via GitOps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;7.5051546391753&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Jenkins X each team gets their own &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/about/features/#environments&quot;&gt;environments&lt;/a&gt;. The default environments are &lt;em&gt;Staging&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Production&lt;/em&gt; but teams can create as many environments as they wish and call them whatever they prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;6.9485714285714&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Environment is a place to deploy code and each Environment maps to a separate &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/overview/working-with-objects/namespaces/&quot;&gt;namespace in Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; so they are isolated from each other and can be managed independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;6.3225806451613&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use something called &lt;em&gt;GitOps&lt;/em&gt; to manage environments and perform &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/about/features/#promotion&quot;&gt;promotion&lt;/a&gt;. This means that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each environment gets its own git repository to store all the environment specific configuration together with a list of all the applications and their version and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Promotion of new versions of applications to an environment results in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a Pull Request is created for the configuration change that triggers the CI pipeline tests on the Environment along with code review and approval&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;once the Pull Request is merged the release pipeline for the environment which updates the applications running in that environment by applying the helm chart metadata from the git repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environments can be configured to either promote &lt;em&gt;automatically&lt;/em&gt; as part of a release pipeline or they can use &lt;em&gt;manual&lt;/em&gt; promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The defaults today are for the &lt;em&gt;Staging&lt;/em&gt; environment to use automatic promotion; so all merges to master are automatically promoted to Staging. Then the &lt;em&gt;Production&lt;/em&gt; environment is configured to use manual promotion; so you choose when do promote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot; readability=&quot;8.4375582479031&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;preview-environments&quot;&gt;Preview Environments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;7.8796680497925&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenkins X lets you create &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/about/features/#preview-environments&quot;&gt;Preview Environments&lt;/a&gt; for Pull Requests. Typically this happens automatically in the Pull Request Pipelines when a Pull Request is submitted but you can also perform this manually yourself via the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/developing/preview/&quot;&gt;jx preview&lt;/a&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following happens when a Preview Environment is created:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;2.1086956521739&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0.66542750929368&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/about/features/#environments&quot;&gt;Environment&lt;/a&gt; of kind &lt;code&gt;Preview&lt;/code&gt; is created along with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/overview/working-with-objects/namespaces/&quot;&gt;kubernetes namespace&lt;/a&gt; which show up the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_environments/&quot;&gt;jx get environments&lt;/a&gt; command along with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/developing/kube-context/&quot;&gt;jx environment and jx namespace commands&lt;/a&gt; so you can see which preview environments are active and switch into them to look around&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Pull Request is built as a preview docker image and chart and deployed into the preview environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a comment is added to the Pull Request to let your team know the preview application is ready for testing with a link to open the application. So in one click your team members can try out the preview!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imageblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jenkins.io/images/jenkins-x/intro/pr-comment.png&quot; alt=&quot;Issue Comment&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is particularly useful if you are working on a web application or REST endpoint; it lets your team interact with the running Pull Request to help folks approve changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot; readability=&quot;9.6868475991649&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;7.2207792207792&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the commit comments reference issues (e.g. via the text &lt;code&gt;fixes #123&lt;/code&gt;) then Jenkins X pipelines will generate release notes like those of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx/releases&quot;&gt;the jx releases&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, as the version associated with those new commits is promoted to &lt;code&gt;Staging&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Production&lt;/code&gt;, you will get automated comments on each fixed issue that the issue is now available for review in the corresponding environment along with a link to the release notes and a link to the app running in that environment. e.g.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imageblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jenkins.io/images/jenkins-x/intro/issue-comment.png&quot; alt=&quot;Issue Comment&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot; readability=&quot;40.228849665246&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you now want to give Jenkins X a try. One of the great features of Jenkins is that it’s super easy to get started: install Java, download a war and run via &lt;code&gt;java -jar jenkins.war&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Jenkins X we’ve tried to follow a similarly simple experience. One complication is that Jenkins X has more moving pieces than a single JVM; it also needs a Kubernetes cluster :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;CodeRay highlight nowrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;jx create cluster gke&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we support creating Kubernetes clusters and installing Jenkins X on Amazon (AWS), Google (GKE), Microsoft Azure, and even locally using minikube. We plan to support AWS EKS soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of this writing the easiest cloud to get started with is Google’s GKE so we recommend you start there unless you already use AWS or Azure. Amazon and Microsoft are working hard to make Kubernetes clusters as easy to create and manage as they are on GKE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the public clouds have a free tier so you should be able to spin up a Kubernetes cluster and install Jenkins X for a few hours then tear it down and it should be cheaper than a cup of coffee (probably free!). Just remember to tear down the cluster when you are done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ELA4tytdFeA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;relationship-between-jenkins-and-jenkins-x&quot;&gt;Relationship between Jenkins and Jenkins X&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot; readability=&quot;34.586956521739&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenkins is the core CI/CD engine within Jenkins X. So Jenkins X is built on the massive shoulders of Jenkins and its awesome community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;10.153846153846&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jenkinsci/jep/tree/master/jep/400&quot;&gt;proposing Jenkins X as a sub project&lt;/a&gt; within the Jenkins foundation as Jenkins X has a different focus: automating CI/CD for the cloud using Jenkins plus other open source tools like Kubernetes, Helm, Git, Nexus/Artifactory etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time we are hoping Jenkins X can help drive some changes in Jenkins itself to become more cloud native, which will benefit the wider Jenkins community in addition to Jenkins X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;please-join-us&quot;&gt;Please join us!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot; readability=&quot;41.447098976109&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;9.4295302013423&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I hope the above has given you a feel for the vision of where we are heading with Jenkins X and to show where we are today. The project is still very young, we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx/issues&quot;&gt;lots to do&lt;/a&gt; and we are looking for more input on where to go next and what to focus on. We’re also working on high level &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/contribute/roadmap&quot;&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of contributing here’s some ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;13.294117647059&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the Jenkins community tends to use IRC for chat and the Kubernetes community uses Slack, so Jenkins X has rooms for &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-x.io/community/&quot;&gt;both IRC and slack&lt;/a&gt; depending on which chat technology you prefer - as the Jenkins X community will be working closely with both the Jenkins community and the various Kubernetes communities (Kubernetes, Helm, Skaffold, Istio et al).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most rewarding things about open source is being able to learn from others in the community. So I’m hoping that even if you are not yet ready to use Kubernetes in your day job or are not yet interested in automating your Continuous Delivery - that you’ll at least consider taking a look at Jenkins X, if for no other reason than to help you learn more about all these new ideas, technologies and approaches!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;about-the-author&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;author box&quot; readability=&quot;2.3549107142857&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.7098214285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;James Strachan&quot; class=&quot;author logo&quot; src=&quot;https://jenkins.io/images/avatars/jstrachan.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;4.7098214285714&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;author name&quot;&gt;James Strachan&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James is a long time open source contributor, created the Groovy programming language and Apache Camel integration framework. For the past few years he’s been working on CI/CD with Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 01:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Garbage</dc:creator>
<og:title>Introducing Jenkins X: a CI/CD solution for modern cloud applications on Kubernetes</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://jenkins.io/blog/2018/03/19/introducing-jenkins-x/index.html</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jenkins.io/blog/2018/03/19/introducing-jenkins-x/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tech company career ladders</title>
<link>http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2018/04/23/pace/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2018/04/23/pace/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Up or out: tech company leveling and mandatory promotions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're thinking about taking a job at a large tech company for the first time, you should remember to ask them how their &quot;leveling&quot; works. This is something that seems to be poorly conveyed to a lot of people, and many folks from outside the valley (myself included, back in the day) have no idea what's going on or how it should work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there is the notion of job ladders. A software engineer is not a production engineer/SRE, project manager, or a people manager. Those are all separate ladders, tracks, whatever you want to call them. If you are hired onto a certain ladder, odds are good that you will have to interview to change to another, no matter how long you've been doing the gig. I &lt;a href=&quot;http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2011/11/22/caste/&quot;&gt;wrote about this in 2011&lt;/a&gt; describing Google, but the same applies to Facebook. It's probably being practiced in plenty of other places, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a job ladder, you then have levels. They tend to map onto years of experience, whether you have a degree or not, what kind of degree it is, how well you do in your interviews, &lt;em&gt;how much money you ask for or hint about&lt;/em&gt;, and possibly how well you did as an intern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of people are hired as &quot;threes&quot;. That is, 3. Level 3. They might be an E3 if a Facebook SWE, IC3 if a Facebook PE, O3 if a Google SA-SRE, T3 if a Google SWE[-SRE], and so on. Microsoft has its own levels which are bigger numbers but the idea is the same. These companies have internal mappings so they can say that someone coming from X at level Y is equal to a Z here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone coming in at 3 might just be a new grad. Someone coming in at 4 might be a new grad... of a Masters or Ph. D. program. Tricky, right? Or, maybe they have some industry experience instead. Whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this should be too surprising. The fact that companies will mis-level people should also not be too surprising. The lower you start, the more rungs there are to climb, and the longer they can keep you hanging on, trying to get &quot;just one more level&quot; out of them. Also, it directly translates into the amount of money they pay you, so keeping that down tends to be a good deal for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, the surprise starts coming in when you start talking about &quot;yellow zones&quot;, &quot;red zones&quot;, and &quot;terminal levels&quot;. What's all this? Whether you know it or not, your company probably has a requirement that you get to a certain level within a certain amount of time. Imagine having two years to get from 3 to 4, and then about three years to make it from 4 to 5. That's pretty close to reality at some companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, once you hit 5, you're good. You can (supposedly) stay right there as long as you want. That's the meaning of &quot;terminal level&quot;. 5 is the first one of those. 3 and 4 are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what's the red zone? This applies to someone who's not yet at a terminal level and is reaching (or has reached) the end of the term. If this happens and that person does not get promoted, something interesting happens. They start being assessed &lt;em&gt;as if&lt;/em&gt; they were already at the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenario: IC3, past the two year mark. Instead of being assessed using the &quot;metrics&quot; for a 3, the ones for a 4 will be used. This can be the difference between &quot;does what they're told&quot; and &quot;actively finds more things to do without supervision&quot;. You can be a 3, be operating as a 3, meeting the bar of a 3, getting paid as a 3, but you will find yourself needing to meet a higher standard once that timer elapses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for 4 to 5. Once the time elapses, those individuals start being assessed using the guidelines for the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big deal, you say. It actually is. Here's why. Maybe you are doing solid 3 work. As a 3, you'd be a &quot;meets all expectations&quot; (MA). However, you're being judged as a 4, and with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; rubric, you miss the mark and get &quot;meets most expectations&quot; (MM) or even &quot;meets some expectations&quot; (MS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you're below MA, a bunch of fun things may happen. Some companies won't let you change teams with a less-than-meets rating. If you just read that and thought &quot;wait, so if my first manager hates me and gives me terrible reviews, then I'm stuck with them forever&quot;, you'd be right. &lt;a href=&quot;http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2012/02/11/moveon/&quot;&gt;Sometimes, the only way up is out.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, you can expect to be put on a &quot;Performance Improvement Plan&quot; (PIP). This is where your boss and HR sit you down and tell you that you will deliver this, this and this, or you will be gone. Then you sign it and it goes into your file, and you start working your tail off, and &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; they accept it and let you proceed as before. Or, maybe they reject the output and can you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can just walk. Some companies will dangle money at you as an alternative to going on the PIP. You can take it and bail. Obviously, this is much easier if you aren't shackled to them by some kind of inhumane quasi-slavery visa situation that we do to our friends who happen to be born somewhere else. If you're a citizen or have the appropriate paperwork, this is no big deal. You take it and split. However, a great many people don't have this option and have to shut up and hope they can pull through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through all of this, if your manager isn't supporting you, you're probably doomed. Unless they do something that's obviously going to get the company in legal trouble, HR won't care. Remember, HR is there to keep the company out of hot water, and &lt;em&gt;they are never there for you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's the takeaway here? Know how the company works before you take the plunge. Ask how much influence the manager has on your progress. If you're coming in at a relatively low level, find out if there are expectations for you to move up within a certain timeframe. If you actually care about staying at the company, focus on solving for that. If your manager has a non-trivial amount of control over your situation and is going to be a showstopper, play nice and change teams while you still can. Don't wait for a bad review to nail your feet to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are in a perilous visa situation, you also have to solve for that at the same time, unfortunately. I really feel for you and am sorry that you have to go through that crap. Nobody deserves to be treated like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Folks at smaller companies which have none of this who have been alternatively rolling around on the floor laughing or scratching their heads at the wackiness described above, you now know how good you have it. Enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 01:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tim_sw</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2018/04/23/pace/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>