<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Visa and Plaid Abandon Merger After Antitrust Division’s Suit to Block</title>
<link>https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/visa-and-plaid-abandon-merger-after-antitrust-division-s-suit-block</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/visa-and-plaid-abandon-merger-after-antitrust-division-s-suit-block</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Department of Justice announced today that Visa Inc. and Plaid Inc. have abandoned their planned $5.3 billion merger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The department filed a civil antitrust lawsuit on Nov. 5, 2020, to stop the merger, alleging that Visa is a monopolist in online debit, charging consumers and merchants billions of dollars in fees each year to process online payments.  Plaid, a successful fintech firm, is developing a payments platform that would challenge Visa’s monopoly.  According to the complaint, the transaction would have enabled Visa to eliminate this competitive threat to its online debit business before Plaid had a chance to succeed, thereby enhancing or maintaining its monopoly.  The case was scheduled for trial in the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of California on June 28, 2021.  As a result of Visa and Plaid’s decision to terminate their merger agreement, the United States has filed a Joint Stipulation of Dismissal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In a victory for American consumers and small businesses, Visa has abandoned its efforts to acquire an innovative and nascent competitor,” said Assistant Attorney General Makan Delrahim of the Justice Department’s Antitrust Division.  “American consumers and business owners rely on the internet to buy and sell goods and services, and Visa – which has immense power in online debit in the United States– has extracted billions of dollars from those transactions.  Now that Visa has abandoned its anticompetitive merger, Plaid and other future fintech innovators are free to develop potential alternatives to Visa’s online debit services.  With more competition, consumers can expect lower prices and better services.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant Attorney General Delrahim continued, “The department is grateful for the team of dedicated civil servants, lawyers and economists, who carefully reviewed this merger and pursued the litigation, ultimately building a case that the merger would extinguish a nascent competitor, further entrench Visa’s dominance in the online debit market, and harm consumers.  Their diligent efforts to prosecute this case convinced the parties to abandon the deal rather than face us in court.  We wish both companies well as they innovate and work to provide their products to American consumers.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. is a Delaware corporation headquartered in Foster City, California.  Visa is a global payments company that operates the largest debit network in the United States.  Visa’s 2019 revenues were approximately $23 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plaid Inc. is a Delaware corporation headquartered in San Francisco, California.  Plaid is a financial services company that operates the leading financial data aggregation platform in the United States.  In 2019, Plaid earned approximately $100 million in revenues. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 21:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>theBashShell</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Visa and Plaid Abandon Merger After Antitrust Division’s Suit to Block</og:title>
<og:description>The Department of Justice announced today that Visa Inc. and Plaid Inc. have abandoned their planned $5.3 billion merger.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.justice.gov/sites/all/modules/features/doj_sharing/images/doj-seal-fb.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/visa-and-plaid-abandon-merger-after-antitrust-division-s-suit-block</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Computer Science Curriculum in 1000 YouTube Videos</title>
<link>https://laconicml.com/computer-science-curriculum-youtube-videos/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://laconicml.com/computer-science-curriculum-youtube-videos/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In this article, we are going to create an entire Computer Science curriculum using only YouTube videos. The Computer Science curriculum is going to cover every skill essential for a Computer Science Engineer that has expertise in Artificial Intelligence and its subfields, like: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, NLP, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The curriculum is going to be organized in 40 courses in total, further organized in 4 academic years, each containing 2 semesters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to try to list a few videos per course as we can, so we can keep the list short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal here is to capture the whole university experience in perspective of the organization of the courses and deliver you the whole curriculum for FREE, so you can gain significant knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that this is not the same as you’ll get at university, but the videos are of high quality, and most of them helped us, during our time at university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-144&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad medrectangle-3 adtester-container adtester-container-144 ezoic-ad-adaptive&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-medrectangle-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad medrectangle-3 adtester-container adtester-container-144&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-medrectangle-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-medrectangle-3-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;290&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad medrectangle-3 adtester-container adtester-container-144&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-medrectangle-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-medrectangle-3-0_1&quot; ezaw=&quot;290&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;We hope you will like it, and it will be of use to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, we’ve seen that most of the visitors on our website, like the articles where we talk about free courses, curriculums, books, etc. Some of our most popular articles in that area are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fusion-reading-box-container reading-box-container-1 fusion-animated&quot; data-animationtype=&quot;slideInUp&quot; data-animationduration=&quot;0.3&quot; data-animationoffset=&quot;100%&quot; readability=&quot;8.4929577464789&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;reading-box reading-box-center element-bottomshadow&quot; readability=&quot;12.267605633803&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, we have a new private Facebook group where we are going to share some materials that are not going to be published online and will be available for our members only. The members will have early access to every new post we make and share your thoughts, tips, articles and questions. Become part of our private Facebook group now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;button fusion-button button-green fusion-button-large button-large button-flat fusion-mobile-button continue-center&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/1682628565239534/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Join Laconicml Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whole Computer Science Curriculum in 40 YouTube Videos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year 1:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Semester 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structured Programming (Programming in C)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course will introduce you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://laconicml.com/machine-learning-weka/&quot;&gt;programming&lt;/a&gt;. It will help you write your first code, run your first application, and see what programming is about. You will start with printing messages on the screen, simple arithmetic operations, if-else statements, loops, data structures (arrays, matrices), memory addresses, pointers, reading and writing files, etc. You will build simple applications that will allow you to understand the material even better. The best two videos that we recommend for this course are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KJgsSFOSQv0&amp;amp;ab_channel=freeCodeCamp.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;C Programming Tutorial For Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-CpG3oATGIs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;C Programming Tutorial | Learn C programming | C language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discrete Mathematics part 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-145&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad medrectangle-4 adtester-container adtester-container-145&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-medrectangle-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-medrectangle-4-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;336&quot; ezah=&quot;280&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad ezoic-adl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;This course will introduce you to declarative statements, sets, and operations with sets, laws, logic, quantifiers, functions, proofs, sequences, and summation. For this course, and it’s a second part which we’ve put in Year 2, we are going to use the same playlist of 60 YouTube videos, but we are going to split it, 34 videos for part 1 (1-34) and 26 videos for the part 2 (35-60).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLl-gb0E4MII28GykmtuBXNUNoej-vY5Rz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Discrete Math playlist (videos: 1-34)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/A3Ffwsnad0k&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculus part 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course will introduce you to limits, intervals, differentiability, continuity, derivatives, antiderivatives, rules, trigonometric functions, inverse trigonometric functions, optimizations, and sums. It will be a huge help to you, once you dive into the later semesters of your studies and will help you understand most of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://laconicml.com/mathematical-skills-data-scientist/&quot;&gt;mathematics&lt;/a&gt; behind Machine Learning, Deep Learning, etc. Here we will suggest you take look at this list of 86 videos. Yes, it looks long, but the videos are quite short and well explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLl-gb0E4MII1ml6mys-RXoQ0O3GfwBPVM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Calculus part 1 playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Computer Science and Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course will introduce you to computer science and programming from a theoretical view. It is very important for every beginner to have a visual representation in its mind about most of the concepts of computer science and programming. That way, it can understand their complexity and unlock its imagination and creativity and use the full power of computer science and programming while respecting their laws. Here we recommend you this video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zOjov-2OZ0E&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intro to Python Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is an introduction to Python programming. Easily one of the most popular programming languages in the world, &lt;a href=&quot;http://laconicml.com/implement-bayesian-regression-python/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; is widely used by many people who work in some sort of IT-related field. It is easy to understand, use has tons of libraries and it has huge community support. It is used in Web Development (Django, Flask), Machine Learning (Scikit-learn, NumPy, pandas, TensorFlow), etc. You are going to use Python a lot, so for this course, we are going to keep it simple by recommending only one video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rfscVS0vtbw&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semester 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculus part 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is the second part of the Calculus. Here you are going to learn about integrals, series, tests, polar coordinates, polar graphs, etc. For this course, we are going to recommend you this playlist of 64 videos. It looks like a lot, but the videos are well explained and are quite short, so you feel like you’ve covered a lot of material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLl-gb0E4MII1OxI-BbNkEhuwPHcKxuPSg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Calculus part 2 playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discrete Mathematics part 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course will introduce you to matrices, graphs, searching algorithms, sorting algorithms, algorithms complexity, introduction to probability, combinatorics, variations, and permutations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-148&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad box-4 adtester-container adtester-container-148&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-box-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-box-4-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;336&quot; ezah=&quot;280&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;This is the second part of the Discrete Mathematics, and as we’ve mentioned in the first part, we are going to use the same playlist of 60 videos, but here we are going to watch starting from the 35th up to the 60th video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLl-gb0E4MII28GykmtuBXNUNoej-vY5Rz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Discrete Math playlist (videos: 35-60)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to C++ and Object-Oriented Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course will introduce me to C++, starting from the basics, up to Object-Oriented Programming (OOP). OOP is one of the main programming paradigms, and probably the most used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the applications that you have on your mobile phone or access from the browser are programmed following this paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the pillar of every program you will write in the future, so you will want to give this course more time. For this course, we will recommend you a video playlist of 29 videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we recommend you to watch them up to the 13th because the rest of them are beyond OOP and if you are new to this, might be complex and difficult to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLGLfVvz_LVvQ9S8YSV0iDsuEU8v11yP9M&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;C++ tutorial playlist (videos: 1-13)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computer System Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-149&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad banner-1 adtester-container adtester-container-149&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-banner-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-banner-1-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;300&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad ezoic-adl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;In this course, you are going to be introduced to set design, processor micro-architecture and pipelining, cache and virtual memory organizations, protection and sharing, I/O and interrupts, in-order and out-of-order superscalar architectures, VLIW machines, vector supercomputers, multithreaded architectures, symmetric multiprocessors, and parallel computers. For this course, we will recommend you the following playlist coming from &lt;a href=&quot;http://laconicml.com/computer-science-engineer-mit-university/&quot;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt;. The list has 39 videos, that are quite long&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5PHm2jkkXmi5CxxI7b3JCL1TWybTDtKq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Computer Systems Architecture full playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zLP_X4wyHbY&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Web Design (HTML + CSS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is your introduction to what one stage of web development (the front-end) looks like. You are going to get familiar with HTML, which is the markup language that makes the elements we see on a webpage, and with CSS, which is a stylesheet that gives life to those elements. Here we recommend two videos, one for HTML and one for CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UB1O30fR-EE&amp;amp;ab_channel=TraversyMedia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;HTML Crash Course For Absolute Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yfoY53QXEnI&amp;amp;ab_channel=TraversyMedia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;CSS Crash Course For Absolute Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year 2: Semester 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is one of the most important courses for every Computer Science Engineer who wants to be an expert in &lt;a href=&quot;http://laconicml.com/free-artificial-intelligence-courses-by-google/&quot;&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;. The course consists of intro to probability, combinatorics, variations, permutations, distributions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-150&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad large-leaderboard-2 adtester-container adtester-container-150&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-large-leaderboard-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-large-leaderboard-2-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;300&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The playlist that we’ve recommended is from Khan’s Academy. It contains 41 videos that are 10 minutes long at max, and are very interesting, and contain tons of practical examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLC58778F28211FA19&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Probability playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the other most important courses if you want to do Machine Learning in the future. The course will get you familiar with the main statistical features, hypothesis testing, levels of measurements, etc. The playlist that we recommend contains 28 videos, which are quite long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5102DFDC6790F3D0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Statistics playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Algorithms and Data Structures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the most important course for every Computer Science Engineer. Here you will get familiar with tons of useful stuff, that you are going to use throughout your carrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you will get familiar with algorithms complexity measurements, data structures like lists, linked lists, arrays, hash tables, trees, graphs, and algorithms that will help you manipulate these structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-151&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad leader-1 adtester-container adtester-container-151&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-leader-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-leader-1-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;250&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad ezoic-adl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;For this course we will recommend you two playlists one theoretical, one using Java, and one video that pretty much combines these playlists, so you are choosing what you think suits you the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLGLfVvz_LVvReUrWr94U-ZMgjYTQ538nT&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Java Algorithms playlist (17 videos)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLpPXw4zFa0uKKhaSz87IowJnOTzh9tiBk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Data Structures theoretical playlist (89 videos)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intro to Client-side development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is an intro to client-side (front-end) development using the language of the web, known as JavaScript. It is a continuation of the Web Desing course, here you are going to power the website skeleton you’ve built with HTML and organized with CSS. Today JavaScript is used in the backend as well, but we are going to talk about that later. We recommend the following video for this course:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PkZNo7MFNFg&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linear Algebra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this course, you are going to get familiar with vectors, matrices, and manipulation with matrices, linear independence, least-square problems, etc. It is a very interesting and engaging course, that will be very useful later, for the Machine Learning and &lt;a href=&quot;https://laconicml.com/future-of-artificial-intelligence/&quot;&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/a&gt; Courses. For this course, we have 46 videos playlist. The videos are 25 minutes long at the most. Most of them are around 10 minutes mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLl-gb0E4MII03hiCrZa7YqxUMEeEPmZqK&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Linear Algebra playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semester 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operating Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-152&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad large-mobile-banner-1 adtester-container adtester-container-152&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-large-mobile-banner-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-large-mobile-banner-1-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;300&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;This course is very important. It is about the infrastructure we build our applications, run our projects, and optimize our solutions. In this course you will get familiar with: Introduction to OS, Operating System Structures, Process Management, Processes, Threads, CPU Scheduling, Process Synchronization, Deadlocks, Memory Management, Main Memory, Virtual Memory, Storage Management, File System Interface, File-System Implementation, Mass-Storage Structure, I/O Systems, Protection and Security, Distributed Systems, Distributed System Structures, Distributed File Systems, Distributed Coordination, Special Purpose Systems. For this course, we have two playlists. One is from UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLBlnK6fEyqRiVhbXDGLXDk_OQAeuVcp2O&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Operating System playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLRdybCcWDFzCag9A0h1m9QYaujD0xefgM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Berkeley CS 162 Operating Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the intro part of this article, we said that we are going to create a curriculum, using only YouTube videos, to help you to gain Computer Science knowledge and expertise in Artificial Intelligence. In this course you are going to get familiar with the basics of AI, types of learning, simple AI algorithms, and AI subfields. For this course we recommend you the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JMUxmLyrhSk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Artificial Intelligence Full Course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLGRecdYLYDNfBOtW6F1t5QTH01RdA5wjj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Artificial Intelligence MIT playlist (30 videos)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this course, you will get familiar with the concepts of building applications and projects, types and standards of programming, ways of organizing teams, planning resources, creating documentations, and running tests. It is very useful, especially as you progress in your software engineering carrier, you are going to use tons of the stuff you are going to learn here. We recommend two playlists for this course, one theoretical and one learning UML, which is a language that is used in software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLWPirh4EWFpG2b1L3CL-OAPYcM25jLjXH&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Software Engineering theoretical playlist (84 videos)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLGLfVvz_LVvQ5G-LdJ8RLqe-ndo7QITYc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;UML 2.0 Tutorial playlist (9 videos)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is a continuation of the Algorithms and Data Structures course from the 3-rd Semester. Here you are going to learn the following topics: the word RAM model, data structures, amortization, online algorithms, linear programming, semidefinite programming, approximation algorithms, hashing, randomized algorithms, fast exponential time algorithms, graph algorithms, and computational geometry. We recommend you the list of 25 videos by Harvard University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL2SOU6wwxB0uP4rJgf5ayhHWgw7akUWSf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Advanced Algorithms Harvard playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-153&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad large-mobile-banner-2 adtester-container adtester-container-153&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-large-mobile-banner-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-large-mobile-banner-2-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;250&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this course, you are going to learn algorithmic techniques for solving an optimization problem by breaking it down into simpler subproblems and utilizing the fact that the optimal solution to the overall problem depends upon the optimal solution to its subproblems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oBt53YbR9Kk&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year 3: Semester 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases (SQL)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a very important course for every CS engineer. Here you are going to learn about what is called backend for every application. You are going to get familiar with databases, relations, naming conventions, lookup tables, normal forms, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to reference a video where you are going to learn SQL. This language is used in the relational databases, the ones you are going to learn here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ztHopE5Wnpc&amp;amp;ab_channel=freeCodeCamp.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Database Design Course – Learn how to design and plan a database for beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HXV3zeQKqGY&amp;amp;ab_channel=freeCodeCamp.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;SQL Tutorial – Full Database Course for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Application Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;For every CS engineer is important to know at least one web application development framework. As a framework of our choice for this course is Django. Django is web app framework for Python. It is very easy to start, understand and use. It is very good for full-stack development and is popular among startups. Some of the biggest companies that use this framework are Instagram and YouTube. Here we will recommend you one playlist of 17 videos, and one 4 hours video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F5mRW0jo-U4&amp;amp;ab_channel=freeCodeCamp.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Python Django Web Framework – Full Course for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL-osiE80TeTtoQCKZ03TU5fNfx2UY6U4p&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Django Tutorial playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we’ve said in the intro part, we are going to base this curriculum around Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning. That being said here is the Machine Learning course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-154&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad mobile-leaderboard-1 adtester-container adtester-container-154&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-mobile-leaderboard-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-mobile-leaderboard-1-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;250&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad ezoic-adl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;In this course you are going to get familiar with Linear Regression, Naïve Bayes, SVM, Kernels, Neural Networks, Logistic Regression, Training, and Testing datasets, etc. Basically, everything that makes the base of Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a must-watch video for this course we recommend the Machine Learning playlist by &lt;a href=&quot;http://laconicml.com/free-artificial-intelligence-courses/&quot;&gt;Stanford University&lt;/a&gt;. The course is by &lt;a href=&quot;http://laconicml.com/andrew-ng-books-recommendation/&quot;&gt;Andrew Ng&lt;/a&gt;. The playlist is 20 videos that are quite long but is one of the best out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a practical guide for this course, we recommend you the famous Practical Machine Learning Tutorial with Python by Sentdex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list is 72 videos, that are quite short and very interesting. We know that this looks quite long, but this course is very important, and the time you are going to spend here will pay off later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jGwO_UgTS7I&amp;amp;list=PLoROMvodv4rMiGQp3WXShtMGgzqpfVfbU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Stanford CS229: Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQVvvaa0QuDfKTOs3Keq_kaG2P55YRn5v&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Practical Machine Learning Tutorial with Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Client-side development with React&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve already had courses that will get us familiar with the client-side of front-end development. The first course was with HTML and CSS, then the second was JavaScript and the third is going to be with React. This course will be the culmination of our front-end development courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;React is a JS library (like Vue and Angular, Angular is a framework), that helps you with the front-end development. It handles stuff like routing, creating reusable components (which is the core of React), fetching data from the backend, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very useful and very popular since it is lightweight and highly customizable. We recommend that every engineer should know at least one front-end library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DLX62G4lc44&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-155&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad leader-3 adtester-container adtester-container-155&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-leader-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-leader-3-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;336&quot; ezah=&quot;280&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad ezoic-adl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed Computing &amp;amp; Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this course, you are going to get familiar with Distributed Computing and Systems. Wikipedia: “Distributed computing is a field of computer science that studies distributed systems. A distributed system is a system whose components are located on different networked computers, which communicate and coordinate their actions by passing messages to one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The components interact with one another in order to achieve a common goal. Three significant characteristics of distributed systems are: concurrency of components, lack of a global clock, and independent failure of components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of distributed systems vary from SOA-based systems to massively multiplayer online games to peer-to-peer applications.” For this course, we recommend a video playlist from MIT, that is 21 videos, and the videos are quite long, and useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrw6a1wE39_tb2fErI4-WkMbsvGQk9_UB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;MIT Distributed Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semester 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-relational Databases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is another version of the Databases course from the previous semester. The Databases course was based on relational databases, since those are easier to understand, and quite similar to the OOP concept and are the most used and most popular solutions for most of the products on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not most of those solutions, have the same complexity or data formats. To satisfy those needs, we have different types of non-relational databases, like: Document-based (Mongo, Firebase), Text Search Engines (Elasticsearch), Multimodal (Fauna), etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-156&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad narrow-sky-2 adtester-container adtester-container-156&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-narrow-sky-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-narrow-sky-2-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;300&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;In this course, you are going to get familiar with Document-based databases, or more precisely with Mongo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uD3p_rZPBUQ&amp;amp;ab_channel=TraversyMedia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;NoSQL Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pWbMrx5rVBE&amp;amp;ab_channel=TraversyMedia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;MongoDB Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Deep Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is your introduction to Deep Learning. Wikipedia: “Deep learning (also known as deep structured learning) is part of a broader family of machine learning methods based on artificial neural networks with representation learning. Learning can be supervised, semi-supervised, or unsupervised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep-learning architectures such as deep neural networks, deep belief networks, recurrent neural networks, and convolutional neural networks have been applied to fields including computer vision, machine vision, speech recognition, natural language processing, audio recognition, social network filtering, machine translation, bioinformatics, drug design, medical image analysis, material inspection, and board game programs, where they have produced results comparable to and in some cases surpassing human expert performance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this course we recommend you the following playlist by MIT, consisting of 31 videos, that are 45 minutes long at maximum. It is very interesting, full of great information and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLtBw6njQRU-rwp5__7C0oIVt26ZgjG9NI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;MIT Introduction to Deep Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practical Implementation of Neural Networks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course will be an introduction to the TensorFlow framework, that allows you easy work with neural networks. You will learn how to use and implement neural networks in different areas like Computer Vision, NLP, Reinforcement Learning, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tPYj3fFJGjk&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile applications – IOS development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this course, you are going to get familiar with IOS development with Swift. This course is important because we have another course that follows in the future semesters, which is Developing Intelligent mobile apps with Swift and TensorFlow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to emphasize that since mobile apps are a huge part of the market and grow each day, meaning we are going to need an intelligent solution for that part of the market as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ulp1Kimblg0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Swift Programming Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=09TeUXjzpKs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;IOS Tutorial: How To Make Your First Application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-157&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad mobile-leaderboard-2 adtester-container adtester-container-157&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-mobile-leaderboard-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-mobile-leaderboard-2-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;250&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile applications – Android development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those of you who do not like Apple, or simply do not own a Mac, here is the course for Android mobile applications development. The importance of Android is the same as IOS, with the difference that Android covers a bigger market in terms of devices sold since are quite cheaper than the iPhones and iPads and are more affordable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fis26HvvDII&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year 4: Semester 7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Signals and Systems (Digital Signal Processing)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The analysis of signals and systems forms a key part of many modern technologies, including communications and feedback &amp;amp; control. These lectures give a conceptual and mathematical introduction to the topic, covering both analog and digital systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this course, we recommend you the playlist from the MIT OpenCourseWare program, which consists of 25 videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUl4u3cNGP61kdPAOC7CzFjJZ8f1eMUxs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;MIT Signals and Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural Language Understanding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is an intro to for future more advanced courses where you are going to learn about Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning. Wikipedia: “Natural-language understanding (NLU) or natural-language interpretation (NLI) is a subtopic of natural-language processing in artificial intelligence that deals with machine reading comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-158&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad leader-2 adtester-container adtester-container-158&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-leader-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-leader-2-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;250&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad ezoic-adl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Natural-language understanding is considered an AI-hard problem. There is considerable commercial interest in the field because of its application to automated reasoning, machine translation, question answering, news-gathering, text categorization, voice-activation, archiving, and large-scale content analysis.” For this course, we recommend you the NLU playlist from Stanford, which is 15 videos long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLoROMvodv4rObpMCir6rNNUlFAn56Js20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Stanford Natural Language Understanding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intelligent Mobile Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this course, you are going to get familiar with developing mobile applications, that use &lt;a href=&quot;http://laconicml.com/coursera-artificial-intelligence-courses/&quot;&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;. We are going to develop Android and IOS apps using their native platforms and TensorFlow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0SBtAjUauOc&amp;amp;ab_channel=TensorFlow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;TensorFlow Lite for IOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s65BigoMV_I&amp;amp;ab_channel=TensorFlow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Swift for TensorFlow: The Next Generation Machine Learning Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computer Vision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia: “Computer vision is an interdisciplinary scientific field that deals with how computers can gain a high-level understanding from digital images or videos. From the perspective of engineering, it seeks to understand and automate tasks that the human visual system can do.” For this course, we recommend a video from MIT with a theoretical explanation about Computer Vision and &lt;a href=&quot;http://laconicml.com/barcode-detection-opencv/&quot;&gt;OpenCV&lt;/a&gt; with Python tutorial, as it is the most used library for Computer Vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CLOAswsxudo&amp;amp;ab_channel=LexFridman&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;MIT Computer Vision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oXlwWbU8l2o&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;OpenCV Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robotics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;MIT: “Robots today move far too conservatively, using control systems that attempt to maintain full control authority at all times. Humans and animals move much more aggressively by routinely executing motions that involve a loss of instantaneous control authority. Controlling nonlinear systems without complete control authority requires methods that can reason about and exploit the natural dynamics of our machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course discusses nonlinear dynamics and control of underactuated mechanical systems, with an emphasis on machine learning methods. Topics include nonlinear dynamics of passive robots (walkers, swimmers, flyers), motion planning, partial feedback linearization, energy-shaping control, analytical optimal control, reinforcement learning/approximate optimal control, and the influence of mechanical design on control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-159&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad narrow-sky-1 adtester-container adtester-container-159&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-narrow-sky-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-narrow-sky-1-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;728&quot; ezah=&quot;90&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Discussions include examples from biology and applications to legged locomotion, compliant manipulation, underwater robots, and flying machines.” For this course, we recommend you the MIT playlist that has 23 videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL58F1D0056F04CF8C&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;MIT Underactuated Robotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semester 8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is a continuation of the Natural Language Understanding course from the previous semester. Here you are going to use some of the most popular algorithms in &lt;a href=&quot;https://laconicml.com/build-natural-language-processing-system/&quot;&gt;NLP&lt;/a&gt; powered by Neural Networks. For this course, we recommend you this list from Stanford that has 20 videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLoROMvodv4rOhcuXMZkNm7j3fVwBBY42z&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Stanford Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning full playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8rXD5-xhemo&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reinforcement Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this course, you are going to get familiar with a specific subfield of Machine Learning, known as Reinforcement Learning. Wikipedia: “Reinforcement learning (RL) is an area of machine learning concerned with how software agents ought to take actions in an environment in order to maximize the notion of cumulative reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinforcement learning is one of three basic machine learning paradigms, alongside supervised learning and unsupervised learning.” It is very popular in every other subfield of ML. One of the most notable users of RL techniques is &lt;a href=&quot;http://laconicml.com/train-robot-agent-cartpole-q-learning/&quot;&gt;OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;, in their OpenAI Five algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-160&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad leader-4 adtester-container adtester-container-160&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;laconicml_com-leader-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-laconicml_com-leader-4-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;336&quot; ezah=&quot;280&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad ezoic-adl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;We recommend you two video playlists, one from Stanford that is 15 videos long and one from Sentdex 6 videos long, where he explains a practical approach to RL with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLoROMvodv4rOSOPzutgyCTapiGlY2Nd8u&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Stanford Reinforcement Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQVvvaa0QuDezJFIOU5wDdfy4e9vdnx-7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Reinforcement Learning with Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Bioinformatics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia: “Bioinformatics is an interdisciplinary field that develops methods and software tools for understanding biological data, in particular when the data sets are large and complex. As an interdisciplinary field of science, bioinformatics combines biology, computer science, information engineering, mathematics, and statistics to analyze and interpret biological data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bioinformatics has been used for in silico analyses of biological queries using mathematical and statistical techniques.” This course is an introduction to computational biology emphasizing the fundamentals of nucleic acid and protein sequence and structural analysis; it also includes an introduction to the analysis of complex biological systems. We recommend the following playlist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUl4u3cNGP63uK-oWiLgO7LLJV6ZCWXac&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;MIT Computational and Systems Biology (22 videos)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLpSOMAcxEB_jUKMvdl8rHqNiZXFIrtd5G&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Bioinformatics with Python (18 videos)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Driving Cars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia: “A self-driving car, also known as an autonomous vehicle (AV), driverless car, or robocar is a vehicle that is capable of sensing its environment and moving safely with little or no human input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-driving cars combine a variety of sensors to perceive their surroundings, such as radar, lidar, sonar, GPS, odometry, and inertial measurement units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced control systems interpret sensory information to identify appropriate navigation paths, as well as obstacles and relevant signage.” This playlist of 10 videos is by MIT is an introduction to self-driving cars, and it is organized by professor Lex Fridman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrAXtmErZgOeY0lkVCIVafdGFOTi45amq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;MIT Self-Driving cars full playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sRxaMDDMWQQ&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning for Healthcare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is your introduction to the implementation of Machine Learning in the Healthcare industry. Introduces students to machine learning in healthcare, the nature of clinical data, and the use of machine learning for risk stratification, disease progression modeling, precision medicine, diagnosis, subtype discovery, and improving clinical workflows. For this course, we recommend you the following MIT playlist of 25 videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUl4u3cNGP60B0PQXVQyGNdCyCTDU1Q5j&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;MIT Machine Learning for Healthcare full playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; data-ezsrc=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vof7x8r_ZUA&quot; class=&quot;ezlazyload&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here is our 40 courses, 4 academic years Computer Science curriculum in 1079 YouTube videos. Now, what’s the verdict? Well, &lt;strong&gt;it can’t replace the traditional curriculum&lt;/strong&gt; from the universities, but it can go along with them as your assistance and look from another perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing is that is &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt;, easy to access by everyone, and opens many other resources in form of other recommended videos or references in the descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in other types of free courses check out our previous articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like with every post we do, we encourage you to continue learning, trying, and creating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fusion-reading-box-container reading-box-container-2 fusion-animated&quot; data-animationtype=&quot;slideInUp&quot; data-animationduration=&quot;0.3&quot; data-animationoffset=&quot;100%&quot; readability=&quot;8.4929577464789&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;reading-box reading-box-center element-bottomshadow&quot; readability=&quot;12.267605633803&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, we have a new private Facebook group where we are going to share some materials that are not going to be published online and will be available for our members only. The members will have early access to every new post we make and share your thoughts, tips, articles and questions. Become part of our private Facebook group now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;button fusion-button button-green fusion-button-large button-large button-flat fusion-mobile-button continue-center&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/1682628565239534/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Join Laconicml Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-172927714-1720-5ffe1a3d43890&quot; data-src=&quot;https://widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=172927714&amp;amp;post_id=1720&amp;amp;origin=laconicml.com&amp;amp;obj_id=172927714-1720-5ffe1a3d43890&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-172927714-1720-5ffe1a3d43890&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 20:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nixass</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Entire Computer Science Curriculum in 1000 YouTube Videos | Laconicml</og:title>
<og:description>This is The Entire Computer Science Curriculum in 1000 YouTube Videos. The curriculum is going to be organized in 40 courses in total, further organized in 4 academic years...</og:description>
<og:url>https://laconicml.com/computer-science-curriculum-youtube-videos/</og:url>
<og:image>https://laconicml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/post_58_naslovna.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://laconicml.com/computer-science-curriculum-youtube-videos/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>U.S. to require negative Covid-19 tests for international air passengers</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-airlines/u-s-to-require-negative-covid-19-tests-for-international-air-passengers-sources-idUSKBN29H2KD</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-airlines/u-s-to-require-negative-covid-19-tests-for-international-air-passengers-sources-idUSKBN29H2KD</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-byline-container-3H6dy&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Byline-byline-1sVmo ArticleBody-byline-10B7D&quot;&gt;By &lt;a class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__black-to-orange___23uc0 TextLabel__serif___3lOpX Byline-author-2BSir&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/journalists/david-shepardson&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Shepardson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-read-time-and-social-2VOIr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__gray___1V4fk TextLabel__small-all-caps-spaced-out___3O9H4 ReadTime-read-time-1s3CG ArticleBody-read-time-29pGN&quot;&gt;2 Min Read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FILE PHOTO: Travelers check in for their flights at Detroit Metropolitan Wayne County Airport, amid the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) pandemic, in Romulus, Michigan, U.S., December 24, 2020. REUTERS/Emily Elconin/File Photo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Nearly all air travelers will need to present a negative coronavirus test to enter the United States under expanded test testing requirements announced on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Under the rules taking effect Jan. 26, nearly all travelers including U.S. citizens must show a negative test within three days of departure or documentation of recovery from COVID-19, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;All travelers aged 2 and older must comply except passengers who are only transiting through the United States. The CDC will also consider waivers of testing requirements for airlines flying to countries with little or no testing capacity, including some places in the Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The order broadened a requirement imposed on Dec. 28 for travelers arriving from the UK as a more transmissible variant of the virus circulated there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The CDC confirmed last week it had circulated a proposal to expand the testing requirement worldwide. Officials briefed on the matter said last week U.S. public health officials had essentially given up winning approval until President-elect Joe Biden took office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Canada imposed similar rules for nearly all international arrivals starting Jan. 7, as have many other countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;At a White House meeting on Monday, CDC Director Robert Redfield again made an urgent case to adopt the testing requirements, people briefed on the meeting said. He raised concerns that vaccines could potentially not be effective against virus variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Earlier this month, major U.S. airlines backed the CDC’s push to implement a global testing program requiring negative tests for air passengers flying to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;5.5178571428571&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution-attribution-Y5JpY&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting by David Shepardson; Editing by Chris Reese, Dan Grebler and Cynthia Osterman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 19:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Element_</dc:creator>
<og:title>U.S. to require negative COVID-19 tests for arriving international air passengers</og:title>
<og:description>Nearly all air travelers will need to present a negative coronavirus test to enter the United States under expanded test testing requirements announced on Tuesday.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.reuters.com/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20210112&amp;t=2&amp;i=1547531421&amp;r=LYNXMPEH0B1CR&amp;w=800</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-airlines-idUSKBN29H2KD</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-airlines/u-s-to-require-negative-covid-19-tests-for-international-air-passengers-sources-idUSKBN29H2KD</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>If it will matter after today, don&amp;#039;t talk about it in a chat room</title>
<link>https://critter.blog/2021/01/12/if-it-matters-after-today-stop-talking-about-it-in-a-chat-room/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://critter.blog/2021/01/12/if-it-matters-after-today-stop-talking-about-it-in-a-chat-room/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Live chat (Slack, Teams, etc.) sucks for important discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking one line at a time lowers the quality of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://critter.blog/2020/01/08/discussion-topics-for-development-teams/&quot;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt;. Knee jerk rapid fire responses become the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversations that last weeks or even days get lost and context gets fuzzy. Threads scroll up into the past and are never seen again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the “asychronous” claim, you have to &lt;a href=&quot;https://critter.blog/2019/09/05/the-chatodoro-breaking-the-group-chat-addiction/&quot;&gt;keep a steady eye on it&lt;/a&gt; and reply in realtime or the conversation will move on without you. Anyone who takes the time to ponder and respond thoughtfully with context and explanation will find that they’re too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go on vacation or even take a few hours of &lt;a href=&quot;https://critter.blog/2020/10/13/heads-down-tuesday/&quot;&gt;focused time for deep work&lt;/a&gt;, you come back to hundreds or thousands of messages. Often your only option is to declare chat room &lt;a href=&quot;https://critter.blog/2020/09/24/declare-bankruptcy-and-dont-be-ashamed-of-it/&quot;&gt;bankruptcy&lt;/a&gt; which means missing out on important discussions and big decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying live chat is useless. It’s great at some things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, &lt;strong&gt;live chat is for the things that can get lost.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://critter.blog/2021/01/07/a-simple-process-beats-a-perfect-process/&quot;&gt;Rule of thumb&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;If a discussion will matter after today, don’t have it in a chat room.&lt;/em&gt; Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discourse.org/&quot;&gt;Discourse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twist.com/&quot;&gt;Twist&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://carrot.io/&quot;&gt;Carrot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://threads.com/&quot;&gt;Threads&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://flarum.org/&quot;&gt;Flarum&lt;/a&gt;, or heck even GitHub issues. These tools exist for a reason. They solve a real problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;They encourage longer form responses rather than quick one liner replies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They show you a list of threads &lt;em&gt;with titles&lt;/em&gt; for maximum &lt;a href=&quot;https://critter.blog/2020/10/05/guerrilla-productivity-tactics/&quot;&gt;skim-ability&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They let you sort (by last comment, for example) and filter threads or archive them once a decision has been reached.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They don’t show online/offline indicators or timezone notifications or “XYZ is typing…” because nobody expects a quick response anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of them even support multi-level (Reddit-style) threading, which can help if a lot of people are involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try it as &lt;a href=&quot;https://critter.blog/2020/08/12/stop-changing-start-experimenting/&quot;&gt;an experiment&lt;/a&gt;. For one sprint, ask if your team will put anything that matters after today in a discussion tool instead of a chat room. Then see if they want to switch back after the sprint ends.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 19:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mcrittenden</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>If it will matter after today, stop talking about it in a chat room</og:title>
<og:url>https://critter.blog/2021/01/12/if-it-matters-after-today-stop-talking-about-it-in-a-chat-room/</og:url>
<og:description>Live chat is for things that can get lost.</og:description>
<og:image>https://mikecrittendenhome.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/stephen-phillips-hostreviews-co-uk-ae0ix-blcjc-unsplash.jpg?w=1200</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://critter.blog/2021/01/12/if-it-matters-after-today-stop-talking-about-it-in-a-chat-room/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Silicon Valley destroyed Parler</title>
<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/how-silicon-valley-in-a-show-of-monopolistic</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://greenwald.substack.com/p/how-silicon-valley-in-a-show-of-monopolistic</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;captioned-image-container&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;image-link image2 image2-1092-1456&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F5bf83518-22df-4333-a423-63fbb59cb9a2_4032x3024.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F5bf83518-22df-4333-a423-63fbb59cb9a2_4032x3024.jpeg&quot; data-attrs=&quot;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/5bf83518-22df-4333-a423-63fbb59cb9a2_4032x3024.jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1092,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:4735534,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Users of the social media platform Parler encountered this error message as of Jan. 11, 2021, after Apple, Google and Amazon united to remove them from app stores and hosting services (Photo by Lorenzo Di Cola/NurPhoto via Getty Images).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critics of Silicon Valley&lt;/strong&gt; censorship for years heard the same refrain: tech platforms like Facebook, Google and Twitter are private corporations and can host or ban whoever they want. If you don’t like what they are doing, the solution is not to complain or to regulate them. Instead, go create your own social media platform that operates the way you think it should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The founders of Parler heard that suggestion and tried. In August, 2018, they created a social media platform similar to Twitter but which promised far greater privacy protections, including a refusal to aggregate user data in order to monetize them to advertisers or algorithmically evaluate their interests in order to promote content or products to them. They also promised far greater free speech rights, rejecting the increasingly repressive content policing of Silicon Valley giants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, Parler encountered immense success. Millions of people who objected to increasing repression of speech on the largest platforms or who had themselves been banned signed up for the new social media company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Silicon Valley censorship radically escalated over the past several months — &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2020/10/15/facebook-and-twitter-cross-a-line-far-more-dangerous-than-what-they-censor/&quot;&gt;banning pre-election reporting&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;em&gt;The New York Post&lt;/em&gt; about the Biden family, denouncing and deleting multiple posts from the U.S. President and then terminating his access altogether, mass-removal of right-wing accounts — so many people migrated to Parler that it was catapulted to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/09/parler-jumps-to-no-1-on-app-store-after-facebook-and-twitter-bans/?guccounter=1&quot;&gt;number one spot&lt;/a&gt; on the list of most-downloaded apps on the Apple Play Store, the sole and exclusive means which iPhone users have to download apps. “Overall, the app was the 10th most downloaded social media app in 2020 with 8.1 million new installs,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/09/parler-jumps-to-no-1-on-app-store-after-facebook-and-twitter-bans/?guccounter=1&quot;&gt;reported TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looked as if Parler had proven critics of Silicon Valley monopolistic power wrong. Their success showed that it was possible after all to create a new social media platform to compete with Facebook, Instagram and Twitter. And they did so by doing exactly what Silicon Valley defenders long insisted should be done: &lt;em&gt;if you don’t like the rules imposed by tech giants, go create your own platform with different rules&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;captioned-image-container&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;image-link image2 image2-849-560&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F4cf23313-31c9-4de7-b0e9-d17361fa3dc0_560x849.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F4cf23313-31c9-4de7-b0e9-d17361fa3dc0_560x849.png&quot; data-attrs=&quot;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/4cf23313-31c9-4de7-b0e9-d17361fa3dc0_560x849.png&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:849,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:560,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:216629,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/png&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;List of most-downloaded apps on Apple Store, Jan. 8, 2021&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But today, if you want to download, sign up for, or use Parler, you will be unable to do so. That is because three Silicon Valley monopolies — Amazon, Google and Apple — abruptly united to remove Parler from the internet, exactly at the moment when it became the most-downloaded app in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one were looking for evidence to demonstrate that these tech behemoths are, in fact, monopolies that engage in anti-competitive behavior in violation of antitrust laws, and will obliterate any attempt to compete with them in the marketplace, it would be difficult to imagine anything more compelling than how they just used their unconstrained power to utterly destroy a rising competitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The united Silicon Valley attack&lt;/strong&gt; began on January 8, when Apple emailed Parler and gave them 24 hours to prove they had changed their moderation practices or else face removal from their App Store. The letter claimed: “We have received numerous complaints regarding objectionable content in your Parler service, accusations that the Parler app was used to plan, coordinate, and facilitate the illegal activities in Washington D.C. on January 6, 2021 that led (among other things) to loss of life, numerous injuries, and the destruction of property.” It ended with this warning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure there is no interruption of the availability of your app on the App Store, please submit an update and the requested moderation improvement plan within 24 hours of the date of this message. If we do not receive an update compliant with the App Store Review Guidelines and the requested moderation improvement plan in writing within 24 hours, your app will be removed from the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 24-hour letter was an obvious pretext and purely performative. Removal was a &lt;em&gt;fait accompli&lt;/em&gt; no matter what Parler did. To begin with, the letter was immediately leaked to &lt;em&gt;Buzzfeed&lt;/em&gt;, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/apple-threatens-ban-parler&quot;&gt;published it in full&lt;/a&gt;. A Parler executive detailed the company’s unsuccessful attempts to communicate with Apple. “They basically ghosted us,” he told me. The next day, Apple notified Parler of its removal from App Store. “We won’t distribute apps that present dangerous and harmful content,” said the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/business/business-news/apple-now-worth-2-trillion-making-it-most-valuable-company-n1237287&quot;&gt;world’s richest company&lt;/a&gt;, and thus: “We have now rejected your app for the App Store.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to overstate the harm to a platform from being removed from the App Store. Users of iPhones are barred from downloading apps onto their devices from the internet. If an app is not on the App Store, it cannot be used on the iPhone. Even iPhone users who have already downloaded Parler will lose the ability to receive updates, which will shortly render the platform both unmanageable and unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;button-wrapper&quot; data-attrs=&quot;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://greenwald.substack.com/p/how-silicon-valley-in-a-show-of-monopolistic?&amp;amp;utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=share&amp;amp;action=share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button primary&quot; href=&quot;https://greenwald.substack.com/p/how-silicon-valley-in-a-show-of-monopolistic?&amp;amp;utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=share&amp;amp;action=share&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October, the House Judiciary Subcommittee on Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law issued a 425-page &lt;a href=&quot;https://judiciary.house.gov/uploadedfiles/competition_in_digital_markets.pdf&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; concluding that Amazon, Apple, Facebook and Google all possess monopoly power and are using that power anti-competitively. For Apple, they emphasized the company’s control over iPhones through its control of access to the App Store. As &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/10/house-amazon-facebook-apple-google-have-monopoly-power-should-be-split/&quot;&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt; when highlighting the report’s key findings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;28.135188866799&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple controls about 45 percent of the US smartphone market and 20 percent of the global smartphone market, the committee found, and is projected to sell its 2 billionth iPhone in 2021. It is correct that, in the smartphone handset market, Apple is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a monopoly. Instead, iOS and Android hold an effective duopoly in mobile operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the report concludes, Apple &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; have a monopolistic hold over what you can &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; with an iPhone. You can only put apps on your phone through the Apple App Store, and Apple has total gatekeeper control over that App Store—that's what &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2020/09/apple-vs-epic-hearing-previews-a-long-hard-fought-trial-to-come/&quot;&gt;Epic is suing the company over&lt;/a&gt;. . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The committee found internal documents showing that company leadership, including former CEO Steve Jobs, &quot;acknowledged that IAP requirement would stifle competition and limit the apps available to Apple's customers.&quot; The report concludes that Apple has also unfairly used its control over APIs, search rankings, and default apps to limit competitors' access to iPhone users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly thereafter, Parler learned that Google, without warning, had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55598887&quot;&gt;also “suspended”&lt;/a&gt; it from its Play Store, severely limiting the ability of users to download Parler onto Android phones. Google’s actions also meant that those using Parler on their Android phones would no longer receive necessary functionality and security updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was precisely Google’s abuse of its power to control its app device that was &lt;a href=&quot;http://competitionlawblog.kluwercompetitionlaw.com/2019/10/15/competition-authorities-to-investigate-mobile-application-store-dominance/&quot;&gt;at issue&lt;/a&gt; “when the European Commission deemed Google LLC as the dominant undertaking in the app stores for the Android mobile operating system (i.e. Google Play Store) and hit the online search and advertisement giant with €4.34 billion for its anti-competitive practices to strengthen its position in various of other markets through its dominance in the app store market.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after a united Apple and Google acted against Parler, Amazon delivered the fatal blow. The company founded and run by the world’s richest man, Jeff Bezos, used virtually identical language as Apple to inform Parler that its web hosting service (AWS) was terminating Parler’s ability to have AWS host its site: “Because Parler cannot comply with our terms of service and poses a very real risk to public safety, we plan to suspend Parler’s account effective Sunday, January 10th, at 11:59PM PST.” Because Amazon is such a dominant force in web hosting, Parler has thus far not found a hosting service for its platform, which is why it has disappeared not only from app stores and phones but also from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, Parler was the most popular app in the United States. By Monday, three of the four Silicon Valley monopolies united to destroy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With virtual unanimity,&lt;/strong&gt; leading U.S. liberals celebrated this use of Silicon Valley monopoly power to shut down Parler, just as they overwhelmingly cheered the prior two extraordinary assertions of tech power to control U.S. political discourse: censorship of &lt;em&gt;The New York Post&lt;/em&gt;’s reporting on the contents of Hunter Biden’s laptop, and the banning of the U.S. President from major platforms. Indeed, one would be hard-pressed to find a single national liberal-left politician even expressing concerns about any of this, let alone opposing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only did leading left-wing politicians not object but some of them were the ones who pleaded with Silicon Valley to use their power this way. After the internet-policing site Sleeping Giants flagged several Parler posts that called for violence, Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AOC/status/1347679332014161920&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt;: “What are &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Apple&quot;&gt;@Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GooglePlay&quot;&gt;@GooglePlay&lt;/a&gt; doing about this?” Once Apple responded by removing Parler from its App Store — a move that House Democrats just three months earlier warned was dangerous anti-trust behavior — she praised Apple and then demanded to know: “Good to see this development from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Apple&quot;&gt;@Apple&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GooglePlay&quot;&gt;@GooglePlay&lt;/a&gt; what are you going to do about apps being used to organize violence on your platform?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The liberal &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; columnist Michelle Goldberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/11/opinion/twitter-facebook-trump-ban.html&quot;&gt;pronounced herself&lt;/a&gt; “disturbed by just how awesome [tech giants’] power is” and added that “it’s dangerous to have a handful of callow young tech titans in charge of who has a megaphone and who does not.” She nonetheless praised these “young tech titans” for using their “dangerous” power to ban Trump and destroy Parler. In other words, liberals like Goldberg are concerned only that Silicon Valley censorship powers might one day be used against people like them, but are perfectly happy as long as it is their adversaries being deplatformed and silenced (Facebook and other platforms have for years banned marginalized people like &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2017/12/30/facebook-says-it-is-deleting-accounts-at-the-direction-of-the-u-s-and-israeli-governments/&quot;&gt;Palestinians at Israel’s behest&lt;/a&gt;, but that is of no concern to U.S. liberals).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is because the dominant strain of American liberalism is not economic socialism but political authoritarianism. Liberals now want to use the force of corporate power to silence those with different ideologies. They are eager for tech monopolies not just to ban accounts they dislike but to remove entire platforms from the internet. They want to imprison people they believe helped their party lose elections, such as Julian Assange, even if it means creating precedents to criminalize journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World leaders have vocally condemned the power Silicon Valley has amassed to police political discourse, and were particularly indignant over the banning of the U.S. President. German Chancellor Angela Merkel, various French ministers, and especially Mexican President Andrés Manuel López Obrador all denounced the banning of Trump and other acts of censorship by tech monopolies on the ground that they were anointing themselves “a world media power.” The warnings from López Obrador were particularly eloquent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the ACLU — which has rapidly transformed from a civil liberties organization into a liberal activist group since Trump’s election — found the assertion of Silicon Valley’s power to destroy Parler deeply alarming. One of that organization’s most stalwart defenders of civil liberties, lawyer Ben Wizner, &lt;a href=&quot;https://judiciary.house.gov/uploadedfiles/competition_in_digital_markets.pdf&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://judiciary.house.gov/uploadedfiles/competition_in_digital_markets.pdf&quot;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; that the destruction of Parler was more “troubling” than the deletion of posts or whole accounts: “I think we should recognize the importance of neutrality when we’re talking about the infrastructure of the internet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet American liberals swoon for this authoritarianism. And they are now calling for the use of the most repressive War on Terror measures against their domestic opponents. On Tuesday, House Homeland Security Chair Bennie Thompson (D-MS) &lt;a href=&quot;https://lawandcrime.com/2020-election/a-terrorist-is-a-terrorist-house-homeland-security-chair-wants-ted-cruz-and-josh-hawley-on-the-no-fly-list/&quot;&gt;urged&lt;/a&gt; that GOP Sens. Ted Cruz and Josh Hawley “be put on the no-fly list,” while &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; reported that “Biden has said he plans to make a priority of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/biden-administration-urged-to-take-fresh-look-at-domestic-terrorism-11605279834&quot;&gt;passing a law against domestic terrorism&lt;/a&gt;, and he has been urged to create a White House post overseeing the fight against ideologically inspired violent extremists and increasing funding to combat them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much of this liberal support for the attempted destruction of Parler is based in utter ignorance about that platform, and about basic principles of free speech. I’d be very surprised if more than a tiny fraction of liberals cheering Parler’s removal from the internet have ever used the platform or know anything about it other than the snippets they have been shown by those seeking to justify its destruction and to depict it as some neo-Nazi stronghold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parler was not founded, nor is it run, by pro-Trump, MAGA supporters. The platform was created based in libertarian values of privacy, anti-surveillance, anti-data collection, and free speech. Most of the key executives are more associated with the politics of Ron Paul and the CATO Institute than Steve Bannon or the Trump family. One is a Never Trump Republican, while another is the former campaign manager of Ron Paul and Rand Paul. Among the few MAGA-affiliated figures is Dan Bongino, an investor. One of the key original investors was Rebekah Mercer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform’s design is intended to foster privacy and free speech, not a particular ideology. They minimize the amount of data they collect on users to prevent advertiser monetization or algorithmic targeting. Unlike Facebook and Twitter, they do not assess a user’s preferences in order to decide what they should see. And they were principally borne out of a reaction to increasingly restrictive rules on the major Silicon Valley platforms regarding what could and could not be said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course large numbers of Trump supporters ended up on Parler. That’s not because Parler is a pro-Trump outlet, but because those are among the people who were censored by the tech monopolies or who were angered enough by that censorship to seek refuge elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is true that one can find postings on Parler that explicitly advocate violence or are otherwise grotesque. But that is even more true of Facebook, Google-owned YouTube, and Twitter. And contrary to what many have been led to believe, Parler’s Terms of Service includes a ban on explicit advocacy of violence, and they employ a team of paid, trained moderators who delete such postings. Those deletions do not happen perfectly or instantaneously — which is why one can find postings that violate those rules — but the same is true of every major Silicon Valley platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, a Parler executive told me that of the thirteen people arrested as of Monday for the breach at the Capitol, none appear to be active users of Parler. The Capitol breach was planned far more on Facebook and YouTube. As &lt;em&gt;Recode&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/recode/22221285/trump-online-capitol-riot-far-right-parler-twitter-facebook&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;, while some protesters participated in both Parler and Gab, many of the calls to attend the Capitol were from YouTube videos, while many of the key planners “have continued to use mainstream platforms like Twitter, Facebook, and YouTube.” The article quoted Fadi Quran, campaign director at the human rights group Avaaz, as saying: “In DC, we saw QAnon conspiracists and other militias that would never have grown to this size &lt;em&gt;without being turbo-charged by Facebook and Twitter&lt;/em&gt;.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s to say nothing of the endless number of hypocrisies with Silicon Valley giants feigning opposition to violent rhetoric or political extremism. Amazon, for instance, is one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/business/technology/la-fi-cia-amazon-cloud-computing-20190403-story.html#:~:text=Amazon%20already%20has%20a%20%24600,it%20says%20would%20favor%20Amazon.&quot;&gt;CIA’s most profitable partners&lt;/a&gt;, with a $600 million contract to provide services to the agency, and it is constantly bidding for more. On Facebook and Twitter, one finds &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/MojKsaEn/&quot;&gt;official accounts&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mojksa_en?lang=en&quot;&gt;most repressive and violent regimes&lt;/a&gt; on earth, including Saudi Arabia, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/General-Abdel-Fattah-el-Sisi-of-Egypt-437247223039646/&quot;&gt;pages devoted to propaganda&lt;/a&gt; on behalf of the Egyptian regime. Does anyone think these tech giants have a genuine concern about violence and extremism?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;captioned-image-container&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;image-link image2 image2-681-942&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F2933ecee-d1a9-4c47-b93f-d28a08cade30_942x681.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F2933ecee-d1a9-4c47-b93f-d28a08cade30_942x681.png&quot; data-attrs=&quot;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/2933ecee-d1a9-4c47-b93f-d28a08cade30_942x681.png&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:681,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:942,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:259257,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/png&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Official Facebook page of the Saudi Justice Ministry&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why did Democratic politicians and journalists focus on Parler rather than Facebook and YouTube? Why did Amazon, Google and Apple make a flamboyant showing of removing Parler from the internet while leaving much larger platforms with far more extremism and advocacy of violence flowing on a daily basis?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In part it is because these Silicon Valley giants — Google, Facebook, Amazon, Apple — donate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/silicon-valley-opens-wallet-joe-biden/&quot;&gt;enormous sums of money&lt;/a&gt; to the Democratic Party and their leaders, so of course Democrats will cheer them rather than call for punishment or their removal from the internet. Part of it is because Parler is an upstart, a much easier target to try to destroy than Facebook or Google. And in part it is because the Democrats are about to control the Executive Branch and both houses of Congress, leaving Silicon Valley giants eager to please them by silencing their adversaries. This corrupt motive was made expressly clear by long-time Clinton operative Jennifer Palmieri:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tweet&quot; data-attrs=&quot;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/jmpalmieri/status/1347064818944118784&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;full_text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;It has not escaped my attention that the day social media companies decided there actually IS more they could do to police Trump’s destructive behavior was the same day they learned Democrats would chair all the congressional committees that oversee them.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;username&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;jmpalmieri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Jennifer Palmieri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;date&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Thu Jan 07 06:17:34 +0000 2021&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;photos&amp;quot;:[],&amp;quot;quoted_tweet&amp;quot;:{},&amp;quot;retweet_count&amp;quot;:33003,&amp;quot;like_count&amp;quot;:158450,&amp;quot;expanded_url&amp;quot;:{}}&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;

It has not escaped my attention that the day social media companies decided there actually IS more they could do to police Trump’s destructive behavior was the same day they learned Democrats would chair all the congressional committees that oversee them.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of monopolistic power is that anti-competitive entities engage in anti-trust illegalities to destroy rising competitors. Parler is associated with the wrong political ideology. It is a small and new enough platform such that it can be made an example of. Its head can be placed on a pike to make clear that no attempt to compete with existing Silicon Valley monopolies is possible. And its destruction preserves the unchallengeable power of a tiny handful of tech oligarchs over the political discourse not just of the United States but democracies worldwide (which is why Germany, France and Mexico are raising their voices in protest).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No authoritarians believe they are authoritarians. No matter how repressive are the measures they support — censorship, monopoly power, no-fly lists for American citizens without due process — they tell themselves that those they are silencing and attacking are so evil, are &lt;em&gt;terrorists&lt;/em&gt;, that anything done against them is noble and benevolent, not despotic and repressive. That is how American liberals currently think, as they fortify the control of Silicon Valley monopolies over our political lives, exemplified by the overnight destruction of a new and popular competitor.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 14:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amadeuspagel</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/how-silicon-valley-in-a-show-of-monopolistic</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How Silicon Valley, in a Show of Monopolistic Force, Destroyed Parler</og:title>
<og:description>In the last three months, tech giants have censored political speech and journalism to manipulate U.S. politics, while liberals, with virtual unanimity, have cheered.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/h_600,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F5bf83518-22df-4333-a423-63fbb59cb9a2_4032x3024.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/how-silicon-valley-in-a-show-of-monopolistic</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sci-Hub Is Now on the ‘Uncensorable Web’</title>
<link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/pirated-academic-database-sci-hub-is-now-on-the-uncensorable-web-2021-01-11</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/pirated-academic-database-sci-hub-is-now-on-the-uncensorable-web-2021-01-11</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/pirated-academic-database-sci-hub-is-now-on-the-uncensorable-web-2021-01-11&quot;&gt;https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/pirated-academic-database-sci-hub-is-now-on-the-uncensorable-web-2021-01-11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25747284&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25747284&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 749&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 345&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 14:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rasengan</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/pirated-academic-database-sci-hub-is-now-on-the-uncensorable-web-2021-01-11</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Plain Text Accounting</title>
<link>https://plaintextaccounting.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://plaintextaccounting.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;who-is-using-this-and-how&quot;&gt;Who is using this, and how?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ledger/ledger/wiki/Who's-using-ledger%3F&quot;&gt;Who's using Ledger?&lt;/a&gt; has some stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;is-it-a-good-fit-for-me&quot;&gt;Is it a good fit for me?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to use a GUI that provides lots of guidance, PTA tools currently don't meet that need. Most current PTA users tend to be comfortable using the command line, editing plain text, and perhaps using version control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-are-the-alternatives&quot;&gt;What are the alternatives?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional GUI-centric accounting software:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open-source_software&quot;&gt;Free/open-source&lt;/a&gt;: GNUCash, Grisbi, KMyMoney..&lt;br/&gt;Commercial: Quicken, Quickbooks, You Need A Budget..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online/cloud-based accounting software: Xero, FreeAgent..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is Wikipedia's &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_accounting_software&quot;&gt;Comparison of accounting software&lt;/a&gt;. Also:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://backchannel.com/a-spreadsheet-way-of-knowledge-8de60af7146e#.2hr7pi9pb&quot;&gt;spreadsheets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keeping accounts on paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using a bookkeeper/accountant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-are-the-advantages-over-traditional-freeopen-source-accounting-software-like-gnucash&quot;&gt;What are the advantages over traditional (Free/open-source) accounting software, like GnuCash?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some key factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. The plain text, human readable, well supported data formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. The division of concerns between creating and managing the data (your responsibility) and analysing it (the tool's responsibility). Ie &quot;immutable data&quot; + &quot;referentially transparent reporting tools&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. The command-line interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. The ecosystem of related tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;create synergies such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. The data is more future proof. You can access it relatively easily with different software, newly-written software, or no software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. The command-line based UI, together with the plain text format, allows easy integration with other software, custom workflows and automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. The user's responsibilities and mental model feel simpler, ie: &quot;I just need to keep a list of transactions&quot;. Complex features and tools are not visible until you need them. Common actions can be easily scripted for daily use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. The data can be managed using the rich ecosystem of tools for managing text. This is appealing to folks familiar with such tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Most significantly, the data can be effectively version controlled, providing an audit trail, unlimited &quot;undo&quot;, and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Because the software (mostly) does not touch your data, and because version control would let you know and roll back if it did, you can have great confidence in the integrity of your data. If the software misbehaves, your data is not at risk. It's safe and relaxing to try out new features or new software on your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7. The data/tool separation facilitates decentralised development, stimulating an ecosystem of more tools and integrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8. The free form DSL-style format provides great expressiveness for modelling and documenting real-world financial activities, without UI-imposed limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-are-the-advantages-over-commercial-accounting-software-like-quickbooks&quot;&gt;What are the advantages over commercial accounting software, like QuickBooks?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the advantages above, being Free or Open Source software helps ensure: - No lockin - your data remains accessible, and there are no yearly fees. - You can fix, enhance and port the software. - The software is more portable, scriptable, and lightweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;where-can-i-read-more-discussion-of-this-approach&quot;&gt;Where can I read more discussion of this approach ?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;objections-and-concerns&quot;&gt;Objections and Concerns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;isnt-personal-accounting-a-waste-of-time&quot;&gt;Isn't personal accounting a waste of time?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have very different needs and practise personal accounting for many different reasons. There is of course a point of diminishing returns; tailor your accounting practices to your needs. Needs change over time. Some of us would benefit from doing more (or better) accounting, some less (I would guess this second group is smaller). In &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Millionaire_Next_Door&quot;&gt;The Millionaire Next Door&lt;/a&gt; (highly recommended), one research finding was that above-average wealth accumulators spend more time on financial planning, which for many of us requires accounting as a foundation. &quot;Minimal time dedicated to financial planning is a leading indicator of a UAW [Under Accumulator of Wealth]&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;must-i-edit-text-and-type-cryptic-commands&quot;&gt;Must I edit text and type cryptic commands?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not entirely! &quot;Plain Text Accounting&quot; is a broad description, referring mainly to the data format. We welcome optional &lt;a href=&quot;https://plaintextaccounting.org/#ui-console&quot;&gt;GUIs&lt;/a&gt;, and they are &lt;a href=&quot;https://plaintextaccounting.org/#ui-console&quot;&gt;coming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;do-you-really-enter-every-little-transaction&quot;&gt;Do you really enter every little transaction?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! Many folks in our community do it. Mahatma Gandhi reconciled to the penny every night. J.D. Rockefeller was famous for his ledgers. It's not required. I started doing it as a temporary learning exercise, and still like it. It makes troubleshooting and reconciling easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-is-that-possible&quot;&gt;How is that possible?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practice, and a process/toolset that suits you. Some folks import most of the data from their banks, so little manual data entry is required. A few prefer to manually enter everything, for the increased awareness and insight. &quot;Manual&quot; data entry is usually assisted in some way: interactive console tools (hledger add and similar), web-based tools (hledger-web and similar), GUI tools (ledgerhelpers), smart editors (eg emacs &amp;amp; ledger-mode), recurring transaction scripts. I currently use a mixture of bank CSV import and rapid copy/paste in emacs. I spend 15 minutes a day on average, and for me that's currently a good investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-do-i-use-the-transaction-data-in-my-banks-web-or-mobile-app&quot;&gt;How do I use the transaction data in my bank's web or mobile app?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can export it as CSV, you can import it and run queries against it. There are also some tools for converting OFX, QIF etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;so-ive-got-a-huge-list-of-transactions-recorded-duplicating-my-bank-statements.-how-does-that-help&quot;&gt;So I've got a huge list of transactions recorded, duplicating my bank statements. How does that help?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accounting is modelling flows of money (or other value). Such a model aggregates information from many sources, in one trusted place. With it you can efficiently generate reports, forecast things (cashflow!), answer questions, try experiments. Some people need a very simple model, others benefit from a more detailed one, and we don't know up front what we might need in future. The most fundamental accounting data is a simple list of transactions (the journal). Once you have captured this, you can mine it for anything you may want later on. Plain text accounting provides nice open data format(s), tools and practices for doing this, and could be a good foundation for more powerful tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;isnt-a-command-line-tool-too-limited-for-real-world-accounting-needs&quot;&gt;Isn't a command-line tool too limited for real-world accounting needs?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;I am sure for a simple expense/budget ledger it will work OK, but when it comes to recurring journals, multiple reconciliation accounts, inter company transfers, control account tracing etc., give me a nice GUI any day...&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understandable. The current plain text accounting tools provide a very generic double entry accounting system with which you can model such things, and script them. There are a number of generic GUIs available (hledger has curses and web interfaces, and there are web/curses/GTK interfaces for Ledger and beancount). But there are not yet a lot of rich task-specific GUIs. There's no reason they can't be built, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;isnt-a-plain-text-format-too-limited-for-large-organizations&quot;&gt;Isn't a plain text format too limited for large organizations?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;it's pretty obvious that plain-text files don't scale to a multinational, with hundreds of accountants of various types all trying to work with the same files. Even with proper use of Git I bet that would get old fast. You would instead want a real database, with a schema, and some data validation and some programs/webpages to smooth out the data entry and querying and whatnot.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I'm not sure. Current plain text accounting tools can do some schema definition and data validation, and will do more in future. The plain text storage format is open, human-readable, future-proof (useful even without the software), scales smoothly from simple to complex needs, and taps a huge ecosystem of highly useful tooling, such as version control systems. And, despite the name, there's no reason these tools can't support other kinds of storage, such as a database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;if-this-is-double-entry-accounting-where-are-the-debits-and-credits&quot;&gt;If this is double entry accounting, where are the debits and credits?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most (not all) plain text accounting implementations use signed amounts instead of debits and credits. This makes them &quot;double entry light&quot; perhaps, but it has been a rather successful simplification, intuitive to most newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-do-i-communicate-with-my-accountant&quot;&gt;How do I communicate with my accountant?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clean up text reports by hand, print them as PDF, export CSV reports to a spreadsheet..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-if-my-accountant-only-uses-quickbooks&quot;&gt;What if my accountant only uses QuickBooks?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll need a new accountant, or a duplicate set of books in QuickBooks, or to pioneer *ledger -&amp;gt; QuickBooks exporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;can-i-use-this-to-do-my-taxes&quot;&gt;Can I use this to do my taxes?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use this to track and report the data needed for tax reporting. Fill out and submit tax forms with another tool, or by hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started-practicalities&quot;&gt;Getting started, Practicalities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;where-can-i-see-a-comparison-of-hledger-ledger-beancount-and-the-rest&quot;&gt;Where can I see a comparison of hledger, Ledger, beancount, and the rest?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glad you asked! See below, and also &lt;a href=&quot;https://plaintextaccounting.org/#comparisons&quot;&gt;comparisons&lt;/a&gt;. hledger's FAQ discusses differences from Ledger, Beancount docs probably do too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-to-organise-files-should-i-split-the-journal-into-many-files&quot;&gt;How to organise files ? Should I split the journal into many files ?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in one file (or one file per year) and ordered by date is simplest and creates the fewest headaches (balance assertions/assignments, scope of directives, where to put entries, finding things..).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use emacs: it’s possible to insert org headings (which are comments to h/ledger) and then use org-mode or org-minor-mode to collapse/expand/navigate sections of your journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also in emacs: in ledger-mode, C-c C-f can give you a filtered view of just one account’s transactions. (But be careful, if you edit in the wrong place it will lose data.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/plaintextaccounting/comments/d69slp/how_do_you_manage_multiple_accounts_in/&quot; class=&quot;uri&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/plaintextaccounting/comments/d69slp/how_do_you_manage_multiple_accounts_in/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-big-is-your-ledgerjournal-file&quot;&gt;How big is your ledger/journal file ?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For individual accounting, somewhere between 500-1500 transactions and 100-400K of journal per year seems typical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/plaintextaccounting/comments/dbjizl/how_big_is_your_ledgerjournal_file/&quot; class=&quot;uri&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/plaintextaccounting/comments/dbjizl/how_big_is_your_ledgerjournal_file/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-do-i-do-budgeting&quot;&gt;How do I do budgeting?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://plaintextaccounting.org/#budgeting&quot;&gt;budgeting&lt;/a&gt; below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sundarurfriend</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://plaintextaccounting.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook to staff: Avoid company-branded clothing for own safety</title>
<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-trump-ban-staff-company-branded-clothing-safety-concerns-2021-1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-trump-ban-staff-company-branded-clothing-safety-concerns-2021-1</guid>
<description>&lt;ul class=&quot;summary-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Facebook told its employees on Monday to avoid wearing clothing that suggests they work at the company as a safety precaution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Global security is encouraging everyone to avoid wearing or carrying Facebook-branded items at this time,&quot; an internal memo, seen by The Information, said.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The safety precaution comes after Facebook suspended President Donald Trump from the platform on Thursday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is also removing all posts that reference the &quot;Stop the Steal&quot; campaign in the wake of the riots at the Capitol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/?hprecirc-bullet&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;summary_bullets&quot;&gt;Visit Business Insider's homepage for more stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook told staff on Monday to avoid wearing company-branded clothing in public out of concern for their safety, after the social media platform suspended President Donald Trump's account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In light of recent events, and to err on the side of caution, global security is encouraging everyone to avoid wearing or carrying Facebook-branded items at this time,&quot; an internal memo sent Monday, reviewed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/articles/facebook-tells-employees-to-avoid-wearing-facebook-branded-apparel?utm_campaign=%5Brtsu%5D+Automated+RTS&amp;amp;utm_content=1002702&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=cio&amp;amp;utm_term=1000266&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;The Information&lt;/a&gt;, said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/photos-show-the-aftermath-of-a-siege-on-capitol-building-2021-1&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;US Capitol siege&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook banned Trump for at least two weeks and began &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-remove-stop-the-steal-election-fraud-content-2021-1&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;removing all posts referencing the &quot;Stop the Steal&quot; campaign&lt;/a&gt;, which falsely claims the Democrats stole the election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company's security team posted the memo in an internal workplace board that can be accessed by more than 56,600 employees, The Information reported.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Facebook didn't immediately respond to Insider's request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mob of violent pro-Trump supporters, fueled by the president's violent rhetoric and claims of election fraud, breached the Capitol on Wednesday. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/us-capitol-police-officer-dies-after-attempted-insurrection-2021-1&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;Five people died&lt;/a&gt;, including one Capitol police officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/trump-video-statement-capitol-rioters-we-love-you-very-special-2021-1&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;posted a video&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook and Twitter on the day, telling the rioters to &quot;go home&quot; but didn't condemn their actions. &quot;We love you; you're very special,&quot; he said. Both platforms later removed the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the siege, Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg said the platform had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-has-blocked-president-trump-indefinitely-2021-1?utm_source=markets&amp;amp;utm_medium=ingest&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;blocked&lt;/a&gt; Trump &quot;indefinitely&quot; because &quot;the risks of allowing the President to continue to use our service during this period are simply too great.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Zuckerberg said Facebook would ban him &quot;for at least the next two weeks until the peaceful transition of power is complete.&quot; President-elect Joe Biden is due to take office on January 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/trump-twitter-social-media-facebook-disinformation-warner-2021-1?r=kd-sub&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;Banning Trump from social media is just 'a Band-Aid on a bullet wound,' critics say — but no one can agree on the best way to wipe out the disinformation contagion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook isn't the only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/how-big-tech-companies-are-handling-trump-after-riots-2021-1&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;social media platform&lt;/a&gt; to crack down on Trump's accounts following the Capitol siege. A day after Facebook banned him, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/twitter-suspended-president-donald-trumps-account-permanently-2021-1&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;Twitter did too&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;due to the risk of further incitement of violence,&quot; the company said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snapchat has also &quot;locked&quot; Trump's account, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/snapchat-locked-donald-trumps-account-during-capitol-insurrection-2021-1&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot; data-analytics-post-depth=&quot;60&quot; data-uri=&quot;c263002344b9a9b5396b2cca741200bd&quot;&gt;Snap spokesperson told Insider on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;San Francisco &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/pro-trump-twitter-hq-san-francisco-2021-1&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;police officers were preparing for a pro-Trump protest&lt;/a&gt; outside Twitter's headquarters on Monday — in the end, only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/pro-trump-twitter-hq-san-francisco-2021-1&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;two people showed up&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pera</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook tells staff to avoid wearing company-branded clothing in public for their own safety after it booted Trump off the platform</og:title>
<og:description>The internal memo, reviewed by The Information, was sent after Facebook suspended President Donald Trump's account in the wake of the Capitol siege.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-trump-ban-staff-company-branded-clothing-safety-concerns-2021-1</og:url>
<og:image>https://i.insider.com/5ffd71aed184b30018aae3b3?width=1200&amp;format=jpeg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-trump-ban-staff-company-branded-clothing-safety-concerns-2021-1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I received my first donation on my open-source side project</title>
<link>https://gourav.io/blog/first-donation-on-open-source-side-project</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gourav.io/blog/first-donation-on-open-source-side-project</guid>
<description>&lt;header&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;flex items-center justify-between text-base&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex items-center text-base&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-14 rounded-full mr-4 my-3&quot; src=&quot;https://gourav.io/gourav.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gourav Goyal&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;m-0 font-medium&quot;&gt;Gourav Goyal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-gray-500&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dec 11, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use VSCode as my go-to editor for anything code. When I first discovered it in 2016, I really liked how it can almost be fully customized as per the likes. Well, almost, because there was no way you could add or configure any buttons on the top side of the editor. FYI, this is possible in many popular IDEs like IntelliJ, Eclipse, Visual Studio, and even Notepad++. I was more of a mouse-guy back then so the lack of GUI buttons was hindering my so called &lt;em&gt;developer productivity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to build an extension for this. That would add handy buttons for many common commands like save file, format (beautify) file, show opened files list, etc. To build this, I followed VSCode extension development docs and learned typescript along the way. I named it &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=jerrygoyal.shortcut-menu-bar&quot;&gt;Shortcut Menu Bar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://gourav.io/_next/static/media/pages/blog/first-donation-on-open-source-side-project/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shortcut Menu Bar&quot; class=&quot;rounded&quot;/&gt;Shortcut Menu Bar
&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to 2020, and it got over 10k+ downloads and multiple 5-star ratings. I guess I wasn't the only mouse-guy out there.&lt;br/&gt;Out of Covid boredom, I decided to put a donate button to see what happens. I explored few platforms to create donation links like buymeacoffee.com (charges 5% fee), patreon.com (more geared towards recurring donations, 5% fee), PayPal (UI sucks), Ko-Fi.com (0% fee and nice clean UI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a free account on ko-fi.com, linked my PayPal account, and created a donation link. I added that link to the extension description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://gourav.io/_next/static/media/pages/blog/first-donation-on-open-source-side-project/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Buy me a coffee&quot; class=&quot;rounded&quot;/&gt;Buy me a coffee
&lt;p&gt;And guess what? someone donated 5$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://gourav.io/_next/static/media/pages/blog/first-donation-on-open-source-side-project/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;donation via ko-fi.com&quot; class=&quot;rounded&quot;/&gt;donation via ko-fi.com
&lt;p&gt;I know I know, it's not that big amount, but somebody put an effort to make that transaction means he cared about it and found it useful. I hope it inspires people who want to contribute and build stuff in the FOSS (Free and Open-Source Software) community. It's so captivating that the whole tech industry relies (and thrives) on open source software made by people in their free time.&lt;br/&gt;You can explore the source code of &lt;code&gt;Shortcut Menu Bar&lt;/code&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GorvGoyl/Shortcut-Menu-Bar-VSCode-Extension&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 10:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jerrygoyal</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://gourav.io/blog/first-donation-on-open-source-side-project</og:url>
<og:title>I received first-ever donation on my open-source side project and it felt great!</og:title>
<og:description>I decided to build an extension for VSCode. That would add handy buttons for many common commands like save file, format file, show opened files etc.</og:description>
<og:image>https://gourav.io/_next/static/media/pages/blog/first-donation-on-open-source-side-project/og.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gourav.io/blog/first-donation-on-open-source-side-project</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook confirms data-sharing agreements with Chinese firms, including Huawei (2018)</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-44379593</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/business-44379593</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;1xgj2ad-InlineLink&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:link{color:#3F3F42;}.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:visited{color:#696969;}.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:link,.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:visited{font-weight:700;border-bottom:1px solid #BABABA;-webkit-text-decoration:none;text-decoration:none;}.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:link:hover,.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:visited:hover,.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:link:focus,.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:visited:focus{border-bottom-color:currentcolor;border-bottom-width:2px;color:#B80000;}@supports (text-underline-offset:0.25em){.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:link,.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:visited{border-bottom:none;-webkit-text-decoration:underline #BABABA;text-decoration:underline #BABABA;-webkit-text-decoration-thickness:1px;text-decoration-thickness:1px;-webkit-text-decoration-skip-ink:none;text-decoration-skip-ink:none;text-underline-offset:0.25em;}.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:link:hover,.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:visited:hover,.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:link:focus,.css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink:visited:focus{-webkit-text-decoration-color:currentcolor;text-decoration-color:currentcolor;-webkit-text-decoration-thickness:2px;text-decoration-thickness:2px;color:#B80000;}}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/05/technology/facebook-device-partnerships-china.html&quot; class=&quot;css-1xgj2ad-InlineLink e1no5rhv0&quot;&gt;The New York Times reported earlier this week &lt;/a&gt;that Facebook had given at least 60 device-makers access to users' data - and that of their Facebook friends - without obtaining explicit consent and that in some cases the details were stored on the firms' own servers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 09:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>z3t111</dc:creator>
<og:description>The network confirms it has a deal with Huawei and others, but says no data left users' phones.</og:description>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/475D/production/_101896281_gettyimages-959804502.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Facebook confirms data-sharing agreements with Chinese firms</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-44379593</og:url>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-44379593</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>