<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>When a rewrite isn’t: rebuilding Slack on the desktop</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@SlackEng/rebuilding-slack-on-the-desktop-308d6fe94ae4</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@SlackEng/rebuilding-slack-on-the-desktop-308d6fe94ae4</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;93.120150777446&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;5.4059405940594&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ia&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ah ag&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.engineering/@SlackEng?source=post_page---------------------------&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Slack Engineering&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/96/96/1*GB9girro1GFX16imhDm_wA.png&quot; class=&quot;n fe ib ic&quot; width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;48&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1c76&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;ja&quot;&gt;by&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@shinypb?source=post_page---------------------------&quot; class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;ja&quot;&gt;Mark Christian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;ja&quot;&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnnyrodgers.is/?source=post_page---------------------------&quot; class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;ja&quot;&gt;Johnny Rodgers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;cc3c&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;A new version of Slack is rolling out for our desktop customers, built from the ground up to be faster, more efficient, and easier to work on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@seemoris?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;source=post_page---------------------------&quot; class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot;&gt;Caleb George&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;source=post_page---------------------------&quot; class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5a57&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2000/04/06/things-you-should-never-do-part-i/?source=post_page---------------------------&quot; class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot;&gt;Conventional wisdom&lt;/a&gt; holds that you should never rewrite your code from scratch, and that’s good advice. Time spent rewriting something that already works is time that won’t be spent making our customers working lives simpler, more pleasant, and more productive. And running code knows things: hard-won knowledge gained through billions of hours of cumulative usage and tens of thousands of bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3d40&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;Still, software codebases have life spans. The desktop version of Slack is our oldest client, growing out of a period of rapid development and experimentation during the earliest moments of our company. During this period, we were optimizing for product-market fit and in a constant sprint to keep up with our customers as their use — and expectations — of the product grew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5c49&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;Today, after more than half a decade of hyper-growth, Slack is used by millions of people with larger companies working with more data than we ever could have imagined when we first started. Somewhat predictably, a few internal cracks were starting to show in the desktop client’s foundation. Additionally, the technology landscape had shifted away from the tools we chose in late 2012 (jQuery, Signals, and direct DOM manipulation) and toward a paradigm of composable interfaces and clean application abstractions. Despite &lt;a class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot; href=&quot;https://slack.engineering/getting-to-slack-faster-with-incremental-boot-ff063c9222e4?source=post_page---------------------------&quot;&gt;our best efforts to keep things snappy&lt;/a&gt;, it became clear that some fundamental changes would be required to evolve the desktop app and prepare it for the next wave of product development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4563&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;The architecture of the existing desktop app had a number of shortcomings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;8591&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz jw jx jy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;Manual DOM updates.&lt;/strong&gt; Slack’s original UI was built using HTML templates that needed to be manually rebuilt whenever the underlying data changed, making it a pain to keep the data model and user interface in sync. We wanted to adopt React, a popular JavaScript framework that made this sort of thing more automatic and less prone to potential errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;f138&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz jw jx jy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;Eager data loading.&lt;/strong&gt; The data model was “complete”, meaning that each user session started by downloading &lt;em class=&quot;ja&quot;&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; relevant to the user. While great in theory, in practice this was prohibitively expensive for large workspaces and meant that we had to do a lot of work to keep data models up-to-date over the course of a user’s session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;8055&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz jw jx jy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;Multiple processes for multiple workspaces.&lt;/strong&gt; When signed into multiple workspaces, each of those workspaces was in fact running a stand-alone copy of the web client inside a separate Electron process, which meant that Slack used more memory than users expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;d192&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot; href=&quot;https://slack.engineering/rebuilding-slacks-emoji-picker-in-react-bfbd8ce6fbfe?source=post_page---------------------------&quot;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot; href=&quot;https://slack.engineering/flannel-an-application-level-edge-cache-to-make-slack-scale-b8a6400e2f6b?source=post_page---------------------------&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; problems were the sort of things that we could incrementally improve over time, but getting multiple workspaces to run within a single Electron process meant changing a fundamental assumption of the original design — that there is only ever a single workspace running at a time. Although we made some &lt;a class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot; href=&quot;https://slack.engineering/reducing-slacks-memory-footprint-4480fec7e8eb?source=post_page---------------------------&quot;&gt;incremental improvements&lt;/a&gt; for folks with lots of idle workspaces, truly solving the multiple process problem meant rewriting Slack’s desktop client from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;d254&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip kr ir ks it kt iv ku ix kv iz&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ship_of_Theseus?source=post_page---------------------------&quot; class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot;&gt;Ship of Theseus&lt;/a&gt; is a thought experiment that considers whether an object that has had each of its pieces replaced one-by-one over time is still the same object when all is said and done. If every piece of wood in a ship has been replaced, is it the same ship? If every piece of JavaScript in an app has been replaced, is it the same app? We sure hoped so, because this seemed like the best course of action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4917&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;Our plan was to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;ce7d&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;keep the existing codebase;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cbcf&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;create a “modern” section of the codebase that would be future-proof and work the way we wanted it to;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;4b51&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;modernize the implementation of Slack bit by bit, replacing existing code with modern code incrementally;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;c766&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;define rules that would enforce a strict interface between existing and modern code so it would be easy to understand their relationship;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;384c&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;and continually ship all of the above with the existing app, replacing older modules with modern implementations that suited our new architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;eefb&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;The final step — and the most important one for our purposes — was to create a modern-only version of Slack that would start out incomplete but gradually work its way toward feature completeness as modules and interfaces were modernized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0c0e&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;We’ve been using this modern-only version of the app internally for much of the last year, and it is now rolling out to customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;558b&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip kr ir ks it kt iv ku ix kv iz&quot;&gt;The first order of business was to create the modern codebase. Although this was just a new subdirectory in our codebase, it had three important rules enforced by convention and tooling, each of which was intended to address one of our existing app’s shortcomings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;76fd&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz jw jx jy&quot;&gt;All UI components had to be built with React&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cd3f&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz jw jx jy&quot;&gt;All data access had to assume a lazily loaded and incomplete data model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;0e10&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz jw jx jy&quot;&gt;All code had to be “multi-workspace aware”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;d87b&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;The first two rules, while time-consuming to fulfill, were relatively straightforward. However, moving to a multi-workspace architecture was quite the undertaking. We couldn’t expect every function call to pass along a workspace ID, and we couldn’t just set a global variable saying which workspace was currently visible since plenty of things continue to happen behind the scenes regardless of which workspace the user is currently looking at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2982&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;The key to our approach ended up being &lt;a href=&quot;https://redux.js.org/?source=post_page---------------------------&quot; class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot;&gt;Redux&lt;/a&gt;, which we were already using to manage our data model. With a bit of consideration and the help of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/reduxjs/redux-thunk?source=post_page---------------------------&quot; class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot;&gt;redux-thunk&lt;/a&gt; library, we were able to model virtually everything as actions or queries on a Redux store, allowing Redux to provide a convenient abstraction layer around the concept of individual workspaces. Each workspace would get its own Redux store with everything living within it — the workspace’s data, information about the client’s connectivity status, the WebSocket we use for real-time updates — you name it. This abstraction created a conceptual container around each workspace without having to house that container in its own Electron process, which was what the legacy client did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3f11&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;With this realization, we had our new architecture in place:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;80&quot;&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;16e9&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip kr ir ks it kt iv ku ix kv iz&quot;&gt;At this point we had a plan and an architecture we thought would work, and we were ready to work our way through the existing codebase, modernizing everything until we were left with a brand new Slack. There was just one last problem to solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6524&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;We couldn’t just start replacing old code with new code willy-nilly; without some type of structure to keep the old and new code separate, they’d end up getting hopelessly tangled together and we’d never have our modern codebase. To solve this problem, we introduced a few rules and functions in a concept called legacy-interop:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;ef8b&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;old code cannot directly import new code:&lt;/strong&gt; only new code that has been “exported” for use by the old code is available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;4b18&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;new code cannot directly import old code:&lt;/strong&gt; only old code that has been “adapted” for use by modern code is available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;9262&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;Exporting new code to the old code was simple. Our original codebase did not use JavaScript modules or imports. Instead, it kept everything on a top-level global variable called TS. The process of exporting new code just meant calling a helper function that made the new code available in a special TS.interop part of that global namespace. For example, TS.interop.i18n.t() would call into our modern, multi-workspace aware string localization function. Since the TS.interop namespace was only used from our legacy codebase, which only loaded a single workspace at a time, we could do a simple look-up to determine the workspace ID behind the scenes without requiring the legacy code to worry about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ab34&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;Adapting old code for new code was less trivial. Both the new code and the old code would be loaded when we were running the classic version of Slack, but the modern version would only include the new code. We needed to find a way to make it possible to conditionally tap into old code without causing errors in the new code, and we wanted the process to be as transparent to developers as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d389&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;Our solution was called adaptFunctionWithFallback, which took a function’s path on our legacy TS object to run, as well as a function to use instead if we were running in the modern-only codebase. This function defaulted to a no-op, which meant that if the underlying legacy code wasn’t present, modern code that tried to call it would have no effect — and produce no errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9945&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;With both of these mechanisms in place, we were able to kick off our modernization effort in earnest. Legacy code could access new code as it got modernized, and new code could access old code &lt;em class=&quot;ja&quot;&gt;until&lt;/em&gt; it got modernized. As you’d expect, over time there were fewer and fewer usages of old code adapted for use from the modern codebase, trending toward zero as we got ready for release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;a2de&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip kr ir ks it kt iv ku ix kv iz&quot;&gt;This new version of Slack has been a long time coming, and it features the contributions of dozens of people who have been working through the last two years to roll it out seamlessly to customers. The key to its success is the incremental release strategy that we adopted early on in the project: as code was modernized and features were rebuilt, we released them to our customers. The first “modern” piece of the Slack app was our emoji picker, which we released more than two years ago — followed thereafter by the channel sidebar, message pane, and dozens of other features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1fa0&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;Had we waited until the entirety of Slack was rewritten before releasing it, our users would have had a worse day-to-day experience with emoji, messages, channel lists, search, and countless other features before we could release a “big bang” replacement. Releasing incrementally allowed us to deliver real value to our customers as soon as possible, helped us stay focused on continuous improvement, and de-risked the release of the new client by minimizing how much completely new code was being used by our customers for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5d7c&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;Conventional wisdom states that rewrites are best avoided, but sometimes the benefits are too great to ignore. One of our primary metrics has been memory usage, and the new version of Slack delivers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;22.333719582851&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9249&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;These results have validated all of the work that we’ve put into this new version of Slack, and we look forward to continuing to iterate and make it even better as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;afae&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz&quot;&gt;When guided by strategic planning, tempered by judicious releases, and buoyed by talented contributors, incremental rewrites are a great way to right the wrongs of the past, build yourself a brand new ship, and make your users’ working lives simpler, more pleasant, and more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;3156&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip kr ir ks it kt iv ku ix kv iz&quot;&gt;We are eager to share more about what we’ve learned during this process. In the coming weeks we’ll be writing more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.engineering/?source=post_page---------------------------&quot; class=&quot;dl cb jb jc jd je&quot;&gt;https://slack.engineering&lt;/a&gt; about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;e18a&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;Slack Kit&lt;/strong&gt;, our UI component library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;d090&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;“Speedy Boots”&lt;/strong&gt;, the prototype that launched this effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fee4&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt;, baked in rather than bolted on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ed26&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;Gantry&lt;/strong&gt;, our app launching framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;c1a4&quot; class=&quot;im in dt ax io b ip jz ir ka it kb iv kc ix kd iz kw jx jy&quot;&gt;and &lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;rolling out a new client&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;io jf&quot;&gt;architecture&lt;/strong&gt; at scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 15:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kgraves</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>When a rewrite isn’t: rebuilding Slack on the desktop</og:title>
<og:description>by Mark Christian and Johnny Rodgers</og:description>
<og:url>https://slack.engineering/rebuilding-slack-on-the-desktop-308d6fe94ae4</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/max/1200/0*cgkWRCMtQXti3jbA</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://slack.engineering/rebuilding-slack-on-the-desktop-308d6fe94ae4?gi=9a4ad80056ab</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GitHub is down</title>
<link>https://www.githubstatus.com/?</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.githubstatus.com/?</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident has been resolved.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jul &lt;var data-var=&quot;date&quot;&gt;22&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&quot;time&quot;&gt;19:47&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; - The source of the issue has been identified and we are working on a solution.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jul &lt;var data-var=&quot;date&quot;&gt;22&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&quot;time&quot;&gt;18:52&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; - We continue to investigate issues on certain user settings functionality and will update with more information when available.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jul &lt;var data-var=&quot;date&quot;&gt;22&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&quot;time&quot;&gt;18:11&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; - Error rates remain low, but we are investigating reports of trouble loading certain user setting pages.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jul &lt;var data-var=&quot;date&quot;&gt;22&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&quot;time&quot;&gt;17:29&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; - Error rates have now dropped as we continue to monitor our systems.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jul &lt;var data-var=&quot;date&quot;&gt;22&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&quot;time&quot;&gt;16:23&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are continuing to investigate reports of issues affecting a number of services.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jul &lt;var data-var=&quot;date&quot;&gt;22&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&quot;time&quot;&gt;16:02&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 15:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tomduncalf</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.githubstatus.com/?</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Ananas – a hackable data tool for beginners</title>
<link>https://ananasanalytics.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ananasanalytics.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ananasanalytics.com/&quot;&gt;https://ananasanalytics.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20498474&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20498474&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 265&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 81&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 14:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>millboh</dc:creator>
<og:title>Ananas Analytics Desktop · Build analytics in minutes</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://ananas-analytics.github.io/</og:url>
<og:description>Build analytics in minutes</og:description>
<og:image>https://ananas-analytics.github.io/img/undraw_online.svg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ananasanalytics.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dropbox Brings Back Support for ZFS, XFS, Btrfs and eCryptFS on Linux</title>
<link>https://www.linuxuprising.com/2019/07/dropbox-brings-back-support-for-zfs-xfs.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.linuxuprising.com/2019/07/dropbox-brings-back-support-for-zfs-xfs.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-kuNPXVvpoHg/W23Acu6tLaI/AAAAAAAABWg/nLkYuagRSO4P3a0-mslsZV3u65HceUt4gCLcBGAs/s1600/dropbox-logo.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-kuNPXVvpoHg/W23Acu6tLaI/AAAAAAAABWg/nLkYuagRSO4P3a0-mslsZV3u65HceUt4gCLcBGAs/s640/dropbox-logo.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dropbox has partially reverted the change of only supporting Ext4 filesystems on Linux. A Dropbox &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropboxforum.com/t5/Desktop-client-builds/Beta-Build-77-3-127/td-p/354660&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;client update&lt;/a&gt; brings back support for ZFS and XFS on 64-bit Linux systems, and eCryptFS and Btrfs on all Linux systems.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxuprising.com/2018/08/dropbox-client-will-only-support-ext4.html&quot;&gt;Dropbox stopped supporting&lt;/a&gt; folder syncing to drives with filesystems it deemed uncommon, which on Linux meant anything but Ext4, upsetting quite a few users. The reason cited for this was that &quot;&lt;em&gt;a supported file system is required as Dropbox relies on extended attributes (X-attrs) to identify files in the Dropbox folder and keep them in sync&lt;/em&gt;&quot;, which doesn't really make sense since there are many filesystems that support X-attrs on Linux.&lt;p&gt;After this change was announced, various workarounds started to appear online, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxuprising.com/2018/11/how-to-use-dropbox-on-non-ext4.html&quot;&gt;including one&lt;/a&gt; that I posted on Linux Uprising. There was even a new unofficial, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxuprising.com/2019/07/maestral-is-new-open-source-dropbox.html&quot;&gt;open source Dropbox client&lt;/a&gt; developed for this reason (which is also much lighter than the official client by the way).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this didn't last long though, as last week, the Dropbox 77.3.127 beta changelog says that Dropbox has added back support for ZFS (on 64-bit systems only), XFS (on 64bit systems only), Btrfs and eCryptFS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since then, it appears that this change has made it into the stable Dropbox client for Linux. This isn't directly mentioned on the Dropbox website, but after a fresh Dropbox installation that I performed on Ubuntu, the reported version is 77.4.131, which is a higher version number than the Dropbox beta version for which it was reported that it now supports ZFS and XFS on 64-bit Linux systems, and eCryptFS and Btrfs on all Linux systems. I also gave it a try on a Btrfs filesystem and folder syncing ran without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.dropbox.com/installs-integrations/desktop/system-requirements#linux&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dropbox system requirements&lt;/a&gt; section has yet to be updated to mention that the Linux client now supports these filesystem types.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/cg4r8u/dropbox_added_support_for_zfs_ecryptfs_xfs_and/&quot;&gt;r/Linux&lt;/a&gt; (u/XavierCLL)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 14:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>logix</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.linuxuprising.com/2019/07/dropbox-brings-back-support-for-zfs-xfs.html</og:url>
<og:title>Dropbox Brings Back Support For ZFS, XFS, Btrfs And eCryptFS On Linux</og:title>
<og:description>Dropbox has partially reverted the change of only supporting Ext4 filesystems on Linux. A Dropbox client update brings back support for ZFS and XFS on 64-bit Linux systems, and eCryptFS and Btrfs on all Linux systems.</og:description>
<og:image>https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-kuNPXVvpoHg/W23Acu6tLaI/AAAAAAAABWg/nLkYuagRSO4P3a0-mslsZV3u65HceUt4gCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/dropbox-logo.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.linuxuprising.com/2019/07/dropbox-brings-back-support-for-zfs-xfs.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Study: Immigrants and their kids founded 45% of U.S. Fortune 500 companies</title>
<link>https://www.axios.com/immigrants-founders-fortune-500-companies-7e883b5a-1b76-462c-83b5-be68e2e9cae4.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.axios.com/immigrants-founders-fortune-500-companies-7e883b5a-1b76-462c-83b5-be68e2e9cae4.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;StoryBody__paragraph--2-Doz&quot;&gt;Immigrants and their children have founded 45% of the U.S.' Fortune 500 companies, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.newamericaneconomy.org/en/fortune500-2019/&quot; class=&quot;StoryBody__link--10w8x&quot;&gt;new study by New American Economy&lt;/a&gt;, a bipartisan pro-immigration group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StoryBody__paragraph--2-Doz&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why it matters:&lt;/strong&gt; The share of the most successful and globally recognized U.S. companies that have immigrant founders is growing, according to NAE's Hanna Siegel and Andrew Lim, while the Trump administration has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/immigration-refugees-asylum-seekers-border-trump-2018-2bb88417-300d-40f3-be7c-99c7c348249c.html&quot; class=&quot;StoryBody__link--10w8x&quot;&gt;tried&lt;/a&gt; to make it more difficult for immigrants to come to the U.S., often claiming that they take American jobs and lower wages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;hidden-7e883b5a-1b76-462c-83b5-be68e2e9cae4&quot; class=&quot;&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;false&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StoryBody__paragraph--2-Doz&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Between the lines:&lt;/strong&gt; Immigrants may have a negative impact on the work prospects of some U.S.-born workers, as Harvard economics and social policy professor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/09/trump-clinton-immigration-economy-unemployment-jobs-214216&quot; class=&quot;StoryBody__link--10w8x&quot;&gt;George Borjas wrote for Politico&lt;/a&gt;. But they also are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/us-population-growth-immigration-fertility-rates-fbcd99b8-01c6-4ff8-b0c4-dc8a76603a3f.html&quot; class=&quot;StoryBody__link--10w8x&quot;&gt;increasingly&lt;/a&gt; a vital part of the U.S. economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StoryBody__paragraph--2-Doz&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By the numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; Fortune 500 companies founded by immigrants or their children employ 13.5 million people, and on average employ 11% more people than the average Fortune 500 company with a nonimmigrant founder, the study found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;StoryBody__item--1cHYD&quot;&gt;These companies brought in $6.1 trillion in annual revenue last year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;StoryBody__item--1cHYD&quot;&gt;More than half of the revenue brought in by Fortune 500 companies in New York, Washington state, Georgia and Pennsylvania, among others, came from companies founded by immigrants or their children.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;StoryBody__item--1cHYD&quot;&gt;In Illinois, the revenue brought in by immigrant-founded Fortune 500 companies was equal to 70% of the state’s GDP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 13:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>elsewhen</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.axios.com/immigrants-founders-fortune-500-companies-7e883b5a-1b76-462c-83b5-be68e2e9cae4.html</og:url>
<og:title>Study: Immigrants and their kids founded 45% of U.S. Fortune 500 companies</og:title>
<og:description>Immigrants and their children have founded 45% of the U.S.'s Fortune 500 companies, according to a new study.</og:description>
<og:image>https://images.axios.com/vs4TNkCTdVdplM-TXiUmFMtGB5U=/0x0:2356x1325/1920x1080/2019/07/19/1563557790928.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.axios.com/immigrants-founders-fortune-500-companies-7e883b5a-1b76-462c-83b5-be68e2e9cae4.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ubisoft joins Blender Development Fund to support open-source animation</title>
<link>https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/353364/ubisoft-joins-blender-development-fund-to-support-open-source-animation</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/353364/ubisoft-joins-blender-development-fund-to-support-open-source-animation</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;© 2019Ubisoft Entertainment. All Rights Reserved. Ubisoft, Ubi.com and the Ubisoft logo are trademarks of Ubisoft Entertainment in the U.S. and/or other countries. *One free trial per Ubisoft Account from September 3rd to 30th, 2019. To begin free trial, you must provide a valid credit or debit card.  You will be charged the full amount of the subscription price ($14.99 per month) on expiration of the free trial on October 1, 2019, unless you cancel before September 30th – 11.59pm, by visiting uplayplus.ubisoft.com. Additional terms and conditions apply including territorial restrictions; for more information please visit the FAQ section on uplayplus.ubisoft.com. This is a promotional offer and is subject to change. Void where prohibited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 13:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kragniz</dc:creator>
<og:title>Ubisoft Joins Blender Development Fund to Support Open Source Animation</og:title>
<og:description>Open-source animation tool will be officially adopted by Ubisoft Animation Studio in Paris to create series inspired by Ubisoft worlds.</og:description>
<og:image>https://ubistatic19-a.akamaihd.net/marketingresource/en-us/ubisoft/ubisoft-news/news/images/llc_ep403_sh123_srgb.0072_353363.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/353364/ubisoft-joins-blender-development-fund-to-support-open-source-animation</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who Pays Writers?</title>
<link>http://whopayswriters.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://whopayswriters.com</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://whopayswriters.com&quot;&gt;http://whopayswriters.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20497678&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20497678&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 219&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 76&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 13:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jawns</dc:creator>
<og:description>An anonymous, crowdsourced list of which publications pay freelance writers, and how much.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://whopayswriters.com</og:url>
<og:title>Who Pays Writers?</og:title>
<og:image>http://whopayswriters.com/images/WPW-logofull.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://whopayswriters.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft is investing $1B in OpenAI</title>
<link>http://openai.com/blog/microsoft</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://openai.com/blog/microsoft</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;js-excerpt&quot; readability=&quot;10.59509202454&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is investing $1 billion in OpenAI to support us building artificial general intelligence (AGI) with &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/charter/&quot;&gt;widely distributed&lt;/a&gt; economic benefits. We're partnering to develop a hardware and software platform within Microsoft Azure which will scale to AGI. We’ll jointly develop new Azure AI supercomputing technologies, and Microsoft will become our exclusive cloud provider—so we'll be working hard together to further extend Microsoft Azure's capabilities in large-scale AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://openai.com/content/images/2019/07/openai-team-offsite-2019.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;openai-team-offsite-2019&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
OpenAI team and their families at our July 2019 offsite.
&lt;p&gt;Each year since 2012, the world has seen a new step function advance in AI capabilities. Though these advances are across very different fields like &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/coinmonks/paper-review-of-alexnet-caffenet-winner-in-ilsvrc-2012-image-classification-b93598314160&quot;&gt;vision&lt;/a&gt; (2012), &lt;a href=&quot;https://danieltakeshi.github.io/2016/12/01/going-deeper-into-reinforcement-learning-understanding-dqn/&quot;&gt;simple video games&lt;/a&gt; (2013), &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.acolyer.org/2016/06/02/sequence-to-sequence-learning-with-neural-networks/&quot;&gt;machine translation&lt;/a&gt; (2014), &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/research/alphago/&quot;&gt;complex board games&lt;/a&gt; (2015), &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/blog/wavenet-generative-model-raw-audio/&quot;&gt;speech synthesis&lt;/a&gt; (2016), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G06dEcZ-QTg&quot;&gt;image generation&lt;/a&gt; (2017), &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/learning-dexterity/&quot;&gt;robotic control&lt;/a&gt; (2018), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/better-language-models/&quot;&gt;writing text&lt;/a&gt; (2019), they are all powered by the same approach: innovative applications of deep neural networks coupled with increasing &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/ai-and-compute/&quot;&gt;computational power&lt;/a&gt;. But still, AI system building today involves a lot of manual engineering for each well-defined task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, an AGI will be a system capable of mastering a field of study to the world-expert level, and mastering more fields than any one human — like a tool which combines the skills of Curie, Turing, and Bach. An AGI working on a problem would be able to see connections across disciplines that no human could. We want AGI to work with people to solve currently intractable multi-disciplinary problems, including global challenges such as climate change, affordable and high-quality healthcare, and personalized education. We think its impact should be to give everyone economic freedom to pursue what they find most fulfilling, creating new opportunities for all of our lives that are unimaginable today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenAI is producing a sequence of increasingly powerful AI technologies, which requires a lot of capital for computational power. The most obvious way to cover costs is to build a product, but that would mean changing our focus. Instead, we intend to license some of our pre-AGI technologies, with Microsoft becoming our preferred partner for commercializing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the creation of beneficial AGI will be the most important technological development in human history, with the potential to shape the trajectory of humanity. We have a hard technical path in front of us, requiring a unified software engineering and AI research effort of massive computational scale, but technical success alone is not enough. To accomplish our mission of ensuring that AGI (whether built by us or not) benefits all of humanity, we'll need to ensure that AGI is deployed safely and securely; that society is well-prepared for its implications; and that its economic upside is widely shared. If we achieve this mission, we will have actualized Microsoft and OpenAI's shared value of empowering everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;btns mt-3 mb-0&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.microsoft.com/2019/07/22/openai-forms-exclusive-computing-partnership-with-microsoft-to-build-new-azure-ai-supercomputing-technologies/&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-padded icon-papers&quot;&gt;Read Press Release&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6559114910486405120/&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-padded icon-play&quot;&gt;Watch Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 12:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gdb</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Microsoft invests in and partners with OpenAI to support us building beneficial AGI</og:title>
<og:description>Microsoft is investing $1 billion in OpenAI to support us building artificial general intelligence (AGI) with widely distributed [https://openai.com/charter/] economic benefits. We're partnering to develop a hardware and software platform within Microsoft Azure which will scale to AGI. We’ll jointly develop new Azure AI supercomputing technologies, and Microsoft will become our exclusive cloud provider—so we'll be working hard together to further extend Microsoft Azure's capabilities in large-s</og:description>
<og:url>https://openai.com/blog/microsoft/</og:url>
<og:image>https://openai.com/content/images/2019/07/openai-msft-twitter_7-21b-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://openai.com/blog/microsoft/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chaos in Hong Kong as hundreds of masked men assault protesters, journalists</title>
<link>https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/07/22/just-chaos-bloodshed-hong-kong-district-hundreds-masked-men-assault-protesters-journalists-residents/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/07/22/just-chaos-bloodshed-hong-kong-district-hundreds-masked-men-assault-protesters-journalists-residents/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of masked assailants dressed in white have assaulted residents, protesters, journalists and a lawmaker in Yuen Long, hours &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/07/21/breaking-hong-kong-police-deploy-tear-gas-protesters-govt-slams-direct-challenge-national-sovereignty/&quot;&gt;after an anti-extradition law march ended.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pyihNeih1NU&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gcyberh gcyberh-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gcyberh-single acyberh-30&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;center/&gt;
&lt;img width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAP///////yH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; onload=&quot;ga('send', 'event', 'banner', 'impression', 'Doubleclick 336x280 ad', 2.00, {'nonInteraction': 1});&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/07/22/hong-kong-police-made-no-arrests-mob-assaulted-commuters-protesters-journalists-yuen-long/&quot;&gt;Hong Kong police made no arrests after mob assaulted commuters, protesters, journalists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group used bamboo sticks and other weapons to attack people in the area and in the West Rail Line station, injuring Democratic Party lawmaker Lam Cheuk-ting, who was seen bleeding from his mouth in a social media live stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_214647&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-214647&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_7194-Copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;yuen long july 21 china extradition&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;670&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_7194-Copy.jpg 1050w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_7194-Copy-768x490.jpg 768w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_7194-Copy-810x517.jpg 810w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Photo: HKFP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police officers were not visibly present when the skirmish occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/07/21/breaking-hong-kong-police-deploy-tear-gas-protesters-govt-slams-direct-challenge-national-sovereignty/&quot;&gt;Hong Kong police deploy tear gas, rubber bullets against protesters as gov’t slams ‘direct challenge to national sovereignty’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_214655&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-214655&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-56-20.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lam Cheuk-ting &quot; width=&quot;1057&quot; height=&quot;769&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Lam Cheuk-ting after the attack. Photo: Lam Cheuk-ting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A photo circulated online by the Civil Human Rights Front, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/07/21/pictures-free-hong-kong-democracy-now-thousands-protest-extradition-bill-amid-security-lockdown/&quot;&gt;organised the rally attended by “430,000” earlier in the day&lt;/a&gt;, showed a person with multiple bloody lashes on his back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/07/22/hong-kong-church-worker-demosisto-member-left-severely-injured-yuen-long-attackers/&quot;&gt;Church worker and Demosisto member left severely injured by Yuen Long attackers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/plf9g07VoQ4&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-mce-type=&quot;bookmark&quot; class=&quot;mce_SELRES_start&quot;&gt;﻿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Front accused the police of failing to take actions in Yuen Long while people were being attacked and instead, unnecessarily &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/07/21/breaking-hong-kong-police-deploy-tear-gas-protesters-govt-slams-direct-challenge-national-sovereignty/&quot;&gt;firing tear gas at protesters in Sheung Wan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_214645&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-214645&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-23-58-Copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;yuen long july 21 china extradition&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;731&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-23-58-Copy.jpg 1050w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-23-58-Copy-768x535.jpg 768w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-23-58-Copy-810x564.jpg 810w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-23-58-Copy-145x100.jpg 145w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Photo: Screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Real thugs have attacked passersby, a journalist and a lawmaker, badly injuring them, but the police have failed to enforce the law. This has angered us greatly,” the statement read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/plf9g07VoQ4&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group said certain “powerful authorities” have been using “thugs” to attack protesters since the 2014 pro-democracy Umbrella Movement. “Hong Kong people must unite to oppose personal violence and structural violence,” they added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_214657&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-214657&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_01-27-54.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;yuen long july 21 china extradition&quot; width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;502&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_01-27-54.jpg 728w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_01-27-54-145x100.jpg 145w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Ex-TVB journalist Ryan Lau. Photo: StandNews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand News reporter Gwyneth Ho said she was left bleeding and injured with swelling at the back of the head and slight dizziness after she was attacked. Ho was sent to hospital to receive treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Journalists Association said a male reporter was beaten and left bleeding in his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The men also took a reporter’s TV camera and destroyed it, the press freedom watchdog said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_214644&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-214644&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-23-22-Copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;yuen long july 21 china extradition&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;622&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-23-22-Copy.jpg 1050w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-23-22-Copy-768x455.jpg 768w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-23-22-Copy-810x480.jpg 810w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Photo: Screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police in riot gear arrived at Yuen Long station at around 11:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MTR announced at around 11pm that West Rail Line trains will not stop at Yuen Long because of the crowds gathering. Train services resumed at 11:25pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_214646&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-214646&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_7192-Copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;yuen long july 21 china extradition&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;664&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_7192-Copy.jpg 1050w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_7192-Copy-768x486.jpg 768w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_7192-Copy-810x512.jpg 810w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Photo: HKFP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement, a government spokesperson condemned the violent scenes: “This is absolutely unacceptable to Hong Kong as a society that observes the rule of law. The SAR Government strongly condemns any violence and will seriously take enforcement actions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_214643&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-214643&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111-5-Copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;yuen long july 21 china extradition&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;626&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111-5-Copy.jpg 1050w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111-5-Copy-768x458.jpg 768w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111-5-Copy-810x483.jpg 810w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Photo: HKFP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in a widely circulated online video, pro-Beijing lawmaker Junius Ho could be seen applauding and giving a “thumbs up” to people dressed in white. He also shook hands with two men who held small Hong Kong bauhinia flags. When a man told Ho, “you are my idol,” the lawmaker replied: “All of you are my heroes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZdEHTc8zAd0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-mce-type=&quot;bookmark&quot; class=&quot;mce_SELRES_start&quot;&gt;﻿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier, Yuen Long District Councillor To Ka-lun wrote in a Facebook post that he had received a complaint from a resident, who said he had called the police for help. However, he was told to “not go out into the streets” if he was afraid, To said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gcyberh gcyberh-7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gcyberh-single acyberh-6&quot;&gt; &lt;img width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAP///////yH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; onload=&quot;ga('send', 'event', 'banner', 'impression', 'DoubleClick Injection Responsive Ad', 2.00, {'nonInteraction': 1});&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 11:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thomasjoulin</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Chaos and bloodshed in Hong Kong district as hundreds of masked men assault protesters, journalists, residents | Hong Kong Free Press HKFP</og:title>
<og:description>Hundreds of masked assailants dressed in white have assaulted residents, protesters, journalists and a lawmaker in Yuen Long, hours after an anti-extradition law march ended. Update: Hong Kong police made no arrests after mob assaulted commuters, protesters, journalists The group used bamboo sticks and other weapons to attack people in the area and in the West Rail …</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/07/22/just-chaos-bloodshed-hong-kong-district-hundreds-masked-men-assault-protesters-journalists-residents/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hkfp_2019-07-22_00-52-23.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/07/22/just-chaos-bloodshed-hong-kong-district-hundreds-masked-men-assault-protesters-journalists-residents/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>India Launches Chandrayaan-2 Moon Mission on Second Try</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/22/world/asia/chandrayaan-india-moon-launch.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/22/world/asia/chandrayaan-india-moon-launch.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;SATISH DHAWAN SPACE CENTER, India — India is on its way to the moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One week after a first attempt was canceled at the last minute, the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/22/science/chandrayaan-2-india-moon.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Chandrayaan-2 mission&lt;/a&gt; blasted off at 2:43 p.m. Monday from the Satish Dhawan Space Center on India’s southeast coast, carrying an uncrewed lunar lander and the dreams of a nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The 142-foot, 700-ton rocket rose on a funnel of fire, ripping through the air perfectly straight and surprisingly fast before vanishing into a thick bank of clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A roaring thunder echoed across the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The mission has been successfully accomplished!” blared a message from loudspeakers at mission control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;If the rest of the mission goes as well, India will become the fourth nation — after the United States, Russia and China — to land on the moon, more than 200,000 miles away. Its target is a region near the mysterious south pole, where no other missions have explored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This would be a huge leap forward for India’s ambitious space program, and scientists and defense experts everywhere are watching to see whether the country can pull it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;So are countless Indians. There are few things as unifying for a nation as a successful space program, and, over the past few weeks, Chandrayaan-2 posters have popped up everywhere and schoolchildren have been hunched over mini-Chandrayaans made from empty plastic bottles, learning the physics of rocketry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The timing could not be better. This weekend was the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/spotlight/apollo-11-moon-landing?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;50th anniversary of the Apollo 11 moon landing&lt;/a&gt;, and the anniversary coverage has fanned lunar fever around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Indian officials insist that the timing was a coincidence — they had wanted to launch the Chandrayaan-2 mission a couple of years ago as a space joint venture with Russia. But when the Russians backed out, the Indians needed more time to build everything on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;On Monday, a huge crowd of space enthusiasts gathered at the gates of Satish Dhawan Space Center, which sits on an empty, bushy coastal plain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Watching the launch near the space center. “Every Indian is immensely proud today!” Prime Minister Narendra Modi said.&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/22/world/22India2/merlin_158292042_4bd08cfd-64ca-4e8a-9ea0-6a350dd89d0d-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/22/world/22India2/merlin_158292042_4bd08cfd-64ca-4e8a-9ea0-6a350dd89d0d-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/22/world/22India2/merlin_158292042_4bd08cfd-64ca-4e8a-9ea0-6a350dd89d0d-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/22/world/22India2/merlin_158292042_4bd08cfd-64ca-4e8a-9ea0-6a350dd89d0d-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 80vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/22/world/22India2/merlin_158292042_4bd08cfd-64ca-4e8a-9ea0-6a350dd89d0d-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Watching the launch near the space center. “Every Indian is immensely proud today!” Prime Minister Narendra Modi said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rebecca Conway for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It was hot and extremely muggy, the kind of weather in which sweat flows freely. Cameras dangled from the necks of spectators. Some people, like K. Kaushal, 8, wore pins saying “I Love India.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It’s going to be like a missile going to the moon!” he said right before the launch. “A lot of fire and noise.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As scientists began the countdown — “T minus five minutes,” “T minus one minute” — huge video screens in the space center’s media room alternated between live images of the rocket on the launchpad and shots of scientists and engineers at mission control, their faces all business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The mission includes four components: a giant Geosynchronous Satellite Launch Vehicle — Mark III rocket (though it is much shorter and lighter than the Saturn V rocket that lifted the Apollo missions); an orbiter; a lander; and a six-wheeled rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The purpose is to probe the south pole of the moon for the possibility of water ice and to study deposits of Helium-3, believed to be a future energy source for Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Indian officials say their new generation of sensors, cameras and other equipment could lead to scientific breakthroughs more than 50 years after the first manned mission to the moon.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Every Indian is immensely proud today!” the Indian prime minister, Narendra Modi, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1153240987587641344&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. “Indian at heart, Indian in spirit!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The mission was relatively inexpensive in space terms, costing less than $150 million — less than it cost to make the 2014 film “Interstellar.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Chandrayaan-2 will take much longer to reach the moon than the relatively straight shot made by the Apollo missions, which cost billions (the presence of humans added to the price tag).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The Indian orbiter will conserve fuel by making ever-widening orbits around Earth before being captured by the moon’s gravity and pulled into lunar orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;The 142-foot, 700-ton rocket rose on a funnel of fire, ripping through the air before vanishing into a thick bank of clouds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rebecca Conway for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The big moment should come in early September. That’s when the lander is expected to break off from the orbiter and gently land on the moon’s surface. Because of the delay in communicating across such far distances, the engineers and scientists back at mission control won’t be able to help much. The lander will essentially be on autopilot, and a computer will be in charge of firing the various thrusters and steering the lander safely down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It will decide on its own and make decisions,” said Vivek Singh, a spokesman for the Indian Space Research Organization, India’s version of NASA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;When an Israeli mission tried this in April, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/11/science/israel-moon-landing-beresheet.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;their lander crashed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But the Indians are supremely confident they can do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The launch on Monday was “the beginning of a historical journey,” said K. Sivan, the chairman of the space agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Sivan stood at a podium in mission control, and as he spoke, the scientists and engineers around him cheered. A week earlier, the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/15/world/asia/india-moon-rocket-launch-delayed.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;first scheduled launch had been scrapped&lt;/a&gt; with less than an hour to go. Engineers had detected a loss of pressure in one of the helium tanks that are part of the rocket’s engine system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But, Mr. Sivan said, “We fixed that technical snag now and ISRO bounced back with flying colors!” Huge applause broke out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;If the soft landing works, Chandrayaan’s little solar-powered rover will venture out and perform experiments, such as collecting soil samples from the moon’s crust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The mission has been timed for the beginning of a moon day, so the rover can get maximum sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Indian scientists said that they had built a small cushion into their timing of orbiting the Earth and that the one-week delay would not affect the intended landing date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But, Mr. Singh admitted, “Some of our flexibility will be reduced.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But those issues were far from the minds of the space enthusiasts who had been looking forward to this launch for months and stood with their heads tilted back on Monday, relishing the few seconds of seeing a rocket fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It was so beautiful to see it disappear into the clouds,” said Neeraj Ladia, an executive at a private space education company called Space India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“And then that roar. It was so much louder than I expected. It was marvelous.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1sngw6j&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1eoytci&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2015/07/19/science/19PLUTO/19PLUTO-articleLarge.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1rha1bf&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-zd32qr&quot;&gt;Sync your calendar with the solar system&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1uuihdo&quot;&gt;Never miss an eclipse, a meteor shower, a rocket launch or any other astronomical and space event that's out of this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 10:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/22/world/asia/chandrayaan-india-moon-launch.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>India Launches Chandrayaan-2 Moon Mission on Second Try</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/22/world/22india1/22india1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Last week, scientists abruptly called off the historic launch right before liftoff. A second attempt on Monday was a success.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/22/world/asia/chandrayaan-india-moon-launch.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>