<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Banned from PayPal after 12 years of business</title>
<link>https://blog.niteo.co/paypal-ban-after-12-years/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.niteo.co/paypal-ban-after-12-years/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;You’d think that being a &lt;strong&gt;legitimate online business&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;having 12 years of history with PayPal&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;hundreds of thousands of dollars processed&lt;/strong&gt;, you’d gain some credibility with them. Not so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our company was banned with a generic “breaking terms of use” email. After calling their support twice, explaining the situation and asking for a reason, we have received nothing but “the decision is final, and we will not provide more information”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.niteo.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/paypalban-1024x934.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-681&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;365&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.niteo.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/paypalban-1024x934.png 1024w, https://blog.niteo.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/paypalban-300x274.png 300w, https://blog.niteo.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/paypalban-768x701.png 768w, https://blog.niteo.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/paypalban.png 1052w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our account &lt;strong&gt;has not been limited or flagged once in these 12 years&lt;/strong&gt;. We have processed hundreds of thousands of dollars in online subscriptions for our software services. The most interesting thing is that we’ve moved away from PayPal in the last two years and have only been receiving some minor payments and paying for a few online services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We never thought this would happen and have absolutely no clue what they’re referring. We have reviewed the &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot;terms of use (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/useragreement-full#r09&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;user agreement&lt;/a&gt; multiple times and there is absolutely nothing there that we’ve engaged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not kid yourself – &lt;strong&gt;your business is never, never safe with PayPal&lt;/strong&gt;. Move away or at least have a plan B in place so that you don’t lose your business over their arbitrary actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We were lucky that we have moved away from PayPal for actual business revenue, otherwise the consequences could’ve been devastating.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 11:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dz0ny</dc:creator>
<og:title>We got banned from PayPal after 12 years of business</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.niteo.co/paypal-ban-after-12-years/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>You'd think that being a legitimate online business, having 12 years of history with PayPal, and hundreds of thousands of dollars processed, you'd gain some credibility with them. Not so. Our company was banned with a generic &quot;breaking terms of use&quot; email. After calling their support twice, expla</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.niteo.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/paypal-ban.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.niteo.co/paypal-ban-after-12-years/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>It’s Time to Break Up Facebook</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/09/opinion/sunday/chris-hughes-facebook-zuckerberg.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/09/opinion/sunday/chris-hughes-facebook-zuckerberg.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;The last time I saw Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/strong&gt; was in the summer of 2017, several months before the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/17/us/politics/cambridge-analytica-trump-campaign.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica scandal broke&lt;/a&gt;. We met at &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/09/opinion/chris-hughes-facebook.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook’s&lt;/a&gt; Menlo Park, Calif., office and drove to his house, in a quiet, leafy neighborhood. We spent an hour or two together while his toddler daughter cruised around. We talked politics mostly, a little about Facebook, a bit about our families. When the shadows grew long, I had to head out. I hugged his wife, Priscilla, and said goodbye to Mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Since then, Mark’s personal reputation and the reputation of Facebook have taken a nose-dive. The company’s mistakes — the sloppy privacy practices that dropped tens of millions of users’ data into a political consulting firm’s lap; the slow response to Russian agents, violent rhetoric and fake news; and the unbounded drive to capture ever more of our time and attention — dominate the headlines. It’s been 15 years since I co-founded Facebook at Harvard, and I haven’t worked at the company in a decade. But I feel a sense of anger and responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;css-1e767xm e1gnsphs0&quot; id=&quot;link-2a69115c&quot;&gt;Watch: A founder of Facebook says it should be broken up.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-bsn42l&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1dv1kvn&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1t0v8sy etkm6pg0&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-1a74oa6 etkm6pg1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1ihorw etkm6pg2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/09/autossell/op-chris/op-chris-videoSixteenByNineJumbo1600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Video player loading&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Chris Hughes, a co-founder of Facebook, says the company is so big and powerful that it threatens our democracy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-cch8ym&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1dv1kvn&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;emkp2hg2 css-1nwzsjy e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mark is still the same person I watched hug his parents as they left our dorm’s common room at the beginning of our sophomore year. He is the same person who procrastinated studying for tests, fell in love with his future wife while in line for the bathroom at a party and slept on a mattress on the floor in a small apartment years after he could have afforded much more. In other words, he’s human. But it’s his very humanity that makes his unchecked power so problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mark’s influence is staggering, far beyond that of anyone else in the private sector or in government. He controls three core communications platforms — Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp — that billions of people use every day. Facebook’s board works more like an advisory committee than an overseer, because Mark &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/technology/2018/11/19/18099011/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-stock-nyt-wsj&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;controls around 60 percent of voting shares&lt;/a&gt;. Mark alone can decide how to configure Facebook’s algorithms to determine what people see in their News Feeds, what privacy settings they can use and even which messages get delivered. He sets the rules for how to distinguish violent and incendiary speech from the merely offensive, and he can choose to shut down a competitor by acquiring, blocking or copying it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;css-1upla3o etf134l0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1plcdrk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mark’s influence is staggering, far beyond that of anyone else in the private sector or in government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mark is a good, kind person. But I’m angry that his focus on growth led him to sacrifice security and civility for clicks. I’m disappointed in myself and the early Facebook team for not thinking more about how the News Feed algorithm could change our culture, influence elections and empower nationalist leaders. And I’m worried that Mark has surrounded himself with a team that reinforces his beliefs instead of challenging them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The government must hold Mark accountable. For too long, lawmakers have marveled at Facebook’s explosive growth and overlooked their responsibility to ensure that Americans are protected and markets are competitive. Any day now, the Federal Trade Commission is expected to impose a $5 billion fine on the company, but that is not enough; nor is Facebook’s offer to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/01/technology/facebook-ftc-settlement.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;appoint&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/01/technology/facebook-ftc-settlement.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;some kind of privacy czar&lt;/a&gt;. After Mark’s congressional testimony last year, there should have been calls for him to truly reckon with his mistakes. Instead the legislators who questioned him were derided as too old and out of touch to understand how tech works. That’s the impression Mark wanted Americans to have, because it means little will change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;We are a nation with a tradition of reining in monopolies, no matter how well intentioned the leaders of these companies may be. Mark’s power is unprecedented and un-American.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It is time to break up Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/06/01/opinion/01hughes1/merlin_136671303_e68047a9-c44b-4521-a23b-54fc51ab4180-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/06/01/opinion/01hughes1/merlin_136671303_e68047a9-c44b-4521-a23b-54fc51ab4180-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/06/01/opinion/01hughes1/merlin_136671303_e68047a9-c44b-4521-a23b-54fc51ab4180-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/06/01/opinion/01hughes1/merlin_136671303_e68047a9-c44b-4521-a23b-54fc51ab4180-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 80vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/06/01/opinion/01hughes1/merlin_136671303_e68047a9-c44b-4521-a23b-54fc51ab4180-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg testifying on Capitol Hill in 2018. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tom Brenner/The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;We already have the tools&lt;/strong&gt; we need to check the domination of Facebook. We just seem to have forgotten about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;America was built on the idea that power should not be concentrated in any one person, because we are all fallible. That’s why the founders created a system of checks and balances. They didn’t need to foresee the rise of Facebook to understand the threat that gargantuan companies would pose to democracy. Jefferson and Madison were voracious readers of Adam Smith, who believed that monopolies prevent the competition that spurs innovation and leads to economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A century later, in response to the rise of the oil, railroad and banking trusts of the Gilded Age, the Ohio Republican John Sherman said on the floor of Congress: “If we will not endure a king as a political power, we should not endure a king over the production, transportation and sale of any of the necessities of life. If we would not submit to an emperor, we should not submit to an autocrat of trade with power to prevent competition and to fix the price of any commodity.” The Sherman Antitrust Act of 1890 outlawed monopolies. More legislation followed in the 20th century, creating legal and regulatory structures to promote competition and hold the biggest companies accountable. The Department of Justice broke up monopolies like Standard Oil and AT&amp;amp;T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For many people today, it’s hard to imagine government doing much of anything right, let alone breaking up a company like Facebook. This isn’t by coincidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Starting in the 1970s, a small but dedicated group of economists, lawyers and policymakers sowed the seeds of our cynicism. Over the next 40 years, they financed a network of think tanks, journals, social clubs, academic centers and media outlets to teach an emerging generation that private interests should take precedence over public ones. Their gospel was simple: “Free” markets are dynamic and productive, while government is bureaucratic and ineffective. By the mid-1980s, they had largely managed to relegate energetic antitrust enforcement to the history books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This shift, combined with business-friendly tax and regulatory policy, ushered in a period of mergers and acquisitions that created megacorporations. In the past 20 years, more than 75 percent of American industries, from airlines to pharmaceuticals, have experienced increased &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2612047&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;concentration&lt;/a&gt;, and the average size of public companies has tripled. The results are a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/20/business/economy/startup-business.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;decline in entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/04/29/upshot/why-is-productivity-so-weak-three-theories.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;stalled productivity growth&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.janeeckhout.com/wp-content/uploads/RMP.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;higher prices and fewer choices&lt;/a&gt; for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The same thing is happening in social media and digital communications. Because Facebook so dominates social networking, it faces no market-based accountability. This means that every time Facebook messes up, we repeat an exhausting pattern: first outrage, then disappointment and, finally, resignation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;In 2005, I was in Facebook’s first office,&lt;/strong&gt; on Emerson Street in downtown Palo Alto, when I read the news that Rupert Murdoch’s News Corporation was acquiring the social networking site Myspace for $580 million. The overhead lights were off, and a group of us were pecking away on our keyboards, our 21-year-old faces half-illuminated by the glow of our screens. I heard a “whoa,” and the news then ricocheted silently through the room, delivered by AOL Instant Messenger. My eyes widened. Really, $580 million?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook was competing with Myspace, albeit obliquely. We were focused on college students at that point, but we had real identities while Myspace had fictions. Our users were more engaged, visiting daily, if not hourly. We believed Facebook surpassed Myspace in quality and would easily displace it given enough time and money. If Myspace was worth $580 million, Facebook could be worth at least double.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Journalists kept close watch as social media became big business.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;From our earliest days, Mark used the word “domination” to describe our ambitions, with no hint of irony or humility. Back then, we competed with a whole host of social networks, not just Myspace, but also Friendster, Twitter, Tumblr, LiveJournal and others. The pressure to beat them spurred innovation and led to many of the features that distinguish Facebook: simple, beautiful interfaces, the News Feed, a tie to real-world identities and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;css-1upla3o etf134l0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1plcdrk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;From our earliest days, Mark used the word “domination” to describe our ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It was this drive to compete that led Mark to acquire, over the years, dozens of other companies, including Instagram and WhatsApp in 2012 and 2014. There was nothing unethical or suspicious, in my view, in these moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One night during the summer of the Myspace sale, I remember driving home from work with Mark, back to the house we shared with several engineers and designers. I was in the passenger seat of the Infiniti S.U.V. that our investor Peter Thiel had bought for Mark to replace the unreliable used Jeep that he had been driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As we turned right off Valparaiso Avenue, Mark confessed the immense pressure he felt. “Now that we employ so many people …” he said, trailing off. “We just really can’t fail.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook had gone from a project developed in our dorm room and chaotic summer houses to a serious company with lawyers and a human resources department. We had around 50 employees, and their families relied on Facebook to put food on the table. I gazed out the window and thought to myself, &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;It’s never going to stop. The bigger we get, the harder we’ll have to work to keep growing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Chris Hughes, right, and Mark Zuckerberg, at Harvard in 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rick Friedman&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Over a decade later, Facebook has earned the prize of domination. It is worth half a trillion dollars and commands, by my estimate, more than 80 percent of the world’s social networking revenue. It is a powerful monopoly, eclipsing all of its rivals and erasing competition from the social networking category. This explains why, even during the annus horribilis of 2018, Facebook’s earnings per share increased by an astounding 40 percent compared with the year before. (I liquidated my Facebook shares in 2012, and I don’t invest directly in any social media companies&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook’s monopoly is also visible in its usage statistics. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pewinternet.org/fact-sheet/social-media/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;About 70 percent&lt;/a&gt; of American adults use social media, and a vast majority are on Facebook products. Over two-thirds use the core site, a third use Instagram, and a fifth use WhatsApp. By contrast, fewer than a third report using Pinterest, LinkedIn or Snapchat. What started out as lighthearted entertainment has become the primary way that people of all ages communicate online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;facebook-size&quot; data-id=&quot;100000006499604&quot; class=&quot;interactive-content interactive-size-scoop css-fdp4hj e13l8dds0&quot;&gt;&lt;header id=&quot;interactive-header&quot; class=&quot;css-cl76n0 interactive-header&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;interactive-headline&quot; class=&quot;css-1su19vv interactive-headline&quot;&gt;Dominating the Market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p data-testid=&quot;leadin&quot; id=&quot;interactive-leadin&quot; class=&quot;css-1vs7yia interactive-leadin&quot;&gt;The total number of users across Facebook’s platforms far exceeds the number on any rival platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-17ih8de interactive-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-fb-size-box&quot; class=&quot;ai2html ai2html-box-v5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-fb-size-600&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;1.916&quot; data-min-width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;g-fb-size-600-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg g-aiAbs&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/2019/04/29/fb-size/625e49dd57150b575926f70c8543868d0b156e91/fb-size-600.png&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhCgAKAIAAAB8fHwAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAKAAoAAAIIhI+py+0PYysAOw==&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-1&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Platforms owned by &lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle0&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-2&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Platforms owned by &lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle1&quot;&gt;others&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;





&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-8&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;1.9B monthly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;active users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-10&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;2.3B monthly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;active users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;














&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-fb-size-300&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;0.716&quot; data-min-width=&quot;300&quot; data-max-width=&quot;599&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;g-fb-size-300-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg g-aiAbs&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/2019/04/29/fb-size/625e49dd57150b575926f70c8543868d0b156e91/fb-size-300.png&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhCgAKAIAAAB8fHwAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAKAAoAAAIIhI+py+0PYysAOw==&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-1&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Platforms owned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle0&quot;&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; Facebook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-2&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Platforms owned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle0&quot;&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-5&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle5&quot;&gt;1.9B monthly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle5&quot;&gt;active users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-6&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle6&quot;&gt;2.3B monthly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle6&quot;&gt;active users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;










&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-17&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle7&quot;&gt;Insta-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle7&quot;&gt;gram&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;







&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer id=&quot;interactive-footer&quot; class=&quot;css-irejme interactive-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;p data-testid=&quot;note&quot; id=&quot;interactive-notes&quot; class=&quot;css-1g8gl4z interactive-notes&quot;&gt;Note: These figures do not necessarily reflect unique users. They are based on monthly active users, active user accounts or unique monthly visitors, and are current as of April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-testid=&quot;source&quot; id=&quot;interactive-source&quot; class=&quot;css-1g8gl4z interactive-source&quot;&gt;Source: Hootsuite and We Are Social, via DataReportal.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-testid=&quot;credit&quot; id=&quot;interactive-credit&quot; class=&quot;css-1g8gl4z interactive-credit&quot;&gt;By The New York Times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Even when people want to quit Facebook, they don’t have any meaningful alternative, as we saw in the aftermath of the Cambridge Analytica scandal. Worried about their privacy and lacking confidence in Facebook’s good faith, users across the world started a “Delete Facebook” movement. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2018/09/05/americans-are-changing-their-relationship-with-facebook/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;According to the Pew Research Center&lt;/a&gt;, a quarter deleted their accounts from their phones, but many did so only temporarily. I heard more than one friend say, “I’m getting off Facebook altogether — thank God for Instagram,” not realizing that Instagram was a Facebook subsidiary. In the end people did not leave the company’s platforms en masse. After all, where would they go?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;Facebook’s dominance is not an accident of history.&lt;/strong&gt; The company’s strategy was to beat every competitor in plain view, and regulators and the government tacitly — and at times explicitly — approved. In one of the government’s few attempts to rein in the company, the F.T.C. in 2011 issued a consent decree that Facebook not share any private information beyond what users already agreed to. Facebook largely ignored the decree. Last month, the day after the company predicted in an earnings call that it &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/facebook-ftc-fine-privacy.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;would need to pay&lt;/a&gt; up to $5 billion as a penalty for its negligence — a slap on the wrist — Facebook’s shares surged 7 percent, adding $30 billion to its value, six times the size of the fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.T.C.’s biggest mistake was to allow Facebook to acquire Instagram and WhatsApp. In 2012, the newer platforms were nipping at Facebook’s heels because they had been built for the smartphone, where Facebook was still struggling to gain traction. Mark responded by buying them, and the F.T.C. approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Neither Instagram nor WhatsApp had any meaningful revenue, but both were incredibly popular. The Instagram acquisition guaranteed Facebook would preserve its dominance in photo networking, and WhatsApp gave it a new entry into mobile real-time messaging. Now, the founders of Instagram and WhatsApp have left the company after &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-mark-zuckerberg-15-months-of-fresh-hell/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;clashing&lt;/a&gt; with Mark over his management of their platforms. But their former properties remain Facebook’s, driving much of its recent growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg introducing the company's 10-year roadmap at a Facebook conference in 2016.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Eric Risberg/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;When it hasn’t acquired its way to dominance, Facebook has used its monopoly position to shut out competing companies or has copied their technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The News Feed algorithm reportedly &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2017/03/13/facebook-native-video-gets-10x-more-shares-than-youtube/#421ef8c41c66&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;prioritized&lt;/a&gt; videos created through Facebook over videos from competitors, like YouTube and Vimeo. In 2012, Twitter introduced a video network called Vine that featured six-second videos. That same day, Facebook blocked Vine from hosting a tool that let its users search for their Facebook friends while on the new network. The decision hobbled Vine, which shut down four years later&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Snapchat posed a different threat. Snapchat’s Stories and impermanent messaging options made it an attractive alternative to Facebook and Instagram. And unlike Vine, Snapchat wasn’t interfacing with the Facebook ecosystem; there was no obvious way to handicap the company or shut it out. So Facebook simply copied it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook’s version of Snapchat’s stories and disappearing messages proved wildly successful, at Snapchat’s expense. At an all-hands meeting in 2016, Mark told Facebook employees not to let their pride get in the way of giving users what they want. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2018/09/05/americans-are-changing-their-relationship-with-facebook/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;According to Wired magazine&lt;/a&gt;, “Zuckerberg’s message became an informal slogan at Facebook: ‘Don’t be too proud to copy.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;(There is little regulators can do about this tactic: Snapchat patented its “ephemeral message galleries,” but copyright law does not extend to the abstract concept itself.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;css-1upla3o etf134l0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1plcdrk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Would-be competitors can’t raise the money to take on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As a result of all this, would-be competitors can’t raise the money to take on Facebook. Investors realize that if a company gets traction, Facebook will copy its innovations, shut it down or acquire it for a relatively modest sum. So despite an extended economic expansion, increasing interest in high-tech start-ups, an explosion of venture capital and growing public distaste for Facebook, no major social networking company has been founded since the fall of 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As markets become more concentrated, the number of new start-up businesses declines. This holds true in other high-tech areas dominated by single companies, like search (controlled by Google) and e-commerce (taken over by Amazon). Meanwhile, there has been plenty of innovation in areas where there is no monopolistic domination, such as in workplace productivity (Slack, Trello, Asana), urban transportation (Lyft, Uber, Lime, Bird) and cryptocurrency exchanges (Ripple, Coinbase, Circle).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;I don’t blame Mark for his quest for domination. He has demonstrated nothing more nefarious than the virtuous hustle of a talented entrepreneur. Yet he has created a leviathan that crowds out entrepreneurship and restricts consumer choice. It’s on our government to ensure that we never lose the magic of the invisible hand. How did we allow this to happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;Since the 1970s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;courts have become increasingly hesitant&lt;/strong&gt; to break up companies or block mergers unless consumers are paying inflated prices that would be lower in a competitive market. But a narrow reliance on whether or not consumers have experienced price gouging fails to take into account the full cost of market domination. It doesn’t recognize that we also want markets to be competitive to encourage innovation and to hold power in check. And it is out of step with the history of antitrust law. Two of the last major antitrust suits, against AT&amp;amp;T and IBM in the 1980s, were grounded in the argument that they had used their size to stifle innovation and crush competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As the Columbia law professor Tim Wu &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://globalreports.columbia.edu/books/the-curse-of-bigness/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt;, “It is a disservice to the laws and their intent to retain such a laserlike focus on price effects as the measure of all that antitrust was meant to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook is the perfect case on which to reverse course, precisely because Facebook makes its money from targeted advertising, meaning users do not pay to use the service. But it is not actually free, and it certainly isn’t harmless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;css-1upla3o etf134l0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1plcdrk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;We pay for Facebook with our data and our attention, and by either measure it doesn’t come cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook’s business model is built on capturing as much of our attention as possible to encourage people to create and share more information about who they are and who they want to be. We pay for Facebook with our data and our attention, and by either measure it doesn’t come cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;I was on the original News Feed team (my name is on the patent), and that product now gets billions of hours of attention and pulls in unknowable amounts of data each year. The average Facebook user spends &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/6/25/17501224/instagram-facebook-snapchat-time-spent-growth-data&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an hour a day&lt;/a&gt; on the platform; Instagram users spend 53 minutes a day scrolling through pictures and videos. They create immense amounts of data — not just likes and dislikes, but how many seconds they watch a particular video — that Facebook uses to refine its targeted advertising. Facebook also &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/you-give-apps-sensitive-personal-information-then-they-tell-facebook-11550851636&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;collects&lt;/a&gt; data from partner companies and apps, without most users knowing about it, according to testing by The Wall Street Journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Some days, lying on the floor next to my 1-year-old son as he plays with his dinosaurs, I catch myself scrolling through Instagram, waiting to see if the next image will be more beautiful than the last. What am I doing? I know it’s not good for me, or for my son, and yet I do it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg introducing new features at a conference last month.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Amy Osborne/Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The choice is mine, but it doesn’t feel like a choice. Facebook seeps into every corner of our lives to capture as much of our attention and data as possible and, without any alternative, we make the trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The vibrant marketplace that once drove Facebook and other social media companies to compete to come up with better products has virtually disappeared. This means there’s less chance of start-ups developing healthier, less exploitative social media platforms. It also means less accountability on issues like privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Just last month, Facebook seemingly &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/zakdoffman/2019/04/19/u-s-authorities-target-zuckerberg-as-instagram-security-breach-hits-millions/#64e13edf5062&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tried to bury news&lt;/a&gt; that it had stored tens of millions of user passwords in plain text format, which thousands of Facebook employees could see. Competition alone wouldn’t necessarily spur privacy protection — regulation is required to ensure accountability — but Facebook’s lock on the market guarantees that users can’t protest by moving to alternative platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;The most problematic aspect of Facebook’s power&lt;/strong&gt; is Mark’s unilateral control over speech. There is no precedent for his ability to monitor, organize and even censor the conversations of two billion people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook engineers write algorithms that select which users’ comments or experiences end up displayed in the News Feeds of friends and family. These rules are proprietary and so complex that many Facebook employees themselves don’t understand them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2014, the rules favored curiosity-inducing “clickbait” headlines. In 2016, they enabled the spread of fringe political views and fake news, which made it easier for Russian actors to manipulate the American electorate. In January 2018, Mark announced that the algorithms would favor non-news content shared by friends and news from “trustworthy” sources, which his engineers &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-mark-zuckerberg-15-months-of-fresh-hell/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;interpreted&lt;/a&gt; — to the confusion of many — as a boost for anything in the category of “politics, crime, tragedy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook has responded to many of the criticisms of how it manages speech by hiring thousands of contractors to enforce the rules that Mark and senior executives develop. After a few weeks of training, these contractors decide which videos count as hate speech or free speech, which images are erotic and which are simply artistic, and which live streams are too violent to be broadcast. (The Verge &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18229714/cognizant-facebook-content-moderator-interviews-trauma-working-conditions-arizona&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that some of these moderators, working through a vendor in Arizona, were paid $28,800 a year, got limited breaks and faced significant mental health risks.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-nvxo42 e73j0it0&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;At a Facebook deletion center in Berlin, contractors flag hate speech.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gordon Welters for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Photos of candidates in the Brazilian election in Facebook’s “war room,” where employees monitored election-related content.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jeff Chiu/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As if Facebook’s opaque algorithms weren’t enough, last year we learned that Facebook executives had permanently deleted their own messages from the platform, erasing them from the inboxes of recipients; the justification was corporate security concerns. When I look at my years of Facebook messages with Mark now, it’s just a long stream of my own light-blue comments, clearly written in response to words he had once sent me. (Facebook now offers this as a feature to all users.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The most extreme example of Facebook manipulating speech happened in Myanmar in late 2017&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; Mark &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/4/6/17204324/zuckerberg-facebook-myanmar-rohingya-hate-speech-open-letter&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said in a Vox interview&lt;/a&gt; that he personally made the decision to delete the private messages of Facebook users who were encouraging genocide there. “I remember, one Saturday morning, I got a phone call,” he said, “and we detected that people were trying to spread sensational messages through — it was Facebook Messenger in this case — to each side of the conflict, basically telling the Muslims, ‘Hey, there’s about to be an uprising of the Buddhists, so make sure that you are armed and go to this place.’ And then the same thing on the other side.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mark made a call: “We stop those messages from going through.” Most people would agree with his decision, but it’s deeply troubling that he made it with no accountability to any independent authority or government. Facebook could, in theory, delete en masse the messages of Americans, too, if its leadership decided it didn’t like them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mark used to insist that Facebook was just a “social utility,” a neutral platform for people to communicate what they wished. Now he recognizes that Facebook is both a platform and a publisher and that it is inevitably making decisions about values. The company’s own lawyers have argued in court that Facebook is &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/jul/02/facebook-mark-zuckerberg-platform-publisher-lawsuit&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a publisher&lt;/a&gt; and thus entitled to First Amendment protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;No one at Facebook headquarters is choosing what single news story everyone in America wakes up to, of course. But they do decide whether it will be an article from a reputable outlet or a clip from “The Daily Show,” a photo from a friend’s wedding or an incendiary call to kill others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mark knows that this is too much power and is pursuing a twofold strategy to mitigate it. He is pivoting Facebook’s focus toward encouraging more &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/30/18524188/facebook-f8-keynote-mark-zuckerberg-privacy-future-2019&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;private&lt;/a&gt;, encrypted messaging that Facebook’s employees can’t see, let alone control. Second, he is hoping for friendly oversight from regulators and other industry executives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Late last year, he proposed an independent commission to handle difficult content moderation decisions by social media platforms. It would afford an independent check, Mark argued, on Facebook’s decisions, and users could appeal to it if they disagreed. But its decisions would not have the force of law, since companies would voluntarily participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/mark-zuckerberg-the-internet-needs-new-rules-lets-start-in-these-four-areas/2019/03/29/9e6f0504-521a-11e9-a3f7-78b7525a8d5f_story.html?utm_term=.2fe1d8be682f&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;op-ed essay in The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; in March, he wrote, “Lawmakers often tell me we have too much power over speech, and I agree.” And he went even further than before, calling for more government regulation — not just on speech, but also on privacy and interoperability, the ability of consumers to seamlessly leave one network and transfer their profiles, friend connections, photos and other data to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;css-1upla3o etf134l0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1plcdrk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook isn’t afraid of a few more rules. It’s afraid of an antitrust case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;I don’t think these proposals were made in bad faith. But I do think they’re an attempt to head off the argument that regulators need to go further and break up the company. Facebook isn’t afraid of a few more rules. It’s afraid of an antitrust case and of the kind of accountability that real government oversight would bring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;We don’t expect calcified rules or voluntary commissions to work to regulate drug companies, health care companies, car manufacturers or credit card providers. Agencies oversee these industries to ensure that the private market works for the public good. In these cases, we all understand that government isn’t an external force meddling in an organic market; it’s what makes a dynamic and fair market possible in the first place. This should be just as true for social networking as it is for air travel or pharmaceuticals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;In the summer of 2006, Yahoo offered us $1 billion&lt;/strong&gt; for Facebook. I desperately wanted Mark to say yes. Even my small slice of the company would have made me a millionaire several times over. For a 22-year-old scholarship kid from small-town North Carolina, that kind of money was unimaginable. I wasn’t alone — just about every other person at the company wanted the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It was taboo to talk about it openly, but I finally asked Mark when we had a moment alone, “How are you feeling about Yahoo?” I got a shrug and a one-line answer: “I just don’t know if I want to work for Terry Semel,” Yahoo’s chief executive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Outside of a couple of gigs in college, Mark had never had a real boss and seemed entirely uninterested in the prospect. I didn’t like the idea much myself, but I would have traded having a boss for several million dollars any day of the week. Mark’s drive was infinitely stronger. Domination meant domination, and the hustle was just too delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg after ringing the opening bell for the Nasdaq stock market on the day his company went public.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Spencer Platt/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mark may never have a boss, but he needs to have some check on his power. The American government needs to do two things: break up Facebook’s monopoly and regulate the company to make it more accountable to the American people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;First, Facebook should be separated into multiple companies. The F.T.C., in conjunction with the Justice Department, should enforce antitrust laws by undoing the Instagram and WhatsApp acquisitions and banning future acquisitions for several years. The F.T.C. should have blocked these mergers, but it’s not too late to act. There is precedent for correcting bad decisions — as recently as 2009, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-wholefoods-ftc/whole-foods-ftc-settle-on-wild-oats-merger-idUSTRE5253AL20090306&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Whole Foods settled antitrust complaints&lt;/a&gt; by selling off the Wild Oats brand and stores that it had bought a few years earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;There is some evidence that we may be headed in this direction. Senator Elizabeth Warren has &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/08/us/politics/elizabeth-warren-amazon.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;called&lt;/a&gt; for reversing the Facebook mergers, and in February, the F.T.C. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/26/18241491/ftc-task-force-tech-monopolies-bureau-competition-online-platforms&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the creation of a task force to monitor competition among tech companies and review previous mergers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;How would a breakup work? Facebook would have a brief period to spin off the Instagram and WhatsApp businesses, and the three would become distinct companies, most likely publicly traded. Facebook shareholders would initially hold stock in the new companies, although Mark and other executives would probably be required to divest their management shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Until recently, WhatsApp and Instagram were administered as independent platforms inside the parent company, so that should make the process easier. But time is of the essence: Facebook is working quickly to integrate the three, which would make it harder for the F.T.C. to split them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;Some economists are&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://qz.com/280197/meet-the-economics-nobelist-who-explains-net-neutrality-and-the-ios-app-store/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;skeptical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that breaking up Facebook would spur that much competition, because Facebook, they say, is a “natural” monopoly. Natural monopolies have emerged in areas like water systems and the electrical grid, where the price of entering the business is very high — because you have to lay pipes or electrical lines — but it gets cheaper and cheaper to add each additional customer. In other words, the monopoly arises naturally from the circumstances of the business, rather than a company’s illegal maneuvering. In addition, defenders of natural monopolies often make the case that they benefit consumers because they are able to provide services more cheaply than anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook is indeed more valuable when there are more people on it: There are more connections for a user to make and more content to be shared. But the cost of entering the social network business is not that high. And unlike with pipes and electricity, there is no good argument that the country benefits from having only one dominant social networking company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Facebook is more valuable when there are more people on  it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jim Wilson/The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Still others worry that the breakup of Facebook or other American tech companies could be a national security problem. Because advancements in artificial intelligence require immense amounts of data and computing power, only large companies like Facebook, Google and Amazon can afford these investments, they say. If American companies become smaller, the Chinese will outpace us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;While serious, these concerns do not justify inaction. Even after a breakup, Facebook would be a hugely profitable business with billions to invest in new technologies — and a more competitive market would only encourage those investments. If the Chinese did pull ahead, our government could invest in research and development and pursue tactical trade policy, just as it is doing today to hold China’s 5G technology at bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The cost of breaking up Facebook would be next to zero for the government, and lots of people stand to gain economically. A ban on short-term acquisitions would ensure that competitors, and the investors who take a bet on them, would have the space to flourish. Digital advertisers would suddenly have multiple companies vying for their dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Even Facebook shareholders would probably benefit, as shareholders often do in the years after a company’s split. The value of the companies that made up Standard Oil doubled within a year of its being dismantled and had increased by fivefold a few years later. Ten years after the 1984 breakup of AT&amp;amp;T, the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://archive.fortune.com/magazines/fortune/fortune_archive/1992/07/27/76697/index.htm&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;value&lt;/a&gt; of its successor companies had tripled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But the biggest winners would be the American people. Imagine a competitive market in which they could choose among one network that offered higher privacy standards, another that cost a fee to join but had little advertising and another that would allow users to customize and tweak their feeds as they saw fit. No one knows exactly what Facebook’s competitors would offer to differentiate themselves. That’s exactly the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The Justice Department faced similar questions of social costs and benefits with AT&amp;amp;T in the 1950s. AT&amp;amp;T had a monopoly on phone services and telecommunications equipment. The government filed suit under antitrust laws, and the case ended with a consent decree that required AT&amp;amp;T to release its patents and refrain from expanding into the nascent computer industry. This resulted in an explosion of innovation, greatly &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.monika-schnitzer.com/uploads/4/9/4/1/49415675/watzinger_etal_0219.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;increasing&lt;/a&gt; follow-on patents and leading to the development of the semiconductor and modern computing. We would most likely not have iPhones or laptops without the competitive markets that antitrust action ushered in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Adam Smith was right: Competition spurs growth and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;Just breaking up Facebook is not enough.&lt;/strong&gt; We need a new agency, empowered by Congress to regulate tech companies. Its first mandate should be to protect privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The Europeans have made headway on privacy with the General Data Protection Regulation, a law that guarantees users a minimal level of protection&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; A landmark privacy bill in the United States should specify exactly what control Americans have over their digital information, require clearer disclosure to users and provide enough flexibility to the agency to exercise effective oversight over time. The agency should also be charged with guaranteeing basic interoperability across platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Finally, the agency should create guidelines for acceptable speech on social media. This idea may seem un-American — we would never stand for a government agency censoring speech. But we already have limits on yelling “fire” in a crowded theater, child pornography, speech intended to provoke violence and false statements to manipulate stock prices. We will have to create similar standards that tech companies can use. These standards should of course be subject to the review of the courts, just as any other limits on speech are. But there is no constitutional right to harass others or live-stream violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;css-1upla3o etf134l0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1plcdrk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;If we don’t have public servants shaping these policies, corporations will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;These are difficult challenges. I worry that government regulators will not be able to keep up with the pace of digital innovation. I worry that more competition in social networking might lead to a conservative Facebook and a liberal one, or that newer social networks might be less secure if government regulation is weak. But sticking with the status quo would be worse: If we don’t have public servants shaping these policies, corporations will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Over two days in April 2018, nearly 100 lawmakers questioned Mark Zuckerberg. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tom Brenner/The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Some people doubt that an effort to break up Facebook would win in the courts, given the hostility on the federal bench to antitrust action, or that this divided Congress would ever be able to muster enough consensus to create a regulatory agency for social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But even if breakup and regulation aren’t immediately successful, simply pushing for them will bring more oversight. The government’s case against Microsoft — that it illegally used its market power in operating systems to force its customers to use its web browser, Internet Explorer — ended in 2001 when George W. Bush’s administration abandoned its effort to break up the company. Yet that prosecution helped rein in Microsoft’s ambitions to dominate the early web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Similarly, the Justice Department’s 1970s suit accusing IBM of illegally maintaining its monopoly on personal computer sales ended in a stalemate. But along the way, IBM changed many of its behaviors. It stopped bundling its hardware and software, chose an extremely open design for the operating system in its personal computers and did not exercise undue control over its suppliers. Professor Wu has written that this “policeman at the elbow” led IBM to steer clear “of anything close to anticompetitive conduct, for fear of adding to the case against it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;We can expect the same from even an unsuccessful suit against Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Finally, an aggressive case against Facebook would persuade other behemoths like Google and Amazon to think twice about stifling competition in their own sectors, out of fear that they could be next. If the government were to use this moment to resurrect an effective competition standard that takes a broader view of the full cost of “free” products, it could affect a whole host of industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The alternative is bleak. If we do not take action, Facebook’s monopoly will become even more entrenched. With much of the world’s personal communications in hand, it can mine that data for patterns and trends, giving it an advantage over competitors for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;I take responsibility for not sounding the alarm earlier.&lt;/strong&gt; Don Graham, a former Facebook board member, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://time.com/5505433/donald-graham-facebook/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has accused&lt;/a&gt; those who criticize the company now as having “all the courage of the last man leaping on the pile at a football game.” The financial rewards I reaped from working at Facebook radically changed the trajectory of my life, and even after I cashed out, I watched in awe as the company grew. It took the 2016 election fallout and Cambridge Analytica to awaken me to the dangers of Facebook’s monopoly. But anyone suggesting that Facebook is akin to a pinned football player misrepresents its resilience and power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;An era of accountability for Facebook and other monopolies may be beginning. Collective anger is growing, and a new cohort of leaders has begun to emerge. On Capitol Hill, Representative David Cicilline has taken a special interest in checking the power of monopolies, and Senators Amy Klobuchar and Ted Cruz have joined Senator Warren in calling for more oversight. Economists like Jason Furman, a former chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers, are speaking out about monopolies, and a host of legal scholars like Lina Khan, Barry Lynn and Ganesh Sitaraman are plotting a way forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This movement of public servants, scholars and activists deserves our support. Mark Zuckerberg cannot fix Facebook, but our government can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;hughes-design&quot; data-id=&quot;100000006499708&quot; class=&quot;interactive-content interactive-size-scoop css-7xzesj e13l8dds0&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-17ih8de interactive-body&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1psfkbx etfikam0&quot;&gt;Chris Hughes, a co-founder of Facebook, is a co-chairman of the Economic Security Project and a senior adviser at the Roosevelt Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 10:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/09/opinion/sunday/chris-hughes-facebook-zuckerberg.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Opinion | It’s Time to Break Up Facebook</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/09/opinion/sunday/09Hughes/09Hughes-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Mark Zuckerberg is a good guy. But the company I helped him build is a threat to our economy and democracy.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/09/opinion/sunday/chris-hughes-facebook-zuckerberg.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tech Companies Are Deleting Evidence of War Crimes</title>
<link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2019/05/facebook-algorithms-are-making-it-harder/588931/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2019/05/facebook-algorithms-are-making-it-harder/588931/</guid>
<description>&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-0&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;f grisly images&lt;/span&gt; stay up on Facebook or YouTube long enough, self-appointed detectives around the world sometimes use them to reconstruct a crime scene. In July 2017, a video capturing the execution of 18 people appeared on Facebook. The clip opened with a half-dozen armed men presiding over several rows of detainees. Dressed in bright-orange jumpsuits and black hoods, the captives knelt in the gravel, hands tied behind their back. They never saw what was coming. The gunmen raised their weapons and fired, and the first row of victims crumpled to the earth. The executioners repeated this act four times, following the orders of a confident young man dressed in a black cap and camouflage trousers. If you slowed the video down frame by frame, you could see that his black T-shirt bore the logo of the Al-Saiqa Brigade, an elite unit of the Libyan National Army. That was clue No. 1: This happened in Libya.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Facebook took down the bloody video, whose source has yet to be conclusively determined, shortly after it surfaced. But it existed online long enough for copies to spread to other social-networking sites. Independently, human-rights activists, prosecutors, and other internet users in multiple countries scoured the clip for clues and soon established that the killings had occurred on the outskirts of Benghazi. The ringleader, these investigators concluded, was Mahmoud Mustafa Busayf al-Werfalli, an Al-Saiqa commander. Within a month, the International Criminal Court had charged Werfalli with the murder of 33 people in seven separate incidents—from June 2016 to the July 2017 killings that landed on Facebook. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icc-cpi.int/CourtRecords/CR2017_05031.PDF&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'0',r'None'&quot;&gt;the ICC arrest warrant&lt;/a&gt;, prosecutors relied heavily on digital evidence collected from social-media sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Werfalli has thus far evaded justice. But human-rights activists still hail the case as a breakthrough for a powerful new tool: online open-source investigations. Even in no-go combat zones, war crimes and other abuses often leave behind an information trail. By piecing together information that becomes publicly accessible on social media and other sites, internet users can hold the perpetrators accountable—that is, unless algorithms developed by the tech giants expunge the evidence first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-0&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2015/11/free-speech-online-is-at-risk-after-paris-attacks/417411/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'1',r'None'&quot;&gt;Read: Shutting down jihadist websites won’t stop terrorism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after the Werfalli arrest warrant was issued, Hadi Al Khatib, a Syrian-born open-source investigator based in Berlin, noticed something that distressed him: User-generated videos depicting firsthand accounts from the war in Syria were vanishing from the internet by the thousands. Khatib is the founder of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://syrianarchive.org/en&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'2',r'None'&quot;&gt;Syrian Archive&lt;/a&gt;, a collective of activists that, since 2014, has been scouring for digital materials posted by people left behind in Syria’s war zone. The Syrian Archive’s aim is “to build a kind of visual documentation relating to human-rights violations and other crimes committed by all sides during the eight-year-old conflict,” Khatib said in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late summer of 2017, Khatib and his colleagues were systematically building a case against the regime of Bashar al-Assad in much the same way ICC investigators pursued Werfalli. They had amassed scores and scores of citizens’ accounts, including video and photos that purportedly showed Assad was targeting hospitals and medical clinics in bombing campaigns. “We were collecting, archiving, and geolocating evidence, doing all sorts of verification for the case,” Khatib recalled. “Then one day we noticed that all the videos that we had been going through, all of a sudden, all of them were gone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t a sophisticated hack attack by pro-Assad forces that wiped out their work. It was the ruthlessly efficient work of machine-learning algorithms deployed by social networks, particularly YouTube and Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/12/dont-shut-down-internets-biggest-jihadi-archive/577630/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'3',r'None'&quot;&gt;Graeme Wood: Don’t shut down the internet’s biggest jihadist archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;W&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;ith some reluctance&lt;/span&gt;, technology companies in Silicon Valley have taken on the role of prosecutors, judges, and juries in decisions about which words and images should be banished from the public’s sight. Lately, tech companies have become almost as skilled at muzzling speech as they are at enabling it. This hasn’t gone unnoticed by government entities that are keen to transform social networks into listening posts. Government, in effect, is “subcontracting” social-media platforms to be its eyes and ears on all kinds of content it deems objectionable, says Fionnuala Ní Aoláin, a law professor and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ohchr.org/EN/Issues/Terrorism/Pages/SRTerrorismIndex.aspx&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'4',r'None'&quot;&gt;special rapporteur for the United Nations Human Rights Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But some of what governments ask tech companies to do, such as suppressing violent content, cuts against other legitimate goals, such as bringing warlords and dictators to justice. Balancing these priorities is hard enough when humans are making judgments in accordance with established legal norms. In contrast, tech giants operate largely in the dark. They are governed by opaque terms-of-service policies that, more and more, are enforced by artificial-intelligence tools developed in-house with little to no input from the public. “We don’t even know what goes into the algorithms, what kind of in-built biases and structures there are,” Ní Aoláin said in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years, social networks relied on users to flag objectionable content, all manner of hate speech, and calls to arms that, among other things, espoused violence. But as this content continued to fill up the fringes and spill into clear sight, pressure mounted on Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, and other popular social networks to automate the cleanup. They turned to machine learning, a powerful subset of artificial intelligence that can make sense of huge amounts of data with little to no oversight from human minders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2018/03/youtube-extremism-and-the-long-tail/555350/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'5',r'None'&quot;&gt;Read: YouTube extremism and the long tail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designed to identify and take down content posted by “extremists”—“extremists” as defined by software engineers—machine-learning software has become a potent catch-and-kill tool to keep the world’s largest social networks remarkably more sanitized places than they were just a year ago. Google and Facebook break out the numbers in their quarterly transparency reports. &lt;a href=&quot;https://transparencyreport.google.com/youtube-policy/removals&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'6',r'None'&quot;&gt;YouTube pulled&lt;/a&gt; 33 million videos off its network in 2018—roughly 90,000 a day. Of the videos removed after automated systems flagged them, 73 percent were removed so fast that no community members ever saw them. Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;https://transparency.facebook.com/community-standards-enforcement#terrorist-propaganda&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'7',r'None'&quot;&gt;Facebook removed&lt;/a&gt; 15 million pieces of content it deemed “terrorist propaganda” from October 2017 to September 2018. In the third quarter of 2018, machines performed 99.5 percent of Facebook’s “terrorist content” takedowns. Just 0.5 percent of the purged material was reported by users first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those statistics are deeply troubling to open-source investigators, who complain that the machine-learning tools are black boxes. Few people, if any, in the human-rights world know how they’re programmed. Are these AI-powered vacuum cleaners able to discern that a video from Syria, Yemen, or Libya might be a valuable piece of evidence, something someone risked his or her life to post, and therefore worth preserving? YouTube, for one, says it’s working with human-rights experts to fine-tune its take-down procedures. But deeper discussions about the technology involved are rare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Companies are very loath to let civil society talk directly to engineers,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://witness.org/portfolio_page/dia-kayyali/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'8',r'None'&quot;&gt;Dia Kayyali&lt;/a&gt;, a technology-advocacy program manager at Witness, a human-rights organization that works with Khatib and the Syrian Archive. “It’s something that I’ve pushed for. A lot.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These concerns are being drowned out by a counterargument, this one from governments, that tech companies should clamp down harder. Authoritarian countries routinely impose social-media blackouts during national crises, as Sri Lanka did after the Easter-morning terror bombings and as Venezuela did during the May 1 uprising. But politicians in healthy democracies are pressing social networks for round-the-clock controls in an effort to protect impressionable minds from violent content that could radicalize them. If these platforms fail to comply, they could face hefty fines and even jail time for their executives. New Zealand Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern and French President Emmanuel Macron intend to up the ante at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/apr/24/christchurch-call-ardern-leads-push-against-online-terror-content&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'9',r'None'&quot;&gt;a summit next week&lt;/a&gt; calling on tech execs and world leaders to band together to eliminate the publication of extremist online content. After the March 15 mosque massacre in Christchurch, New Zealand, was streamed live on Facebook, countries including New Zealand, Australia, and the United Kingdom passed or proposed comprehensive new online-terror laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/doceo/document/A-8-2019-0193_EN.html?redirect&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'10',r'None'&quot;&gt;A proposed European Union law&lt;/a&gt; has been in the works for months. It would require technology companies to pull down harmful user-generated material—whether words or images—that “incites or solicits the commission or contribution of terrorist offenses, or promotes the participation in activities of a terrorist group.” That standard is extraordinarily broad. But if the companies don’t eliminate such posts within one hour, they face fines of up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18274201/european-terrorist-content-regulation-extremist-terreg-upload-filter-one-hour-takedown-eu&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'11',r'None'&quot;&gt;4 percent of global revenues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/12/facebook-punish-censorship/577654/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'12',r'None'&quot;&gt;Conor Friedersdorf: The speech that Facebook plans to punish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;H&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;uman-rights advocates&lt;/span&gt; worry about the decisions tech giants and their algorithms will make under such outside pressure. “The danger is that governments will often get the balance wrong,” argued Ní Aoláin. “But actually we have the methods and means to challenge governments when they do so. But private entities? We don’t have the legal processes. These are private companies. And the legal basis upon which they regulate their relationships with their users, whether they’re in conflict zones or not, is determined by [the company’s] terms of service. It’s neither transparent nor fair. Your recourse is quite limited.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July, she wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ohchr.org/Documents/Issues/Terrorism/OL_OTH_46_2018.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'13',r'None'&quot;&gt;an open letter&lt;/a&gt; to Facebook’s founder, Mark Zuckerberg, finding fault with how Facebook defines terrorism-related content, a key determination in what it decides to flag and take down. From what Ní Aoláin can tell, “they just came up with a definition for terrorism that bears no relationship to the global definition agreed by states, which I think is a very dangerous precedent. I made that very clear in my communications with them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I asked Facebook to comment on Ní Aoláin’s complaint, a company spokesperson &lt;a href=&quot;https://fbnewsroomus.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/12.11.18-Content-Standard-Forum-Minutes-.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'14',r'None'&quot;&gt;shared detailed minutes&lt;/a&gt; from a December content-standards forum. The minutes are a remarkable document, one that underscores the complexity of the judgments tech companies are being asked to make as they seek to monetize human interactions on a global scale. Is a terrorist organization one that “engages in premeditated acts of violence against persons or property,” or should the definition expand to include any non-state group that “engages in or advocates and lends substantial support” to “purposive and planned acts of violence”? “It would shock me,” one person at the meeting commented, “if in a year we don’t come back and say we need to refine this definition again.” (A company spokesperson said recently that there’s no update on the matter to announce.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the tech giants’ algorithms will implement these subtle standards is an open question. But a new crop of anti-terrorism bills, post-Christchurch, will thrust technology companies into an even more assertive enforcement role. Under the threat of massive fines, tech giants are likely to invest more in aggressive machine-learning content filters to suppress potentially objectionable material. All this will have a chilling effect on those who are trying to expose wrongdoing in war zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-4&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Khatib, at the Syrian Archive, said the rise of machine-learning algorithms has made his job far more difficult in recent months. But the push for more filters continues. (As a Brussels-based digital-rights lobbyist in a separate conversation deadpanned, “Filters are the new black, essentially.”) The EU’s online-terrorism bill, Khatib noted, sends the message that sweeping unsavory content under the rug is okay; the social-media platforms will see to it that nobody sees it. He fears the unintended consequences of such a law—that in cracking down on content that’s deemed off-limits in the West, it could have ripple effects that make life even harder for those residing in repressive societies, or worse, in war zones. Any further crackdown on what people can share online, he said, “would definitely be a gift for all authoritarian regimes. It would be a gift for Assad.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“On the ground in Syria,” he continued, “Assad is doing everything he can to make sure the physical evidence [of potential human-rights violations] is destroyed, and the digital evidence, too. The combination of all this—the filters, the machine-learning algorithms, and new laws—will make it harder for us to document what’s happening in closed societies.” That, he fears, is what dictators want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;c-foundation-line&quot; id=&quot;foundation-line&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;c-foundation-line__text&quot;&gt;This article is part of “The Speech Wars,” a project supported by the Charles Koch Foundation, the Reporters Committee for the Freedom of the Press, and the Fetzer Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;c-letters-cta&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;c-letters-cta__text&quot;&gt;We want to hear what you think about this article. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/contact/letters/&quot; class=&quot;c-letters-cta__link&quot;&gt;Submit a letter&lt;/a&gt; to the editor or write to letters@theatlantic.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;address id=&quot;article-writer-0&quot; class=&quot;c-article-writer lazyload&quot; data-author-id=&quot;23539&quot; data-include=&quot;css:https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/static/b/frontend/dist/theatlantic/css/components/article-writer.ccce81ff6d92.css&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/Person&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__bio&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/bernhard-warner/&quot; class=&quot;author-link&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;Bernhard Warner&lt;/a&gt; is a journalist based in Rome.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 03:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>anfilt</dc:creator>
<og:title>Tech Companies Are Deleting Evidence of War Crimes</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2019/05/facebook-algorithms-are-making-it-harder/588931/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2019/05/RTS6BJ1/facebook.jpg?1557324903</og:image>
<og:description>Algorithms that take down “terrorist” videos could hamstring efforts to bring human-rights abusers to justice.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2019/05/facebook-algorithms-are-making-it-harder/588931/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>For Better Computing, Liberate CPUs from Garbage Collection</title>
<link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/computing/hardware/this-little-device-relieves-a-cpu-from-its-garbage-collection-duties</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/computing/hardware/this-little-device-relieves-a-cpu-from-its-garbage-collection-duties</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzI5ODkzOA.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration of a CPU chained to a garbage can, and the chain is broken.&quot;/&gt; Illustration: IEEE Spectrum; icons: iStockphoto
&lt;section id=&quot;side-module&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;medium-top-ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-module&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;recommended-side&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor’s Picks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;article-rec&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzI0OTEwNw&quot; alt=&quot;Marea cable running out to ocean&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Squeezing More Data Through Less Fiber&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzI1NDYwNQ&quot; alt=&quot;Probe wires are attached to a green circuit board. An oscilloscope displays multiple traces in the background.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Very Noisy Signal: Intel Circuit Squashes Side-Channel Sniffing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzIxOTk4Ng&quot; alt=&quot;Silicon wafers&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What’s Better Than 40 GPU-based Computers? A Computer With 40 GPUs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;mobileHide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imgWrapper offsetLeft lt sm&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/static/journal-watch&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Journal Watch report logo, link to report landing page&quot; src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzI0MTAwOQ.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without you noticing (much), your computer is working hard in the background to organize its memory system. On top of its many tasks, a CPU must do something called “garbage collection,” whereby it identifies and deletes redundant or irrelevant data from applications to free up additional memory space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garbage collection is meant to spare programmers from having to manually address this unnecessary data, but the automated process that CPUs are tasked with consumes a lot of computational power—up to 10 percent or more of the total time a CPU spends on an application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While completing his PhD at the University of California, Berkeley, &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.eecs.berkeley.edu/~maas/&quot;&gt;Martin Maas&lt;/a&gt;, who now works at Google, designed a new type of device that relieves the CPU from its garbage collection duties. The design is described in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8695831&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; published 23 April in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/RecentIssue.jsp?punumber=40&quot;&gt;IEEE Micro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maas notes that CPUs, which have traditionally been assigned garbage collection, were never specifically designed for the task. “CPUs are built to be flexible and run a wide range of applications. As a result, they are relatively large and can take up a significant amount of power,” he explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, Maas and his colleagues created a compact accelerator unit that requires a small amount of chip area and power. It can be added to the CPU, similar to how many modern processor chips are integrated into graphics processing units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While the software application is running on the CPU, this unit sits on the side and performs garbage collection for the application,” says Maas. “In principle, this means that you could build a system where the software does not have to worry about garbage collection at all and just keeps using the available memory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notably, the accelerator unit does its garbage collection in a more efficient manner than how CPUs have traditionally done it. For instance, CPUs have to complete some garbage collection actions in a certain order, whereas the new accelerator unit exploits the fact that these actions do not need to be done sequentially. By doing a larger number of memory operations simultaneously, it is more efficient at garbage collection than a CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Maas’s team compared the accelerator to a small CPU core, they found that their accelerator had 18 times better performance given each device’s respective sizes. In terms of power consumption, they estimate that the accelerator reduces the energy required for garbage collection by 15 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delegating the task of garbage collection to an accelerator unit could enhance the productivity of computers. Maas points out that although the 10 percent of computation power that CPUs dedicate to garbage collection may not seem like a lot, globally this represents a large amount of computing resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also points out that many garbage collection mechanisms can result in unpredictable pauses, where the computer system stops for a brief moment to clean up its memory. “While you typically don’t notice it, this can be a problem in scenarios where you care about your system being very responsive, and programmers go out of their way to avoid these pauses, often at the cost of spending even more cycles on garbage collection,” he says. The new accelerator unit addresses both of these issues, paving the way for more efficient computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their paper, the researchers suggest that this new device could become a common component of future systems, bypassing the need for CPUs to be burdened by garbage collection.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 02:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mbroncano</dc:creator>
<og:title>For Better Computing, Liberate CPUs From Garbage Collection</og:title>
<og:url>https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/computing/hardware/this-little-device-relieves-a-cpu-from-its-garbage-collection-duties</og:url>
<og:description>An accelerator unit improves both the performance and efficiency of a system by taking over one simple task</og:description>
<og:image>https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzI5ODk3MQ.jpeg</og:image>
<og:type>blog-tech-talk</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/computing/hardware/this-little-device-relieves-a-cpu-from-its-garbage-collection-duties</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon S3 Path Deprecation Plan – The Rest of the Story</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/amazon-s3-path-deprecation-plan-the-rest-of-the-story/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/amazon-s3-path-deprecation-plan-the-rest-of-the-story/</guid>
<description>&lt;table id=&quot;amazon-polly-audio-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;amazon-polly-audio-tab&quot;&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;amazon-polly-by-tab&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/polly/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://a0.awsstatic.com/aws-blog/images/Voiced_by_Amazon_Polly_EN.png&quot; width=&quot;554&quot; height=&quot;56&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2019/ritchie_and_thompson_pdp11_1.jpeg&quot;/&gt;Last week we made a fairly quiet (too quiet, in fact) announcement of our plan to slowly and carefully deprecate the path-based access model that is used to specify the address of an object in an S3 bucket. I spent some time talking to the S3 team in order to get a better understanding of the situation in order to write this blog post. Here’s what I learned…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/amazon_s3/&quot;&gt;launched S3&lt;/a&gt; in early 2006. Jeff Bezos’ original spec for S3 was very succinct – he wanted &lt;code&gt;malloc&lt;/code&gt; (a key memory allocation function for C programs) for the Internet. From that starting point, S3 has grown to the point where it now stores many trillions of objects and processes millions of requests per second for them. Over the intervening 13 years, we have added many new storage options, features, and security controls to S3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Old vs. New&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;S3 currently supports two different addressing models: path-style and virtual-hosted style. Let’s take a quick look at each one. The path-style model looks like either this (the global S3 endpoint):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://s3.amazonaws.com/jbarr-public/images/ritchie_and_thompson_pdp11.jpeg&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://s3.amazonaws.com/jeffbarr-public/classic_amazon_door_desk.png&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or this (one of the regional S3 endpoints):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://s3-us-east-2.amazonaws.com/jbarr-public/images/ritchie_and_thompson_pdp11.jpeg&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://s3-us-east-2.amazonaws.com/jeffbarr-public/classic_amazon_door_desk.png&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;code&gt;jbarr-public&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;jeffbarr-public&lt;/code&gt; are bucket names; &lt;code&gt;/images/ritchie_and_thompson_pdp11.jpeg&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/classic_amazon_door_desk.png&lt;/code&gt; are object keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the objects are owned by distinct AWS accounts and are in different S3 buckets (and possibly in distinct AWS regions), both of them are in the DNS subdomain &lt;code&gt;s3.amazonaws.com&lt;/code&gt;. Hold that thought while we look at the equivalent virtual-hosted style references (although you might think of these as “new,” they have been around since at least 2010):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://jbarr-public.s3.amazonaws.com/images/ritchie_and_thompson_pdp11.jpeg&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://jeffbarr-public.s3.amazonaws.com/classic_amazon_door_desk.png&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These URLs reference the same objects, but the objects are now in distinct DNS subdomains (&lt;code&gt;jbarr-public.s3.amazonaws.com&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;jeffbarr-public.s3.amazonaws.com&lt;/code&gt;, respectively). The difference is subtle, but very important. When you use a URL to reference an object, DNS resolution is used to map the subdomain name to an IP address. With the path-style model, the subdomain is always &lt;code&gt;s3.amazonaws.com&lt;/code&gt; or one of the regional endpoints; with the virtual-hosted style, the subdomain is specific to the bucket. This additional degree of endpoint specificity is the key that opens the door to many important improvements to S3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out with the Old&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In response to feedback on the original deprecation plan that we announced last week, we are making an important change. Here’s the executive summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Plan&lt;/strong&gt; – Support for the path-style model ends on September 30, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revised Plan&lt;/strong&gt; – Support for the path-style model continues for buckets created on or before September 30, 2020. Buckets created after that date must be referenced using the virtual-hosted model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are moving to virtual-hosted references for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First,&lt;/strong&gt; anticipating a world with billions of buckets homed in many dozens of regions, routing all incoming requests directly to a small set of endpoints makes less and less sense over time. DNS resolution, scaling, security, and traffic management (including DDoS protection) are more challenging with this centralized model. The virtual-hosted model reduces the area of impact (which we call the “blast radius” internally) when problems arise; this helps us to increase availability and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second&lt;/strong&gt;, the team has a lot of powerful features in the works, many of which depend on the use of unique, virtual-hosted style subdomains. Moving to this model will allow you to benefit from these new features as soon as they are announced. For example, we are planning to deprecate some of the oldest security ciphers and versions (details to come later). The deprecation process is easier and smoother (for you and for us) if you are using virtual-hosted references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In With the New&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As just one example of what becomes possible when using virtual-hosted references, we are thinking about providing you with increased control over the security configuration (including ciphers and cipher versions) for each bucket. If you have ideas of your own, feel free to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moving Ahead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here are some things to know about our plans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identifying Path-Style References&lt;/strong&gt; – You can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/ServerLogs.html&quot;&gt;S3 Access Logs&lt;/a&gt; (look for the &lt;code&gt;Host Header&lt;/code&gt; field) and AWS &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/awscloudtrail/latest/userguide/logging-management-and-data-events-with-cloudtrail.html?shortFooter=true#logging-data-events-examples&quot;&gt;CloudTrail Data Events&lt;/a&gt; (look for the &lt;code&gt;host&lt;/code&gt; element of the &lt;code&gt;requestParameters&lt;/code&gt; entry) to identify the applications that are making path-style requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programmatic Access&lt;/strong&gt; – If your application accesses S3 using one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/tools/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS SDKs&lt;/a&gt;, you don’t need to do anything, other than ensuring that your SDK is current. The SDKs already use virtual-hosted references to S3, except if the bucket name contains one or more “.” characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bucket Names with Dots&lt;/strong&gt; – It is important to note that bucket names with “.” characters are perfectly valid for &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/WebsiteHosting.html&quot;&gt;website hosting&lt;/a&gt; and other use cases. However, there are some known issues with TLS and with SSL certificates. We are hard at work on a plan to support virtual-host requests to these buckets, and will share the details well ahead of September 30, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-Routable Names&lt;/strong&gt; – Some characters that are valid in the path component of a URL are not valid as part of a domain name. Also, paths are case-sensitive, but domain and subdomain names are not. We’ve been enforcing more stringent rules for new bucket names since last year. If you have data in a bucket with a non-routable name and you want to switch to virtual-host requests, you can use the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-amazon-s3-batch-operations/&quot;&gt;S3 Batch Operations&lt;/a&gt; feature to move the data. However, if this is not a viable option, please reach out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/premiumsupport/plans/developers/&quot;&gt;AWS Developer Support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation&lt;/strong&gt; – We are planning to update the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/s3/index.html&quot;&gt;S3 Documentation&lt;/a&gt; to encourage all developers to build applications that use virtual-host requests. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/VirtualHosting.html&quot;&gt;Virtual Hosting&lt;/a&gt; documentation is a good starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re Here to Help&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The S3 team has been working with some of our customers to help them to migrate, and they are ready to work with many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to make this deprecation smooth and uneventful, and we want to help minimize any costs you may incur! Please do not hesitate to reach out to us if you have questions, challenges, or concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffbarr&quot;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS – Stay tuned for more information on tools and other resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jeffbarr</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon S3 Path Deprecation Plan – The Rest of the Story | Amazon Web Services</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/amazon-s3-path-deprecation-plan-the-rest-of-the-story/</og:url>
<og:description>Last week we made a fairly quiet (too quiet, in fact) announcement of our plan to slowly and carefully deprecate the path-based access model that is used to specify the address of an object in an S3 bucket. I spent some time talking to the S3 team in order to get a better understanding of […]</og:description>
<og:image>https://d2908q01vomqb2.cloudfront.net/da4b9237bacccdf19c0760cab7aec4a8359010b0/2019/05/09/ritchie_and_thompson_pdp11_1.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/amazon-s3-path-deprecation-plan-the-rest-of-the-story/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>United Nations Expert Arrested in Tunisia for Using an RTL-SDR</title>
<link>https://www.rtl-sdr.com/united-nations-expert-arrested-in-tunisia-for-using-an-rtl-sdr/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.rtl-sdr.com/united-nations-expert-arrested-in-tunisia-for-using-an-rtl-sdr/</guid>
<description>&lt;header&gt;&lt;time datetime=&quot;2019-05-08T04:26:25+00:00&quot; pubdate=&quot;&quot;&gt;May 8, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;49.099946552646&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently several newspapers [&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.channelnewsasia.com/news/world/tunisia-s-arrest-of-un-expert-sparks-diplomatic-row-11495352&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CNA&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.france24.com/en/20190503-detention-un-investigator-moncef-kartas-tunisia-libya&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;France24&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/apr/30/un-expert-on-breaches-of-libya-arms-embargo-must-be-released-by-tunisia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Guardian&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.middleeastmonitor.com/20190502-tunisias-arrest-of-un-libya-expert-stirs-diplomatic-anger/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MEM&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.huffpostmaghreb.com/entry/arrestation-obscure-de-moncef-kartas-expert-onusien-disparu-a-son-arrive-a-laeroport-tunis-carthage_mg_5c9df018e4b0474c08cc7fff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HuffPostMG&lt;/a&gt;] have reported a story about a United Nations (UN) expert being arrested in Tunisia for having an RTL-SDR dongle. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://globalinitiative.net/experts/moncef-kartas/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dr. Moncef Kartas&lt;/a&gt; is a member of a UN panel of experts investigating violations of the UN arms embargo on Libya. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 26, 2019 Kartas was arrested on his arrival in Tunisia on suspicion of spying for &quot;unnamed foreign parties&quot;, and one of the key arguments being used against him is that he was in possession of and had used an RTL-SDR dongle. In the France24 article, they explain that he was using the RTL-SDR as part of his investigation for monitoring air traffic to Libya in an attempt to link flights against violations of the arms embargo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Kartas' business in Tunisia was to present his findings on the arms embargo violations, other experts believe that the arrest is politically motivated, and that ownership of the RTL-SDR for espionage is simply being used as an excuse. However, while the investigation continues Kartas remains in Jail, and in Tunisia a charge of espionage could be punishable by death. As Kartas holds UN diplomatic immunity, and as Tunisia is a member of the UN, the arrest and detainment is seen as illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that Kartas is safe and will be released soon. If you want to keep an eye on his story, there is a Twitter account called &quot;Free Moncef Kartas&quot; &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FreeMoncefK&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@FreeMoncefK&lt;/a&gt; that appears to be posting news articles and tweet about his arrest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtl-sdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/moncef-kartas-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-31120&quot; src=&quot;https://www.rtl-sdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/moncef-kartas-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Human Rights Watch Denounces the arrest of Moncef Kartas&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Human Rights Watch Denounces the arrest of Moncef Kartas [&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://directinfo.webmanagercenter.com/2019/03/29/tunisie-human-rights-watch-demande-la-liberation-de-moncef-kartas/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Photo Source&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;div class=&quot;swp_social_panel swp_horizontal_panel swp_flat_fresh swp_default_full_color swp_other_full_color swp_individual_full_color scale-100 scale-full_width&quot; data-min-width=&quot;1100&quot; data-float-color=&quot;#ffffff&quot; data-float=&quot;none&quot; data-float-mobile=&quot;none&quot; data-transition=&quot;slide&quot;&gt;





&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;swp_count&quot;&gt;598 &lt;span class=&quot;swp_label&quot;&gt;Shares&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author-label&quot;&gt;Written by&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtl-sdr.com/author/rtlsdr/&quot; title=&quot;Posts by admin&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot;&gt;admin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;categories&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;categories-label&quot;&gt;Posted in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtl-sdr.com/category/news/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;News&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtl-sdr.com/category/rtl-sdr/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;RTL-SDR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tags&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tags-label&quot;&gt;Tagged with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtl-sdr.com/tag/rtl-sdr-2/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;rtl-sdr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtl-sdr.com/tag/rtl2832/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;rtl2832&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtl-sdr.com/tag/rtl2832u/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;rtl2832u&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>newman8r</dc:creator>
<og:description>Recently several newspapers have reported a story about a United Nations (UN) expert being arrested in Tunisia for having an RTL-SDR dongle. Dr. Moncef Kartas is a member of a UN panel of experts investigating violations of the UN arms embargo on Libya.Â  On March 26, 2019 Kartas was arrested on his arrival in Tunisia on suspicion of spying for 'unnamed foreign parties', and one of the key arguments being used against him is that he was in possession of and had used an RTL-SDR dongle. In the France24 article, they explain that he was using the RTL-SDR as part</og:description>
<og:title>United Nations Expert Arrested in Tunisia for Using an RTL-SDR</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.rtl-sdr.com/united-nations-expert-arrested-in-tunisia-for-using-an-rtl-sdr/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.rtl-sdr.com/united-nations-expert-arrested-in-tunisia-for-using-an-rtl-sdr/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inheritance versus Composition</title>
<link>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/787800/b7f5351b3a41421a/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/787800/b7f5351b3a41421a/</guid>
<description>&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;Form&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; readability=&quot;3.2439024390244&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.7317073170732&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;9.2682926829268&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits for LWN subscribers&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary benefit from &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/subscribe/&quot;&gt;subscribing to LWN&lt;/a&gt; is helping to keep us publishing, but, beyond that, subscribers get immediate access to all site content and access to a number of extra site features. Please sign up today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;FeatureByline&quot;&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Jake Edge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;May 8, 2019
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Archives/ConferenceByYear/#2019-PyCon&quot;&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of &quot;inheritance&quot; is something that most students learn about early on when they are studying object-oriented programming (OOP). But one of the seminal books about OOP recommends favoring &quot;composition&quot; over inheritance. Ariel Ortiz came to PyCon in Cleveland, Ohio to describe the composition pattern and to explain the tradeoffs between using it and inheritance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ortiz is a full-time faculty member at Tecnológico de Monterrey, which is a private university in Mexico. He noted that the title of his talk, &quot;The Perils of Inheritance&quot;, sounded like &quot;clickbait&quot;; he jokingly suggested that perhaps he should have named it: &quot;4 dangers of inheritance; you won't believe number 3!&quot;. That elicited a good laugh, but he said that clickbait was not his intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has been teaching computer science for more than 30 years, using many languages, including Python. He likes Python and uses it for several courses, including data structures, web development, and compiler construction. He started with Python 2.0 in 2001 or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Definitions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to proceed, Ortiz said, he needed to define the two concepts at hand. &quot;Inheritance&quot; in the OOP sense starts with one class, known as the base class or superclass, and another class that is related to it. That second class is known as the derived class or subclass. The derived class has various attributes, such as variables and methods, that have come directly from the base class. Those attributes can be overridden in the derived class; new attributes can be added as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Composition&quot;, on the other hand, has the composite or wrapper class and a component that is being wrapped, sometimes known as the &quot;wrapee&quot;. Inheritance embodies the idea of an &quot;is a&quot; relationship, while composition creates a &quot;has a&quot; relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Python terms, you might have a &lt;tt&gt;Vehicle&lt;/tt&gt; class that is used as the base for a derived &lt;tt&gt;Bicycle&lt;/tt&gt; class, which would be created as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
    class Bicycle(Vehicle):
        pass
&lt;/pre&gt;
So, a &lt;tt&gt;Bicycle&lt;/tt&gt; &quot;is a&quot; &lt;tt&gt;Vehicle&lt;/tt&gt;. An example of composition might be a class &lt;tt&gt;Engine&lt;/tt&gt; that is used by another class:
&lt;pre&gt;
    class Car:
        def __init__(self):
            self.engine = Engine()
&lt;/pre&gt;
So, a &lt;tt&gt;Car&lt;/tt&gt; &quot;has a&quot; (an) &lt;tt&gt;Engine&lt;/tt&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/787879/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.lwn.net/images/2019/pycon-ortiz-sm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;5&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;[Ariel Ortiz]&quot; title=&quot;Ariel Ortiz&quot; width=&quot;239&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_Patterns&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design Patterns: Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented Software&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; book has suggested favoring composition over inheritance. At the time it was published, over 20 years ago, most OO programmers were favoring inheritance in languages like C++ and Java. But, even all these years later, inheritance is the first and main tool that programmers reach for as part of their code reuse strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inheritance and composition are two mechanisms for code reuse. Inheritance is &quot;white-box&quot; (or even better, &quot;crystal-box&quot;, Ortiz said) reuse. The derived class can see (too) many of the details of the base class. He prefers &quot;black-box&quot; reuse, which is what composition provides. The implementation of the component object is kept as a secret from the composite class. That secrecy is not because the object developer does not want people to know how it does its job, but because knowing those details is irrelevant. The component object can simply be used through its interface without needing to know anything further about its guts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some advantages to inheritance, however. It is the easiest way to reuse code, he said; in Python you just list the base classes that you want to inherit from in the derived class definition. It is also easy to change the inherited implementation and to add to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disadvantages of inheritance exist as well, of course. For one, the relationship between the base and derived classes is statically fixed; technically, that is not true for Python because of its dynamic nature, but is for C++ and Java. Inheritance supports weak encapsulation, so that derived classes can use parts of the base class in ways that the designer did not intend; also, name collisions can occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, derived classes get everything from the base class, even things that they don't want. As the creator of Erlang, Joe Armstrong, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.defprogramming.com/quotes-by/joe-armstrong/&quot;&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;You wanted a banana but what you got was a gorilla holding the banana and the entire jungle.&quot; And, finally, any changes in the base class impact all of the classes deriving from it. So, for example, adding a new method to the base class can cause name collisions all over the hierarchy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to show some of the differences between inheritance and composition, he presented two implementations of a simple last-in-first-out (LIFO) linked list that can be seen in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ariel-ortiz/pycon2019_perils_of_inheritance&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; (and in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vRNv4rLHUdM03wPOfe8GuqZQWjrVKfaDtULV2K_qVa4oHkR4WPfjsYaQy22sCuZcoAO26WToGcI7HME/pub&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YXiaWtc0cgE&quot;&gt;YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; of the talk). The code implements &lt;tt&gt;LinkedList&lt;/tt&gt; as one class along with an &lt;tt&gt;InsertCounter&lt;/tt&gt; class that is meant to count all of the insertions done to the list (it ignores removals from the list so the value is not the same as the length).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example is a bit contrived, perhaps, but it does show that changing the implementation of the &lt;tt&gt;insert_all()&lt;/tt&gt; method (which takes an iterable and adds each element to the list) in the base class actually affects the derived class. It leads to the count being incorrect in the &lt;tt&gt;InsertCounter&lt;/tt&gt; object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The composition version passes the &lt;tt&gt;LinkedList&lt;/tt&gt; into the initialization of the &lt;tt&gt;InsertCounter&lt;/tt&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
    counter = InsertCounter(LinkedList())
&lt;/pre&gt;
After that, the &lt;tt&gt;counter&lt;/tt&gt; object can be used in code that looks exactly the same as it was for the inheritance version:
&lt;pre&gt;
    counter.insert(42)
    counter.insert_all([1, 2, 3])
    counter.remove()
    print(f'len = {len(counter)}, counter = {counter.counter}')
&lt;/pre&gt;
The final print statement would yield:
&lt;pre&gt;
    len = 3, counter = 4
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as Ortiz pointed out, there is lots that &lt;tt&gt;InsertCounter&lt;/tt&gt; gets for free when it uses inheritance that needs to be explicitly added to the class when it uses composition. Many methods (e.g. &lt;tt&gt;remove()&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;clear()&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;__len__()&lt;/tt&gt;, etc.) that came with the &lt;tt&gt;LinkedList&lt;/tt&gt; via inheritance needed to be implemented for the class when it uses composition. On the other hand, the composed &lt;tt&gt;InsertCounter&lt;/tt&gt; was not affected by the changes to &lt;tt&gt;LinkedList&lt;/tt&gt;. But, on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Gripping_Hand&quot;&gt;gripping hand&lt;/a&gt;, the implementation of &lt;tt&gt;insert_all()&lt;/tt&gt; was, presumably deliberately, set up to be susceptible to this problem; a more realistic example would be hard to fit into the 30-minute slot for the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ortiz pointed to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/forwardable/&quot;&gt;&lt;tt&gt;forwardable&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/a&gt; module as a way to avoid having to implement all of that extra code for the composite object (&lt;tt&gt;InsertCounter&lt;/tt&gt;). The module makes it easy to delegate functionality from the composite object to the component. His last change to his example code used &lt;tt&gt;forwardable&lt;/tt&gt; in the &lt;tt&gt;InsertCounter&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several advantages to composition. The implementation of the component can be chosen at runtime because it can be passed in as part of the initialization of the composite object. Interface changes have a limited ripple effect. If the component interface changes, only the code in the composite object needs to change; users of the composite object are unaffected. With composition, one can create a class that has relationships with multiple components; this is a design pattern known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facade_pattern&quot;&gt;façade pattern&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are, of course, disadvantages to composition. It requires more code than inheritance, as we saw, Ortiz said. It is often more difficult to read the code using composition than it is to read code using inheritance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His talk was not meant to demonize inheritance, there are good reasons to use it sometimes. In particular, when the base and derived classes are in the same package and are under the control of the same developers, inheritance may well be the right choice. &quot;Inheritance is not wrong&quot;, he said, there are many circumstances where it makes sense, especially when there truly is an &quot;is a&quot; relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He ended with a Spanish question that was evidently made popular in a US advertisement: &quot;¿Por qué no los dos?&quot;, which means &quot;Why not both?&quot;. Inheritance and composition are both useful tools; developers should understand when to use each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[I would like to thank LWN's travel sponsor, the Linux Foundation, for travel assistance to Cleveland for PyCon.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;hr width=&quot;60%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Login/?target=/Articles/787800/&quot;&gt;Log in&lt;/a&gt; to post comments)</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 23:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chmaynard</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/787800/b7f5351b3a41421a/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Denver decriminalizes psychedelic mushrooms</title>
<link>https://www.denverpost.com/2019/05/08/denver-psychedelic-magic-mushroom/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.denverpost.com/2019/05/08/denver-psychedelic-magic-mushroom/</guid>
<description>&lt;img class=&quot; lazyautosizes lazyload&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.denverpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/AP_070802036452.jpg?fit=620%2C9999px&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;Magic mushrooms are seen at the ...&quot; width=&quot;2312&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.denverpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/AP_070802036452.jpg?fit=620%2C9999px&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.denverpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/AP_070802036452.jpg?fit=620%2C9999px&amp;amp;ssl=1 620w,https://i0.wp.com/www.denverpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/AP_070802036452.jpg?fit=310%2C9999px&amp;amp;ssl=1 310w&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peter Dejong, The Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;
Psychedelic mushrooms are seen at the Procare farm in Hazerswoude, central Netherlands, in this 2007 file photo.
&lt;p&gt;Denver is poised to become the first city in the nation to effectively decriminalize psychedelic mushrooms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.denverpost.com/2019/05/07/psychedelic-magic-mushrooms-denver-election/&quot;&gt;closing an early vote deficit Tuesday night&lt;/a&gt; and early Wednesday, final unofficial results &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.denvergov.org/electionresults#/results/20190507&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; late in the afternoon showed a reversal of fortune — with Initiative 301 set to pass narrowly with 50.6 percent of the vote. The total stands at 89,320 votes in favor and 87,341 against, a margin of 1,979.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Denver Elections Division will continue accepting military and overseas ballots, but typically those numbers are small. Results will be certified May 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s been one hell of a 21 and a half hours,” Initiative 301 campaign manager Kevin Matthews said. “If these results hold, this is an example of the absurd comedy of the great metaphor. Against all odds, we prevailed. This is what happens when a small team of dedicated and passionate people unite under a single idea to create change.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RELATED:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.denverpost.com/2019/05/08/find-out-who-your-new-denver-city-council-member-is-or-if-you-have-to-vote-again/&quot;&gt;Find out who your new Denver City Council member is — or if you have to vote again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denver’s vote &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/crime-law/2019/05/08/denver-voters-apparently-reject-decriminalization-magic-mushrooms/?utm_term=.16a348698b58&quot;&gt;has attracted national attention&lt;/a&gt;. While efforts are afoot to get psilocybin-related measures on the ballot in Oregon and California in 2020, Denver hosted the first-ever U.S. popular vote on the matter, according to organizers. An earlier effort in California last year failed to qualify for the ballot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Initiative 301 attracted no organized opposition, critics of Colorado’s legalization of marijuana lamented the prospect of Denver blazing yet another trail they see as misguided and potentially harmful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measure essentially tells police to look the other way on adult psilocybin use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’ll see what the final numbers are, but we’re a little stunned to see a 7,000-vote flip overnight on that,” said Jeff Hunt, director of the Centennial Institute at Colorado Christian University, who &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffhunt/status/1126259864978612225&quot;&gt;initially questioned on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; whether vote-tampering was involved. “We’ll continue to fight the growing drug culture. Denver’s becoming the illicit drug capital of the world. The larger issue here is not good for our city.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added: “Marijuana has brought more problems than it’s solved to our city and our state, and if we continue to go down this track, we’re going to continue to see Colorado get in worse and worse shape.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supporters extolled emerging research showing potential health benefits with psychedelic mushrooms. The measure likely was put over the top by younger voters, who tend to cast their ballots closer to or on Election Day, even though all registered voters receive their ballots in the mail about three weeks earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last fall, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration &lt;a href=&quot;https://newatlas.com/psilocybin-magic-mushrooms-depression-fda-breakthrough-therapy/56928/&quot;&gt;granted psilocybin “breakthrough therapy” designation&lt;/a&gt; for its potential to help with treatment-resistant depression, a status that &lt;a href=&quot;https://reason.com/2018/10/25/fda-recognizes-psilocybin-as-breakthroug/&quot;&gt;speeds up the development and review process&lt;/a&gt; for a medicine containing the substance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What Initiative 301 tells police to do&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As written, I-301 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.denverpost.com/2019/02/19/psychedelic-mushrooms-denver/&quot;&gt;directs police via ordinance&lt;/a&gt; to treat enforcement of laws against possession of psilocybin mushrooms as their lowest priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot; lazyautosizes lazyload&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.denverpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/magicmushrooms-021319-cha-050.jpg?fit=620%2C9999px&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;Kevin Matthews is leading the decriminalization ...&quot; width=&quot;8014&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.denverpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/magicmushrooms-021319-cha-050.jpg?fit=620%2C9999px&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.denverpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/magicmushrooms-021319-cha-050.jpg?fit=620%2C9999px&amp;amp;ssl=1 620w,https://i0.wp.com/www.denverpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/magicmushrooms-021319-cha-050.jpg?fit=310%2C9999px&amp;amp;ssl=1 310w&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hyoung Chang, The Denver Post&lt;/p&gt;
Kevin Matthews led the decriminalization campaign for magic mushrooms in Denver. He was photographed on Feb. 12, 2019.
&lt;p&gt;It’s similar to decriminalization measures approved by Denver voters for marijuana years before Colorado’s Amendment 64 won statewide approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our victory here is a clear signal to the rest of the country that we’re ready for a broader conversation around psilocybin and its potential benefits,” said Matthews, a 33-year-old stay-at-home dad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychedelic mushrooms still would remain illegal to buy, sell or possess, with the latter crime a felony that carries a potential punishment of up to a year in prison and a fine. But Initiative 301 backers hope to lower the risk users face of getting caught with mushrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past marijuana efforts are instructive, though. Denver voters signed off on decriminalization measures in 2005 and 2007, but that didn’t stop police from enforcing the law — though drug law-liberalization advocates say the public discussion prompted by the ballot initiatives helped pave the way for statewide legalization in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ll say this: We’re looking forward to creating a positive relationship with city officials,” Matthews said. “We have the resources ready to make sure the Justice Department, the (district attorney’s) office and the Denver Police Department have the education they need to implement this in a way that’s fair.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initiative 301 requires the city to create a panel to monitor the effects and implementation of the ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tide turned Wednesday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some national media outlets as well as the Centennial Institute wrongly called I-301 a bust late Tuesday, based on the early results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;related right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the gap tightened throughout the night. By 1 a.m. Wednesday, when Denver Elections put out its last release before pausing counting for the night, the measure still was losing by 3.4 percentage points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It overcame that margin in the next — and final — round of results shortly after 4 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 22:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Denver first in U.S. to decriminalize psychedelic mushrooms</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.denverpost.com/2019/05/08/denver-psychedelic-magic-mushroom/</og:url>
<og:description>Denver is poised to become the first city in the nation to effectively decriminalize psychedelic mushrooms after final ballot-counting flipped Initiative 301’s margin in favor of narrow passa…</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.denverpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/AP_070802036452.jpg?w=1024&amp;h=690</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.denverpost.com/2019/05/08/denver-psychedelic-magic-mushroom/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“Users want control” is a shoulder shrug</title>
<link>https://www.ianbicking.org/blog/2019/04/users-want-control-is-a-shrug.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ianbicking.org/blog/2019/04/users-want-control-is-a-shrug.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Making the claim “users want control” is the same as saying you don’t know what users want, you don’t know what is good, and you don’t know what their goals are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first started thinking about this during the debate over what would become the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patient_Protection_and_Affordable_Care_Act&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ACA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The rhetoric was filled with this idea that people want choice in their medical care: &lt;em&gt;people want control&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No! People want &lt;strong&gt;good health care&lt;/strong&gt;. If they don’t trust systems to provide them good health care, if they don’t trust their providers to understand their priorities, then &lt;em&gt;choice&lt;/em&gt; is the fallback: it’s how you work the system when the system isn’t working for you. And it sucks! Here you are, in the middle of some health issue, with treatments and symptoms and the rest of your life duties, and now you have to become a researcher on top of it? But the politicians and the pundits could not stop talking about control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt; is what you need when you want something and it won’t happen on its own. But (usually) it’s not control you want, it’s just a means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when we say &lt;em&gt;users want control over X&lt;/em&gt; – their privacy, their security, their data, their history – we are first acknowledging that current systems act against users, but we aren’t proposing any real solution. We’re avoiding even talking about the problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, we say “users want control over their privacy,” but what people really want is some subset of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;To avoid embarrassment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To avoid persecution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;… sometimes for doing illegal and wrong things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To keep from having the creeping sensation they left something sitting out that they didn’t want to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They want to make some political statement against surveillance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They want to keep things from the prying eyes of those close to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They want to avoid being manipulated by bad-faith messaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s no easy answers, not everyone holds all these desires, but these are concrete ways of thinking about what people want. They don’t all point in the same direction. (And then consider the complex implications of someone else talking about you!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some cases when a person really does want control. If the person wants to determine their own path, if &lt;strong&gt;having choice is itself a personal goal&lt;/strong&gt;, then you need control. That’s a goal about &lt;em&gt;who you are&lt;/em&gt; not just &lt;em&gt;what you get&lt;/em&gt;. It’s worth identifying moments when this is important. But if a person does not pay attention to something then that person probably does not identify with the topic and is not seeking control over it. “Privacy advocates” pay attention to privacy, and attain a sense of identity from the very act of being mindful of their own privacy. Everyone else does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s think about another example: &lt;em&gt;users want control over their data&lt;/em&gt;. What are some things they want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;They don’t want to lose their data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They don’t want their data used to hold them hostage (e.g., to a subscription service)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They don’t want to delete data and have it still reappear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They want to use their data however they want, but more likely they want their data available for use by some other service or tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They feel it’s unfair if their data is used for commercial purposes without any compensation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are offended if their data is used to manipulate themselves or others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They don’t want their data used against them in manipulative ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They want to have shared ownership of data with other people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They want to prevent unauthorized or malicious access to their data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again these motivations are often against each other. A person wants to be able to copy their data between services, but also delete their data permanently and completely. People don’t want to lose their data, but having personal control over your data is a great way to lose it, or even to lose control over it. The professionalization and centralization of data management by services has mostly improved access control and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we simply say &lt;em&gt;users want control&lt;/em&gt; it’s giving up on understanding people’s specific desires. Still it’s not exactly wrong: it’s reasonable to assume people will use control to achieve their desires. But if, as technologists, we can’t map functionality to desire, it’s a bit of a stretch to imagine everyone else will figure it out on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 21:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>collinmanderson</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ianbicking.org/blog/2019/04/users-want-control-is-a-shrug.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: 2D Graphics on Modern GPU</title>
<link>https://raphlinus.github.io/rust/graphics/gpu/2019/05/08/modern-2d.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://raphlinus.github.io/rust/graphics/gpu/2019/05/08/modern-2d.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Is the traditional 2D imaging model nearing the end of its usefulness, or does it have a shiny future in the “modern graphics” world? I spent a week on a research retreat in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stonesthrowfarmca.com/&quot;&gt;cottage in the woods&lt;/a&gt; to answer this question, as it shapes the future of UI toolkits. Performant UI &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; use GPU effectively, and it’s increasingly common to write UI directly in terms of GPU rendering, without a 2D graphics API as in the intermediate layer. Is that the future, or perhaps a mistake?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found that, if you can depend on modern compute capabilities, it seems quite viable to implement 2D rendering directly on GPU, with very promising quality and performance. The prototype I built strongly resembles a software renderer, just running on an outsized multicore GPU with wide SIMD vectors, much more so than rasterization-based pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing a 2D renderer is a fairly ambitious project, doubly so to make it run efficiently on GPU. I deliberately reduced the scope of the project in a number of ways to make it viable. Most importantly, I targeted &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; Metal 2.1, which is only a year old and only at &lt;a href=&quot;http://gs.statcounter.com/macos-version-market-share/desktop/worldwide&quot;&gt;42.5% share&lt;/a&gt; among worldwide macOS users. Thus, I am targeting the near future of GPU and ignoring the past. My faithful readers will no doubt be curious how much of this work can be adapted to older GPUs, but I believe that’s a much more complex question, and one I deliberately did not address. (Other work like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pcwalton/pathfinder&quot;&gt;PathFinder&lt;/a&gt; is more appropriate.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I think the capabilities of Metal 2.1 are fairly mainstream and more so in coming years. From my perspective, it finally lets us program a GPU as if it were a big SIMD computer, which is basically what it’s been under the hood for a long time. Looking at newer features in, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.nvidia.com/cuda-toolkit/whatsnew&quot;&gt;CUDA 10&lt;/a&gt;, I don’t see anything that would profoundly change the way I would approach this problem. I believe this is a very attractive target for research and practice in efficient GPU implementation of classical algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not surprising that 2D graphics can be efficiently implemented on GPU. The excellent 2014 &lt;a href=&quot;http://w3.impa.br/~diego/projects/GanEtAl14/&quot;&gt;Massively-Parallel Vector Graphics&lt;/a&gt; was a major inspiration to this work, and there have been follow-ups such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://kunzhou.net/zjugaps/pathrendering/&quot;&gt;Li 2016&lt;/a&gt; that promise even more performance. But both of these papers seemed very complex and focused narrowly on path rendering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had great fun implementing my prototype and learned a lot. Along the way I kept a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1LILagXyJgYtlm6y83x1Mc2VoNfOcvW_ZiCldZbs4yO8/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;notes document&lt;/a&gt; that recounts some of my struggles and touches on some deeper topics that I will only briefly touch on in this blog post. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/linebender/piet-metal&quot;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; is available and could be fun to play with or look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll stress again that this is a research prototype, not a finished product. The most promising use case for the work is likely CAD tools, where there might be quite complex scenes and it’s not necessarily practical to organize the UI drawing around GPU primitives (as opposed to 3D games, for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-architecture&quot;&gt;The architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rendering starts with a “scene graph,” which is an on-GPU serialization of 2D drawing operations. It has a tree structure, in that operations like clipping are represented as a node with children; in the case of clipping, one child for the clip mask and another for the contents being clipped. It also has a graph structure, in that multiple instances can be shared by reference (with appropriate transform nodes to change their position). (Note: I didn’t get around to implementing much of the graph structure, but the prototype is designed to accommodate it without much trouble. I’m describing it anyway because it’s important to the motivation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The imaging model allows per-pixel operations only; operations like blur are purposefully excluded. Thus, a simplistic approach to parallel rendering would be for each pixel in the target framebuffer to traverse the scene graph, applying the computation at each node (each of which can be seen as a small functional program), and finally writing the pixel color computed at the root node. That approach is of course quite inefficient, but forms the basis of what the code actually does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve performance, the code divides the target framebuffer into fixed size &lt;em&gt;tiles,&lt;/em&gt; currently 16x16 pixels each. There are two passes, a &lt;em&gt;tiling pass&lt;/em&gt; that creates a command list for each tile, and a &lt;em&gt;rendering pass&lt;/em&gt; that consumes the command list, evaluating all 256 pixels of the tile in parallel, each pixel sequentially evaluating the commands for the tile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the approach to tiling is similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pcwalton/pathfinder&quot;&gt;PathFinder&lt;/a&gt;, but with important differences in the details. PathFinder renders intermediate alpha masks to a mask texture buffer, requiring a write and a read of global device memory, but I do all the blending in local memory in the rendering shader, as in &lt;a href=&quot;http://w3.impa.br/~diego/projects/GanEtAl14/&quot;&gt;MPVG&lt;/a&gt;. Minimizing global memory traffic is a major shared theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 16x16 tile should be close to the sweet spot. It results in 128x96 (12k total) tiles for a typical 2048x1536 window. It’s not a huge amount of work to generate the tiles, but with fewer tiles it would be harder to exploit parallelism in the tiling phase. Similarly, if graphic elements are much smaller than the tile size, there would be wasted work during rendering, as (for the most part) the entire tile needs to be rendered for any element that touches the tile. But again, 16x16 is a good size for a threadgroup dispatch, to exploit parallelism within the tile, and the savings from the leftover parts of a tile would be offset by per-tile overhead as tiles get smaller. It’s always possible to tune such things, but it’s not reasonable to expect any big wins. (I will note, though, that &lt;a href=&quot;http://w3.impa.br/~diego/projects/GanEtAl14/&quot;&gt;MPVG&lt;/a&gt; uses a quadtree structure, which basically amounts to adapting tile size to the workload. There are potential savings, but I also think it adds a lot to their overall complexity.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rendering kernel (similar to a fragment shader) is fairly straightforward - it’s basically just computing signed area coverage for fills, distance fields for strokes, texture sampling for images and pre-rendered glyphs, and blends for clipping and compositing. The functional program represented by the scene graph is flattened into a linear sequence of operations, filtered of course to only those elements that touch the tile. For blend groups, nesting in the scene graph is represented by push/pop operations, with an explicit, local stack. (Again disclosure: I didn’t get too far into actually implementing blend groups, but it should be easy to see how they’d work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, most of the interesting parts are in tiling. That’s all about efficiently traversing the scene graph, quickly skipping over parts of the graph that don’t touch the tile being generated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the simplistic rendering strategy above, a simple approach to tile generation would be to have a thread per tile (~12k threads), each of which sequentially traverses the scene graph. That’s a lot less work than doing a per-pixel traversal, but is still not great. As I’ll describe in the next section, the key to performance is a good serialization format for the scene graph, and SIMD techniques for extracting more parallelism from the traversal. The basic structure is there, though; the traversal of the scene graph and generation of tiles is at heart sequential, not relying on tricky GPU-compute techniques such as sorting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;serialization&quot;&gt;Serialization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s often said that GPU is bad at data structures, but I’d turn that around. Most, but not all, data structures are bad at GPU. An extreme example is a linked list, which is still considered reasonable on CPU, and is the backbone of many popular data structures. Not only does it force sequential access, but it also doesn’t hide the latency of global memory access, which can be as high as 1029 cycles on a modern GPU such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1804.06826.pdf&quot;&gt;Volta&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well known to game developers, what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; efficient on GPU is a structure-of-arrays approach. In particular, the tiling phase spends a lot of time looking at bounding boxes, to decide what belongs in each tile. Each group node in the graph has an array of bounding boxes of its children, 8 bytes each, and a separate array for the child contents. The core of the tiling pass is consuming those bounding box arrays, only dropping down to traverse the child when there’s an intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, the serialization format is not that exotic, broadly similar to &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.github.io/flatbuffers/&quot;&gt;FlatBuffers&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://capnproto.org/&quot;&gt;Cap’n Proto&lt;/a&gt;. As a digression, I find it amusing that the word for packing a data structure into a byte buffer is “serialization” even when it’s designed to be accessed in parallel. Maybe we should come up with a better term, as “parallel-friendly serialization” is an oxymoron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I mostly focused on parallel read access, I’m also intrigued by the possibility of &lt;em&gt;generating&lt;/em&gt; the scene graph in parallel, which obviously means doing allocations in a multithread-friendly way. Nical has a good &lt;a href=&quot;https://nical.github.io/posts/rust-2d-graphics-02.html&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on some of the issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;exploiting-simd-for-bounding-box-culling&quot;&gt;Exploiting SIMD for bounding box culling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we get to the heart of the algorithm: going through an array of bounding boxes, looking for those that intersect a subset of tiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core computational model provided by shader languages is an independent thread per tiny grain of work (vertex, fragment, etc.), and the compiler and hardware conspire mightily in support of that illusion. You’ll hear numbers like 2560 cores, and it’s very difficult to wrap one’s mind around that. For workloads typical of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shadertoy.com/&quot;&gt;shadertoy&lt;/a&gt;, you don’t have to think too much about it, it magically gets through an impressive amount of computation per pixel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality is very different. It’s also useful to think of a GPU as a SIMD computer with dozens of cores, each of which has a SIMD width of hundreds of bits. If you write code optimized for, say, a 24 core computer with 512 bit SIMD, or 12 cores x 1024 bits wide, that’s likely to run well on an Intel Iris 640. That’s not actually what it is, but the details are shrouded in mystery, so I tell myself these simplified stories to keep myself comfortable. Note that these numbers aren’t that different than a high end desktop or server chip. (Also see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1LILagXyJgYtlm6y83x1Mc2VoNfOcvW_ZiCldZbs4yO8/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;notes doc&lt;/a&gt; for why I have two different numbers here, kind of a fun story that kept me up a bit one night)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In keeping with the 3D graphics tradition of clear and consistent naming, the SIMD concept is called SIMD groups on Metal, warps on Nvidia, wavefronts on AMD, and subgroups on Vulkan. (But note that there is an important distinction between pure SIMD and the “SIMT” concept in newer Nvidia models, see this presentation on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irisa.fr/alf/downloads/collange/talks/collange_warp_synchronous_gpu17.pdf&quot;&gt;cooperative groups&lt;/a&gt; for more detail.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for running the tiling kernel, instead of having a few hundred or a couple thousand independent threads traversing the bounding box array, there are actually a few dozen “SIMD groups”, each of which is, say, 16 wide. In the simple version of the code, all the ALU’s in a SIMD group load the same bounding box, test against it, and go to the next iteration of the loop. We want to do better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current code gives the 16-wide SIMD group responsibility for a block of tiles (16 wide, 1 tall, in a typical threadgroup geometry). On an iteration of the loop, each ALU loads a &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; bounding box, then tests for intersection against a 256x16 region of the target frame buffer. It then shares the result of that test with the other ALU’s in the SIMD group (using the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;simd_ballot&lt;/code&gt; intrinsic). There’s another pass with finer grained checking, but in the common case where no bounding boxes intersect the 256x16 region, it can immediately go to the next iteration. This is literally a 16x increase in theoretical bandwidth for consuming the bounding boxes, and I see that borne out by measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In similar fashion, the SIMD approach crunches through the segments of filled and stroked paths, quickly sifting to assign them to the relevant tiles. Inside the tiler are a number of other optimizations; for example tiles in the interior of a filled path just get a constant color. (This logic is similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pcwalton/pathfinder&quot;&gt;PathFinder&lt;/a&gt; and was inspired by it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performance is impressive. I haven’t done careful benchmarking yet, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Ghostscript_Tiger.svg&quot;&gt;Ghostscript tiger&lt;/a&gt;, the standard benchmark of 2D graphics renders in a 2048x1536 window in 2.8ms of GPU time on Intel Iris 640 integrated graphics. (A fun fact, this is a 500x speedup over results I got &lt;a href=&quot;https://levien.com/svg/&quot;&gt;20 years ago&lt;/a&gt;). More careful empirical evaluation is needed, especially as methodology of GPU performance can be quite tricky. Also, there are a bunch more things that can be done to improve performance further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, I have confidence that it will render any reasonable UI scene, up to a high level of complexity, smoothly at 60 frames per second. It should be especially nice for data visualization, CAD, and of course tools for graphic artists. An especially nice feature is that the GPU does basically all the heavy lifting, freeing up the CPU for application logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;imaging-model&quot;&gt;Imaging model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prototype mostly does just does fills and strokes of vector paths, but the &lt;em&gt;architecture&lt;/em&gt; of the renderer is designed to accommodate a full 2D graphics imaging model. Basically, it can handle any operation that works on a pixel at a time. Those include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Soft masking and blending&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The PhotoShop &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blend_modes&quot;&gt;blend modes&lt;/a&gt; (also present in PDF and other imaging models)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tone mapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color space conversions, including CMYK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Halftone effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gradients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A wide variety of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ronja-tutorials.com/2018/11/10/2d-sdf-basics.html&quot;&gt;distance-field rendering techniques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Probably the most important effect that is not included in this set is image-based blurring. That said, it is possible to get analytic or approximate blurring of many shapes, for example this &lt;a href=&quot;http://madebyevan.com/shaders/fast-rounded-rectangle-shadows/&quot;&gt;approximate blurred rounded rectangle&lt;/a&gt;, which can easily be adapted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m particularly interested in the rendering quality. All antialiasing and blending in the prototype is done in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://linebender.gitbook.io/linebender-graphics-wiki/&quot;&gt;linear sRGB&lt;/a&gt; colorspace, which makes for especially clear vector shapes without rope-like visual artifacts. In the notes document are more ideas about improving distance field rendering (hint: never use smoothstep).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m mostly focused on making high resolution (4k and even higher) rendering fast, but an intriguing topic is to lavish compute power on making the finest possible images for lower resolution. One idea is to apply RGB &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subpixel_rendering&quot;&gt;subpixel rendering&lt;/a&gt; techniques (similar to ClearType), but for general vector graphics, not just fonts. There are more ideas (including a link to a code sketch) in the notes doc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;implications&quot;&gt;Implications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2D rendering engine is a fairly central component of any graphics-intensive application. Its performance and quality characteristics can have profound implication for the rest of the system. As one example, if rendering is very slow, the system around it develops workarounds like rendering layers to textures and compositing them, which generally solves smooth scrolling but creates other problems. This work reopens the question: what should a system look like when rendering is really fast?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such related topic is immediate mode vs retained mode UI, a longstanding controversy, with passionate defenders on both sides. To be very clear, this renderer will work well with both. But I think there’s a special affinity for retained mode, as I hope to explain briefly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very often in UI, the biggest challenge in performance is traversing the entire UI state in order to determine the new appearance. Immediate mode GUI solves this by writing the UI logic in a fast language, so that it reliably comes in under the time budget. But another approach is to minimize the work by only touching the parts of UI state that actually changed. In classical 2D, that often manifests as “damage regions,” so that only a subregion of the screen is repainted. That’s not very effective for scrolling or things like animation of layer opacity, and many people believe that damage regions are obsolete (I disagree, mostly for reasons of power consumption, but that’s a story for another day).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A related approach is to retain parts of the scene graph (also commonly called “display list”), updating only those that have actually changed. Then the renderer redraws the screen based on the updated graph. Updated parameters can include translation (for scrolling) or alpha, so only a tiny amount of data need be uploaded to the GPU from frame to frame. &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutter.dev/&quot;&gt;Flutter&lt;/a&gt; is a good modern approach to this, and its “layers” are one of the keys to its performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The piet-metal approach is designed to support this approach, by hosting the scene graph on the GPU, so that the process of painting a frame does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; rely on replaying the scene graph data structure resident on the CPU into GPU drawing commands. For simple scenes, this may not matter much, but for very complex visuals the difference might be significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;discussion&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week in the woods was extremely rewarding, and I recommend the format. Stones Throw Farm was a great setting for the research retreat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, what I have now is a research prototype. It only implements a subset of the imaging model, and only works on relatively recent GPU hardware. But I believe it has some very appealing properties, making it especially useful as the groundwork for next-generation UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the venerable 2D imaging model has lots of life left in it, as there is compelling evidence (not just my own work) that it can be implemented efficiently on GPU. I did the work largely to inform what to include and exclude in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/linebender/piet&quot;&gt;piet&lt;/a&gt; API - anything that &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; efficiently be implemented on GPU is off the table. I plan to go forward on the existing piet/druid plans, confident that I can use existing platform-based drawing libraries like Direct2D for now, and that highly performant GPU-based implementations are at least possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work has benefitted from discussions with many, though of course the mistakes I’ve made are my own. In particular, thanks to Allan MacKinnon and his Spinel work for inspiring me to consider compute for rendering, Patrick Walton for many stimulating discussions, and Brian Merchant (our Google Summer of Code student on this project) for asking provoking questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 20:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>raphlinus</dc:creator>
<og:title>2D Graphics on Modern GPU</og:title>
<og:description>Is the traditional 2D imaging model nearing the end of its usefulness, or does it have a shiny future in the “modern graphics” world? I spent a week on a research retreat in a cottage in the woods to answer this question, as it shapes the future of UI toolkits. Performant UI must use GPU effectively, and it’s increasingly common to write UI directly in terms of GPU rendering, without a 2D graphics API as in the intermediate layer. Is that the future, or perhaps a mistake?</og:description>
<og:url>https://raphlinus.github.io/rust/graphics/gpu/2019/05/08/modern-2d.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://raphlinus.github.io/rust/graphics/gpu/2019/05/08/modern-2d.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>