<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>First-party isolation in Firefox: what breaks if you enable it?</title>
<link>https://www.ctrl.blog/entry/firefox-fpi</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ctrl.blog/entry/firefox-fpi</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;First-Party Isolation (FPI) is an optional privacy feature built-in to Firefox that enforces stricter security policies to block tracking between websites. Essentially, every website you visit will store data separately and isolated from every other website you visit. So what could go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-7416&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First-Party Isolation offers the same privacy protection within one browser as you would get if you open one website in Safari (or another web browser) and then open another website in Firefox. Network connections, caches of different types, cookies and other persistent data stores would work as normal but there is no known way for one website to save data in a way that could be read by any other website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a more complete protection against cross-origin tracking between different websites by traditional means like the option for disabling third-party cookies and storage found in most web browsers. FPI was originally designed for use in the privacy oriented Tor browser, which is based on Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla have been really quiet about this feature. It was first introduced in Firefox 55 after years of development work, but wasn’t mentioned in the official release notes or marketing. I’m not sure whether that is because Mozilla consider it unsafe, unpractical, or don’t want to commit to maintain the feature in future releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;First-Party Isolation is a fundamental change in how the web browser operates and it breaks many assumptions made by web developers. If you want to enable the feature and gain better privacy than you also have to pay the price of breaking those assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of the types of problems you can expect to run into with FPI enabled:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Third-party login failures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla ran a study where they looked at how many issues people would run into if they enabled one of eight different privacy-enhancing settings in Firefox. The study found that people in the group with First-Party Isolation enabled reported the most number of issues out of any of the test groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;boxa adu-in&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt; &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle adu-fb adu-fr&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-1835247814769107&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;rectangle&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;9890932244&quot;/&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The same study found that people ran into trouble with Facebook and Google domains, and had trouble login in to websites. Both Facebook and Google provide authentication and login services for other websites that don’t always work as expected when you enable FPI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the implementation, you click on a login button on a website which opens a window with either Facebook or Google. This new window is opened in a new security context and is isolated from the originating website. Users can poke a hole in the isolation barrier by changing the &lt;samp&gt;privacy.firstparty.isolate.restrict_opener_access&lt;/samp&gt; option to &lt;samp&gt;false&lt;/samp&gt;, which allows for some communication between the login provider and the original website. However, changing this option only makes the login break later in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can sometimes work around these issues to some degree. E.g. a comment form from Disqus or Facebook is loaded inside a frame on the original page. By right-clicking on the frame and choosing &lt;kbd&gt;This Frame: Open Frame In a New Tab&lt;/kbd&gt;, you’ll end up on a new frame with just the comment form with the origin as either a Disqus or Facebook domaim. By loading the frame from the original origin, you’ll have access to the cookies for that origin and can login and comment as per normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fully resolve this issue, the login service providers has to change their products to work with stricter origin controls. Unless Mozilla were to enable FPI by default, I doubt any company will invest any time or money in fixing these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;No migration path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loose all your cookies, caches, and data stores when you first enable First-Party Isolation in Firefox. Firefox doesn’t record the origin of data before enabling the setting, so existing user data has to go when switching to a stricter origin-policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox can’t record this data before isolating websites from each other as it otherwise wouldn’t know which changes were made by which website if multiple websites had access to read and write to the same data stores. It’s kind of an unavoidable problem, as I see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial loss of logins, website settings, and avalanche of reappearing cookie consent toolbars could help explain for the higher number of issue reports in Mozilla’s study. Mozilla doesn’t mention this issue specifically in any publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;More CAPTCHAs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I noted only recently, Google reCAPTCHA has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ctrl.blog/entry/coinhive-captcha&quot; title=&quot;“On using Coinhive CAPTCHA instead of reCAPTCHA by Google”&quot;&gt;99,3 % global marketshare&lt;/a&gt; in CAPTCHA services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No CAPTCHA reCAPTCHA uses Google’s knowledge and insights about you from tracking you around the web to determine whether you’re a computer or a human; instead of asking you to pass a cognitive tests. Google seem to have &lt;strong&gt;reduced confidence in their ability to identify you as a human&lt;/strong&gt; with reduced tracking and an unusual number of unique users (every website is assigned different tracking/user ID/user instead of sharing the same ID) from your IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my own experience, I’ve had to spend more time and energy trying to manually solve the harder reCAPTCHA options rather than bypassing it altogether with Google’s No CAPTCHA reCAPTCHA after enabling First-Party Isolation in Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Less shared caching means more data usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caching is good. It means you don’t have to download the same font or JavaScript library multiple times if it’s already stored in your browser’s cache. Firefox will still cache content with First-Party Isolation enabled, however it will do so far less efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, your browser will download one copy of a specific font or JavaScript library once from a content-delivery network (CDN) which can be shared between multiple websites. FPI disrupts this causing the browser to download a new copy per website instead of relying of its own shared cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox doesn’t set aside more disk storage space for its cache when enabling FPI. The browser thus have to store multiple copies of the same files in the same amount of disk space; which causes reduced efficiency for prioritizing what to keep in the cache and what to delete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can somewhat reduce the impact of this for some types of common JavaScript libraries by installing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ctrl.blog/entry/decentraleyes-cdn&quot; title=&quot;“Embed a JavaScript CDN in your web browser with Decentraleyes”&quot;&gt;Decentraleyes extension&lt;/a&gt;. This extension acts as a local CDN provider that can bypass the First-Party Isolation by serving the content from the extension rather than a remote CDN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your location and internet connection, enabling First-Party Isolation in Firefox may significantly increase costs and slow down page loading times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Can’t log-in to many extensions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extension API for OAuth2 logins, &lt;code&gt;browser.identify.launchWebAuthFlow&lt;/code&gt;, fails to inform extensions about whether logins failed or succeeded. Extensions will wait for login attempts forever; believing the user just haven’t completed it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can work-around the problem temporarily by disabling First-Party Isolation, restarting the browser, logging in to the extension, and then re-enabling First-Party Isolation. Depending on the configuration of the service you login to,m you may nee to repeat the process every few months, weeks, days, or even hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-update&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update &lt;time datetime=&quot;2018-07-12&quot;&gt;2018 July&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Added information about login issues with extension API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other extensions assume that they can access cookies cross-domains in a way that is prohibited by First-Party Isolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Can’t log-in to Pocket&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com/&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; is Mozilla’s reading list and article recommendation service that you’ll find built-right in to Firefox. Unfortunately, you can’t login to Pocket when First-Party isolation is enabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can work-around the problem by temporarily disabling First-Party Isolation, restarting the browser, logging in to Pocket, and then re-enabling First-Party Isolation. The process must be repeated every six months or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-update&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update &lt;time datetime=&quot;2018-07-11&quot;&gt;2018 July&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Added information about Pocket login issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Enabling First-Party Isolation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can enable the feature by typing &lt;kbd&gt;about:config&lt;/kbd&gt; in the address field, changing the &lt;samp&gt;privacy.firstparty.isolate&lt;/samp&gt; option to &lt;kbd&gt;true&lt;/kbd&gt;, and restarting Firefox. You should only enable the feature if you’re prepared to run into a few issues now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve enabled First-Party Isolation myself and have used it for months already. It can be annoying, but I believe it to overall be a good security and privacy feature that I hope Firefox can one day enable by default. You can check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en&quot; title=&quot;“What is Tor Browser?”&quot;&gt;Tor Browser&lt;/a&gt; if you wish to use a web browser based on Firefox that enables this feature by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Sources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1475124&quot;&gt;identity.launchWebAuthFlow doesn’t work when privacy.firstparty.isolate is enabled&lt;/a&gt;, issue 1475124, &lt;time&gt;2018-07-12&lt;/time&gt;, Daniel Aleksandersen, Firefox bug tracker, Mozilla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1384657&quot;&gt;Pocket doesn't work with privacy.firstparty.isolate set to true&lt;/a&gt;, issue 1384657, &lt;time&gt;2018-05-09&lt;/time&gt;, Firefox bug tracker, Mozilla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser/design/#identifier-linkability&quot;&gt;4.5. Cross-Origin Identifier Unlinkability&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;time&gt;2018-02-19&lt;/time&gt;, The Design and Implementation of the Tor Browser, Tor Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/data/2018/01/26/improving-privacy-without-breaking-the-web/&quot;&gt;Improving privacy without breaking the web&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;time&gt;2018-01-26&lt;/time&gt;, Firefox Data blog, Mozilla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghacks.net/2017/11/22/how-to-enable-first-party-isolation-in-firefox/&quot;&gt;How to enable First-Party Isolation in Firefox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;time&gt;2017-11-22&lt;/time&gt;, Martin Brinkmann, gHacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/55.0/releasenotes/&quot;&gt;Firefox 55.0 Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;time&gt;2017-08-08&lt;/time&gt;, Mozilla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://security.googleblog.com/2014/12/are-you-robot-introducing-no-captcha.html&quot;&gt;Are you a robot? Introducing “No CAPTCHA reCAPTCHA”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;time&gt;2014-12-03&lt;/time&gt;, Vinay Shet, Google Security Blog, Google&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 08:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fanf2</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>What is First-Party Isolation in Firefox and what breaks if you enabled it</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.ctrl.blog/entry/firefox-fpi</og:url>
<og:description>Instead of modifying and blocking page contents; Firefox optionally lets users modifies the browser to become harder to track across websites.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.ctrl.blog/media/fox-snow-nap-1072x603.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ctrl.blog/entry/firefox-fpi</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tell HN: Google requiring phone number to log into Chromebook</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17944311</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17944311</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.9289191820837&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.2502434274586&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;17944311&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17944311&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Tell HN: Google requiring phone number to log into Chromebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.75949367088608&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_17944311&quot;&gt;280 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=pisky&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;pisky&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17944311&quot;&gt;19 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_17944311&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=17944311&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D17944311&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Tell%20HN%3A%20Google%20requiring%20phone%20number%20to%20log%20into%20Chromebook&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Tell%20HN%3A%20Google%20requiring%20phone%20number%20to%20log%20into%20Chromebook&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=17944311&amp;amp;auth=c107bf3e3f94057fc46ce023bef9f3a6e3660f01&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17944311&quot;&gt;165 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;Long story short: bought a couple of Chromebooks over the years (as they're nice multi user machines), created Google accounts on each but never gave a phone number. Now after years of use, Google pops up an &quot;unrecognized device&quot; roadblock AFTER I enter the password to log in, with the message &quot;enter a phone number to get a text message with a verification code&quot;.
&lt;p&gt;There is no mention of suspicious activity. The only trigger I can think of is a recent modem reset that changed my Public IP, and my new IP doesn't appear to resolve to my old physical location in Google's geoip db.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I crazy or does this seem like an extremely cynical attempt to get more phone numbers? I don't even understand how giving them my phone number proves anything as I definitely did not ever give them one previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately burner phones are not available in my country, so that's not an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Winter 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 04:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pisky</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17944311</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>XSV: A fast CSV command-line toolkit written in Rust</title>
<link>https://github.com/BurntSushi/xsv</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/BurntSushi/xsv</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;xsv is a command line program for indexing, slicing, analyzing, splitting and joining CSV files. Commands should be simple, fast and composable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simple tasks should be easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance trade offs should be exposed in the CLI interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Composition should not come at the expense of performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This README contains information on how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/xsv#installation&quot;&gt;install &lt;code&gt;xsv&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in addition to a quick tour of several commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/BurntSushi/xsv&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/a03458c557a758d6ea3f5617683fe984bc7fed7b/68747470733a2f2f6170692e7472617669732d63692e6f72672f4275726e7453757368692f7873762e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Linux build status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://api.travis-ci.org/BurntSushi/xsv.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ci.appveyor.com/project/BurntSushi/xsv&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/5e2ec797b366d5dd7cce14975a99e50e789b3c7f/68747470733a2f2f63692e6170707665796f722e636f6d2f6170692f70726f6a656374732f7374617475732f6769746875622f4275726e7453757368692f7873763f7376673d74727565&quot; alt=&quot;Windows build status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/github/BurntSushi/xsv?svg=true&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/xsv&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/bf8b7f29d267c7360312c4724a7007c8087a65ec/687474703a2f2f6d6572697462616467652e6865726f6b756170702e636f6d2f787376&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://meritbadge.herokuapp.com/xsv&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dual-licensed under MIT or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://unlicense.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;UNLICENSE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Available commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cat&lt;/strong&gt; - Concatenate CSV files by row or by column.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;count&lt;/strong&gt; - Count the rows in a CSV file. (Instantaneous with an index.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fixlengths&lt;/strong&gt; - Force a CSV file to have same-length records by either padding or truncating them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;flatten&lt;/strong&gt; - A flattened view of CSV records. Useful for viewing one record at a time. e.g., &lt;code&gt;xsv slice -i 5 data.csv | xsv flatten&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fmt&lt;/strong&gt; - Reformat CSV data with different delimiters, record terminators or quoting rules. (Supports ASCII delimited data.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;frequency&lt;/strong&gt; - Build frequency tables of each column in CSV data. (Uses parallelism to go faster if an index is present.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;headers&lt;/strong&gt; - Show the headers of CSV data. Or show the intersection of all headers between many CSV files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index&lt;/strong&gt; - Create an index for a CSV file. This is very quick and provides constant time indexing into the CSV file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;input&lt;/strong&gt; - Read CSV data with exotic quoting/escaping rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;join&lt;/strong&gt; - Inner, outer and cross joins. Uses a simple hash index to make it fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;partition&lt;/strong&gt; - Partition CSV data based on a column value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sample&lt;/strong&gt; - Randomly draw rows from CSV data using reservoir sampling (i.e., use memory proportional to the size of the sample).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reverse&lt;/strong&gt; - Reverse order of rows in CSV data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;search&lt;/strong&gt; - Run a regex over CSV data. Applies the regex to each field individually and shows only matching rows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;select&lt;/strong&gt; - Select or re-order columns from CSV data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;slice&lt;/strong&gt; - Slice rows from any part of a CSV file. When an index is present, this only has to parse the rows in the slice (instead of all rows leading up to the start of the slice).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sort&lt;/strong&gt; - Sort CSV data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;split&lt;/strong&gt; - Split one CSV file into many CSV files of N chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stats&lt;/strong&gt; - Show basic types and statistics of each column in the CSV file. (i.e., mean, standard deviation, median, range, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;table&lt;/strong&gt; - Show aligned output of any CSV data using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/tabwriter&quot;&gt;elastic tabstops&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;A whirlwind tour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's say you're playing with some of the data from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/petewarden/dstkdata&quot;&gt;Data Science Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;, which contains several CSV files. Maybe you're interested in the population counts of each city in the world. So grab the data and start examining it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ curl -LO http://burntsushi.net/stuff/worldcitiespop.csv
$ xsv headers worldcitiespop.csv
1   Country
2   City
3   AccentCity
4   Region
5   Population
6   Latitude
7   Longitude
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing you might want to do is get an overview of the kind of data that appears in each column. The &lt;code&gt;stats&lt;/code&gt; command will do this for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ xsv stats worldcitiespop.csv --everything &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv table
field       &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;     min            max            min_length  max_length  mean          stddev         median     mode         cardinality
Country     Unicode  ad             zw             2           2                                                   cn           234
City        Unicode   bab el ahmar  Þykkvibaer     1           91                                                  san jose     2351892
AccentCity  Unicode   Bâb el Ahmar  ïn Bou Chella  1           91                                                  San Antonio  2375760
Region      Unicode  00             Z9             0           2                                        13         04           397
Population  Integer  7              31480498       0           8           47719.570634  302885.559204  10779                   28754
Latitude    Float    -54.933333     82.483333      1           12          27.188166     21.952614      32.497222  51.15        1038349
Longitude   Float    -179.983333    180            1           14          37.08886      63.22301       35.28      23.8         1167162
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;xsv table&lt;/code&gt; command takes any CSV data and formats it into aligned columns using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/tabwriter&quot;&gt;elastic tabstops&lt;/a&gt;. You'll notice that it even gets alignment right with respect to Unicode characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this command takes about 12 seconds to run on my machine, but we can speed it up by creating an index and re-running the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ xsv index worldcitiespop.csv
$ xsv stats worldcitiespop.csv --everything &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv table
...
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which cuts it down to about 8 seconds on my machine. (And creating the index takes less than 2 seconds.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notably, the same type of &quot;statistics&quot; command in another &lt;a href=&quot;https://csvkit.readthedocs.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CSV command line toolkit&lt;/a&gt; takes about 2 minutes to produce similar statistics on the same data set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating an index gives us more than just faster statistics gathering. It also makes slice operations extremely fast because &lt;em&gt;only the sliced portion&lt;/em&gt; has to be parsed. For example, let's say you wanted to grab the last 10 records:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ xsv count worldcitiespop.csv
3173958
$ xsv slice worldcitiespop.csv -s 3173948 &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv table
Country  City               AccentCity         Region  Population  Latitude     Longitude
zw       zibalonkwe         Zibalonkwe         06                  -19.8333333  27.4666667
zw       zibunkululu        Zibunkululu        06                  -19.6666667  27.6166667
zw       ziga               Ziga               06                  -19.2166667  27.4833333
zw       zikamanas village  Zikamanas Village  00                  -18.2166667  27.95
zw       zimbabwe           Zimbabwe           07                  -20.2666667  30.9166667
zw       zimre park         Zimre Park         04                  -17.8661111  31.2136111
zw       ziyakamanas        Ziyakamanas        00                  -18.2166667  27.95
zw       zizalisari         Zizalisari         04                  -17.7588889  31.0105556
zw       zuzumba            Zuzumba            06                  -20.0333333  27.9333333
zw       zvishavane         Zvishavane         07      79876       -20.3333333  30.0333333
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These commands are &lt;em&gt;instantaneous&lt;/em&gt; because they run in time and memory proportional to the size of the slice (which means they will scale to arbitrarily large CSV data).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switching gears a little bit, you might not always want to see every column in the CSV data. In this case, maybe we only care about the country, city and population. So let's take a look at 10 random rows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ xsv &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Country,AccentCity,Population&lt;/span&gt; worldcitiespop.csv \
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv sample 10 \
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv table
Country  AccentCity       Population
cn       Guankoushang
za       Klipdrift
ma       Ouled Hammou
fr       Les Gravues
la       Ban Phadèng
de       Lüdenscheid      80045
qa       Umm ash Shubrum
bd       Panditgoan
us       Appleton
ua       Lukashenkivske
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoops! It seems some cities don't have population counts. How pervasive is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ xsv frequency worldcitiespop.csv --limit 5
field,value,count
Country,cn,238985
Country,ru,215938
Country,id,176546
Country,us,141989
Country,ir,123872
City,san jose,328
City,san antonio,320
City,santa rosa,296
City,santa cruz,282
City,san juan,255
AccentCity,San Antonio,317
AccentCity,Santa Rosa,296
AccentCity,Santa Cruz,281
AccentCity,San Juan,254
AccentCity,San Miguel,254
Region,04,159916
Region,02,142158
Region,07,126867
Region,03,122161
Region,05,118441
Population,(NULL),3125978
Population,2310,12
Population,3097,11
Population,983,11
Population,2684,11
Latitude,51.15,777
Latitude,51.083333,772
Latitude,50.933333,769
Latitude,51.116667,769
Latitude,51.133333,767
Longitude,23.8,484
Longitude,23.2,477
Longitude,23.05,476
Longitude,25.3,474
Longitude,23.1,459
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The &lt;code&gt;xsv frequency&lt;/code&gt; command builds a frequency table for each column in the CSV data. This one only took 5 seconds.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems that most cities do not have a population count associated with them at all. No matter—we can adjust our previous command so that it only shows rows with a population count:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ xsv search -s Population &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;[0-9]&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; worldcitiespop.csv \
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Country,AccentCity,Population&lt;/span&gt; \
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv sample 10 \
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv table
Country  AccentCity       Population
es       Barañáin         22264
es       Puerto Real      36946
at       Moosburg         4602
hu       Hejobaba         1949
ru       Polyarnyye Zori  15092
gr       Kandíla          1245
is       Ólafsvík         992
hu       Decs             4210
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;bg&lt;/span&gt;       Sliven           94252
gb       Leatherhead      43544
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erk. Which country is &lt;code&gt;at&lt;/code&gt;? No clue, but the Data Science Toolkit has a CSV file called &lt;code&gt;countrynames.csv&lt;/code&gt;. Let's grab it and do a join so we can see which countries these are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
curl -LO https://gist.githubusercontent.com/anonymous/063cb470e56e64e98cf1/raw/98e2589b801f6ca3ff900b01a87fbb7452eb35c7/countrynames.csv
$ xsv headers countrynames.csv
1   Abbrev
2   Country
$ xsv join --no-case  Country sample.csv Abbrev countrynames.csv &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv table
Country  AccentCity       Population  Abbrev  Country
es       Barañáin         22264       ES      Spain
es       Puerto Real      36946       ES      Spain
at       Moosburg         4602        AT      Austria
hu       Hejobaba         1949        HU      Hungary
ru       Polyarnyye Zori  15092       RU      Russian Federation &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; Russia
gr       Kandíla          1245        GR      Greece
is       Ólafsvík         992         IS      Iceland
hu       Decs             4210        HU      Hungary
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;bg&lt;/span&gt;       Sliven           94252       BG      Bulgaria
gb       Leatherhead      43544       GB      Great Britain &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; UK &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; England &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; Scotland &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; Wales &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; Northern Ireland &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; United Kingdom
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoops, now we have two columns called &lt;code&gt;Country&lt;/code&gt; and an &lt;code&gt;Abbrev&lt;/code&gt; column that we no longer need. This is easy to fix by re-ordering columns with the &lt;code&gt;xsv select&lt;/code&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ xsv join --no-case  Country sample.csv Abbrev countrynames.csv \
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;'Country[1],AccentCity,Population'&lt;/span&gt; \
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv table
Country                                                                              AccentCity       Population
Spain                                                                                Barañáin         22264
Spain                                                                                Puerto Real      36946
Austria                                                                              Moosburg         4602
Hungary                                                                              Hejobaba         1949
Russian Federation &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; Russia                                                          Polyarnyye Zori  15092
Greece                                                                               Kandíla          1245
Iceland                                                                              Ólafsvík         992
Hungary                                                                              Decs             4210
Bulgaria                                                                             Sliven           94252
Great Britain &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; UK &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; England &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; Scotland &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; Wales &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; Northern Ireland &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; United Kingdom  Leatherhead      43544
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps we can do this with the original CSV data? Indeed we can—because joins in &lt;code&gt;xsv&lt;/code&gt; are fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ xsv join --no-case Abbrev countrynames.csv Country worldcitiespop.csv \
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;'!Abbrev,Country[1]'&lt;/span&gt; \
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; worldcitiespop_countrynames.csv
$ xsv sample 10 worldcitiespop_countrynames.csv &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xsv table
Country                      City                   AccentCity             Region  Population  Latitude    Longitude
Sri Lanka                    miriswatte             Miriswatte             36                  7.2333333   79.9
Romania                      livezile               Livezile               26      1985        44.512222   22.863333
Indonesia                    tawainalu              Tawainalu              22                  -4.0225     121.9273
Russian Federation &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; Russia  otar                   Otar                   45                  56.975278   48.305278
France                       le breuil-bois robert  le Breuil-Bois Robert  A8                  48.945567   1.717026
France                       lissac                 Lissac                 B1                  45.103094   1.464927
Albania                      lumalasi               Lumalasi               46                  40.6586111  20.7363889
China                        motzushih              Motzushih              11                  27.65       111.966667
Russian Federation &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; Russia  svakino                Svakino                69                  55.60211    34.559785
Romania                      tirgu pancesti         Tirgu Pancesti         38                  46.216667   27.1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;!Abbrev,Country[1]&lt;/code&gt; syntax means, &quot;remove the &lt;code&gt;Abbrev&lt;/code&gt; column and remove the second occurrence of the &lt;code&gt;Country&lt;/code&gt; column.&quot; Since we joined with &lt;code&gt;countrynames.csv&lt;/code&gt; first, the first &lt;code&gt;Country&lt;/code&gt; name (fully expanded) is now included in the CSV data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;code&gt;xsv join&lt;/code&gt; command takes about 7 seconds on my machine. The performance comes from constructing a very simple hash index of one of the CSV data files given. The &lt;code&gt;join&lt;/code&gt; command does an inner join by default, but it also has left, right and full outer join support too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binaries for Windows, Linux and Mac are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/xsv/releases/latest&quot;&gt;from Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a &lt;strong&gt;Mac OS X Homebrew&lt;/strong&gt; user, then you can install xsv from homebrew-core:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ brew install xsv
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a &lt;strong&gt;Nix/NixOS&lt;/strong&gt; user, you can install xsv from nixpkgs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ nix-env -i xsv
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can compile from source by &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/install&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;installing Cargo&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rust-lang.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Rust's&lt;/a&gt; package manager) and installing &lt;code&gt;xsv&lt;/code&gt; using Cargo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cargo install xsv
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compiling from this repository also works similarly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
git clone git://github.com/BurntSushi/xsv
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; xsv
cargo build --release
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compilation will probably take a few minutes depending on your machine. The binary will end up in &lt;code&gt;./target/release/xsv&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Benchmarks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've compiled some &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/xsv/blob/master/BENCHMARKS.md&quot;&gt;very rough benchmarks&lt;/a&gt; of various &lt;code&gt;xsv&lt;/code&gt; commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are several valid criticisms of this project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;You shouldn't be working with CSV data because CSV is a terrible format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your data is gigabytes in size, then CSV is the wrong storage type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various SQL databases provide all of the operations available in &lt;code&gt;xsv&lt;/code&gt; with more sophisticated indexing support. And the performance is a zillion times better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm sure there are more criticisms, but the impetus for this project was a 40GB CSV file that was handed to me. I was tasked with figuring out the shape of the data inside of it and coming up with a way to integrate it into our existing system. It was then that I realized that every single CSV tool I knew about was woefully inadequate. They were just too slow or didn't provide enough flexibility. (Another project I had comprised of a few dozen CSV files. They were smaller than 40GB, but they were each supposed to represent the same kind of data. But they all had different column and unintuitive column names. Useful CSV inspection tools were critical here—and they had to be reasonably fast.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key ingredients for helping me with my task were indexing, random sampling, searching, slicing and selecting columns. All of these things made dealing with 40GB of CSV data a bit more manageable (or dozens of CSV files).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting handed a large CSV file &lt;em&gt;once&lt;/em&gt; was enough to launch me on this quest. From conversations I've had with others, CSV data files this large don't seem to be a rare event. Therefore, I believe there is room for a tool that has a hope of dealing with data that large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 22:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/456674?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>BurntSushi/xsv</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/BurntSushi/xsv</og:url>
<og:description>A fast CSV command line toolkit written in Rust. Contribute to BurntSushi/xsv development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/BurntSushi/xsv</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tell HN: Using Gmail? You will be force logged into Chrome</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17942252</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17942252</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.361474435196&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.4286563614744&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;17942252&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17942252&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Tell HN: Using Gmail? You will be force logged into Chrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.76923076923077&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_17942252&quot;&gt;483 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=ronilan&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;ronilan&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17942252&quot;&gt;1 day ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_17942252&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=17942252&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D17942252&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Tell%20HN%3A%20Using%20Gmail%3F%20You%20will%20be%20force%20logged%20into%20Chrome&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Tell%20HN%3A%20Using%20Gmail%3F%20You%20will%20be%20force%20logged%20into%20Chrome&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=17942252&amp;amp;auth=045bef4cdc36ee6450b0de2e63341390c981c534&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17942252&quot;&gt;297 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;23.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;So, it turns out Chrome 69 is a lot more than just redesign of the tabs and removal of the www from the url.
&lt;p&gt;I'm using the Mac version of Chrome (Version 69.0.3497.81 (Official Build) (64-bit) to be pedantic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until two days ago, logging into gmail and logging into chrome were two different things, as they obviously are (one is a web service the other is a web browser, to be pedantic again)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would usually be logged into gmail in the browser, but would only log into Chrome on special occasions and/or with specific accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, if I hit www.gmail.com and log in, I'm automatically logged into Chrome. If I log out of Chrome, I'm also logged out of gmail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can't be a bug... can it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Winter 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 19:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ronilan</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17942252</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OxyContin billionaire has patented a drug to wean addicts from opioids</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/business/wp/2018/09/08/the-man-who-made-billions-of-dollars-from-oxycontin-is-pushing-a-drug-to-wean-addicts-off-opioids</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/business/wp/2018/09/08/the-man-who-made-billions-of-dollars-from-oxycontin-is-pushing-a-drug-to-wean-addicts-off-opioids</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/aScULsx2bXh0J0xwB0Lce1LC2Vk=/311x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/DNABDRTUS43KDH4XRK5I6NHNJA.jpg&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/CXB7wpzGILwPK787Pp6jSdLxGYI=/960x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/DNABDRTUS43KDH4XRK5I6NHNJA.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/aScULsx2bXh0J0xwB0Lce1LC2Vk=/311x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/DNABDRTUS43KDH4XRK5I6NHNJA.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/DNABDRTUS43KDH4XRK5I6NHNJA.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;311&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;(iStock)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;author-timestamp&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2018-09-08T07:00-500&quot;&gt;September 8 at 7:00 AM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Following &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/6/7/15724054/opioid-epidemic-lawsuits-purdue-oxycontin&quot;&gt;hundreds of lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; over the years against pharmaceutical giant Purdue Pharma, Colorado’s attorney general is suing the OxyContin creator for its “significant role in causing the opioid epidemic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;2&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://coag.gov/press-room/press-releases/09-06-18&quot;&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; claims Purdue Pharma L.P. and Purdue Pharma Inc. deluded doctors and patients in Colorado about the potential for addiction with prescription opioids and continued to push the drugs. And it comes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/a3a53ae8-b1e3-11e8-8d14-6f049d06439c&quot;&gt;amid news&lt;/a&gt; that the company’s former chairman and president, Richard Sackler, has patented &lt;a href=&quot;http://patft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1&amp;amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;amp;d=PALL&amp;amp;p=1&amp;amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsrchnum.htm&amp;amp;r=1&amp;amp;f=G&amp;amp;l=50&amp;amp;s1=98,61,628.PN.&amp;amp;OS=PN/98,61,628&amp;amp;RS=PN/98,61,628&quot;&gt;a new drug&lt;/a&gt; to help wean addicts from opioids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;3&quot;&gt;“Purdue’s habit-forming medications coupled with their reckless marketing have robbed children of their parents, families of their sons and daughters, and destroyed the lives of our friends, neighbors, and co-workers,” Colorado Attorney General Cynthia Coffman &lt;a href=&quot;https://coag.gov/press-room/press-releases/09-06-18&quot;&gt;said Thursday in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. “While no amount of money can bring back loved ones, it can compensate for the enormous costs brought about by Purdue’s intentional misconduct.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;4&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2018/national/amp-stories/oxycontin-how-misleading-marketing-got-america-addicted/&quot;&gt;OxyContin and our opioid crisis: How the misleading marketing of one pain pill helped get America addicted&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;5&quot;&gt;The lawsuit states that Purdue Pharma “downplayed the risk of addiction associated with opioids,” “exaggerated the benefits” and “advised health care professionals that they were violating their Hippocratic Oath and failing their patients unless they treated pain symptoms with opioids,” according to the statement from the Colorado attorney general’s office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;6&quot;&gt;But Purdue Pharma “vigorously” denied the accusations Friday in a statement to The Washington Post, saying that although it shares “the state’s concern about the opioid crisis,” it did not mislead health-care providers about prescription opioids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;7&quot;&gt;“The state claims Purdue acted improperly by communicating with prescribers about scientific and medical information that FDA has expressly considered and continues to approve,” a spokesman for Purdue Pharma said in the statement. “We believe it is inappropriate for the state to substitute its judgment for the judgment of the regulatory, scientific and medical experts at FDA.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;8&quot;&gt;In 2016, there were more than 63,000 drug overdose deaths in United States, and more than 66 percent of them were attributed to opioids, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/drugoverdose/data/statedeaths.html&quot;&gt;according to the most recent data&lt;/a&gt; from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;9&quot;&gt;The CDC states that both illegal opioids and prescription opioids, which are commonly used to treat pain, have been associated with addiction, overdoses and death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;10&quot;&gt;In federal court in 2007, three top current and former employees for Purdue pleaded guilty to criminal charges, admitting that they had falsely led doctors and their patients to believe that OxyContin was less likely to be abused than other drugs in its class, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2007/05/11/business/11drug.html?ex=1336536000&amp;amp;en=1408963d334a8436&amp;amp;ei=5090&amp;amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;according to the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. Then earlier this year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/purdue-pharma-to-stop-promoting-oxycontin-to-u-s-doctors-1518307565&quot;&gt;the Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; reported that Purdue planned to stop promoting the drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;11&quot;&gt;Now, it seems, a new business venture is only adding to the outcry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;12&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/a3a53ae8-b1e3-11e8-8d14-6f049d06439c&quot;&gt;Financial Times reported&lt;/a&gt; that Sackler, whose family owns Purdue Pharma, a multibillion-dollar company, patented a new drug earlier this year that is a form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.samhsa.gov/medication-assisted-treatment/treatment/buprenorphine&quot;&gt;buprenorphine&lt;/a&gt;, a mild opioid that is used to ease withdrawal symptoms. However, some are expressing outrage that the Sacklers, who have in essence profited from opioid addictions, may soon be profiting from the antidote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;13&quot;&gt;“It’s reprehensible what Purdue Pharma has done to our public health,” Luke Nasta, director of Camelot, a New York-based treatment center for drug and alcohol addiction, told the Financial Times. He told the newspaper that the Sackler family “shouldn’t be allowed to peddle any more synthetic opiates — and that includes opioid substitutes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;14&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://patft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1&amp;amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;amp;d=PALL&amp;amp;p=1&amp;amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsrchnum.htm&amp;amp;r=1&amp;amp;f=G&amp;amp;l=50&amp;amp;s1=98,61,628.PN.&amp;amp;OS=PN/98,61,628&amp;amp;RS=PN/98,61,628&quot;&gt;patent’s description&lt;/a&gt; acknowledges the risk of addiction that is associated with opioids:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;citation blockquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot;&gt;While opioids have always been known to be useful in pain treatment, they also display an addictive potential in view of their euphorigenic activity. Thus, if opioids are taken by healthy human subjects with a drug seeking behaviour they may lead to psychological as well as physical dependence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot;&gt;These usually undesired characteristics of opioids can however become important in certain scenarios such as drug substitution therapies for drug addicts. One of the fundamental problems of illicit drug abuse by drug addicts (“junkies”) who are dependent on the constant intake of illegal drugs such as heroin is the drug-related criminal activities resorted to by such addicts in order to raise enough money to fund their addiction. The constant pressures upon addicts to procure money for buying drugs and the concomitant criminal activities have been increasingly recognised as a major factor that counteracts efficient and long-lasting withdrawal and abstinence from drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;16&quot;&gt;The patent states that the drug could be used both in drug replacement therapy as well as for pain management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;17&quot;&gt;Purdue Pharma did not respond to requests for comment on the new drug, but in addressing the lawsuit in Colorado, the company said: “We share the state’s concern about the opioid crisis. While our opioid medicines account for less than 2% of total prescriptions, we will continue to work collaboratively with the state toward bringing meaningful solutions to address this public health challenge.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;18&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;19&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp/2018/08/09/death-reports-make-the-opioid-crisis-personal-for-doctors/?utm_term=.271ce109b102&quot;&gt;Telling doctors their patient died from overdose could prevent some opioid abuse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;20&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/i-survived-i-made-it-out-she-used-to-be-addicted-to-crack-cocaine-now-she-wants-to-help-opioid-abusers/2018/05/10/0f096a9a-52f1-11e8-9c91-7dab596e8252_story.html?utm_term=.f80167035490&quot;&gt;She used to be addicted to crack cocaine. Now, she wants to help opioid abusers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;21&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp/2018/01/31/a-town-of-3200-was-flooded-with-21-million-pain-pills-as-addiction-crisis-worsened-lawmakers-say/?utm_term=.91d547e820ce&quot;&gt;A town of 3,200 was flooded with nearly 21 million pain pills as addiction crisis worsened, lawmakers say&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 14:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dsr12</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/business/wp/2018/09/08/the-man-who-made-billions-of-dollars-from-oxycontin-is-pushing-a-drug-to-wean-addicts-off-opioids/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/CxEb98mscNOJNmxPk3n5dF-cXEk=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/VL7TKMHHVA2OXEFDHSXNFXQHWM.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The man who made billions of dollars from OxyContin is pushing a drug to wean addicts off opioids</og:title>
<og:description>Purdue Pharma's former chairman and president Richard Sackler stands to profit from a drug to help wean addicts from opioids.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/business/wp/2018/09/08/the-man-who-made-billions-of-dollars-from-oxycontin-is-pushing-a-drug-to-wean-addicts-off-opioids/?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A year later, Equifax has faced little fallout from losing data</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/08/equifax-one-year-later-unscathed/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/08/equifax-one-year-later-unscathed/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;featured__span-first-words&quot;&gt;A lot can&lt;/span&gt; change in a year. Not when you’re Equifax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The credit rating giant, one of the largest in the world, was trusted with some of the most sensitive data used by banks and financiers to determine who can be lent money. But the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/17/the-learned-helplessness-of-equifax/&quot;&gt;company failed to patch a web server&lt;/a&gt; it knew was vulnerable for months, which let hackers crash the servers and steal data on 147 million consumers. Names, addresses, Social Security numbers and more — and &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/08/equifax-filing-reveals-hack-was-somehow-even-worse-than-previous-estimates/&quot;&gt;millions more driver license and credit card numbers&lt;/a&gt; were stolen in the breach. Millions of British and Canadian nationals were also affected, sparking a global response to the breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was “one of the most egregious examples of corporate malfeasance since Enron,” said Senate Democratic leader Chuck Schumer at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, a year on from following the devastating hack that left the company reeling from a breach of almost every American adult, the company has faced little to no action or repercussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath, the company’s response to the breach was chaotic, sending consumers &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/07/equifax-data-breach-help-site-leaves-consumers-with-more-questions-than-answers/&quot;&gt;scrambling to learn&lt;/a&gt; if they were affected but were instead &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/08/psa-no-matter-what-you-write-equifax-may-tell-you-youve-been-impacted-by-the-hack/&quot;&gt;led into a broken site&lt;/a&gt; that was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/equifax-freeze-your-account-site-is-also-vulnerable-to-hacking/&quot;&gt;vulnerable to hacking&lt;/a&gt;. And when consumers were looking for answers, Equifax’s own Twitter account sent concerned users to a site that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/20/16339612/equifax-tweet-wrong-website-phishing-identity-monitoring&quot;&gt;easily could have been a phishing page&lt;/a&gt; had it not been for a good samaritan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, the company went unpunished. In the end, Equifax was in law as much a victim as the 147 million Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There was a failure of the company, but also of lawmakers,” said Mark Warner, a Democratic senator, in a call with TechCrunch. Warner, who serves Virginia, was one of the first lawmakers to file new legislation after the breach. Alongside his Democratic colleague, Sen. Elizabeth Warren, the two senators said their bill, if passed, would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c-span.org/video/?434275-5/senator-warren-equifax-security-data-breach&quot;&gt;hold credit agencies accountable&lt;/a&gt; for data breaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With Equifax, they knew for months before they reported, so at what point is that violating securities laws by not having that notice?,” said Warner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“There was a failure of the company, but also of lawmakers.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Sen. Mark Warner (D-VA)&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The message sent to the market is ‘if you can endure some media blowback, you can get through this without serious long-term ramifications’, and that’s totally unacceptable,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers held hearings and grilled the company’s former chief executive, Richard Smith, who retired with &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2017/09/26/equifax-ceo-richard-smith-net-worth/&quot;&gt;his full $90 million retirement package&lt;/a&gt;, adding insult to injury. Equifax further shuffled its executive suite, including the hiring of a new chief information security officer Jamil Farshchi and former lawyer turned “chief transformation officer” Julia Houston to oversee “the company’s response to the cybersecurity incident.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equifax declined to make either executive available for interview or comment when reached by TechCrunch, but Equifax spokesperson Wyatt Jefferies said protecting customer data is the company’s “top priority.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s not much to show for it beyond superficial gestures of free credit monitoring — provided by Equifax, no less — and a credit locking app which, unsurprisingly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/31/your-money/new-service-same-old-equifax-credit-locking-app-freezes-up.html?module=WatchingPortal&amp;amp;amp;region=c-column-middle-span-region&amp;amp;amp;pgType=Homepage&amp;amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;amp;mediaId=thumb_square&amp;amp;amp;state=standard&amp;amp;amp;contentPlacement=5&amp;amp;amp;version=internal&amp;amp;amp;contentCollection=www.nytimes.com&amp;amp;amp;contentId=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2018%2F01%2F31%2Fyour-money%2Fnew-service-same-old-equifax-credit-locking-app-freezes-up.html&amp;amp;amp;eventName=Watching-article-click&quot;&gt;had its own flaws&lt;/a&gt;. In the year since, the company has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/equifax-has-spent-242-7-million-on-its-data-breach-so-far/&quot;&gt;spent more than $240 million&lt;/a&gt; — some $50 million was covered by cyber-insurance. That’s a drop in the ocean to more than $3 billion in revenue in the year since, according to quarterly earnings filings — or more than $500 million in profits. And although Equifax’s stock price initially collapsed in the weeks following, the price bounced back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financially, the company looks almost as healthy as it’s ever been. But that may change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1708053&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout size-full wp-image-1708053&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-857524294.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;716&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Former Equifax chief executive Richard Smith prepares to testify before the lawmakers. Smith later retired after hackers broke into the credit reporting agency and made off with the personal information of nearly 145 million Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the company asked a federal judge to reject claims from dozens of banks and credit unions for costs taken to prevent fraud following the data breach. The claims, if accepted, could force Equifax to shell out tens of millions of dollars — perhaps more. The hundreds of class action suits filed to date have yet to hit the courts, but historically even the largest class action cases have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/anthem-customers-to-get-less-than-one-dollar-each-after-2015-hack/&quot;&gt;resulted in single dollar amounts&lt;/a&gt; for the individuals affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when the credit agent giant isn’t fighting the courts, federal regulators have shown little interest in pursuit of legal action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An investigation launched by a former head of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, responsible for protecting consumers from fraud, sputtered after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-equifax-cfpb/exclusive-u-s-consumer-protection-official-puts-equifax-probe-on-ice-sources-idUSKBN1FP0IZ&quot;&gt;the new director reportedly declined to pursue&lt;/a&gt; the company. And, although the company is under investigation by the Federal Trade Commission for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2012/10/ftc-settlements-require-equifax-forfeit-money-made-allegedly&quot;&gt;the second time this decade&lt;/a&gt;, fines are likely to be limited — if levied at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warren &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4840265-Warren-letter-to-CFPB-and-FTC.html&quot;&gt;sent a letter&lt;/a&gt; Thursday to the heads of both agencies lamenting their lack of action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Companies like Equifax do not ask the American people before they collect their most sensitive information,” said Warren. “This information can determine their ability to access credit, obtain a job, secure a home loan, purchase a car, and make dozens of other transactions that are critical to their personal financial security.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The American people deserve an update on your investigations,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, only the Securities and Exchange Commission has brought charges — not for the breach itself, but against three former staffers for allegedly insider trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Escaping any local action, Equifax agreed with eight states, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dfs.ny.gov/about/press/pr1806251.htm&quot;&gt;including New York&lt;/a&gt; and California, to take further cybersecurity steps and measures to prevent another breach, escaping any fines or financial penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“The American people deserve an update on your investigations”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Sen. Elizabeth Warren (D-MA)&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warner blamed much of the inaction to the patchwork of data breach laws that vary by state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’ve got different laws and you don’t have any standard, and part of the challenge around the data breach is that every industry wants to be exempted,” said Warner. It’s not a partisan issue, he said, but one where every industry — from telecoms to retail — wants to be exempt from the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If we really want to improve our business cyber-hygiene, you have got to have consequences for failing to keep up those cyber-hygiene standards,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a tough sell to posit Equifax, which fluffed almost every step of the breach process, before and after its disclosure, as a victim. While the millions affected can take solace in the beating Equifax got in the press, those demanding regulatory action might be in for a disappointingly long wait.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 14:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sahin-boydas</dc:creator>
<og:title>A year later, Equifax lost your data but faced little fallout</og:title>
<og:description>A lot can change in a year. Not when you’re Equifax. The credit rating giant, one of the largest in the world, was trusted with some of the most sensitive data used by banks and financiers to determine who can be lent money. But the company failed to patch a web server it knew was […]</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-8575243184.jpg?w=556</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/09/08/equifax-one-year-later-unscathed/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/08/equifax-one-year-later-unscathed/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tools of the Trade, from Hacker News</title>
<link>https://github.com/cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools of The Trade, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade#contents&quot;&gt;Contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; · &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade#use&quot;&gt;Use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; · &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade#authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Background&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Joshua Schachter, the founder of Delicious, &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=1769910&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;posted the following&lt;/a&gt; on Hacker News:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started delicious, we had to host most of the services ourselves. CVS, mail, mailing lists, etc etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, lots of that stuff is available as SaaS. What are the tools and services people use instead of hosting their own?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I'm not talking about actual production services like EC2 and Heroku and whatnot. We can go over this in another thread.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, Sharjeel Qureshi, &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5235137&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;posted the following&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few years ago, Joshua Schachter started this thread on HN for discussing hosted useful services: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=1769910&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=1769910&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contribution in thread introduced many interesting SaaS services which can immensely help in deploying services as well as development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been three years since then. What do we have today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to the big contributors to the previous threads, including garrettdimon, espeed, netshade, and cmadan, and many more that I haven't named.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Now&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've collected more data from Hacker News, AngelList and Quora, to make the 2015 (and hopefully beyond) version. This list also includes self-hosted as well as hosted services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hosted on GitHub for a reason! Please submit pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Identity Verification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Browser/Email Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug/Issue Tracking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;BitBucket Issues | &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://bitbucket.org&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bitbucket&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@bitbucket&lt;/a&gt; | $10/mo - $200/mo | Unlimited private code repositories | Host, manage, and share Git and Mercurial repositories in the cloud. Free, unlimited private repositories for up to 5 developers give teams the flexibility to grow and code without restrictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BugHerd | &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugherd.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://bugherd.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bugherd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@bugherd&lt;/a&gt; | $29/mo - $180/mo | Turn client feedback into actionable tasks. | BugHerd lets you quickly see, at a glance, how your project is going and what everyone is working on. The task board lets you keep team members in sync by assigning and scheduling tasks with a simple drag and drop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugify | $59 | &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugify.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://bugify.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bugify&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@bugify&lt;/a&gt; | Self hosted issue management system. One-time payment. Written in PHP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub Issues | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;https://github.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GitHub&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@GitHub&lt;/a&gt; | $7/mo - $50/mo | Build software better, together. | GitHub is the largest code host on the planet with over 13.2 million repositories. Large or small, every repository comes with the same powerful tools. These tools are open to the community for public projects and secure for private projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitLab Issues | &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://about.gitlab.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gitlabhq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@gitlabhq&lt;/a&gt; | free |GitLab is open source software to collaborate on code that is used by more than 100,000 organisations worldwide. Unlimited private repositories on GitLab.com or host your own instance. Enterprise Edition includes deep LDAP support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huboard | &lt;a href=&quot;https://huboard.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://huboard.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/huboard&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@huboard&lt;/a&gt; | $7/mo - $24/mo | GitHub issues made awesome Instant project management for GitHub repositories |&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JIRA | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JIRA&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@JIRA&lt;/a&gt; | $10/mo hosted - $10/yr self-hosted | JIRA is the tracker for teams planning and building great products. Thousands of teams choose JIRA to capture and organize issues, assign work, and follow team activity. At your desk or on the go with the new mobile interface, JIRA helps your team get the job done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lighthouse | &lt;a href=&quot;http://lighthouseapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://lighthouseapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lighthouseapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@lighthouseapp&lt;/a&gt; | $25/mo - $100/mo | Whether you're a large company or a small bootstrapped team, Lighthouse is the perfect ticket tracking solution. | Collaborate effortlessly on projects. Whether you’re a team of 5 or studio of 50, Lighthouse will help you keep track of your project development with ease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinitto.me | &lt;a href=&quot;https://pinitto.me&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://pinitto.me&lt;/a&gt; | Post It Notes on a virtual corkboard (OSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post It Notes on a (Physical) Wall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sifter | &lt;a href=&quot;http://sifterapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://sifterapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sifterapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@sifterapp&lt;/a&gt; | $29/mo - $149/mo | Less configuring. More doing. | We've put in the time researching bug tracking to help create the simplest possible workflow for you to get work done. From time-to-time we even blog about some of our ideas around this optimal bug tracking process…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usersnap | &lt;a href=&quot;https://usersnap.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://usersnap.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/usersnap&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@usersnap&lt;/a&gt; | $19/mo-$99/mo | Usersnap is visual bug reporting for anyone working on web projects. | Get visual feedback and precious browser information with every bug report to reproduce and fix them even faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instabug | &lt;a href=&quot;https://instabug.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://instabug.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/instabug&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@instabug&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo-$349/mo | Instabug is comprehensive bug reporting and in-app feedback tool for mobile apps. | Receive detailed feedback attached with every bug report sent by your testers or users to debug and build better apps, faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Project Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Aha! | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aha.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.aha.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aha_io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@aha_io&lt;/a&gt; | $69/mo, Ask about startup plan | The new way to create brilliant product strategy and visual roadmaps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprintly | &lt;a href=&quot;http://sprint.ly&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://sprint.ly&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sprintly&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@sprintly&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo- $399/mo | Don't ask how projects are going. Watch how they're going in real-time. | Use our elegant interface to prioritize, tag, manage, estimate, and measure your software developers' progress in real-time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podio | &lt;a href=&quot;https://podio.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://podio.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Podio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Podio&lt;/a&gt; | free | Teamwork made easy | News and views from the team behind Podio - changing the way the world works since 2009.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flow | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getflow.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.getflow.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/flowapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@flowapp&lt;/a&gt; | $19/mo - $249/mo | Stop managing projects from your inbox. | Flow is a collaborative task management app for the web and iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basecamp | &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://basecamp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/37signals&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@37signals&lt;/a&gt; | $20/mo - $150/mo | The official account for Basecamp®. Helping Basecamp customers every Mon-Fri 9am-6pm CT! | Basecamp to help organize the store design, develop fixtures, and manage craftspeople. Primarily through word-of-mouth alone, Basecamp has become the world’s #1 project management tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apollo | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apollohq.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.apollohq.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/applicomhq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@applicomhq&lt;/a&gt; | $23/mo - $148/mo | Integrated Project and Contact Management Done Right | Apollo is project and contact management done right. Using Apollo, you will realise that it's built to help you get things done, quickly and efficiently. With Apollo, you will always know where your projects, your contacts and your life are at and you will feel on top of everything — regardless of how hectic your schedule is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pivotal Tracker | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pivotaltracker.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.pivotaltracker.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pivotaltracker&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@pivotaltracker&lt;/a&gt; | $7/mo - $175/mo | BUILD BETTER SOFTWARE FASTER | Break your project down into bite-sized stories, which get your product closer to the business goal. Use points to estimate each story’s relative complexity and prioritize it in the backlog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asana | &lt;a href=&quot;https://asana.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://asana.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/asana&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@asana&lt;/a&gt; | $50/mo - $800/mo | Teamwork without email | Asana is our go-to for prioritizing projects, keeping up w/orders &amp;amp; staying on top of a growing to-do list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WeekPlan | &lt;a href=&quot;https://weekplan.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://weekplan.net&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/weekplan&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@weekplan&lt;/a&gt; | $7/mo- $19/mo | Time management inspired by the &quot;7 habits of highly effective people&quot; Features: goals of the week, week view and quadrant matrix, pomodoro timer, shared workspaces, etc...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trello | &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://trello.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trello&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@trello&lt;/a&gt; | $5/mo | Organize anything, together Trello is the fastest, easiest way to organize anything, from your day-to-day work, to a favorite side project, to your greatest life plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blossom | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blossom.co&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.blossom.co&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/blossom_io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@blossom_io&lt;/a&gt; | $19/mo - $149/mo | Agile Project Management | Blossom gives each member of the team clear overview about who’s doing what &amp;amp; why and at the same time it helps you to focus on what matters most. With Blossom you can efficiently manage your whole development process in one place, built with simplicity in mind. Blossom is based on the principles ofKanban, a way of working that emphasizes iterative delivery cycles and continuously improves the workflow of your team or organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redmine | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.redmine.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.redmine.org&lt;/a&gt; | Flexible project management web application. Written using Ruby on Rails framework, it is cross-platform and cross-database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JIRA Agile | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira/agile&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira/agile&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JIRA&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@jira&lt;/a&gt; | $10/mo - $30/mo | Dream big, work smart, deliver fast | Makers of @JIRA, @Confluence, @Bitbucket and more. Software to plan, collaborate, code, and support. Built for teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom's Planner | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomsplanner.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.tomsplanner.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomsplanner&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@tomsplanner&lt;/a&gt; | $9/mo - $19/mo | | Tom's Planner is online Gantt chart software that allows anyone to create, collaborate and share Gantt Charts online with drag and drop simplicity. It's web based, extremely intuitive and easy-to-use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LeanKit | &lt;a href=&quot;https://leankit.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://leankit.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/leankit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@leankit&lt;/a&gt; | $15/mo - $19/mo | Instant Project visibility | In LeanKit, you map your organization’s processes onto virtual whiteboards. On each board the process steps are represented as vertical and horizontal lanes. Cards represent work items, which team members update and move from across the board as they complete their share of the work. Rather than having to ask for status reports, managers and customers can just look at the board. Board updates are visible in seconds around the globe and e-mail alerts and RSS feeds are available, so you and your team can take immediate action to resolve issues before they turn into serious problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breeze | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breeze.pm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.breeze.pm&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BreezeTeam&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@BreezeTeam&lt;/a&gt; | $29/mo - $129/mo | Organize and track everything. Breeze shows you what's being worked on, who's working on what, where things are in the workflow and how much time it took.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Time Tracking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Toggl | &lt;a href=&quot;https://toggl.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://toggl.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/toggl&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@toggl&lt;/a&gt; | free-$59/mo | Toggl’s time tracker is built for speed and ease of use. Time logging with Toggl is so simple that you’ll actually use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clockify | &lt;a href=&quot;https://clockify.me&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://clockify.me&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/clockify&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@clockify&lt;/a&gt; | free | Clockify is the only 100% free time tracking software that lets you and your team track time with one click. It works like Toggl but offers unlimited features and unlimited users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hubstaff | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hubstaff.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://hubstaff.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Hubstaff&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@hubstaff&lt;/a&gt; | free-$9/mo | Hubstaff is time tracking software designed to make remote team management more effective and efficient. You just have to sign up, download our intuitive desktop app and push the start button to begin tracking time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tickspot | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tickspot.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.tickspot.com/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tickspot&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@tickspot&lt;/a&gt; | free-$149/mo | Straightforward time tracking software to help your team run more profitable projects. Whether you prefer iOS, Android, the Apple Watch, or your desktop computer, Tick is the easiest way to track your time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kimai | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kimai.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.kimai.org/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kimai_org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@kimai_org&lt;/a&gt; | Kimai is a free open source timetracker. It tracks work time and prints out a summary of your activities on demand. Yearly, monthly, daily, by customer, by project, by action, etc. | self-hosted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timetrap | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samg/timetrap&quot;&gt;https://github.com/samg/timetrap&lt;/a&gt; | free | simple open source command line time tracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;App Developer Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Localization &amp;amp; Internationalization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Business &amp;amp; Traffic Analytics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;KISSmetrics | &lt;a href=&quot;https://kissmetricshq.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://kissmetricshq.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kissmetrics/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@kissmetrics/&lt;/a&gt; | $150/mo - $500/mo | KISSmetrics tells you who’s doing it. | Every last piece gets connected to a real person. All of it. It doesn’t matter if people bounce around between different browsers and devices. Or even if it takes them 6 months to come back. You’ll see what real people do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Localytics | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.localytics.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.localytics.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/localytics/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@localytics/&lt;/a&gt; | Free up to 10k MAUs, $200/mo - $2700/mo above that | Find out what works in your mobile or web app. Do more of it. All in one place | Advanced analytics provide data and insight to help you build more successful apps. Integrated Marketing helps you easily engage and acquire more customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mixpanel | &lt;a href=&quot;https://mixpanel.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://mixpanel.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mixpanel/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@mixpanel/&lt;/a&gt; | $150/mo - $2000/mo | Actions speak louder than page views. | For years, companies have pushed page views as a primary measure of success. Page view counts are popular because they are easy to report, but ultimately cannot tell you how engaged your visitors are. Mixpanel lets you measure what customers do in your app by reporting actions, not page views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amplitude | &lt;a href=&quot;https://amplitude.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://amplitude.com&lt;/a&gt; | $299/mo | Mobile Analytics for decision makers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snowplow | &lt;a href=&quot;https://snowplowanalytics.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://snowplowanalytics.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SnowPlowData&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@SnowPlowData&lt;/a&gt; | | Snowplow is the most powerful, flexible, scalable web analytics platform in the world. | Snowplow enables analysts to perform a wide variety of both simple and sophisticated analytics on your web analytics data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Segment | &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://segment.com&lt;/a&gt; | | $29/mo - $349/mo | The right way to manage your tools. | The idea is simple: one pipeline for all your data. Send data to any third-party tool with a single integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clicky | &lt;a href=&quot;https://clicky.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://clicky.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/clicky&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@clicky&lt;/a&gt; | $9.99/mo - $19.99/mo | Real Time Web Analytics | Clicky lets you see every visitor and every action they take on your web site, with the option to attach custom data to visitors, such as usernames or email addresses. Analyze each visitor individually and see their full history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Analytics | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/analytics/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.google.com/analytics/&lt;/a&gt; | Google Analytics lets you measure your advertising ROI as well as track your Flash, video, and social networking sites and applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matomo | &lt;a href=&quot;https://matomo.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://matomo.org&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/matomo_org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@matomo_org&lt;/a&gt; | Whether you are an individual blogger, a small business, or a large corporation, Matomo helps you gain valuable insights to help your business or readership grow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chartio | &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartio.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://chartio.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chartio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@chartio&lt;/a&gt; | | Visualize and explore your data with Chartio. | Create interactive charts and perfect dashboards through an intuitive drag and drop interface. Switch from basic tables to sophisticated data visualizations in a single click. Powerful filters let you slice and dice your data, and you can drill down into most charts without configuring a thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chartbeat | &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartbeat.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://chartbeat.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chartbeat&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@chartbeat&lt;/a&gt; | $9.95/mo - $49.95/mo | Build a loyal and valuable audience for your site. | Chartbeat's real-time traffic and audience-behavior data shows you who's on your site and how they're engaging with your content right now — so you can take action on what matters when it matters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calq | &lt;a href=&quot;https://calq.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://calq.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CalqAnalytics&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@CalqAnalytics&lt;/a&gt; | $0 - $2500/mo | Advanced custom analytics for mobile and web applications. | Calq is an analytics platform that measures user actions rather than page views. An action can be anything a user does: reviewing a product, playing a level on a mobile game, making a purchase on your site, anything. Calq's ability to work with custom events AND custom data is what raises it above more traditional analytics platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoSquared | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gosquared.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.gosquared.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GoSquared&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@gosquared&lt;/a&gt; | £21.60 - £396/mo | Easy to use real-time web analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvely | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.improvely.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.improvely.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/improvelycom&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@improvelycom&lt;/a&gt; | $29 - $899/mo | Conversion tracking and click fraud monitoring platform. The easiest way to track the performance of marketing campaigns and monitor them for click fraud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keen IO | &lt;a href=&quot;https://keen.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://keen.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/keen_io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@keen_io&lt;/a&gt; | $0 - $2000+/mo | Custom analytics shouldn't be a pain in the backend. Keen IO's powerful APIs do the heavy lifting for you, so you can gather all the data you want and start getting the answers you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heap Analytics | &lt;a href=&quot;https://heapanalytics.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://heapanalytics.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/heap&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@heap&lt;/a&gt; | 0 - $599+ | Instant, retroactive analytics for web and iOS. No code required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gauges | &lt;a href=&quot;https://get.gaug.es&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://get.gaug.es&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gaugesapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@GaugesApp&lt;/a&gt; | $6-$48/mo | Gauges provides real time web analytics such as how many people visit your site, where they come from, and where they go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wisdom | &lt;a href=&quot;https://getWisdom.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://getWisdom.io&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $2000+/mo | Session Replay | Wisdom is the most accurate live visitor session recorder service available. Focusing only on session replay, Wisdom reconstructs a virtual desktop screen for every visitor, across all tabs, to capture the true feel of every visitor's experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Conversion Optimization &amp;amp; A/B Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Optimizely | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.optimizely.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.optimizely.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/optimizely&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@optimizely&lt;/a&gt; | $17/mo - $359/mo | A/B testing you'll actually use | Track engagement, clicks, conversions, sign ups, or anything else that matters to you and your business. Optimizely's custom goal tracking provides an endless range of measurable actions that you can define. Just tell Optimizely what to measure, and we will do the rest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual Website Optimizer | &lt;a href=&quot;https://vwo.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://vwo.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wingify&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@wingify&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo - $129/mo | Increase your website sales and conversions | Using Visual Website Optimizer, they A/B test different versions of their website and landing pages to find out which one works best. Made for marketers, our tool is incredibly easy to use, and doesn't need IT resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EyeQuant | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eyequant.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.eyequant.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eyequant&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@eyequant&lt;/a&gt; | $199/mo - $999/mo | Instantly understand what your visitors will see and miss in their first seconds on your site, and improve your conversions. Analyse live sites or mockups within seconds, no code required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;User Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;User Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Silverback 2.0 | &lt;a href=&quot;http://silverbackapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://silverbackapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/silverbackapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@silverbackapp&lt;/a&gt; | 69.95 | Guerrilla usability testing software for designers and developers | Silverback makes it easy, quick and cheap for everyone to perform guerrilla usability tests with no setup and no expense, using hardware already in your Mac.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HotJar | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hotjar.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.hotjar.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hotjar&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@hotjar&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $29/mo (personal) | Records videos and collects heatmaps of your site visitor actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wisdom | &lt;a href=&quot;https://getWisdom.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://getWisdom.io&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $2000+/mo | Session Replay | Wisdom is the most accurate live visitor session recorder service available. Focusing only on session replay, Wisdom reconstructs a virtual desktop screen for every visitor, across all tabs, to capture the true feel of every visitor's experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;HR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Workday | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.workday.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.workday.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/workday&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@workday&lt;/a&gt; | | Workday works the way people work—collaboratively, on the go, and in real-time. Explore the product previews below to learn how Workday can change the way you work. | With powerful business applications and a user experience that's unmatched in enterprise software, Workday gives you everything you need to transform your business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lever | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lever.co&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.lever.co&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lever&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@lever&lt;/a&gt; | A modern web app for hiring | Leverage your entire company – interviewers, managers, and recruiters – to source, vet, and close.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zenefits | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zenefits.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.zenefits.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zenefits&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@zenefits&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo | The #1 All-In-One HR Platform | Payroll. Benefits. Time. Compliance. All online, all in one place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TestDome | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.testdome.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.testdome.com/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TestDome&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@TestDome&lt;/a&gt; | $8/candidate - $20/candidate | Automated testing of programming skills, ask candidates to write real code before calling them for an interview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HackerRank | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackerrank.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.hackerrank.com/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hackerrank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@hackerrank&lt;/a&gt; | paid | End-to-end technical recruiting platform for hiring engineers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Payroll&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gusto | &lt;a href=&quot;https://gusto.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://gusto.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gustohq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@gustohq&lt;/a&gt; | $29/mo + $6/user | Payroll and benefits that put people first, easy setup, automated tax filings and thoughtful support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WagePoint | &lt;a href=&quot;https://wagepoint.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://wagepoint.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wagepoint&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@wagepoint&lt;/a&gt; | $20 + $2/employy | The Simple, Fast &amp;amp; Friendly way to pay your employees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Continuous Integration/Code Quality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Travis | &lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://travis-ci.org&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/travisci&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@travisci&lt;/a&gt; | free - $489/mo | Hi I’m Travis CI, a hosted continuous integration service for open source and private projects: &lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;travis-ci.com&lt;/a&gt; System status updates: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/traviscistatus&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@traviscistatus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AppVeyor | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.appveyor.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.appveyor.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/appveyor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@appveyor&lt;/a&gt; | AppVeyor automates building, testing and deployment of .NET applications, helping your team to focus on delivering great apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Codeship | &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeship.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://codeship.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/codeship&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@codeship&lt;/a&gt; | Continuous Delivery as a service, start testing and deploying your code immediately | Start with 100 builds per month free, Unlimited plans start at 49$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Circle | &lt;a href=&quot;http://circleci.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://circleci.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/circleci&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@circleci&lt;/a&gt; | $19/mo - $269/mo | Ship better code, faster | Easy, fast, continuous integration and deployment for web apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nevercode | &lt;a href=&quot;https://nevercode.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://nevercode.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nevercodehq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@nevercodehq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hound | &lt;a href=&quot;https://houndci.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://houndci.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/houndci&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@houndci&lt;/a&gt; | Free | Automated Code Review | Take care of pesky code reviews with a trusty Hound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CodeClimate | &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeclimate.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://codeclimate.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/codeclimate&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@codeclimate&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo - $399/mo | Automated Code Review | Code Climate hosted software metrics help you ship quality Ruby and JavaScript code faster. Get control of your technical debt with real time static analysis of your code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Codacy | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codacy.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.codacy.com&lt;/a&gt; | $0-$150/mo | Automated Code Review | Continuous Static Analysis designed to complement your unit tests. Similar to CodeClimate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Codecov | &lt;a href=&quot;https://codecov.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://codecov.io&lt;/a&gt; | $0-$5/mo | Hosted Code Coverage | Code coverage reporting done right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semaphore | &lt;a href=&quot;https://semaphoreci.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://semaphoreci.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/semaphoreci&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@semaphoreci&lt;/a&gt; | $14/mo - $899/mo | Create an Amazing Workflow. | Semaphore assumes that your private or open source project is on GitHub. There are no new dependencies, hooks or SSH keys to manage. It works without any change in source code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solano CI | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.solanolabs.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.solanolabs.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/solanolabs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@SolanoLabs&lt;/a&gt; | $15/mo - $100/mo | Faster Continuous Integration and Deployment with patented auto-parallelization | Solano CI sets up Continuous Integration in minutes, frees you from managing a build server, and lets you deploy software 10x - 80x faster by running tests in parallel safely and automatically. It also lets you use our massively scalable environment even before you push to CI. Seamlessly integrates into existing workflows. Free 14-day trial, no credit card required. Formerly loved as tddium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jenkins | &lt;a href=&quot;https://jenkins.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://jenkins.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jenkinsci&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@jenkinsci&lt;/a&gt; | Jenkins provides continuous integration services for software development. It is a server-based system that supports SCM tools including AccuRev, CVS, Subversion, Git, Mercurial, Perforce, Clearcase and RTC, and can execute Apache Ant and Apache Maven based projects as well as arbitrary shell scripts and Windows batch commands. Released under the MIT License, Jenkins is free software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bamboo | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/software/bamboo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.atlassian.com/software/bamboo&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/atlassian&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@atlassian&lt;/a&gt; | $10/mo - $1000/mo | | Bamboo does more than just run builds and tests. It connects issues, commits, test results, and deploys so the whole picture is available to your entire product team – from project managers, to devs and testers, to sys admins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buildkite (Buildbox) | &lt;a href=&quot;https://buildkite.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://buildkite.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/buildkite&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@buildkite&lt;/a&gt; | $15/dev/mo | Semi-hosted continuous integration and deployment | Buildkite uses your own infrastructure to run builds so you can test any language or run any deployment scripts. You can run as many parallel agents (and builds) as you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crucible | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/software/crucible&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.atlassian.com/software/crucible&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/atlassian&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@atlassian&lt;/a&gt; | $10/mo - $8000/mo | Code review system | Review code, discuss changes, share knowledge, and identify defects with Crucible's flexible review workflow. It's code review made easy for Git, Subversion, CVS, Perforce, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coveralls | &lt;a href=&quot;https://coveralls.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://coveralls.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/coverallsapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@coverallsapp&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo - $50/mo | Coveralls works with your continuous integration server to give you test coverage history and statistics. It integrates with any langauge and is free for open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testributor | &lt;a href=&quot;http://about.testributor.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://about.testributor.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/testributor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@testributor&lt;/a&gt; | Free | Testributor is an open source Continuous Integration platform. A hosted version is available for free, both for open source and private projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wercker | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wercker.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.wercker.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wercker&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@wercker&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo - $350/mo | Wercker is a Docker-Native CI/CD Automation platform for Kubernetes &amp;amp; Microservice Deployments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monkey Test It | &lt;a href=&quot;https://monkeytest.it&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://monkeytest.it&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/monkeytestit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@monkeytestit&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo - $199/mo | Automated website checking tool to catch bugs on your website (broken links, missing images, JS errors, etc) before your users do. Integrates with Slack, most CI systems, webooks, and supports built-in scheduling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Dashboards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Geckoboard | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.geckoboard.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/geckoboard&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@geckoboard&lt;/a&gt; | $17/mo - $899/mo | Meet Geckoboard. It's Your Key Data, In One Place. | Geckoboard monitors your business’s vital signs – don’t wait, see it live on a business dashboard as it happens. Focus on what matters and react faster to important events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Telemetry | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telemetrytv.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.telemetrytv.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/telemetrytv&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@telemetrytv&lt;/a&gt; | $9/mo - $749/mo | Build realtime dashboard with powerful visualizations that look beautiful on big screen TVs, desktop computers, mobile devices, and embedded systems—all using a simple REST API that works with all modern languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashing | &lt;a href=&quot;http://dashing.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://dashing.io&lt;/a&gt; | Dashing is a Sinatra based framework that lets you build beautiful dashboards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Klipfolio | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.klipfolio.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.klipfolio.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/klipfolio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@klipfolio&lt;/a&gt; | $5/user/mo - $20/user/mo | Meet Your Business Dashboard | Connect to any data service to bring your key numbers together on one dashboard. Assign your data to visualizations to show the story behind the numbers. Cultivate a data-driven culture by sharing dashboards with everyone on your team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grafana | &lt;a href=&quot;https://grafana.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://grafana.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/grafana&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@grafana&lt;/a&gt; | $0 - $90/mo (+9/user/mo) | The analytics platform for all your metrics | Grafana allows you to query, visualize, alert on and understand your metrics no matter where they are stored. Create, explore, and share dashboards with your team and foster a data driven culture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Error/Exception Handling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CatchJS | &lt;a href=&quot;https://catchjs.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://catchjs.com&lt;/a&gt; | $49 - $499 | JavaScript error reporting for web apps. Can take screenshots and collect click trails, so reproducing bugs becomes easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crashlytics | &lt;a href=&quot;http://try.crashlytics.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://try.crashlytics.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/crashlytics&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@crashlytics&lt;/a&gt; | Free | Crash reports and grouping for easier analysis. Basic analytics and reports. | iOS &amp;amp; Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sentry | &lt;a href=&quot;https://sentry.io/welcome/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://sentry.io/welcome/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getsentry&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@getsentry&lt;/a&gt; | $24/mo - $199/mo | Sentry notifies you when your users experience errors. | Know immediately when things happen in your application. Engage users before they have a chance to report a problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HoneyBadger | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.honeybadger.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.honeybadger.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/honeybadgerapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@honeybadgerapp&lt;/a&gt; | $39/mo - $249/mo | Exception, uptime, and performance monitoring for Ruby. | It tells you about errors, downtime and performance issues as they happen. And it gives you the tools you need to fix them ...without burying you in data. Without silly rate limits or per-server fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BugSnag | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bugsnag.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.bugsnag.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bugsnag&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@bugsnag&lt;/a&gt; | $29/mo - $249/mo | Automatic, full-stack error monitoring | Web app monitoring for Rails, PHP, Node.js, Java, and every other leading platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raygun | &lt;a href=&quot;https://raygun.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://raygun.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/raygunio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@raygunio&lt;/a&gt; | $14/mo - $199/mo | Exceptional Error Tracking | Your software faults get automatically sent to the Raygun service and analysis begins immediately. Raygun intelligently groups your errors so you're dealing with root causes, not every single error instance!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Airbrake | &lt;a href=&quot;https://airbrake.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://airbrake.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/airbrake&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@airbrake&lt;/a&gt; | $49-249/mo | No More Searching Log Files Capture and Track Your Application's Exceptions in 3 Minutes | Airbrake is the leading exception reporting service, currently providing error tracking for 50,000 applications with support for 18 programming languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atatus | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atatus.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.atatus.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/atatusapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@atatusapp&lt;/a&gt; | $12/mo - $159/mo | Simple JavaScript Error Tracking | Atatus is a simple error tracking and uptime monitoring system. Add two lines of code and get alerted on any errors that occurs in your application in realtime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rollbar | &lt;a href=&quot;https://rollbar.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://rollbar.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rollbar&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@rollbar&lt;/a&gt; | $12/mo - $1249/mo | Take control of your errors | Rollbar is platform-agnostic and can accept data from anything that can speak HTTP and JSON. You can use our official libraries for Ruby, Python, PHP, Node.js, JavaScript, Android, iOS, or Flash, or roll your own with our API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Errorception | &lt;a href=&quot;https://errorception.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://errorception.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/errorception&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@errorception&lt;/a&gt; | $5/mo - $59/mo | Painless JavaScript Error Tracking | Errorception is a simple and painless way to find out about JavaScript errors, as they occur in your users' browsers. All you need to do is insert a script tag on your page, and you will start recording errors as they happen in real-time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Errbit | OSS | &lt;a href=&quot;https://errbit.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://errbit.com&lt;/a&gt; | The open source error catcher that's Airbrake API compliant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OverOps | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.overops.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.overops.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/overopshq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@overopshq&lt;/a&gt; | God Mode in Production Code for java and scala applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Application Distribution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;HockeyApp | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hockeyapp.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.hockeyapp.net&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hockeyapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@hockeyapp&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $129/mo depending on number of apps and number of owners | Distribution of iOS, Android, Windows Phone and Mac OS apps | Includes analytics, user feedback and crash reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Log Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fluentd | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fluentd.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.fluentd.org&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fluentd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@fluentd&lt;/a&gt; | | Set Up Once, Collect More | Fluentd is an open source data collector designed for processing data streams. 150+ plugins instantly enable you to store the data for Log Management, Big Data Analytics, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flume | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cloudera/flume&quot;&gt;https://github.com/cloudera/flume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graylog | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.graylog.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.graylog.org&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/graylog2&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@graylog2&lt;/a&gt; | Field-tested open source data analytics system used and trusted all around the world. Search your logs, create charts, send reports and be alerted when something happens. All running on the existing JVM in your datacenter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LogEntries | &lt;a href=&quot;https://logentries.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://logentries.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/logentries&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@logentries&lt;/a&gt; | $16/mo - $245/mo | Log Management &amp;amp; Analytics Made Easy | Logentries provides an easy-to-use cloud service for log management and analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loggly | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loggly.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.loggly.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/loggly&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@loggly&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo - $349/mo | Solve operational problems faster. | Loggly helps cloud-centric organizations—organizations that build and manage cloud-facing applications—to solve operational problems faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logstash | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elastic.co/products/logstash&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.elastic.co/products/logstash&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/logstash&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@logstash&lt;/a&gt; | | Ship logs from any source, parse them, get the right timestamp, index them, and search them. | logstash is a tool for managing events and logs. You can use it to collect logs, parse them, and store them for later use (like, for searching). Speaking of searching, logstash comes with a web interface for searching and drilling into all of your logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Papertrail | &lt;a href=&quot;https://papertrailapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://papertrailapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/papertrailapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@papertrailapp&lt;/a&gt; | $7/mo - $230/mo | Frustration-free log management. Get started in seconds. | Use Papertrail's time-saving log tools, flexible system groups, team-wide access, long-term archives, charts and analytics exports, monitoring webhooks, and 45-second setup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stackify | &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackify.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://stackify.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Stackify&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Stackify&lt;/a&gt; | $15/ mo | Connecting the dots for you | Stackify focuses on application health, magnifying critical insights for developers, operations, and support teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;statsd | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/etsy/statsd/&quot;&gt;https://github.com/etsy/statsd/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sumo Logic | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sumologic.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.sumologic.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SumoLogic&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@SumoLogic&lt;/a&gt; | | Log Data is Big Data | Once enabled by the administrator, the new data will be searchable in the customer account. Sumo Logic provides an Application for Data Volume for out-of–the-box dashboards and searches that deliver a comprehensive view of data usage volume by category, collector, source name, and hosts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Application Performance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;AppNeta | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.appneta.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.appneta.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AppNeta&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@AppNeta&lt;/a&gt; | Free to $119 / mo | Full-stack application monitoring for web apps | Get visibility into code, network, and end user, especially for polyglot and service-oriented applications, by looking at transactions, errors, browser metrics, host metrics, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DripStat | &lt;a href=&quot;https://dripstat.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://dripstat.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dripstat&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@DripStat&lt;/a&gt; | $20/ mo | Application monitoring for Java | Next gen Java APM. Full visibility across your stack. Specificially designed for Java. Supports SQL databases, MongoDB and Cassandra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Relic | &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrelic.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://newrelic.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NewRelic&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@NewRelic&lt;/a&gt; | $149/ mo | Application monitoring for all your web apps. | It’s about gaining actionable, real-time business insights from the billions of metrics your software is producing, including user click streams, mobile activity, end user experiences and transactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AppSignal | &lt;a href=&quot;https://appsignal.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://appsignal.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AppSignal&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@AppSignal&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo - $259/mo | Better monitoring for your Rails applications. | Get detailled statistics on your site's performance with mean and 90th percentile measurements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instrumental | &lt;a href=&quot;https://instrumentalapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://instrumentalapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/instrumental&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@instrumental&lt;/a&gt; | $150/mo - $750/mo | Monitor Your App in Realtime | Instrumental’s made to monitor metrics at a ridiculously high scale. At rates of 500,000 metrics per second and higher, it doesn’t even break a sweat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Load Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bees with Machine Guns! | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/newsapps/beeswithmachineguns&quot;&gt;https://github.com/newsapps/beeswithmachineguns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flood.io | &lt;a href=&quot;https://flood.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://flood.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/flood_io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@flood_io&lt;/a&gt; | Free to $399/mo | Auto setup and results summaries/graphs of JMeter and Gatling load tests. Can easily scale to 100K+ reqs/min.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neustar Website Load Testing | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neustar.biz/services/web-performance/load-testing&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.neustar.biz/services/web-performance/load-testing&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Neustar&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Neustar&lt;/a&gt; | $80/mo | | Tackle performance problems such as bandwidth limitations, error rates exceeding thresholds, server PU limitations and much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loader.io | &lt;a href=&quot;https://loader.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://loader.io&lt;/a&gt; | Free to 100.00$ / mo | Loader.io is a free load testing service that allows you to stress test your web-apps/apis with thousands of concurrent connections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locust.io | &lt;a href=&quot;https://locust.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://locust.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/locustio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@locustio&lt;/a&gt; | Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;k6.io | &lt;a href=&quot;https://k6.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://k6.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/k6_io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@k6_io&lt;/a&gt; | Free | Open Source | k6 is a developer centric open source load testing tool for testing the performance of your backend infrastructure. It’s built with Go and JavaScript to integrate well into your development workflow, so you can stay on top of performance without fuzz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loadimpact.com | &lt;a href=&quot;https://loadimpact.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://loadimpact.com/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/loadimpact&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@loadimpact&lt;/a&gt; | $99.00+ | A SaaS performance testing solution for modern DevOps teams, built on top of the open source k6.io project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Server Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Server Density | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.serverdensity.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.serverdensity.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/serverdensity&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@serverdensity&lt;/a&gt; | | Premium hosted website and server monitoring tool. | All your activity syncs in real time - from starting new instances to upgrading or deleting old ones. Work wherever you want - through web, mobile, API or directly with your provider. Everything stays in sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Datadog | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datadoghq.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.datadoghq.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/datadoghq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@datadoghq&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo - $15/host/mo | Datadog is a monitoring service for IT, Operations and Development teams who write and run applications at scale, and want to turn the massive amounts of data produced by their apps, tools and services into actionable insight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Circonus | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.circonus.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.circonus.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/circonus&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@circonus&lt;/a&gt; | $15/host/mo - $25/host/mo | Circonus combines multiple monitoring, alerting, event reporting, and analytical tools into one unified solution. Use any data, in any application, from any system, and visualize it in real-time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TrueSight Pulse | &lt;a href=&quot;http://truesightpulse.bmc.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://truesightpulse.bmc.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/truesightpulse&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@truesightpulse&lt;/a&gt; | | Real-time visibility into cloud and server infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Librato | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.librato.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.librato.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Librato&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Librato&lt;/a&gt; | $0.05/metric/mo to $0.30/metric/mo | Librato provides a complete solution for monitoring and understanding the metrics that impact your business at all levels of the stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scout | &lt;a href=&quot;https://scoutapp.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://scoutapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Customer Support/Help Desks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Desk | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.desk.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.desk.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/desk&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@desk&lt;/a&gt; | $3/mo - $50/mo | Deliver Customer Service That Wows | Desk.com creates the leading customer service application, which helps fast-growing companies deliver outstanding customer support. Desk.com's intuitive user interface and powerful features make solving customers' problems more efficient for the entire company. Plus, Desk.com is the only Customer Service Application backed by Salesforce, providing easy integration with other Salesforce services and robust security. There are thousands of companies using Desk.com as their help desk software application, from household names like Square and Instagram to the burrito shop down the street. Give it a try for free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HelpScout | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.helpscout.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.helpscout.net&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/helpscout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@helpscout&lt;/a&gt; | $15/ mo | Scalable customer support, no help desk headaches | Based on conditions you specify, Help Scout automatically performs one or more actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ZenDesk | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zendesk.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zendesk&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@zendesk&lt;/a&gt; | $1/mo - $195/mo | Relationships between businesses and their customers can be hard. | Better customer service starts with better communication Zendesk brings all your customer conversations into one place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groove | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.groovehq.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.groovehq.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/groove&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@groove&lt;/a&gt; | $15/ mo | Everything you need to deliver awesome, personal support to every customer. | Your customers will never know that you’re using a helpdesk. To them, your messages look like regular emails. It feels like personal support, and it helps you build deeper relationships with your customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intercom | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intercom.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.intercom.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intercom&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@intercom&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo - $449/mo | The easiest way to see and talk to your users | Intercom is a single platform where you can see in real-time who is using your product and send personalized messages to the right users at the right time based on their behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tender | &lt;a href=&quot;http://tenderapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://tenderapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tenderapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@tenderapp&lt;/a&gt; | $9/mo - $99/mo | Better, Simpler, Customer Support Software. | Support your customers in the open! With public forums, you can offer a public space to your users to discuss common issues and get feedback, while still keeping certain categories private (billing, orders, ...). Power users can subscribe to categories and new discussions, and help out other customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enchant | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enchant.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.enchant.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/enchanthq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@enchanthq&lt;/a&gt; | $9/ mo | It's like gmail on steroids! | Enchant is a powerful helpdesk that helps your team deliver awesome support to each and every customer. To your customers, it's just email. They will never see a ticket number and will never have to log into anything!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freshdesk | &lt;a href=&quot;https://freshdesk.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://freshdesk.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/freshdesk&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@freshdesk&lt;/a&gt; | $16/mo - $70/mo | Everything you need to deliver Exceptional Customer Support | Freshdesk keeps you from running behind issues blindly and gets your customer support issues under control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UserDeck | &lt;a href=&quot;https://userdeck.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://userdeck.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/user_deck&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@user_deck&lt;/a&gt; | $0 - $25/mo | Customer support software that embeds into your existing website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sirportly | &lt;a href=&quot;https://sirportly.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://sirportly.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sirportly&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@sirportly&lt;/a&gt; | £0 - £15/mo | Grow your business and provide world class customer support. Simply setup your helpdesk in less than a few minutes. Integrate with your other software tools and take advantage of the automated rules and macros to scale your customer support to a new level, become more professional and customer focused and turn your customers into raving fans with Sirportly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Olark | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.olark.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.olark.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SnapEngage | &lt;a href=&quot;https://snapengage.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://snapengage.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get Satisfaction! | &lt;a href=&quot;https://getsatisfaction.com/corp/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://getsatisfaction.com/corp/&lt;/a&gt; | Customer communities for social support, social marketing &amp;amp; customer feedback - online community software | Get Satisfaction is the leading customer engagement platform that helps companies build better relationships with their customers and prospects, through the best online customer community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reamaze | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reamaze.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.reamaze.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/reamaze&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@reamaze&lt;/a&gt; | $15/mo | Lightweight, Lightspeed Help Desk. Email, Social, Branded, Integrated. | Reamaze provides your team with helpdesk functionality that integrates with your application, as well as integrations with popular 3rd party tools in your workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jitbit Helpdesk | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jitbit.com/helpdesk/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.jitbit.com/helpdesk/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jitbithelpdesk&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@jitbithelpdesk&lt;/a&gt; | $29/mo - $199/mo | A help desk app that actually makes your work easier, not harder. | Comes in both hosted and on-premise versions. Very well designed and easy to use. Has all the must-have features and doesn't get in your way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drift | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drift.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.drift.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/drift&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@drift&lt;/a&gt; | free for &amp;lt; 100 contacts, paid from $49/mo | Stop wasting your website traffic. | Sales-oriented live chat and in-app messaging, with chatbot automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drift | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drift.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.drift.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/drift&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@drift&lt;/a&gt; | free for &amp;lt; 100 contacts, paid from $49/mo | Stop wasting your website traffic. | Sales-oriented live chat and in-app messaging, with chatbot automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zammad | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zammad.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.zammad.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zammadhq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@zammadhq&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo - $24/mo | Zammad is a award winning open source helpdesk/customer support system with a beautiful UI and many features to manage customer communication via several channels like telephone, facebook, twitter, chat and e-mails. It is distributed under the GNU AFFERO General Public License (AGPL).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Transactional Email&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Postmark | &lt;a href=&quot;https://postmarkapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://postmarkapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/postmarkapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@postmarkapp&lt;/a&gt; | $1.50 | Email delivery for web apps – done right. | Postmark removes the headaches of delivering and parsing transactional email for webapps with minimal setup time and zero maintenance. We have years of experience getting email to the inbox, so you can work and rest easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandrill | &lt;a href=&quot;http://mandrill.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://mandrill.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mandrillapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@mandrillapp&lt;/a&gt; | $0.20/mo - $0.10/mo | THE FASTEST WAY TO DELIVER EMAIL | Mandrill is a scalable and affordable email infrastructure service. Whether you're just getting started, have some questions, or are looking for a quick reference, we've got you covered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MailGun | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mailgun.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.mailgun.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Mail_Gun&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Mail_Gun&lt;/a&gt; | $20.00 | The Email Service For Developers | Easy SMTP integration and a simple, RESTful API abstracts away the messy details of email. Scale quickly, whether you need to send 10 or 10 million emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS SES&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SendGrid | &lt;a href=&quot;https://sendgrid.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://sendgrid.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SendGrid&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@SendGrid&lt;/a&gt; | $9.95/mo - $399.95 | Email Delivery. Simplified. | SendGrid delivers billions of emails for companies of all sizes every month. Select the package that best fits with your sending volume, set-up your account, and let SendGrid take care of the rest!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CritSend | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.critsend.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.critsend.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/critsend&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@critsend&lt;/a&gt; | $50/mo - $3000/Mo | The Best SMTP Relay for Developers | Use the most reliable infrastructure for your transactional and bulk emails. It only takes 5 minutes to setup Critsend and start enjoying fast delivery time and automatic scalability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postage | &lt;a href=&quot;http://postageapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://postageapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/postagebird&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@postagebird&lt;/a&gt; | $9/mo - $399/mo | The easier way to send email from web apps | ostageApp helps design, send, and analyze emails within minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sendwithus | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sendwithus.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.sendwithus.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/send_with_us&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@sendwithus&lt;/a&gt; | Free 'Hacker' plan of 1000 messages/month | Transactional email A/B testing and drip campaigns |&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Other APIs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Filestack | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filestack.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.filestack.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FileStack&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@FileStack&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo - $49/mo | Easy, Powerful File Uploads | Connect, Store, and Process any file from anywhere on the Internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Exchange Rates | &lt;a href=&quot;https://openexchangerates.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://openexchangerates.org&lt;/a&gt; | | $12/mo - $97/mo | Real-time exchange rates &amp;amp; currency conversion JSON API | A simple and easy-to-integrate exchange rates API in JSON format, with HTTPS and JSONP support, with examples, guides and full documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FormAPI | &lt;a href=&quot;https://formapi.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://formapi.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/form_api&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@form_api&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo - $249/mo | PDF Service for Developers | Makes it easy for programmers to fill out and sign PDF documents. Saves a lot of development time if you need to generate a lot of contracts, invoices, etc. |&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Site Search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Elasticsearch | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elastic.co/products/elasticsearch&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.elastic.co/products/elasticsearch&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/elasticsearch&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@elasticsearch&lt;/a&gt; | | an end-to-end search and analytics platform. infinitely versatile. | By combining the massively popular Elasticsearch, Logstash and Kibana we have created an end-to-end stack that delivers actionable insights in real-time from almost any type of structured and unstructured data source. Built and supported by the engineers behind each of these open source products, the Elasticsearch ELK stack makes searching and analyzing data easier than ever before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swiftype | &lt;a href=&quot;https://swiftype.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://swiftype.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/swiftype&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Swiftype&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $250/mo, Enterprise Plans available | Swiftype is a hosted website search service, available as a web crawler or as an API integration. API clients are available for major frameworks and languages, plugins are available for major third party platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algolia | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algolia.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.algolia.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Algolia&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Algolia&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo - $449/mo | Build Realtime Search | Algolia is a fully hosted search service, available as a REST API. API clients are also available for all major frameworks, platforms and languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache Solr | &lt;a href=&quot;http://lucene.apache.org/solr/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://lucene.apache.org/solr/&lt;/a&gt; - an open source search platform, based and co-released with Apache Lucene.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon Cloudsearch | &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/cloudsearch/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://aws.amazon.com/cloudsearch/&lt;/a&gt; | Search SaaS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Email Marketing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;MailCharts | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mailcharts.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.mailcharts.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mailcharts&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@mailcharts&lt;/a&gt; | $30/mo | Track &amp;amp; understand how your competitors use email marketing | MailCharts tracks over a thousand companies, bringing you actionable insights to help you improve your email marketing strategy, make data-driven decisions and gain design and content inspiration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer.io | &lt;a href=&quot;https://customer.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://customer.io&lt;/a&gt; | | $50/mo - $1250/Mo | Send email based on what people do or don't do in your app | Customer.io lets you send newsletters to segments of customers using data from your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vero | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getvero.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.getvero.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/veroapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@veroapp&lt;/a&gt; | $99/mo | Send emails based on what your customers do | Vero makes it easy to create segments of customers based on the attributes you capture (e.g. age, location, gender) and the actions your customers take (e.g. logged in, used feature x, checked out, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MailChimp | &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchimp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://mailchimp.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Campaign Monitor | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campaignmonitor.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.campaignmonitor.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campaignmonitor.com/customers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@&lt;/a&gt; | $9/mo - $699/mo | CAMPUnbounce Feature Tour |&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sendy | &lt;a href=&quot;https://sendy.co&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://sendy.co&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getSendy&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@getsendy&lt;/a&gt; | $59 one time fee, host yourselfor use a hosted sendy instance from a variety of providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image-Charts | &lt;a href=&quot;https://image-charts.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://image-charts.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/imagecharts&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@imagecharts&lt;/a&gt; | free - $49/mo, self-hosted plan available | Include animated charts as image into emails, no server-side rendering, 1 URL = 1 chart, compatible with Google Image Charts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drip | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drip.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.drip.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getdrip&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@getdrip&lt;/a&gt; | free for &amp;lt; 100 subscribers, paid plans from $49/mo | Advanced marketing automation with workflows, drip campaigns, conversion tracking etc..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MailerLite | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mailerlite.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.mailerlite.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mailerlite&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@mailerlite&lt;/a&gt; | free - $140/month | free plan offers a lot of features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MarketHero | &lt;a href=&quot;https://markethero.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://markethero.io/&lt;/a&gt; | $99+/mo | Autoresponder / email marketing tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Email Collection/Landing Page Apps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Launchrock | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.launchrock.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.launchrock.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/launchrock&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@launchrock&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo - $199/mo | | Even if you know how to code a web page with HTML, you'll love how much faster it is with our landing page builder. Load up your logo and graphic assets, set up a few base colors from your brand palette and publish away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unbounce | &lt;a href=&quot;https://unbounce.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://unbounce.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unbounce&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@unbounce&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo - $199/mo | | Unbounce empowers marketers to act independently from technical teams, improving their efficiency and their ability to generate sales. Produce high-converting landing pages without dealing with I.T. bottlenecks. See how Unbounce can enhance your campaigns and maximize your marketing spend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LeadPages | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leadpages.net/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.leadpages.net/&lt;/a&gt; | $25/mo - $199/mo | Generate leads and increase revenue using the industry-leading landing page builder with accompanying suite of lead generation and opt-in tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instapge | &lt;a href=&quot;https://instapage.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://instapage.com/&lt;/a&gt; | $29/mo - $127/mo | A landing page solution for optimizing your ad spend. Build, Integrate, Collaborate &amp;amp; Optimize.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KickoffLabs | &lt;a href=&quot;https://kickofflabs.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://kickofflabs.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kickofflabs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@kickofflabs&lt;/a&gt; | $29/mo - $99/mo | Stop building landing pages. Start building smarter campaigns. | Send customers to a tailored page that speaks to them. Keep them engaged with signup-forms, newsletters and – best of all – a very cool, unique REWARD system for customer referrals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prefinery | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prefinery.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.prefinery.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/prefinery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@prefinery&lt;/a&gt; | $19/mo- $399/mo | Stress-free Beta Invitation and Management | Prefinery is beta invitations &amp;amp; management for serious product launches. You need more than just a landing page -- outsource your beta to Prefinery!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;CRM/Sales Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Salesforce | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salesforce.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.salesforce.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/salesforce&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@salesforce&lt;/a&gt; | | TRANSFORM CONSUMERS INTO CUSTOMERS ACROSS ALL DIGITAL CHANNELS. | The ExactTarget Marketing Cloud, built on the Salesforce1 Platform, allows marketers to create 1:1 campaigns like never before. So you can combine traditional digital channels like email, mobile, social, and the web with any conceivable IP-addressable product to turn consumers into customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SalesforceIQ | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.salesforceiq.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.salesforceiq.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/salesforceiq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@salesforceiq&lt;/a&gt; | £17-85/user/mo | Helps businesses build stronger relationships using Relationship Intelligence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SugarCRM | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sugarcrm.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.sugarcrm.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sugarcrm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@sugarcrm&lt;/a&gt; | $35/mo - $150/mo | Sugar's open, flexible platform easily solves real business problems. From automating sales, marketing and customer support to creating a custom CRM application, we've got you covered. | By placing the individual at the center of its solution, SugarCRM puts the &quot;i&quot; in CRM and empowers every customer-facing individual to create extraordinary customer relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insight.ly | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insightly.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.insightly.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/insightly&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@insightly&lt;/a&gt; | $7/mo | Small Business CRM | Manage contacts, organizations, partners, vendors and suppliers. See everything from background, email history, events, projects or opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close.io | &lt;a href=&quot;https://close.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://close.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/closeio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@closeio&lt;/a&gt; | $59/mo - $299/mo | Sales Communication Platform | Close.io automatically logs sent and received emails with your leads. You can send/receive emails painlessly from Close.io. Or, by entering your IMAP and SMTP mail settings, Close.io can track emails that you send from Gmail or any email client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streak | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.streak.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.streak.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/streak&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@streak&lt;/a&gt; | | Manage email support inside Gmail | Streak lets you keep track of all your deals right from your inbox. We let you group emails from the same customer together into one view and push that customer through your pipeline. When a new email comes in, you'll have all the context you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Base | &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbase.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://getbase.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getbase&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@getbase&lt;/a&gt; | $15/mo - $125/mo | The Sales and CRM Software Your Team Will Actually Use | Base is designed to significantly boost your team’s sales productivity and give you the core sales tools you need to grow your business. Your leads come from a variety of sources. Lead management in Base helps you organize leads and assign them to the right sales reps so they can be followed up on and qualified quickly. After being qualified, convert a lead in Base and all of the contact information you have about your lead is transferred your new customer contact card. Optionally, you can specify follow up tasks and even create a deal at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pipedrive | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pipedrive.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.pipedrive.com&lt;/a&gt; | | $9/ mo | Pipeline software that gets you organized. | Pipedrive is built for salespeople who need to put in serious effort to turn leads into sales. It helps to organize the work and spend less time on admin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contactually | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.contactually.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.contactually.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/contactually&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Contactually&lt;/a&gt; | $17.99/mo - $99.99/mo | Maximize your network ROI. More referrals. More repeat business | Contactually helps businesses follow up with the right people, at the right time, to maximize relationship ROI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjbarber/best-crm-for-startups&quot;&gt;Best CRM Software for Startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Social Media Marketing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Buffer | &lt;a href=&quot;https://buffer.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://buffer.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/buffer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@buffer&lt;/a&gt; | $10/mo | Buffer is the easiest way to publish on social media | Buffer helps you share to Twitter, Facebook and more. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HootSuite | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hootsuite.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://hootsuite.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HootSuite&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@HootSuite&lt;/a&gt; | $8.99/mo | Add speed and agility to your social media strategy | From one dashboard you’ll schedule Tweets and Facebook posts, monitor conversations, and more. When you need to prove your social ROI, quickly create and customize ready-to-present analytics reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claim.io | &lt;a href=&quot;http://claim.io/welcome&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://claim.io/welcome&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/claimio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@claimio&lt;/a&gt; | $189/mo- $499/mo | | Owning your name on 300 Social media sites not only makes it easier for people to find you or your business online - it also works as a &quot;social media identity insurance&quot;, protecting you from name squatting and identity fraud, minimizing risk to your brand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exacttarget Marketing Cloud/Buddy Media | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salesforce.com/products/marketing-cloud/overview/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.salesforce.com/products/marketing-cloud/overview/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/marketingcloud&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@marketingcloud&lt;/a&gt; | | Bringing you closer to your social customers with an integrated social content solution. | Run integrated campaigns across Facebook, Twitter, YouTube and your websites Increase fans, followers and advocates. Publish engaging and interactive social apps. Easily create landing pages and microsites and extend social to your websites. Understand engagement trends, demographics, conversions and business metrics with powerful analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprout Social | &lt;a href=&quot;https://sproutsocial.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://sproutsocial.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sproutsocial&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@sproutsocial&lt;/a&gt; | $59/mo- $1500/mo | Powerful Social Media Software | Sprout lets you post messages on Facebook, Twitter, Google+ and LinkedIn simultaneously from one easy-to-use message composition tool. Shorten links, attach photos, target your audience on Facebook, customize your posts and much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;F5Bot | &lt;a href=&quot;https://f5bot.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://f5bot.com&lt;/a&gt; | free | F5Bot is free social media keyword monitoring | F5Bot will send you an email when your startup, your product, or your competitors are mentioned on Hacker News or Reddit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Naming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trademarkia | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trademarkia.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.trademarkia.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trademarkia&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@trademarkia&lt;/a&gt; | | Trademarkia is one of the largest trademark search engines in the world. | LegalForce's network of licensed patent attorneys and agents have filed hundreds of patent applications for companies of every size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NameRobot | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.namerobot.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.namerobot.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/namerobotEN&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@namerobotEN&lt;/a&gt;] | 0$ - 300$/mo | Find, create and check the name for your project. NameRobot offers everything you need to create suitable naming ideas in a short time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DomainTools Whois Lookup | &lt;a href=&quot;http://whois.domaintools.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://whois.domaintools.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DomainTools&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@DomainTools&lt;/a&gt; | free / $99/mo | Go beyond ordinary Whois to discover the people or organizations behind a domain name or IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Space Rental&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;42Floors | &lt;a href=&quot;https://42floors.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://42floors.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/42floors&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@42floors&lt;/a&gt; | | The Best Place to Find Office &amp;amp; Commercial Space Rentals | We're gathering listing data from everyone in the market. Even including off-market listings that landlords haven't yet posted on 42Floors.com or anywhere else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidspace | &lt;a href=&quot;https://liquidspace.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://liquidspace.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LiquidSpace&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@LiquidSpace&lt;/a&gt; | | Optimize Real Estate for Your Enterprise | Whether planning ahead or booking on the fly, find and reserve a great place to work. Rent professional conference and meeting rooms, private offices, or coworking spaces daily or hourly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PivotDesk | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pivotdesk.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.pivotdesk.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PivotDesk&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@PivotDesk&lt;/a&gt; | | An office sharing marketplace that helps startups that need space find host companies that have excess space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Community Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Discourse | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discourse.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.discourse.org&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/discourse&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@discourse&lt;/a&gt; | | Ready for a new discussion platform? | Discussion software is a group of people interested in a common topic who are willing to type paragraphs to each other on a web page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Personal Productivity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tomatoes | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tomato.es/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.tomato.es/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomatoesapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@tomatoesapp&lt;/a&gt; | | Track your time and be productive with the Pomodoro Technique | Tomatoes is a &quot;pomodoro tracker&quot;, a Pomodoro technique® driven time tracker. Track your time using 25 minutes slots called &quot;pomodoros&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RescueTime | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rescuetime.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.rescuetime.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rescuetime&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@rescuetime&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $9/mo | RescueTime gives you an accurate picture of how you spend your time to help you become more productive every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Qbserve | &lt;a href=&quot;https://qotoqot.com/qbserve/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://qotoqot.com/qbserve/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Qbserve&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Qbserve&lt;/a&gt; | $40 one-time | Qbserve is a time tracker for Mac that does whatever RescueTime can but also tracks project time automatically, generates invoices, and stores tracked data locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timing | &lt;a href=&quot;https://timingapp.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://timingapp.com/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TimingApp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@TimingApp&lt;/a&gt; | $29 - $79 | Automatic time and productivity tracking for Mac. Helps you stay on track with your work and ensures no billable hours get lost (if you are billing hourly).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fman | &lt;a href=&quot;https://fman.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://fman.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/m_herrmann&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@m_herrmann&lt;/a&gt; | $14 | Manage and transfer your files with ease. For Windows, Mac and Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WakaTime | &lt;a href=&quot;https://wakatime.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://wakatime.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WakaTime&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@WakaTime&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $9/mo | Automatic productivity metrics using text editor plugins. Goals, leaderboards, GitHub integration, automatic project/language/branch detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Prototyping/Mockups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Creately | &lt;a href=&quot;https://creately.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://creately.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/creately&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@creately&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $750/mo | Creately | Web based diagramming tool for fast easy diagrams. Supports flowcharts, mock-ups, wire-frames, mind maps, organizational charts, network diagrams, AWS diagrams, UML diagrams and many other diagram types. Real-time collaboration plus innovative productivity features to create diagrams 3 times faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keynote | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/keynote/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.apple.com/keynote/&lt;/a&gt; | $19.99 | Easily create gorgeous presentations with the all-new Keynote, featuring powerful yet easy-to-use tools and dazzling effects that will make you a very hard act to follow. Also checkout the &lt;a href=&quot;https://keynotopia.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Keynotopia Themes&lt;/a&gt; to get all the common UI elements for iOS, Android etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OmniGraffle | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omnigroup.com/omniGraffle&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.omnigroup.com/omniGraffle&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/omniGraffle&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@omniGraffle&lt;/a&gt; | $99.99 | Diagramming Worth a Thousand Words | Need a diagram, process chart, quick page-layout, website wireframe or graphic design? OmniGraffle can help you make eye-popping graphic documents quickly by keeping lines connected to shapes even when they're moved, providing powerful styling tools, and magically organizing diagrams with just one click. Whether you need a quick &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moqups | &lt;a href=&quot;https://moqups.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://moqups.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/moqups&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@moqups&lt;/a&gt; | $9/mo- $39/mo | Moqups is a nifty HTML5 App used to create wireframes, mockups or UI concepts, prototypes depending on how you like to call them. | The most stunning HTML5 app for creating resolution-independent SVG mockups &amp;amp; wireframes for your next project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balsamiq | &lt;a href=&quot;https://balsamiq.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://balsamiq.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/balsamiq&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@balsamiq&lt;/a&gt; | Life's too short for bad software! | Balsamiq Mockups is a rapid wireframing tool that helps you Work Faster &amp;amp; Smarter. It reproduces the experience of sketching on a whiteboard, but using a computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proto.io | &lt;a href=&quot;https://proto.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://proto.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/protoio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@protoio&lt;/a&gt; | $24/mo- $199/mo | Silly-fast mobile prototyping | Build high-fidelity fully interactive mobile app prototypes in minutes. Prototypes can be viewed on browser or device giving a real experience to the user how the app will look like and behave. Multiple devices like smart phones and tablets/pads are supported including iPhone, iPad and Android devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invision | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.invisionapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/InVisionApp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@InVisionApp&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo- $100+/mo | Free Web &amp;amp; Mobile (iOS, Android) Prototyping and UI Mockup Tool | Transform your Web &amp;amp; Mobile (iOS, Android) designs into clickable, interactive Prototypes and Mockups. Share and Collaborate on them with others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sketch | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sketchapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.sketchapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sketchapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@sketchapp&lt;/a&gt; | $99 | Professional digital design for Mac. Sketch gives you the power, flexibility and speed you always wanted in a lightweight and easy-to-use package. Finally you can focus on what you do best: Design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figma | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.figma.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/figmadesign&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@figmadesign&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $12/editor/mo | Design and prototyping tool, with a focus on collaboration and teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anima | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.animaapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.animaapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/animaapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@animaapp&lt;/a&gt; | $0 - $39/mo | Sketch to Code Toolkit. Anima converts web design to code. Make your Sketch design responsive, interactive and alive, and export to HTML/JS/CSS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Content Creation/Infographics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Visual.ly | &lt;a href=&quot;https://visual.ly&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://visual.ly&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Visually&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Visually&lt;/a&gt; | $195/mo- $994/mo | ORIGINAL VISUAL CONTENT FOR BRANDS | We only work with the best creative talent available. Thousands of designers, journalists, animators and developers are standing by to help you achieve your goals and take your project to the next level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canva | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canva.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.canva.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/canva&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@canva&lt;/a&gt; | Design great social media images with text and graphics for free or a few bucks depending on the images you select&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Customer Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PickFu | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pickfu.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.pickfu.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pickfu&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@pickfu&lt;/a&gt; | $20/mo- $299/mo | REAL CONSUMER FEEDBACK IN MINUTES | PickFu is a tool that provides instant, unbiased and insightful public opinion on questions that you care about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoter.io | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.promoter.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.promoter.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/promoter_io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Promoter_io&lt;/a&gt; | $50/mo - $500/mo | Helps companies quickly gain predictive customer intelligence &amp;amp; insights driven by NPS (Net Promoter) to increase revenue and reduce churn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Factual | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.factual.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.factual.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Factual&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Factual&lt;/a&gt; | | GLOBAL DATA. LOCAL CONTEXT. | Factual’s location platform enriches mobile location signals with definitive global data, enabling personalized and contextually relevant mobile experiences. Built from billions of inputs, the data is constantly updated by Factual’s real-time data stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Database&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Citus | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citusdata.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.citusdata.com&lt;/a&gt; | Citus scales out PostgreSQL through sharding, replication, and query parallelization. So you can focus on your application, not worry about your database. Citus is available as open source, enterprise software, and fully managed database as a service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bulbs | &lt;a href=&quot;http://bulbflow.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://bulbflow.org&lt;/a&gt; | Python persistence framework for graph databases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Datomic | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datomic.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.datomic.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/datomic_team&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@datomic_team&lt;/a&gt; | The fully transactional, cloud-ready, immutable database. | Immutable data means strong consistency combined with horizontal read scalability, plus built-in caching. Datomic is a distributed database designed to enable scalable, flexible and intelligent applications, running on next-generation cloud architectures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tinkerpop | &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinkerpop.apache.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://tinkerpop.apache.org&lt;/a&gt; | Open source software products in the graph space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vertabelo | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vertabelo.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.vertabelo.com&lt;/a&gt; | Web-based tool for database design | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Vertabelo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@vertabelo&lt;/a&gt; | Vertabelo allows you to visually design database models for PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, SQLite, and IBM DB2. You can import the existing database structure from SQL, XML, or using reverse engineering tool. After you design a model, you can generate SQL script or ready-to-use code for various ORMs (Propel, jOOQ, SQLAlchemy, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://mobile-orm.vertabelo.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Vertabelo Mobile ORM&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Accounting/Invoicing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Harvest | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getharvest.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.getharvest.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/harvest&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@harvest&lt;/a&gt; | $12/mo- $99/mo | Time Tracking Made Easy | Time tracking is simple and lightning fast with Harvest. Set up takes seconds, and there’s nothing to install. We’ve simplified the timesheet and timesheets approval process so you can stay focused on work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ballpark | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getballpark.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.getballpark.com&lt;/a&gt; | | $12/mo- $99/mo | Stop sending your clients ugly paper invoices. Go paperless today, with Ballpark. | Our beautiful, web-based invoices and estimates make it easier than ever to get paid and discuss projects with your clients and colleagues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PaySimple | &lt;a href=&quot;https://paysimple.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://paysimple.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PaySimple&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@PaySimple&lt;/a&gt; | $34.95/mo | Simplify how you bill and collect | PaySimple is an industry-leading provider of payment management solutions. PaySimple simplifies billing and collection processes by enabling you to bill, collect and deposit all of your payments automatically. Our customized, secure ASP solution includes auto-recurring billing, electronic check processing, direct debit and credit card processing at some of the lowest rates available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FreshBooks | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freshbooks.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.freshbooks.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/freshbooks&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@freshbooks&lt;/a&gt; | $19.95/mo- $39.95/mo | Accounting Made for You, the Non-Accountant | FreshBooks is simple and intuitive, so accounting isn't intimidating. Plus you can talk to a real, live person anytime you have a question, 9am-6pm EDT, Mon-Fri.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FreeAgent | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freeagent.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.freeagent.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/freeagent&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@freeagent&lt;/a&gt; | US $20 /mo | Accounting software trusted by over 35,000 freelancers and small businesses | Reconcile money in and out of the business via your electronic bank statements and build monthly balance charts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blinksale | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blinksale.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.blinksale.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/blinksale&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@blinksale&lt;/a&gt; | $15.00 | INTRODUCING BLINKSALE UNLIMITED. ONE PLAN. ONE PRICE. UNLIMITED EVERYTHING. | Blinksale makes you look your best. With over a dozen invoice designs &amp;amp; thank you notes, you’re sure to put your best foot forward. Every time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cashboard | &lt;a href=&quot;http://cashboardapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://cashboardapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cashboard&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@cashboard&lt;/a&gt; | $8.25/mo- $250/mo | FREELANCE TIME TRACKING &amp;amp; INVOICE SOFTWARE TRUSTED BY THOUSANDS, WORLDWIDE | Cashboard is the tool we designed to remedy that situation. It works for our software consultancy and we think it’ll work for you too. We launched Cashboard in Spring of 2007after many sleepless nights of hard work. It was the first solution to combine estimates, invoices, time tracking, and online payments into one tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paydirt | &lt;a href=&quot;https://paydirtapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://paydirtapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paydirtapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@paydirtapp&lt;/a&gt; | $8/mo- $149/mo | Smart Time Tracking Easier Invoicing Online Payments | In Paydirt, you can start a timer from any page in one click. No fiddly menus. No navigating around. Just a start button for each task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Privacy Policy, Terms &amp;amp; Conditions, Legal Documents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;iubenda | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iubenda.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.iubenda.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iubenda&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@iubenda&lt;/a&gt; | free - $27/year - customization services | The easiest way to generate a professional, customizable, self-updating privacy policy. Choose between 6 languages. Documents hosted and kept up to date. Backed by real lawyers. Additional assistance service with premium legal team for custom Privacy Policy and Terms &amp;amp; Conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Income Analytics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Payments, Billing &amp;amp; Downloads&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PayPal | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.paypal.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PayPal&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@PayPal&lt;/a&gt; | PayPal is an international e-commerce business allowing payments and money transfers to be made through the Internet. Online money transfers serve as electronic alternatives to paying with traditional paper methods, such as checks and money orders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gumroad | &lt;a href=&quot;https://gumroad.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://gumroad.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gumroad&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@gumroad&lt;/a&gt; | | See higher conversion, lower fees, and more customer control. Sell films directly to your viewers. | Creating digital products is hard, selling them shouldn't be. We let you start selling downloads in seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FetchApp | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fetchapp.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.fetchapp.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fetchapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@fetchapp&lt;/a&gt; | $5/mo- $500/mo | The Simpler way to Fetch. | Simply put, FetchApp allows you to sell and digitally delivery downloadable goods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chargify | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chargify.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.chargify.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chargify&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@chargify&lt;/a&gt; | $459/mo- $65/mo | Easily Manage Your Recurring Revenue Business | Customers sign up, make payments, use coupons, upgrade... You bill one-time &amp;amp; recurring fees using whatever pricing model you need, charge cards, send invoices &amp;amp; reminders, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recurly | &lt;a href=&quot;https://recurly.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://recurly.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Recurly&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Recurly&lt;/a&gt; | $99/mo- $259/mo | Subscription Billing Automation | As the leading recurring billing platform, Recurly ensures setup is easy, integrations are quick, and our service scales with the needs of your business. With Recurly you'll be ready to accept payments and focus on growing your sales in no time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ChargeBee | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chargebee.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.chargebee.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chargebee&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@chargebee&lt;/a&gt; | $49/mo- $249/mo | ChargeBee is an easy to use recurring billing and invoicing solution for online businesses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Billing &amp;amp; Payment Processing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Braintree | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.braintreepayments.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.braintreepayments.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/braintree&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@braintree&lt;/a&gt; | | Accept payments in your app or website | Braintree handles transactions for some of the fastest growing mobile companies like Uber, Airbnb, HotelTonight and Fab. With native, easy-to-follow SDKs for iOS, Android and Windows Phone you can quickly add native payments to your app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dwolla | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dwolla.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.dwolla.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dwolla&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@dwolla&lt;/a&gt; | 25¢ per transaction | The best way to move money. | Dwolla, Inc. is an agent of Veridian Credit Union and all funds associated with your account in the Dwolla network are held in a pooled account at Veridian Credit Union. These funds are not eligible for individual insurance, and may not be eligible for share insurance by the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund. Dwolla, Inc. is the operator of a software platform that communicates user instructions for funds transfers to Veridian Credit Union.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stripe | &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://stripe.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stripe&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@stripe&lt;/a&gt; | 2.9% + 30¢ per successful charge. | Feature-packed payments | No need to design payment forms from scratch. Stripe Checkout offers a beautiful, customizable payment flow that works great across desktop and mobile. When you use Checkout, you’re always up-to-date, with no extra code required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pin | &lt;a href=&quot;https://pinpayments.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://pinpayments.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pin_payments&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@pin_payments&lt;/a&gt; | 2.9% + 30¢ per successful charge. | Payments, Rebooted. | Accepting credit card payments from a global audience typically requires a merchant acount. The process of establishing a merchant account for each currency can be too difficult and costly for small businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PayMill | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paymill.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.paymill.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Paymill&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Paymill&lt;/a&gt; | 0.28 € - 0.25 € | Online payments made easy | Make payments personal by customising the checkout according to the flow of your website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spreedly | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spreedly.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.spreedly.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spreedly&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@spreedly&lt;/a&gt; | $150/mo - $1500/mo | Payments as a Platform | One of Spreedly's major benefits is reaching a large number of merchant accounts by working across multiple payment gateways. As a direct merchant you can transact globally but deposit funds in unique merchant accounts based on geographic or other business rules. As a SaaS platform you can support the unique merchant accounts of your individual customers. A payment gateway token is your way to indicate to us which unique merchant account this particular transaction will go against. Each unique merchant account = one unique payment gateway token.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WePay | &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.wepay.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://go.wepay.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wepay&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@wepay&lt;/a&gt; | 2.9% + 30¢ per transaction. | WePay is the first payments engine to offer platforms — marketplaces, crowdfunding, and business software/tools — a way to own their customer experience while still shielding them from 100 percent of fraud and regulatory risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paddle | &lt;a href=&quot;https://paddle.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://paddle.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PaddleHQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@PaddleHQ&lt;/a&gt; | 5% + 50¢ per transaction. | Payment processing and fulfillment, specialized for desktop apps and SaaS subscription services. Handles VAT and invoicing for you, so your accounting becomes easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Banking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Phone/PBX/SMS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;System Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shipping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;User Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Designers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Group Communication/Chat Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjbarber/hipchat-alternatives&quot;&gt;HipChat (now Stride) Alternatives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Remote Collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DNS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Status Blogs/User Alerts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Forms / Surveys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wufoo | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wufoo.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.wufoo.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Forms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typeform | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typeform.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.typeform.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/typeform&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@typeform&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo - $25/mo | Ask Awesomely! | Typeform makes asking questions easy, human &amp;amp; beautiful. A user experience that makes your questions look &amp;amp; feel great everywhere. Stimulated, inspired, excited, happy respondents boost completion rates. Gain insights with integrated analysis tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Qualaroo | &lt;a href=&quot;https://qualaroo.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://qualaroo.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/qualarooinc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@qualarooinc&lt;/a&gt; | $63/mo -499/mo | Qualaroo website surveys uncover customer insights that lead to better business results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formcarry | &lt;a href=&quot;https://formcarry.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://formcarry.com&lt;/a&gt; | $0/mo - $99/mo | Handle forms without a single line of back-end code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FormKeep | &lt;a href=&quot;https://formkeep.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://formkeep.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/formkeep&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@formkeep&lt;/a&gt; | $59/mo - $199/mo | Premium Forms Backend service with built in spam protection, data integrations to over a 1000 services, data retention policies and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Source Code Hosting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design Collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PaaS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;VPS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Heroku Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;AWS Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Database-aaS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;HumongouS.io | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humongous.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.humongous.io&lt;/a&gt; | HumongouS.io is a web-based user interface (GUI) for MongoDB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mLab | &lt;a href=&quot;https://mlab.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://mlab.com&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compose | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.compose.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.compose.com&lt;/a&gt; | Compose is a fully-managed platform used by developers to deploy, host and scale databases (Elasticsearch and MongoDB.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RedisLabs | &lt;a href=&quot;https://redislabs.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://redislabs.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RedisLabsInc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@RedisLabsInc&lt;/a&gt; | free - $338+/mo | RedisLabs offers fully-managed cloud service for hosting and running your redis or memcache datasets in a highly-available and scalable manner, with predictable and stable top performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Backend-aaS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WebSockets-aaS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ops Alerts and Scheduling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PagerDuty | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pagerduty.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.pagerduty.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opsgenie | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opsgenie.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.opsgenie.com&lt;/a&gt; | @opsgenie | $0 - $16 user/month | We make alerts work for you | We provide the tools you need to design meaningful, actionable alerts and ensure the right people are notified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Accounting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Video Hosting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Knowledge Tracking/Wiki&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Offsite Backups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Personal Machine Backups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Remote Workers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deployment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEO Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;AccuRanker | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accuranker.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.accuranker.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ahrefs | &lt;a href=&quot;https://ahrefs.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://ahrefs.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ahrefs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@ahrefs&lt;/a&gt; | $79/mo - $2500/mo | Ahrefs provide a complete digital marketing suite with tools for analyzing back links, analizing websites, rank tracking, content exploring and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SerpBook | &lt;a href=&quot;https://serpbook.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://serpbook.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WooRank | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.woorank.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.woorank.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/woorank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@woorank&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $49/mo | WooRank analyzes your website for optimization best practices and shows how it ranks against your competition. Its real-time brandable reports, consisting of over 150 data-points, help you to instantly spot critical issues that impact traffic, usability and conversions. Sync your analytics, social accounts and keywords for even more robust tracking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moz | &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://moz.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/moz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@moz&lt;/a&gt; | $99/mo - $599/mo | Moz provides you all the tools you need to effectively do search engine optimization. On site optimization graders, competitor tracking, back link analysis, rank trakcing and many more features available to users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KWFinder | &lt;a href=&quot;https://kwfinder.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://kwfinder.com/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mangools_com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@mangools_com&lt;/a&gt; | $30+/mo | Keyword research tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;API Builder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Postman | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getpostman.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.getpostman.com/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/postmanclient&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@postmanclient&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $8/mo | Build, test, document and monitor your APIs faster. Used by 5 million developers and more than 100,000 companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployd | &lt;a href=&quot;http://deployd.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://deployd.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/deploydapp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@deploydapp&lt;/a&gt; | Free (OSS) | Design, build, and scale APIs for web and mobile apps in minutes instead of days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apiary | &lt;a href=&quot;https://apiary.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://apiary.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/apiaryio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@apiary&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $99/mo | Powerful API Design Stack. Built for Developers. | Work together to quickly design, prototype, document and test APIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Password Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources of Clicks/Ad Platforms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Storage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kloudless | &lt;a href=&quot;https://kloudless.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://kloudless.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Kloudless&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@Kloudless&lt;/a&gt; | $10/10k API requests/month | Kloudless provides developers with a single cloud storage API in the place of many | Kloudless is the last cloud storage API you'll ever need. Integrate a single REST API instead of many and use our UI tools to quickly build cloud storage support into your app. We maintain all the integrations so you can focus on building awesome products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Task Scheduling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;EasyCron | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.easycron.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.easycron.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IFTTT | &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://ifttt.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zapier | &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://zapier.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zapier&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; | $99/mo - $15/mo | Superpowers to get your work done. | A Zap is a link between two apps (a &quot;trigger&quot; and an &quot;action&quot;). Zaps run automatically in the background every few minutes to move and manage data on your behalf. Only live Zaps count against your limit — you can have as many paused and unfinished Zaps as you'd like. For example, one Zap might be &quot;Send me an SMS every time I get a new email&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integromat | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.integromat.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.integromat.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/integromat&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@integromat&lt;/a&gt; | free for &amp;lt; 1000 operations or 100 MB per month, paid from $9 per month | Automates your tasks &amp;amp; connects to almost any app or service. | Very powerful toolset with features like error handling, iterators, aggregators, routers, functions, data stores, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dead Man's Snitch | &lt;a href=&quot;https://deadmanssnitch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://deadmanssnitch.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/deadmanssnitch&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@DeadMansSnitch&lt;/a&gt; | Free - $49/mo | Monitoring for scheduled tasks (like cron) and service heartbeats. Makes it easy to know when and why a particular job failed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dash | &lt;a href=&quot;https://kapeli.com/dash&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://kapeli.com/dash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zeal | &lt;a href=&quot;https://zealdocs.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://zealdocs.org&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zealdocs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@zealdocs&lt;/a&gt; | Free | Offline documentation browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevDocs | &lt;a href=&quot;https://devdocs.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://devdocs.io/&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DevDocs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@DevDocs&lt;/a&gt; | Free | DevDocs combines multiple API documentations in a fast, organized, and searchable interface. You don't have to use your mouse — use keyboard shortcuts. The search supports fuzzy matching. You can search using your browser's address bar. DevDocs is free and open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Business Cards and Print Material&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Presentations / Slides&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best ways to use this list are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;by browing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade#contents&quot;&gt;contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by using &lt;kbd&gt;command&lt;/kbd&gt; + &lt;kbd&gt;F&lt;/kbd&gt; to search the contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This list also uses tags to help when searching the contents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosted?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Hosted&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Self-hosted&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Authors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chrisbarber.co&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chris Barber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjbarber&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/61c3d43199fc0b9a40b5a0817d4316f273598d89/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f666f6c6c6f776572732f636a6261726265722e7376673f7374796c653d736f6369616c266c6162656c3d466f6c6c6f77253230636a626172626572&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/followers/cjbarber.svg?style=social&amp;amp;label=Follow%20cjbarber&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chrisbarber&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/d61fd278cca6002cb53a3b245074e18f5e9a6bc0/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f747769747465722f666f6c6c6f772f63687269736261726265722e7376673f7374796c653d736f6369616c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/chrisbarber.svg?style=social&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://davison.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Craig Davison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davisonio&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/0de24e1bfff80e3cbc57393a1a83fb34c31d8614/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f666f6c6c6f776572732f64617669736f6e696f2e7376673f7374796c653d736f6369616c266c6162656c3d466f6c6c6f7725323064617669736f6e696f&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/followers/davisonio.svg?style=social&amp;amp;label=Follow%20davisonio&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davisonio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/9dc94489441aea9763d5ef56641c172de7dbca2c/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f747769747465722f666f6c6c6f772f64617669736f6e696f2e7376673f7374796c653d736f6369616c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/davisonio.svg?style=social&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With many thanks to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;contributors&lt;/a&gt;. 👏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributions are welcome!&lt;/strong&gt; Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&quot;&gt;Contributing Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. 🙌&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 09:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rayascott</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/3237905?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade</og:url>
<og:description>Tools of The Trade, from Hacker News. Contribute to cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/cjbarber/ToolsOfTheTrade</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Popular iPhone apps caught sending user location data to monetization firms</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/07/a-dozen-popular-iphone-apps-caught-quietly-sending-user-locations-to-monetization-firms/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/07/a-dozen-popular-iphone-apps-caught-quietly-sending-user-locations-to-monetization-firms/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A group of security researchers say dozens of popular iPhone apps are quietly sharing the location data of “tens of millions of mobile devices” with third-party data monetization firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all require access to a user’s location data to work properly, like weather and fitness apps, but share that data often as a way to generate revenue for free-to-download apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, the apps send precise locations and other sensitive, identifiable data “at all times, constantly,” and often with “little to no mention” that location data will be shared with third-parties, say security researchers &lt;a href=&quot;https://guardianapp.com/ios-app-location-report-sep2018.html&quot;&gt;at the GuardianApp project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I believe people should be able to use any app they wish on their phone without fear that granting access to sensitive data may mean that this data will be quietly sent off to some entity who they do not know and do not have any desire to do business with,” said Will Strafach, one of the researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using tools to monitor network traffic, the researchers found 24 popular iPhone apps that were collecting location data — like Bluetooth beacons to Wi-Fi network names — to know where a person is and where they visit. These data monetization firms also collect other device data from the accelerometer, battery charge status and cell network names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In exchange for data, often these data firms pay app developers to collect data and grow their databases and often to deliver ads based on a person’s location history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But although many claim they don’t collect personally identifiable information, Strafach said that latitude and longitude coordinates can pin a person to a house or their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To name a few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/askfm-ask-anonymous-questions/id635896473?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASKfm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a teen-focused anonymous question-and-answer app, has 1,400 ratings on the Apple App Store and touts tens of millions of users. It asks for access to a user’s location that “won’t be shared with anyone.” But the app sends that location data to two data firms, AreaMetrics and Huq. When reached, the app maker said it believes its location collection practices “fit industry standards, and are therefore acceptable for our users.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/noaa-weather-radar/id749133753?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOAA Weather Radar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has more than 266,000 reviews and has millions of downloads. Access to your location “is used to provide weather info.” But an earlier version of the app from March was sending location data to three firms, Factual, Sense360 and Teemo. The code has since been removed. A spokesperson for Apalon, which built the app, said it “conducted a limited, brief test with a few of these providers” earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/homes-for-sale-rent/id306423353?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Homes.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular app that asks that you switch on your location to help “find nearby homes.” But the code, thought to be old code, still sends precise coordinates to AreaMetrics. The app maker said it used AreaMetrics “for a short period” last year but said the code was deactivated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/perfect365/id475976577?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perfect365&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an augmented reality beauty app with more than 100 million users, asks for location to “customize your experience based on your location and more,” and refers users &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perfect365.com/about/privacy-policy&quot;&gt;to the privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; for more — which does state that location data will be used for advertising. The app was briefly pulled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/nicolenguyen/how-apps-take-your-data-and-sell-it-without-you-even&quot;&gt;after a BuzzFeed News story&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year outed the researchers, but returned to the app store days later. The current app version contains code for eight separate data monetization firms in the latest version of the app. The app maker did not return a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the list goes on — including more than a hundred Sinclair-owned local news and weather apps, which share location data with Reveal, a data tracking and monetization firm, &lt;a href=&quot;https://revealmobile.com/2015930reveal-mobile-and-sinclair-broadcast-group-partner-for-mobile-audience-data-and-ad-targeting/&quot;&gt;which the company says&lt;/a&gt; will help the media giant bolster its sales by “providing advertisers with target audiences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That can quickly become a lucrative business for developers with popular apps and monetization firms alike, some of which collect billions of locations each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the data monetization firms deny any wrongdoing and say that users can opt out at any time. Most said that they demand that app makers explicitly state that they require app developers to explicitly state that they are collecting and sending data to third-party firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team’s research shows that those requirements are almost never verified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reveal said it requires customers “state the use cases for location data in their privacy policy” and that users can opt-out at any time. Huq, like Reveal, said it carries out “regular checks on our partner apps to ensure that they have implemented” measures that explain the company’s services. AreaMetrics, which collects primarily Bluetooth beacon data from public areas like coffee shops and retail stores, says it has “no interest” in receiving personal data from users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/sense360&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;sense360&quot;&gt;Sense360&lt;/a&gt; said the data it collects is anonymous and requires apps to get explicit consent from its users, but Strafach said few apps he’s seen contained text that sought assurances. But the company did not answer a specific question why it no longer works with certain apps. Wireless Registry said it also requires apps seek consent from users, but would not comment on the security measures it uses to ensure user privacy. And in remarks, inMarket said it follows advertising standards and guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/cuebiq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;cuebiq&quot;&gt;Cuebiq&lt;/a&gt; claims to use an “advanced cryptography method” to store and transmit data, but Strafach said he found “no evidence” that any data was scrambled. It says it’s not a “tracker” but says while some app developers look to monetize users’ data, most are said to use it for insights. And, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/factual&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;factual&quot;&gt;Factual&lt;/a&gt; said it uses location data for advertising and analytics, but must obtain in-app consent from users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reached, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/databerries&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;databerries&quot;&gt;Teemo&lt;/a&gt; did not answer our questions. SafeGraph, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/mobiquity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;mobiquity&quot;&gt;Mobiquity&lt;/a&gt; and Fysical did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“None of these companies appear to be legally accountable for their claims and practices, instead there is some sort of self-regulation they claim to enforce,” said Strafach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said there isn’t much users can do, but limiting ad tracking in your iPhone’s privacy settings can make it more difficult for location trackers to identify users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple’s crackdown on apps that don’t have privacy policies kicks in next month. But given how few people read them in the first place, don’t expect apps to change their behavior any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 23:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tareqak</dc:creator>
<og:title>Dozens of popular iPhone apps caught sending user location data to monetization firms</og:title>
<og:description>A group of security researchers say dozens of popular iPhone apps are quietly sharing the location data of “tens of millions of mobile devices” with third-party data monetization firms. Almost all require access to a user’s location data to work properly, like weather and fitness …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-578768440.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/09/07/a-dozen-popular-iphone-apps-caught-quietly-sending-user-locations-to-monetization-firms/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/07/a-dozen-popular-iphone-apps-caught-quietly-sending-user-locations-to-monetization-firms/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Academic Activists Send a Published Paper Down the Memory Hole</title>
<link>https://quillette.com/2018/09/07/academic-activists-send-a-published-paper-down-the-memory-hole/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://quillette.com/2018/09/07/academic-activists-send-a-published-paper-down-the-memory-hole/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In the highly controversial area of human intelligence, the ‘Greater Male Variability Hypothesis’ (GMVH) asserts that there are more idiots and more geniuses among men than among women. Darwin’s research on evolution in the nineteenth century found that, although there are many exceptions for specific traits and species, there is generally more variability in males than in females of the same species throughout the animal kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidence for this hypothesis is fairly robust and has been reported in species ranging from adders and sockeye salmon to wasps and orangutans, as well as humans. Multiple studies have found that boys and men are over-represented at both the high and low ends of the distributions in categories ranging from birth weight and brain structures and 60-meter dash times to reading and mathematics test scores. There are significantly more men than women, for example, among Nobel laureates, music composers, and chess champions—and also among homeless people, suicide victims, and federal prison inmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darwin had also raised the question of &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; males in many species might have evolved to be more variable than females, and when I learned that the answer to his question remained elusive, I set out to look for a scientific explanation. My aim was not to prove or disprove that the hypothesis applies to human intelligence or to any other specific traits or species, but simply to discover a &lt;em&gt;logical&lt;/em&gt; reason that could help explain how gender differences in variability might naturally arise in the same species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came up with a simple intuitive mathematical argument based on biological and evolutionary principles and enlisted Sergei Tabachnikov, a Professor of Mathematics at Pennsylvania State University, to help me flesh out the model. When I posted a preprint on the open-access mathematics archives in May of last year, a variability researcher at Durham University in the UK got in touch by email. He described our joint paper as “an excellent summary of the research to date in this field,” adding that “it certainly underpins my earlier work on impulsivity, aggression and general evolutionary theory and it is nice to see an actual theoretical model that can be drawn upon in discussion (which I think the literature, particularly in education, has lacked to date). I think this is a welcome addition to the field.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we had written up our findings, Sergei and I decided to try for publication in the &lt;em&gt;Mathematical Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;, the ‘Viewpoint’ section of which specifically welcomes articles on contentious topics. The &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;’s editor-in-chief is Marjorie Wikler Senechal, Professor Emerita of Mathematics and the History of Science at Smith College. She liked our draft, and declared herself to be untroubled by the prospect of controversy. “In principle,” she told Sergei in an email, “I am happy to stir up controversy and few topics generate more than this one. After the Middlebury fracas, in which none of the protestors had read the book they were protesting, we could make a real contribution here by insisting that all views be heard, and providing links to them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Senechal suggested that we might enliven our paper by mentioning Harvard President Larry Summers, who was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2005/02/why-feminist-careerists-neutered-larry-summers/303795/&quot;&gt;swiftly defenestrated in 2005&lt;/a&gt; for saying that the GMVH might be a contributing factor to the dearth of women in physics and mathematics departments at top universities. With her editorial guidance, our paper underwent several further revisions until, on April 3, 2017, our manuscript was officially accepted for publication. The paper was typeset in India, and proofread by an assistant editor who is also a mathematics professor in Kansas. It was scheduled to appear in the international journal’s first issue of 2018, with an acknowledgement of funding support to my co-author from the National Science Foundation. All normal academic procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*     *     *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, at about the same time, anxiety about gender-parity erupted in Silicon Valley. The same anti-variability argument used to justify the sacking of President Summers resurfaced when Google engineer James Damore suggested that several innate biological factors, including gender differences in variability, might help explain gender disparities in Silicon Valley hi-tech jobs. For sending out an internal memo to that effect, he too &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google%27s_Ideological_Echo_Chamber&quot;&gt;was summarily fired&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No sooner had Sergei posted a preprint of our accepted article on his website than we began to encounter problems. On August 16, a representative of the Women In Mathematics (WIM) chapter in his department at Penn State contacted him to warn that the paper might be damaging to the aspirations of impressionable young women. “As a matter of principle,” she wrote, “I support people discussing controversial matters openly … At the same time, I think it’s good to be aware of the effects.” While &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt; was obviously able to debate the merits of our paper, she worried that other, presumably less sophisticated, readers “will just see someone wielding the authority of mathematics to support a very controversial, and potentially sexist, set of ideas…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later, she again contacted Sergei on behalf of WIM and invited him to attend a lunch that had been organized for a “frank and open discussion” about our paper. He would be allowed 15 minutes to describe and explain our results, and this short presentation would be followed by readings of prepared statements by WIM members and then an open discussion. “We promise to be friendly,” she announced, “but you should know in advance that many (most?) of us have strong disagreements with what you did.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 4, Sergei sent me a weary email. “The scandal at our department,” he wrote, “shows no signs of receding.” At a faculty meeting the week before, the Department Head had explained that sometimes values such as academic freedom and free speech come into conflict with other values to which Penn State was committed. A female colleague had then instructed Sergei that he needed to admit and fight bias, adding that the belief that “women have a lesser chance to succeed in mathematics at the very top end is bias.” Sergei said he had spent “endless hours” talking to people who explained that the paper was “bad and harmful” and tried to convince him to “withdraw my name to restore peace at the department and to avoid losing whatever political capital I may still have.” Ominously, “analogies with scientific racism were made by some; I am afraid, we are likely to hear more of it in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day, I wrote to the three organisers of the WIM lunch and offered to address any concrete concerns they might have with our logic or conclusions or any other content. I explained that, since I was the paper’s lead author, it was not fair that my colleague should be expected to take all the heat for our findings. I added that it would still be possible to revise our article before publication. I never received a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, on September 8, Sergei and I were ambushed by two unexpected developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the National Science Foundation wrote to Sergei requesting that acknowledgment of NSF funding be removed from our paper with immediate effect. I was astonished. I had never before heard of the NSF requesting removal of acknowledgement of funding for any reason. On the contrary, they are usually delighted to have public recognition of their support for science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ostensible reason for this request was that our paper was unrelated to Sergei’s funded proposal. However, a Freedom of Information request subsequently revealed that Penn State WIM administrator Diane Henderson (“Professor and Chair of the Climate and Diversity Committee”) and Nate Brown (“Professor and Associate Head for Diversity and Equity”) had secretly co-signed a letter to the NSF that same morning. “Our concern,” they explained, “is that [this] paper appears to promote pseudoscientific ideas that are detrimental to the advancement of women in science, and at odds with the values of the NSF.” Unaware of this at the time, and eager to err on the side of compromise, Sergei and I agreed to remove the acknowledgement as requested. At least, we thought, the paper was still on track to be published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, that same day, the &lt;em&gt;Mathematical Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;’s editor-in-chief Marjorie Senechal notified us that, with “deep regret,” she was rescinding her previous acceptance of our paper. “Several colleagues,” she wrote, had warned her that publication would provoke “extremely strong reactions” and there existed a “very real possibility that the right-wing media may pick this up and hype it internationally.” For the second time in a single day I was left flabbergasted. Working mathematicians are usually thrilled if even five people in the world read our latest article. Now some progressive faction was worried that a fairly straightforward logical argument about male variability might encourage the conservative press to actually read and cite a science paper?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my 40 years of publishing research papers I had never heard of the rejection of an already-accepted paper. And so I emailed Professor Senechal. She replied that she had received no criticisms on scientific grounds and that her decision to rescind was entirely about the reaction she feared our paper would elicit. By way of further explanation, Senechal even compared our paper to the Confederate statues that had recently been removed from the courthouse lawn in Lexington, Kentucky. In the interests of setting our arguments in a more responsible context, she proposed instead that Sergei and I participate in a ‘Round Table’ discussion of our hypothesis argument, the proceedings of which the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt; would publish in lieu of our paper. Her decision, we learned, enjoyed the approval of Springer, one of the world’s leading publishers of scientific books and journals. An editorial director of Springer Mathematics later apologized to me twice, in person, but did nothing to reverse the decision or to support us at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what in the world had happened at the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;? Unbeknownst to us, Amie Wilkinson, a senior professor of mathematics at the University of Chicago, had become aware of our paper and written to the journal to complain. A back-and-forth had ensued. Wilkinson then enlisted the support of her father—a psychometrician and statistician—who wrote to the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt; at his daughter’s request to express his own misgivings, including his belief that “[t]his article oversimplifies the issues to the point of embarrassment.” Invited by Professor Senechal to participate in the proposed Round Table discussion, he declined, admitting to Senechal that “others are more expert on this than he is.” We discovered all this after he gave Senechal permission to forward his letter, inadvertently revealing Wilkinson’s involvement in the process (an indiscretion his daughter would later—incorrectly—blame on the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote polite emails directly to both Wilkinson and her father, explaining that I planned to revise the paper for resubmission elsewhere and asking for their criticisms or suggestions. (I also sent a more strongly worded, point-by-point rebuttal to her father.) Neither replied. Instead, even long after the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt; rescinded acceptance of the paper, Wilkinson continued to trash both the journal and its editor-in-chief on social media, inciting her &lt;em&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt; friends with the erroneous allegation that an entirely different (and more contentious) article had been accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, faced with career-threatening reprisals from their own departmental colleagues and the diversity committee at Penn State, as well as displeasure from the NSF, Sergei and his colleague who had done computer simulations for us withdrew their names from the research. Fortunately for me, I am now retired and rather less easily intimidated—one of the benefits of being a Vietnam combat veteran and former U.S. Army Ranger, I guess. So, I continued to revise the paper, and finally &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1703.04184.pdf&quot;&gt;posted it on the online mathematics archives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*     *     *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On October 13, a lifeline appeared. Igor Rivin, an editor at the widely respected online research journal, the &lt;em&gt;New York Journal of Mathematics&lt;/em&gt;, got in touch with me. He had learned about the article from my erstwhile co-author, read the archived version, and asked me if I’d like to submit a newly revised draft for publication. Rivin said that Mark Steinberger, the &lt;em&gt;NYJM&lt;/em&gt;’s editor-in-chief, was also very positive and that they were confident the paper could be refereed fairly quickly. I duly submitted a new draft (this time as the sole author) and, after a very positive referee’s report and a handful of supervised revisions, Steinberger wrote to confirm publication on November 6, 2017. Relieved that the ordeal was finally over, I forwarded the link to interested colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three days later, however, the paper had vanished. And a few days after that, a completely different paper by different authors appeared at &lt;em&gt;exactly the same page of the same volume&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;NYJM&lt;/em&gt; Volume 23, p 1641+) where mine had once been. As it turned out, Amie Wilkinson is married to Benson Farb, a member of the &lt;em&gt;NYJM&lt;/em&gt; editorial board. Upon discovering that the journal had published my paper, Professor Farb had written a furious email to Steinberger demanding that it be deleted at once. “Rivin,” he complained, “is well-known as a person with extremist views who likes to pick fights with people via inflammatory statements.” Farb’s “father-in law…a famous statistician,” he went on, had “already poked many holes in the ridiculous paper.” My paper was “politically charged” and “pseudoscience” and “a piece of crap” and, by encouraging the &lt;em&gt;NYJM&lt;/em&gt; to accept it, Rivin had “violat[ed] a scientific duty for purely political ends.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unaware of any of this, I wrote to Steinberger on November 14, to find out what had happened. I pointed out that if the deletion were permanent, it would leave me in an impossible position. I would not be able to republish anywhere else because I would be unable to sign a copyright form declaring that it had not already been published elsewhere. Steinberger replied later that day. Half his board, he explained unhappily, had told him that unless he pulled the article, they would all resign and “harass the journal” he had founded 25 years earlier “until it died.” Faced with the loss of his own scientific legacy, he had capitulated. “A publication in a dead journal,” he offered, “wouldn’t help you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*     *     *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleagues I spoke to were appalled. None of them had ever heard of a paper in any field being disappeared after formal publication. Rejected prior to publication? Of course. Retracted? Yes, but only after an investigation, the results of which would then be made public by way of explanation. But simply &lt;em&gt;disappeared&lt;/em&gt;? Never. If a formally refereed and published paper can later be erased from the scientific record and replaced by a completely different article, without any discussion with the author or any announcement in the journal, what will this mean for the future of electronic journals?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Professor Wilkinson had now widened her existing social media campaign against the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt; to include attacks on the &lt;em&gt;NYJM&lt;/em&gt; and its editorial staff. As recently as April of this year, she was threatening Facebook friends with ‘unfriending’ unless they severed social media ties with Rivin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early February, a friend and colleague suggested that I write directly to University of Chicago President Robert Zimmer to complain about the conduct of Farb and Wilkinson, both of whom are University of Chicago professors. The previous October, the conservative &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; columnist Bret Stephens &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/20/opinion/robert-zimmer-chicago-speech.html&quot;&gt;had called Zimmer&lt;/a&gt; “America’s Best University President.” The week after I wrote to Zimmer, the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-free-speech-university-1518824261&quot;&gt;describe Chicago&lt;/a&gt; as “The Free-Speech University” based upon its president’s professed commitment to the principles of free inquiry and expression. Furthermore, Professor Zimmer is a mathematician from the same department and even the same subfield as Farb and Wilkinson, the husband-wife team who had successfully suppressed my variability hypothesis research and trampled on the principles of academic liberty. Surely I would receive a sympathetic hearing there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I wrote directly to Professor Zimmer, mathematician to mathematician, detailing five concrete allegations against his two colleagues. When I eventually received a formal response in late April, it was a somewhat terse official letter from the vice-provost informing me that an inquiry had found no evidence of “academic fraud” and that, consequently, “the charges have been dismissed.” But I had made no allegation of academic fraud. I had alleged “unprofessional, uncollegial, and unethical conduct damaging to my professional reputation and to the reputation of the University of Chicago.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I appealed the decision to the president, I received a second official letter from the vice-provost, in which he argued that Farb and Wilkinson had “exercised their academic freedom in advocating against the publication of the papers” and that their behavior had not been either “unethical or unprofessional.” A reasonable inference is that I was the one interfering in their academic freedom and not vice versa. My quarrel, the vice-provost concluded, was with the editors-in-chief who had spiked my papers, decisions for which the University of Chicago bore no responsibility. At the Free Speech University, it turns out, talk is cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*     *     *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years there has undoubtedly been significant bias and discrimination against women in mathematics and technical fields. Unfortunately, some of that still persists, even though many of us have tried hard to help turn the tide. My own efforts have included tutoring and mentoring female undergraduates, graduating female PhD students, and supporting hiring directives from deans and departmental chairs to seek out and give special consideration to female candidates. I have been invited to serve on two National Science Foundation gender and race diversity panels in Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is to say that I understand the importance of the causes that equal opportunity activists and progressive academics are ostensibly championing. But pursuit of greater fairness and equality cannot be allowed to interfere with dispassionate academic study. No matter how unwelcome the implications of a logical argument may be, it must be allowed to stand or fall on its merits not its desirability or political utility. First Harvard, then Google, and now the editors-in-chief of two esteemed scientific journals, the National Science Foundation, and the international publisher Springer have all surrendered to demands from the radical academic Left to suppress a controversial idea. Who will be the next, and for what perceived transgression? If bullying and censorship are now to be re-described as ‘advocacy’ and ‘academic freedom,’ as the Chicago administrators would have it, they will simply replace empiricism and rational discourse as the academic instruments of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Educators must practice what we preach and lead by example. In this way, we can help to foster intellectual curiosity and the discovery of fresh reasoning so compelling that it causes even the most sceptical to change their minds. But this necessarily requires us to reject censorship and open ourselves to the civil discussion of sensitive topics such as gender differences, and the variability hypothesis in particular. In 2015, the University of Chicago’s Committee on Freedom of Expression summarized the importance of this principle beautifully &lt;a href=&quot;https://freeexpression.uchicago.edu/sites/freeexpression.uchicago.edu/files/FOECommitteeReport.pdf&quot;&gt;in a report&lt;/a&gt; commissioned by none other than Professor Robert Zimmer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a word, the University’s fundamental commitment is to the principle that debate or deliberation may not be suppressed because the ideas put forth are thought by some or even by most members of the University community to be offensive, unwise, immoral, or wrong-headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ted Hill is Professor Emeritus of Mathematics at Georgia Tech, and currently a research scholar in residence at the California Polytechnic State University in San Luis Obispo. His memoir &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookstore.ams.org/mbk-103&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PUSHING LIMITS: From West Point to Berkeley and Beyond&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was recently published jointly by the American Mathematical Society and the Mathematical Association of America.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;cb_p6_patreon_button&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cb_p6_message_over_post_button&quot;&gt;If you liked this article please consider becoming a patron of Quillette&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/Quillette&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/quillette.com/wp-content/plugins/patron-button-and-widgets-by-codebard/images/become_a_patron_button.png?w=1023&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-official sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quads-location quads-ad10&quot; id=&quot;quads-ad10&quot;/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 23:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alexmat</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Academic Activists Send a Published Paper Down the Memory Hole - Quillette</og:title>
<og:description>In the highly controversial area of human intelligence, the ‘Greater Male Variability Hypothesis’ (GMVH) asserts that there are more idiots and more geniuses among men than among women. Darwin’s research on evolution in the nineteenth century found that, although there are many exceptions for specific traits and species, there is generally more variability in males than in females of the same species throughout the animal kingdom. Evidence for this hypothesis is fairly robust and has been reported in species ranging from adders and sockeye salmon to wasps and orangutans, as well as humans. Multiple studies have found that boys and men are over-represented at both the high and low ends of the distributions in categories ranging from birth weight and brain structures and 60-meter dash times to reading and mathematics test scores. There are significantly more men than women, for example, among Nobel laureates, music composers, and chess champions—and also among homeless people, suicide victims, and federal prison inmates. Darwin had also raised the question of why males in many species might have evolved to …</og:description>
<og:url>https://quillette.com/2018/09/07/academic-activists-send-a-published-paper-down-the-memory-hole/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i0.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/07020822/AdobeStock_61396442.jpeg?fit=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-AU</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://quillette.com/2018/09/07/academic-activists-send-a-published-paper-down-the-memory-hole/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jack Ma to Retire from Alibaba</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/technology/alibaba-jack-ma-retiring.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/technology/alibaba-jack-ma-retiring.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;44.352860096485&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;36.245348035837&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;HONG KONG — Alibaba’s co-founder and executive chairman, Jack Ma, said he planned to step down from the Chinese e-commerce giant on Monday to pursue philanthropy in education, a changing of the guard for the $420 billion internet company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/08/technology/the-unlikely-ascent-of-jack-ma-alibabas-founder.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;A former English teacher&lt;/a&gt;, Mr. Ma started Alibaba in 1999 and built it into one of the world’s most consequential e-commerce and digital payments companies, transforming how Chinese people shop and pay for things. That fueled his net worth to more than $40 billion, making him China’s richest man. He is revered by many Chinese, some of whom have put his portrait in their homes to worship in the same way that they worship the God of Wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ma is retiring as China’s business environment has soured, with Beijing and state-owned enterprises increasingly playing more interventionist roles with companies. Under President Xi Jinping, China’s internet industry has grown and become more important, prompting the government to tighten its leash. The Chinese economy is also facing slowing growth and increasing debt, and the country is embroiled in an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/business/trump-china-trade-war-tariffs.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;escalating trade war with the United States&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“He’s a symbol of the health of China’s private sector and how high they can fly whether he likes it or not,” Duncan Clark, author of the book “Alibaba: The House Jack Ma Built,” said of Mr. Ma. “His retirement will be interpreted as frustration or concern whether he likes it or not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;47.148066298343&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;41.909392265193&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In an interview, Mr. Ma said his retirement is not the end of an era but “the beginning of an era.” He said he would be spending more of his time and fortune focused on education. “I love education,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ma will remain on Alibaba’s board of directors and continue to mentor the company’s management. Mr. Ma turns 54 on Monday, which is also a holiday in China known as Teacher’s Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The retirement makes Mr. Ma one of the first founders among a generation of prominent Chinese internet entrepreneurs to step down from their companies. Firms including Alibaba, Tencent, Baidu and JD.com have flourished in recent years, growing to nearly rival American internet behemoths like Amazon and Google in their size, scope and ambition. For Chinese tycoons to step aside in their 50s is rare; they usually remain at the top of their organizations for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The departure of Mr. Ma is likely to jolt China’s internet industry, which has been reeling from the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/04/technology/jdcom-richard-liu-arrest-rape.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;arrest last weekend of Liu Qiangdong&lt;/a&gt;, the billionaire founder of the online retailer JD.com. Mr. Liu, who goes by Richard Liu in the English-speaking world, was arrested on a rape allegation in Minneapolis during a business trip. He was released and has since returned to Beijing, where JD.com is based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For Alibaba, Mr. Ma’s retirement completes a transition of power to other executives. Mr. Ma stepped down as Alibaba’s chief executive in 2013; the company’s current &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/08/business/international/alibaba-q4-earnings-new-ceo.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;chief executive is Daniel Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, who is a candidate to succeed Mr. Ma. Yet Mr. Ma had remained active as the face of the e-commerce firm, as well as an architect of its long-term strategy. He owns &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://otp.investis.com/clients/us/alibaba/SEC/sec-show.aspx?Type=page&amp;amp;FilingId=12879202-870682-963516&amp;amp;CIK=0001577552&amp;amp;Index=11800&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a 6.4 percent stake&lt;/a&gt; of Alibaba, according to securities filings, but has considerably more sway over the company thanks to its complicated legal structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;50.089014222658&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;48.684649337911&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ma, a natural salesman and charismatic leader, co-founded Alibaba with 17 others — some of them his students — out of his apartment in Hangzhou in eastern Zhejiang province in 1999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Alibaba started as an online marketplace for businesses to sell their products to other businesses. But it did not take off until it began the Taobao marketplace in 2003, which merchants used to sell goods directly to consumers. Alibaba later rolled out Alipay, an online payment service, to facilitate transactions in a country where few people had credit cards. Alipay later became Ant Financial, the financial subsidiary that Mr. Ma also controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Today, Alibaba’s empire encompasses e-commerce, online banking, cloud computing, digital media and entertainment — and even a corporate messaging service similar to Slack. The company owns or holds stakes in some of China’s most important media assets, including the Twitter-like social media site Weibo and the Hong Kong-based English-language newspaper The South China Morning Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Among China’s biggest companies, Alibaba is viewed as one of the firms with the deepest ranks of management talent. Many of the co-founders are still around, and professionals who joined the company later are now in charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Last month, Alibaba &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/23/technology/alibaba-earnings.html?rref=collection%2Ftimestopic%2FAlibaba&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=business&amp;amp;region=stream&amp;amp;module=stream_unit&amp;amp;version=latest&amp;amp;contentPlacement=2&amp;amp;pgtype=collection&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;reported a 60 percent increase&lt;/a&gt; in quarterly sales, even as profits fell. The company’s annual revenue totals about 250 billion yuan, or $40 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;While Alibaba has become dominant in China, it has faced a tougher time expanding internationally. The company has increased its presence outside of China by investing in e-commerce and online finance companies in India and Southeast Asia. But its efforts to muscle into the United States largely have not been successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Even after &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/video/business/100000004861537/trump-and-alibabas-founder.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Mr. Ma met with President-elect Donald J. Trump&lt;/a&gt; in early 2017 and promised to bring one million jobs to the United States, the federal government rejected Ant Financial’s bid to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/02/business/moneygram-ant-financial-china-cfius.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;acquire the American money transfer company MoneyGram&lt;/a&gt; this year over national security concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;44.359550561798&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;36.808988764045&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As Beijing has increased its involvement in the private sector, Mr. Ma has shifted what he has said about China’s government. He used to say that businesses should be in love with the government but never get married to each other, indicating that an arms-length relationship was preferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At a conference last November, Mr. Ma was more positive. “There’s no country like China in the world,” he said. “With political stability, social safety and 6 percent-plus economic growth, we have the best business environment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As Alibaba has flourished, Mr. Ma has talked many times about how he did not want to spend his whole life at the company, saying he would retire one day and go back to teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In 2014, he created the Jack Ma Foundation, which has worked to improve education in rural China. Mr. Ma’s Weibo social media handle is “spokesman for village teachers — Jack Ma.” Within Alibaba, he is known and referred to as “Teacher Ma.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-09-06/billionaire-jack-ma-prepares-for-life-after-alibaba&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;interview with Bloomberg TV this week&lt;/a&gt;, Mr. Ma signaled he was thinking about focusing more on philanthropy. He cited the Microsoft co-founder and philanthropist Bill Gates as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ma said he could never be as rich as Mr. Gates — but that he could retire earlier than Mr. Gates. Mr. Gates &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/05/technology/new-boss-at-microsoft-with-gates-at-his-side.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;stepped down as Microsoft’s chairman&lt;/a&gt; in 2014, at the age of 58.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;28.427295918367&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-k8fkhk&quot; readability=&quot;8.3333333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Li Yuan on Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LiYuan6&quot;&gt;@LiYuan6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interested in All Things Tech?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/signup/TU&quot;&gt;Get the Bits newsletter&lt;/a&gt; delivered to your inbox weekly for the latest from Silicon Valley and the technology industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-3glrhn&quot; readability=&quot;7.3317073170732&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page B1 of the New York edition with the headline: Founder Sees A ‘Beginning’ As He Retires From Alibaba&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 22:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/technology/alibaba-jack-ma-retiring.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Alibaba’s Jack Ma, China’s Richest Man, to Retire From Company He Co-Founded</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/09/08/business/08alibaba-print-dress/08alibaba1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>In an interview, Mr. Ma said it was “the beginning of an era” for him and that he planned to focus on philanthropy in education.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/technology/alibaba-jack-ma-retiring.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>