<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>I Got Paid $0 from the Uber Security Bug Bounty</title>
<link>https://medium.com/bread-and-circuses/how-i-got-paid-0-from-the-uber-security-bug-bounty-aa9646aa103f</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/bread-and-circuses/how-i-got-paid-0-from-the-uber-security-bug-bounty-aa9646aa103f</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;09dc&quot; id=&quot;09dc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;So Uber partners with HackerOne to offer a public bug bounty program, advertising a &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackerone.com/uber&quot; data-href=&quot;https://hackerone.com/uber&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$500 minimum guaranteed payout&lt;/a&gt; if a security vulnerability is found within an Uber app or information asset. Fair enough, I’ve led numerous penetration tests over the years in addition to delivering advanced pentest training for corporate clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;da06&quot; id=&quot;da06&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I spend a few days getting some resources lined up for the analysis piece, and build a fairly comprehensive map of Uber’s various endpoints using subdomain enumeration and application fingerprinting. I also start kicking the tires of Uber’s Android app, which is locked down pretty tight per the Uber Bug Bounty Treasure Map with &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/bug-bounty/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/bug-bounty/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;certificate-pinned HTTPS requests&lt;/a&gt;. After a few hours of wrangling with the Android SDK, I get the most recent Uber .apk running in an ARM emulator as they apparently don’t publish any x86 Android apps. Slooooooow progress to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e34a&quot; id=&quot;e34a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I manage to bypass some of the certificate pinning security in the Uber .apk, sufficient to start mapping out some of the Uber mobile endpoints. There is reference in that traffic to a Microsoft Phone API, so I head over to the Microsoft Store and start testing the Uber Surface/Windows Phone app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bf51&quot; id=&quot;bf51&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It doesn’t implement any type of certificate pinning, which is a violation of Uber’s own publicly-stated Treasure Map; so there’s the first guaranteed $500 payout per their bug bounty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;eb10&quot; id=&quot;eb10&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Uber uses OAuth2 tokens for all of their mobile app authentication workflow, which has a lot of security benefits over old school cookie-based authentication methods. I put together a Python-based client that can talk to Uber’s backends, to start harvesting OAuth2 tokens for entropy analysis and to see if there are any issues with their PRNG. What’s weird though is that the OAuth2 token doesn’t ever change, and I can’t find anything in the Uber developer documentation that deals with token expiration; literally the same token I was issued when I first created my Uber account for testing is the same token I keep getting, no matter how many times I log in and out of my account using the Surface app. Surely Uber is expiring these tokens at least once every few days?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cf4a&quot; id=&quot;cf4a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I put that issue on the back burner and start probing the Uber promo endpoint, which has two pretty glaring vulnerabilities in that it doesn’t implement any type of rate limiting for promo code POSTs nor does it require any multifactor authentication. Or in other words, I can fire up a massively concurrent Golang HTTP load testing suite such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tsenart/vegeta&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/tsenart/vegeta&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vegeta&lt;/a&gt; to issue thousands of promo code POSTs to this endpoint, to enumerate OAuth2 tokens; after getting Vegeta talking to the promo endpoint, I’m able to enumerate over a million OAuth2 tokens without any type of IP blacklisting or rate limiting taking place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dbca&quot; id=&quot;dbca&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So back to this token expiration issue. If I can pull a couple hundred thousand OAuth2 tokens by somehow figuring out how Uber expires issued tokens, then I can use some visualization tools to see if there are any patterns or attractors that emerge, which in turn can then be used with function approximation to try to guess some valid OAuth2 tokens. But this Surface app doesn’t actually communicate with the Uber backend whenever it processes a logout event, and I am able to access all Uber rider endpoints using my OAuth2 token even after the Surface app logs off. Huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b79a&quot; id=&quot;b79a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So Uber is processing mobile app logouts locally, without any type of token expiration or invalidation taking place. That’s a big one, and now I understand why there is no mention made to OAuth2 token expiration in any of the Uber developer documentation: because once a user creates an account with Uber, the OAuth2 token that’s issued never expires and their mobile applications &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;only process logout events locally in the client itself&lt;/em&gt;. This is a big application security No No that maps to several public CVE and OWASP vulnerability definitions, so I submit the first round of these issues to HackerOne for payment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0a7e&quot; id=&quot;0a7e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Issue 1: The Uber Customer Promo Endpoint does not implement multi factor authentication resulting in the ability of an attacker to enumerate millions of OAuth2 rider and driver tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;13fe&quot; id=&quot;13fe&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Issue 2: The Uber Customer Promo Endpoint does not implement any type of rate limiting and/or IP address blacklisting resulting in the ability of an attacker to enumerate millions of OAuth2 rider and driver tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b11d&quot; id=&quot;b11d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Issue 3: The Uber Microsoft Surface/Phone app does not implement certificate pinning in addition to accepting self-signed certificates in violation of the “cn.uber.com is a RESTful API performed over certificate-pinned HTTPS requests” required by the Uber Bug Bounty Treasure Map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;39cb&quot; id=&quot;39cb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Issue 4: Uber mobile apps are only processing logout events locally, resulting in OAuth2 tokens never being expired and with the ability to access driver and rider information after a user has logged out of their Uber mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2319&quot; id=&quot;2319&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So these tickets get assigned to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rbfletcher&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rbfletcher&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rob Fletcher&lt;/a&gt; with Uber’s security team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ff08&quot; id=&quot;ff08&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Issue 1: Uber knows about this problem, we are going to fix it in the future. No payout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e6aa&quot; id=&quot;e6aa&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Issue 2: Uber knows about this problem, we are going to fix it in the future. No payout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4c3e&quot; id=&quot;4c3e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Issue 3: Uber knows about this problem, we are going to fix it in the future. No payout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;36bb&quot; id=&quot;36bb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Issue 4: Uber does not currently have the ability to expire issued tokens. We are going to address this issue with our next generation authentication framework. No payout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5084&quot; id=&quot;5084&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At this point I’ve spent over a week of my time on this bug bounty that has a clearly stated $500 minimum payout policy; not one of these issues have been publicly documented as out-of-scope on Uber’s Bug Bounty Treasure Map and/or the HackerOne Uber Bug Bounty disclosure page; and, with the certificate pinning vulnerability directly contradicting the requirements of Uber’s Bug Bounty Treasure Map itself…?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;745f&quot; id=&quot;745f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So I file a mediation request with HackerOne. It gets assigned to Kevin Rosenbaum. His response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;d62a&quot; id=&quot;d62a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sorry you are having a negative experience with this issue, but we have contacted the Uber App Sec team and they have confirmed with us that these are not security issues that are in scope on their program. I understand that this can be a disappointment but I can assure you that they looked at this report and gave it the proper attention it deserved. I hope you can continue to work on our site and I wish you the best of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2f2b&quot; id=&quot;2f2b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;OK. Now I am determined to demonstrate a critical severity vulnerability that Uber can’t get around. It’s obviously open mic night in their infosec department, and I bet I can hammer them with something that they can’t dismiss as vaguely out of scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f579&quot; id=&quot;f579&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Another day of digging around and I can reflect query parameters from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.uber.com&quot; data-href=&quot;https://m.uber.com&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://m.uber.com&lt;/a&gt; mobile endpoint. Their Content Security Policy includes a whitelist for *.cloudfront.net. I can enable Cloudfront in my Amazon Web Services console and host whatever arbitrary JavaScript code I want there, to be executed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.uber.com.&quot; data-href=&quot;https://m.uber.com.&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://m.uber.com.&lt;/a&gt; These are two separate issues considered critical severity findings under Content Security Policy 3, in addition to the ability to reflect arbitrary whatever through their mobile endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2059&quot; id=&quot;2059&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I submit the report to Uber:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;0fa8&quot; id=&quot;0fa8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;11.36690647482&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The udi-id request parameter at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.uber.com/0-dfffb25d2cf6ceeb0a27.js&quot; data-href=&quot;https://m.uber.com/0-dfffb25d2cf6ceeb0a27.js&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--blockquote-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://m.uber.com/0-dfffb25d2cf6ceeb0a27.js&lt;/a&gt; mobile endpoint is copied into a javascript string encapsulated in double quotation marks, resulting in SSL-protected payloads being reflected unmodified in the application’s response. The script-src whitelist at the endpoint includes a wildcard *.cloudfront.net host, which could be used by any attacker with an Amazon Web Services account to provision an arbitrary cloudfront.net host to serve trusted files from. The endpoint also has a missing base-uri, which allows the injection of base tags. They can be used to set the base URL for all relative (script) URLs to an attacker controlled domain. In addition to the reflected XSS issue, both the script-src and base-uri issues are considered high severity findings under Content Security Policy 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;13e2&quot; id=&quot;13e2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;I’m also able to bypass the Uber OneLogin SSO portal, resulting in source code disclosure from their internal uChat employee messaging system. It’s not as serious as the XSS/CSP issues, but I throw that in a second report for good measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;942b&quot; id=&quot;942b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Rob Fletcher gets assigned the ticket:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;713a&quot; id=&quot;713a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll take a look into this one more time, but so far this is not a security bug that is in scope — you’ve failed to demonstrate Javascript execution in a modern browser and the other behavior you allude to with “generating some arbitrary text using single quotes” sounds like simple content injection, which is out of scope for our program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;6649&quot; id=&quot;6649&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refrain from making theoretical arguments for why something has security impact and instead familiarize yourself with our scope page and demonstrate actual security impact that is in scope per our guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;10ef&quot; id=&quot;10ef&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8229&quot; id=&quot;8229&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;One of my responses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;7daf&quot; id=&quot;7daf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Rob,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;9d87&quot; id=&quot;9d87&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is reflected XSS, and certainly in scope. For example, here is the Uber sample report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;72d0&quot; id=&quot;72d0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Summary&lt;br/&gt;reflected XSS in partners.uber.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;9cfb&quot; id=&quot;9cfb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Security Impact&lt;br/&gt;Since partners.uber.com has an authenticated experience, an XSS in this domain&lt;br/&gt;means an attacker can forge authenticated requests on behalf of the victim.&lt;br/&gt;Also, advanced phishing attacks and defacement are possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;5bcd&quot; id=&quot;5bcd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Reproduction Steps&lt;br/&gt;This is a reflected XSS in `partners.uber.com/ via the `lang` querystring&lt;br/&gt;parameter via the route `/documents`.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;475c&quot; id=&quot;475c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular issue is almost word-for-word the same as your sample vulnerability report, with a POC that executes arbitrary html from an SSL-protected Uber website, so I don’t know how you could possibly say this is not in scope…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7560&quot; id=&quot;7560&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;His response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;174f&quot; id=&quot;174f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not XSS if you can’t get Javascript to execute — we’re verifying your most recent payloads to see if they fire Javascript and will go from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0214&quot; id=&quot;0214&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;Ok. So I’ve demonstrated reflected XSS through their mobile endpoint, but their WAF is apparently filtering double quotes to prevent arbitrary JavaScript execution. So I build another payload, this time evading their WAF, and then inject an HTML form that says “ENTER YOUR UBER USERNAME AND PASSWORD” which gets perfectly rendered from &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.uber.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://m.uber.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://m.uber.com&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;61c6&quot; id=&quot;61c6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a login form. Not properly formatted, because I am not a web developer or professional phisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ded3&quot; id=&quot;ded3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;So now it’s a completely verified critical security vulnerability, with working POC that will harvest usernames and passwords from an Uber mobile endpoint, and SSL-protected with Uber’s signed certificate. The Uber development team gets involved, and additionally verifies that yes, they can execute arbitrary JavaScript code from any *.cloudfront.net host, so these are three distinct critical severity security issues: reflected XSS, HTML content injection, and a CSP that allows execution of arbitrary JavaScript from any *.cloudfront.net host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;49aa&quot; id=&quot;49aa&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So Uber pulls the &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.uber.com&quot; data-href=&quot;https://m.uber.com&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://m.uber.com&lt;/a&gt; endpoint, and starts redirecting the various offending applications to their OneLogin SSO portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8c54&quot; id=&quot;8c54&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Followed by locking and then closing without payment all of my submitted security reports, so that they can’t be viewed or publicly disclosed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e896&quot; id=&quot;e896&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And now the HackerOne / Uber Bug Bounty report submission button:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*XQ7OTHmiQfbygzIEVQhG5g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;927&quot; data-height=&quot;514&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*XQ7OTHmiQfbygzIEVQhG5g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*XQ7OTHmiQfbygzIEVQhG5g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;da3c&quot; id=&quot;da3c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;73d6&quot; id=&quot;73d6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Uber maintains GPS coordinate tracking data for tens of millions of people in the U.S. and abroad, so the security of their information assets is almost a matter of public interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;ec99&quot; id=&quot;ec99&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;All of the recent bad press about the brotato corporate culture at Uber is really real.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;0d41&quot; id=&quot;0d41&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Uber is not serious about their security efforts, and their HackerOne Bug Bounty is completely bogus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;e6a9&quot; id=&quot;e6a9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;If you invest any time and effort into HackerOne Bug Bounties, HackerOne does not honor their minimum bug bounty guarantee, and will not go to bat for you if you have a dispute with one of their well-placed vendors such as Uber.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;e24c&quot; id=&quot;e24c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Caveat Emptor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d7c7&quot; id=&quot;d7c7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:totallynotrobots@protonmail.com&quot; data-href=&quot;mailto:totallynotrobots@protonmail.com&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;totallynotrobots@protonmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 18:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>GregoryVPerry</dc:creator>
<og:title>How I Got Paid $0 From the Uber Security Bug Bounty</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/bread-and-circuses/how-i-got-paid-0-from-the-uber-security-bug-bounty-aa9646aa103f</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*XQ7OTHmiQfbygzIEVQhG5g.png</og:image>
<og:description>So Uber partners with HackerOne to offer a public bug bounty program, advertising a $500 minimum guaranteed payout if a security…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/bread-and-circuses/how-i-got-paid-0-from-the-uber-security-bug-bounty-aa9646aa103f</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Axiom Beta – Digital cinema camera built around FOSS and open hardware</title>
<link>https://www.apertus.org/axiom-beta</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apertus.org/axiom-beta</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20Standard%20wallpaper%2001%20Many%20Tweaks.png&quot; class=&quot;colorbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20Standard%20wallpaper%2001%20Many%20Tweaks.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured: AXIOM Beta Developer Kit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing AXIOM Beta, a professional digital cinema camera built around FOSS and open hardware licenses.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;twocoloumns&quot; readability=&quot;16.505592841163&quot;&gt;The first of its kind, and providing users with the ability to swap or upgrade sensors at any time, our community’s debut camera is the result of years of collaboration with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.magiclantern.fm/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Magic Lantern&lt;/a&gt; team. With powerful internal components, custom-built printed circuit boards and plugin modules, FPGAs and an onboard Linux operating system at your disposal, changing the entire operation of your camera to suit the needs of any project is now possible.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;The most interesting aspect of the AXIOM cameras is that they have the potential to be the last camera you will ever need… they won't eventually become technologically obsolete like most cameras.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20Compact%20Overview%2003.png&quot; class=&quot;colorbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20Compact%20Overview%2003.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AXIOM Beta Compact enclosure concept circa Nov 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This truly is the first camera where nothing is hidden from you.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera boasts superb image quality, high frame rates, rich colour science properties and a small, lightweight form factor. It's designed to evolve continuously and give users unparalleled access to the raw data being recorded from a sensor. Individual hardware components can be swapped out and upgraded as and when required, and software can be modified to suit the needs of specific use cases anytime. Take what we’ve done, modify anything you like in whatever way you like, and make it yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;We need a camera that is fully customisable. I can build my PC and pick every single part to fit my needs and upgrade each part as and when needed. It would be great to just upgrade the AF system or upgrade to a new sensor instead of buying a whole new camera.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Adam Cross&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Versions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AXIOM Beta is available/planned in the following enclosures/versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row-fluid&quot; readability=&quot;26.498204207286&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span4&quot; readability=&quot;22.390015600624&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20DK%20w%20Lens%20on%20e1e1e1.png&quot; class=&quot;colorbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20DK%20w%20Lens%20on%20e1e1e1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;AXIOM Beta Developer Kit&lt;/h3&gt;
This version of the camera is suitable for anyone who’d like to work on development, reconfigure its software and or core components, or build their own enclosures etc… Developer Kits are supported by a custom CNC-milled skeleton framework and provide easy access to the camera’s printed circuit boards - With this in mind associated design files, board layouts, BOMs, CAD models, software source code repositories, etc. are all made freely available.&lt;p&gt;For insight into how AXIOM Beta Developer Kits have been configured by members of the community see &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apertus.org/index.php/AXIOM_Beta/Case_Studies&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Case Studies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Price: €3,990.00 (excl. VAT + Shipping)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apertus.org/index.php/AXIOM_Beta/Prices&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-warning&quot;&gt;Order&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span4&quot; readability=&quot;20.322580645161&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20CP%20w%20Lens%20on%20e1e1e1.png&quot; class=&quot;colorbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20CP%20w%20Lens%20on%20e1e1e1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;AXIOM Beta Compact&lt;/h3&gt;
This enclosure option provides a solid but lightweight aluminum layer around the camera's electronics and incorporates several mount points and future expansion slots. Individual modules are swappable (eg. lens mount, plugin modules) and extra care has been taken to use screws instead of glue so that customisation, and, should the need arise, simple repairs are made easy.&lt;p&gt;AXIOM Beta Compact is purpose-built for rig integration and general in-the-field protection, making it ideally suited to most photo and video production environments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Price: €5,990.00 (excl. VAT + Shipping)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScLBP_C61CxAE39xH4B25re8TI5hxU9cf8ad9N-HjuMIlNs4Q/viewform?usp=send_form&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-warning&quot;&gt;Get Pre-Order Access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span4&quot; readability=&quot;15.206997084548&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20EX%20on%20e1e1e1%20b.png&quot; class=&quot;colorbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20EX%20on%20e1e1e1%20b.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;AXIOM Beta Extended&lt;/h3&gt;
Currently in a state of early development, and inspired by the 35mm film camera magazines of yesteryear's golden age of analog film cameras, this enclosure is ideal for any film production scenario and rests well on the DOP's shoulders. With ergonomics in mind and providing space for a more sophisticated airflow system, AXIOM Beta Extended is a camera and integrated AXIOM Recorder combination that plans to incorporate an INTEL NUC and 2.5&quot; SSD(s). And of course, the AXIOM Recorder module can be attached in various locations around the enclosure and at different angles.&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the AXIOM Beta Extended from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/axiom-team-talk-volume-13.2-article-november-2017&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Team Talk 13.2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Price: TBD&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScLBP_C61CxAE39xH4B25re8TI5hxU9cf8ad9N-HjuMIlNs4Q/viewform?usp=send_form&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-warning&quot;&gt;Get Pre-Order Access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hand-built. Constantly evolving.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;twocoloumns&quot; readability=&quot;15.243010752688&quot;&gt;Over the past five years our core team and the wider community have custom-built the PCBs (printed circuit boards) and software that bring AXIOM Beta to life. Since the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apertus.org/index.php/AXIOM_Project_Background&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;project’s beginnings&lt;/a&gt; each camera has been painstakingly assembled by hand and, wherever possible, open source programs and equipment have been used to accomplish all aspects of project development. Now, in the same way, we’ve also built machines to assemble the camera as precisely as we did.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“... regardless of the open source aspect of the project, it's different to other cameras because of how they implement the hardware. Whereas [other manufacturers] use their own ASICs (Application Specific Integrated Circuits) for the image &amp;amp; data processing, the AXIOM Beta uses an FPGA (Field Programmable Gate Array)... With an FPGA you can change the entire operation of the camera down to how it handles handshakes with the analog-to-digital converters from the sensor. Thus, the apertus° team can continuously provide updates and new features easier than any other manufacturer.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20II%20Overview%2001.png&quot; class=&quot;colorbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20II%20Overview%2001.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AXIOM Beta Compact enclosure concept circa Nov 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;twocoloumns&quot; readability=&quot;11.697478991597&quot;&gt;The AXIOM Beta's internal components consist of five PCBs, one of which accommodates two high speed module slots. Each module has a total bandwidth to and from the camera's main processing FPGA of at least 6 Gbit/s. This makes the modules perfect for dealing with high bandwidth video outputs like HDMI/Displayport/SDI, and has allowed us to explore the provision of solid state media recording facilities for an AXIOM Recorder. Learn more about structure on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apertus.org/index.php/AXIOM_Beta/Camera_Structure&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Project Wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;The hardware design of the AXIOM Beta was kept simple at first, purely addressing problems discovered with its predecessor, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/alpha_prototype&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;AXIOM Alpha&lt;/a&gt;. In the beginning we had intended to design the camera around a single board on top of an off-the-shelf FPGA/system-on-chip development board: the MicroZed™, but as a result of field testing and together with feedback gathered from the community we agreed to make it far more powerful by devising a more complex stack of boards where each layer is dedicated to specific functions.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Sebastian Pichelhofer, apertus°.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Specifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;table table-striped&quot; readability=&quot;19.091277890467&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.4666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;150px&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Sensor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;8.9735099337748&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ams Sensors Belgium CMV12000 - 4K resolution, Super 35mm diameter, global shutter with up to 300 frames per second at full resolution&lt;br/&gt;(This sensor has been used for research and development purposes but more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/axiom-beta-imagesensors&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;options&lt;/a&gt; will become available. For other compatible alternatives see &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apertus.org/index.php/Image_Sensor_Table&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Wiki: Image Sensor Table&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lens Mount&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive E-mount&lt;br/&gt;Compatible with mechanical adapters to accomodate every manual lens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camera Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SSH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebGUI (Smartphone, Tablet, Laptop, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AXIOM Remote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expansion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2x High-speed plugin module slots&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1x Medium-speed shield slot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1x Low-speed shield slot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2x Center Solder On (CSO) modules&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;21.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expansion Modules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single HDMI 1080p60 (4:4:4) output plugin module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dual 6G SDI output plugin module (in development)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genlock, Trigger, Timecode, LANC shields (in development)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4K Displayport/HDMI plugin module (in development)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSO Module for Motion Tracking (3D Accelerometer, 3D magnetometer, 3D gyroscope, air pressure e.g. for 3D tracking or image stabilization) (in development)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3x PMOD debug plugin module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1x PMOD debug plugin module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Connectivity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB / Serial Console / Gigabit Ethernet / WiFi (optional)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Image Processing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matrix color conversion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look-Up-Tables (LUTs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed Pattern Noise (FPN) compensation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;False color display&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overlays&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xilinx Zynq 7020 based MicroZed&lt;br/&gt;FPGA + Dual ARM Core&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operating System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embedded Linux (Arch)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power Supply&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5V DC supply module (swappable)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wide input voltage range module 5-40V (planned)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20Sensor%20Board%20PR%20Card%2004.png&quot; class=&quot;colorbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/AXIOM%20Beta%20Sensor%20Board%20PR%20Card%2004.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Very promising characteristics are being achieved with preliminary internal image capture and processing,&lt;br/&gt;indicating that, when development reaches a stage of greater maturity, the camera will record digital film at exceptional quality.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;twocoloumns&quot; readability=&quot;16.406976744186&quot;&gt;The modularity of the camera means that any of its internal components can be swapped out and replaced or upgraded, including the sensor. When we began the process of crowdfunding research and development we ran polls asking what sensor the community would like to see being used for demonstration purposes. Approximately 90% of project backers chose the ams Sensors Belgium, 35mm, 4K CMV12000. The following video was part of a Shakespearean adaptation shot by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5902750/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Traum und Wahnsinn&lt;/a&gt;, on AXIOM Beta, using the CMV12000.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;We're happy with the footage that's been captured with the camera through this particular sensor, but there's definitely room for good improvement as software matures.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Herbert Pötzl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L65zNiAnM0E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; gesture=&quot;media&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; YouTube transcoding downgrades image quality, but you may want to visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apertus.org/index.php/AXIOM_Beta/Video&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Video Archive&lt;/a&gt; to see early test footage submissions. There are uncompressed .mov .mp4 and .dng files in 720p, 1080p and 4K archived here if you'd like to play with them.&lt;h2&gt;Freedom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row-fluid&quot; readability=&quot;18.998027613412&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span4&quot; readability=&quot;13.641732283465&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/Overview%20ML2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full potential unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AXIOM Beta is being built together with experts from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.magiclantern.fm/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Magic Lantern&lt;/a&gt; team. The community that brought you the features Canon never wanted you to have are now bringing a cinema camera into the film-making world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because the AXIOM project and the software they originally pioneered are underpinned by the same ethos, Magic Lantern partnered with apertus° Association in September 2014. Since then they’ve been responsible for color science and raw processing inside the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;span4&quot; readability=&quot;17.826923076923&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/Overview%20Tux2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Love Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AXIOM project has been built around the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/what-is-linux&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; operating system. Together with the development tools it offers, Linux provides unparalleled control over the camera software’s functions and processing, but you don’t have to be a programmer to operate it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AXIOM Beta’s software incorporates a purpose-built user interface so that general functions e.g. shutter presets, ISO and inputting meta-data, can be controlled from the comfort of WiFi connected devices such as laptops, tablets and smart-phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The beauty of an open source camera to me is a step back toward the dark room, in which making the tools is part of the joy of making the art.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Lee Parker, IMAX Cinematographer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row-fluid&quot; readability=&quot;10.013513513514&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apertus.org/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/Overview%20Wiki%2002.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span9&quot; readability=&quot;15.258687258687&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
For all technical information e.g. User Manual, electronics schematics, PCB layouts, BOMs, STLs, and detailed reading on all aspects of project development, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apertus.org/index.php/Main_Page&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Project Wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;Any help with keeping Wiki pages up to date is greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row-fluid&quot; readability=&quot;6.7095435684647&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lab.apertus.org/home/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/Overview%20Labs.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span9&quot; readability=&quot;8.6265560165975&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Labs&lt;/h3&gt;
Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://lab.apertus.org/home/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;AXIOM Labs&lt;/a&gt; are like a forum with some extra performance modules. It has a rich content history dating back years and all project tasks are organised and discussed here. If you have feedback or ideas then consider creating a profile.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row-fluid&quot; readability=&quot;5.6949152542373&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apertus-open-source-cinema&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/Overview%20GH3.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span9&quot; readability=&quot;6.6440677966102&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Source Code&lt;/h3&gt;
Access all of the project's software source code repositories and mechanical component drawings on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apertus-open-source-cinema&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row-fluid&quot; readability=&quot;5.9613259668508&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/axiom-ecosystem&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/sites/default/files/images/Overview%20Ecosystem.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span9&quot; readability=&quot;7.3370165745856&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h3&gt;
By creating a profile on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apertus.org/axiom-ecosystem&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;AXIOM Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; you can list yourself as offering products or services to the community. See where your nearest AXIOM Beta camera is located here.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 14:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jarmitage</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apertus.org/axiom-beta</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Autocorrects Names of Some Medications to Names of Different Medications</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/slatestarcodex/status/944739157988974592</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/slatestarcodex/status/944739157988974592</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/slatestarcodex/status/944739157988974592&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/slatestarcodex/status/944739157988974592&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15997503&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15997503&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 239&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 124&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 02:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Houshalter</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/slatestarcodex/status/944739157988974592</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Effect of Atmospheric Nuclear Testing on American Mortality Patterns [pdf]</title>
<link>https://www.keithameyers.com/s/MeyersFalloutMortalityWebsite.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.keithameyers.com/s/MeyersFalloutMortalityWebsite.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/59262540b3db2b0d0d6d7d2b/t/59fbd873e31d19c9d1730554/1509677191992/Meyers.Fallout.Mortality.Website.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 01:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stablemap</dc:creator>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/59262540b3db2b0d0d6d7d2b/t/59fbd873e31d19c9d1730554/1509677191992/Meyers.Fallout.Mortality.Website.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Text-only news sites are slowly making a comeback</title>
<link>https://www.poynter.org/news/text-only-news-sites-are-slowly-making-comeback-heres-why</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.poynter.org/news/text-only-news-sites-are-slowly-making-comeback-heres-why</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A few days before Hurricane Irma hit South Florida, I received a query on Twitter from a graphic designer named Eric Bailey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Has anyone researched news sites capability to provide low-bandwidth communication of critical info during crisis situations?” he asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question was timely — two days later, CNN announced that they created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://lite.cnn.io/en&quot;&gt;text-only version&lt;/a&gt; of their site with no ads or videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;6.6453488372093&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;In Hurricane &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Irma?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Irma&lt;/a&gt;’s path with a weak phone connection? Stay up to date with the text-only version of our website &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/HkoJyA4UZZ&quot;&gt;https://t.co/HkoJyA4UZZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— CNN (@CNN) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CNN/status/906655810612232193&quot;&gt;September 9, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same week, NPR began promoting its text-only site, &lt;a href=&quot;http://thin.npr.org/&quot;&gt;text.npr.org&lt;/a&gt; on social media as a way for people with limited Internet connectivity during Hurricane Irma to receive updated information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related Training:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsu.org/courses/investigative-reporting-disaster-aftermath&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Investigative Reporting in the Wake of a Disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These text-only sites — which used to be more popular in the early days of the Internet, when networks were slower and bandwidth was at a premium – are incredibly useful, and not just during natural disasters. They load much faster, don’t contain any pop-ups or ads or autoplay videos, and help people with low bandwidth or limited Internet access. They’re also beneficial for people with visual impairments who use screen readers to navigate the Internet. (Related: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poynter.org/news/designing-journalism-products-accessibility&quot;&gt;Designing Journalism Products for Accessibility.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they were incredibly well received:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;5.1724137931034&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Hands down the best news site design of 2017. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/drsZcpjZyp&quot;&gt;https://t.co/drsZcpjZyp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— dan sinker (@dansinker) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dansinker/status/906691093919621120&quot;&gt;September 10, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;5.4285714285714&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;The text-only version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CNN&quot;&gt;@CNN&lt;/a&gt;’s website is incredibly refreshing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/0jWUhsGKDH&quot;&gt;https://t.co/0jWUhsGKDH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Jason Brush (@jasonbrush) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonbrush/status/912757490793684992&quot;&gt;September 26, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;6.7080745341615&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Maybe I'm just a grognard but this is pretty much the best designed news site I've seen. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/HS0FAuUZJ9&quot;&gt;https://t.co/HS0FAuUZJ9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Nicholas Lange (@nglange) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nglange/status/907698867621253120&quot;&gt;September 12, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;4.9345794392523&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Best web design I've seen in a while &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/f7cWUehCW0&quot;&gt;https://t.co/f7cWUehCW0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Brent Jackson (@jxnblk) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jxnblk/status/906941931309162496&quot;&gt;September 10, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPR’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://thin.npr.org/&quot;&gt;text.npr.org&lt;/a&gt; is likely the oldest example of a working text-only news site that’s still in existence. It originally launched as thin.npr.org back in June 2005, in response to the September 11th attacks — when many news sites struggled to stay online amidst record traffic numbers — and also to help people who were navigating to npr.org back in 2005 on handheld mobile devices like Blackberries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, a number of improvements were made to the site (which redirects to thin.npr.org) aimed specifically at low-bandwidth users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“More recently, our full site [npr.org] has made major accessibility gains,” write Patrick Cooper, NPR’s director of web and engagement, and Sara Goo, the managing editor of digital news. “But as accessible or as fast as you can make your full site —and speed is critical for us — low-bandwidth situations are a different challenge. [Our] improvements focused on those users in particular.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text.npr.org’s improvements included  “adding a caching layer to greatly improve speed and adding code to make the site display well on phones,” write Cooper and Goo. “We also increase[d] the number of stories on the [text.npr.org] homepage, made the homepage use the story ordering from our full site, updated the navigation links, removed an interim page in each story that showed only the first paragraph (something that was more valuable before we improved the page speed), and created an easier to remember “text.npr.org” redirect for the site.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent months, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.twitter.com/official/en_us/topics/product/2017/introducing-twitter-lite.html&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/08/facebook-lite/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/topics/journalism-news/introducing-google-news-lite-mode/&quot;&gt;Google News&lt;/a&gt; have also published their own versions of stripped-down sites that use less bandwidth, mainly aimed at users in emerging markets who might not have access to faster network connections. Earlier this week, Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/24/16357684/twitter-testing-twitter-lite-android-app-philippines&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it was now experimenting with an Android app designed to use less data for people with limited connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet most news organizations — aside from CNN, NPR, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theage.com.au/text&quot;&gt;The Age&lt;/a&gt; in Australia — don’t have low-bandwidth sites versions of their sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways that news organizations can improve the ways they serve both low-bandwidth users and people with visual impairments by stripping out unnecessary elements and optimizing different parts of a website. To learn more, I reached out to front-end website designer &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jalbertbowdenii&quot;&gt;J. Albert Bowden&lt;/a&gt;, who frequently tweets about accessibility and web design standards, to ask a few questions about how we might approach building text-only sites to help end users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kramer:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m curious. What kinds of things can be stripped from sites for low-bandwidth users and people with visual impairments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bowden:&lt;/strong&gt; Those are two very distinct user groups but some of the approaches bleed over and can be applied together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For low-bandwidth users: Cut the fluff. No pictures, no video, no ads or tracking. Text files are good enough here. Anything else is just fluff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For visually impaired users: I’m going to just talk about a11y [which is a shorthand way of referring to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_accessibility&quot;&gt;computer accessibility&lt;/a&gt;] here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A11y is best addressed in the foundation of a website, in the CSS, HTML, and JavaScript. There are other ways to go about doing it, but they are much more resource intensive and therefore are never going to be default for mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typical user agents for those with visual impairments are screen readers, which rely on the foundation (literally HTML) of a website to interpret its content and regurgitate it back to the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kramer:&lt;/strong&gt; Is text-only the way to go? Are there ways to think about preloading images and/or other methods that might help these users?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bowden:&lt;/strong&gt; Text in HTML is the way to go here; you cover accessibility issues and SEO bots, while simultaneously also being usable on the maximum number of devices possible. HTML and CSS are forgiving in the sense that you can make mistakes in them, and something will still be rendered to the user. Browsers are built with backwards compatibility, so combining them all grants you the extended coverage. Meaning that basic sites will work on nearly any phone. Any computer. Any browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you deviate from this path, all bets are off. Some are solid, no doubt, but most are shaky at least, and downright broken at worst. JavaScript is the bee’s knees and you can do anything in the world with it ... but if you make certain mistakes, your web page will not render in the browser; the browser will choke to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a plethora of best practices that can be utilized today that would make all of this much less painful. Lazy loading images/resources is one way, pre-caching resources is another,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are actually so many different things you can do here I won’t list them out. A better way to say this is: Every process in the chain can be optimized. You have to want it. You have to have resources to do it. You have to institutional support. Without these, you can still do a lot, but in the end you won’t ever get the best optimization because somewhere along the line will be an obstacle you won’t have the authority to remove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kramer:&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of the conversations taking place now around low-bandwidth news sites are focused on natural disasters, but I suspect these sites would also help people in news deserts or places where Internet access isn't as robust as on the coasts. Any other use cases?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bowden:&lt;/strong&gt; Even in cities [it would be useful]. The Metro suuuuuuuuuuuuucks for this; I don’t even try to click links on it; I actually have a routine where I either get what I want to load before I get on the train, or move to stored content/text on my phone. There’s no point in even trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you familiar with a different low-bandwidth news sites that’s not listed here? Please let me know. I’d love to make a more comprehensive list for a future column. Please email me: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melodykramer@gmail.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;melodykramer@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Sara Goo is now managing editor of digital news at NPR. A previous version of this story had an older title for her.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 01:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>georgecmu</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.poynter.org/news/text-only-news-sites-are-slowly-making-comeback-heres-why</og:url>
<og:title>Text-only news sites are slowly making a comeback. Here's why.</og:title>
<og:image>https://www.poynter.org/sites/default/files/2017-09/Text%20sites.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.poynter.org/news/text-only-news-sites-are-slowly-making-comeback-heres-why</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Papercraft with Blender</title>
<link>https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/2017/12/23/papercraft-with-blender/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/2017/12/23/papercraft-with-blender/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Blender version 2.79 incorporated functionality which enables you to fabricate 3D models by folding paper. I decided to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Drawing the model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I downloaded a 3D model of a goat and re-meshed it so that it had fewer polygons and it would be easier to assemble. This is how it looks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;27&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg?w=840&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,1688&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg?w=840?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg?w=840?w=840&quot; src=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg?w=840&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-27 alignnone size-full&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg?w=840 840w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg?w=1680 1680w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0002-1623609323.jpeg?w=1024 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;28&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/img-20171101-wa0000105392085/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg?w=840&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,1688&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg?w=840?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg?w=840?w=840&quot; src=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg?w=840&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-28 alignnone size-full&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg?w=840 840w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg?w=1680 1680w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0000105392085.jpeg?w=1024 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;29&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/img-20171101-wa0004822196356/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg?w=840&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,1688&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg?w=840?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg?w=840?w=840&quot; src=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg?w=840&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-29 alignnone size-full&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg?w=840 840w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg?w=1680 1680w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171101-wa0004822196356.jpeg?w=1024 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Printing the templates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it was time to let the Blender plugin do the mathemagic. After some parameter tweaks, this is a sample of what I got printed on a cardboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;26&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg?w=840&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,1688&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg?w=840?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg?w=840?w=840&quot; src=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg?w=840&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-26 alignnone size-full&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg?w=840 840w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg?w=1680 1680w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171029-wa0005-270844442.jpeg?w=1024 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;25&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/img-20171102-wa0005530656369/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg?w=840&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1688,3000&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg?w=840?w=169&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg?w=840?w=576&quot; src=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg?w=840&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-25 alignnone size-full&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg?w=840 840w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg?w=1680 1680w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg?w=84 84w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg?w=169 169w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171102-wa0005530656369.jpeg?w=576 576w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Folding and glueing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used a mix of glue and paper tape. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After several hours of folding and pasting, here is the final result:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;22&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/img-20171222-wa00051963948810/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg?w=840&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,1688&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg?w=840?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg?w=840?w=840&quot; src=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg?w=840&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-22 alignnone size-full&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg?w=840 840w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg?w=1680 1680w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00051963948810.jpeg?w=1024 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;24&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/img-20171222-wa00032125589475/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg?w=840&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,1688&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg?w=840?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg?w=840?w=840&quot; src=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg?w=840&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-24 alignnone size-full&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg?w=840 840w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg?w=1680 1680w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00032125589475.jpeg?w=1024 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;23&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/img-20171222-wa00011034282948/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg?w=840&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,1688&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg?w=840?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg?w=840?w=840&quot; src=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg?w=840&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-23 alignnone size-full&quot; srcset=&quot;https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg?w=840 840w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg?w=1680 1680w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg?w=1024 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 709px) 85vw, (max-width: 909px) 67vw, (max-width: 1362px) 62vw, 840px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this is a really time consuming endeavor, it’s a fun way to burn away a whole weekend + you’ll have a lasting reminder that you lived that weekend, as opposed to other weekends in which you just spent the time and got nothing for it. The end results look superb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ideas floating my head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What if I would plasma-cut it from a metal sheet with a CNC and tig-weld it? 🤔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if I filled the hull with some other material? Woul&lt;span&gt;d it have any application? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I make it faster? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember to be nice to goats and other animals, keep them out of your plate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Compártelo:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-140174882-30-5a403f083446e&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=140174882&amp;amp;post_id=30&amp;amp;origin=matiasmorant.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=140174882-30-5a403f083446e&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-140174882-30-5a403f083446e&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9eb3f772852ff5c02a3d895c38d11c19?s=42&amp;amp;d=identicon&amp;amp;r=G&quot; class=&quot;avatar avatar-42&quot; height=&quot;42&quot; width=&quot;42&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wvlia5</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Papercraft with Blender</og:title>
<og:url>https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/2017/12/23/papercraft-with-blender/</og:url>
<og:description>Blender version 2.79 incorporated functionality which enables you to fabricate 3D models by folding paper. I decided to try it out. Drawing the model I downloaded a 3D model of a goat and re-meshed…</og:description>
<og:image>https://matiasmorant.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/img-20171222-wa00011034282948.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://matiasmorant.wordpress.com/2017/12/23/papercraft-with-blender/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Algorithmic Solution to My Insomnia</title>
<link>http://ilya.sukhar.com/blog/an-algorithmic-solution-to-insomnia.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://ilya.sukhar.com/blog/an-algorithmic-solution-to-insomnia.html</guid>
<description>&lt;header&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Ilya Sukhar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve struggled with insomnia for all of my adult life. It began in college and has waxed and waned in severity ever since, correlating with stress levels but not entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My form of insomnia starts with an active mind some evening. Maybe it’s active because I’m thinking through a challenge at work. Or I’m replaying a lively dinner conversation. Or I’m on a trip and excited. So, not necessarily stressful thoughts, just engaging ones. I go to bed but my mind doesn’t quiet down. 30 minutes later, I realize I’m not asleep and I start to think, “I really need to get to sleep. I have a lot going on tomorrow.” That only exacerbates the problem. My thoughts turn entirely meta and self defeating, “What’s wrong with me? Ugh, tomorrow will be miserable. Ok, let’s try for real now.” Repeat ad nauseam, laying in bed for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, as you might imagine, the next day is indeed terrible and the next evening my mind is primed with negative thoughts about my sleep habits. The cycle continues. At its worst, I would go entirely without sleep for a half a dozen nights out of a month. In the steady state, it’d be one or two nights a month. Needless to say, both the peaks and troughs were quite disruptive to my quality of life and work output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I had come to just accept it and cope. I figured I’d been dealt a poor hand in the relevant genetic lottery and this was the cost of doing business. Sometimes I’d use Ambien or other aids to get through it but I was always wary of the side effects and addiction potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early 2016, I got fed up. I was blissfully unemployed and throughly de-stressed from having traveled extensively after quitting my job. Yet, I was still having issues sleeping — still going almost entirely sleepless for a couple nights a month. This seemed ridiculous, so I resolved to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to read up on the latest research about insomnia but I found the volume of academic literature overwhelming for a layman. And it was mostly pharmacologically-oriented which I was intent on avoiding. Outside of journals, the online information on sleep is largely terrible — a rehash of common wisdom or an attempt to sell you something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I sought out a Stanford researcher with a private sleep-therapy practice. After disqualifying me of more serious mental health issues, she ran me through a variant of a program known as CBT-i or “Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Insomnia”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;/&gt;. It turned out to be extremely effective and I now have a playbook for good sleep even as my stress levels have rebounded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m thrilled to have made this breakthrough. But it was time consuming and expensive to get there. And it struck me how it all boiled down to a fairly simple algorithm albeit one that requires a lot of willpower and would be hard to derive on your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish someone had told me to try this many years earlier. So I write this in hopes that it’ll help someone out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;common-wisdom-invariants&quot;&gt;Common Wisdom Invariants&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have trouble sleeping, I’m sure you’ve heard these all before. In my experience they are necessary but not sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exercise regularly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit caffeine and alcohol consumption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t eat late at night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t nap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wind down an hour before bed. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invest in your bed. Keep your bedroom dark and cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;unintuitive-new-invariants&quot;&gt;Unintuitive New Invariants&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gist here is: “don’t force it and don’t hang out in bed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Never get in bed and try to sleep because “it’s bedtime”. Only get in bed when you are dying to go to bed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re in bed for more than 20 minutes and haven’t fallen asleep yet, get out and do something else. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get out of bed right away when you wake up in the morning. Don’t linger and don’t try to sleep in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t change your day based on your quality of sleep. No matter how bad it was, don’t deviate from your normal routine — don’t cancel meetings, don’t skip a workout, don’t try to sleep earlier the following evening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-algorithm&quot;&gt;The Algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gist here is: “sleep a lot less before you can sleep more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Start out by setting a wake up time that leaves you plenty of time in the morning. For me, this was 6 a.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick a target sleep time that leaves you with about two hours of sleep &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; than you think you need. For me, this was midnight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treat the target sleep time as a goalpost to get past. That is, don’t sleep, nap, or get in bed before it — no matter what. And make sure to strictly abide by all the invariants above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you wake up, jot down the following:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;When you went to bed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you fell asleep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How long you spent awake in the middle of the night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you woke up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you got out of bed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of every week, calculate the average of your time spent asleep divided by your time spent in bed each night. Like so &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;/&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;efficiency=average(time asleeptime in bed)=17∑i=17di−bi−ciei−ai\text{efficiency} = \text{average(}\frac{\text{time asleep}}{\text{time in bed}}\text{)} = \frac{1}{7}\sum_{i=1}^{7}\frac{d_i-b_i-c_i}{e_i-a_i}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;efficiency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;average(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm mtight&quot;&gt;time in bed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm mtight&quot;&gt;time asleep&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm mtight&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm mtight&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop op-symbol small-op&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel mtight&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm mtight&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm mtight&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size3 size1 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin mtight&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size3 size1 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size3 size1 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin mtight&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size3 size1 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin mtight&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size3 size1 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;efficiency&amp;lt;.8\text{efficiency} &amp;lt; .8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;efficiency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, push your target sleep time back even later by 20 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;.9≤efficiency&amp;lt;.95.9 \leq \text{efficiency} &amp;lt; .95&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;≤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;efficiency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathrm&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, push your target sleep time up earlier by 20 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, stay the course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go back to step #3. Repeat forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s the point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it turns out that insomnia is largely a form of performance anxiety that accrues over years of episodic poor sleep due to stress, travel, environmental changes, etc. Your mind gradually loses confidence in the act of going to sleep and jumps quickly to counter-productive thoughts while you lay in bed. If you expect to sleep poorly, you will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drastically restricting your sleep with this regimen wrestles control away from your mind and puts it back into the rightful hands of your body and its circadian rhythm&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;/&gt;. If you stick to the rules, you’re effectively running a search algorithm to find your body’s optimal schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The algorithm starts by finding an aggregate level of sleep low enough that your body’s need for it overpowers your mind’s obstructionism. Finding this lower bound is painful but it definitely exists. Once you’ve found it, you relax the constraint gradually as your mind builds confidence that it can indeed sleep well and that the bed is a relaxing oasis. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually the algorithm converges and you have a schedule that works without any of the bookkeeping. You still need to stick to the invariants so as not to trip up the rhythm you’ve locked in. If you do get knocked off track by a spike in stress or long term travel, just restart the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if this helps you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written December 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 23:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>csmajorfive</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://ilya.sukhar.com/blog/an-algorithmic-solution-to-insomnia.html</og:url>
<og:title>An Algorithmic Solution to Insomnia</og:title>
<og:description>I’ve struggled with insomnia for all of my adult life. It began in college and has waxed and waned in severity ever since, correlating with stress levels but not entirely.</og:description>
<og:image>http://ilya.sukhar.com/assets/insomnia.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://ilya.sukhar.com/blog/an-algorithmic-solution-to-insomnia.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>NumPy Tricks and Pitfalls</title>
<link>http://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/vlad17/np-learn/blob/master/presentation.ipynb?flush_cache=true</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/vlad17/np-learn/blob/master/presentation.ipynb?flush_cache=true</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Why on earth would you do the above? Selection, sampling, algorithms that are based on offsets of arrays (i.e., basically all of them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's going on?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced indexing is best thought of in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical &lt;code&gt;ndarray&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;, with shape &lt;code&gt;(n0, ..., nN-1)&lt;/code&gt; has &lt;code&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; corresponding &lt;em&gt;indices&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(range(n0), ..., range(nN-1))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indices work like this: the &lt;code&gt;(i0, ..., iN-1)&lt;/code&gt;-th element in an array with the above indices over &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(range(n0)[i0], ..., range(n2)[iN-1]) == (i0, ..., iN-1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the &lt;code&gt;(i0, ..., iN-1)&lt;/code&gt;-th element of &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; is the &lt;code&gt;(i0, ..., iN-1)&lt;/code&gt;-th element of &quot;x with indices &lt;code&gt;(range(n0), ..., range(nN-1))&lt;/code&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An advanced index &lt;code&gt;x[:, ..., ind, ..., :]&lt;/code&gt;, where &lt;code&gt;ind&lt;/code&gt; is some 1D list of integers for axis &lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt; between &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;nj&lt;/code&gt;, possibly with repretition, replaces the straightforward increasing indices with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(range(n0), ..., ind, ..., range(nN-1))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;(i0, ..., iN-1)&lt;/code&gt;-th element is &lt;code&gt;(i0, ..., ind[ij], ..., iN-1)&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the shape will now be &lt;code&gt;(n0, ..., len(ind), ..., nN-1)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can get even more complicated -- &lt;code&gt;ind&lt;/code&gt; can be higher dimensional.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 20:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vladf</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/vlad17/np-learn/blob/master/presentation.ipynb?flush_cache=true</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ten years in, nobody has come up with a use for blockchain</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@kaistinchcombe/ten-years-in-nobody-has-come-up-with-a-use-case-for-blockchain-ee98c180100</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@kaistinchcombe/ten-years-in-nobody-has-come-up-with-a-use-case-for-blockchain-ee98c180100</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;5ab1&quot; id=&quot;5ab1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Everyone says the blockchain, the technology underpinning cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin, is going to change EVERYTHING. And yet, after years of tireless effort and billions of dollars invested, nobody has actually come up with a use for the blockchain—besides currency speculation and illegal transactions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fbe7&quot; id=&quot;fbe7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Each purported use case — from payments to legal documents, from escrow to voting systems—amounts to a set of contortions to add a distributed, encrypted, anonymous ledger where none was needed. What if there isn’t actually any use for a distributed ledger at all? What if, ten years after it was invented, the reason nobody has adopted a distributed ledger at scale is because nobody wants it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;5b6d&quot; id=&quot;5b6d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Payments and banking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;59be&quot; id=&quot;59be&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;The original intended use of the blockchain was to power currencies like bitcoin — a way to store and exchange value much like any other currency. Visa and MasterCard were dinosaurs, everyone proclaimed, because there was now a costless, instant way to exchange value without the middleman taking a cut. A revolution in banking was just the start… governments, unable to issue currency by fiat anymore, would take a back seat as individual citizens transacted freely outside any national system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*JO6Hc6Xt4m7g_A9sn5Xrgw.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;576&quot; data-height=&quot;277&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*JO6Hc6Xt4m7g_A9sn5Xrgw.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*JO6Hc6Xt4m7g_A9sn5Xrgw.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The killer feature: knowing you can get your money back
&lt;p name=&quot;8347&quot; id=&quot;8347&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;It didn’t take long for that dream to fall apart. For one thing, there’s already a costless, instant way to exchange value without a middleman: cash. Bitcoins substitute for dollars, but Visa and MasterCard actually sit on top of dollar-based banking transactions, providing a set of value-added services like enabling banks to track fraud disputes, and verifying the identity of the buyer and seller. It turns out that for the person paying for a product, the key feature of a new payment system — think of PayPal in its early days — is the confidence that if the goods aren’t as described you’ll get your money back. And for the person accepting payment, basically the key feature is that their customer has it, and is willing to use it. Add in points, credit lines, and a free checked bag on any United flight and you have something that consumers choose and merchants accept. Nobody actually wants to pay with bitcoin, which is why it hasn’t taken off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;cec7&quot; id=&quot;cec7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pullquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key feature of a new payment system — think of PayPal in its early days — is the confidence that if the goods aren’t as described you’ll get your money back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*BR-yP7KTiDCVV9VIaDFkOg.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;1500&quot; data-height=&quot;625&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*BR-yP7KTiDCVV9VIaDFkOg.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*BR-yP7KTiDCVV9VIaDFkOg.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
It would take 5,000 nuclear reactors to run Visa on the blockchain.
&lt;p name=&quot;0a81&quot; id=&quot;0a81&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Plus, it’s not actually that good a payment system — Visa can handle sixty thousand transactions per second, while Bitcoin historically taps out at seven. There are technical modifications going on to improve Bitcoin’s efficiency, but as a starting point, you have something that’s about 0.01% as good at clearing transactions. (And, worth noting, for those seven transactions a second Bitcoin is already estimated to use 35 times as much energy as Visa. If you brought Bitcoin’s transaction volume up to Visa’s it would be using as much electricity as the rest of the world put together.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;9686&quot; id=&quot;9686&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Freedom to transact without government supervision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c81f&quot; id=&quot;c81f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;In many countries, and often our own, a little bit of ability to keep a few things private from the authorities probably makes the world a better place. In places like Cuba or Venezuela, many prefer to transact in dollars, and bitcoin could in theory serve a similar function. Yet there are two reasons this hasn’t been the panacea it’s assumed: the advantages of government to the individual, and the advantages of government to society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*3aCwHQ0Z30QzArL8hLgQ4A.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-height=&quot;1090&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*3aCwHQ0Z30QzArL8hLgQ4A.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*3aCwHQ0Z30QzArL8hLgQ4A.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Mt Gox loses all its customers’ money
&lt;p name=&quot;75b9&quot; id=&quot;75b9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The government-backed banking system provides FDIC guarantees, reversibility of ACH, identity verification, audit standards, and an investigation system when things go wrong. Bitcoin, by design, has none of these things. I saw a remarkable message thread by someone whose bitcoin account got drained because their email had been hacked and their password was stolen. They were stunned to have no recourse! And this is widespread — in 2014, the then-#1 bitcoin trader, Mt. Gox, also lost $400m of investor money due to security failures. The subsequent #1 bitcoin trader, Bitfinex, also shut down after a loss of customer funds. Imagine the world if more banks had been drained of customer funds than not. Bitcoin is what banking looked like in the middle ages — “here’s your libertarian paradise, have a nice day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;a8f4&quot; id=&quot;a8f4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pullquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is what banking looked like in the middle ages — “here’s your libertarian paradise, have a nice day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*ppv1m-NBW9M6WajMhWdQWg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;720&quot; data-height=&quot;389&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*ppv1m-NBW9M6WajMhWdQWg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*ppv1m-NBW9M6WajMhWdQWg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Mongolian banks experienced +400% transaction volume with new sanctions against Russia. New slogan –“Bitcoin: less cops than Mongolia.”
&lt;p name=&quot;7c81&quot; id=&quot;7c81&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Second, government policies are designed to disrupt terrorist financing and organized crime, and prevent traffic in illegal goods like stolen credit card numbers or child pornography. The mainstream preference is to have transactions private but not &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;undiscoverable under warrant&lt;/em&gt; — ask “should the government have a list everyone you’ve paid money to,” and most will say no; ask “should the government be able under warrant to get a list everyone a child pornography collector has paid money to,” and most will say yes. Nobody wants bitcoin to 100x the total traffic in goods and services our government defines as illegal — as one bitcoin enthusiast pointed out to me, “If you invented cash today, it would be illegal too.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;04d6&quot; id=&quot;04d6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Micropayments and bank-to-bank transfers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6148&quot; id=&quot;6148&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;It’s worth noting two particular payment use cases where people are particularly excited about blockchain-based currencies: micropayments and bank-to-bank transfers. In terms of micropayments, people enthuse that bitcoin transactions are free and instant. Actually, they take about eight minutes to clear and cost about four cents to process. People have proposed that you will use bitcoins for micropayments — for example, paying two cents to a musician to listen to their song on the internet, or four cents to read a newspaper article. Yet the infrastructure to do this — for example, advance authorization with the source of funds so you don’t have to wait eight minutes to read the article you just clicked — actually eliminates the need for bitcoin at all. If you’re happy to pay four cents an article or two cents a song, you can set it up to bill once a month from your bank account and read to your heart’s content. And in practice, people prefer subscription services to micropayments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*10d8C4mgV04dHzf8UA1eEw.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;355&quot; data-height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*10d8C4mgV04dHzf8UA1eEw.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Three years in, Ripple is to SWIFT what toothpicks are to the US GDP
&lt;p name=&quot;c6d2&quot; id=&quot;c6d2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;In terms of interbank payments, many people mention Ripple as a promising way to transfer money between banks. Over the last 30 days it processed two billion dollars (as of this writing) worth of interbank and interpersonal transactions — about 40 seconds’ worth of volume on the SWIFT interbank network — after three years of being available to banks to trade 90% of the world’s high-volume currencies. This is like the proportion of US GDP comprised by toothpick sales. Why haven’t banks preferred this new technology? The answer is that setting up a Ripple Gateway isn’t actually much different than using the existing corresponding-account system — except that a lost password or security token can lead to much larger and more instant actual losses — which, as a reminder, has happened to more leading bitcoin exchanges than have managed to avoid it. The same features that make the banking system attractive to end users also make it attractive to banks. They already have ledgers, and don’t need to distribute them, anonymize them, encrypt them, publish them, and make them irreversible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;3998&quot; id=&quot;3998&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;“Smart” contracts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;34ec&quot; id=&quot;34ec&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;“Smart” contracts are contracts written as software, rather than written as legal text. Because you can encode them directly on the blockchain, they can involve the transfer of value based directly on the cryptographic consent of the parties involved — in other words, they are “self-executing.” And in theory, contracts written in software are cheaper to interpret — because their operation is literally mathematical and automatic, there are no two ways to interpret them, which means there’s no need for expensive legal battles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*hVxwPdClc3-g5qVCnYOiJg.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;859&quot; data-height=&quot;624&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*hVxwPdClc3-g5qVCnYOiJg.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*hVxwPdClc3-g5qVCnYOiJg.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The DAO loses all its customers’ money
&lt;p name=&quot;6aa2&quot; id=&quot;6aa2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;And yet the real-world examples show the ways this is problematic. The most prominent and largest smart contract to date, an investment vehicle called the Distributed Autonomous Organization (DAO), enabled its members to invest directly using their private cryptographic keys to vote on what to invest in. No lawyers, no management fees, no opaque boardrooms, the DAO “removes the ability of directors and fund managers to misdirect and waste investor funds.” And yet, due to a software bug, the DAO “voted” to “invest” $50m, a third of its members’ money, into a vehicle controlled by very clever programmers who knew a lot about recursion issues during balance updates. Some said this was a hack or an exploit because the software had not functioned as intended, while others said that there was no such thing as a hack — &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;the whole point&lt;/em&gt; was that the software made decisions autonomously and there were no two ways to interpret it, and if you didn’t understand how the software worked you shouldn’t have participated. In the end, everyone got together and voted to retroactively amend the software contract and move the money back to its original owners. What’s the takeaway? &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Even the most die-hard blockchain enthusiasts actually want a bunch of humans arguing about the underlying intention behind a contract, rather than letting the software self-execute.&lt;/em&gt; Maybe the “dumb” way is smart after all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*0J35OvYBL8EwL_4PwO8wCA.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;980&quot; data-height=&quot;650&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*0J35OvYBL8EwL_4PwO8wCA.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*0J35OvYBL8EwL_4PwO8wCA.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Even crypto enthusiasts want to argue about what their contracts mean
&lt;p name=&quot;4413&quot; id=&quot;4413&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The DAO was an illustrative experiment, but what about for routine transactions at big companies? The investors and startups in the smart-contract space promise that the block chain will enable super-fast execution and payment — for example that in healthcare applications, “instead of waiting 90–180 days for a claim to be processed, or spending hours on the phone trying to get your bill paid, it can in theory be processed on the spot.” But that’s true for any software-enabled purchasing system. My company’s Amazon servers scale automatically based on website traffic and bill us for how much we use. The idea that smart contracts would change this is a fallacy — it conflates the legal arrangement being &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;put into effect&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;with software&lt;/em&gt; with the legal arrangement itself being &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;coded as software&lt;/em&gt;. Amazon’s terms of service are not a smart contract, but the billing system that implements those terms is automated. To the extent that health insurance billing, for example, is not automated, the problem isn’t that existing software isn’t “smart” enough to handle submitting claims and paying them electronically, it’s that the insurance company is slow moving, either by accident or because they on-purpose prefer a human review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*II2cvkSwiXzg9W05LiKU4g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1012&quot; data-height=&quot;319&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*II2cvkSwiXzg9W05LiKU4g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*II2cvkSwiXzg9W05LiKU4g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Can bitcoin make this go faster please?
&lt;p name=&quot;85ee&quot; id=&quot;85ee&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;In the end, everyone from blockchain enthusiasts to health insurers actually wants to argue out in human language what the business relationship is and interpret it on an ongoing basis, and then to write software that handles the fulfillment and payment. That already exists — it’s the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;5bcc&quot; id=&quot;5bcc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Distributed storage, computing, and messaging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2e59&quot; id=&quot;2e59&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Another implausible idea is using the blockchain as a distributed storage mechanism. On its face it makes sense — you break your document up into “blocks”, encrypt them, and put them in a distributed ledger… it’s backed up across multiple locations, it’s secure, and easy to track everything that happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1afa&quot; id=&quot;1afa&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Yet there are multiple excellent ways to break up files, encrypt them, and replicate them across multiple storage media in different locations. There is already a company that bills itself as a cheaper, distributed Dropbox, which encrypts and stores files across multiple users’ hard drives and pays them a small fee for the free space on their hard drives. The block chain is just a particularly inefficient and insecure way of doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*sU70xqzFnMITIeanLeuQTw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1034&quot; data-height=&quot;424&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*sU70xqzFnMITIeanLeuQTw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*sU70xqzFnMITIeanLeuQTw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Ha! Can your blockchain do &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--figure-em&quot;&gt;THIS?&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;de49&quot; id=&quot;de49&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;There are four additional problems with a blockchain-driven approach. First, you’re relying on single-point encryption — your own private keys — rather than a more sophisticated system that might involve two-factor authorization, intrusion detection, volume limits, firewalls, remote IP tracking, and the ability to disconnect the system in an emergency. Second, price tradeoffs are entirely implausible — the bitcoin blockchain has consumed almost a billion dollars worth of electricity to hash an amount of data equivalent to about a sixth of what I get for my ten dollar a month dropbox subscription. Fourth, systematically choosing where and how much to replicate data is an advantage in the long run — the blockchain’s defaults on data replication just aren’t that smart. And finally, Dropbox and Box.com and Google and Microsoft and Apple and Amazon and everyone else provide a set of valuable other features that you don’t actually want to go develop on your own. Analogous to Visa, the problem isn’t storing data, it’s managing permissions, un-sharing what you shared before, getting an easy-to-view document history, syncing it on multiple devices, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4474&quot; id=&quot;4474&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The same argument holds for proposed distributed computing and secure messaging applications. Encrypting it, storing it forever, and replicating it across the entire network is just a ton of overhead relative to what you’re actually trying to accomplish. There are excellent computing, messaging, and storage solutions out there that have all the encryption and replication anyone needs — actually better than blockchain based solutions — and have plenty of other great features in addition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;06be&quot; id=&quot;06be&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Stock issuance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d026&quot; id=&quot;d026&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;It was much-heralded when NASDAQ launched an internal blockchain-driven exchange for privately-held stocks. But wait: correct me if I’m wrong, but the whole purpose of NASDAQ (or the DTCC trade clearing system, for example) is that it has a ledger of who owns what stocks? Were they &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;nervous&lt;/em&gt; that their systems, absent blockchain, would soon be unable to keep track of who owns what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0133&quot; id=&quot;0133&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Similar to other transaction-tracking problems such as customer-to-merchant payments, the difference between NASDAQ’s ledger and blockchain’s ledger is that blockchain is distributed — it addresses the problem of lack of a trusted intermediary. And yet (for legal transactions) the company itself, its transfer agent of record, a clearinghouse, or an exchange are all trusted intermediaries and typically provide value-added services in addition. The reason NASDAQ is the right home for a blockchain-driven exchange is that they’re expert in the compliance and security aspects of trading stock. Cut out the middleman (here, NASDAQ itself) and the government and you’ll ultimately be limited to companies that choose to make an end-run around the legal, compliance, and tracking systems common to the mainstream market. As people who trade in unlisted stocks will tell you, that’s a recipe for getting your money stolen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*5l3iId_4U4kuqoTJMaFI7g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1140&quot; data-height=&quot;712&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*5l3iId_4U4kuqoTJMaFI7g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*5l3iId_4U4kuqoTJMaFI7g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Why you want to file securities paperwork when you issue securities
&lt;p name=&quot;c243&quot; id=&quot;c243&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;And we’re already seeing this. New companies have also begun creating blockchain-based “coins” convertible into company stock, and selling them to the public in Initial Coin Offerings, or ICOs, as a cheaper and more flexible way to raise money than a traditional Initial Public Offering of stocks on an exchange. It will be interesting to see how long this craze lasts — among other things, offering tokens convertible to stock counts as a securities offering, and so the SEC rules presumably apply to these securities offerings just like any other. Either the “coins” are just less-secure electronic stock certificates — protected by however carefully you store your password, rather than by the laws and protections of a securities exchange — or it’s another attempt to do an end-run around the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;2292&quot; id=&quot;2292&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Authenticity verification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dc02&quot; id=&quot;dc02&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Another plausible use of the blockchain is that if you want to make a public, unalterable, undeleteable signed statement, you can “publish” it to the block chain — thinking of the distributed ledger as more like a diary than a way to buy and sell. In theory you could use this for recording vote tallies, verifying the origin of diamonds or brand-name gear, verifying people’s identity, resolving the ownership of domain names, keeping items in escrow, disclosing provisional patents under seal, notarizing documents, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*LFPLgkmCA6GQHhI_UUsA4g.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3744&quot; data-height=&quot;2496&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*LFPLgkmCA6GQHhI_UUsA4g.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*LFPLgkmCA6GQHhI_UUsA4g.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
One vote per person. Bitcoin wallets are harder to count!
&lt;p name=&quot;7d62&quot; id=&quot;7d62&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Without diving too thoroughly into the details of each of these, it seems the use cases all fall apart pretty quickly. For voting, the status quo is recording the total number of ballots cast, with the voter dropping a visible paper ballot in a box, and journalists and observers from both sides watching the ballot boxes the whole time. The tough problem in voting is keeping who voted for who anonymous and yet making sure that voters and votes are one to one. Paper does this &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much better than blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8bc9&quot; id=&quot;8bc9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For a public notary or similar, verifying your driver’s license or having witnesses known to you present means that it wasn’t signed with a stolen password or private key — but, if a password or private key is adequate, you can just publish it signed with a PGP key. For establishing the authenticity of brand name goods like watches or handbags, or that a diamond was ethically mined, the ledger being distributed and encrypted doesn’t add any value — the originating company can just include a certificate you can verify online, just as they have done in the past. In cases of escrow, a smart contract can automatically pay for the goods without a need for a third party to verify and hold the funds, but you still need a trusted party to verify that the goods are delivered and as-promised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*_pNkxCQHJDHGZ5hOK3EjWQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;628&quot; data-height=&quot;354&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*_pNkxCQHJDHGZ5hOK3EjWQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*_pNkxCQHJDHGZ5hOK3EjWQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Proving you know something, in the modern world
&lt;p name=&quot;abc2&quot; id=&quot;abc2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;And finally, if you want to irrefutably prove that you knew X at time Y without disclosing the actual knowledge publicly, encrypt it and email it to yourself at both a gmail and a hotmail address or post it on bitbucket, or print it out and notarize it, or postmark it by mailing it to yourself, or tweet an md5 of it, or whatever. But then again, how large is the irrefutably-prove-you-knew-X-at-time-Y-without-disclosing-X industry? Can you think of any leading company, or any company at all, that provides this service?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;aed9&quot; id=&quot;aed9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For domain resolution — the process of figuring out whose servers get to see the traffic and respond to your requests when you type a URL into your address bar — it’s promising to imagine that an all-digital record of smart contracts, where the actual act of payment being published to the ledger also updates who the domain resolves to, obviating the need for domain escrow services. Yet in practice, as with the DAO or other smart contracts, if valuable domains change hands due to theft or security issues, you actually need a way to override the ledger — as the result of a court order, for example. Just like with government-backed, law-backed bank accounts, real companies won’t prefer a situation in which a security breach or stolen password could result in someone else permanently and irrevocably owning bankofamerica.com or disney.com or sony.com or whatever. Adopting block chain technology makes theft or impersonation more likely rather than less. It sounds hypothetical until you realize more leading bitcoin exchanges have been hacked than not — something that very rarely happens with the leading domain name providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;d2be&quot; id=&quot;d2be&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;So what’s left?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*AL237iO4mGeVBMTyCoO-zw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1490&quot; data-height=&quot;408&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*AL237iO4mGeVBMTyCoO-zw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*AL237iO4mGeVBMTyCoO-zw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Washing machines of the future will be able to order their own detergent
&lt;p name=&quot;26d6&quot; id=&quot;26d6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Each of these seems trivial — yes, everyone knows handbags already come with certificates of authenticity with an ID number you can look up online — except that in each case, millions if not tens of millions of dollars have been spent on entire companies dedicated to just that particular use case. And you can get even more esoteric — Second Life on the blockchain, or blockchain-enabled appliances so your washing machine can smart-contract for its own detergent, or a sports league where the coaching decisions are written on the blockchain. (For real!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;03cb&quot; id=&quot;03cb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In the end, the advantages of the existing human and software systems surrounding transactions — from verifying identity with a driver’s license to calling and clarifying the statements made in a credit disputed transaction to automatically billing your credit card for a newspaper subscription — outweigh the purported benefits, as well as hidden costs, of irrevocable, automated execution. Blockchain enthusiasts often act as if the hard part is getting money from A to B or keeping a record of what happened. In each case, moving money and recording the transaction is actually the cheap, easy, highly-automated part of a much more complex system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;cdf7&quot; id=&quot;cdf7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pullquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody went out and did a survey about whether most credit card users would be willing to give up their frequent flyer miles in return for also losing the ability to dispute a transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c7f6&quot; id=&quot;c7f6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote&quot;&gt;Which leaves us where we started — currency speculation and illegal transactions — along with perhaps a lesson. In conversations with bitcoin entrepreneurs and investors and consultants, there was often a lack of knowledge or even interest in how the jobs were being done today or what the value to the end user was. With all the money spent on bitcoin cash registers, nobody went out and did a survey about whether most credit card users would be willing to give up their frequent flyer miles in return for also losing the ability to dispute a transaction. Presumably, they thought, the reason IPOs are so expensive or venture fund formation paperwork is so onerous is because all those lawyers and accountants are just getting rich sitting around pushing paper… a bunch of smart engineers in their 20s with no industry experience could certainly do their jobs, automatically, in a matter of months, with just a few million bucks of venture capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;31e9&quot; id=&quot;31e9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So far, not so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*xyE_CNdoQMXrWSEU4TSdaw.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;480&quot; data-height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*xyE_CNdoQMXrWSEU4TSdaw.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Don’t smart contract me, bro!
&lt;p name=&quot;eef9&quot; id=&quot;eef9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure graf--trailing&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Kai Stinchcombe is CEO and cofounder of&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truelinkfinancial.com/card/true-link-card&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.truelinkfinancial.com/card/true-link-card&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;True Link Financial&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;, a banking and investment service for seniors. In his spare time he enjoys hoping that, post singularity, a detergent delivery drone doesn’t self-execute a smart contract on his life, bitbleaching him from the sky into a hissing pool of unstructured data in exchange for a handful of bitcoins.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 15:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<og:title>Ten years in, nobody has come up with a use for blockchain</og:title>
<og:url>https://hackernoon.com/ten-years-in-nobody-has-come-up-with-a-use-case-for-blockchain-ee98c180100</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*3aCwHQ0Z30QzArL8hLgQ4A.png</og:image>
<og:description>Everyone says the blockchain, the technology underpinning cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin, is going to change EVERYTHING. And yet, after…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackernoon.com/ten-years-in-nobody-has-come-up-with-a-use-case-for-blockchain-ee98c180100?gi=1b3ec1e8e1b</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How I went from programming to consulting (2012)</title>
<link>https://training.kalzumeus.com/newsletters/archive/consulting_1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://training.kalzumeus.com/newsletters/archive/consulting_1</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Clients Pay For Value, Not For Time&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I was a much-put-upon grunt programmer at a large Japanese megacorp. I go home every Christmas to Chicago, so I was going to be in Chicago during December 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an Internet buddy in Chicago named Thomas Ptacek. We met on Hacker News. He's the #1 poster by karma and I'm #2. Since we apparently share the same mental disease characterized by being totally unable to resist comment boxes, I decided to invite Thomas out to coffee. My agenda, such that it was, was to gossip about HN threads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas runs a very successful webapp security consultancy, Matasano. (Brief plug: they're hiring and if it weren't for this business thing I'd work there in a heartbeat: some of the smartest folks I know doing very, very interesting work which actually matters. If you can program they'll train you on the security stuff.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, after we got our coffee, Thomas invited me into their conference room. We talked shop for three hours: Thomas and his VP wanted to hear what I'd do to market their products and services offering. I had been writing about how I marketed Bingo Card Creator for a while, and started applying some of the lessons learned to their content creation strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The actual contents of the conversion are not 100% germane to the story, but I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kalzumeus.com/2009/12/31/engineering-your-way-to-marketing-success/&quot;&gt;blogged a bit about it&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=1024678&quot;&gt;Thomas posted his thoughts on HN&lt;/a&gt;. Long story short: programmers can do things which meaningfully affect marketing outcomes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the conversation, Thomas &lt;strong&gt;said something which, no exaggeration, changed my life&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas: Some food for thought: If this hadn't been a coffee date, but rather a consulting engagement, I'd be writing you a check right now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me: Three hours at $100 an hour or whatever an intermediate programmer is worth would only be $300. Why worry about that?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thomas: &lt;strong&gt;I got at least $15,000 of value out of this conversation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll notice that I immediately thought the proposed transaction was time-for-money, but Thomas (the savvy business owner) saw the same conversation as an exchange of business-results-for-money. He correctly anticipated that Matasano would be able to take that advice and turn it into a multiple of $15,000. (They did, within two weeks, but that isn't my story to tell.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is, far and away, the most important lesson to learn as a consultant.&lt;/strong&gt; People who are unsavvy about business, like me in 2009 or like most freelancers today, treat themselves like commodity providers of a well-understood service that is available in quantity and differentiated purely based on price. This is &lt;strong&gt;stunningly not the case for programming&lt;/strong&gt;, due to how competitive the market for talent is right now, and it is even more acutely untrue for folks who &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; program but instead choose to offer the much-more-lucrative service &quot;I solve business problems -- occasionally a computer is involved.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after this conversation, I stopped saying &quot;I don't think I could do that&quot; when companies asked me to work with them... and I also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kalzumeus.com/2011/10/28/dont-call-yourself-a-programmer/&quot;&gt;stopped calling myself a programmer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could literally talk for several hours on properly pricing consulting services. Erm, strike that, I literally have. Ramit Sethi and I talked about it for a few hours (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kalzumeus.com/2012/09/17/ramit-sethi-and-patrick-mckenzie-on-getting-your-first-consulting-client/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kalzumeus.com/2012/09/21/ramit-sethi-and-patrick-mckenzie-on-why-your-customers-would-be-happier-if-you-charged-more/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, with transcript). It was also the topic of a recent podcast episode with my cohost Keith Perhac and Brennan Dunn, again &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kalzumeus.com/2012/10/10/kalzumeus-podcast-3-growing-consulting-practices-with-brennan-dunn/&quot;&gt;available with transcript&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Read those.&lt;/strong&gt; People have told me that, in aggregate, they've made hundreds of thousands of dollars just by walking their rates up as a response to those interviews. (Brennan also writes a book about concrete strategies to do that. I bought a copy myself. It is &lt;a href=&quot;http://doubleyourfreelancingrate.com&quot;&gt;worth your time&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could tell you that after speaking to Thomas I had a sudden burst of enlightenment on this topic, but that would be a lie. When I started consulting several months later, I went straight back to $100 an hour &quot;to get my feet wet&quot;, but did learn one thing from the experience: I charged weekly rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Charging Weekly: It Makes Everything Automatically Better&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's the difference between $100 an hour and $4,000 a week? Aren't they mathematically equivalent? &lt;strong&gt;No. Weekly billing strictly dominates hourly billing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Weekly billing means you never waste time itemizing minute by minute invoices (&quot;37 minutes: call with Bob about the new login page&quot;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weekly billing means you have uninterrupted schedulable consulting availability in weekly blocks, and non-billable overhead like prospecting or contract negotiations happens between the blocks (when you weren't billable anyhow) rather than during the workday (when, as an hourly freelancer, you are in principle supposed to be billing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weekly billing makes it easy to align units of work to quantifiable business goals, where those goals dwarf the rate charged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weekly billing also does wonderful things for pricing negotiations... because &lt;strong&gt;you'll stop having them&lt;/strong&gt;. When I write a proposal for an engagement, I typically write a list of things we can do and my estimate for how many will fit into 1, 2, or 3 weeks. If clients don't have 3 weeks in the budget, we can compromise on scope rather than compromising on my rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you quote hourly rates rather than weekly rates, that encourages clients to see you as expensive and encourages them to take a whack at your hourly just to see if it sticks. Think of anything priced per hour. $100 an hour is more than that costs, right? So $100 per hour, even though it is not a market rate for e.g. intermediate Ruby on Rails programmers, suddenly sounds expensive. Your decisionmaker at the client probably does not make $100 an hour, and they know that. So they might say &quot;Well, the economy is not great right now, we really can't do more than $90.&quot; That isn't objectively true, the negotiator just wants to get a $10 win... and yet it costs you 10% of your income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you're charging weekly rates, the conversation goes something more like this: &quot;So you don't have $12,000 in the budget for 3 weeks? OK. What is the budget? $10,000? Alright, what do you want us to cut?&quot; You can then give the negotiator something to hang his cost-cutting hat on while still preserving your ability to charge your full rate in this engagement and all future engagements. (Word to the wise: no client, anywhere, likes giving up discounts after they've been given them. I have ridiculously successful client relationships where I, stupidly, cut them a discount years ago and I'm &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; paying for that decision.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I bet you're wondering how I got from $4,000 a week to $X0,000 a week. Sadly, no silver bullet: I just climbed a ladder of project importance, gradually (over ~20 engagements and ~2 years) accumulating wins and using each win to get me to the next rung of the ladder. Let's look at how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Clients: The Importance Of Social Proof&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my first consulting clients was Fog Creek Software. They got in touch with me after having read my blog and forum comments for a while. We've done the odd gig together over the years, beginning with a relaunch of their marketing site for FogBugz (writeup &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.fogcreek.com/our-marketing-is-up-fog-creek-and-what-we-did-about-it/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and continuing with a very fun project that will be written up on their blog Very Soon Now (TM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People occasionally tell me that my strategy is not replicable because I'm, air quotes, &quot;Internet famous.&quot; Back when Fog Creek got in touch with me, my blog had a few hundred readers on a very good day. I never demonstrated (and don't possess) untouchable genius unmatched by anyone before or since... I simply talked openly about things that worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;always ask to follow a successful consulting engagement with a case study&lt;/strong&gt;. My pitch is &quot;This is a mutual win: you get a bit more exposure and I get a feather in my cap, for landing the next client.&quot; Case studies of successful projects with some of my higher profile consulting clients (like e.g. Fog Creek) helped me to get other desirable consulting clients. &lt;strong&gt;Very few clients turn down free publicity&lt;/strong&gt;, particularly if you offer to do all the work in arranging it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can't get a public case study (do all the work for them and just ask for their approval -- this makes it very easy to say &quot;Yes, go for it.&quot;), there are intermediate options. One is to ask for them to just OK a one or two sentence testimonial about working together. &lt;strong&gt;Write this testimonial for them&lt;/strong&gt; and ask if they want to make any changes to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a bad testimonial: &quot;Patrick is smart. We enjoy working with him. -- A Client&quot; That testimonial does not resolve the #1 issue in your prospect's head: will this engagement make the business more than it costs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a much more persuasive testimonial:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick's advice on starting a drip campaign for WPEngine was an epic win for us -- it &lt;strong&gt;permanently moved the needle on signups&lt;/strong&gt; after just a week of work. And it's easy to measure and therefore to improve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;-- Jason Cohen, Founder &amp;amp; CEO, WPEngine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Permanently moving the needle on signups&quot; is one of the most persuasive things you could possibly offer a SaaS business. (It sure sounds better than &quot;He wrote 8 emails. They were good!&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That testimonial is in Jason's own words, but I hinted in the direction of what would be useful for him to say. (The main change he did was striking a number that I had suggested.) Notice that this testimonial, even with that edit, remains &lt;strong&gt;specific, focused on a business result, and highly credible&lt;/strong&gt;. In a discussion with a new prospect, their big worry is &quot;Can Patrick do something valuable for me?&quot; and &quot;If I have him do it, will it generate a wildly positive result for the business?&quot; Jason's testimonial assuages both worries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can't get either a writeup or a public testimonial, at least ask for a private reference. I have a few from companies which I can't publicly mention as clients. They sometimes help sway people who are on-the-fence about hiring me, particularly companies which are at the upper end of places where I could reasonably work. (I'm being oblique here. Sorry, nature of the business. I can reasonably work for Fog Creek / WPEngine, and in fact have. I couldn't reasonably be entrusted with strategic level projects at, say, Google. There exist a few order-of-magnitude jumps in between those two. Periodically, I try making one of those order-of-magnitude jumps. When I successfully manage one, I will -- naturally -- ask to do a public case study.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I occasionally joke that every time I get a new case study, my weekly rate gets another zero, but that is directionally accurate. My first rate was $4,000 a week. It is now several multiples of that, all justified by &quot;A client very similar to you paid my prevailing rate and had $THIS_FABULOUS_RESULT. If I could do that for you, what would it be worth?&quot;, with rates moving up every time I was comfortable doing so. (Both in terms of &quot;My pipeline is sufficiently stuffed such that losing engagements over price shock is not a problem&quot; and &quot;Even at 25% more than what I charge right now, I'm still confident customers will have a successful outcome from working with me.&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Scaling A Consulting Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't do consulting full-time because I enjoy running my own businesses more. That said, there are a couple of ways to take a consultancy and scale it. They're fascinating, since you can layer so many different business models onto the base money-for-time offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do well by your clients, you'll soon have too much work to handle. You've got two options at this point: raising your rates and turning away work in excess of your capacity to deliver, or raising your capacity, typically by hiring people. (Working more hours has serious scaling challenges... another reason to do weekly rates, by the way, as many folks working hourly succumb to the temptation to bill &quot;just another hour&quot; and end up with miserable work/life balance.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, you can either hire other people on a per-engagement basis (a freelancer managing freelancers, like my good buddy Keith Perhac) or you can have full-time employees who you charge out to customers, like Brennan Dunn's Rails consultancy. We talked in-depth about these models in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kalzumeus.com/2012/10/10/kalzumeus-podcast-3-growing-consulting-practices-with-brennan-dunn/&quot;&gt;our podcast recently&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big surprise to me, when I investigated this as an option, was that you have to &lt;strong&gt;be very careful to maintain your margins&lt;/strong&gt;. I once had the bright idea, back when I was charging $5k a week, to bring in someone at $4k a week and pay them $80 a hour. $800 a week for doing nothing, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That's a catastrophically bad idea.&lt;/strong&gt; In addition to having to cover your overhead, when you're sitting between a client and your employees' paychecks, you are absorbing significant risk of non-payment or delayed payment. Your payroll check needs to clear on Friday regardless of whether the customer has paid their invoice yet. There are occasionally &lt;em&gt;terrifying&lt;/em&gt; cash flow swings in the consulting business... heck, that is practically the definition of the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ooh, let's do story time. Earlier this year I got married. Weddings are expensive. You don't get any significant price break for buying two of them at once, which I did because my wife and I are from different countries and we wanted to include everybody. I recommend getting married, assuming you've found the right person, because how else are you going to have conversations like &quot;You should pay $500 for a single balloon&quot; and find yourself saying &quot;That sounds perfectly reasonable, but only if we could pop the balloon immediately on receiving it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One particular portion of the wedding cost $30k. I anticipated that $30k of receivables (work that had been done but hadn't been paid for yet) would turn into $30k of wire transfers prior to the wedding hall needing the money. They didn't. There was &lt;em&gt;nothing unusual at all&lt;/em&gt; with this state of affairs: collecting invoices is like trying to dance the samba while simultaneously juggling, and I missed a ball or two. I ended up putting that on a credit card for a few weeks while waiting for my business to sort things out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have two employees, you can easily have &lt;em&gt;a wedding worth of cash go out the door every two weeks&lt;/em&gt;. Accordingly, you need to be better at cash flow management than I was. One way to do it is by charging your employees out at a rate substantially higher than you pay them, and then using the difference to build a cash-flow cushion. (Brennan recommends having $30k around &lt;em&gt;per employee&lt;/em&gt; prior to scaling to your next hire. That strikes me as a great start.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concrete example:&lt;/strong&gt; If you charge someone out at $4k a week, you should reasonably think of paying them on the order of $60 an hour (if they're freelancers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things get even more difficult if you hire full-time.&lt;/strong&gt; You have to worry about maintaining utilization of your team -- i.e. always having work for them ready to go, because they get paid whether or not you've got them scheduled. In general, you should shoot for about 70% utilization, or them working 3 weeks a month. Let's say you hire an intermediate Rails developer at market rates: $8k per month. This costs you about $12k after you pay for taxes/health care/etc etc. (Employee benefits: welcome to being a business, please enjoy your stay.) You'll need to hire them out at in excess of $6k a week to accomplish that safely, at 70% utilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The economic returns to running a consultancy come largely from &quot;leverage&quot;: being able to bill out your employees, as opposed to walking up your own rates as the principal. (Many principals find that their take-home goes down after hiring employees, at least for a while, while they iron out the kinks of cash flow and pipeline management.) After you're at 3 employees, even at a fairly healthy rate for yourself, you're probably making half your money on your billings and half on the margin between what your employees cost and what you successfully bill them for. This scales right on up, with the additional wrinkle that as one has more employees one spends more time on non-billable overhead (prospecting, HR, business administration, yadda yadda) and less on what you got into the business to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A necessary collorary to this: the principals of a technical consultancy do &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; well for themselves. I don't know if that is a secret but it certainly isn't well appreciated: nobody says Occupy Boutique Rails Consultancies, but the principals of them do end up in the 1%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hybridizing Consultancies With Product Businesses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I've seen a few people run product businesses concurrently with consultancies. (And I do it myself.) Some of the models are very interesting, but they're not obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the most common one is using the consulting revenues to underwrite product development. For example, 37signals and Fog Creek both started as web development consultancies. There are quite a few products produced along the same model these days: the principals hire themselves out at generous rates, only take modest salaries, use the difference to hire programmers at market rates, and have the programmers build the product they wish to sell. This has a lot to recommend it over e.g. bootstrapping the product from nothing (everyone gets a paycheck every two weeks) or e.g. taking investment (it is hard to close $20k in angel investment but easy to close $20k in consulting contracts, and if the product takes off, you can stop consulting but you can't conveniently forget ever having been invested in). Consulting also helps develop generic business skills (which are very applicable to product businesses) and helps expose you to the problems of companies which pay money for solutions to problems, which makes customer development for your products much easier. (You can even share sales channels.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://training.kalzumeus.com/lifecycle-emails&quot;&gt;course on lifecycle emails&lt;/a&gt; which I made was a variant of this: it is a productized consulting offering. Basically, I took an engagement that I've delivered five times now and said &quot;How could I refactor this engagement such that I can deliver much of the value for near-zero marginal time investment?&quot; The answer was collecting my expertise and experience in a package that customers could use to self-direct themselves through implementing the advice. It seems to have worked out really well for many customers: instead of paying me $X0,000 for a week they can pay $500 to hear much of the same advice. It worked out very, very well for my business, too: I got approximately 1~2 weeks of consulting revenue without needing 1~2 weeks of on-site availability, and I now know that it will work if I want to repeat the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another popular offering for consulting firms is to offer training workshops. For example, if you are an expert in a particular field, many companies are willing to pay for you to train up internal experts at their company. You can either convince one client to pay for a 1-, 2-, or 3-day event, or sell tickets to one which you put on for yourself. Typical rates I see for internal training range from $5k to $15k &lt;em&gt;per day&lt;/em&gt; depending on what is taught and to whom. For public training, price points in the $500 to $1,500 a ticket range are common. Why is that a hybrid product offering as opposed to being straight consulting with a different charging model? After you have the curriculum/courseware for the engagement mapped out, you can then scale delivery of it almost arbitrarily: the cost of a trainer to deliver a day-long workshop in e.g. optimizing Postgres performance is much cheaper than someone who can actually optimize Postgres performance at an arbitrary company, and they're (relatively) common. You could take your single expert's knowledge and then package it up in several dozen workshops delivered in-person or online, with delivery performed by folks hired for the purpose. Amy Hoy and Thomas Fuchs used to run in-person and then online Javascript performance training workshops. It worked out very well but the rest of their businesses basically ate their availability. Sometimes billing $25,000 for a day just isn't worth the opportunity costs. #firstworldproblems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many consulting companies shut down their availability after successfully getting a product business going. That isn't a law of nature (Pivotal Labs' consulting arm survived Pivotal Tracker, for example), but after you've figured out scaling for a product business (highly non-trivial), they often scale so well that continuing with the consulting would be economically irrational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is This Interesting To You?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a bit off the beaten path for my writing, but a lot of you asked for it over email, and I seem to get strong responses when I post about it publicly. If you want to hear more like this, hit Reply and tell me what, specifically, you'd like to hear about. I tried to keep this fairly generic but if you want to hear a deep-dive into e.g. how to sell consulting clients on A/B testing or just want to hear what is in my bag-of-tricks I'm happy to oblige.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also look forward to doing some more writing about software in the near future. If you've got a particular topic you want covered, drop me an email. I read them all and respond to most. (n.b. A belated Happy Halloween. Sorry for the few months of dead air -- six weeks of international travel plus the busy season for my business coincided, and that cut down a bit on my available time to write these.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick McKenzie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. Quick plug: Brennan Dunn has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessoffreelancing.com&quot;&gt;podcast on consulting&lt;/a&gt;. They're at six episodes now and they're all fantastic and, moreover, actionable, like on how you can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://businessoffreelancing.com/episodes/005-content-marketing/&quot;&gt;content marketing as a lead generation tool&lt;/a&gt;. I'd definitely suggest listening to them at the gym or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 15:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>putnam</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://training.kalzumeus.com/newsletters/archive/consulting_1</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>