<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Europe says 737-Max won&amp;#039;t fly until it completes it own design review</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-07/europe-says-737-max-won-t-fly-until-its-design-review-complete</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-07/europe-says-737-max-won-t-fly-until-its-design-review-complete</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-07/europe-says-737-max-won-t-fly-until-its-design-review-complete&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-07/europe-says-737-max-won-t-fly-until-its-design-review-complete&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19979977&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19979977&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 211&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 194&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 11:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prmph</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=daf8be10-7caa-11e9-8d6b-dd6880022b8d&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wNS0wNy9ldXJvcGUtc2F5cy03MzctbWF4LXdvbi10LWZseS11bnRpbC1pdHMtZGVzaWduLXJldmlldy1jb21wbGV0ZQ==</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Go is Google’s language, not the community’s</title>
<link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/programming/GoIsGooglesLanguage</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/programming/GoIsGooglesLanguage</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Over on Twitter, I saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kapoorsunny/status/1130150301468700674&quot;&gt;the following question&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/golang/comments/bqiyyb/generics_in_go/&quot;&gt;via&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is lot of conversation around generics in #go, can't we have something like OpenGo, where community can implement generics , rather that waiting for official #go generics to happen ? Something like OpenJDK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many answers for why this won't happen, but one that does not usually get said out loud is that &lt;strong&gt;Go is Google's language, not the community's&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, there's a community that contributes things to Go, some of them important and valued things; you only have to look at the diversity of people in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/golang/go/blob/master/CONTRIBUTORS&quot;&gt;CONTRIBUTORS&lt;/a&gt; or see the variety of people appearing in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/golang/go/commits/master&quot;&gt;the commits&lt;/a&gt;. But Google is the gatekeeper for these community contributions; it alone decides what is and isn't accepted into Go. To the extent that there even is a community process for deciding what is accepted, there is an 800-pound gorilla in the room. Nothing is going to go into Go that Google objects to, and if Google decides that something needs to be in Go, it will happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The most clear and obvious illustration of this is what happened with Go modules, where one member of Google's Go core team discarded the entire system the outside Go community had been working on in favour of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.swtch.com/vgo&quot;&gt;relatively radically different model&lt;/a&gt;. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://peter.bourgon.org/blog/2018/07/27/a-response-about-dep-and-vgo.html&quot;&gt;eg&lt;/a&gt; for one version of this history.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or in short, Go has community contributions but it is not a community project. It is Google's project. This is an unarguable thing, whether you consider it to be good or bad, and it has effects that we need to accept. For example, if you want some significant thing to be accepted into Go, working to build consensus in the community is far less important than persuading the Go core team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(As a corollary, sinking a lot of time and effort into a community effort that doesn't have enthusiastic buy-in from the Go core team is probably a waste of time; at the most, your work might help the Go core team understand the issues better. Again, see Go modules for this in action.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, it's extremely clear that the community's voice doesn't matter very much for Go's development, and those of us working with Go outside Google's walls just have to live with that. If we're very lucky, our priorities match up with Google's; if we're reasonably lucky, the Go core team and Google will decide that they care enough about our priorities to work on them. The good news is that Google and the Go core team do care (so far) about Go being a success in the outside world, not just inside Google, so they're willing to work on pain points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(On the good and bad scale, there is a common feeling that Go has done well by having a small core team with good taste and a consistent vision for the language, a team that is not swayed by outside voices and is slow moving and biased to not making changes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I like Go and have for a fair while now, and I'm basically okay with how the language has been evolving and how the Go core team has managed it. I certainly think it's a good idea to take things like generics slowly. But at the same time, how things developed around Go modules has left a bad taste in my mouth and I now can't imagine becoming a Go contributor myself, even for small trivial changes (to put it one way, I have no interest in knowing that I'm always going to be a second class citizen). I'll file bug reports, but that's it. The whole situation leaves me with ambiguous feelings, so I usually ignore it completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(And claims by the Go team that they really care about the community and want them to be involved now sound laughable. I'm sure they care, but only up to a certain point. I think that the Go core team should be bluntly honest about the situation, rather than pretend and implicitly lead people on.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sidebar: Google and the Go core team&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could ask if Go is Google's language or the Go core team's language, since Go's direction is set and controlled by that small core team. However, at the moment I believe that most or all of the active Go core team is employed by Google, making the distinction impossibly to determine in practice (at least from outside Google). In practice we'll only get a chance to find out who Go really belongs to if Go core team members start leaving Google and try to remain active in determining Go's direction. If that works, especially if the majority of them no longer work for Google, then Go probably is their language, not Google's, in the same way that Python has always been Guido van Rossum's language regardless of who he worked for at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a practical level, it's undeniable that at the moment Google provides much of the infrastructure and resources to support Go, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/&quot;&gt;golang.org&lt;/a&gt;, and as a result owns the domain names and so on. Google also holds the trademarks on 'Go' as a programming language, per &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/permissions/trademark/trademark-list/&quot;&gt;their trademarks list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 05:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uggedal</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/programming/GoIsGooglesLanguage</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Revolution in Your Pocket</title>
<link>https://rbs.io/2019/05/a-revolution-in-your-pocket/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://rbs.io/2019/05/a-revolution-in-your-pocket/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;main-content-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet users have been trained over the past decade or so to believe the argument that the services we have grown to think of as “the internet” are expensive to run and that the only way to pay for those services is to let ourselves be tracked everywhere in the service of advertising. Our concepts of privacy, particularly when we talk about laws and regulations, are often presumed to take place solely within this frame. The platforms want us to be asking “how is all of this going to be paid for, if not advertising based on mining of personal information?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following that logic, however, leads to a thought-provoking conclusion: If this status quo value exchange is truly what the platforms are suggesting we should continue to engage in, its a horrendous deal for most of us! We are giving away all of own information–incredibly detailed portraits of ourselves, families, and friends that will be stored forever and used in ways we can’t imagine–in exchange for computing resources that can be had today for $35, and code with equivalents that are free and open source. Indeed, the argument about the value of these online services seems to be presuming the conclusion that services like these must be paid for to begin with. In reality, our future technology need not be owned by any one platform and doesn’t require anyone to pay for it. Why? Because we have all already spent the money (or other resources). We just don’t usually think of it as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many, if not most, of us already own a hand-sized computer with a persistent network connection that we take pretty much everywhere and which lives in our pockets or bags. The top of the line Android and Apple personal computing devices (honestly, does anyone use their “phone” primarily as a voice communication device anymore?) run at upwards of 2 Ghz, have around 4GB of RAM, and on-board storage ranging between 64 and 512 GB. If those numbers don’t mean much to you, they are roughly equivalent to a full laptop from 2010. All these devices are also capable of receiving and transmitting across a decently wide range of frequencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those frequencies are another resource that we already possess (at least, conceptually). The airwaves were long considered to be public property that Federal Communications Commission was responsible for parceling out because of the problems inherent in competing broadcasting signals. That viewpoint withered in the face of the deregulatory agenda of the Reagan years, but its recent revival can be seen in the use of explicitly unlicensed spectrum that makes technologies such as WiFi and Bluetooth possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using these existing resources and just a few others, we have the opportunity to reshape how we have been taught the internet is supposed to work: from a set of walled-off services belonging to massive companies with far-away data centers to a harmonized set of free tools speaking a common language, working together to enable all of us to make the most of every day, all from our own pockets. What might that look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is the potential today to reclaim control of our digital lives from monopolist platforms and unnecessary rent-seeking. There is a world within reach where always-on, always-connected pocket computers become personal data stores. All your photos, documents, messages, and other data live with you, not on a faceless server belonging to a random corporation. The only machine learning done is done for you. Data only leaves your device because you want to send it somewhere. Here’s what it might look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What we call a phone today will transition even further toward a general computing and communications device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our data will stay on our mobile computers and be backed up (encrypted of course) in the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will carry with us the fundamental representation of our identity, backed and verified by advanced encryption, instead of cumbersome passwords or logins associated with the same large platforms that control our social lives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing of data, either broadly with a large group or directly person to person, will happen directly between mobile computers, skipping the intermediaries like Facebook or Twitter we’re used to today&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where possible, that sharing will take place over pervasive locally formed networks, without needing the internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artificial assistance will be local first – for example, searches for the best nearby coffee shop will turn to the nearby network for responses before asking the entire planet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning will provide personalized intelligent assistance that runs on your own mobile computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shift I’m contemplating won’t be easy. Obstacles to making it happen are everywhere and powerful entities have a lot to lose if the status quo is upended. While much of the technology already exists, there are also large swaths that are still very much under construction, such as the details of &lt;a href=&quot;https://w3c-ccg.github.io/did-spec/&quot;&gt;decentralized identity&lt;/a&gt; and the need for exhaustive &lt;a href=&quot;https://simplysecure.org/blog/decentral-patterns-project&quot;&gt;user experience testing and user interface design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while 2018 and 2019 have seen a large growth in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2018/03/27/americans-complicated-feelings-about-social-media-in-an-era-of-privacy-concerns/&quot;&gt;the number of people who are aware of and find problematic the mass collection of personal data&lt;/a&gt;, it isn’t clear that a fundamental shift in how our computing infrastructure operates will catch on. There are powerful entities for whom the status quo makes a lot of money, and getting people to change their behaviors takes more than a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is plenty of work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;technical&quot;&gt;Technical&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical part of this vision focuses on the personal Mobile Computing Device (MCD). Instead of a large and heavy all-in-one device, we may carry smaller devices and use other input methods. A piece of jewelry could contain enough computing power for the job and a few different forms of interaction could make it accessible to us. Voice control through a Bluetooth headset, a UI projected onto a wall or desk, or augmented reality glasses, could all provide different methods of controlling and working with our personal computing device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MCD will also serve as our online presence. Social media, messaging, collaboration, gaming, and all sorts of other uses of data we haven’t thought of yet, will all be centered on your own mobile computer. Private messages will be delivered directly to others while social media with a broad audience can be reshared by followers in case an MCD goes offline for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the core of that presence will be our &lt;a href=&quot;https://identity.foundation/&quot;&gt;digital identity (DID)&lt;/a&gt;. The decentralized identity projects just growing out of the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) use peer to peer data structures to give each person a universally compatible proof of identity (or identities) that they control and which cannot be taken away. The DID represents a canonical statement of how to reach an entity, information about the entity that others have attested to (e.g. can drive a car, graduated from a university, is a citizen of a country), and where to access public encryption keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last five years have seen an explosion in research into and development of tools that will enable this decentralized vision. Mesh networking, Dat, IPFS, Secure Scuttlebutt, ActivityPub, and (yes) even some blockchain applications, have all been pushing forward the distributed tech state of the art. Simultaneously, the capabilities of smart phones have exploded, so much so that modern phones are shipping with artificial intelligence chips built in. Those chips mean that even more computation can happen on edge devices, rather than being farmed out to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The Future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still plenty of places where the technology needs to continue to evolve, however. For example, we have always viewed our phones as devices that only ever connect to servers, and never as servers themselves that should listen for connections. Changing that viewpoint is certainly possible, but there are technical blockers like Network Address Translation (NAT), as well as engineering preconceptions that need to be reexamined such as security threat models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fundamental technical expectation that will have to change surrounds how we construct our networks and route the traffic of the internet. Our networks today are arranged in a hub-and-spoke model, though it is a network with a huge number of hubs. In a world in which we share our data directly peer to peer, our networks need to look more like the mesh of a window screen than the spokes of a bike wheel. We need to take advantage of every slice of spectrum, and we need to work as a community to relay our neighbors’ traffic and even to store messages destined for other nodes until there exists a route to deliver them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a challenge that is technical and cultural at the same time. Almost all of the technologies that could make the distributed network vision possible are still in the early adopter phase. What is still needed is user experience and interface design to make them more accessible to people who are not yet as invested in the dream of a different network. One of the barriers to achieving the great user experience that the public needs is the fractured nature of the decentralized software community as it is today. Each of the projects out there solves its own particular problem in its own particular way, but there is clear lack of overarching solution aimed at consumers, with a user experience that abstracts away the gritty details while delivering the best of all of the projects it uses under the hood. Similarly, there is an important communication problem in how these projects are described to the public. Making the tech and its benefits accessible to every smartphone user out there must be a near term goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;political&quot;&gt;Political&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many decentralization advocates either ignore governments or purposefully reject the establishment of law and public policy as contrary to the spirit of the entire project. Whether or not that is the case, from a practical perspective governments exist and wield the power to hinder progress on decentralization if convinced to do so, or to help the vision move forward if we take the time to reach out and explain the technology and the opportunities. There are a variety of ways in which we can use laws and public policy to reach our goals, what follows is just a few of them. These suggestions focus mainly on the United States government and laws, because they are what I know best, but most can be adapted to other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ipv6&quot;&gt;IPv6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one overarching goal is to enable people with the power to collect and distribute their own data as they desire, having a device able to act as a server, either from home or even more ideally from mobile, will be an important capability. Servers on the internet have to be reachable by anywhere else on the network, a fundamental premise known as the “end-to-end principle.” That means they can’t be hidden behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_address_translation&quot;&gt;network address translation (NAT)&lt;/a&gt;–a technique that masks a bunch of devices, each with one of a number of “private” Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, behind one public IP. This technique has taken off in the past two decades or so because of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arin.net/vault/announcements/2015/20150924.html&quot;&gt;steady decline in the number of available IPv4 addresses&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the security benefits of hiding most people’s computers away from the global internet. Most homes only have one globally routable IP address, and there are a non-negligible number of broadband providers (particularly mobile providers and smaller ISPs with less access to IP addresses) that have implemented “carrier-grade NAT,” meaning that individual subscribers, and even entire families, may not have a single globally routable IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution here is, on the surface, a technical one. A newer version of the Internet Protocol called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv6&quot;&gt;IPv6&lt;/a&gt; (don’t ask what happened to IPv5) has been available for nearly two decades and vastly increases the number of available IP addresses. Implementation has been lethargic, however, because the broadband consumer market doesn’t understand the problem and doesn’t know what to ask for as the solution. Providers have therefore seen no incentive to invest in making the transition. We have to find another lever to use in order to encourage IPv6 deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One possibility that wouldn’t entail actually legislating the details of broadband deployment would see the Federal Communications Commission include the end-to-end principle in their official definition of “broadband.” This would give ISPs some incentive to roll out IPv6 and make other changes that would make running services from home or mobile more practicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;open-radio-spectrum&quot;&gt;Open Radio Spectrum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The existence of radio spectrum that can be used without a government license has an interesting history. Originally set aside in 1947 because microwave ovens created so much interference that it was undesirable for other radio purposes, the 2.4 GHz band, among others, was designated for industrial, scientific, and medical (ISM) machinery, and any other uses as long as those uses put up with the inevitable radio noise from nearby equipment. For a long time, these unlicensed bands were only sporadically used for communications–in the US, some of the Citizens’ Band frequencies are in ISM ranges. It is only in the last few decades that technologies such as WiFi and Bluetooth have developed along with methods such as error correction and frequency hopping that make it possible to avoid and compensate for the interference inherent in the spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of the massive success of the unlicensed bands for Bluetooth, WiFi, and other protocols, we should be making a concerted push for governments to set aside larger and more varied frequency bands for unlicensed use. Such a change would open up more opportunities for building robust mesh networks that allow people’s devices to relay communications for others and have their own traffic relayed in turn. It would also give devices the option of using different frequency bands for different purposes. Higher frequencies, such as the 2.4 and 5 Gigahertz that WiFi uses, can carry a lot of bandwidth but are limited to short distances and can’t penetrate solid walls very well. Lower frequencies, such as those used by FM radio, can carry great distances but aren’t capable of delivering nearly the same amount of data. Having available unlicensed spectrum across the various options could let software choose the most efficient means of reaching another device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the US, the Federal Communications Commission has the power to make some decisions about how spectrum is used, but much of the frequency assignment happens at the International Telecommunications Union–a UN treaty organization. Petitioning the FCC is worthwhile for freeing up spectrum in the near term, but a wholesale overhaul of global spectrum allocation (e.g. in order to allow for unlicensed use of all or most of the available frequencies) is stuck behind a slow moving and diverse bureaucracy. Change in this area will be slow and incremental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;education&quot;&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a host of other public policy levers that could be usefully leaned on to help build a decentralized future, from truly protective privacy legislation to wholesale attack on the economic theories underlying late-stage capitalism, particularly surveillance capitalism. At the end of the day, however, the tactic that will probably move the needle the most with policy-makers is simple education. To many people in government, technology is already something of a black box. Concepts such as peer to peer data sharing, mesh networking, or distributed computing are still likely to be greeted with blank stares or vague associations to copyright violations using BitTorrent or massive blockchain fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing that fact will take a lot of very basic engagement. Some of that will no doubt take the form of patient explanation of the technical underpinnings of MerkleDAGs or Distributed Hash Tables, but much of it will be about socializing the fact of alternatives: Alternatives to the image of consumption baked into the server/client metaphor; alternatives to the idea that privacy is something that is dead or not a concern; alternatives to the edifice of corporate capitalism that acknowledge the human drive to collaborate, cooperate, share, and help our neighbors. It would entail speaking up for the type of spirit that drives &lt;a href=&quot;https://enspiral.com&quot;&gt;worker-owned cooperatives&lt;/a&gt;, mesh networks &lt;a href=&quot;https://librerouter.org/what-the-project-is-about-2/&quot;&gt;providing internet access to off-the-grid villages&lt;/a&gt; from Argentina to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/av/world-africa-47723967/internet-access-in-africa-are-mesh-networks-the-future&quot;&gt;South Africa&lt;/a&gt;, and protocols aimed at creating &lt;a href=&quot;http://activitypub.rocks/&quot;&gt;social networks driven by community rather than rage-induced addiction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of advocacy is grueling and necessary. It also calls for a skill-set that doesn’t always (though by no means never) overlap with the ability to design eventually consistent distributed data structures. The vision I’ve just laid out needs buy in as much as it needs code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past few decades, the marriage of technical innovation and unharnessed capitalism has chugged confidently down the tracks, resulting in a handful of companies controlling how the whole world interacts and collecting personal information from people without their understanding. The last few years have seen a surge in alternative technologies and organizational models and the past 18 months have seen an explosion in popular skepticism toward the big platforms and their conduct. The time is ripe to bring together the amazing tools and technology of the decentralization movement with the usability and design that make Apple products so iconic. The public is ready for an alternative. At the same time, governments everywhere are starting to wake to the dangers to privacy and competition that the platforms represent and are ready to learn about something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iron is just getting hot. It’s time to strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 23:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Supermighty</dc:creator>
<og:description>Internet users have been trained over the past decade or so to believe the argument that the services we have grown to think of as “the internet” are expensive to run and that the only way to pay for those services is to let ourselves be tracked everywhere in the service of advertising. Our concepts of privacy, particularly when we talk about laws and regulations, are often presumed to take place solely within this frame.</og:description>
<og:type>blog</og:type>
<og:title>A Revolution In Your Pocket</og:title>
<og:url>/2019/05/a-revolution-in-your-pocket/</og:url>
<og:image>https://rbs.io/images/head-shot.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://rbs.io/2019/05/a-revolution-in-your-pocket/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Procrastination is not a time management problem, it is an emotion</title>
<link>https://cognitiontoday.com/2019/05/you-procrastinate-because-of-emotions-not-laziness-regulate-them-to-stop-procrastinating/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cognitiontoday.com/2019/05/you-procrastinate-because-of-emotions-not-laziness-regulate-them-to-stop-procrastinating/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There are two trains of thought – One leads to procrastination and one leads to motivation. And somewhere in between, there is a junction called anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s first look at the procrastination train of thought&lt;/strong&gt; (at least that’s going somewhere, amirite?). People often think procrastination is about time management, laziness, or a weak will but that is not the best way to understand procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to research, &lt;a href=&quot;http://eprints.whiterose.ac.uk/91793/1/Compass%20Paper%20revision%20FINAL.pdf&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;poor emotional regulation and a failure of self-regulation&lt;/a&gt; cause people to procrastinate. We procrastinate because some tasks put us in a lousy mood and we want to repair that mood to feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, time is not entirely irrelevant when it comes to procrastination. After all, there are deadlines. But, it really is more about emotion/mood repair mechanisms in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0092656606000833&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;context of time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; – specifically, the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not intuitive at first but to overcome procrastination, we need to address emotions and thoughts about the outcome of completing certain tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tweetshare-theme-10 tweetshare_tweetbox tweetshare-plugin&quot; data-value=&quot;4031&quot; data-value1=&quot;https://cognitiontoday.com/wp-admin/admin.php&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tweetshare-panels&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tweetshare-panels-body&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;get_text&quot; onclick=&quot;test()&quot;&gt;People procrastinate or avoid aversive tasks to improve their short-term mood at the cost of long-term goals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a &lt;s&gt;small&lt;/s&gt; moderately detailed detour. What does science really say about procrastination?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all practical purposes, we will define procrastination as the intentional and &lt;em&gt;voluntary delay of an intended activity even if the delay creates negative consequences&lt;/em&gt;. And, we will label the ‘stuff’ done while procrastinating as &lt;em&gt;aversion activities&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/em&gt; Procrastination can be a symptom in many psychological &amp;amp; neurological disorders. This post doesn’t look at the root cause of those disorders. For that, please consult a therapist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;ez-toc-container&quot; class=&quot;ez-toc-wrap-left counter-hierarchy&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ez-toc-title-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ez-toc-title&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;nav/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ez-toc-section&quot; id=&quot;Why_do_people_procrastinate&quot;&gt;Why do people procrastinate?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1041608016302187&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;In a 2016 paper&lt;/a&gt; published using the randomized control trial framework, researchers reported that the ability to deal with aversive emotions and modifying them reduced procrastination. The researchers extended their experiments to see if training people on emotional regulation reduced procrastination. Guess what?? It did!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But what exactly is emotional regulation?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://econtent.hogrefe.com/doi/full/10.1024/1661-4747.56.2.141&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Emotional regulation&lt;/a&gt; describes a person’s ability to effectively manage, control, and deal with emotions, emotional experiences, and emotional thoughts. There are multiple mechanisms people use in their daily life to regulate emotions: Taking breaks, sleeping, talking with friends, binge-watching, smoking, self-harm, picking fights, sarcasm, talking with others, etc. Some emotion regulation strategies are healthy (like taking breaks) and some are unhealthy (like picking fights).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code-block code-block-2&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-layout=&quot;in-article&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;fluid&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-3543566244103973&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;9507723509&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sake of generalization, you can extend this concept to include a broad range of cognitive strategies such as modifying, adapting, utilizing, controlling, and resolving emotions. We can broadly call this emotional self-regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://search.proquest.com/openview/7e3502c28fb06c9517ccbe6e08fd637e/1?pq-origsite=gscholar&amp;amp;cbl=1819046&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;A paper based on experience sampling&lt;/a&gt; of undergraduate students (analyzing thoughts, emotions, behaviors, etc. with qualitative data) revealed that students procrastinate stressful and unpleasant tasks. When procrastinating, they engage in more pleasant behaviors. One important thing to note here is that any task can be considered stressful and unpleasant based on a few personal factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic tasks can be stressful and unpleasant when a person is depressed or suffers from anxiety disorders. Low self-worth, low self-esteem, low confidence can mediate this and make virtually anything unpleasant. In fact, there are self-sabotaging behaviors which manifest as procrastination. For example, a person demonstrating low self-worth and a sense of deserving unpleasant feelings could delay work and sabotage it to prove that feeling correct. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.proquest.com/openview/2b0a5945bd9f95970fe3a7610cd088af/1?pq-origsite=gscholar&amp;amp;cbl=28723&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Research on the aspects of mental health&lt;/a&gt; such as depression, anxiety, and finer aspects like poor confidence in abilities, worrying, negative thinking, perfectionism, etc. predict procrastination like behaviors. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/03069885.2014.896454&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Some part of your procrastination&lt;/a&gt; may be due to mental health problems. &lt;em&gt;Please seek professional help if you feel like you are suffering from mental health issues.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mildly demanding tasks can become stressful if a person overthinks. One could overthink as a result of cognitive biases, obsessive and intrusive thoughts, anxiety, etc. and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cognitiontoday.com/2018/03/8-powerful-ways-to-overcome-thinking-errors-and-cognitive-biases/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;internal&quot; rel=&quot;follow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;overcoming thinking errors&lt;/a&gt; might help in having a clearer mental picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/buy/2000-14236-004&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Research shows&lt;/a&gt; that people, when upset, tend to act on existing impulses to make themselves feel better. However, when people believe that their bad mood is unchangeable, they do not engage in frivolous procrastination or acting on other impulses to engage in other activities (which lead to procrastination, at times). This may happen because believing that one’s mood is unchangeable has a hidden assumption: Nothing can be done to make it better. So why do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negative repetitive thoughts which are related to procrastination are often present in this complex cluster of perceived anxiety. They even have a special name – procrastinatory cognitions. These are direct destructive thoughts about procrastination and metacognitions such as worrying about procrastination itself. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Clarry_Lay/publication/272828242_Trait_Procrastinators_and_BehaviorTrait-Specific_Cognitions/links/54f0ab720cf2f9e34efd0b53/Trait-Procrastinators-and-Behavior-Trait-Specific-Cognitions.pdf&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Researchers have reported&lt;/a&gt; that procrastinatory cognitions are not compatible with healthy emotional self-regulation and mediate the link between procrastination and the &lt;em&gt;negative affect&lt;/em&gt; cluster: anxiety, stress &amp;amp; negative emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tweetshare-theme-10 tweetshare_tweetbox tweetshare-plugin&quot; data-value=&quot;4031&quot; data-value1=&quot;https://cognitiontoday.com/wp-admin/admin.php&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tweetshare-panels&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tweetshare-panels-body&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;get_text&quot; onclick=&quot;test()&quot;&gt;Procrastination is not a time management problem. It is an emotion regulation problem - we delay activities which might make us feel not-so-good.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ez-toc-section&quot; id=&quot;The_process_of_procrastination&quot;&gt;The process of procrastination&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a neat process which describes procrastination (and no, it’s not the oversold habit loop). It is based on what researchers call the &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/1464-0597.00021&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;CAPS construct&lt;/a&gt;. CAPS stands for Cognitive-Affective Personality System. Here is the model; it’s pretty self-explanatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-a6d53b1cb142ffef99dccf2e651c462b&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Model proposed by Wendelien Van Eerde, Eindhoven University of Technology&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAPS construct has 5 key factors which are involved in procrastination&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Encodings (cognitive representations of information)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competency &amp;amp; Self-regulation planning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals &amp;amp; Values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expectancies &amp;amp; Beliefs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affect (emotions, mood)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This process is quite holistic because it looks at a person’s traits, attitude, skill, personality, values, self-knowledge, environment, rewards, time pressure, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code-block code-block-5&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-layout=&quot;in-article&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;fluid&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-3543566244103973&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7363987611&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In short,&lt;/strong&gt; we often procrastinate because of perceived anxiety, stress, and poor emotional regulation about the completion of a task. If you are procrastinating reading study material, it’s probably related to some perceived anxiety based on the outcome of studying. Perhaps, if you start studying, you’ll realize you don’t know anything. Or maybe you’ll feel that you are not smart enough to even begin addressing the study material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perceived anxieties make us feel ‘not so good.’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feeling that you get about the outcome of doing a task is the core cause of procrastination. It could be a belief about yourself, it could be based on previous experiences, or it could be an amplified version of something small. You’d know best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the perceived anxiety/negative thought kills our buzz, we end up doing an aversion activity like going out with friends or watching YouTube or Netflix. &lt;strong&gt;The aversion activity is a mechanism to avoid or delay the anxiety and repair the short-term negative mood.&lt;/strong&gt; Think about it. Most of us end up doing something more pleasurable because the procrastinated task spoiled our mood in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, of course, is a very simplistic picture. Motivation complicates things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ez-toc-section&quot; id=&quot;The_opposing_force_of_motivation&quot;&gt;The opposing force of motivation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s now look at the motivation train of thought.&lt;/strong&gt; The fact that there are consequences for procrastinating is a source of anxiety and stress in itself. This could motivate you to not procrastinate in the first place. But that doesn’t always happen. The motivation could stay in the background or it could even push you toward your goal. However, the anxiety remains until it is dealt with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the anxiety builds up, it hits you in many forms: suddenly-one-night-I-got-the-mental-strength-to-get-up-and-do-it is one form in which it hits you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here is the thing, the brain CAN handle and maintain 2 conflicting thoughts and mental sets at the same. It’s called cognitive dissonance and research shows that the dissonance has broad applications for guiding behavior and gaining psychological comfort. Cognitive dissonance leads to psychological discomfort and that might amplify the double whammy… which… I will talk about in a few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0963721414566449&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Cognitive dissonance isn’t a sob story&lt;/a&gt;. It can facilitate effective behaviors and actions. Just to highlight the complex nature of motivation… The discomfort arising from dissonance might drive you to take some action because in most cases, the conflict needs to be resolved for you to feel better. While it might not be &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; obvious (I hope many disagree), feeling better is something humans like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/WhatsApp-Image-2019-05-03-at-16.47.56.jpeg?w=825&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;I am so stressed that relaxing makes me more stressed because I am not working on what's making me stressed&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-4035&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/WhatsApp-Image-2019-05-03-at-16.47.56.jpeg?w=640&amp;amp;ssl=1 640w, https://i2.wp.com/cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/WhatsApp-Image-2019-05-03-at-16.47.56.jpeg?resize=300%2C240&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember I said that there is a junction called anxiety? If you are at that junction, you’ll receive a double whammy attack from anxiety – one from your motivation, and one from your procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code-block code-block-5&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-layout=&quot;in-article&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;fluid&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-3543566244103973&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7363987611&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this junction, you can experience anxiety from both trains of thought and it bleeds into your mental space. This could get a lot worse because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3181635/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;anxiety is notorious as a bed-time feeder&lt;/a&gt;. To make matters even worse, if you have a habit of ruminating stressful thoughts about work, productivity, ambitions, etc. before bedtime, it could &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/15402002.2015.1083022&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;worsen your sleep&lt;/a&gt;. Night time negative repetitive thinking is a huge problem in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An idle mind before sleeping is a hotspot for this anxiety junction to get overwhelming. It kills your sleep, makes you tired, and gives you zero clarity on how to continue the journey toward successful procrastination or successful avoidance of procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait… did I say ‘toward successful procrastination’?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, because, we don’t often just procrastinate. The story would be simple if we just delayed tasks, the anxiety would be relatively less intense. We procrastinate &lt;strong&gt;and are conflicted&lt;/strong&gt; by the polar opposite drive to complete the procrastinated task – via intrinsic motivation, rewards, validation, acknowledgment, happiness, satisfaction, pride, honor, and glory. Chronic procrastinators know this all too well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tweetshare-theme-10 tweetshare_tweetbox tweetshare-plugin&quot; data-value=&quot;4031&quot; data-value1=&quot;https://cognitiontoday.com/wp-admin/admin.php&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tweetshare-panels&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tweetshare-panels-body&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;get_text&quot; onclick=&quot;test()&quot;&gt;Procrastination + Motivation = Conflict + Action&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do these insights tell us about overcoming or, at least, reducing procrastination? Can we really do anything about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there is good news. The research is vast and consistent enough to give us actionable tips to counter procrastination. Here are some solutions based on the recommendations proposed by researchers. I’ve repackaged some insights for practical use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ez-toc-section&quot; id=&quot;10_Scientific_solutions_for_overcoming_procrastination&quot;&gt;10 Scientific solutions for overcoming procrastination&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Address the perceived anxiety about the completion of a task. You know it’s there but it might not be in awareness. So you might have to dig and address your feelings first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. It might help if you can bring the avoided/procrastinated task closer to you and distance the aversion activities you are habituated with. You can do this by assigning more value/meaning to the avoided task and trivialize the aversion activity. If that’s not enough, modify your environment to have easier access to completing your tasks. For example, if you procrastinate paying bills in spite of having money, make sure you are logged into paying portals and the process of paying is easy. Behaviors like not remembering a password or account details are unnecessary hindrances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Before sleeping, relaxing (via stretching, yoga, breathing exercise, meditation, progressive muscle relaxation, etc.) can help your brain reboot. After rebooting, you can plan and strategize how you’ll go about the task the next morning. Once you have assured yourself that the anxiety was not needed and you gain the confidence in beginning the task (however, challenging), procrastination will stop destroying your sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code-block code-block-2&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-layout=&quot;in-article&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;fluid&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-3543566244103973&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;9507723509&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. If possible, walk yourself through the task and ready your mind. You can make a To-Do List, a roadmap, a Not-To-Do list, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Readying yourself to sleep properly is a separate but related activity you’ll need to employ. This must go hand in hand with addressing the perceived anxiety and gaining emotional clarity. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cognitiontoday.com/2018/07/7-effective-methods-to-fall-asleep-faster-and-improve-the-quality-of-sleep/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;internal&quot; rel=&quot;follow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;This might help you to sleep better&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Depending on the severity of your procrastination and anxiety, you might need to put in some additional effort to cultivate new habits. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cognitiontoday.com/2017/08/overcoming-procrastination-with-a-habit-changing-psychological-method/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;internal&quot; rel=&quot;follow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Here is a pro-productivity anti-procrastination habit routine&lt;/a&gt; you can use if you are a chronic procrastinator and want to cultivate new healthy habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7. Use the emotional self-regulation strategy recommended in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.springer.com/in/book/9781493910212&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Berking and Whitley’s book&lt;/a&gt; which verifiably decreases procrastination:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Choose the task you procrastinate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring aversive and negative emotions &amp;amp; thoughts associated with the task into awareness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instruct yourself to tolerate those negative emotions such as boredom, fear of failure, fear of judgment, feelings of incompetence, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address those emotions by regulating your emotions in a structured manner. Begin with allowing those emotions to exist. Do not suppress them. Then tell yourself that you are strong, tough, and resilient. Finally, ascribe more emotional meaning to the task and emotionally commit to that task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;8. Not exactly a solution to procrastination but, &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10942-012-0151-y&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;being mindful can do some damage control&lt;/a&gt; for regular procrastinators by improving their wellbeing and health. Mindfulness might help with emotional regulation or it might even reduce the impact of stress due to procrastination. Mindfulness. Mindfulness, in its many forms, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3480633/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;promotes self-regulation&lt;/a&gt; via cognitive, behavioral, and emotional pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9. Forgive yourself for the times you’ve procrastinated a specific task in the past and suffered through guilt, stress, and anxiety. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886910000474&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;According to a paper&lt;/a&gt; which gives us this incredibly easy strategy, self-forgiveness reduces negative emotions about oneself, and &lt;em&gt;that reduces the likelihood&lt;/em&gt; of procrastinating the same activity again. So if you procrastinate a medical appointment once, forgive yourself for delaying it. The second time might not occur. Self-forgiveness can also be expanded into self-compassion which helps with self-regulation by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/15298868.2011.558404&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;countering the depletion of mental resources&lt;/a&gt; to cope with stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10. Use the popular PoMoDoRo technique to gain control over your tasks and relieve the pressure from some associated anxiety. The PoMoDoRo technique is a structured time management technique which allows users to break tasks into 20-25 minute chunks. This changes the concept of time from ‘how much time is needed’ to ‘what I can accomplish in 20 minutes’. This cognitive change facilitates control and possibly, increases motivation. Although popular, not much research has gone into exploring the effectiveness of this technique on stopping procrastination. However, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.bham.ac.uk/~rjh/courses/ResearchTopicsInHCI/2015-16/Submissions/fengjia.pdf&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;preliminary report&lt;/a&gt; shows that there is some value in using it. Follow the next steps to implement the PoMoDoRo technique:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pick a timer (or an app), Set it to 20 or 25 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend 20-25 minutes on a task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the timer rings, stop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a break of 5 minutes (cycle 1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return to another 20-25 minutes on a series of tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a break of 5 minutes (cycle 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After 4 cycles, take a longer break&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/59425521_2423761121179004_6378903020205244416_n.jpg?w=825&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;How to not procrastinate&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-4036&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/59425521_2423761121179004_6378903020205244416_n.jpg?w=750&amp;amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i0.wp.com/cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/59425521_2423761121179004_6378903020205244416_n.jpg?resize=600%2C600&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i0.wp.com/cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/59425521_2423761121179004_6378903020205244416_n.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/59425521_2423761121179004_6378903020205244416_n.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;amp;ssl=1 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baby steps, right? Hope these insights help you reduce procrastination, procrastinatory cognitions, gain emotional clarity, and learn a ridiculously valuable life skill called emotion regulation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. I like writing ‘PoMoDoRo’ with the capitalized consonants. It doesn’t have to be written that way, it’s just fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.P.S. There are many ways in which procrastination sustains itself as a habit. For example, feeling the success of completing a task, in spite of putting it off until the 11th hour, can be interpreted as a reward. You could get conditioned to this reward and feel nothing was lost to procrastination. Or, the satisfaction of completion is overwhelming and you like it. These feelings can have a strong biological component via classical and operant conditioning. The brain may associate the increasing tension of procrastination with success, if you are successful. That association underlies a habit or a rigid tendency.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;code-block code-block-6&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;autorelaxed&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-3543566244103973&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;1603512519&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 22:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>whack</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>You Procrastinate Because Of Emotions, Not Laziness. Regulate Them To Stop Procrastinating! | Cognition Today</og:title>
<og:description>We procrastinate because of poor emotion regulation. Instead of addressing the anxiety associated with completing the task and then doing it, we engage in pleasurable tasks to delay the anxiety. This piles up when motivation kicks in and conflicts us. Here are scientific solutions to overcome procrastination.</og:description>
<og:url>https://cognitiontoday.com/2019/05/you-procrastinate-because-of-emotions-not-laziness-regulate-them-to-stop-procrastinating/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i2.wp.com/cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/WhatsApp-Image-2019-05-03-at-16.47.56.jpeg?fit=640%2C512&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cognitiontoday.com/2019/05/you-procrastinate-because-of-emotions-not-laziness-regulate-them-to-stop-procrastinating/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Notifying administrators about unhashed password storage</title>
<link>https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/g-suite/notifying-administrators-about-unhashed-password-storage</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/g-suite/notifying-administrators-about-unhashed-password-storage</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Google’s policy is to store your passwords with cryptographic hashes that mask those passwords to ensure their security. However, we recently notified a subset of our enterprise G Suite customers that some passwords were stored in our encrypted internal systems unhashed. This is a G Suite issue that affects business users only–no free consumer Google accounts were affected–and we are working with enterprise administrators to ensure that their users reset their passwords. We have been conducting a thorough investigation and have seen no evidence of improper access to or misuse of the affected G Suite credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Google Stores Passwords for Consumers &amp;amp; G Suite Enterprise Customers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;If you have a Google account, Google’s core sign-in system is designed not to know your password. How, then, can we verify your password when you sign in to your Google account again? The answer lies in a bit of cryptography: when you set your password, instead of remembering the exact characters of the password, we scramble it with a “hash function”, so it becomes something like “72i32hedgqw23328”, and that’s what we store with your username. Both are then also encrypted before being saved to disk. The next time you try to sign in, we again scramble your password the same way. If it matches the stored string then you must have typed the correct password, so your sign-in can proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effectiveness of the hash function lies in its one-way nature: it is simple to scramble your password, but nearly impossible to unscramble it. So, if someone should obtain the scrambled password, they won’t be able to recover your real password. The downside of password hashing is that if you forget your password, we cannot show you what it was; there’s nothing we can do other than reset it to a temporary password (valid one time only) and then require you to pick a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G Suite enterprise accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In our enterprise product, G Suite, we had previously provided domain administrators with tools to set and recover passwords because that was a common feature request. The tool (located in the admin console) allowed administrators to upload or manually set user passwords for their company’s users. The intent was to help them with onboarding new users; e.g., a new employee could receive their account information on their first day of work, and for account recovery. The functionality to recover passwords this way no longer exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The issues discovered with G Suite enterprise accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We made an error when implementing this functionality back in 2005: The admin console stored a copy of the unhashed password. This practice did not live up to our standards. To be clear, these passwords remained in our secure encrypted infrastructure. This issue has been fixed and we have seen no evidence of improper access to or misuse of the affected passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, as we were troubleshooting new G Suite customer sign-up flows, we discovered that starting in January 2019 we had inadvertently stored a subset of unhashed passwords in our secure encrypted infrastructure. These passwords were stored for a maximum of 14 days. This issue has been fixed and, again, we have seen no evidence of improper access to or misuse of the affected passwords. We will continue with our security audits to ensure this is an isolated incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has my company been impacted?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We recently notified G Suite administrators to change those impacted passwords. Out of an abundance of caution, we will reset accounts that have not done so themselves. Our authentication systems operate with many layers of defense beyond the password, and we deploy numerous &lt;a href=&quot;https://security.googleblog.com/2019/05/new-research-how-effective-is-basic.html&quot;&gt;automatic systems&lt;/a&gt; that block malicious sign-in attempts even when the attacker knows the password. In addition, we provide G Suite administrators with numerous &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com/2step&quot;&gt;2-step verification (2SV) options&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/security-key/&quot;&gt;Security Keys&lt;/a&gt;, which Google relies upon for its own employee accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We take the security of our enterprise customers extremely seriously, and pride ourselves in advancing the industry’s best practices for account security. Here we did not live up to our own standards, nor those of our customers. We apologize to our users and will do better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 22:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Notifying Administrators About Unhashed Password Storage | Google Cloud Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Google’s policy is to store your passwords with cryptographic hashes that mask those passwords to ensure their security. However, we recently notified a su</og:description>
<og:image>https://cloud.google.com/blog/static/assets/GCP_Twitter_Card-2000×1000.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/g-suite/notifying-administrators-about-unhashed-password-storage/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/g-suite/notifying-administrators-about-unhashed-password-storage</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple introduces 8-core MacBook Pro</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/05/apple-introduces-first-8-core-macbook-pro-the-fastest-mac-notebook-ever/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/05/apple-introduces-first-8-core-macbook-pro-the-fastest-mac-notebook-ever/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Apple updated MacBook Pro with faster 8th- and 9th-generation Intel Core processors, bringing eight cores to MacBook Pro for the first time. MacBook Pro now delivers two times faster performance than a quad-core MacBook Pro and 40 percent more performance than a 6-core MacBook Pro, making it the fastest Mac notebook ever.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; These new processors, combined with powerful graphics, the brilliant and colorful Retina display, super-fast SSDs, the Apple T2 Security Chip, all-day battery life and macOS, make MacBook Pro the world’s best pro notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Whether it’s college students mastering a course of study, developers building world-class apps or video editors creating feature films, we’re constantly amazed at what our customers do with their MacBook Pro,” said Tom Boger, Apple’s senior director of Mac Product Marketing. “Now with 8-core processors for an incredible performance boost, along with its stunning Retina display, fast storage, all-day battery life and running macOS, MacBook Pro continues to be the world’s best pro notebook and we can’t wait to get it into our customer’s hands to see what they do next.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>css</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Apple introduces first 8-core MacBook Pro, the fastest Mac notebook ever</og:title>
<og:description>Apple updated MacBook Pro with faster 8th- and 9th-generation Intel Core processors, bringing eight cores to MacBook Pro for the first time.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/05/apple-introduces-first-8-core-macbook-pro-the-fastest-mac-notebook-ever/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/mac/standard/apple_macbookpro-8-core_video-editing_05212019_LP_hero.jpg.og.jpg?201905212030</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/05/apple-introduces-first-8-core-macbook-pro-the-fastest-mac-notebook-ever/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Most Expensive Lesson of My Life: Details of SIM Port Hack</title>
<link>https://medium.com/coinmonks/the-most-expensive-lesson-of-my-life-details-of-sim-port-hack-35de11517124</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/coinmonks/the-most-expensive-lesson-of-my-life-details-of-sim-port-hack-35de11517124</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;25.732209737828&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;uiScale uiScale-ui--regular uiScale-caption--regular u-flexCenter u-marginVertical24 u-fontSize15 js-postMetaLockup&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-flex0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link u-baseColor--link avatar&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cooncesean?source=post_header_lockup&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-source=&quot;post_header_lockup&quot; data-action-value=&quot;291948cd8e98&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; data-user-id=&quot;291948cd8e98&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/100/100/1*BvSyyQiddVCLGYwlKjo-fw.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;avatar-image u-size50x50&quot; alt=&quot;Go to the profile of Sean Coonce&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3e82&quot; id=&quot;3e82&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;I lost north of $100,000 last Wednesday. It evaporated over a 24-hour time span in a “SIM port attack” that drained my Coinbase account. It has been four days since the incident and I’m gutted. I have zero appetite; my sleep is restless; I am awash in feelings of anxiety, remorse, and embarrassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a52e&quot; id=&quot;a52e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This was the single most expensive lesson of my life and I want to share my experience + lessons learned with as many people as possible. My goal is to increase awareness about these types of attacks and to motivate &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; to increase the security of your online identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5031&quot; id=&quot;5031&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;This is still very raw (I haven’t even told my family yet); please reserve judgement with regards to the naive security practices laid out in this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;9939&quot; id=&quot;9939&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Details Of The Attack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f613&quot; id=&quot;f613&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;You might be asking yourself, what exactly is a “SIM port attack”? In order to describe the attack, let’s examine a typical online identity. The diagram below should look familiar to most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*ZPjYgJc8Z2DXsXE8_bgZgA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1500&quot; data-height=&quot;903&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*ZPjYgJc8Z2DXsXE8_bgZgA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2400/1*ZPjYgJc8Z2DXsXE8_bgZgA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Most of us have a primary email account that is connected to A LOT of other online accounts. Most of us also have a mobile device that can be used to recover your email password should you ever forget it.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;0813&quot; id=&quot;0813&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Authorized SIM Porting&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1ed3&quot; id=&quot;1ed3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;The ability to port your SIM card to another device is a service that mobile carriers provide to their customers. It allows a customer to request their phone number be transferred to a new device. In most cases, this is a perfectly legitimate request; this happens when we upgrade to a new phone, switch mobile carriers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;aa89&quot; id=&quot;aa89&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;A SIM Port Attack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6f4f&quot; id=&quot;6f4f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;A “SIM port attack”, however, is a malicious port performed by an unauthorized source — the attacker. The attacker ports &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; SIM card to a phone that &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; control. The attacker then initiates the password reset flow on your email account. A verification code is sent from your email provider to your phone number — which is intercepted by the attacker, as they now control your SIM card. The diagram below outlines the attack step by step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*-0AtUPyi3NS0EE7DGD-lzA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1500&quot; data-height=&quot;1250&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*-0AtUPyi3NS0EE7DGD-lzA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2400/1*-0AtUPyi3NS0EE7DGD-lzA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;29.930265995687&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3aa9&quot; id=&quot;3aa9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Once the attacker controls your primary email account, they begin to move laterally across any lucrative online services that you manage via that email address (bank accounts, social media accounts, etc.). If they’re terribly malicious, they can even lock &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; out of your own accounts with little recourse to reclaim them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4084&quot; id=&quot;4084&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Take a moment to consider the sheer volume of sensitive information tied to a single Google Account:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;6332&quot; id=&quot;6332&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Your address, date of birth, and other private, personally identifiable information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;a1cb&quot; id=&quot;a1cb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Access to potentially compromising photos of you (and/or your partner)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;518c&quot; id=&quot;518c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Access to your calendar and upcoming travel dates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;16a3&quot; id=&quot;16a3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Access to your private emails, documents, and search history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;7817&quot; id=&quot;7817&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Access to your personal contacts and &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--li-em&quot;&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; private information as well as relation to you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;a7d6&quot; id=&quot;a7d6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Access to all other online services for which your primary email address was used as the authentication source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 name=&quot;96b2&quot; id=&quot;96b2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Timeline of Events&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;63bc&quot; id=&quot;63bc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;With a better grasp on how such an attack is carried out and the scope of what’s at stake, let’s dive into the timeline of &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; specific attack. I want to paint a picture of how the attack was executed, how I experienced these events, and what &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; can do differently to protect yourself should you experience similar symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d303&quot; id=&quot;d303&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The timeline is broken out into four sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;5238&quot; id=&quot;5238&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;What I experienced:&lt;/strong&gt; The events as experienced from my point of view — if you encounter something similar, these are clear indicators that you are likely under attack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;b5a3&quot; id=&quot;b5a3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;What the attacker was doing:&lt;/strong&gt; The underlying tactics that the hacker used to work their way into my Coinbase account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;68e5&quot; id=&quot;68e5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;My perceived threat level:&lt;/strong&gt; The threat level I attributed to these events as they were happening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;f802&quot; id=&quot;f802&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;The threat level I should have had:&lt;/strong&gt; In hindsight, the threat level I wish I would have had as these events unfolded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*4E53hNpw2fH6Z1KstNR1GQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1250&quot; data-height=&quot;4806&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*4E53hNpw2fH6Z1KstNR1GQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*4E53hNpw2fH6Z1KstNR1GQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;a4cf&quot; id=&quot;a4cf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Lessons Learned + Recommendations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;301e&quot; id=&quot;301e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;This was the single most expensive lesson of my life. I lost a meaningful percentage of net worth in a 24 hour period; irreversibly. Below are a few pieces of advice I would encourage others use to better protect themselves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;0ff4&quot; id=&quot;0ff4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Use A Hardware Wallet To Secure Your Crypto:&lt;/strong&gt; Move your crypto to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ledger.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.ledger.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hardware wallet&lt;/a&gt;/offline storage/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitgo.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.bitgo.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;multi-sig wallet&lt;/a&gt; whenever you are &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; transacting. Do not leave funds idle on exchanges or fiat on-ramps. I treated Coinbase like a bank account and you have absolutely zero recourse in the case of an attack. I knew the risks better than most, but never thought something like this could happen to me. &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--li-em&quot;&gt;I intensely regret not taking stronger security measures with my crypto.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;a8d5&quot; id=&quot;a8d5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;SMS Based 2FA Is Not Enough:&lt;/strong&gt; Regardless of the assets and/or identities you are trying to protect online, upgrade to hardware based security (ie: something physical that an attacker would have to physically obtain in order to perform an attack). While &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.authenticator2&amp;amp;hl=en_US&quot; data-href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.authenticator2&amp;amp;hl=en_US&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Authenticator&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://authy.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://authy.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Authy&lt;/a&gt; can turn your mobile device into a piece of hardware based security, I would advise going a step further. Pick up a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YubiKey&lt;/a&gt; that you physically control and cannot be spoofed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;dcfd&quot; id=&quot;dcfd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Reduce Your Online Footprint:&lt;/strong&gt; Reduce the urge to needlessly share personally identifiable information (birthdate, location, pictures with geolocation data embedded in them, etc.) online. All of that quasi publicly available data can be turned against you in the event of an attack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;cc7b&quot; id=&quot;cc7b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Google Voice 2FA:&lt;/strong&gt; In some cases, an online service will not support hardware-based 2FA (they rely on weaker SMS based 2FA). In these cases, you might be better off creating a &lt;a href=&quot;https://voice.google.com/u/0/about&quot; data-href=&quot;https://voice.google.com/u/0/about&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Voice&lt;/a&gt; phone number (which cannot be SIM ported) and using that has your 2-Factor Auth recovery number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;e40e&quot; id=&quot;e40e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Create a Secondary Email Address:&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of binding everything to a single email address, create a secondary address for your critical online identities (bank accounts, social media accounts, crypto exchanges, etc.). Do not use this email address for anything else and keep it private. Back up that address with some form of hardware-based 2FA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;7bc6&quot; id=&quot;7bc6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li graf--trailing&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Offline Password Manager:&lt;/strong&gt; Use a password manager for your passwords. Even better, use an offline password manager like Password Store. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lrvick/security-token-docs/blob/master/Use_Cases/Password_Mangement.md&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/lrvick/security-token-docs/blob/master/Use_Cases/Password_Mangement.md&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lrvick has an excellent comparison chart of various password managers&lt;/a&gt; as well as a vetted recommendation for the more technically inclined.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 16:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Reedx</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Most Expensive Lesson Of My Life: Details of SIM port hack</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/coinmonks/the-most-expensive-lesson-of-my-life-details-of-sim-port-hack-35de11517124</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*ZPjYgJc8Z2DXsXE8_bgZgA.png</og:image>
<og:description>I lost north of $100,000 last Wednesday. It evaporated over a 24 hour timespan in a “SIM port attack” that drained my Coinbase account.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/coinmonks/the-most-expensive-lesson-of-my-life-details-of-sim-port-hack-35de11517124</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Technical Debt</title>
<link>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebt.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebt.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;tags&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/tags/technical%20debt.html&quot;&gt;technical debt&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/tags/clean%20code.html&quot;&gt;clean code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tagLabel&quot;&gt;tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software systems are prone to the build up of &lt;strong&gt;cruft&lt;/strong&gt; - deficiencies in internal quality that make it harder than it would ideally be to modify and extend the system further. Technical Debt is a metaphor, coined by Ward Cunningham, that frames how to think about dealing with this cruft, thinking of it like a financial debt. The extra effort that it takes to add new features is the interest paid on the debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fullPhoto&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/images/tech-debt/sketch.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine I have a confusing module structure in my code base. I need to add a new feature. If the module structure was clear, then it would take me four days to add the feature but with this cruft, it takes me six days. The two day difference is the interest on the debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What most appeals to me about the debt metaphor is how it frames how I think about how to deal with this cruft. I could take five days to clean up the modular structure, removing that cruft, metaphorically paying off the principal. If I only do it for this one feature, that's no gain, as I'd take nine days instead of six. But if I have two more similar features coming up, then I'll end up faster by removing the cruft first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stated like that, this sounds like a simple matter of working the numbers, and any manager with a spreadsheet should figure out the choices. Sadly since we &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/CannotMeasureProductivity.html&quot;&gt;CannotMeasureProductivity&lt;/a&gt;, none of these costs are objectively measurable. We can &lt;em&gt;estimate&lt;/em&gt; how long it takes to do a feature, &lt;em&gt;estimate&lt;/em&gt; what it might be like if the cruft was removed, and &lt;em&gt;estimate&lt;/em&gt; the cost of removing the cruft. But our accuracy of such estimates is pretty low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this, usually the best route is to do what we usually do with financial debts, pay the principal off gradually. On the first feature I'll spend an extra couple of days to remove some of the cruft. That may be enough to reduce the interest rate on future enhancements to a single day. That's still going to take extra time, but by removing the cruft I'm making it cheaper for future changes to this code. The great benefit of gradual improvement like this is that it naturally means we spend more time on removing cruft in those areas that we modify frequently, which are exactly those areas of the code base where we most need the cruft to be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking of this as paying interest versus paying of principal can help decide which cruft to tackle. If I have a terrible area of the code base, one that's a nightmare to change, it's not a problem if I don't have to modify it. I only trigger an interest payment when I have to work with that part of the software (this is a place where the metaphor breaks down, since financial interest payments are triggered by the passage of time). So crufty but stable areas of code can be left alone. In contrast, areas of high activity need a zero-tolerance attitude to cruft, because the interest payments are cripplingly high. This is especially important since cruft accumulates where developers make changes without paying attention to internal quality - the more changes, the greater risk of cruft building up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metaphor of debt is sometimes used to justify neglecting internal quality. The argument is that it takes time and effort to stop cruft from building up. If there new features that are needed urgently, then perhaps it's best to take on the debt, accepting that this debt will have to be managed in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The danger here is that most of the time this analysis isn't done well. Cruft has a quick impact, slowing down the very new features that are needed quickly. Teams who do this end up maxing out all their credit cards, but still delivering later than they would have done had they put the effort into higher internal quality. Here the metaphor often leads people astray, as the dynamics don't really match those for financial loans. Taking on debt to speed delivery only works if you stay below the design payoff line of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/DesignStaminaHypothesis.html&quot;&gt;DesignStaminaHypothesis&lt;/a&gt;, and teams hit that line in weeks rather than months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are regular debates whether different kinds of cruft should be considered as debt or not. I found it useful to think about whether the debt is acquired deliberately and whether it is prudent or reckless - leading me to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebtQuadrant.html&quot;&gt;TechnicalDebtQuadrant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;furtherReading&quot; readability=&quot;35.544609665428&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, Ward first introduced this concept in an experience report for &lt;a href=&quot;http://c2.com/doc/oopsla92.html&quot;&gt;OOPSLA 1992&lt;/a&gt;. It has also been discussed on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.c2.com/cgi/wiki?ComplexityAsDebt&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ward Cunningham has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pqeJFYwnkjE&quot;&gt;video talk&lt;/a&gt; where he discusses this metaphor he created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave Nicolette expands on Ward's view of technical debt with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://neopragma.com/index.php/2019/03/30/technical-debt-the-man-the-metaphor-the-message/&quot;&gt;fine case study&lt;/a&gt; of what I refer to as &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebtQuadrant.html&quot;&gt;Prudent Intentional debt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of readers sent in some similarly good names. David Panariti refers to ugly programming as &lt;strong&gt;deficit programming&lt;/strong&gt;. Apparently he originally started using a few years ago when it fitted in with government policy; I suppose it's natural again now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Wood suggested &quot;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Inflation&lt;/strong&gt; could be viewed as the ground lost when the current level of technology surpasses that of the foundation of your product to the extent that it begins losing compatibility with the industry. Examples of this would be falling behind in versions of a language to the point where your code is no longer compatible with main stream compilers.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.construx.com/10x_Software_Development/Technical_Debt/&quot;&gt;Steve McConnell&lt;/a&gt; brings out several good points in the metaphor, particularly how keeping your unintended debt down gives you more room to intentionally take on debt when it's useful to do so. I also like his notion of minimum payments (which are very high to fix issues with embedded systems as opposed to web sites).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaron Erickson talks about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=1401640&quot;&gt;Enron financing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.crisp.se/2013/10/11/henrikkniberg/good-and-bad-technical-debt&quot;&gt;Henrik Kniberg argues&lt;/a&gt; that it's older technical debt that causes the greatest problem and that it's wise to a qualitative debt ceiling to help manage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Dietrich discusses the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daedtech.com/human-cost-tech-debt/&quot;&gt;human cost of technical debt&lt;/a&gt;: team infighting, atrophied skills, and attrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;revisions&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Revisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally published this post on October 1 2003. I gave it a thorough rewrite in April 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BerislavLopac</dc:creator>
<og:title>bliki: TechnicalDebt</og:title>
<og:url>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebt.html</og:url>
<og:description>Technical Debt is a metaphor for the consequences of cruft. You either have to accept a drag on further features (paying interest) or fix the software (paying the principal)</og:description>
<og:image>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/images/tech-debt/sketch.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebt.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bullshit I had to go through while organizing a software conference</title>
<link>https://notamonadtutorial.com/the-bullshit-i-had-to-go-through-while-organizing-a-software-conference-4de1225d0acb</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://notamonadtutorial.com/the-bullshit-i-had-to-go-through-while-organizing-a-software-conference-4de1225d0acb</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;uiScale uiScale-ui--regular uiScale-caption--regular u-flexCenter u-marginVertical24 u-fontSize15 js-postMetaLockup&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-flex0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link u-baseColor--link avatar&quot; href=&quot;https://notamonadtutorial.com/@unbalancedparen?source=post_header_lockup&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-source=&quot;post_header_lockup&quot; data-action-value=&quot;d257e779bd2c&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; data-user-id=&quot;d257e779bd2c&quot; data-collection-slug=&quot;this-is-not-a-monad-tutorial&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/100/100/1*8CQ8azFtqLAzUYdnx--Vxg.png&quot; class=&quot;avatar-image u-size50x50&quot; alt=&quot;Go to the profile of unbalancedparentheses&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c382&quot; id=&quot;c382&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;This time I am not writing an interview or a technical post. I am writing about a series of events that took place in the context of the conference organization which exposed me to a situation that is now out of control despite my efforts to avoid conflict. The impact these events are having oblige me to write this article as a tool to clarify what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8b2a&quot; id=&quot;8b2a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I expect this specific case illustrates the type of things that might happen to anyone out there trying to create something for the community. I hope the article it is not too boring, I want to give more precise information but I can’t yet. In the end, the truth comes out and people show their true colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e75a&quot; id=&quot;e75a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Reach me via twitter at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unbalancedparen&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unbalancedparen&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;@unbalancedparen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;if you have any comments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*EuMfVua_a5Ch7RaAbc9gRQ.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3088&quot; data-height=&quot;2320&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*EuMfVua_a5Ch7RaAbc9gRQ.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*EuMfVua_a5Ch7RaAbc9gRQ.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Teammates and I in last year’s conference
&lt;p name=&quot;2e59&quot; id=&quot;2e59&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Why organize a conference?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;20bf&quot; id=&quot;20bf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Organizing a conference involves a great expenditure of time and money. True, sponsors make up for a big part of financing, and ticket sales help. Still, conferences tend to net to a loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;62f0&quot; id=&quot;62f0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Then why do we do it? Because they are also an enormous source of satisfaction. For a couple of days, conferences generate a vibrant community, where people have the opportunity to grow and learn together, renew passion for their work and create relationships that will evolve in new projects that will last far beyond the scope of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2d09&quot; id=&quot;2d09&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What are the usual problems that appear while organizing a conference?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0693&quot; id=&quot;0693&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Anyone that has organized an event of this scale knows how hard it is to sell tickets, publicise, organize logistics, get sponsors, look for accomodation, buy airfare tickets, coordinate catering, pay for insurance, arrange stands and manage audio and video recording. Also, differences within the organizing team and diverse points of view will most likely appear. Basically, “whatever can go wrong, will go wrong”, and this is quite a challenge during the preproduction and during the conference itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1bfd&quot; id=&quot;1bfd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What has been our experience so far?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;aeda&quot; id=&quot;aeda&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Until now, my team and I have organized several meetups and participated in lots of conferences; but only last year we took the plunge and organized our first software conference, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://buzzconf.org/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://buzzconf.org/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BuzzConf&lt;/a&gt;. This will be the second time we started a new telecommunication conference called &lt;a href=&quot;https://zruput.org/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://zruput.org/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zruput&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2a1e&quot; id=&quot;2a1e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We learned how to deal with the unexpected: flights were cancelled, the catering messed up the gluten-free food, the cell phone of one of our speakers went missing during the conference, the audio and video recording of the talks failed and some sponsors paid months after the conference. Despite these inconveniences, which are normal, it was an incredible experience and we enjoyed it greatly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d43b&quot; id=&quot;d43b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We were able to bring people who develop Linux’s kernel, who are part of the Rust language core team, who make important contributions to distributed systems, people who launch satellites, among other things. The people we met and the things we learned broadened our horizons. This year we are expecting computer scientists that were involved in the design of Haskell, that created an amazing package managers and that implemented Python packages, used by hedge funds, for statistical modeling. We know we are privileged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;89f7&quot; id=&quot;89f7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What happened this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b90e&quot; id=&quot;b90e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;My team and I were contacted by different people to warn us that they were uncomfortable with the participation of a speaker and her boyfriend in our conference. Sadly, I can’t go into details until the legal issue is over. This communication took us by surprise since we had performed a basic background check on the chosen speakers to avoid these kinds of issues. Like many of you who are reading this article, I am skeptical of what people I don’t know say over the Internet. I initially hesitated to do something based upon these comments when my team and I discussed the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f89a&quot; id=&quot;f89a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;When you are in a difficult situation, the most reasonable thing to do is to search for the help of those who can provide knowledge and experience, so we consulted on what we should do with different people on what to do. Several people who knew both of them confirmed that they had had problems with them in the past. We also talked with the organizers of other conferences and with dev that are part of gender groups focalized in technology and all of them recommended us to take distance from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0ce8&quot; id=&quot;0ce8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This was how we finally decided that the best thing to do was to inform the speaker she wasn’t going to be a member of the conference. It was a difficult decision in which we prioritized the participation of the public that had reached out to us while also knowing that many people, especially women, wouldn’t come to the conference if we did nothing about this situation. Neither I nor the rest of the organization wanted to create a problematic situation, we were just trying to solve a difficult conflict in the best possible way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3c3e&quot; id=&quot;3c3e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Therefore, on April 25, 2019, I, along with an employee of my company, communicated to her our decision in a meeting held in a place of her choice. She took it badly. We knew it was hard news to take on. Nevertheless, we didn’t expect a threatening reaction followed by several emails, Twitter DMs, persistent phone calls and Whatsapp messages. She even texted my girlfriend, one of the organizers of the conference, whose telephone number is not public and wasn’t given to her at any moment. At the same time, she started contacting other speakers of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;31ae&quot; id=&quot;31ae&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Problems escalate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c4ac&quot; id=&quot;c4ac&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A few hours later, I was contacted via Whatsapp by a person who told me he needed to meet me to talk about the conference because he had a big problem which could be solved by talking. That person identified himself. I didn’t know who he was and I replied that I had no problem speaking but I didn’t know how I could help him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fc51&quot; id=&quot;fc51&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At around the same time I got a message from an employee of my company who told me that the same person had contacted a speaker of our conference and requested a meeting with him. The speaker confirmed this to me and told me he had felt uncomfortable with the way in which this person had written to him. When this happened, I asked around and acquaintances of mine told me that this person was the boyfriend of the speaker we had decided wouldn’t be a part of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;34f9&quot; id=&quot;34f9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At this point I found out this man is an internationally renowned information security specialist. He found vulnerabilities in known operating systems and privacy-oriented messaging platforms. I was learning all this in the spur of the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;46a1&quot; id=&quot;46a1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It was late in the day, but before I went to sleep I found an anonymous threat which stated private information about me would be published. I can’t confirm who the author was, as it was anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5bd7&quot; id=&quot;5bd7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Conference encounter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;99e1&quot; id=&quot;99e1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Two days later on April 27th, a software conference took place that has no relationship with the conference I am organizing. I went there to meet two acquaintances. After meeting with them I decided to tour around and see the different stands of the conference. At that precise moment I saw the former speaker. She was calling the security of the event and using her cellphone to record me. She yelling that I was at the conference to stalk her, and that I was harassing her and following her. I never thought something like this could ever happen. It is worth noting that, at this point, I had only talked over the phone with her once, met her in person also once and, as I stated before, I had received several persistent communications from her. Now she was accusing me of following her to her work, to a conference and of being a stalker. One of the organizers of this conference intervened and let her yell at me instead of trying to solve the issue. A few days after I learned he was a close friend of her and her partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dc66&quot; id=&quot;dc66&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I had to leave the conference, depressed by the whole situation. Luckily, my girlfriend and other friends were there to help me. I was just attending a conference and was subjected, along with my acquaintances, to a very unpleasant moment by being unfairly accused by a person I didn’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0888&quot; id=&quot;0888&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;They went public&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4a4d&quot; id=&quot;4a4d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After this incident, a friend gave me a heads up that the boyfriend of this person had taken to Twitter to post that I was harassing and threatening his girlfriend. He even suggested that I was personally attacking him through his girlfriend. He later deleted this tweet but I managed to save screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3331&quot; id=&quot;3331&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After this I felt powerless and despaired. I never imagined that telling someone she would not speak at the conference would expose me and my team to this sort of situation. Several people contacted us to ask what was going on and why I was being accused of harassing a woman. I had to give explanations to our sponsors. Being accused like that caused me harm. He had already gone public with his version, so I decided to tell my side of the story on Twitter too. I needed people to know the facts: we had contacted a speaker to tell her she was no longer a part of the conference, we were harassed and I was the victim of a false accusation that had a commercial impact for me. I had to talk with clients, sponsors and employees to explain what was happening. Due to all of this, I decided to file the corresponding lawsuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e3f7&quot; id=&quot;e3f7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;While I was sleeping, early morning May 4th, my phone began to ring incessantly for minutes with notifications. It was an employee’s phone sending messages via Signal, for several minutes. I called him to ask what was going on. He said he hadn’t touched his phone. I asked him to turn off his phone, but the messages kept coming. At the same time, another employee called me to tell me he was getting those messages too and wanted to know what was happening. To be clear, I don’t think in any way somebody exploited a vulnerability of Signal, but it was used. In the years I have been using Signal, this never happened to me nor do I know of similar cases, but I have talked with security specialists that pointed me to how this might have happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cb3e&quot; id=&quot;cb3e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is just one of many similar issues I had to go through since then, but this article would become long and boring if I listed them all, and I think you already get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;28b3&quot; id=&quot;28b3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What is the best way to act in these cases?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f553&quot; id=&quot;f553&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Sometimes, our initial reaction to this type of situation is keeping quiet and hope it goes away. As soon as you start talking you start being judged and getting deep into even a bigger problem. These are the reasons why we hesitated within my team to make this situation public. We didn’t want to waste time, energy and resources on this affair. Generally, the best scenario is to talk with the involved parties, to cooperate and to seek a solution that doesn’t make the problem bigger. This isn’t always possible. In this case they went public and accused me and I had to explain what happened. I had to explain to sponsors, clients, employees and other members of the community what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b795&quot; id=&quot;b795&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What’s the legal status of the conflict?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1299&quot; id=&quot;1299&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’m currently analyzing with different attorneys and advisers the steps to take next. One of the pieces of advice they gave me were not to give any names to avoid escalating the situation even further. It pains me to do so, because I feel I need to warn the community so that this doesn’t happen to more people. But I understand this is the way things work and right now I need to trust that the justice system in my country will do its work. Therefore, I will take the necessary legal actions to bring light to this situation, and I will request the legal system to publish all necessary documents to prove I acted with integrity at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;063c&quot; id=&quot;063c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Why is it important to create safe and diverse cooperation spaces?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ed89&quot; id=&quot;ed89&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Some people consider that software conferences are focusing too much on inclusion and diversity. What they want is for conferences to be exclusively technical. This makes sense only in abstract. The problem with this is that they aren’t taking into account that many people can’t partake in the way they could and would like to. There is no way of making a technical conference if some people feel insecure or uncomfortable. This is why inclusion and diversity are essential in these kinds of events, as well as the participation of the groups that promote these values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d303&quot; id=&quot;d303&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We know that hostile environments are often generated where harassment and uncomfortable situations make women and minorities step aside. It is important to generate a space where everybody, no matter what gender, ethnicity, religion or ideology, is able to share knowledge in a friendly, pleasant environment with a collaboration spirit. There are several ways to achieve this. One of them is to work along gender and minority technology groups, which are doing an excellent work in promoting bigger diversity, and cooperate with them. Giving discounts to those minorities that have less resources is another way. It is also necessary to be attentive towards potential conflict situations that may occur so we can solve them by following a code of conduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5d63&quot; id=&quot;5d63&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This year, only 2 of the 9 speakers in our conference will be women. The conference is still really behind its gender equality goals in this sense. We are working with different women’s groups to improve. I am sure that we will do better in the following years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;05e6&quot; id=&quot;05e6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;How will we move forward?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cc79&quot; id=&quot;cc79&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Today, we are working to leave all this behind us, but since there are legal complaints, this will probably take more time, more money and more energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;93e8&quot; id=&quot;93e8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Being involved in situations like this is part of the risk one takes when organizing a conference and facing a greater deal of public exposure. It was probably naive of me not to consider these kind of things could happen. I actually believed that the hard part of organizing a conference was the logistics, but I learned that sometimes the hardest part is the human factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;61b8&quot; id=&quot;61b8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The best way to face this type of situation is to always be faithful to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lambdaclass/buzzconf/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/lambdaclass/buzzconf/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;, not give in to undue pressure and consult groups dedicated to ethics, gender and minorities in technology because they know the most about these issues. Also, to lay things out in the open, speak up and not let there be a taboo is essential to prevent other people to go through the same ordeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ab19&quot; id=&quot;ab19&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;Finally, I would like to thank everybody that contacted us. In times like these, those gestures are worth a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 16:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>unbalancedparen</dc:creator>
<og:title>The bullshit I had to go through while organizing a software conference</og:title>
<og:url>https://notamonadtutorial.com/the-bullshit-i-had-to-go-through-while-organizing-a-software-conference-4de1225d0acb</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*EuMfVua_a5Ch7RaAbc9gRQ.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>This time I am not writing an interview or a technical post. I am writing about a series of events that took place in the context of the…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://notamonadtutorial.com/the-bullshit-i-had-to-go-through-while-organizing-a-software-conference-4de1225d0acb?gi=527d92ee54d6</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Solution for Loneliness: Get out and volunteer, research suggests</title>
<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-solution-for-loneliness/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-solution-for-loneliness/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region mura-region-loose&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region-local&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was riding a bus recently and noticed an older man sitting outside a coffee shop on a busy sidewalk. He had set up a chessboard on the table in front of him, and he watched as people passed by, mostly engrossed in their phones. His eyes kept jumping from person to person, searching for someone to notice and join him for a game of chess. Right before the traffic cleared and my bus moved on, he reached over to make the first move, and then resumed his searching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loneliness is rampant, and it’s killing us—&lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1000316&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;literally&lt;/a&gt;. Anywhere from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2018/08/31/loneliness-is-pervasive-and-rising-particularly-among-the-young&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one quarter&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.multivu.com/players/English/8294451-cigna-us-loneliness-survey/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one half&lt;/a&gt; of Americans feel lonely a lot of the time, which puts them at risk for developing a range of physical and mental illnesses, including heart disease, cancer, diabetes, and depression. This is a public health problem that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/to-combat-loneliness-promote-social-health1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;needs to be addressed&lt;/a&gt; on a wide scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at the individual level, there is much we can do to ward off loneliness. One strategy is to bring a chessboard to a busy street and wait for someone to play with you. For the older man’s sake, I sincerely hope that this is effective, but I can’t be sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another strategy is to volunteer. In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncvo.org.uk/images/documents/policy_and_research/volunteering/Volunteer-experience_Full-Report.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recent survey&lt;/a&gt; of over 10,000 people in the UK, two-thirds reported that volunteering helped them feel less isolated. Similarly, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/psychsocgerontology/article/73/3/501/3938841&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2018 study&lt;/a&gt; of nearly 6,000 people across the US examined widows who, unsurprisingly, felt lonelier than married adults. After starting to volunteer for two or more hours per week, their average level of loneliness subsided to match that of married adults, even after controlling for demographics, baseline health, personality traits, and other social involvement. These benefits may be especially strong the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.royalvoluntaryservice.org.uk/Uploads/Documents/Reports%20and%20Reviews/the_impact_of_volunteering_on_wellbeing_in_later_life.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;older you are&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12730314&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more often&lt;/a&gt; you volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participating in volunteer opportunities may help alleviate loneliness and its related health impact for several reasons. The first and most obvious is that it’s a meaningful way to connect with others and make new friends. I experienced this firsthand when I moved to San Francisco and knew almost no one. After joining a young professionals volunteer group, getting involved with a local nonprofit serving seniors and adults with disabilities, and both organizing and assisting with neighborhood events, I felt my own sense of community and social support increase dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, volunteering can make up for the loss of meaning that commonly occurs with loneliness. Research using the UCLA Loneliness Scale and Meaning in Life Questionnaire has shown that more loneliness is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2717555/#S16title&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;associated&lt;/a&gt; with less meaning. This makes sense, given our deeply rooted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Mark_Leary2/publication/15420847_The_Need_to_Belong_Desire_for_Interpersonal_Attachments_as_a_Fundamental_Human_Motivation/links/5b647053aca272e3b6af9211/The-Need-to-Belong-Desire-for-Interpersonal-Attachments-as-a-Fundamental-Human-Motivation.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;need for belonging&lt;/a&gt;. By volunteering for social causes that are important to us, we can gain a sense of purpose, which in turn may shield us from negative health outcomes. For example, purpose in life has been linked to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022399913000391&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reduced&lt;/a&gt; likelihood of stroke and &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.2044-8295.1992.tb02429.x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;greater&lt;/a&gt; psychological well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, loneliness and isolation can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23362501&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lead to&lt;/a&gt; cognitive decline, such as memory loss. But &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/lisa_genova_what_you_can_do_to_prevent_alzheimer_s/transcript&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;according&lt;/a&gt; to the neuroscientist Lisa Genova, people who regularly engage in mentally stimulating activities build up more neural connections and are subsequently more resilient to symptoms of Alzheimer’s. So, volunteering is one way to stay engaged and stimulated, rather than isolated and lonely, and thereby protect against cognitive decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These insights may be especially relevant for the growing senior population. By 2030, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/newsroom/press-releases/2018/cb18-41-population-projections.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one in five&lt;/a&gt; residents in the US will be of retirement age, may no longer have work to provide purpose and connection, and will be prone to isolation due to increased physical limitations and loved ones passing away. Given that loneliness seems to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22303614&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;most prevalent&lt;/a&gt; among those over 65 and under 25 years old, mentoring across ages could be a powerful way to volunteer and connect. Indeed, I recently experimented with &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/world-economic-forum-global-shapers-san-francisco/bridging-the-intergenerational-divide-5ee500025774&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt; an intergenerational friendship gathering and found that it left baby boomers and millennials—not to mention me—feeling gratified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could have stopped my bus and skipped my plans that day to play chess with the older man. He struck me as a symbol of our times: people wanting desperately to connect—not through a screen, but face-to-face, with others from their community. Now more than ever, we have a real need and opportunity to build a culture of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/to-combat-loneliness-promote-social-health1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;social health&lt;/a&gt;, one interaction at a time. Volunteering is a great way to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 15:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>headalgorithm</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>A Solution for Loneliness</og:title>
<og:description>Get out and volunteer, research suggests</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.scientificamerican.com/sciam/cache/file/98EA5202-9A46-4C37-A03304875C5889D8.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-solution-for-loneliness/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-solution-for-loneliness/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>