<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>How to recognize AI snake oil [pdf]</title>
<link>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/~arvindn/talks/MIT-STS-AI-snakeoil.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cs.princeton.edu/~arvindn/talks/MIT-STS-AI-snakeoil.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.princeton.edu/~arvindn/talks/MIT-STS-AI-snakeoil.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 19:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>longdefeat</dc:creator>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/~arvindn/talks/MIT-STS-AI-snakeoil.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to run your own mail server (2017)</title>
<link>https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;A guide to self-hosting your email on FreeBSD using Postfix, Dovecot, Rspamd, and LDAP.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;Cullum Smith&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;date&quot; content=&quot;2017-08-20&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;/css/style.css?1542419245&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;application/rss+xml&quot; href=&quot;/rss/&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; href=&quot;/favicon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;How To Run Your Own Mail Server&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;567.36572696078&quot;&gt;
&lt;nav&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;posted-on&quot;&gt;20 Aug 2017&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;header readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subtitle&quot;&gt;A guide to self-hosting your email on FreeBSD using Postfix, Dovecot, Rspamd, and LDAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting off GMail is one of the best ways to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/self-hosting-guide/&quot;&gt;take back your data&lt;/a&gt; in the face of dragnet surveillance. Unfortunately, it's also one of the most difficult. If you search for &quot;how to run your own mail server,&quot; many of the results will tell you it's simply too difficult to reliably do it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, running your own mail server is not as daunting as many would have you believe. After all, that is how email is &lt;em&gt;designed to work&lt;/em&gt;. Email is perhaps the most successful federated, decentralized protocol to ever exist. It's a shame we've allowed a centralized, monolithic advertising company to obtain a near monopoly on such a great technology. Luckily, I've spent the last few years tweaking my mail server setup, and I'm willing to enable your laziness in the spirit of a more free and open internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive in, an important caveat: You will become a sysadmin of your own mail server. &lt;em&gt;If you screw something up, you might not be able to send or receive email.&lt;/em&gt; Sure, if all else fails, you can admit defeat and point your MX records at a Google Apps account and carry on. However, you run the risk of losing emails in the interim. I'm going to try to make this guide as foolproof as possible, but if you're not comfortable assuming this responsibility, it might be best to leave it to the experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, here's what this guide will get you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Opportunistic TLS for sending/receiving email with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.postfix.org&quot;&gt;Postfix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to your email anywhere using IMAP with &lt;a href=&quot;https://dovecot.org&quot;&gt;Dovecot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast, modern spam filtering with &lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com&quot;&gt;Rspamd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full-text search of your mailbox with &lt;a href=&quot;https://lucene.apache.org/solr/&quot;&gt;Apache Solr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DKIM, SPF, and DMARC records to ensure your outgoing mail is not spam-filtered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical training of your spam filter based on what you move in/out of the Junk folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom email sorting/filtering using &lt;a href=&quot;http://sieve.info&quot;&gt;sieve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;After running this setup for year or so, I have found many aspects to be &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; than GMail. I think the spam filtering works better, and being able to write a sieve script to sort your inbox is a godsend compared to GMail's convoluted filter system. And as Google occasionally seems to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2017/aug/1/jordan-b-petersons-youtube-account-locked-during-b/&quot;&gt;suspend the accounts of those with opinions they don't like&lt;/a&gt;, you'll have peace of mind with all your mail on a system &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final note: I run everything on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsd.org/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;, so you may have to massage some of the commands to work on your Linux flavor of choice, if that's your thing. All the software used is open source, and should run equally well on any Unix-like OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#dns&quot;&gt;DNS Records&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#postfix&quot;&gt;Postfix: The Mail Transfer Agent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#dovecot&quot;&gt;Dovecot: The Mail Delivery Agent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#solr&quot;&gt;Solr: Full-Text Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#rspamd&quot;&gt;Rspamd: Spam Filtering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#dkim&quot;&gt;DKIM: Validation for Your Outgoing Mail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#sieve&quot;&gt;Sieve: Scripting Your Mailbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;87.86553073912&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, take a deep breath, and feast your eyes on this convoluted Rube Goldberg machine of an email system which you will soon bring lumbering to life: &lt;img alt=&quot;architecture diagram&quot; src=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/img/mail_server_diagram.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's walk through the architecture. All email (whether sent or received) first goes through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.postfix.org&quot;&gt;Postfix&lt;/a&gt; - the Mail Transfer Agent (MTA). Postfix is responsible for transferring email to wherever it's supposed to go. If the recipient domain's mailbox is on our own server, Postfix will accept the message for delivery. Otherwise, Postfix will relay the message to the recipient's mail server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are &lt;em&gt;sending&lt;/em&gt; an email to someone, you connect to Postfix over SMTP with mandatory STARTTLS encryption on port 587. After successfully validating your username and password, Postfix will accept your message to relay to the recipient's mail server over SMTP using opportunistic TLS. (&quot;Opportunistic&quot; means that we will use encryption if the other side supports it, and fall back to plaintext if they don't.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are &lt;em&gt;receiving&lt;/em&gt; an email from someone, the sender's mail server will connect to Postfix over SMTP with opportunistic TLS on port 25. After doing some basic security and spam checks (like prohibiting unauthorized relaying and ensuring the other side has valid DNS records in place), Postfix will accept the message for delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether a message is relayed (you sent an email to someone) or accepted for delivery (someone sent an email to you), it is first filtered through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com&quot;&gt;rspamd&lt;/a&gt; milter. (&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.postfix.org/MILTER_README.html&quot;&gt;milter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is just a term for a Postfix mail filter.) For incoming mail, rspamd does some spam checking and may flag the message as spam or reject it altogether. For outgoing mail, rspamd just takes care of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dkim.org&quot;&gt;DKIM&lt;/a&gt; signing (discussed in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#dkim&quot;&gt;DKIM section&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an accepted email makes it through the rspamd milter, it is delivered to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovecot.org&quot;&gt;Dovecot&lt;/a&gt; - the Mail Delivery Agent (MDA) - using a local unix domain socket. Dovecot takes the emails from Postfix and stores them in the user's mailbox. The mailbox can be stored on the filesystem in a few different formats - with Maildir and mbox being commonly used. Dovecot provides remote access to your mailbox using the POP3 and IMAP protocols. In addition, it supports automatic mail filtering using custom &lt;a href=&quot;http://sieve.info&quot;&gt;sieve&lt;/a&gt; scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Dovecot receives a message, it first passes it to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lucene.apache.org/solr/&quot;&gt;Solr&lt;/a&gt; server, which indexes it for future full-text searches. Then, a sieve script will run which automatically places mail with the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;X-SPAM&lt;/span&gt; header into the user's Junk folder. In addition, when a user moves a message in or out of their Junk folder, Dovecot will inform rspamd to re-train a message as spam or ham. POP3 is ancient history, so in our setup we'll only expose our emails over SSL-secured IMAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run a local &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ldap.com/getting-started-with-ldap&quot;&gt;LDAP server&lt;/a&gt;, which allows me to use a single username and password for all my self-hosted apps. In this guide, I'll describe how to store your mail credentials and email aliases in LDAP. However, it's just as easy to store this information in a relational database or flat files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick note: Dovecot supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc2177&quot;&gt;IMAP IDLE&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a pseudo-push functionality to get notified of new mail &quot;instantly.&quot; While this works for most desktop mail clients, such as &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mutt.org&quot;&gt;mutt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and OS X's Mail.app, it isn't supported by mobile clients (with Android's &lt;a href=&quot;https://k9mail.github.io&quot;&gt;K-9 Mail&lt;/a&gt; being a notable exception). There is an open-source implementation of the Exchange ActiveSync protocol called &lt;a href=&quot;http://z-push.org&quot;&gt;Z-Push&lt;/a&gt;, which integrates with your IMAP server to provide push notifications to iOS and Android devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran Z-Push for a few months, but there were enough small bugs (along with the hassle of running PHP in production) to make me uninstall it. Setting my iPhone to check for new mail every 15 minutes is plenty fast for me, and I still have about 40% battery left at the end of the day. However, if you are dead set on having &lt;em&gt;instant&lt;/em&gt; email notifications, it might be something to look into. It works well enough, I just didn't find it worth the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT (20 Sep 2017): I've got native push notifications working on iOS.&lt;/strong&gt; See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/dovecot-push-notifications/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; for a step-by-step guide.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, all the examples in this guide will use the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;example.com&lt;/span&gt; domain and non-routable IP addresses. Obviously, you'll need to acquire your own domain name and public IP address for your mail server, and modify my examples accordingly. All commands in this guide should be run as root unless otherwise specified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;62.974428912376&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;dns&quot;&gt;DNS Records&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you will need to set some DNS records so that other mail servers know where to send your email. If you use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/dns-hidden-master/&quot;&gt;hidden master server to host your DNS&lt;/a&gt; like I do, you can just edit your zone file and reload BIND. Otherwise, you can set these records in your DNS provider's management portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably want to set a low TTL (around 60 seconds) until you've verified everything is working correctly. It's very annoying to realize you typed the wrong IP address and then have to wait 3 hours for the TTL to expire in order to test again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you'll need is an MX record. MX records tell other mail servers which hosts are running mail servers for a given domain. You can specify multiple MX records, each with their own priority, to use as fallback mail servers when your primary one is down. For my &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;example.com&lt;/span&gt; domain, I only have a single mail server, &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;mail.example.com&lt;/span&gt;, so in my zone file I have a single MX record. Of course, you will need to substitute your own IP address and domain name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/named/master/example.com.db&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$TTL    10800
$ORIGIN example.com.
@  1D  IN  SOA ns1.example.com.  root.example.com. (
      2017080802 
      1d 
      3m 
      1w 
      3h 
     )
 IN  MX  10 mail.example.com.

@      IN  A      203.0.113.41
@      IN  AAAA   2001:db8::2
mail   IN  A      203.0.113.42
mail   IN  AAAA   2001:db8::3
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is &lt;strong&gt;critically important&lt;/strong&gt; that you have &lt;strong&gt;reverse&lt;/strong&gt; DNS records for your mail server host. If your reverse DNS records do not point back to your mail server, other mail servers may reject your email as spam. Normally, you can set reverse DNS records in your hosting provider's web portal. Make sure to set reverse DNS for both the IPv4 and IPv6 address of your mail server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your mail server's reverse DNS and fully qualified domain name don't have to match exactly, but your hostname in reverse DNS should probably resolve to the same IP as your MX record. Your best bet is to have it point straight back to your mail server's hostname. You can verify your reverse DNS record using the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;dig&lt;/span&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
dig +short -x 203.0.113.42

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, just having any reverse DNS record in place is enough for most mail servers to accept your mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will also need to set an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openspf.org&quot;&gt;SPF record&lt;/a&gt; for your mail server. While an SPF record is not technically required for your mail server to work, having one in place significantly reduces the likelihood of your mail being rejected as spam. An SPF record tells other mail servers which hosts are allowed to send mail on behalf of your domain. In my case, I have a single mail server, and I want others to accept mail from that server only. So my SPF record looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/named/master/example.com.db&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
@  IN  TXT  &quot;v=spf1 mx -all&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicates that only my MX records (&lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;mail.example.com&lt;/span&gt;) are allowed to send mail for &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;example.com&lt;/span&gt;, and mail coming from anywhere else should be assumed to be spam and rejected. You can add your SPF definition as a TXT record in your DNS provider's web portal (without the quotes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;201.17375922369&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;postfix&quot;&gt;Postfix: The Mail Transfer Agent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we're ready to install and configure some software. I install my packages from FreeBSD ports, so substitute the appropriate commands for your package manager of choice. First, bring everything up to date:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
portsnap fetch &amp;amp;&amp;amp; portsnap update
portmaster -aBd
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Postfix will be responsible for sending and receiving mail for our domain over SMTP. Install it from ports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/ports/mail/postfix
make install clean
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my setup, I use the following build options: &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;LDAP PCRE PGSQL TLS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you've watched the magic text scroll for a few minutes, postfix should be installed. Navigate to it's configuration directory and edit the config file. (On FreeBSD, software packages from ports are always installed under the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/usr/local&lt;/span&gt; prefix. It should be under &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/etc/postfix&lt;/span&gt; if you're on Linux.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/local/etc/postfix
vim main.cf
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is what I have in my &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;main.cf&lt;/span&gt;. I've given you some brief commentary on what all the config options do, but you can always check &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.postfix.org/postconf.5.html&quot;&gt;the man page&lt;/a&gt; if you need more details on something. This is a pretty standard &lt;em&gt;virtual users&lt;/em&gt; setup. Rather than host mail for actual unix accounts on the server, postfix will use an external database (LDAP, in my case) to determine which email addresses it should accept mail for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a message is accepted for delivery, postfix hands it off to Dovecot. Postfix will also use Dovecot's &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;auth&lt;/span&gt; mechanism to authenticate SMTP users. We'll configure the LDAP authentication in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#dovecot&quot;&gt;Dovecot section&lt;/a&gt; and let postfix just re-use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll set some standard spam-proofing and security options here as well, but we'll be coming back to this file when we set up rspamd in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#rspamd&quot;&gt;section below&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/postfix/main.cf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

compatibility_level = 2


biff = no


mail_spool_directory = /var/mail/local



myhostname = mail.example.com





mydestination = awesomebox.example.com, localhost.example.com, localhost



myorigin = awesomebox.example.com


disable_vrfy_command = yes


strict_rfc821_envelopes = yes


show_user_unknown_table_name = no




message_size_limit = 51200000
mailbox_size_limit = 51200000


allow_percent_hack = no
swap_bangpath = no


recipient_delimiter = +


smtpd_tls_cert_file = /usr/local/etc/ssl/certs/mail.example.com.rsa.crt
smtpd_tls_key_file = /usr/local/etc/ssl/certs/mail.example.com.rsa.key





smtpd_tls_eccert_file = /usr/local/etc/ssl/certs/mail.example.com.ecc.crt
smtpd_tls_eckey_file = /usr/local/etc/ssl/certs/mail.example.com.ecc.key
smtpd_tls_eecdh_grade = ultra



smtp_tls_CAfile=/etc/ssl/cert.pem




smtp_tls_security_level = dane
smtp_dns_support_level = dnssec







smtp_bind_address = 203.0.113.42
smtp_bind_address6 = 2001:db8::3










smtpd_tls_mandatory_protocols = !SSLv2, !SSLv3, !TLSv1, !TLSv1.1, TLSv1.2
smtpd_tls_mandatory_ciphers = high
tls_high_cipherlist = ECDHE-ECDSA-AES256-GCM-SHA384:ECDHE-RSA-AES256-GCM-SHA384:ECDHE-ECDSA-CHACHA20-POLY1305:ECDHE-RSA-CHACHA20-POLY1305:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES128-GCM-SHA256:ECDHE-RSA-AES128-GCM-SHA256:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES256-SHA384:ECDHE-RSA-AES256-SHA384:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES128-SHA256:ECDHE-RSA-AES128-SHA256


smtpd_tls_security_level = may


tls_ssl_options = no_ticket, no_compression


smtpd_tls_dh512_param_file  = /usr/local/etc/ssl/dh512.pem
smtpd_tls_dh1024_param_file = /usr/local/etc/ssl/dh2048.pem


smtpd_tls_session_cache_database = btree:${data_directory}/smtpd_tlscache
smtp_tls_session_cache_database  = btree:${data_directory}/smtp_tlscache



smtpd_sasl_auth_enable = yes
smtpd_sasl_path = private/auth
smtpd_sasl_type = dovecot


smtpd_tls_auth_only = yes


smtpd_sasl_security_options = noanonymous, noplaintext

smtpd_sasl_tls_security_options = noanonymous


smtpd_tls_received_header = yes



smtpd_helo_required = yes








smtpd_client_restrictions =
permit_mynetworks,
permit_sasl_authenticated,
reject_unknown_reverse_client_hostname,





reject_unauth_pipelining
smtpd_helo_restrictions =
permit_mynetworks,
permit_sasl_authenticated,
reject_invalid_helo_hostname,
reject_non_fqdn_helo_hostname,





reject_unauth_pipelining
smtpd_sender_restrictions =
permit_mynetworks,
permit_sasl_authenticated,
reject_non_fqdn_sender,
reject_unknown_sender_domain,
reject_unauth_pipelining
smtpd_relay_restrictions =
permit_mynetworks,
permit_sasl_authenticated,

reject_unauth_destination

smtpd_recipient_restrictions =
permit_mynetworks,
permit_sasl_authenticated,
reject_non_fqdn_recipient,
reject_unknown_recipient_domain,
reject_unauth_pipelining,
reject_unverified_recipient
smtpd_data_restrictions =
permit_mynetworks,
permit_sasl_authenticated,
reject_multi_recipient_bounce,
reject_unauth_pipelining


virtual_transport = lmtp:unix:private/dovecot-lmtp


virtual_mailbox_domains = ldap:/usr/local/etc/postfix/ldap-virtual-mailbox-domains.cf

virtual_mailbox_maps = ldap:/usr/local/etc/postfix/ldap-virtual-mailbox-maps.cf, hash:/usr/local/etc/postfix/system-virtual-mailboxes

virtual_alias_maps = ldap:/usr/local/etc/postfix/ldap-virtual-alias-maps.cf






&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll need to create some of the files and directories we specified in this file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

mkdir /var/mail/local
chown root:mail /var/mail/local
chmod 775 /var/mail/local


openssl dhparam -out /usr/local/etc/ssl/dh512.pem 512
openssl dhparam -out /usr/local/etc/ssl/dh2048.pem 2048
chmod 644 /usr/local/etc/ssl/dh{512,2048}.pem
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;master.cf&lt;/span&gt;, you can set service-specific overrides for the options you set in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;main.cf&lt;/span&gt;. We'll use this file to make encryption mandatory on the submission port (587). You can just change the lines below the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;smtp&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;submission&lt;/span&gt; declarations - no need to change anything else in this file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/postfix/master.cf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;


smtp      inet  n       -       n       -       -       smtpd
-o smtpd_sasl_auth_enable=no



submission inet n       -       n       -       -       smtpd
-o smtpd_tls_security_level=encrypt
-o tls_preempt_cipherlist=yes
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we need to tell postfix which users and domains we want to accept mail for. I use LDAP, so the files below just tell postfix which queries to run to get the neccessary information. You can check out how I setup OpenLDAP &lt;a class=&quot;disabled&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (another blog post I need to write). If you want to use flat files instead, you can use &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;hash:&lt;/span&gt; instead of &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;ldap:&lt;/span&gt; in the last three lines of &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;main.cf&lt;/span&gt; shown above. You can then enter your users, domains, and aliases in plain text directly in those files, and &quot;compile&quot; them with the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;postmap&lt;/span&gt; command. Or you could put the information in a PostgreSQL database - there's plenty of online tutorials for that as well. You can read more details on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.postfix.org/VIRTUAL_README.html&quot;&gt;postfix virtual readme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if you're using LDAP, read on. I haven't spent much time perfecting my LDAP schema—I got a personal &quot;single sign on&quot; system working with it, and left it at that. If you have a more robust LDAP setup, you'll probably need to tweak these queries. The first file specifies which domains this server will accept mail for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/postfix/ldap-virtual-mailbox-domains.cf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
server_host = ldapi://%2fvar%2frun%2fopenldap%2fldapi/
search_base = ou=domains,dc=example,dc=com
version = 3
bind = no
query_filter = (&amp;amp;(ObjectClass=dNSDomain)(dc=%s))
result_attribute = dc
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next file specifies the mailboxes (email addresses) this server will accept mail for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/postfix/ldap-virtual-mailbox-maps.cf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
server_host = ldapi://%2fvar%2frun%2fopenldap%2fldapi/
search_base = ou=users,dc=example,dc=com
version = 3
bind = no
query_filter = (&amp;amp;(objectclass=inetLocalMailRecipient)(mail=%s))
result_attribute = mail
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last file specifies the aliases for those email addresses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/postfix/ldap-virtual-mailbox-alias-maps.cf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
server_host = ldapi://%2fvar%2frun%2fopenldap%2fldapi/
search_base = ou=users,dc=example,dc=com
version = 3
bind = no
query_filter = (&amp;amp;(objectclass=inetLocalMailRecipient)(mailLocalAddress=%s))
result_attribute = mail
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to set up your users and domains in LDAP is to set up an SSH tunnel to your server and run &lt;a href=&quot;http://directory.apache.org/studio/&quot;&gt;Apache Directory Studio&lt;/a&gt;. You can see how I have my domains set up in the query below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;$ ldapsearch -b dc=example.com,ou=domains,dc=example,dc=com&lt;/strong&gt;
# extended LDIF
#
# LDAPv3
# base &amp;lt;dc=example.com,ou=domains,dc=example,dc=com&amp;gt; with scope subtree
# filter: (objectclass=*)
# requesting: ALL
#

# example.com, domains, example.com
dn: dc=example.com,ou=domains,dc=example,dc=com
dc: example.com
objectClass: dNSDomain
objectClass: top

# search result
search: 2
result: 0 Success

# numResponses: 2
# numEntries: 1
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next query shows how I have users configured. The username is specified by the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;uid&lt;/span&gt; parameter. &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;mail&lt;/span&gt; contains the user's primary mailbox, and each &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;mailLocalAddress&lt;/span&gt; entry specifies an email alias for the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;$ ldapsearch -b uid=alphonsus,ou=users,dc=example,dc=com&lt;/strong&gt;
# extended LDIF
#
# LDAPv3
# base &amp;lt;uid=alphonsus,ou=users,dc=example,dc=com&amp;gt; with scope subtree
# filter: (objectclass=*)
# requesting: ALL
#

# alphonsus, users, example.com
dn: uid=alphonsus,ou=users,dc=example,dc=com
cn: Alphonsus Liguori
givenName: Alphonsus
mail: alphonsus@example.com
mailLocalAddress: administrator@example.com
mailLocalAddress: root@example.com
mailLocalAddress: postmaster@example.com
o: The Church Triumphant
objectClass: person
objectClass: organizationalPerson
objectClass: inetOrgPerson
objectClass: inetLocalMailRecipient
sn: Liguori
uid: alphonsus
displayName: Alphonsus Liguori
userPassword: e0HEfj4uiQyYSQxMCRTbHVTYXJshYf4aS4udX...

# search result
search: 2
result: 0 Success

# numResponses: 2
# numEntries: 1
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With those files in place, you can now start postfix! On FreeBSD, you will need to disable the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;sendmail&lt;/span&gt; daemon included by default in base and enable postfix to start on boot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/rc.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
sendmail_enable=&quot;NONE&quot;
postfix_enable=&quot;YES&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you can kill sendmail and start postfix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service sendmail onestop
service postfix start
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the output of &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/var/log/maillog&lt;/span&gt; for any errors. Also, be sure to enable TCP traffic to ports 25 and 587 in your firewall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now have almost everything you need you need for a working postfix installation. We just need to get Dovecot running so postfix has somewhere to deliver the mail. Luckily, Dovecot is a little less arcane to set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;192.19769053118&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;dovecot&quot;&gt;Dovecot: The Mail Delivery Agent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dovecot will provide IMAP access to your mailbox, so you can access your email remotely from multiple devices. It can be easily installed from ports on FreeBSD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/ports/mail/dovecot
make install clean
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the following build options on my server: &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;KQUEUE LZ4 LDAP PGSQL ICU SOLR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to install &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;dovecot-piegeonhole&lt;/span&gt; as well in order to get sieve filtering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/ports/mail/dovecot-pigeonhole
make install clean
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;LDAP&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;MANAGESIEVE&lt;/span&gt; options on my server. The &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;managesieve&lt;/span&gt; protocol allows you to edit your sieve scripts from your email client. Unfortunately, the only client I know of that supports this functionality is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kde.org/applications/internet/kmail/&quot;&gt;KMail&lt;/a&gt;, so I haven't messed with it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Dovecot is installed, you will need to create a &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;vmail&lt;/span&gt; user to handle mail for the virtual users. You will also need to create the directories to store the virtual mail. We will use a separate attachments directory, so Dovecot will never waste disk space by storing the same attachment twice. Pretty neat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
pw useradd -u 145 -n vmail -c &quot;Virtual Mail Handler&quot; -d /var/mail/vhosts -s /usr/sbin/nologin
mkdir /var/mail/{vhosts,attachments}
chown vmail:vmail /var/mail/{vhosts,attachments}
chmod 770 /var/mail/{vhosts,attachments}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, you can navigate to Dovecot's configuration directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/local/etc/dovecot
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you should find a &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;README&lt;/span&gt; and an &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;example-config&lt;/span&gt; directory. Feel free to read over them, or you can just dive into my configs. First, create some additional directories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
mkdir /usr/local/etc/dovecot/{conf.d,sieve,sieve-before.d,sieve-after.d}
chown root:dovecot /usr/local/etc/dovecot/{sieve,sieve-before.d,sieve-after.d}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;dovecot.conf&lt;/span&gt; first. Here, we will set some generic options and include the rest of the config files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/dovecot.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

protocols = imap lmtp


first_valid_uid = 145
last_valid_uid = 145

!include conf.d/*.conf
!include_try local.conf
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining config files live in the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;conf.d&lt;/span&gt; directory. Each file from my configuration is reproduced in its entirety below, with some helpful comments where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/10-auth.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

auth_cache_size = 10M
auth_cache_ttl = 1 hour
auth_cache_negative_ttl = 1 hour


auth_mechanisms = plain


passdb {
  driver = ldap
  args = /usr/local/etc/dovecot/ldap.conf.ext
}




userdb {
  driver = static
  args = uid=vmail gid=vmail home=/var/mail/vhosts/%d/%n
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file specified by &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;passdb&lt;/span&gt; provides the LDAP query information necessary to authenticate usernames and passwords. Note that in my setup, I authenticate with the &lt;em&gt;user&lt;/em&gt; part only. Some other mail providers like to use the entire email address as the username—not so in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/ldap.conf.ext&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
hosts = localhost
auth_bind = no
ldap_version = 3
base = ou=users,dc=example,dc=com
deref = never
scope = subtree
user_attrs =
user_filter = (&amp;amp;(objectclass=inetOrgPerson)(uid=%n)
pass_attrs = mail=user,userPassword=password
pass_filter = (&amp;amp;(objectclass=inetOrgPerson)(uid=%n))
default_pass_scheme = CRYPT
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/10-mail.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

mail_home = /var/mail/vhosts/%d/%n







mail_location = mdbox:~/mdbox



namespace inbox {
  separator = /
  inbox = yes
}


mail_privileged_group = vmail



mail_attachment_dir = /var/mail/attachments
mail_attachment_min_size = 64k



&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/10-master.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;


mail_fsync = never

service imap-login {
  
  inet_listener imap {
    address = 127.0.0.1, ::1
  }

  
  
  service_count = 0
  
  process_min_avail = 3
  vsz_limit = 1G
}


service pop3-login {
  inet_listener pop3 {
    port = 0
  }
  inet_listener pop3s {
    port = 0
  }
}


service imap {
  service_count = 256
  
  process_min_avail = 3
}


service lmtp {
  unix_listener /var/spool/postfix/private/dovecot-lmtp {
    group = postfix
    mode = 0600
    user = postfix
  }
}


service auth {
  unix_listener /var/spool/postfix/private/auth {
    mode = 0660
    user = postfix
    group = postfix
  }
}


service auth-worker {
  user = vmail
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/10-ssl.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

ssl = required

ssl_cert = &amp;lt;/usr/local/etc/ssl/certs/mail.example.com.ecc.crt
ssl_key = &amp;lt;/usr/local/etc/ssl/certs/mail.example.com.ecc.key


ssl_dh_parameters_length = 2048
ssl_protocols = !SSLv2 !SSLv3 !TLSv1 !TLSv1.1 TLSv1.2
ssl_cipher_list = ECDHE-ECDSA-AES256-GCM-SHA384:ECDHE-RSA-AES256-GCM-SHA384:ECDHE-ECDSA-CHACHA20-POLY1305:ECDHE-RSA-CHACHA20-POLY1305:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES128-GCM-SHA256:ECDHE-RSA-AES128-GCM-SHA256:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES256-SHA384:ECDHE-RSA-AES256-SHA384:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES128-SHA256:ECDHE-RSA-AES128-SHA256
ssl_prefer_server_ciphers = yes
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/15-lda.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;


protocol lda {
  
  mail_fsync = optimized
  mail_plugins = $mail_plugins sieve
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/15-mailboxes.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;


namespace inbox {
  mailbox Drafts {
    auto = subscribe
    special_use = \Drafts
  }
  mailbox Junk {
    auto = create
    special_use = \Junk
  }
  mailbox Trash {
    auto = create
    special_use = \Trash
  }
  mailbox Archive {
    auto = subscribe
    special_use = \Archive
  }
  mailbox Sent {
    auto = subscribe
    special_use = \Sent
  }
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/20-imap.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;


imap_idle_notify_interval = 29 mins

protocol imap {
  
  mail_max_userip_connections = 50
  
  mail_plugins = $mail_plugins imap_sieve
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/20-lmtp.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
protocol lmtp {
  
  mail_fsync = optimized
  mail_plugins = $mail_plugins sieve
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/20-managesieve.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
protocols = $protocols sieve













&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/90-fts.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;






&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/90-sieve.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
plugin {
  
  sieve = file:~/sieve;active=~/.dovecot.sieve

  
  
  sieve_before = /usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve-before.d
  sieve_after  = /usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve-after.d

  
  recipient_delimiter = +

  
  sieve_quota_max_storage = 50M
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now have a fully functional IMAP server. Enable Dovecot to start on boot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/rc.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
dovecot_enable=&quot;YES&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you can start Dovecot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service dovecot start
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure to check &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/var/log/maillog&lt;/span&gt; for any errors. Congratulations! You should now have a fully functional mail server! Make sure TCP traffic to port 993 is enabled in your firewall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining sections—full-text search, spam filtering, etc—are just extras. Now is a good time to stop and make sure everything works before you go any further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section readability=&quot;88.773824650572&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;mail-test&quot;&gt;Testing Your Mail Server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, get a separate terminal open and tail your mail log while you are testing everything:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
tail -f /var/log/maillog
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by checking your MX records in DNS using the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;dig&lt;/span&gt; command. If your DNS is configured correctly, you should see results like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
dig example.com MX +short

dig mail.example.com +short

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can test your ability to send and receive mail. Don't worry if you can't connect to your server over port 25—almost all residential ISPs block all traffic on this port to deter spammers. From your local machine, you can use an email client to connect to your mail server. Your connectivity details will be the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Incoming Mail: IMAP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;username:&lt;/strong&gt; ldap username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;password:&lt;/strong&gt; ldap password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;server:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;mail.example.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;port:&lt;/strong&gt; 993&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSL:&lt;/strong&gt; yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outgoing Mail: SMTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;username:&lt;/strong&gt; ldap username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;password:&lt;/strong&gt; ldap password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;email address:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;username@example.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;server:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;mail.example.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;port:&lt;/strong&gt; 587&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSL:&lt;/strong&gt; STARTTLS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you can log in, you should see an empty mailbox with default folders (Inbox, Drafts, Junk, etc). If not, you'll need to check your mail log and troubleshoot Dovecot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you'll need to test outgoing mail. Hopefully you have a spare GMail account or another working email address you can test with. When you send an email through your mail client, you should see something like this in your mail log:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
postfix/smtpd[39231]: connect from SOME-IP-ADDRESS
postfix/smtpd[39231]: AA752DDA7D8: client=SOME-IP_ADDRESS, sasl_method=PLAIN, sasl_username=user@example.com
postfix/cleanup[39248]: AA752DDA7D8: message-id=&amp;lt;EE3CDE5B-9A46-405D-A74A-E409769F791D@example.com&amp;gt;
postfix/qmgr[39210]: AA752DDA7D8: from=&amp;lt;user@example.com&amp;gt;, size=762, nrcpt=1 (queue active)
postfix/smtp[39251]: AA752DDA7D8: to=&amp;lt;YOUR-OTHER-EMAIL@gmail.com&amp;gt;, relay=gmail-smtp-in.l.google.com[74.125.130.27]:25, delay=8.9, delays=4.9/0.03/3/1, dsn=2.0.0, status=sent (250 2.0.0 OK 1502808287 y15si6196590pli.453 - gsmtp)
postfix/qmgr[39210]: AA752DDA7D8: removed
postfix/smtpd[39231]: disconnect from SOME-IP-ADDRESS ehlo=2 starttls=1 auth=1 mail=1 rcpt=1 data=1 quit=1 commands=8
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't see any errors in the log, you should find the email you just sent in your other email account's inbox. If it's not there, be sure to check your spam folder. (If it got flagged as spam, the testing steps in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#dkim&quot;&gt;DKIM section&lt;/a&gt; should help determine why.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you can test incoming mail. In your other email account, reply to the message you just sent yourself. This should be the first email ever sent to your new, personal email server. Fingers crossed! If the other side successfully finds your mail server and delivers the message, you should see something like this in your mail log:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
postfix/smtpd[39448]: connect from mail-yw0-x22b.google.com[2607:f8b0:4002:c05::22b]
postfix/verify[39459]: cache btree:/var/db/postfix/verify_cache full cleanup: retained=9 dropped=0 entries
postfix/smtpd[39448]: 98DA9DDA7D8: client=mail-yw0-x22b.google.com[2607:f8b0:4002:c05::22b]
postfix/cleanup[39460]: 98DA9DDA7D8: message-id=&amp;lt;CALM7EhMmCkzpex5pKu0TXh0z3+iYeLCGpw5VO9Sv_RanqgohYQ@mail.gmail.com&amp;gt;
postfix/qmgr[39210]: 98DA9DDA7D8: from=&amp;lt;YOUR-OTHER-EMAIL@gmail.com&amp;gt;, size=3449, nrcpt=1 (queue active)
dovecot: lmtp(39462): Connect from local
dovecot: lmtp(user@example.com): MMb/MfoPk1kmmgAA/gk8FQ: sieve: msgid=&amp;lt;CALM7EhMmCkzpex5pKu0TXh0z3+iYeLCGpw5VO9Sv_RanqgohYQ@mail.gmail.com&amp;gt;: stored mail into mailbox 'INBOX'
postfix/lmtp[39461]: 98DA9DDA7D8: to=&amp;lt;user@example.com&amp;gt;, relay=mail.example.com[private/dovecot-lmtp], delay=0.26, delays=0.21/0.01/0.01/0.03, dsn=2.0.0, status=sent (250 2.0.0 &amp;lt;user@example.com&amp;gt; MMb/MfoPk1kmmgAA/gk8FQ Saved)
dovecot: lmtp(39462): Disconnect from local: Successful quit
postfix/qmgr[39210]: 98DA9DDA7D8: removed
postfix/smtpd[39448]: disconnect from mail-yw0-x22b.google.com[2607:f8b0:4002:c05::22b] ehlo=2 starttls=1 mail=1 rcpt=1 data=1 quit=1 commands=7
postfix/smtpd[39471]: connect from unknown[181.49.241.194]
postfix/smtpd[39471]: disconnect from unknown[181.49.241.194] helo=1 auth=0/1 quit=1 commands=2/3
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there were no errors, you should see the very first message in your new IMAP inbox! If there was a failure logged, you'll have to investigate postfix. Most likely there was problem finding your virtual mailbox, or postfix had some issue handing the mail off to Dovecot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you didn't receive the email, and you don't see anything logged &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;, then you probably have a firewall issue or some problem with your MX records in DNS. Also, make sure your hosting provider allows traffic on port 25–some of them are paranoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you're able to send and receive emails from your new mail server, you're ready to get the rest of the goodies like full-text searching and spam filtering. Read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;92.248767123288&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;solr&quot;&gt;Solr: Full-Text Search&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solr is a standalone full-text search platform from Apache the Apache Foundation. It's heavyweight and based on Java, but currently it's your best bet if you want open source full-text search with Dovecot. It's easily installed from ports on FreeBSD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/ports/textproc/apache-solr
make install clean
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will pull in Java as a dependency, so you may want to grab a coffee or something while the JVM compiles. The defaults in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/usr/local/etc/solr.in.sh&lt;/span&gt; are fine. Enable solr to start on boot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/rc.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
solr_enable=&quot;YES&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, start the solr server:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service solr start
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we need to create a collection for Dovecot to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
su -m solr -c &quot;/usr/local/solr/bin/solr create -c dovecot -n dovecot&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will create a Solr collection for Dovecot in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/var/db/solr/dovecot&lt;/span&gt;. Navigate to the configuration directory—we'll need to include some magic incantations I found on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mor-pah.net/2016/08/15/dovecot-2-2-with-solr-6-or-5/&quot;&gt;this guy's blog&lt;/a&gt; to get Solr working with Dovecot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /var/db/solr/dovecot/conf
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delete the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;managed-schema&lt;/span&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
rm /var/db/solr/dovecot/conf/managed-schema
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a file called &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;schema.xml&lt;/span&gt; with the contents &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/files/schema.xml&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
curl -o /var/db/solr/dovecot/conf/schema.xml https://www.c0ffee.net/files/schema.xml
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, replace the entire contents of &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;solrconfig.xml&lt;/span&gt; with the version &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/files/solrconfig.xml&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
curl -o /var/db/solr/dovecot/conf/solrconfig.xml https://www.c0ffee.net/files/solrconfig.xml
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, make sure the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;solr&lt;/span&gt; user still owns those files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
chown solr:solr /var/db/solr/dovecot/conf/{schema,solrconfig}.xml
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solr should now be ready to index email for Dovecot. Restart the server for your changes to take effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service solr restart
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you just need to configure Dovecot to use the Solr server. All you have to do is uncomment some lines in the files from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#dovecot&quot;&gt;the previous section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/10-mail.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
mail_plugins = $mail_plugins fts fts_solr
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/90-fts.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
plugin {
  fts_autoindex = yes
  fts = solr
  fts_solr = url=http://127.0.0.1:8983/solr/dovecot/
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reload Dovecot for your changes to take effect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service dovecot reload
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, whenever you receive an email or move a message from one IMAP folder to another, you should see something like this in your mail log:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
dovecot: indexer-worker(user@example.com): Indexed 1 messages in INBOX
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indexing only occurs when a new message arrives in a folder. To index the entire inbox of all your mail users, run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
doveadm index -A inbox
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.dovecot.org/Plugins/FTS/Solr&quot;&gt;the Dovecot documentation&lt;/a&gt;, the Solr database needs to be issued a &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;commit&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;optimize&lt;/span&gt; command every so often. This is easily accomplished by adding the following cron jobs (make sure you get the path to &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;curl&lt;/span&gt; correct if you're using Linux):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/crontab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
15 2 * * *  solr /usr/local/bin/curl -s 'http://localhost:8983/solr/dovecot/update?optimize=true' &amp;gt; /dev/null
*/5 * * * * solr /usr/local/bin/curl -s 'http://localhost:8983/solr/dovecot/update?commit=true' &amp;gt; /dev/null
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now have full-text search of your mailbox over IMAP. You can test it out by searching for some text on your mobile IMAP client (often desktop mail clients will perform searches using local cached data). Or, you can test it yourself from your server using &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;telnet&lt;/span&gt;. Type the following lines (including the preceding numbers) into the prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
telnet localhost imap
* OK [CAPABILITY IMAP4rev1 LITERAL+ SASL-IR...] I am ready.
1 login your_username your_password
2 select Inbox
3 SEARCH text &quot;test&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues, Solr provides a web interface on localhost port 8983. You can set up an SSH tunnel to your server and forward the port to your local machine to check its status. You can also view the logs in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/var/log/solr&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;224.00023696682&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;rspamd&quot;&gt;Rspamd: Spam Filtering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com&quot;&gt;Rspamd&lt;/a&gt; is a fast, open source spam filtering system which utilizes multiple techniques to prevent spam from reaching your mailbox. I was a happy user of &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/dspam/&quot;&gt;dspam&lt;/a&gt; for years, but it has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/p/dspam/mailman/message/32585111/&quot;&gt;offically abandoned since 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rspamd is actively developed and appears to be a much more modern project. Written in C, it is quite fast and integrates directly into postfix as a milter. Like dspam, it uses bayesian filtering to learn what users consider to be spam and ham. However, it also incorporates many other anti-spam measures: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com/doc/modules/rbl.html&quot;&gt;RBL checks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com/doc/modules/spf.html&quot;&gt;SPF&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com/doc/modules/dkim.html&quot;&gt;DKIM&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://dmarc.org&quot;&gt;DMARC&lt;/a&gt; validation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rhyolite.com/dcc/&quot;&gt;DCC bulk mail checks&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com/doc/modules/greylisting.html&quot;&gt;greylisting&lt;/a&gt;, to name a few. In addition, it has some other useful features like &lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com/doc/modules/dkim_signing.html&quot;&gt;DKIM signing of outgoing mail&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com/doc/modules/replies.html&quot;&gt;automatic whitelisting when you reply to someone&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rspamd.com/webui/&quot;&gt;web interface&lt;/a&gt; where you can see spam checking results in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sold yet? Let's get rspamd installed. It's available in FreeBSD ports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/ports/mail/rspamd
make install clean
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the following build options: &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;GD HYPERSCAN&lt;/span&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://01.org/hyperscan&quot;&gt;hyperscan&lt;/a&gt; option is especially cool—it enables high performance regex matching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enable rspamd to start at boot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/rc.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
rspamd_enable=&quot;YES&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, start rspamd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service rspamd start
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many rspamd modules require a &lt;a href=&quot;https://redis.io&quot;&gt;redis&lt;/a&gt; instance to work, so install that as well. The default build options are fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/ports/databases/redis
make install clean
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll want to set some redis options recommended by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com/doc/quickstart.html#caching-setup&quot;&gt;official rspamd tutorial&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/redis.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

bind 127.0.0.1 ::1



maxmemory 512mb
maxmemory-policy volatile-lru
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enable redis to start at boot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/rc.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
redis_enable=&quot;YES&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, start the redis daemon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service redis start
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the rspamd modules we will use depends on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dcc-servers.net/dcc/&quot;&gt;DCC daemon&lt;/a&gt; to check mails for bulkiness. You can install it from ports as well. The default build options are fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/ports/mail/dcc-dccd
make install clean
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncomment the following options in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/usr/local/dcc/dcc_conf&lt;/span&gt;. We'll be using the DCC service to detect spam, but won't be actively reporting anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/dcc/dcc_conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
DCCM_LOG_AT=NEVER
DCCM_REJECT_AT=MANY
DCCIFD_ENABLE=on
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DCC is rather arcane and doesn't seem to log to syslog like modern software. I haven't figured out a nice way of rotating its logs with &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;newsyslogd&lt;/span&gt; yet, so for now I just have a cronjob to delete them every day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/crontab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
0 2 * * * /usr/bin/find /usr/local/dcc/log/ -not -newermt '1 days ago' -delete
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enable DCC to start at boot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/rc.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
dccifd_enable=&quot;YES&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, start the DCC daemon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service dccifd start
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, your're ready to configure rspamd itself. Rspamd's default configuration files live in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd&lt;/span&gt;. Don't edit these files directly, as they will be overwritten when the rspamd package is updated. Instead, create a local configuration directory. All your custom configuration will go here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
mkdir /usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the rspamd website, you'll find the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rspamd.com/doc/quickstart.html&quot;&gt;rspamd quick start guide&lt;/a&gt;, along with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rspamd.com/doc/modules/&quot;&gt;documentation for all the modules&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free design your own setup, or you can just copy what I've done in the files below. I've enabled most of the useful modules and provided some commentary where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/worker-controller.inc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;


password = &quot;$2$or9n9ffj4qsogh7i8d9qi5u1hxt53q6o$ntp4kj...&quot;;



bind_socket = &quot;/var/run/rspamd/rspamd.sock mode=0666 owner=nobody&quot;;


bind_socket = &quot;127.0.0.1:11334&quot;;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/worker-normal.inc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;


enabled = false;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/worker-proxy.inc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

milter = yes;


bind_socket = &quot;/var/run/rspamd/milter.sock mode=0666 owner=nobody&quot;;



timeout = 120s;
upstream &quot;local&quot; {
  default = yes;
  self_scan = yes;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/redis.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

servers = &quot;127.0.0.1&quot;;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/classifier-bayes.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
autolearn = true;
backend = &quot;redis&quot;;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/dcc.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

host = &quot;/usr/local/dcc/dccifd&quot;;
timeout = 5.0;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/dkim_signing.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

path = &quot;/var/db/rspamd/dkim/$domain.$selector.key&quot;;
selector = &quot;dkim&quot;;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/mx_check.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

enabled = true;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/phishing.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

openphish_enabled = true;
phishtank_enabled = true;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/replies.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

action = &quot;no action&quot;;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/surbl.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

redirector_hosts_map = &quot;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/redirectors.inc&quot;;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/url_reputation.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

enabled = true;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/url_tags.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

enabled = true;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart rspamd for all these changes to take effect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service rspamd restart
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you'll need to configure postfix to use rspamd as a milter. Open &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/usr/local/etc/postfix/main.cf&lt;/span&gt; and uncomment the lines you added in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#postfix&quot;&gt;the postfix section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/postfix/main.cf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
milter_protocol = 6

milter_default_action = accept
smtpd_milters = unix:/var/run/rspamd/milter.sock
milter_mail_macros = i {mail_addr} {client_addr} {client_name} {auth_authen}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reload postfix for your changes to take effect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service postfix reload
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, rspamd should be filtering your incoming email as it arrives through postfix. To verify, send yourself a test email and check the output of your mail log, along with &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/var/log/rspamd/rspamd.log&lt;/span&gt;. You also can view real-time filtering stats in the rspamd web interface. Just set up an SSH tunnel to your server, forward port 11334 to localhost, and point your web browser there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you've verified rspamd and postfix are working together, all that's left is to configure Dovecot to train rspamd when you move messages in and out of your Junk folder. The steps for achieving this were derived from &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki2.dovecot.org/HowTo/AntispamWithSieve&quot;&gt;this Dovecot guide&lt;/a&gt;. Add a new file, &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;90-imapsieve.conf&lt;/span&gt;, under Dovecot's &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;conf.d&lt;/span&gt; directory with the following contents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/conf.d/90-imapsieve.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
plugin {
  sieve_plugins = sieve_imapsieve sieve_extprograms

  
  imapsieve_mailbox1_name = Junk
  imapsieve_mailbox1_causes = COPY
  imapsieve_mailbox1_before = file:/usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve/report-spam.sieve

  
  imapsieve_mailbox2_name = *
  imapsieve_mailbox2_from = Junk
  imapsieve_mailbox2_causes = COPY
  imapsieve_mailbox2_before = file:/usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve/report-ham.sieve

  sieve_pipe_bin_dir = /usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve

  sieve_global_extensions = +vnd.dovecot.pipe
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart Dovecot to load the necessary sieve plugins:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service dovecot restart
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create the following sieve scripts in the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve&lt;/span&gt; directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve/report-spam.sieve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
require [&quot;vnd.dovecot.pipe&quot;, &quot;copy&quot;, &quot;imapsieve&quot;, &quot;environment&quot;, &quot;variables&quot;];

if environment :matches &quot;imap.email&quot; &quot;*&quot; {
  set &quot;email&quot; &quot;${1}&quot;;
}

pipe :copy &quot;train-spam.sh&quot; [ &quot;${email}&quot; ];
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve/report-ham.sieve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
require [&quot;vnd.dovecot.pipe&quot;, &quot;copy&quot;, &quot;imapsieve&quot;, &quot;environment&quot;, &quot;variables&quot;];

if environment :matches &quot;imap.mailbox&quot; &quot;*&quot; {
  set &quot;mailbox&quot; &quot;${1}&quot;;
}

if string &quot;${mailbox}&quot; &quot;Trash&quot; {
  stop;
}

if environment :matches &quot;imap.email&quot; &quot;*&quot; {
  set &quot;email&quot; &quot;${1}&quot;;
}

pipe :copy &quot;train-ham.sh&quot; [ &quot;${email}&quot; ];
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These sieve scripts will be triggered whenever email gets moved in or out of your Junk folder. You will need to manually compile them, since Dovecot doesn't have write permission to this directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve
sievec report-spam.sieve
sievec report-ham.sieve
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you need to create the shell scripts that the sieve scripts will execute. Create &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;train-spam.sh&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;train-ham.sh&lt;/span&gt; in the same directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve/train-spam.sh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
exec /usr/local/bin/rspamc -h /var/run/rspamd/rspamd.sock learn_spam
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve/train-ham.sh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
exec /usr/local/bin/rspamc -h /var/run/rspamd/rspamd.sock learn_ham
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure they are executable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
chmod +x /usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve/train-{spam,ham}.sh
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we need to tell Dovecot to automatically move emails that rspamd tagged as spam to your Junk folder. We do this using a global filter on the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;X-SPAM&lt;/span&gt; header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve-before.d/10-rspamd.sieve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
require [&quot;fileinto&quot;];

if header :is &quot;X-Spam&quot; &quot;Yes&quot; {
  fileinto &quot;Junk&quot;;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll need to pre-compile this script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /usr/local/etc/dovecot/sieve-before.d
sievec 10-rspamd.sieve
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reload Dovecot for your changes to take effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
service dovecot reload
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dovecot should now inform the rspamd daemon to retrain a messages as spam or ham when you move it in or out of your Junk folder. To test, move a message in and out of Junk from mail client, and check your mail and rspamd logs. You should a message in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/var/log/rspamd/rspamd.log&lt;/span&gt; whenever a message is retrained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;74.151785714286&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;dkim&quot;&gt;DKIM: Validation for Your Outgoing Mail&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dkim.org&quot;&gt;DKIM&lt;/a&gt;, or DomainKeys Identified Mail, is a standard by which mail servers can cryptographically verify that an email claiming to originate from a given domain did indeed originate from a server within that domain's control. The general idea is that the sender's mail server signs outgoing messages with a private key, and the recipient's mail server retrieves the public key from a TXT record hosted in the sender's DNS zone to verify the authenticity of the message. Using DKIM, a recipient can be certain that a message really did come from the sender's authorized mail server, and that it wasn't tampered with in transit.
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, rspamd provides &lt;a href=&quot;https://rspamd.com/doc/modules/dkim_signing.html&quot;&gt;built-in support for DKIM signing&lt;/a&gt; using the postfix milter we already configured in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#rspamd&quot;&gt;previous section&lt;/a&gt;. That means there's no additional software to configure! All you need to do is generate your private key, and create a DKIM record containing your public key in DNS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall the following file we created in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#rspamd&quot;&gt;rspamd section&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/rspamd/local.d/dkim_signing.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
path = &quot;/var/db/rspamd/dkim/$domain.$selector.key&quot;;
selector = &quot;dkim&quot;;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;$domain&lt;/span&gt; variable does what you'd expect: an outgoing email from an &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;@example.com&lt;/span&gt; email address will be signed using the corresponding &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;example.com&lt;/span&gt; private key file. The &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;$selector&lt;/span&gt; variable bears further explanation: The DKIM specification allows you to use multiple keys for a single domain, and distinguish between them using a &lt;em&gt;selector&lt;/em&gt; value in the DKIM header of the message. In our case, we'll keep it simple and just use a single selector called &quot;dkim&quot; for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can generate a DKIM keypair using the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;rspamadm&lt;/span&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
rspamadm dkim_keygen -k /var/db/rspamd/dkim/example.com.dkim.key -b 2048 -s dkim -d example.com
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will save a private key file for &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;example.com&lt;/span&gt; in rspamd's DKIM directory, and print a DNS record for the DKIM public key to standard output. You should see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
dkim._domainkey IN TXT ( &quot;v=DKIM1; k=rsa; &quot;
  &quot;p=MIIBIjANBgkqhkiG9w0BAQEFAAOCAQ8AMIIBCgKCAQEAzGdxkFW0tIDYdNrGyj/J2Hff7N/9BEWE2qxMw6PBW5FhJRullZT9WNZOVrrXk1TsiBHRq8YQrSS1TfLbNV9PE7sE0vGx0eLgkiqnqLMwTy5Y9+jEbiNrddNR6v+TGHuMckYJO3JMjiROhMi/86Lv6P/rv2R/lxFldCeYQxa41/8LH+b3ZXWTLYRM6y2/2UpGz/wtknvA+DtO0rn+Y&quot;
  &quot;uLuPrh+ftzmJb6i3g01XFgAO8ZzMLMdO/k7UJDX/Q6himKxVv2t3vSvS1MGqiWThXiU3WxhQED0zZUlkC5Lfx4BCo1h0v7fwZeMdu2NPOzlDBMDq5HRYgbwuFXTAmxSM7WRqQIDAQAB&quot;
) ;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are running your own DNS server, you can just paste that directly into your zone file. If you are using a DNS provider's web interface, there's a small caveat: the 2048-bit public key is too large to fit in a single DNS record. In a zone file, the parenthetical syntax above causes your DNS server to split the key into separate records. When you add it to your provder's web interface, you'll need to create a TXT record at &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;dkim._domainkey.example.com&lt;/span&gt; and generate the value by contatenating all three lines together (removing the quotes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you should have both SPF and DKIM properly configured. However, you haven't informed other mail servers what to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; if either of those safeguards should fail. That's where &lt;a href=&quot;https://dmarc.org&quot;&gt;DMARC&lt;/a&gt; comes in. DMARC uses a special DNS record to declare how other mail servers should treat mail from your domain when validations fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a TXT record at &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;_dmarc.example.com&lt;/span&gt; like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/usr/local/etc/named/master/example.com.db&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
_dmarc  IN  TXT  &quot;v=DMARC1; p=reject; adkim=r; aspf=r; sp=reject&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;p=reject&lt;/span&gt; field indicates that any emails from our domain which do not pass SPF and DKIM checks should be assumed to be spam and rejected. The &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;adkim=r&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;aspf=r&lt;/span&gt; fields indicate that we are using &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;relaxed&lt;/span&gt; validation, which is the default. Finally, the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;sp=reject&lt;/span&gt; field indicates that this policy should apply to all subdomains of &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;example.com&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section readability=&quot;28.588824020017&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;testing-dkim&quot;&gt;Testing DKIM, DMARC, and SPF&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your public key and DMARC records are in DNS, you're ready to test DKIM signing. You can check whether your records have propagated using &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;dig&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
dig +short TXT dkim._domainkey.example.com

dig +short TXT _dmarc.example.com

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of online tools you can use to test whether or not DKIM signing is working for your domain. My favorite is &lt;a href=&quot;http://dkimvalidator.com&quot;&gt;DKIMValidator.com&lt;/a&gt;. The site provides you a randomized email address. Simply send a test email from your mail server to the provided email address, wait a few seconds, and hit &quot;View Results.&quot; You will be presented with a report describing whether or not DKIM and SPF validation passed for your domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also test DKIM, DMARC, and SPF by sending a test email to a GMail account. In your GMail inbox, click the arrow next to the reply button and choose &quot;Show Original.&quot; You will be presented with a table containing pass/fail results for SPF, DKIM, and DMARC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any of the validations fail, check the message headers for clues, as well as your rspamd and mail logs for errors. If they all passed, then congratulations—your mail server is more professionally configured than half the mail I get from &quot;real&quot; companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;71.155975252361&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;sieve&quot;&gt;Sieve: Scripting Your Mailbox&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once of the best things about running your own mail server is being able to script your inbox. Instead of creating filters using a kludgy synax through a web interface, you can literally write programs to determine how to sort your mail. With sieve, regular expressions, if/else control structures, and full message metadata (including headers) are at your disposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/#dovecot&quot;&gt;the Dovecot section&lt;/a&gt; that sieve scripts live in the &lt;em&gt;virtual home directory&lt;/em&gt; of each IMAP user. Dovecot's sieve functionality allows a user to have multiple sieve scripts stored on the server, but only one of them can be &quot;active&quot; at any given time. In our configuration, the active sieve script for the user &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;alphonsus&lt;/span&gt; would be located at &lt;span class=&quot;monospace break-word&quot;&gt;/var/mail/vhosts/example.com/alphonsus/.dovecot.sieve&lt;/span&gt;. The &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;.dovecot.sieve&lt;/span&gt; file should be a symlink to a script in the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;sieve&lt;/span&gt; directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;root@awesomebox:/var/mail/vhosts/example.com/alphonsus # ls -l&lt;/strong&gt;
total 12
lrwxr-xr-x  1 vmail  vmail   18 Mar  4 07:35 .dovecot.sieve@ -&amp;gt; sieve/my_cool_script.sieve
-rw-rw-r--  1 vmail  vmail  472 Mar  4 07:38 .dovecot.svbin
drwx------  4 vmail  vmail  512 Aug 15 04:45 mdbox/
drwxrwxr-x  2 vmail  vmail  512 Mar  4 07:35 sieve/
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use a mail client with ManageSieve support (like KMail), these details are handled for you automatically. You can also use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/philpennock/sieve-connect&quot;&gt;sieve-connect&lt;/a&gt;, a command-line ManageSieve client. I rarely modify my sieve script, so when I need to make a change I just SSH to my server and edit it in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;vim&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's make a basic sieve script. Open up a root shell and navigate to your IMAP user's virtual home directory under &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/var/mail/vhosts&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /var/mail/vhosts/example.com/user
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;sieve&lt;/span&gt; directory if it doesn't already exist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
mkdir sieve
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, create a sieve script. You can name this file whatever you like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
vim sieve/my_awesome_script.sieve
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you're ready to write your script. You can check out some example sieve scripts on the Dovecot wiki &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki2.dovecot.org/Pigeonhole/Sieve/Examples&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We'll keep it simple for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/var/mail/vhosts/example.com/user/sieve/my_awesome_script.sieve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
require [&quot;regex&quot;, &quot;fileinto&quot;, &quot;imap4flags&quot;];


if allof (address :is &quot;from&quot; &quot;root@awesomebox.example.com&quot;, header :contains &quot;subject&quot; &quot;run output&quot;) {
  fileinto &quot;Logs&quot;;
  stop;
}


if anyof (address :is         &quot;from&quot; &quot;auto-confirm@amazon.com&quot;,
    address :is :domain &quot;from&quot; &quot;earthfare.com&quot;) {
  fileinto &quot;Shopping&quot;;
  stop;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't believe the sieve script will create any new IMAP folders for you, so be sure to create any folders you need in your mail client first. Now you need to create a symlink so Dovecot knows that this is your &quot;active&quot; script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
ln -s sieve/my_awesome_script.sieve .dovecot.sieve
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your script actually compiles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
sievec .dovecot.sieve
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, make sure everything is still owned by the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;vmail&lt;/span&gt; user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
chown -R vmail:vmail .dovecot.sieve .dovecot.svbin sieve
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check your mail log the next time you receive an email to verify that Dovecot didn't have any trouble executing your script. You can get as convoluted as you want with sieve—I've seen some cool setups where people call external shell scripts when certain emails are receieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;44.978345363687&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you made it this far, you should have a pretty decent personal email server. I've been hosting my family's email on a VPS with this setup for a year or so with great results. I've yet to have a spammer make it past rspamd, and sync and search work great with all of our iDevices. Also, despite the warnings of various online naysayers, I've never had an issue with others not receieving my mail, and tech recruiters, for better or worse, seem to have no trouble reaching my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I didn't cover in this guide was a webmail setup—mostly because I've never felt the need for one. Mutt, Mail.app, and the iOS mail client have served me quite well, and I honestly hate dealing with the additional attack vector of some PHP/Ruby-off-the-Rails web application. However, if that's something you need, I have heard good things about &lt;a href=&quot;https://roundcube.net&quot;&gt;Roundcube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, and I can't stress this enough, &lt;strong&gt;back up your mail directory regularly!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No doubt, it's a lot of work to get a mail server up and running. But once you get it working, it's very set-and-forget. Just keep your system updated, rotate your SSL certificates before they expire, and use good DevOps practices, and it will serve you well as long as you keep paying your hosting provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure many will argue that this is too much work for too little gain, because the NSA can probably crack all our encryption, most mail goes through GMail anyway, tons of email is still plain text, etc. However, my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/self-hosting-guide&quot;&gt;reasons for self-hosting things&lt;/a&gt; are more philosophical than technical. The net neutrality debate is moot if all of our online communication is controlled by a handful of monolothic advertising companies. The internet's greatest strength has always been in the free exchange of ideas and information. Let's make sure it stays that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 19:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>starbugs</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hospitals pledge to fight admin price transparency plan in court</title>
<link>https://www.healthcaredive.com/news/hospitals-pledge-to-fight-trump-admin-price-transparency-plan-in-court/567474/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.healthcaredive.com/news/hospitals-pledge-to-fight-trump-admin-price-transparency-plan-in-court/567474/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hospitals were swift to condemn the Trump administration's plans to force secret negotiated rates with payers out into the open, vowing to challenge the policy in court. Insurers also rebuked the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.healthcaredive.com/news/hospitals-and-now-insurers-to-reveal-secret-rates-under-latest-trump-ad/567421/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;plan announced Friday&lt;/a&gt; that also puts the squeeze on payers to unveil prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experts told Healthcare Dive the government clearly foresaw a legal challenge from the industry, but questioned whether its authority is adequate to force hospitals and insurers to publicly disclose their rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Friday afternoon press conference at the White House, President Donald Trump said patients have &quot;been getting ripped off for years&quot; and HHS Secretary Alex Azar called the requirements a &quot;revolutionary&quot; change for the industry.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But the event also touched on the difficult road ahead. Rick Shultz, chief medical officer at Texas Free Market Surgery, told reporters more price transparency will fuel innovation in the sector, but won't be welcome. &quot;This is going to be a fight. This is very disruptive,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under a new proposed rule, insurers would be required to make public the negotiated rates for in-network providers and out-of-network services as well as make real-time cost-sharing information easily available to members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A separate hospital payment final rule carries forward a previously announced plan to force hospitals to reveal negotiated rates. They will be required to share information about gross charges, payer-specific rates, minimum and maximum negotiated charges and the amount the hospital is willing to accept in cash from a patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quartet of hospital groups, including the American Hospital Association and Federation of American Hospitals, said in a statement they will be joining member hospitals to file a lawsuit charging that the price transparency rules exceed the administration's authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Instead of helping patients know their out-of-pocket costs, this rule will introduce widespread confusion, accelerate anticompetitive behavior among health insurers, and stymie innovations in value-based care delivery,&quot; they wrote. &quot;America's hospitals and health systems have repeatedly urged CMS to work with hospitals, doctors, insurers, patients, and other stakeholders to identify solutions to provide patients with the information they need to make informed health care decisions and know what their expected out-of-pocket costs will be.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Payer lobbies were also not pleased. They focused on the most controversial part of the plan — public posting of negotiated rates with providers. America's Health Insurance Plans argued the new rules will confuse patients, not empower them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blue Cross Blue Shield Association and the Alliance of Community Health Plans sent out similar views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Unfortunately, the rules the administration released today will not help consumers better understand what health services will cost them and may not advance the broader goal of lowering health care costs,&quot; BCBSA CEO Scott Serota said in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcbs.com/press-releases/blue-cross-blue-shield-association-statement-the-administrations-health-care-cost&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No payer group has explicitly and publicly said it will sue over the rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;standard-heading&quot;&gt;Question of authority&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Administration officials point to a section in the Public Health Service Act and claim it gives them authority to force standard charges — which they argue include negotiated rates — out into the open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Bulleit, a partner at Ropes and Gray, told Healthcare Dive the administration is clearly anticipating a fight as officials have devoted many pages of the final rule to explain its legal authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I am dubious that this gives them authority to define that term [standard charges] as broadly as that,&quot; Bulleit said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interesting wrinkle, the pertinent section in the Public Health Service Act was added by the Affordable Care Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;So if the administration is successful in its lawsuit to overturn the ACA, their authority for this rule would evaporate,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some argue the release of rates would violate the First Amendment, making the rules unconstitutional. But attorney Jonathan Emord, president of Emord and Associates, disagrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Like nutrient content, alcohol content and manufacturing location information, negotiated rate information is factual data the disclosure of which supports more fully informed consumer choice,&quot; he told Healthcare Dive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;standard-heading&quot;&gt;Economists weigh in&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forcing rates into the open may shame some providers into lowering their prices, but the reality is that many hospitals have monopoly power in their markets. Transparency is not going to work where there is no competition, Emily Gee, a health economist at the left-leaning Center for American Progress, told Healthcare Dive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The rule is a gesture in the right direction, but transparency needs to be accompanied by much stronger policies in order to rein in hospital costs,&quot; Gee said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In markets with limited competition, the data could promote &quot;tacit collusion,&quot; Chris Garmon, a former economist for the Federal Trade Commission, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.healthcaredive.com/news/price-transparency-proposals-raise-thorny-questions/556356/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;previously told Healthcare Dive&lt;/a&gt;. Garmon is now a professor at the University of Missouri-Kansas City.​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;For instance, it could allow one provider to follow and match the prices of the other provider (like two gas stations across the street from one another who face no other competition),&quot; Garmon said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at an industry event in D.C. over the weekend, Molly Smith, vice president of coverage and state issues forum for AHA, also cited her concerns about the risk of rising prices due to payer-provider collusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I think the government has very much underestimated the very real challenges that exist,&quot; she said during U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report's annual Healthcare of Tomorrow conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rebecca Pifer contributed reporting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 16:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>howard941</dc:creator>
<og:title>Hospitals pledge to fight Trump admin price transparency plan in court</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.healthcaredive.com/news/hospitals-pledge-to-fight-trump-admin-price-transparency-plan-in-court/567474/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.healthcaredive.com/user_media/cache/28/c5/28c5ed4a98cb6b453ffeb7a8fb755c1b.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>In a Friday afternoon press conference, President Donald Trump said patients have &quot;been getting ripped off for years&quot; and HHS Secretary Alex Azar said the requirements are a &quot;revolutionary&quot; change for the industry.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.healthcaredive.com/news/hospitals-pledge-to-fight-trump-admin-price-transparency-plan-in-court/567474/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Valve confirm Half-Life: Alyx, a VR game being revealed on Thursday</title>
<link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2019/11/19/valve-confirm-half-life-alyx-a-vr-game-being-revealed-on-thursday/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2019/11/19/valve-confirm-half-life-alyx-a-vr-game-being-revealed-on-thursday/</guid>
<description>&lt;header&gt;&lt;nav class=&quot;breadcrumb&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-grid count-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-lightboxed=&quot;false&quot; data-original=&quot;https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images/2019/11/alyx-vance.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images/2019/11/alyx-vance.jpg/RPSS/resize/760x-1/format/jpg/quality/90&quot; title=&quot;This screen is not from Half-Life: Alyx, obvs.&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-758019&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;Goodness me, Valve actually are making a new Half-Life game. Following the weekend’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2019/11/18/rumour-valve-will-announce-vr-only-half-life-alyx-on-december-12th/&quot;&gt;leaky rumours&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game/half-life-alyx/&quot;&gt;Half-Life: Alyx&lt;/a&gt;, Valve have confirmed yup, it actually is real. They actually are making a new Half-Life, and it actually is for VR. They call Half-Life: Alyx “our flagship VR game” but aren’t saying much of anything about what it is until an unveiling on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Valve don’t have any more to say, now the game’s confirmed I would now place more faith in details from the leak, which looked like a transcript of a video chat with The Game Awards host Geoff Keighley. In it, Keighley asked about it being VR-only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, I mean we would love to be delivering a version of this that you could play with a mouse and a keyboard, but like as we said, it began as an exploration of VR,” Valve responded. So it sounds a game where touch-feely hands-on gogged-up Half-Living is the point. If the leak was real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would probably expect Valve’s own reveal at 6pm on Thursday then, if I’m trusting the leak, more at The Game Awards on December 12th (well, 1:30am on the 13th for us).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valve haven’t released even a Quarter-Life since Half-Life 2: Episode Two in October 2007. We’ve still no whiff of an Episode 3 or a Half-Life 3, though a former Valve writer may have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2017/08/25/half-life-2-episode-3-plot/&quot;&gt;given away the once-planned plot&lt;/a&gt; and fans have happily picked up the slack with &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/jam/epistle-3-jam&quot;&gt;games based on that&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2017/02/21/half-life-2-episode-3-creator-reflects-on-reception-one-year-after-release/&quot;&gt;wild flights of fancy&lt;/a&gt;. Yeah yeah, Half-Life’s grand and all and I’d give an HL3 a go, but I adore the current world where Valve’s flagship series has been taken over by fans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 15:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>atemerev</dc:creator>
<og:title>Valve confirm Half-Life: Alyx, a VR game being revealed on Thursday</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2019/11/19/valve-confirm-half-life-alyx-a-vr-game-being-revealed-on-thursday/</og:url>
<og:image>https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images/2019/11/alyx-vance.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2019/11/19/valve-confirm-half-life-alyx-a-vr-game-being-revealed-on-thursday/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alan Moore on superhero culture</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/newsbeat-50473092</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/newsbeat-50473092</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Watchmen film&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/E316/production/_109743185_watchmen.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Alamy&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The graphic novel series has been made into a film
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Is it embarrassing for adults to like superheroes?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Alan Moore - creator of the Watchmen series and widely considered one of the greatest comic book writers - it is. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He says superheroes are perfectly fine for 12 or 13-year-olds but adults should think again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I think the impact of superheroes on popular culture is both tremendously embarrassing and not a little worrying,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alan wrote Watchmen in 1986. The series depicts an alternate history where superheroes emerged in the 1940s and 1960s and their presence changed the course of history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He believes the characters are &quot;perfectly suited&quot; to the imaginations of a younger audience - but now, they serve a &quot;different function, and are fulfilling different needs&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The writer claims adults enjoy superhero films because they don't wish to leave their &quot;relatively reassuring childhoods&quot; behind, or move into the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Alan Moore also wrote V for Vendetta
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alanmooreworld.blogspot.com/2019/11/moore-on-jerusalem-eternalism-anarchy.html&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;The comments&lt;/a&gt; were made in a 2017 interview with Brazilian newspaper Folha de São Paulo - the full details of which have only just been released.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He adds the popularity of the genre among adults suggests a &quot;kind of deliberate, self-imposed state of emotional arrest&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And his criticism extends to creators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He says superheroes are written and drawn by people who've never stood up for their own rights against the companies that employ them - saying they appear &quot;to be largely employed as cowardice compensators&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He claims the lack of diversity in the comic book world suggests books and iconic characters are &quot;still very much white supremacist dreams of the master race&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But there was praise from Marvel fans earlier this year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-49070232&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;with the announcement&lt;/a&gt; that the next stage of the Marvel Cinematic Universe will feature its first deaf superhero, its first Asian-American superhero and an openly gay superhero.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Debate around the genre is pretty hot right now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Martin Scorsese is another critic of superhero films
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.empireonline.com/movies/features/irishman-week-martin-scorsese-interview/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;an interview&lt;/a&gt; with Empire, film director Martin Scorsese was asked about Marvel movies - and he argued they should be considered something other than cinema. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I don't see them,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I tried, you know? But that's not cinema. Honestly, the closest I can think of them, as well made as they are, with actors doing the best they can under the circumstances, is theme parks. It isn't the cinema of human beings trying to convey emotional, psychological experiences to another human being.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Follow Newsbeat on &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bbcnewsbeat/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;, &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/bbcnewsbeat/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;, &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BBCNewsbeat&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; and &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCe1Ef-K5jpnRsmVY5hCBhOw&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Listen to Newsbeat &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/live:bbc_radio_one&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; at 12:45 and 17:45 weekdays - or listen back &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006wkry/episodes/player&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 15:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cmsefton</dc:creator>
<og:title>'Modern superhero culture is embarrassing'</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>One of the greatest comic book writers says it's embarrassing for adults to like superheroes.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/newsbeat-50473092</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/E316/production/_109743185_watchmen.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/newsbeat-50473092</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;Google Stadia is not a product that exists because people want it&quot;</title>
<link>https://threader.app/thread/1196557401710837762</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://threader.app/thread/1196557401710837762</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;thread-head&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pic-user d-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://threader.app/@mcclure111&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;post-img-user&quot; class=&quot;users-thread&quot; src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/852519442047225857/juzc1JeR_400x400.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot; id=&quot;thread-post-start&quot;&gt;A long time ago— like 15 years ago— I worked at Sun Microsystems. The company was nearly dead at the time (it died a couple years later) because they didn't make anything that anyone wanted to buy anymore. So they had a lot of strange ideas about how they'd make their comeback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I heard a lot of highups there talk at the time about &quot;what Sun is going to be about over the next 10 years&quot;. They all seemed to have different ideas what that was. But the most common thing I heard was an idea they called &quot;Utility Computing&quot;, that only seemed to exist within Sun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;They thought in the future no one would own a &quot;computer&quot;. Instead, your computer would exist &quot;in the cloud&quot; (though that word didn't exist yet). ISP NOCs would have big megacomputers, and you'd just have a screen that would connect to the nearest NOC, and it would stream to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;So you'd have &quot;your&quot; computer desktop, but it wouldn't be a real computer running its own OS. It would just be a user account on some server somewhere that stored your icons and your data, and your programs would all run on the server and you'd pay a monthly bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Sun believed people would do this because, if people did this, it would create business for the big-iron servers Sun made at the time, &amp;amp; this way Sun would not go bankrupt. They didn't really have a user story. They thought users would use Solaris. Nobody used Solaris, even then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;So this never caught on as a product. But the thing is, they *built* this. It *existed*. It *worked*.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I went to work at Sun, there were no desktop computers. Instead every desk had a &quot;Sunblade&quot; on it. It looked like a Nintendo Wii (though this was years before the Wii). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Every Sunblade had a monitor and a keyboard plugged in, and a slot on the front, like for a credit card. Everybody who worked at Sun had a card clipped to our jeans— the same card we used to unlock the doors to the building. And we'd stick the card in. And there was our desktop. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;At the end of the day, you'd pull the card out and go home. And the next day you'd come back and put the card in, and there were all your programs, just like you'd left them— even if the SunRay you put your card in wasn't the same one you were using yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Because nothing ran on the SunRay, it was just streaming window instructions from a big server in the center of the building. There was even some way or other to go home and connect from your computer, and you could be running your SunRay screen at home, with just a little delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;This was *incredible*, actually. It was *magic*. Sometimes you'd want to go to someone's office and ask for help, and if they said &quot;well, can you show me?&quot; you could just stick your card in their SunRay and— and instantly, there's your computer! It followed you upstairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The way you'd do that in a modern workspace is everyone would have a MacBook, and when you went upstairs you'd carry your MacBook, but like in that awkward way where it's 2 inches open so it doesn't go to sleep? And try not to walk into anyone else carrying a laptop the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Of course, there were problems. You couldn't do some things you'd expect to be able to do on a computer, like run a screensaver, cuz that would suck up the CPU. It only really worked for like… writing documents and stuff. Low animation stuff. Oh, and you had to run Solaris. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;And, of course, &quot;run Solaris&quot; just killed the whole thing instantly, so instantly it baffles me how they didn't stop the project on day one. In 2004 nobody could use Linux except programmers— you struggled to run office suites on Linux— and Solaris was one step harder than Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Still, they didn't kill this obviously-unworkable project, they BUILT it, whether anyone wanted it or not, and they replaced all their own computers with it, and I've never heard of anyone other than Sun *using* it. But for one summer I got to use this awesome, alien-future tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Here's why this is interesting to me: Why did the Sunray fail?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think the answer's obvious. Because they designed the product backward. They didn't think &quot;what do people want?&quot;, or even go Apple and think &quot;what COULD people want, if we showed them why they wanted it?&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Sun started with: &quot;What can we build?&quot; &quot;What would be good for US, if people wanted it?&quot;. And then assumed they'd figure out a way to work backwards, somehow, into convincing people they wanted it &amp;amp; wanted to pay monthly for it &amp;amp; pay an expensive sysadmin &amp;amp; use a 3-button mouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;So obviously I'm not really thinking about the Sunray here. I'm thinking about Google Stadia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Stadia is not a product that exists because people want it. I'm not sure why it exists. But it seems to exist because it *could*. Google knew how to make it, &amp;amp; it would be a good thing for Google if people wanted it, so they just *made* it &amp;amp; assumed the reasons why would follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Stadia is &quot;utility computing&quot; for games, but they don't have to call it that, because we have words like &quot;in the cloud&quot; and &quot;streaming&quot;. It's a lot like the Sunray system, really. But if I try to compare Sunray to Stadia, I notice something: *The Sunray actually solved problems*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The Sunray solved *A* problem. It had things it did better than the alternatives that existed at the time. It was made with *A* user in mind, even if that user (Sun Microsystems employees) were the same people making the Sunray. There was *someone*— me, in 2004— it was great for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I do not know if I can say the same about Stadia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I think about Stadia, I *want* to be afraid. I want to see it as one spike (with Apple Arcade) of an encroaching change that ends general computing and brings game creation under a publisher system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I am finding it hard to be afraid of Stadia. The design thinking is just too backward. Every single step seems to be &quot;what can we build&quot; &quot;what could we license&quot; and not &quot;what does someone want&quot;. Someone was being incentivized based on &quot;did we ship&quot; and not &quot;did anyone use it&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;If I were trying to build Stadia, I'd start by asking what content people are playing on it. Stadia has limitations (latency), so I'd design content where those limitations don't matter, but the advantages of Stadia (central servers) stand out. Highly social casual games maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Say you don't stream *everything*— you move UI to a simple javascript-like layer so it feels responsive (that's what the SunBlade did)— and make games nongamers with cheap Android phones and old Macbooks play. Farmville but everyone's farm is next to yours visible at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Stadia is doing the opposite of that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They pitched to the high-end hardcore gamer crowd, pixel shaders and AAA content. The exact people most likely to complain about latency. And they aren't obviously cheaper or better looking than the existing products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Looking at the launch lineup, I see no exclusives. I see nothing specifically designed for Stadia (to take advantage of cloud possibilities). I see nothing that's hot in streaming RN (to take advantage of YouTube). I do see two fighting games and two rhythm games (latency hell!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Maybe this is a tech demo that one day they'll find a way to pivot into a serious product. But I think this fails for the same reason the Sunblade fails. Not because the tech was bad. But because Google doesn't know what the tech is for. Bad institutional thinking is hard to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;For Stadia to be &quot;scary&quot; to me as a game developer— &quot;scary&quot; meaning &quot;I expect I'll be locked into a disadvantageous contract just to make cheap indie games, because it ate the market while no one was paying attention&quot;— Google will have to fundamentally change the way they design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Hm, OK. So this looks like something I'd play if it was on the PS4. I don't see any Stadia features tho. Previous game by this developer was a Unreal game &amp;amp; probably so is this, so it probably *could* run on the PS4 if &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%24GOOG&quot; title=&quot;$GOOG&quot; class=&quot;tweet-url cashtag&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;$GOOG&lt;/a&gt; wasn't paying for exclusivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I'm making VR games, for a living, right now. That's another tech that might turn out to be a white elephant nobody wants. The approach I'm taking, with my current game and the one I want to make after it, is *don't make a game for VR unless that game could ONLY exist in VR*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;You want people to use a thing? *Show them why they need it!* Show them what they can do with your technology that they *can't* do without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Note: I've just realized in this thread I use &quot;Sunray&quot; and &quot;Sunblade&quot; kind of interchangeably. The product I was talking about was the Sunray. Sunblade was just a line of sparc desktops. I got confused. Maybe this is evidence their branding was not as clear as it could have been?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=mcclure111&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@mcclure111&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;share-info&quot;&gt;Share this thread&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bookmark-info&quot;&gt;Bookmark&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;____&lt;br/&gt;Tip: mention &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=threader_app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; id=&quot;tip-threader&quot;&gt;@threader_app&lt;/a&gt; on a Twitter thread with the keyword “compile” to get a link to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy Threader? &lt;a href=&quot;https://threader.app/thread/1196557401710837762#&quot; data-target=&quot;#modalsignup&quot; id=&quot;popsignup&quot;&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Threader is an independent project created by only two developers. The site gets 500,000+ visits a month and our iOS Twitter client was featured as an &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/story/id1367658799&quot;&gt;App of the Day&lt;/a&gt; by Apple. Running this space is expensive and time consuming. If you find Threader useful, please consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://threader.app/faq/how-to-support-threader&quot;&gt;supporting us&lt;/a&gt; to make it a sustainable project.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;img id=&quot;checkblock&quot; src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/926857336924397568/AB4-K0OD_mini.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 14:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>necrodome</dc:creator>
<og:title>A thread written by @mcclure111</og:title>
<og:image>https://s3.amazonaws.com/bucketmany/threadercovers/m2MevecuuGQj7-6jTCp1L7geCopFlWzoSleV3H0oWb-wSwB7faWs7onf_SNA.png</og:image>
<og:description>A long time ago— like 15 years ago— I worked at Sun Microsystems. The company was nearly dead at the time (it died a couple years later) because they didn't make anything that anyone wanted to buy anymore. So they had a lot of strange ideas about how they'd make their comeback.</og:description>
<og:url>https://threader.app/thread/1196557401710837762</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://threader.app/thread/1196557401710837762</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>TikTok hits 1.5B downloads, outperforming Instagram</title>
<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/tiktok-hits-15-billion-downloads-outperforming-instagram-2019-11</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.businessinsider.com/tiktok-hits-15-billion-downloads-outperforming-instagram-2019-11</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/tiktok-hits-15-billion-downloads-outperforming-instagram-2019-11&quot;&gt;https://www.businessinsider.com/tiktok-hits-15-billion-downloads-outperforming-instagram-2019-11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21572911&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21572911&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 262&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 287&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 14:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>elorant</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://www.businessinsider.com/tiktok-hits-15-billion-downloads-outperforming-instagram-2019-11</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We ‘may’ have discovered a potential remedy for tinnitus</title>
<link>https://www.linkedin.com/content-guest/article/we-may-have-discovered-potential-remedy-tinnitus-spencer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.linkedin.com/content-guest/article/we-may-have-discovered-potential-remedy-tinnitus-spencer</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was studying the effectiveness of a head-mounted device to stop motion sickness in driverless cars when something unexpected happened. One of the participants in my experiment reported that her tinnitus had dramatically improved, she scored 100% for motion sickness susceptibility so was of interest even with the additional confounding effect of tinnitus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both motion sickness and tinnitus are linked to hearing and the inner ear, so it’s not uncommon for people who suffer from one condition to suffer from the other. Motion sickness happens when there is a mismatch between what the eyes are telling the brain and what the inner ears sense as motion (1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a car, this means that if you look down at a phone, a newspaper or a stationary object, your eyes are telling your brain that you’re not moving. But your vestibular system (the organs of balance in your ear) are telling your brain that you are moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the reason that having a good view of the road ahead and looking at the horizon to anticipate future motion prevents sickness. What your eyes see matches what you sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The head-mounted vibrating device I was investigating lightly vibrates just behind your ear. In the lab, it is known that this method reduces motion sickness (2). I wanted to know if it worked on real roads in driverless cars when people are facing forwards and backwards using a convenient wearable device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know from an earlier experiment that facing backwards in a driverless car causes a lot of motion sickness – more than trains – and may limit the number of people who use driverless cars with seats that face in this direction (3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the experiment, we recruited 24 volunteers all of whom were highly susceptible to motion sickness. The device we asked them to wear has four vibration levels. Half the volunteers (the control group) had the device set to the lowest vibration (level one), and half had it set to level three (the experimental group). Level 3 is the effective vibration level for motion sickness reduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test lasted about 15 minutes with people getting sick after only six minutes while being driven around an urban route at normal speeds. The vehicle we used was a modified minivan with seats that faced towards the rear window, like many future driverless vehicle concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The volunteers completed a search-and-find puzzle to make sure that they all looked down and not out the windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The device did, indeed, help those who became sick during the experiment. The extra vibrations on level three meant that people took nearly twice as long to become sick under the same conditions as the control group and commented that they recovered quickly when on straight roads. This means that for people who are highly susceptible to motion sickness, a journey could be 12 minutes long with the device, compared with six minutes without the device, before the person felt nauseous. The motion sickness findings will be detailed in a future scientific journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, one of our volunteers has tinnitus. She described the condition as constantly hearing a cricket chirrup. For her, the condition is a torment, especially when she is at home and it is quiet. For a tinnitus sufferer there is often no quiet time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beaming smile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I applied the vibration device to the volunteer’s head and set it to level three. After the initial surprise of the vibration, she immediately noticed that her tinnitus had improved. Her beaming smile was something to behold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over many years, she had seen several doctors and specialists about her condition, but with no real progress. I don’t know why the device had this effect, only that it vibrates the inner ear, important for motion sickness and tinnitus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have since offered the device to other tinnitus sufferers (image below). They all have a similar smile. Some took the device home to use in the quiet where tinnitus is perceived at its worst. Afterwards, they don’t want to give the device back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;slate-resizable-image-embed slate-image-embed__resize-full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tinnitus patients relief&quot; data-media-urn=&quot;&quot; data-li-src=&quot;https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/C4D12AQFl6KdiT25sbw/article-inline_image-shrink_1500_2232/0?e=1579737600&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=m6amERA_vywP04KYH9hQsTt7dL6zbCOs1ysL2wy8vXQ&quot; src=&quot;https://:0/&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The device is comfortable to wear. Indeed, after a minute or two, people forget that they are wearing it. It is not noisy; the vibrations are below what we can hear. In fact, I had to ask for people to hand them back from the motion sickness experiment, they didn’t know they were still wearing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this is only anecdotal evidence, it was a real privilege to see those tinnitus sufferers experience some relief from their condition. The device is being developed further for motion sickness, vertigo and tinnitus. It is hoped that this information generates further research by others within the field of hearing / vestibular dysfunction.  I have finished the research for my PhD, this however I feel should be continued with active tinnitus researchers (over to you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For updates please use the following link : &lt;a href=&quot;https://otolithlabs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Subscribe here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/335159616_We_'may'_have_discovered_a_potential_remedy_for_tinnitus_-by_accident&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;ResearchGate&lt;/a&gt; : Spencer Salter, salters@uni.coventry.ac.uk ;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.        Bles W, Bos JE, De Graaf B, Groen E, Wertheim AH. Motion sickness: Only one provocative conflict? Brain Res Bull. 1998;47(5):481–7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.        Bos JE. Less sickness with more motion and/or mental distraction. J Vestib Res Equilib Orientat. 2015;25(1):23–33.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.        Salter S, Diels C, Herriotts P, Kanarachos S, Thake D. Motion sickness in automated vehicles with forward and rearward facing seating orientations. Appl Ergon [Internet]. 2019;78(July 2019):54–61. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apergo.2019.02.001&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33.453154875717&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;ugc-post-bar__published_by&quot;&gt;Published By&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;ugc-post-bar__container&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ugc-post-bar__follow-button&quot; data-tracking-will-navigate=&quot;&quot; data-tracking-control-name=&quot;ugc-post-bar__follow-button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/uas/login?session_redirect=https%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Elinkedin%2Ecom%2Fpulse%2Fwe-may-have-discovered-potential-remedy-tinnitus-spencer&amp;amp;trk=ugc-post-bar__follow-button&quot;&gt;Follow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ugc-post-bar__share-text&quot;&gt;Anyone suffer from Tinnitus? During my motion sickness research I found that Bone Conducted Vibration (BCV) can improve motion sickness but also Tinnitus. I have finished the PhD, the Tinnitus finding needs more research by those in the field. #tinnitus #hearing #motionsickness #driverlesscars #motionsickness @otolithlabs https://www.researchgate.net/publication/335159616_We_'may'_have_discovered_a_potential_remedy_for_tinnitus_-by_accident&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 13:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DanielBMarkham</dc:creator>
<og:title>We ‘may’ have discovered a potential remedy for tinnitus – by accident.</og:title>
<og:description>I was studying the effectiveness of a head-mounted device to stop motion sickness in driverless cars when something unexpected happened. One of the participants in my experiment reported that her tinnitus had dramatically improved, she scored 100% for motion sickness susceptibility so was of interes</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/C4D12AQEnTq_-3qussA/article-cover_image-shrink_720_1280/0?e=1579737600&amp;v=beta&amp;t=_gsbf-yAziLo0S-ZWRNILPTxBVvu6luRoUHvg0p1WzU</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/we-may-have-discovered-potential-remedy-tinnitus-spencer</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.linkedin.com/content-guest/article/we-may-have-discovered-potential-remedy-tinnitus-spencer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Some users say they&amp;#039;re getting rid of Fitbit because they don&amp;#039;t trust Google</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/17/people-getting-rid-of-fitbits-after-google.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/17/people-getting-rid-of-fitbits-after-google.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;InlineImage-imageEmbed hasBkg&quot; id=&quot;ArticleBody-InlineImage-105796975&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;InlineImage-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitbit Insire HR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd Haselton | CNBC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; readability=&quot;28.494031221304&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Mike Carpenter learned &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=GOOGL&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;'s latest acquisition would be Fitbit, the maker of a device he wore at all hours of the day except in the shower, he left his Fitbit Charge 3 on the table at his office where he was working that day. He, and others like him, haven't picked theirs up since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Nov. 1, Google said would be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/01/google-to-acquire-fitbit-valuing-the-smartwatch-maker-at-about-2point1-billion.html&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;buying Fitbit&lt;/a&gt; for $2.1 billion in hopes of boosting its hardware business getting a foothold in the health space. Google explicitlysaid in the deal announcement that it won't sell their personal or health data. Despite that assurance, some Fitbit users say they don't trust the company, and are shedding the product altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;I'm not only afraid of what they can do with the data currently, but what they can do with it once their AI advances in 10 or 20 years,&quot; Carpenter told CNBC, saying he didn't believe the company's privacy assurances. &quot;Health insurance companies would love to get their hands on that data and their purposes wouldn't be advertising so is that what they are going to do with it? They didn't spend the money to not utilize it in some way.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; readability=&quot;66.900936037441&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trend of people throwing or threatening to throw out their Fitbit devices comes as Google faces a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/13/google-trust-deficit-could-kill-the-companys-cloud-ambitions.html&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;perception problem&lt;/a&gt; that has spanned everyday users and regulators alike. The company has paid data privacy fines in the EU and made recent strides into the stringently regulated healthcare industry, which has caused the public to re-think seemingly harmless tools. Privacy groups this week began &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/13/privacy-consumer-groups-seek-to-block-google-fitbit-deal-citing-antitrust-and-privacy-concerns.html?&amp;amp;amp;qsearchterm=privacy%20group&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;pushing&lt;/a&gt; regulators to block the Fitbit acquisition, which the company originally hoped to close in early 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google didn't respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I only recently got it and now I'm thinking I don't need Google watching literally my every step or my every heart beat,&quot; said Dan Kleinman, who said he is getting rid of his Fitbit Versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people cited Google's 2014 acquisition of Nest Labs, which, at the time consisted of smart home thermostats. Since then, the company has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/business/technology/story/2019-10-24/homebuilders-ditch-google-nest&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;tied&lt;/a&gt; Nest's technology, branding and device accounts to its digital assistant and smart speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;I use a lot of Google services and think they do a decent job, but I'm not interested in adding my health data to their systems,&quot; said Fredrik Matheson who got rid of his Charge 3 after the announcement. &quot;The moment my wife — who is not in tech — heard Google had agreed to acquire Fitbit, she asked me to figure out which watch she should replace her Fitbit with.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter users have been tweeting about their plans to get rid of their devices upon hearing of the acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;With news of the acquisition of your company, I intend to sell my Fitbit &amp;amp; delete my account,&quot; said a tweet from Tanya Janca, which received several hundred retweets and likes. &quot;I like your product and have enjoyed it many years, but I value my privacy much, much more. The aggregation of data possible makes me extremely uncomfortable.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some critical users say they're now considering Fitbit's main rival, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=AAPL&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; Watch, while others longed for the early days of low-tech fitness tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This may push me to pay for an Apple Watch, and jettison my current Fitbit (assuming I even still want a thing strapped to my wrist collecting data about me),&quot; tweeted author Stephen Anderson. &quot;Can we just bring back Pebble?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carpenter and Kleinman later pointed to the news about Google's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/12/google-project-nightingale-hospital-data-deal-raises-privacy-fears.html&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;partnership&lt;/a&gt; with health giant Ascension, saying they were glad they made the decision to leave their Fitbit devices behind. &quot;Google could know which medications I take, and what any medical diagnosis's I have,&quot; Carpenter said. &quot;It makes me feel sick to my stomach.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WATCH NOW:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/video/2019/11/11/googles-struggling-hardware-business.html&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;Why Google keeps selling hardware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 13:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Classicaldj34</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Some Fitbit users say they're getting rid of the devices because they don't trust Google</og:title>
<og:description>Privacy groups this week began pushing regulators to block the Fitbit acquisition, which the company originally hoped to close in early 2020.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/17/people-getting-rid-of-fitbits-after-google.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/105796975-1552676905396screenshot2019-03-15at3.03.54pm.png?v=1552677087</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/17/people-getting-rid-of-fitbits-after-google.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>40% of multinational profits are shifted to tax havens each year</title>
<link>https://missingprofits.world/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://missingprofits.world/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Multinational firms shift profits to tax havens to reduce their global tax bills. Take the example of Google: In 2017, Google Alphabet reported $23 billion in revenue in Bermuda, a small island in the Atlantic where the corporate income tax rate is zero. Globally, about $650 billion in profits are shifted to such tax havens by multinational from all countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can explore the map to see which countries attract and lose profits in this shell game. The map covers 86 countries that constitute 92% of global economic activity and more than 70% of World population. By clicking on each country you can see the amount of profits shifted to tax havens and to which havens the profits were shifted. You can also see the implied loss of corporate income tax revenue. Some countries are marked in green; these are tax havens. For the tax havens we report how much profits they attract from high-tax countries and what the effective corporate income tax rate is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The loss of profit is the highest for the (non-haven) European Union countries. U.S. multinationals shift comparatively more profits (about 60% of their foreign profits) than multinationals from other countries (40% for the world on average). The shareholders of U.S. multinationals thus appear to be the main winners from global profit shifting. Moreover, the governments of tax havens derive sizable benefits from this phenomenon: by taxing the large amount of paper profits they attract at low rates (less than 5%), they are able to generate more tax revenue, as a fraction of their national income, than the United States and non-haven European countries that have much higher tax rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, this research would not have been possible, because firms usually do not publicly disclose the countries in which their profits are booked, and national accounts data did not make it possible to study multinational corporations separately from other firms. But in recent years, the statistical institutes of most of the world’s developed countries (including the key tax havens) have started releasing new macroeconomic data known as foreign affiliates statistics. These data allow to obtain a comprehensive view of where multinational companies book their profits, and in particular to estimate the amount of profit booked in tax havens globally. To further our understanding of this issue we need more and better data. In particular it would be desirable that all countries publish foreign affiliates statistics, and that these statistics be extended to always include information on taxes paid.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 13:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mopolo</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Frontpage - Economists without borders</og:title>
<og:url>https://missingprofits.world/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://missingprofits.world/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>