<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Assange Indicted Under Espionage Act, Raising First Amendment Issues</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/23/us/politics/assange-indicted-espionage-act-first-amendment.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/23/us/politics/assange-indicted-espionage-act-first-amendment.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;WASHINGTON — Julian Assange, the WikiLeaks leader, has been indicted on 17 counts of violating the Espionage Act for his role in obtaining and publishing secret military and diplomatic documents in 2010, the Justice Department announced on Thursday — a novel case that raises profound First Amendment issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://int.nyt.com/data/documenthelper/1037-julian-assange-espionage-act-indictment/426b4e534ab60553ba6c/optimized/full.pdf#page=1&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new charges&lt;/a&gt; were part of an expanded indictment obtained by the Trump administration that significantly raised the stakes of the legal case against Mr. Assange, who is already fighting extradition proceedings in London based on &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/11/world/europe/julian-assange-wikileaks-ecuador-embassy.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;an earlier hacking-related count&lt;/a&gt; brought by federal prosecutors in Northern Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The case has nothing to do with Russia’s 2016 election interference, when Mr. Assange’s organization published Democratic emails stolen by Russia to help elect President Trump, the case has nothing to do with the election interference. Instead, it focuses on Mr. Assange’s role in the leak, by the former army intelligence analyst Chelsea Manning, of hundreds of thousands of State Department cables and diplomatic files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Justice Department officials did not explain why they decided to charge Mr. Assange under the Espionage Act — a step also debated within the Obama administration but ultimately not taken. Although the indictment established a precedent that deems criminal actions related to obtaining, and in some cases publishing, state secrets, the officials sought to minimize the implications for press freedoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;[&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/11/us/politics/assange-indictment.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Press freedoms and the case against Julian Assange, explained.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;They noted that most of the new charges were related to obtaining the archives of secret documents, as opposed to publishing them. In the counts that deemed the publication of the files a crime, prosecutors focused on a handful of documents revealing the names of people who provided information to the United States in dangerous places like war zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Some say that Assange is a journalist and that he should be immune for prosecution for these actions,” said John Demers, the head of the department’s National Security Division, at a briefing with reporters. “The department takes seriously the role of journalists in our democracy and we thank you for it. It is not and has never been the department’s policy to target them for reporting.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Mr. Assange, he said, was “no journalist.” Mr. Demers accused him of conspiring with Ms. Manning to obtain classified information and said “no responsible actor, journalist or otherwise, would purposefully publish the names of individuals he or she knew to be confidential human sources in a war zone, exposing them to the gravest of dangers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Still, the Trump administration’s move could establish a precedent used to criminalize future acts of national security journalism that are essentially the same from a legal perspective, said Jameel Jaffer of the Knight First Amendment Institute at Columbia University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The charges rely almost entirely on conduct that investigative journalists engage in every day,” he said. “The indictment should be understood as a frontal attack on press freedom.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Demers left the press briefing without taking questions, and a Justice Department official who stayed behind to answer questions on the condition that he would not be named would not address any about how most of the basic actions the indictment deemed felonies by Mr. Assange differed in a legally meaningful way from ordinary national-security investigative journalism — working with sources to obtain secret information of news value and publishing that information without the government’s permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Notably, The New York Times, among many other news organizations, obtained precisely the same archives of documents from WikiLeaks, without authorization from the government — the act that most of the charges addressed. While The Times &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2010/07/26/world/26editors-note.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;did take steps to withhold the names of informant&lt;/a&gt;s in the subset of the files it published, it is not clear how that is legally different from publishing other classified information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Barry J. Pollack, a lawyer for Mr. Assange, said his client was being charged with a crime “for encouraging sources to provide him truthful information and for publishing that information.” That dramatic step, he said, removed the “fig leaf” that the case about his client was only about hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“These unprecedented charges demonstrate the gravity of the threat the criminal prosecution of Julian Assange poses to all journalists in their endeavor to inform the public about actions that have taken by the U.S. government,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-bsn42l&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1dv1kvn&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1t0v8sy etkm6pg0&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-1a74oa6 etkm6pg1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1ihorw etkm6pg2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/15/us/politics/11dc-history1-promo/11dc-history1-videoSixteenByNine3000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Video player loading&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Over the years, the WikiLeaks founder has been embraced by everyone from Lady Gaga to Sean Hannity. But he’s also made enemies along the way. Our video shows how his anti-secrecy agenda has attracted, and repelled, people across the political spectrum.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-cch8ym&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1dv1kvn&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;emkp2hg2 css-1nwzsjy e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Andrew Testa for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For most of American history, it was rare for the government to treat the leaking of its secrets to the news media as a crime. But starting under the Bush administration, the Justice Department began making much more routine use of the Espionage Act to go after officials who provided information to the public through reporters, as opposed to actual spies. The World War I-era law criminalizes the disclosure of potentially damaging national security secrets to someone not authorized to receive them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;On its face, the Espionage Act could also be used to prosecute reporters who publish government secrets. But many legal scholars believe that prosecuting people for acts related to receiving and publishing information would violate the First Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;That notion has never been tested in court, however, because until now the government has never brought such charges. The closest it came was indicting two lobbyists for a pro-Israel group in 2005 who received classified information about American policy toward Iran and passed it on, but that case fell apart after several skeptical pretrial rulings by a judge and the charges were dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Though he is not a conventional journalist, much of what Mr. Assange does at WikiLeaks is difficult to distinguish in a legally meaningful way from what traditional news organizations like The New York Times do: seek and publish information that officials want to be secret, including classified national security matters, and take steps to protect the confidentiality of sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The Obama administration had also weighed charging Mr. Assange, but rejected that step out of fears that it would chill investigative journalism and could be struck down as unconstitutional. A Justice Department official declined to address whether there was any new evidence that had come to light recently or whether the Trump administration had simply decided to take a step the Obama administration had shied away from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The three charges that squarely addressed Mr. Assange’s publication of government secrets were focused on a handful of files that contained the names of people who had provided information to the United States in dangerous places like the Afghanistan and Iraq war zones, and authoritarian states like China, Iran and Syria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The evidence laid out in the indictment against Mr. Assange mapped onto information presented by military prosecutors in the 2013 court-martial trial of Ms. Manning. Prosecutors in her case also alleged that her actions endangered the people whose names were revealed in the documents when Mr. Assange published them, though they presented no evidence that anyone was killed as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A Justice Department official declined to say whether any such evidence now exists, but stressed that prosecutors would only need to prove in court what they say in the indictment: that publication put people in danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Manning was sentenced to 35 years in prison — by far the longest punishment for a leak case in American history. But in one of his last acts in office, former President Barack Obama commuted most of the remainder of her sentence in January 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;She is now back in jail again, after a judge held her in contempt for refusing to testify about her interactions with Mr. Assange before the grand jury in the Eastern District of Virginia that indicted him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Manning’s disclosures via WikiLeaks was one of the most extraordinary leaks in American history — the bulk disclosure of hundreds of thousands of State Department cables that revealed many secret things about the world, dossiers about Guantánamo Bay detainees being held without trial, and logs of significant events in the Afghanistan and Iraq wars that revealed, among other things, that civilian casualties were far higher than official estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;When Ms. Manning’s disclosures initially vaulted Mr. Assange and WikiLeaks to global fame, he was seen as a villain by the Obama administration and the permanent bureaucracy of law-enforcement and national-security officials, but treated as an icon by transparency and antiwar activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;His image later transformed significantly when WikiLeaks published archives of Democratic emails that had been stolen and provided to him by the Russian government as part of its covert efforts to help Mr. Trump win the 2016 election. But the legal case against Mr. Assange has nothing to do with those subsequent events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Assange was indicted in March 2018 in federal court in Alexandria, Va., on a charge of conspiring to commit unlawful computer intrusion. Prosecutors accused Mr. Assange of agreeing to help Ms. Manning crack an encoded portion of a passcode that would have enabled her to log on to a classified military network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;That charge was unveiled in April, when Mr. Assange was arrested in London after being dragged out of the Ecuadorean Embassy, where he had resided for years to avoid capture. The United States has asked Britain to extradite Mr. Assange, who is fighting it, and the filing of the new charges clears the way for British courts to weigh whether it would be lawful to transfer custody of him to a place where he will face Espionage Act charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 20:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/23/us/politics/assange-indictment.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Assange Indicted Under Espionage Act, Raising First Amendment Issues</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/23/us/politics/23dc-assange/23dc-assange-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange faces 17 counts in a superseding indictment over his role in publishing classified documents in 2010.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/23/us/politics/assange-indictment.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Notre Dame is unstable: a strong wind could make the walls collapse, report says</title>
<link>https://www.theartnewspaper.com/analysis/notre-dame-is-unstable</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theartnewspaper.com/analysis/notre-dame-is-unstable</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;ap-content-advert-cont&quot; id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-mpu1-body&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ap-content-blocks&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-comp cb-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mw-comp&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mw-description-cont&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-credit-cont&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;An aerial photo of the damaged vaults of Notre Dame Cathedral&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Notre Dame is not stable and urgently needs reinforcing. That is the conclusion of an initial assessment of damage caused by the fire which destroyed its roof and spire on the night of 15 April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;The collapse of a part of the vaults has severely reduced the safety of its structural system, which, in the case of a Gothic cathedral, does not rely on the heavy mass of the walls, as in classical architecture, but on discharging weight through clustered columns, external flying buttresses and counter-supports—a structural “exoskeleton” that until now has been extremely effective and resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Paolo Vannucci, a mechanical engineer at the University of Versailles, has modelled the engineering of the structure and shown that the walls of Notre Dame could collapse under the pressure of wind speeds higher than 90km per hour, while before the fire they could withstand winds of up to 220km per hour, so they urgently need temporary supports. The stability of the vaults is also causing concern because the stone has been weakened by the fire and the weight of tons of water and the molten lead of the roof covering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Strengthening and restoring the structural system of Notre Dame must, therefore, be the primary goal in the rebuilding process, and it will certainly require more time than initially thought (President Macron announced the cathedral would be restored within five years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;The walls need to be reinforced, and the rib vaults rebuilt and consolidated in order to allow the replacement of the roof, which itself plays an important structural role in the overall frame of the monument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;flèche&lt;/em&gt; (spire) erected by Eugène Viollet-le-Duc in 1860, which collapsed in the fire, was structurally independent of the roof and walls, resting on the pillars of the crossing of nave and transept, but its weight also contributed to the stability of the building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-comp cb-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mw-comp&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mw-description-cont&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-credit-cont&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;With a Gothic building, the vertical forces are discharged down the walls, while horizontal forces such as wind pressure are discharged through clustered columns, the external flying buttresses and counter-supports.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;The different elements of the cathedral thus form a unitary system, but the initial proposals have been for separate restoration of the main structure, the roof, and the damaged or lost decorative elements, and for the rebuilding of the spire. In fact, two days after the fire, President Macron invited architects around the world to propose ideas for a new one, as though it were an element independent of the rest of the building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Whether the government now launches an architectural competition or decides to rely on the highly professional bodies in charge of French monuments (in particular, the Compagnie des Architects en Chef, to which Philippe Villeneuve, the architect in charge of Notre Dame, belongs), it should demand an integrated project for the entire structure and not allow the design and implementation processes to be fragmented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Notre Dame has Unesco World Heritage status, and this requires the conservation, restoration and reconstruction principles promoted by the World Heritage Convention, and the International Council on Monuments and Sites (ICOMOS) Charters, to be taken into account. The architectural forms that have been lost should be reinstated, although this definitely does not preclude the use of modern techniques, materials, fire-prevention measures and advanced monitoring technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;On 10 May, the Assemblée nationale (parliament) adopted special legislation for the restoration and reconstruction of Notre Dame, which is expected to be passed in the senate on 27 May. This does not address technical issues, but creates a public agency in charge of managing procedures, which have been streamlined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-comp cb-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Francesco Bandarin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;is an architect and former senior official at Unesco, director of its World Heritage Centre (2000-2010) and assistant director-general for culture (2010-2018).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 17:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rutenspitz</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Notre Dame is unstable: a strong wind could make the walls collapse, independent report says</og:title>
<og:description>The current approach to its restoration fails to take account of the interconnected structural “engineering” of Gothic architecture</og:description>
<og:url>http://theartnewspaper.com/analysis/notre-dame-is-unstable</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.graph.cool/v1/cj6c28vh912680101ozc2paxj/cjvxrpi100bly01954ics099c/0x17:1084x569/1200x630/unknown.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theartnewspaper.com/analysis/notre-dame-is-unstable</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>After 15 Years, the Pirate Bay Still Can’t Be Killed</title>
<link>https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/after-15-years-the-pirate-bay-still-cant-be-killed</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/after-15-years-the-pirate-bay-still-cant-be-killed</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In a quiet corner of my high school’s study room in 2009, I booted up my busted laptop while making sure nobody could peer over my shoulder. I knew it was a risk to do this on a school Wi-Fi connection, but it sure felt safer than doing it at home. All it took was one website and a desktop app. The result was getting my hands on, well, pretty much any digital content I wanted, all for free.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Little did I know that the site I was using, The Pirate Bay, was facing major legal turmoil at that time because of millions of users just like me. I also never expected that I’d still be using the same site, 10 years later, as if nothing ever changed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The explosion of the internet in the early 2000s introduced me to many things: search engines, pornography, chat rooms, e-commerce. But nothing captured my attention quite like piracy, which seemed like a glorified label to give the act of illegally downloading copyrighted content. I grew up in the 1990s consuming VHS and cassettes. Now, here was an alternative — a trove of songs, TV and movies, ready for download with a few quick clicks thanks to the magic of so-called&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peer-to-peer_file_sharing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;peer-to-peer file-sharing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;technology. For a kid without much money to spend on CDs, this was a godsend. The problem was that so many&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;early programs came loaded with viruses, unreliable files and unstable connections.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then there was The Pirate Bay.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Every longtime user of The Pirate Bay seems to remember how they fell in love with the site, which was born in 2003 but remains an online juggernaut today. John, a 35-year-old redditor in London who asked to use a pseudonym, describes discovering The Pirate Bay as “feeling a ray of sunlight, just beckoning me to a better world of pirating without dealing with garbage user interfaces and shit files.” Alex (also a pseudonym, since he’s a practicing lawyer), a 28-year-old in L.A., says The Pirate Bay became “the clear favorite” upon first use, thanks to the organization and layout that felt “way less sketchy” than other platforms. Thomaz Paschoal, one of my college roommates, sums it up best. “It was always easy to find exactly what you wanted, not like, clicking on a link that says Batman and you get some crazy porn movie,” he tells me with a laugh. “It changed everything.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Unlike some early&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computerworld.com/article/2588287/networking-peer-to-peer-network.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;file-sharing programs, The Pirate Bay uses a system of torrent files that allows for a faster, more efficient method of downloading content. Instead of receiving a shared file from a single uploader,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://fossbytes.com/how-torrent-works-what-is-bittorrenting/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;torrents create decentralized downloads&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, meaning the data is assembled from multiple users in different places rather than the site or program itself. The more people share a file, the faster download speeds you can get.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But this general advantage of torrents doesn’t explain why the internet’s love affair with The Pirate Bay remains so strong. Other competitors have succumbed to lawsuits, criminal cases and the competitive marketplace. The people who created and run The Pirate Bay have been smacked by those blows, too. Yet despite widespread legal scrutiny, blockages in multiple countries, millions of dollars in fines and beyond, the site with the iconic mahogany pirate ship logo sails on, supported by an anonymous crowd of diehard pirates who revive the site every time it seems down for good. “It’s absurd to me that this platform still works and it’s still so widely popular, given that it’s so…&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;illegal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. I’m really impressed by the longevity,” Paschoal says. “I remember one time when they took down the original URL, the dot-org site, and the next day you could go on Google and find 100 identical Pirate Bay mirror sites with the same torrents.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A decade ago, the Swedish government decided to try and punish the founders of The Pirate Bay, all Swedish men, with a barrage of 34 charges based on copyright infringement. While half of the charges were quickly dropped due to a lack of evidence, the case concluded with an unprecedented result: A year of prison and roughly $3.5 million in fines for the four defendants. Legal experts at the time considered it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelocal.se/20090417/18930&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the most important file-sharing case&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;in Europe, as significant as the previous U.S. crackdown against the pioneering P2P service Napster (which&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Napster#Shutdown&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;effectively died&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;as a result of that verdict).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Copyright cases brought down other legacy names like Kazaa and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/limewire-memes-millennials&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Limewire&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;as well as two of the biggest torrent sites in the world,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/two-years-on-alleged-kat-founder-continues-to-fight-extradition-180720/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Kickass Torrents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/extratorrent-shuts-down-for-good-170517/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ExtraTorrents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Meanwhile, despite widespread concern that the Swedish case would cripple the site, The Pirate Bay lives today, still hosting torrents that have&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/pirate-bays-oldest-torrents-survived-15-years-of-turmoil-190519/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;survived for 15 years&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Part of the reason for the site’s longevity may simply be because it hasn’t been caught red-handed in a jurisdiction with tougher punishments, says&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uidaho.edu/law/people/faculty/abridy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Annemarie Bridy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a professor of law at the University of Idaho with extensive expertise on online piracy issues. “But part of the problem, too, is that there’s this legacy that The Pirate Bay has, where it’s grown into something more than the people who first operated the site,” Bridy tells me. “It’s a phenomenon. And there are people who are just ideologically committed to the operation of The Pirate Bay. For as long as that’s the case, it’s going to be very, very hard to shut down.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is the story of a plain-looking website that sprung from the most fertile period of the early internet, blatantly raised its middle fingers at intellectual property laws and copyright owners and lived for what is an eternity in the timeline of digital evolution. It’s thrived, growing from 25 million users to reportedly more than double that figure over the last 10 years, and shows little sign of slowing down. “It’s a testament to what an anonymous crew can do if they really believe in the cause of giving us access to these products that are so corporatized and endlessly monetized,” John says.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* * * * *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The prosecution of Pirate Bay began in 2006, a little past noon on May 31st, with a raid in a data center in Stockholm. While 65 police officers were enlisted for the high-profile mission, it went off without much drama:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=1&amp;amp;v=30HF-m_I6yYhttps://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=1&amp;amp;v=30HF-m_I6yY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Surveillance footage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;shows the men calmly walking into the server room and searching through the aisles (and eventually, covering the cameras up).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;568&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/30HF-m_I6yY?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Pirate Bay was initially established three years prior by the Swedish anti-copyright group&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Piratbyr%C3%A5n&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Piratbyrån&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and its operations were managed by Fredrik Neij and Gottfrid Svartholm Warg. The two coders took the ideals of a free, uncensored internet seriously, but also appeared to find some joy in the act of pissing off authorities. In 2004, they created their own internet service provider,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PRQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;dubbed PRQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, that had a “no questions asked” hosting policy — even if other ISPs and web hosts had censored a site, it could find safe harbor there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The duo were soon joined by Peter Sunde, a fellow&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Piratbyr%C3%A5n&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Piratbyrån&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;member, who became a third co-founder of The Pirate Bay and worked as its spokesman. It didn’t take long for the trio to attract negative attention, and in the months leading up to the May 2006 raid, Neij and Svartholm Warg noticed they were being followed and surveilled by private investigators. So Svartholm Warg wasn’t exactly shocked when he heard that police had arrived at the data center on the morning of May 31st. He immediately called Neij, urging him to get to the facility. At that point, the exact purpose of the raid wasn’t clear, but Neij paused before leaving his apartment. If the target was the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent_tracker&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;torrent “tracker”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;for The Pirate Bay, it would be safest to back up the entire website immediately, Neij thought. So he did.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It’s a move that observers now consider the “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/the-pirate-bay-remains-on-top-11-years-after-the-raid-170531/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;pivotal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;” moment in time for The Pirate Bay’s survival. The confiscation of servers shut down the website, but the backup allowed the site to come back online within just two days (with a new logo featuring the ship&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://g0tmk.blogspot.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;firing cannonballs at a Hollywood sign&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, for kicks). TPB’s founders believed that the crackdown from Swedish authorities came as a result of pressure from powerful international industry trade groups, primarily the Motion Picture Association of America. They also stood defiant in the aftermath. “I’m quite sure we won’t be convicted, anyhow,” Sunde&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20080114-swedish-prosecutors-dump-4000-legal-docs-on-the-pirate-bay.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;told&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;ARS Technica&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;two years later&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, as prosecutors began assembling the case.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the meantime, the founders had work to do, too. They tried to create a physical safe haven for operations by buying the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principality_of_Sealand&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Isle of Sealand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a human-made structure seven miles off the coast of Britain that’s not technically part of any nation. But they couldn’t raise enough money, and instead “sold” The Pirate Bay off to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2009/10/who-owns-the-pirate-bay-part-ii/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;a shadowy company named Reservella&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;in the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seychelles&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Seychelles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, later claiming in court that it was a legit sale despite offering zero evidence of a transaction. Sunde, Svartholm Warg and Neij were also outright arrogant about ignoring content takedown requests from industry groups and copyright holders. One such request from Dreamworks SKG&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/nov/05/sp-pirate-bay-cofounder-peter-sunde-in-prison&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;once inspired Svartholm Warg to reply&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;“It is the opinion of us and our lawyers that you are fucking morons, and that you should please go sodomise yourself with retractable batons.” That attitude didn’t dissipate as the actual trial kicked off in February 2009, with charges of copyright infringement against the three operators and Carl Lundström, a Swedish businessman accused of providing support for TPB.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The fact that half the charges were dropped due to insufficient evidence on the second day of the trial seemed auspicious, and the three founders remained confident as the examinations dragged on. At one point in the 2013 documentary&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2608732/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;TPB AFK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, which follows the trial, we see Neij testify to how he literally programmed an email filter to ignore and forward messages that refer to a copyright takedown request. “I get a lot of spam. Spam are emails that I haven’t requested,” Neij concludes with a straight face. (Neij also won applause across the internet for stating that he had literally tweaked Pirate Bay code and fixed a site shutdown&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/the-pirate-bay-lives-on-a-decade-after-operators-were-found-guilty-190420/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;while sitting in court&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;during the final trial day.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Despite the attitude — or perhaps because of it, if allegations about the presiding judge’s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.networkworld.com/article/2259165/pirate-bay-judge-cleared-of-bias-charges.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;bias for pro-copyright organizations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;are to be believed — the four men got hit with guilty convictions on April 17, 2009. They were each sentenced to a year in jail, plus an initial total of about $3.5 million in fines and d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;amages. Once again, Sunde, Svartholm Warg and Neij refused to capitulate. “We can’t pay, and we wouldn’t pay,”&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomshardware.com/news/pirate-bay-torrent-download,7582.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sunde said at a press conference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. “Even if I had the money I would rather burn everything I owned, and I wouldn’t even give them the ashes.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Instead, he made a sign with a sheet of paper, reading “I OWE U 31,000,000 SEK,” referring to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swedish_krona&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Swedish Krona currency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. “That’s as close as you’re going to get,” Sunde continued. “We have seen that some people that we don’t know have started collecting donations for us, so we can pay those silly fines. We firmly ask you NOT to do this. Do not gather or send any money. We do not want them since we will not pay any fines!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;They may have taken it in stride, with mocking smiles, but the incident divided the trio. Neij immediately bolted from Sweden for Malaysia and migrated into Laos, where he spent much of the next three years and even ended up marrying a Thai woman. He was&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/nov/04/pirate-bay-founder-fredrik-neij-arrested-thailand&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;arrested in November 2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;while crossing into Thailand, and was taken to Sweden to serve&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/pirate-bay-was-worth-doing-prison-time-for-co-founder-says-160705/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;10 months in jail&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Thai officials at the time said&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/fredrik-neij-pirate-bay-co-founder-arrested-in-thailand-1.2822840&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;a “U.S.-based movie association,”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;Swedish&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;government authorities, had hired a lawyer in Thailand to raise flags about Neij’s Interpol warrant with local immigration police and find him. (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wikileaks.org/sony/emails/emailid/106071&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Leaked emails from Sony Pictures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;show MPAA leadership, including Executive Vice President Jan Van Voorn and anti-piracy head Mike Robinson, celebrating Neij’s arrest; Sony attorney Aimee Wolfson adds it’s a “huge win.”)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Svartholm Warg also went down a similar path, fleeing Sweden for Cambodia, where he would live peacefully until being tracked down and deported in 2012. He served his shortened sentence in Sweden but ended up back in jail on unrelated hacking charges in Denmark, and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsweek.com/pirate-bay-co-founder-released-prison-378055&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ultimately became a free man in 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, cracking jokes about being imprisoned the entire way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Nice to read all your support. Please don’t tell my guards that I’m tweeting. That will confuse them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— GottfridSW (@anakata) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/anakata/status/419141810171023360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Arr, tweeps! Just me doing some years in jail t' make you able t' be a pirate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— GottfridSW (@anakata) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/anakata/status/528162828616609792?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 31, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sunde, meanwhile, managed to hide out in southern Sweden for two years before being&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/nov/05/sp-pirate-bay-cofounder-peter-sunde-in-prison&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;caught and serving&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;his own shortened sentence. “People ask if I would have done anything different if I could,” he told the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Guardian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;while behind bars. “The answer is no. This has been nothing more than five months of wasted time.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* * * * *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since their respective releases from jail, the three co-founders have remained fairly low-key. Sunde has been the most visible, creating (and selling) the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flattr&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;microtransaction app Flattr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and being involved in socialist politics, even running for a seat in the European Parliament as the representative of Finland’s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pirate_Party&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pirate Party&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Svartholm Warg is reportedly getting back into IT work, albeit behind the scenes. And Neij is back in Southeast Asia, raising a family with his wife.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Each of the founders say they’re no longer involved in The Pirate Bay. There’s no real way to prove that, but it’s accepted by experts that TPB operates via&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/pirate-bay-king-torrents-160814/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;an anonymous staff&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Three iconoclastic men have been replaced, in other words, by an obscured network of hardcore supporters. What remains is the trio’s vision: that a free and open internet is paramount, that the institution of copyright should be challenged and that running a technologically complex project like TPB is, in the words of Neij,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/eTOKXCEwo_8?t=1140&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“great fun.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;That legacy is hard to fade. “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Pirate Bay was operated by a very vocal group of people that didn’t mind confronting copyright holders. They were unique in that sense,” says Ernesto Van der Sar, who uses a pseudonym as editor and founder of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;TorrentFreak.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, which covers the industry closely.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pirate Bay is no longer the gleaming standard for decentralized file-sharing on the internet, he adds, and it’s easy to find complaints that it’s not as reliable, or feature-rich, as some newer platforms like&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/top-10-most-popular-torrent-sites-of-2019/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;YTS or 1337x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. But the current proliferation of torrenting, and the evolution of other technologies used for pirating digital content, is directly tied to the experience The Pirate Bay created 15 years ago. Ironically, the raid and trial helped boost its appeal higher than ever — the operators reported that traffic doubled practically overnight after the 2006 raid shut the site down for a day, for starters.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Van der Sar notes, though, that even if the site is still up, the 2009 prosecution did shatter the myth that legislators and law enforcement couldn’t actually levy concrete punishments to people who run decentralized file-sharing sites. While the death of Napster had shown the danger of running a file-sharing program that&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://superuser.com/questions/617264/difference-between-bittorrent-and-p2p-services-like-napster-limewire&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;directly connected people to copyrighted material&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, the clever tech behind torrents were supposed to create plausible deniability. “So to many people, the site appeared to be invincible, but the prosecution showed that this wasn’t the case. It was a turning point,” he adds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Perhaps that created a silver lining, of sorts. The Pirate Bay has since been more mobile and flexible than ever, with staffers relocating operations to “the cloud” rather than a physical location, among other savvy moves. Even a massive 2014 raid, which led to a two-month shutter for TPB, didn’t kill the original site. It seems Sunde was right when,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/187iwo/i_am_peter_sunde_cofounder_of_tpb_ama/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;in a Reddit AMA in 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, he wrote, “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;TPB being blocked in a country has, in every single attempt, given more traffic to it. It’s like trying to shoot a black hole with a bow and arrow.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Naturally, the site’s biggest fans are relieved for now, but are unsure about how prosecuting tactics will adapt in coming years. Alex says that he has always supported the site as a kind of “Robin Hood” figure, providing content to the masses without unfair price tags. He’s also worried that the political climate around copyright and piracy hasn’t changed much, even with a number of studies that show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2017/09/eu-study-finds-piracy-doesnt-hurt-game-sales-may-actually-help/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;illegal downloads don’t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://entertainment.time.com/2013/03/21/illegal-music-downloads-not-hurting-industry-study-claims/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;impact&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://lifehacker.com/how-piracy-benefits-companies-even-if-they-dont-admit-1649353452&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;bottom-line revenues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;for artists and creators. “The Pirate Bay&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;came back, again and again. I don’t know the future, but it’s still standing. But the problem of the system is still there, the persistent pursuit of the government against people who advocate for something like The Pirate Bay,” Alex says. “That hasn’t changed at all.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bridy, the legal expert, agrees that anti-piracy efforts remain a focus of industry groups like the MPAA or the Recording Industry Association of America. She says it’s worth keeping an eye on the decision to extradite the operator of Kickass Torrents,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/two-years-on-alleged-kat-founder-continues-to-fight-extradition-180720/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Artem Vaulin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, to the U.S. for trial. But a critical distinction, she adds, is that torrent sites like The Pirate Bay are no longer the white whales for prosecution. “Most civil efforts are targeted at&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.billboard.com/articles/business/8508821/us-trade-rep-stream-ripping-notorious-markets-special-country-report&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;illegal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;streaming&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;services and sites&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;now. They’re more popular in 2019 than ever. So yeah, they’ll keep going after stream rippers and other cases the industry thinks it can win, and where it’s good PR for them,” Bridy tells me. “There is this whole seamy underbelly that’s suing peer-to-peer file-sharing sites, but they’re mostly pornography suits. The trade groups aren’t about that anymore.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I admit I still log onto The Pirate Bay every once in a while, but the evolution of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;legal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;streaming sites like Netflix, Hulu and Spotify has taken a big edge off my piracy appetite. Like Alex, Bridy is quick to observe that affordably priced content remains the “No. 1 fix to piracy.” But we’re also seeing the splitting of streaming services, with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/g00/news/disney-plus-shows-movies-price-release-date-shows-movies-avengers-endgame-hulu/?i10c.ua=1&amp;amp;i10c.encReferrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8%3d&amp;amp;i10c.dv=19&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Disney pulling out of Netflix&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;for its own site and other major networks planning similar platforms. To my eyes, this feels like a consumer threat —&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;now I’m going to have to pay for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;two&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;sites to get a similar amount of content?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It’s a question many people are mulling as they consider the value of their entertainment in 2019. And it’s a question that makes me think The Pirate Bay still has a long journey ahead, even if Sunde has recently been&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/qkjpbd/pirate-bay-founder-peter-sunde-i-have-given-up&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;deeply cynical about TPB and the “lost war”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;for a free internet. It also reminds me of a scene in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;TPB AFK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, when the three men were far more idealistic about the world and their role in it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;Sunde and Svartholm Warg are at a press conference, where a moderator asks what will happen to The Pirate Bay if the operators are found guilty.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Nothing,” Sunde says. He looks at Svartholm Warg, who nods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“What are they going to do about it?” the latter adds. “They already tried shutting it down once. They’re welcome to come and fail again.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-authors&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;contributor-item -wide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;contributor-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/author/eddie-kim&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://melmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/IMG_5256-80x80.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5256&quot; title=&quot;IMG_5256&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;contributor-info&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/author/eddie-kim&quot;&gt;Eddie Kim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;contributor-bio&quot;&gt;Eddie Kim is a features writer based in Los Angeles, covering social and cultural issues for MEL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 15:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>paulpauper</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>After 15 Years, the Pirate Bay Still Can’t Be Killed - MEL Magazine</og:title>
<og:description>In a quiet corner of my high school’s study room in 2009, I booted up my busted laptop while making sure nobody could peer over...</og:description>
<og:url>https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/after-15-years-the-pirate-bay-still-cant-be-killed</og:url>
<og:image>https://melmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/PirateBay.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/after-15-years-the-pirate-bay-still-cant-be-killed</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Video filmed at four trillion frames per second captures light in a flash</title>
<link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01625-5</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01625-5</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;content content--narrow position-relative cleared clear mq1200-padded&quot; data-component=&quot;article-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;figure__image&quot; data-src=&quot;//media.nature.com/w700/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01625-5/d41586-019-01625-5_16737808.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Images of the letter A written in dye, acquired at distinct wavelengths and different time delays&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;figure__image figure--no-js&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w700/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01625-5/d41586-019-01625-5_16737808.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Images of the letter A written in dye, acquired at distinct wavelengths and different time delays&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;figure__caption sans-serif&quot;&gt;The writing of a letter A, as documented by a high-speed camera that created 4 images over the course of 12 trillionths of a second. Each colour represents an image seen at a separate wavelength of light and each column represents a particular elapsed time. Credit: Y. Lu &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Phys. Rev. Lett&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-container position-relative cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__copy&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;article-item__header&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;article-item__subject&quot;&gt;Optics and photonics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-item__date&quot;&gt;&lt;time itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot;&gt;23 May 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article-item__teaser-text serif&quot;&gt;Super-high-speed camera produces a film consisting of 60 consecutive frames.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-item__body serif&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new ultra-fast camera can generate a film of dozens of frames at trillions of frames per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-speed cameras capture frames on light sensors composed of semiconductors. Such cameras typically save each frame of a sequence on a separate area of the sensor. But inherent limits on the sensor’s size can limit the length of a film to just a few shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feng Chen of Xi’an Jiaotong University in Shaanxi, China, Lidai Wang at the City University of Hong Kong and their colleagues instead expose each frame on separate but overlapping areas of the camera sensor. Each successive frame is imprinted with a random tag before it reaches the sensor. These tags allow the image captured by the sensor to be teased apart into distinct frames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this technique, the camera could generate a sequence of up to 60 shots at a rate of almost 4 trillion frames per second. This allowed the team to film a light pulse as it travelled through a material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed intensity--high&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;figure__image&quot; alt=&quot;A 33-picosecond clip produced showing a light pulse travelling through a transparent solid.&quot; data-src=&quot;//media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01625-5/d41586-019-01625-5_16737810.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;A 33-picosecond clip produced showing a light pulse travelling through a transparent solid.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01625-5/d41586-019-01625-5_16737810.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;figure__caption sans-serif&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr10&quot;&gt;The imaging system captures a light pulse (in a slowed video) as it passes through a material, exits the material (at the dashed yellow line) and bounces off a mirror (solid yellow line) back into the material.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Credit: Y. Lu &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Phys. Rev. Lett.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approach could be used to watch high-speed processes — such as the interaction between light and biological tissue in laser surgery — unfold over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 13:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chriskanan</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01625-5</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Video filmed at four trillion frames per second captures light in a flash</og:title>
<og:description>Super-high-speed camera produces a film consisting of 60 consecutive frames.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.nature.com/lw1024/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01625-5/d41586-019-01625-5_16737804.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01625-5</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>BigInt Shipping in Firefox</title>
<link>https://wingolog.org/archives/2019/05/23/bigint-shipping-in-firefox</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://wingolog.org/archives/2019/05/23/bigint-shipping-in-firefox</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to share with folks the results of a project I have been helping out on for the last few months: implementation of &quot;BigInt&quot; in Firefox, which is finally shipping in Firefox 68 (beta).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;what's a bigint?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BigInts are a new kind of JavaScript primitive value, like numbers or strings. A BigInt is a true integer: it can take on the value of any finite integer (subject to some arbitrarily large implementation-defined limits, such as the amount of memory in your machine). This contrasts with JavaScript number values, which have the well-known property of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Number/MAX_SAFE_INTEGER&quot;&gt;only being able to precisely represent integers between -2&lt;sup&gt;53&lt;/sup&gt; and 2&lt;sup&gt;53&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BigInts are written like &quot;normal&quot; integers, but with an &lt;tt&gt;n&lt;/tt&gt; suffix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
var a = 1n;
var b = a + 42n;
b &amp;lt;&amp;lt; 64n
// result: 793209995169510719488n
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the bigint proposal, the usual mathematical operations (&lt;tt&gt;+&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;-&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;*&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;/&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;%&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;**&lt;/tt&gt;, and the comparison operators) are extended to operate on bigint values. As a new kind of primitive value, bigint values have their own &lt;tt&gt;typeof&lt;/tt&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
typeof 1n
// result: 'bigint'
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides allowing for more kinds of math to be easily and efficiently expressed, BigInt also allows for better interoperability with systems that use 64-bit numbers, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nodejs/node/pull/20220&quot;&gt;&quot;inodes&quot; in file systems&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sauleau.com/notes/wasm-bigint.html&quot;&gt;WebAssembly i64 values&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/api/process.html#process_process_hrtime_bigint&quot;&gt;high-precision timers&lt;/a&gt;, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/BigInt&quot;&gt;read more about the BigInt feature over on MDN&lt;/a&gt;, as usual. You might also like this &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/updates/2018/05/bigint&quot;&gt;short article on BigInt basics&lt;/a&gt; that V8 engineer Mathias Bynens wrote when Chrome shipped support for BigInt last year. There is an accompanying &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/blog/bigint&quot;&gt;language implementation&lt;/a&gt; article as well, for those of y'all that enjoy the nitties and the gritties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;can i ship it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try out BigInt in Firefox, simply download a copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/channel/desktop/&quot;&gt;Firefox Beta&lt;/a&gt;. This version of Firefox will be fully released to the public in a few weeks, on July 9th. If you're reading this in the future, I'm talking about Firefox 68.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BigInt is also shipping already in V8 and Chrome, and my colleague Caio Lima has an project in progress to implement it in JavaScriptCore / WebKit / Safari. Depending on your target audience, BigInt might be deployable already!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thanks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must mention that my role in the BigInt work was relatively small; my Igalia colleague Robin Templeton did the bulk of the BigInt implementation work in Firefox, so large ups to them. Hearty thanks also to Mozilla's Jan de Mooij and Jeff Walden for their patient and detailed code reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks as well to the V8 engineers for their open source implementation of BigInt fundamental algorithms, as we used many of them in Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I need to make one big thank-you, and I hope that you will join me in expressing it. The road to ship anything in a web browser is long; besides the &quot;simple matter of programming&quot; that it is to implement a feature, you need a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-bigint/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;specification with buy-in from implementors and web standards people&lt;/a&gt;, you need a good working relationship with a browser vendor, you need willing technical reviewers, you need to follow up on the inevitable security bugs that any browser change causes, and all of this takes time. It's all predicated on having the backing of an organization that's foresighted enough to invest in this kind of long-term, high-reward platform engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that regard I think all people that work on the web platform should send a big shout-out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techatbloomberg.com&quot;&gt;Tech at Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt; for making BigInt possible by underwriting all of &lt;a href=&quot;https://igalia.com/&quot;&gt;Igalia&lt;/a&gt;'s work in this area. Thank you, Bloomberg, and happy hacking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 13:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://wingolog.org/archives/2019/05/23/bigint-shipping-in-firefox</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>PostgreSQL 12 Beta 1 Released</title>
<link>https://www.postgresql.org/about/news/1943/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.postgresql.org/about/news/1943/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Posted on &lt;strong&gt;2019-05-23&lt;/strong&gt; by PostgreSQL Global Development Group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PostgreSQL Global Development Group announces that the first beta release of PostgreSQL 12 is now available for download. This release contains previews of all features that will be available in the final release of PostgreSQL 12, though some details of the release could change before then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of the open source PostgreSQL community, we strongly encourage you to test the new features of PostgreSQL 12 in your database systems to help us eliminate any bugs or other issues that may exist. While we do not advise you to run PostgreSQL 12 Beta 1 in your production environments, we encourage you to find ways to run your typical application workloads against this beta release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your testing and feedback will help the community ensure that the PostgreSQL 12 release upholds our standards of providing a stable, reliable release of the world's most advanced open source relational database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PostgreSQL 12 Features Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Indexing Performance, Functionality, and Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL 12 improves the overall performance of the standard B-tree indexes with improvements to the space management of these indexes as well. These improvements also provide a reduction of index size for B-tree indexes that are frequently modified, in addition to a performance gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, PostgreSQL 12 adds the ability to rebuild indexes concurrently, which lets you perform a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/sql-reindex.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;REINDEX&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; operation without blocking any writes to the index. This feature should help with lengthy index rebuilds that could cause downtime when managing a PostgreSQL database in a production environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL 12 extends the abilities of several of the specialized indexing mechanisms. The ability to create covering indexes, i.e. the &lt;code&gt;INCLUDE&lt;/code&gt; clause that was introduced in PostgreSQL 11, has now been added to GiST indexes. SP-GiST indexes now support the ability to perform K-nearest neighbor (K-NN) queries for data types that support the distance (&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;) operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of write-ahead log (WAL) overhead generated when creating a GiST, GIN, or SP-GiST index is also significantly reduced in PostgreSQL 12, which provides several benefits to the disk utilization of a PostgreSQL cluster and features such as continuous archiving and streaming replication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Inlined WITH queries (Common table expressions)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common table expressions (aka &lt;code&gt;WITH&lt;/code&gt; queries) can now be automatically inlined in a query if they a) are not recursive, b) do not have any side-effects and c) are only referenced once in a later part of a query. This removes an &quot;optimization fence&quot; that has existed since the introduction of the &lt;code&gt;WITH&lt;/code&gt; clause in PostgreSQL 8.4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If need be, you can force a &lt;code&gt;WITH&lt;/code&gt; query to materialize using the &lt;code&gt;MATERIALIZED&lt;/code&gt; clause, e.g.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;WITH c AS MATERIALIZED ( SELECT * FROM a WHERE a.x % 4 = 0 ) SELECT * FROM c JOIN d ON d.y = a.x;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Partitioning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL 12 improves on the performance when processing tables with thousands of partitions for operations that only need to use a small number of partitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL 12 also provides improvements to the performance of both &lt;code&gt;INSERT&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;COPY&lt;/code&gt; into a partitioned table. &lt;code&gt;ATTACH PARTITION&lt;/code&gt; can now be performed without blocking concurrent queries on the partitioned table. Additionally, the ability to use foreign keys to reference partitioned tables is now permitted in PostgreSQL 12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;JSON path queries per SQL/JSON specification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL 12 now allows execution of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/functions-json.html#FUNCTIONS-SQLJSON-PATH&quot;&gt;JSON path queries&lt;/a&gt; per the SQL/JSON specification in the SQL:2016 standard. Similar to XPath expressions for XML, JSON path expressions let you evaluate a variety of arithmetic expressions and functions in addition to comparing values within JSON documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A subset of these expressions can be accelerated with GIN indexes, allowing the execution of highly performant lookups across sets of JSON data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL 12 now supports case-insensitive and accent-insensitive comparisons for ICU provided collations, also known as &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/collation.html#COLLATION-NONDETERMINISTIC&quot;&gt;nondeterministic collations&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. When used, these collations can provide convenience for comparisons and sorts, but can also lead to a performance penalty as a collation may need to make additional checks on a string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Most-common Value Extended Statistics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/sql-createstatistics.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;CREATE STATISTICS&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, introduced in PostgreSQL 10 to help collect more complex statistics over multiple columns to improve query planning, now supports most-common value statistics. This leads to improved query plans for distributions that are non-uniform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Generated Columns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL 12 allows the creation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/ddl-generated-columns.html&quot;&gt;generated columns&lt;/a&gt; that compute their values with an expression using the contents of other columns. This feature provides stored generated columns, which are computed on inserts and updates and are saved on disk. Virtual generated columns, which are computed only when a column is read as part of a query, are not implemented yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pluggable Table Storage Interface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL 12 introduces the pluggable table storage interface that allows for the creation and use of different methods for table storage. New access methods can be added to a PostgreSQL cluster using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/sql-create-access-method.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;CREATE ACCESS METHOD&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; command and subsequently added to tables with the new &lt;code&gt;USING&lt;/code&gt; clause on &lt;code&gt;CREATE TABLE&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A table storage interface can be defined by creating a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/tableam.html&quot;&gt;table access method&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In PostgreSQL 12, the storage interface that is used by default is the &lt;code&gt;heap&lt;/code&gt; access method, which is currently is the only built-in method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Page Checksums&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;pg_verify_checkums&lt;/code&gt; command has been renamed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/app-pgchecksums.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;pg_checksums&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and now supports the ability to enable and disable page checksums across a PostgreSQL cluster that is offline. Previously, page checksums could only be enabled during the initialization of a cluster with &lt;code&gt;initdb&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Authentication &amp;amp; Connection Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GSSAPI now supports client-side and server-side encryption and can be specified in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/auth-pg-hba-conf.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;pg_hba.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file using the &lt;code&gt;hostgssenc&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;hostnogssenc&lt;/code&gt; record types. PostgreSQL 12 also allows for discovery of LDAP servers based on &lt;code&gt;DNS SRV&lt;/code&gt; records if PostgreSQL was compiled with OpenLDAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Noted Behavior Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several changes introduced in PostgreSQL 12 that can affect the behavior as well as management of your ongoing operations. A few of these are noted below; for information about other changes, please review the &quot;Migrating to Version 12&quot; section of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/release-12.html&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;recovery.conf&lt;/code&gt; configuration file is now merged into the main &lt;code&gt;postgresql.conf&lt;/code&gt; file. PostgreSQL will not start if it detects that &lt;code&gt;recovery.conf&lt;/code&gt; is present. To put PostgreSQL into a non-primary mode, you can use the &lt;code&gt;recovery.signal&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;standby.signal&lt;/code&gt; files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can read more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/runtime-config-wal.html#RUNTIME-CONFIG-WAL-ARCHIVE-RECOVERY&quot;&gt;archive recovery&lt;/a&gt; here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/runtime-config-wal.html#RUNTIME-CONFIG-WAL-ARCHIVE-RECOVERY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just-in-Time (JIT) compilation is now enabled by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OIDs can no longer be added to user created tables using the &lt;code&gt;WITH OIDs&lt;/code&gt; clause. Operations on tables that have columns that were created using &lt;code&gt;WITH OIDS&lt;/code&gt; (i.e. columns named &quot;OID&quot;) will need to be adjusted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running a &lt;code&gt;SELECT *&lt;/code&gt; command on a system table will now also output the OID for the rows in the system table as well, instead of the old behavior which required the OID column to be specified explicitly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many other new features and improvements have been added to PostgreSQL 12, some of which may be as or more important to specific users than what is mentioned above. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/release-12.html&quot;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; for a complete list of new and changed features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Testing for Bugs &amp;amp; Compatibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stability of each PostgreSQL release greatly depends on you, the community, to test the upcoming version with your workloads and testing tools in order to find bugs and regressions before the general availability of PostgreSQL 12. As this is a Beta, minor changes to database behaviors, feature details, and APIs are still possible. Your feedback and testing will help determine the final tweaks on the new features, so please test in the near future. The quality of user testing helps determine when we can make a final release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.postgresql.org/wiki/PostgreSQL_12_Open_Items&quot;&gt;open issues&lt;/a&gt; is publicly available in the PostgreSQL wiki. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/account/submitbug/&quot;&gt;report bugs&lt;/a&gt; using this form on the PostgreSQL website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.postgresql.org/account/submitbug/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Beta Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first beta release of version 12. The PostgreSQL Project will release additional betas as required for testing, followed by one or more release candidates, until the final release in late 2019. For further information please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/developer/beta/&quot;&gt;Beta Testing&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;newstag&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/about/newsarchive/pgsql/&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 12:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jakobegger</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.postgresql.org/about/news/1943/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“Once-in-a-Hundred Year” Sightings of Bamboo Blossoms Reported in Japan</title>
<link>https://grapee.jp/en/114838</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://grapee.jp/en/114838</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Many of our readers have probably seen bamboo growing and perhaps even visited famous Japanese bamboo forests such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://grapee.jp/en/99010&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one in Arashiyama, Kyoto&lt;/a&gt;. However, since many of the 1,200 species in existence bloom infrequently, it is safe to assume that far fewer of our readers have even seen a bamboo blossom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://grapee.jp/en/wp-content/uploads/13468_12-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;image-cite&quot;&gt;© grape Japan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The mystery of bamboo blossoms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some species of bamboo produce blossoms as often as once every three years, many of them flower at extremely long intervals, between 40 to 80 years. In the case of &lt;em&gt;madake&lt;/em&gt; 真竹 &lt;em&gt;Phyllostachys bambusoides&lt;/em&gt;, pictured at the top of this article, they only flower once every 130 years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps even more surprising than the long intervals at which they flower is the fact that all plants of the same stock of bamboo will bloom at the same time, and then die, no matter where they are in the world. Although the mechanism has yet to be explained by science, many believe there is some kind of natural &quot;alarm clock&quot; in the plant's cells causing the behavior. The depletion of bamboo can have considerable environmental and economic impacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A bad omen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many parts of the world where bamboo thrives, the blossoms are therefore dreaded as harbingers of bad luck, Japan being no exception. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://tenki.jp/suppl/usagida/2017/05/16/22741.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; in weather news site Tenki.jp, in the 1960s, one third of &lt;em&gt;Phyllostachys bambusoides&lt;/em&gt; in Japan died, wreaking havoc on industries and local crafts which used the bamboo species as their primary source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Bamboo blossoms being reported from Central to Southern Japan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019 may turn out to be one of those years where major groupings of bamboo stock populations wither and die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports of bamboo blossoms from central to southern Japan have been coming in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Kochi: December 12, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As reported by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kochinews.co.jp/article/239598/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kochi Shimbun&lt;/a&gt; newspaper, the Kochi Prefectural Makino Botanical Garden learned that its &lt;em&gt;kinmeichiku&lt;/em&gt; 金明竹 bamboo, a &lt;em&gt;madake&lt;/em&gt; variant with the unwieldy scientific name Phyllostachys bambusoides Sieb. et Zucc. cv. Castillonis, had blossomed for the first time since it was planted in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hyogo: Late January, 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kobe-np.co.jp/news/akashi/201902/0012027065.shtml&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; dated February 1, 2019 from the Kobe Shimbun newspaper reported that a science teacher at the Hyogo Prefectural Akashi High School in Hyogo Prefecture noticed blossoms on the &lt;em&gt;kurochiku&lt;/em&gt; 黒竹 (Phyllostachys nigra) growing in the school courtyard. The species is known to have a life cycle ranging anywhere between 60 and 120 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Miyazaki: December, 2018 to February, 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man in Mimata, Miyazaki Prefecture discovered blossoms on bamboo plants (species unknown) growing in his yard, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asahi.com/articles/ASM294QB5M29TNAB007.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a story&lt;/a&gt; published by Asahi Shimbun on February 10th. Apparently, the man found one blossom in late December and they continued to bloom in the months that followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Kanagawa: April 17th, 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kanaloco.jp/article/entry-161937.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a report&lt;/a&gt; in the Kanagawa Shimbun newspaper, a similar private individual report was made by a man in Yokosuka, Kanagawa Prefecture on the &lt;em&gt;touchiku&lt;/em&gt; 唐竹 (Sinobambusa tootsik) bamboo growing in his yard. It hadn't flowered in the 15 years in which he had it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tokushima: April 27th, 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.topics.or.jp/articles/-/192736&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;An article&lt;/a&gt; in the Tokushima Shimbun newspaper reported a man discovering that all of the some 200 &lt;em&gt;hachiku&lt;/em&gt; 破竹 (Phyllostachys nigra var. henonis) bamboo plants on his property had flowered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ehime: May 1, 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just recently, on May 1st, the Ehime Shimbun newspaper &lt;a href=&quot;https://headlines.yahoo.co.jp/hl?a=20190502-02010101-ehime-l38&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; on a man in Niihama, Ehime Prefecture finding that the bamboo (species unknown) in his garden had bloomed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Will 2019 be the year of bamboo blossoms?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this trend is any indication, it is likely that further reports of bamboo blossoms will come in as the year progresses, although it remains to be seen whether there will be the kind of mass depletion of bamboo forests seen in the 1960s. It could turn out to be like 2008, when several reports came in but the range was limited. However, even if bamboo depleting were to happen on a larger scale, the economic impact on Japan as a whole would probably not be as severe as it was in 1960s. For one thing, the production of bamboo material has plummeted to less than a tenth of what it used to be. For example, only 1.272 million culms were produced in 2016, compared to 10.494 million culms in 1975 (based on information &lt;a href=&quot;http://nittokusin.jp/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/c6a5030a72606abe62b7b7306002c7f0.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;provided by&lt;/a&gt; the Japan Special Forest Product Promotion Association).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A new beginning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any event, 2019 may be the perfect year to see bamboo blossoms when you visit Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you feel discouraged by the notion that they are bad omens, why not consider the silver lining: While it's true that the flowers signal the death of the plant, they also symbolize new beginnings, since those who rely on supercentenarian species like &lt;em&gt;madake&lt;/em&gt; can eventually expect a fresh, healthy and abundant supply of new shoots which will last for a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot; readability=&quot;6.0277777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://grapee.jp/en/wp-content/uploads/Bamboo-Shoot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;950&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;image-cite&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/c471G&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nakae&lt;/a&gt; &quot;at Jizoin temple&quot; | © Flickr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 10:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vectorbunny</dc:creator>
<og:title>“Once-In-A-Hundred Year” Sightings of Bamboo Blossoms Reported In Japan</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://grapee.jp/en/114838</og:url>
<og:image>https://grapee.jp/en/wp-content/uploads/BambooFlower.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>&lt;p&gt;Many of our readers have probably seen bamboo growing and perhaps even visited famous Japanese bamboo forests such as the one in Arashiyama, Kyoto. However,…&lt;/p&gt;</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://grapee.jp/en/114838</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GitHub Sponsors</title>
<link>https://github.com/sponsors</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/sponsors</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://github-cloud.s3.amazonaws.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-3+HOqCwtQal5hOJQ+mdxiq5zmGOTjF6RhjDsPLxbKDYgGlLFeCwzoIanb7j5IiCuXKUqyC2q8FdkC4nmx2P2rA==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/frameworks-a2fba223d5af91496cac70d4ec3624df.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-MRlTIqIyb8caK5+o8llXVntXovciHyAM4qE3kWU2S7SIjAPDxYp4mE0jQp4kP5UYegy+lG9y1I6VlsdzEjb5Qw==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/site-294181adec18ed639e160b96b45d17ac.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-rsD81z23enDfs9K8QwuOdeneWb2QHFNY9t5B56bADHpt6HdhHGuAg2uTvL4Ct95hfkjZyKIQH6S2ETUBSR3VIA==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/github-6556dfa9be535e551ffffaadfecdad99.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;GitHub Sponsors · GitHub&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;GitHub is where people build software. More than 36 million people use GitHub to discover, fork, and contribute to over 100 million projects.&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;search&quot; type=&quot;application/opensearchdescription+xml&quot; href=&quot;/opensearch.xml&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;fluid-icon&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/fluidicon.png&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:app_id&quot; content=&quot;1401488693436528&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image:src&quot; content=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/site/social-cards/sponsors.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@github&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary_large_image&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;GitHub Sponsors&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;Financially support the people behind your favorite open source projects with GitHub Sponsors.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/site/social-cards/sponsors.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;website&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;GitHub Sponsors&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;Financially support the people behind your favorite open source projects with GitHub Sponsors.&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;assets&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;pjax-timeout&quot; content=&quot;1000&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;request-id&quot; content=&quot;C7F8:8AD5:2BBCAF:3AF184:5CE73450&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;selected-link&quot; value=&quot;/sponsors&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;KT5gs8h0wvaagLKAVWq8bbeNwnZZK1r1XQysX3xurLU&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;ZzhVyEFwb7w3e0-uOTltm8Jsck2F5StVihD0exw2fsA&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;GXs5KoUUkNCoaAZn7wPN-t01Pywp9M3sEjnt_3_ZWPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-host&quot; content=&quot;collector.githubapp.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-app-id&quot; content=&quot;github&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-event-url&quot; content=&quot;https://collector.githubapp.com/github-external/browser_event&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-request_id&quot; content=&quot;C7F8:8AD5:2BBCAF:3AF184:5CE73450&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-region_edge&quot; content=&quot;sea&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-region_render&quot; content=&quot;iad&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-analytics&quot; content=&quot;UA-3769691-2&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta class=&quot;js-ga-set&quot; name=&quot;dimension1&quot; content=&quot;Logged Out&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;hostname&quot; content=&quot;github.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;user-login&quot; content=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;expected-hostname&quot; content=&quot;github.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;js-proxy-site-detection-payload&quot; content=&quot;ZTY0NWZlZGRhOWI5Yzk1ZDBjYjM4NzM1YjU0NjRjODg1ZDMyMGNhMDBlMzE4YjYxYTA1YjBiNTJiNTIwM2M0OXx7InJlbW90ZV9hZGRyZXNzIjoiNjguMjMwLjY2LjE2OSIsInJlcXVlc3RfaWQiOiJDN0Y4OjhBRDU6MkJCQ0FGOjNBRjE4NDo1Q0U3MzQ1MCIsInRpbWVzdGFtcCI6MTU1ODY1NjA4MCwiaG9zdCI6ImdpdGh1Yi5jb20ifQ==&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;enabled-features&quot; content=&quot;SPONSORS,UNIVERSE_BANNER,MARKETPLACE_INVOICED_BILLING,MARKETPLACE_SOCIAL_PROOF_CUSTOMERS,MARKETPLACE_TRENDING_SOCIAL_PROOF,MARKETPLACE_RECOMMENDATIONS&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;html-safe-nonce&quot; content=&quot;c207ab2359d76909b610ca6fb1e29bb4589d7c8a&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;x-pjax-version&quot; content=&quot;7316fd3f82d82f876fd2a0d6a680dd51&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-MRlTIqIyb8caK5+o8llXVntXovciHyAM4qE3kWU2S7SIjAPDxYp4mE0jQp4kP5UYegy+lG9y1I6VlsdzEjb5Qw==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/site-294181adec18ed639e160b96b45d17ac.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;browser-stats-url&quot; content=&quot;https://api.github.com/_private/browser/stats&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;browser-errors-url&quot; content=&quot;https://api.github.com/_private/browser/errors&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mask-icon&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/pinned-octocat.svg&quot; color=&quot;#000000&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/x-icon&quot; class=&quot;js-site-favicon&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/favicon.ico&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#1e2327&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;u2f-enabled&quot; content=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;manifest&quot; href=&quot;/manifest.json&quot; crossorigin=&quot;use-credentials&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;logged-out env-production page-responsive f4&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;50.472316384181&quot;&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;application-main&quot; data-commit-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mx-auto py-6 py-lg-8 mb-5 position-relative&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container-xl mx-auto d-md-flex flex-wrap position-relative gutter gutter-spacious&quot; readability=&quot;6.3792569659443&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-lg-7 text-center text-lg-left py-4 py-lg-6 py-xl-9&quot; readability=&quot;33.019230769231&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;f4 text-mono text-normal text-gray-light mb-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;v-align-middle&quot;&gt;GitHub Sponsors&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;Label Label--outline v-align-middle&quot;&gt;Beta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;col-12 col-md-9 col-lg-10 mt-2 mt-lg-0 mx-auto mx-lg-0 mb-4 f3 text-gray-light&quot;&gt;Connect with the community that depends on your work.&lt;br class=&quot;d-none d-lg-inline-block&quot;/&gt;
Receive recurring funds to build our shared digital infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-lg-5 position-relative position-lg-absolute top-0 right-0 pt-xl-7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;d-flex flex-justify-center width-full&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;d-inline-block flex-self-center position-relative&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bg-white box-shadow-large rounded-2 text-center position-relative mx-lg-0 mx-auto pt-4&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;px-4 py-3 text-left&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-mktg lh-condensed&quot;&gt;Mona Lisa&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;f4 text-gray-light mb-3&quot;&gt;octocat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsoring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-gray-light f5&quot;&gt;Hi, I'm Mona, the GitHub Octocat!&lt;br/&gt;I love to code and tinker. Best friends with Hubot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/site/sponsors/confetti-1.svg&quot; class=&quot;position-absolute top-0 right-0 right-md-12 right-lg-0 z-n1&quot; width=&quot;150%&quot; alt=&quot;decorative confetti&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;overflow-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container-xl mx-auto py-lg-6 px-3 px-md-6 position-relative&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;d-sm-flex flex-wrap gutter-sm gutter-lg-spacious mt-3&quot; readability=&quot;9.9525139664804&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-lg-6 mb-5 mt-lg-6 text-center text-lg-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h0-mktg lh-condensed mb-6 mb-lg-0 bg-white&quot;&gt;And support&lt;br class=&quot;d-md-none&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;list-style-none d-inline-block overflow-hidden v-align-bottom position-relative Slots text-center text-lg-left&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;Slots-item pt-1 d-block&quot;&gt;developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;Slots-item pt-1 d-block&quot;&gt;maintainers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;Slots-item pt-1 d-block&quot;&gt;writers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;Slots-item pt-1 d-block&quot;&gt;teachers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;Slots-item pt-1 d-block&quot;&gt;programmers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;you depend on, too.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-lg-5 offset-lg-7 position-relative left-lg-5 py-6 py-lg-8 text-center text-lg-left mr-lg-4 mb-lg-4 bg-white&quot; readability=&quot;32.598039215686&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/site/sponsors/hearts.svg&quot; class=&quot;d-inline-block d-lg-none mx-auto ml-lg-2 mt-0 mt-lg-n4 mb-3 mb-lg-0&quot; alt=&quot;hearts&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;f4 text-mono text-normal text-gray-light mb-2&quot;&gt;2x your sponsorship&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h1-mktg mb-2 d-inline-block&quot;&gt;We match!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/site/sponsors/hearts.svg&quot; class=&quot;d-none d-lg-inline-block ml-2 ml-md-3 mt-n4&quot; alt=&quot;hearts&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;col-sm-9 col-lg-12 mx-auto ml-0 text-gray-light mb-4&quot;&gt;To boost community funding, we'll match contributions up to $5,000 during a developer’s first year in GitHub Sponsors with the GitHub Sponsors Matching Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;text-blue-mktg Bump-link no-underline&quot; href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/about-github-sponsors&quot; data-ga-click=&quot;Sponsors, click, text:Learn more&quot;&gt;Learn more &lt;span class=&quot;Bump-link-symbol&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-lg-5 py-6 pt-md-6 pt-lg-1 pb-lg-8 text-center text-lg-left&quot; readability=&quot;33.967741935484&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;f4 text-mono text-normal text-gray-light mb-2&quot;&gt;100% to developers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h1-mktg mb-2&quot;&gt;Zero fees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;col-sm-9 col-lg-12 mx-auto text-gray-light mb-4&quot;&gt;GitHub will not charge fees for GitHub Sponsors. And to celebrate the launch, we’ll cover payment processing costs for the first year, too! One-hundred percent of your sponsorship goes to the developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;text-blue-mktg Bump-link no-underline&quot; href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/about-github-sponsors&quot; data-ga-click=&quot;Sponsors, click, text:Learn more&quot;&gt;Learn more &lt;span class=&quot;Bump-link-symbol&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bg-gray mb-8 mb-lg-12 position-relative&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container-xl mx-auto py-8 px-3 px-md-6 position-relative&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;d-flex flex-wrap flex-justify-between flex-items-center&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-lg-6 mb-6&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;d-none d-md-flex position-relative mx-auto&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;avatar rounded-1 mr-3&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; width=&quot;48&quot; alt=&quot;example user profile image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/site/sponsors/example-user-photo-2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;Box rounded-2 width-full&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-sm-9 col-lg-5 mx-auto mx-lg-0 text-center text-lg-left position-relative&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h1-mktg mb-2 lh-condensed&quot;&gt;A new way to&lt;br class=&quot;d-none d-lg-inline&quot;/&gt;
contribute on GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-gray-light mb-0&quot;&gt;Funding developers through GitHub Sponsors is one more way to contribute to open source projects you appreciate. Help developers get the resources they need, and recognize contributors working behind the scenes to make open source better for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-gray-light mb-0 mt-3&quot;&gt;With Sponsors, any GitHub user can sponsor any open source developer in the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container-xl mx-auto pb-6 pb-lg-8 px-3 px-md-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-md-11 mx-auto d-flex flex-wrap flex-justify-between flex-items-center&quot; readability=&quot;10.77397260274&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-sm-9 col-lg-5 mx-auto text-center text-lg-left ml-lg-0&quot; readability=&quot;41.13698630137&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h1-mktg mb-2 lh-condensed&quot;&gt;Get funded as a&lt;br class=&quot;d-none d-lg-inline&quot;/&gt;
sponsored developer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-gray-light mb-3&quot;&gt;Anyone who contributes to open source—whether through code, documentation, leadership, mentorship, design, or beyond—is eligible for sponsorship. Tell us about your open source work, and join the waitlist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;f4 btn-mktg mr-2 lh-condensed-ultra disabled&quot; data-ga-click=&quot;Sponsors, click, text:Join the waitlist&quot;&gt;Join the waitlist&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;f5 mt-3 text-gray&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;no-underline&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/login?return_to=%2Fsponsors&quot;&gt;Log in&lt;/a&gt; to join the waitlist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 position-relative&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/site/sponsors/confetti-2.svg&quot; alt=&quot;confetti&quot; class=&quot;width-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t perform that action at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-stale-session-flash stale-session-flash flash flash-warn flash-banner&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;signed-in-tab-flash&quot;&gt;You signed in with another tab or window. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors&quot;&gt;Reload&lt;/a&gt; to refresh your session.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;signed-out-tab-flash&quot;&gt;You signed out in another tab or window. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors&quot;&gt;Reload&lt;/a&gt; to refresh your session.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;details class=&quot;details-reset details-overlay details-overlay-dark lh-default text-gray-dark&quot; open=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 08:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Heliosmaster</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/site/social-cards/sponsors.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>GitHub Sponsors</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/sponsors</og:url>
<og:description>Financially support the people behind your favorite open source projects with GitHub Sponsors.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/sponsors</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dependabot is joining GitHub</title>
<link>https://dependabot.com/blog/hello-github/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://dependabot.com/blog/hello-github/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Dependabot has been acquired by GitHub and we couldn't be more excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/4de2bf167c7884c8a02e39250883fcb4f3a050db/8378f/hello-github-12689cd7913704d67900e1adaf7701e2.png&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub + Dependabot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what you need to know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We're integrating Dependabot directly into GitHub, starting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2019-05-23-introducing-new-ways-to-keep-your-code-secure/&quot;&gt;security fix PRs&lt;/a&gt; 👮‍♂️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can still install Dependabot from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/marketplace/dependabot-preview&quot;&gt;GitHub Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; whilst we integrate it into GitHub, but it's now free of charge 🎁&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We've doubled the size of Dependabot's team; expect lots of great improvements over the coming months 👩‍💻👨‍💻👩‍💻👨‍💻👩‍💻👨‍💻&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a dream outcome for us at Dependabot, and we can't wait to bring automated dependency updates to millions of GitHub users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're an existing Dependabot customer, the changes you'll notice are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dependabot is now free. You'll no longer be billed for it, and if you paid for future months, we'll be in touch to refund you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In time, you'll be able to configure Dependabot within GitHub, so you'll no longer need the Dependabot dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for making Dependabot what it is today. Your feedback, bug reports and encouragement over the last two years have been invaluable. We couldn't have built Dependabot without you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grey, Harry and Philip&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-is-happening-to-the-existing-dependabot-product&quot;&gt;What is happening to the existing Dependabot product?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The existing Dependabot app has been renamed to &quot;Dependabot Preview.&quot; It will remain available in the GitHub Marketplace, fully supported and now free of charge, whilst we integrate its features directly into GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;can-new-users-still-sign-up&quot;&gt;Can new users still sign up?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! If you're not already a Dependabot user, we encourage you to give &quot;Dependabot Preview&quot; a try. We'll use your feedback on it to inform the integration with GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;who-do-we-contact-with-any-other-questions&quot;&gt;Who do we contact with any other questions?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, you can reach us on support@dependabot.com with any questions, or post to our public &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dependabot/feedback&quot;&gt;feedback repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;whats-happening-to-my-paid-membership&quot;&gt;What’s happening to my paid membership?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependabot is now free. You'll no longer be billed for it, and if you paid for future months, we'll be in touch to refund you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;will-there-be-any-changes-to-dependabots-privacy-policy&quot;&gt;Will there be any changes to Dependabot's privacy policy?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not planning to make any changes to Dependabot's privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;will-dependabot-core-remain-open-source&quot;&gt;Will dependabot-core remain open source?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependabot Core is currently source available and hosted &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dependabot/dependabot-core&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It will remain source available, with a license in keeping with the intention in the project's &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dependabot/dependabot-core#license&quot;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 08:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>reqres</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://dependabot.com/blog/hello-github/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google faces first investigation by its European lead authority over GDPR</title>
<link>https://brave.com/dpc-google/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://brave.com/dpc-google/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;et-boc&quot; class=&quot;et-boc&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_builder_inner_content et_pb_gutters3&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_section et_pb_section_1 et_pb_with_background et_section_regular&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_row et_pb_row_0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0 et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today, Ireland’s Data Protection Commission (DPC) has announced a major GDPR probe into “suspected infringement” by Google’s “DoubleClick/Authorized Buyers” advertising business. The probe was triggered by a formal complaint from Dr Johnny Ryan, Chief Policy Officer at Brave, the private web browser. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-20899 aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/images/IrishTimes-DPC-May2019.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Irish Times, May 2019&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;798&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week marks one year since the application of the GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Irish Data Protection Commission &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dataprotection.ie/en/news-media/latest-news&quot;&gt;has just announced&lt;/a&gt; that “a statutory inquiry pursuant to section 110 of the Data Protection Act 2018 has been commenced in respect of Google Ireland Limited’s processing of personal data in the context of its online Ad Exchange”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s DoubleClick/Authorized Buyers advertising system is active on 8.4 million websites, according to &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trends.builtwith.com/websitelist/DoubleClick.Net&quot;&gt;BuiltWith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn1&quot; name=&quot;_ednref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Dr Ryan’s &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fixad.tech/evidence/&quot;&gt;evidence to the DPC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; revealed a massive and ongoing data breach in which Google’s DoubleClick/Authorized Buyers leaks intimate data about the people visiting these websites to thousands of companies every day. Article 5(1)(f) of the GDPR requires that personal data be tightly controlled. Article 5(1)(a) and (b) also require that individuals be adequately informed about what will happen to their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google bought DoubleClick/Authorized Buyers for $3.1B in 2007.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn2&quot; name=&quot;_ednref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; It is a driver of Google’s $19.9B&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn3&quot; name=&quot;_ednref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; revenue from ads served on publishers’ websites and relies on broadcasting users’ personal data, unbeknownst to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-20687 aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/images/Screenshot-2019-05-08-at-16.25.33.png&quot; alt=&quot;Section 110 of the Irish Data Protection Act&quot; width=&quot;1791&quot; height=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ireland’s Data Protection Commission is Google’s lead authority under the GDPR. The DPC issued Google formal notice that it will now “conduct inquiry into suspected infringement” under Section 110 of Ireland’s Data Protection Act.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn4&quot; name=&quot;_ednref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; It has the power to order Google to completely stop using personal data in its advertising system, and also to impose significant financial penalties.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn5&quot; name=&quot;_ednref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; This comes as the first anniversary of the GDPR approaches on 25 May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key facts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Google DoubleClick/Authorized Buyers is installed on 8.4+ million websites.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn6&quot; name=&quot;_ednref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It broadcasts personal data about visitors to these sites to 2,000+ companies,&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn7&quot; name=&quot;_ednref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; hundreds of billions of times a day.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn8&quot; name=&quot;_ednref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data can include people’s locations, inferred religious, sexual, political characteristics, what they are reading, watching, and listening to online, and unique codes that allow long term profiles about each person to be built up over time.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn9&quot; name=&quot;_ednref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no control over what happens to the data once broadcast.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn10&quot; name=&quot;_ednref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This appears to be by far the largest leakage of personal data ever recorded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Irish Data Protection Commission is now investigating Google’s “suspected infringement” of the GDPR under Section 110 of the Irish Data Protection Act.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Article 5(1)(f) of the GDPR requires that personal data be tightly controlled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Article 5(1)(a) and (b) of the GDPR require that individuals be adequately informed about what will happen to their data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google may be forced to stop processing all personal data for its DoubleClick/Authorized Buyers ad business, and may be fined up to 4% of global turnover.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn11&quot; name=&quot;_ednref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Surveillance capitalism is about to become obsolete&lt;/em&gt;,” said Dr Ryan of Brave. “&lt;em&gt;The Irish Data Protection Commission’s action signals that now – nearly one year after the GDPR was introduced – a change is coming that goes beyond just Google. We need to reform online advertising to protect privacy, and to protect advertisers and publishers from legal risk under the GDPR&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dr-johnny-ryan&quot;&gt;Dr Ryan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; submitted his formal GDPR &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fixad.tech/september2018/&quot;&gt;complaint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; to the DPC in September 2018. Duplicate &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fixad.tech/september2018/&quot;&gt;complaints&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; were also submitted to the UK Information Commissioner by &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openrightsgroup.org/people/jim-killock&quot;&gt;Jim Killock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, Executive Director of the Open Rights Group and &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://michae.lv/&quot;&gt;Dr Michael Veale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; of University College London. Dr Ryan, Dr Veale and Mr Kilock are represented by Mr Ravi Naik of ITN Solicitors in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Poland, &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.panoptykon.org/team&quot;&gt;Katarzyna Szymielewicz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, CEO of the Panoptykon Foundation, submitted &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fixad.tech/january2019/&quot;&gt;duplicate complaints&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; in January. Similar complaints were filed on 20 May 2019 in the Netherlands, Belgium, Spain and Luxembourg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google’s DoubleClick/Authorized Buyers is a data protection free zone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time a person visits a website that uses Google’s DoubleClick/Authorized Buyers system, intimate personal data about them and what they are viewing is broadcast in a “bid request” to tens or hundreds of companies, to solicit bids from potential advertisers’ for the opportunity to show an ad to this specific visitor.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn12&quot; name=&quot;_ednref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; This occurs hundreds of billions of times every day,&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn13&quot; name=&quot;_ednref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; and is the most massive leakage of personal data recorded so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ravi Naik, a partner at ITN Solicitors instructed by the complainants, said “&lt;em&gt;For too long, the AdTech industry has operated without due regard for the protection of consumer data. We are pleased that the Data Protection Commissioner has taken action. The industry must change&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no limit on or control over what is done with this information about internet users.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn14&quot; name=&quot;_ednref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; For example, Google relies on self-regulatory &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/doubleclick/adxbuyer/guidelines.html&quot;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; that rely on the companies that receive its broadcasts to inform it if they are breaking its rules.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn15&quot; name=&quot;_ednref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; Google says that &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/third-party-ads/adx-vendors&quot;&gt;over 2,000 companies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; are “certified” in this way.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn16&quot; name=&quot;_ednref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; Google DoubleClick/Authorized Buyers sends intimate personal information about virtually every single online person to these companies, billions of times a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But under the GDPR, a company is not permitted to use personal data unless it tightly controls what happens to that data. Article 5 (1)(f) of the GDPR requires that personal data be “processed in a manner that ensures appropriate security of the personal data, including protection against unauthorized or unlawful processing and against accidental loss.”&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn17&quot; name=&quot;_ednref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What data about you could be broadcast when Google places an ad?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT YOU ARE READING, WATCHING, OR LISTENING TO&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn18&quot; name=&quot;_ednref18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The specific URL you are loading, which shows what you are reading or watching. (&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/admanager/answer/6334919?hl=en&quot;&gt;Sometimes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; publishers using Google’s system prevent their URL from being shared.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn19&quot; name=&quot;_ednref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The category of content that you are reading/watching/listening, from Google’s &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/downloads/publisher-verticals&quot;&gt;category list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, including topics such as “eating disorders”, “left-wing politics”, “male impotence”, and “Judaism”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;YOUR DEVICE&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn20&quot; name=&quot;_ednref20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Identification codes that are unique to your device so that it and you can be recognized again. These codes are encrypted, but recipients can &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/response-guide/decrypt-advertising-id&quot;&gt;decrypt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; them too.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn21&quot; name=&quot;_ednref21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; (Google &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/user_data_treatments&quot;&gt;claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; to impose what it calls “special constraints” on this in “some circumstances”, but neither constraints nor circumstances are defined).&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn22&quot; name=&quot;_ednref22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your device’s operating system and version, and web browser software and version (some of this “user agent” information &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide#bidrequest-object&quot;&gt;may be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; partially redacted).&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn23&quot; name=&quot;_ednref23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your device manufacturer, model, and version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Height, width, and ratio of your screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your language settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mobile network carrier your device is using.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;YOU&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn24&quot; name=&quot;_ednref24&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your Google ID, which is unique to your personal Google account (Google &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/user_data_treatments&quot;&gt;claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; to impose what it calls “special constraints” on this in “some circumstances”, but neither constraints nor circumstances are defined).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google’s “Cookie Match Service” results, which enables a company to determine if you are someone they already have a profile of, and to &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/cookie-guide?hl=en&quot;&gt;combine their existing data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; about you with new data in the bid request. (Google &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/user_data_treatments&quot;&gt;claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; to impose what it calls “special constraints” on this in “some circumstances”, but neither constraints nor circumstances are defined).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your interests, based on what you are reading/watching/listening to, from Google’s &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/downloads/publisher-verticals&quot;&gt;category list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, including topics such as “eating disorders”, “left-wing politics”, “male impotence”, and “Judaism”.&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn25&quot; name=&quot;_ednref25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether the website visitor is present on a particular “user list” of targeted people (which may be a category previously decided by an advertiser, or the data broker they acquired the data from, based on the broker’s previous profiling of this particular person).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;YOUR LOCATION&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_edn26&quot; name=&quot;_ednref26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Latitude and longitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zip/postal code, or postal code prefix if a full post code is unavailable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether the user is present within a small “hyper local” area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Johnny Ryan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:johnny@brave.com&quot;&gt;johnny@brave.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref1&quot; name=&quot;_edn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; DoubleClick.Net Usage Statistics, (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://trends.builtwith.com/ads/DoubleClick.Net&quot;&gt;https://trends.builtwith.com/ads/DoubleClick.Net&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref2&quot; name=&quot;_edn2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; “Google Buys DoubleClick for $3.1 Billion”, New York Times, 14 April 2007 (URL: https://www.nytimes.com/2007/04/14/technology/14DoubleClick.html).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref3&quot; name=&quot;_edn3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; Alphabet Inc. Form 10-K, for the fiscal year ended 31 December 2018 (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://abc.xyz/investor/static/pdf/20180204_alphabet_10K.pdf?cache=11336e3&quot;&gt;https://abc.xyz/investor/static/pdf/20180204_alphabet_10K.pdf?cache=11336e3&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref4&quot; name=&quot;_edn4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Section 110, Data Protection Act 2018 (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irishstatutebook.ie/eli/2018/act/7/enacted/en/pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.irishstatutebook.ie/eli/2018/act/7/enacted/en/pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref5&quot; name=&quot;_edn5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; Article 58 (2) (f) and (i), General Data Protection Regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref6&quot; name=&quot;_edn6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; DoubleClick.Net Usage Statistics, (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://trends.builtwith.com/ads/DoubleClick.Net&quot;&gt;https://trends.builtwith.com/ads/DoubleClick.Net&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref7&quot; name=&quot;_edn7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; “Ad Exchange Certified External Vendors”, Google Authorized Buyers (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/third-party-ads/adx-vendors&quot;&gt;https://developers.google.com/third-party-ads/adx-vendors&lt;/a&gt;), last updated 18 April 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref8&quot; name=&quot;_edn8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; “Number of bid requests per day”, evidence submitted to the Irish Data Protection Commission, and UK Information Commissioner’s Office, 20 February 2019 (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://fixad.tech/images/4-appendix-on-market-saturation-of-the-systems.pdf&quot;&gt;https://fixad.tech/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/4-appendix-on-market-saturation-of-the-systems.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref9&quot; name=&quot;_edn9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; See “Ryan report on behavioral advertising and personal data” (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/Behavioural-advertising-and-personal-data.pdf&quot;&gt;https://brave.com/Behavioural-advertising-and-personal-data.pdf&lt;/a&gt;) and “Examples of data in a bid request from IAB OpenRTB and Google Authorized Buyers’ specification documents” (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://fixad.tech/images/3-bid-request-examples.pdf&quot;&gt;http://fixad.tech/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/3-bid-request-examples.pdf&lt;/a&gt;); and “Google’s publisher verticals list” (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/update-rtb-ad-auction-gdpr/Google-publisher-verticals-marked-up.pdf&quot;&gt;https://brave.com/update-rtb-ad-auction-gdpr/Google-publisher-verticals-marked-up.pdf&lt;/a&gt;), evidence submitted to the Irish Data Protection Commission, and UK Information Commissioner’s Office, 12 September 2018 and 20 February 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref10&quot; name=&quot;_edn10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; “Ryan report on behavioral advertising and personal data”, evidence submitted to the Irish Data Protection Commission, and UK Information Commissioner’s Office, 12 September 2018 (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/Behavioural-advertising-and-personal-data.pdf&quot;&gt;https://brave.com/Behavioural-advertising-and-personal-data.pdf&lt;/a&gt;); see also “pubvendors.json v1.0”, an IAB document presented in evidence to the Irish Data Protection Commission, and UK Information Commissioner’s Office, 20 February 2019 (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://fixad.tech/images/2-pubvendors.json-v1.0.pdf&quot;&gt;http://fixad.tech/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/2-pubvendors.json-v1.0.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref11&quot; name=&quot;_edn11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; Article 58 (2) (f) and (i), GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref12&quot; name=&quot;_edn12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; “Ryan report on behavioral advertising and personal data”, evidence submitted to the Irish Data Protection Commission, and UK Information Commissioner’s Office, 12 September 2018 (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/Behavioural-advertising-and-personal-data.pdf&quot;&gt;https://brave.com/Behavioural-advertising-and-personal-data.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref13&quot; name=&quot;_edn13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; “Number of bid requests per day”, evidence submitted to the Irish Data Protection Commission, and UK Information Commissioner’s Office, 20 February 2019 (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://fixad.tech/images/4-appendix-on-market-saturation-of-the-systems.pdf&quot;&gt;https://fixad.tech/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/4-appendix-on-market-saturation-of-the-systems.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref14&quot; name=&quot;_edn14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; “Ryan report on behavioral advertising and personal data”, evidence submitted to the Irish Data Protection Commission, and UK Information Commissioner’s Office, 12 September 2018 (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/Behavioural-advertising-and-personal-data.pdf&quot;&gt;https://brave.com/Behavioural-advertising-and-personal-data.pdf&lt;/a&gt;); see also “pubvendors.json v1.0”, an IAB document presented in evidence to the Irish Data Protection Commission, and UK Information Commissioner’s Office, 20 February 2019 (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://fixad.tech/images/2-pubvendors.json-v1.0.pdf&quot;&gt;http://fixad.tech/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/2-pubvendors.json-v1.0.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref15&quot; name=&quot;_edn15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; Authorized Buyers Program Guidelines, Google Authorized Buyers, last updated 22 August 2018 (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/doubleclick/adxbuyer/guidelines.html&quot;&gt;https://www.google.com/doubleclick/adxbuyer/guidelines.html&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref16&quot; name=&quot;_edn16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; “Ad Exchange Certified External Vendors”, Google Authorized Buyers, last updated 18 April 2019  (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/third-party-ads/adx-vendors&quot;&gt;https://developers.google.com/third-party-ads/adx-vendors&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref17&quot; name=&quot;_edn17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; Article 5(1)(f), GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref18&quot; name=&quot;_edn18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt; All items in this list are drawn from “Authorized Buyers Real-Time Bidding Proto”, Google Authorized Buyers (URL: &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide&quot;&gt;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref19&quot; name=&quot;_edn19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; “Set your mobile app inventory to Anonymous or Branded in Ad Exchange”, Google Ad Manager Help (URL: &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/admanager/answer/6334919?hl=en&quot;&gt;https://support.google.com/admanager/answer/6334919?hl=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref20&quot; name=&quot;_edn20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt; All items in this list are drawn from “Authorized Buyers Real-Time Bidding Proto”, Google Authorized Buyers (URL: &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide&quot;&gt;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref21&quot; name=&quot;_edn21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; See “Decrypt Advertising ID”, Authorized Buyers, Google (URL:  &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/response-guide/decrypt-advertising-id&quot;&gt;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/response-guide/decrypt-advertising-id&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref22&quot; name=&quot;_edn22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt; See “User Data Treatments”, Google Authorized Buyers (URL: &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/user_data_treatments&quot;&gt;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/user_data_treatments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref23&quot; name=&quot;_edn23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; “Certain data may be redacted or replaced”, see “user_agent” in “Authorized Buyers Real-Time Bidding Proto”, Google, 5 September 2018 (URL: &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide&quot;&gt;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref24&quot; name=&quot;_edn24&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt; All items in this list are drawn from “Authorized Buyers Real-Time Bidding Proto”, Google Authorized Buyers (URL: &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide&quot;&gt;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref25&quot; name=&quot;_edn25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt; “Google’s publisher verticals list” (URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/update-rtb-ad-auction-gdpr/Google-publisher-verticals-marked-up.pdf&quot;&gt;https://brave.com/update-rtb-ad-auction-gdpr/Google-publisher-verticals-marked-up.pdf&lt;/a&gt;), evidence submitted to the Irish Data Protection Commission, and UK Information Commissioner’s Office, 20 February 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/#_ednref26&quot; name=&quot;_edn26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt; All items in this list are drawn from “Authorized Buyers Real-Time Bidding Proto”, Google Authorized Buyers (URL: &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide&quot;&gt;https://developers.google.com/authorized-buyers/rtb/realtime-bidding-guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_section et_pb_section_2 et_pb_with_background et_section_regular&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_row et_pb_row_1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1 et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_blog_0 et_pb_blog_grid_wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_blog_grid clearfix et_pb_bg_layout_light&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_ajax_pagination_container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_salvattore_content&quot; data-columns=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;article id=&quot;post-20745&quot; class=&quot;et_pb_post clearfix post-20745 post type-post status-publish format-standard has-post-thumbnail hentry category-brave-insights-category category-gdpr-category category-policy-category tag-adtech tag-brian-okelley tag-federal-law tag-gdpr tag-johnny-ryan tag-judiciary-committee tag-privacy-law tag-rtb tag-us-privacy-law tag-us-senate&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_image_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/ryan-testimony-may-2019/&quot; class=&quot;entry-featured-image-url&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/images/Ryan-Senate-400x250.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dr Johnny Ryan’s testimony at the US Senate Judiciary Committee&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;250&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Johnny Ryan of Brave testified today at the US Senate Judiciary Committee hearing on “Understanding the Digital Advertising Ecosystem and the Impact of Data Privacy and Competition Policy”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;post-20724&quot; class=&quot;et_pb_post clearfix post-20724 post type-post status-publish format-standard has-post-thumbnail hentry category-brave-insights-category category-gdpr-category category-policy-category tag-adtech tag-complaint tag-david-korteweg tag-diego-fanjul tag-gdpr tag-gemma-galdon-clavell tag-jef-ausloos tag-jose-belo tag-patricia-macedo-alves tag-pierre-dewitte tag-rtb&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_image_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/rtb-complaint-5-new-countries/&quot; class=&quot;entry-featured-image-url&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/images/gpdr-4-400x250.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ad Tech GDPR complaint is extended to four more European regulators&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;250&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDPR complaints about Real-Time Bidding (RTB) in the online advertising industry were filed today with Data Protection Authorities in Spain, the Netherlands, Belgium, and Luxembourg. The complaints detail the vast scale of personal data leakage by Google and other major companies in the “Ad Tech” industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;post-20205&quot; class=&quot;et_pb_post clearfix post-20205 post type-post status-publish format-standard has-post-thumbnail hentry category-brave-insights-category category-gdpr-category category-policy-category tag-ab-1760 tag-aclu tag-buffy-wicks tag-california tag-california-consumer-protection-act tag-ccpa tag-eff tag-henry-stern tag-personal-information tag-privacy-for-all tag-sb-753 tag-senator-stern tag-wicks&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_image_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/brave-ccpa-april-2019/&quot; class=&quot;entry-featured-image-url&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/images/Screenshot-2019-04-16-at-11.53.11-400x250.png&quot; alt=&quot;A worrying adtech exemption to California’s new privacy law&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;250&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brave has written to the California Department of Justice to highlight potential loopholes in the California Consumer Protection Act (CCPA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_section et_pb_section_4 et_pb_with_background et_pb_fullwidth_section et_section_regular&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;et_pb_with_border et_pb_module et_pb_fullwidth_header et_pb_fullwidth_header_0 brave-the-web-button et_pb_bg_layout_dark et_pb_text_align_center&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_fullwidth_header_container center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;header-content-container center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;header-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;et_pb_module_header&quot;&gt;Ready to Brave the new internet?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;et_pb_fullwidth_header_subhead&quot;&gt;Brave is built by a team of privacy focused, performance oriented pioneers of the web. Help us fix browsing together.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;et_pb_button et_pb_more_button et_pb_button_one&quot; href=&quot;https://brave.com/download/&quot;&gt;Download Brave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_section et_pb_section_6 et_pb_with_background et_section_regular&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_with_border et_pb_row et_pb_row_2&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_1_5 et_pb_column_3 et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_5 et_hover_enabled et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Join the Newsletter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_1_5 et_pb_column_6 et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_9 et_hover_enabled et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Offices&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5/&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Brave San Francisco&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;512 Second St., Floor 2&lt;br/&gt;San Francisco, CA 94107&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Brave London&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mindspace Shoreditch&lt;br/&gt;9 Appold St&lt;br/&gt;London, EC2A 2AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_row et_pb_row_4 et_pb_equal_columns&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_2_5 et_pb_column_8 et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_image et_pb_image_0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;et_pb_image_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brave.com/dpc-google/fonts/brave_logo_2color_reversed.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 08:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>logTom</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google faces first investigation by its European lead authority for “suspected infringement” of the GDPR, following formal complaint from Brave</og:title>
<og:description>Today, Ireland’s Data Protection Commission (DPC) has announced a major GDPR probe into “suspected infringement” by Google’s DoubleClick/Authorized Buyers advertising business. The probe was triggered by a formal complaint from Dr Johnny Ryan, Chief Policy Officer at Brave, the private web browser.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.brave.com/blog/dpc-google/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.brave.com/images/IrishTimes-DPC-May2019.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://brave.com/dpc-google/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>