<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>No one should have to travel in fear</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@andreasgal/no-one-should-have-to-travel-in-fear-b2bff4c460e5</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@andreasgal/no-one-should-have-to-travel-in-fear-b2bff4c460e5</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;uiScale uiScale-ui--regular uiScale-caption--regular u-flexCenter u-marginVertical24 u-fontSize15 js-postMetaLockup&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-flex0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link u-baseColor--link avatar&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@andreasgal?source=post_header_lockup&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-source=&quot;post_header_lockup&quot; data-action-value=&quot;3408864634d7&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; data-user-id=&quot;3408864634d7&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/100/100/0*oib1wMtJ4oOIPTf7.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;avatar-image u-size50x50&quot; alt=&quot;Go to the profile of Andreas Gal&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5b4e&quot; id=&quot;5b4e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;I’ve worked for Silicon Valley companies for more than a decade and international travel is a necessary part of my job. I’ve had my fair share of delays and missed connections, but one thing I’ve never experienced while traveling in airports is fear. That changed last December when I returned from a business trip to Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*vDdOq-Or2dTr2Z5kM4DwwA.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3720&quot; data-height=&quot;2483&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*vDdOq-Or2dTr2Z5kM4DwwA.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*vDdOq-Or2dTr2Z5kM4DwwA.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a75c&quot; id=&quot;a75c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Going through customs is usually routine for me. I signed up for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ttp.cbp.dhs.gov/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://ttp.cbp.dhs.gov/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Global Entry&lt;/a&gt; program years ago. It allows me to bypass lines using an electronic kiosk. With my travel schedule, Global Entry is a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8e2e&quot; id=&quot;8e2e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;On this trip, the kiosk directed me to a Customs and Border Patrol agent who kept my passport and sent me to secondary inspection. There I quickly found myself surrounded by three armed agents wearing bullet proof vests. They started to question me aggressively regarding my trip, my current employment, and my past work for Mozilla, a non-profit organization dedicated to open technology and online privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;658d&quot; id=&quot;658d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The agents proceeded to search my belongings and demanded that I unlock my smartphone and laptop. This was rather concerning for me. My phone and laptop are property of my employer and contain unreleased software and proprietary information. I’ve signed a non-disclosure agreement promising not to give anyone access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d2db&quot; id=&quot;d2db&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Because I was uncertain about my legal responsibilities to my employer, I asked the agents if I could speak to my employer or an attorney before unlocking my devices. This request seemed to aggravate the customs officers. They informed me that I had no right to speak to an attorney at the border despite being a U.S. citizen, and threatened me that failure to immediately comply with their demand is a violation of federal criminal code 18 USC 111.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4605&quot; id=&quot;4605&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’m not an attorney, and I have no prior experience with federal law enforcement, but I did study the U.S. Constitution as part of my citizenship test three years ago. I wasn’t sure what the legal definition of an unreasonable search and seizure was, but three armed men detaining me, threatening me, and refusing to allow me to consult with an attorney definitely felt like one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3668&quot; id=&quot;3668&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I declined to answer any further questions, and continued to ask to speak to an attorney instead. The interrogation and threats continued for some time, which I endured silently. Despite initial threats that they would keep my devices if I didn’t unlock them, I was eventually permitted to leave the customs area with my devices. The customs agents did however keep my Global Entry card as a punishment for not complying with their demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1ac2&quot; id=&quot;1ac2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As I have learned since, my experience was not unique. While CBP has a long history of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gq.com/story/border-patrol-dont-call-cages-cages&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.gq.com/story/border-patrol-dont-call-cages-cages&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mistreating foreigners, immigrants, and asylum seekers&lt;/a&gt; entering the US, more recently CBP has also started to &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicintegrity.org/immigration/shocked-and-humiliated-lawsuits-accuse-customs-border-officers-of-invasive-searches-of-minors-women/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://publicintegrity.org/immigration/shocked-and-humiliated-lawsuits-accuse-customs-border-officers-of-invasive-searches-of-minors-women/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;aggressively question&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/blog/immigrants-rights/ice-and-border-patrol-abuses/us-border-patrol-detained-us-citizens-speaking&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/blog/immigrants-rights/ice-and-border-patrol-abuses/us-border-patrol-detained-us-citizens-speaking&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;unlawfully detain&lt;/a&gt;, and in some cases &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-nation/wp/2017/07/13/u-s-family-suing-federal-government-after-11-hour-detention-on-canadian-border/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.1727001cb3eb&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-nation/wp/2017/07/13/u-s-family-suing-federal-government-after-11-hour-detention-on-canadian-border/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.1727001cb3eb&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;physically assault&lt;/a&gt; U.S. citizens crossing the border. These so-called border searches are not random. NBC recently reported that CBP maintains &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/immigration/u-s-officials-made-list-reporters-lawyers-activists-question-border-n980301&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/immigration/u-s-officials-made-list-reporters-lawyers-activists-question-border-n980301&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dossiers of U.S. citizens&lt;/a&gt; and targets lawyers, journalists, and activists, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://papersplease.org/wp/2019/01/10/cbp-finalizes-rules-for-social-media-surveillance/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://papersplease.org/wp/2019/01/10/cbp-finalizes-rules-for-social-media-surveillance/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;monitors social media activity&lt;/a&gt; of U.S. citizens. My past work on encryption and online privacy is well documented, and so is my disapproval of the Trump administration and my history of significant campaign contributions to Democratic candidates. I wonder whether these CBP programs led to me being targeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2a4e&quot; id=&quot;2a4e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;If the government intended to scare me, they certainly succeeded. Ever since, I travel in fear. I’ve reduced my international travel and my heart pounds every time I go through U.S. customs. I will, however, not be silent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0072&quot; id=&quot;0072&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;When I became a U.S. citizen I swore to defend the Constitution. I’m a proud U.S. citizen and I take my oath seriously. It is in that spirit that I have filed a civil rights complaint with the help of the ACLU against CBP for unlawfully detaining me and violating my constitutional rights. The time is overdue for Congress to step in and provide meaningful oversight and legislation to reign in CBP’s egregious misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 20:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>geofft</dc:creator>
<og:title>No one should have to travel in fear</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@andreasgal/no-one-should-have-to-travel-in-fear-b2bff4c460e5</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*vDdOq-Or2dTr2Z5kM4DwwA.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>I’ve worked for Silicon Valley companies for more than a decade and international travel is a necessary part of my job. I’ve had my fair…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@andreasgal/no-one-should-have-to-travel-in-fear-b2bff4c460e5</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sweden Wants to Revive Europe’s Overnight Trains</title>
<link>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/04/europe-night-train-sweden-eco-travel-sleeper-car-fossil-free/586228/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/04/europe-night-train-sweden-eco-travel-sleeper-car-fossil-free/586228/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the quest to reduce the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2018/10/un-climate-report-transportation-choices/572494/&quot;&gt;massive carbon footprint from global transportation&lt;/a&gt;, Sweden plans to revive a staple of 20th century travel: the overnight train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Swedish government announced Sunday that it will fund the creation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dn.se/nyheter/politik/regeringen-satsar-50-miljoner-pa-nattag-ut-i-europa/&quot;&gt;overnight train services&lt;/a&gt; from Sweden to the European mainland. According to a statement from the Social Democrat-Green coalition government, the state will pump 50 million Kronor ($5.3 million) into creating night links by train to major European destinations, as part of a drive to give Swedes more low-carbon ways to travel long distances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just promising news for people who want to see carbon emissions reduced—it’s also a major shot in the arm for Europe’s night trains overall, which have been struggling to the point of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2014/10/goodnight-to-night-trains/382012/&quot;&gt;risking extinction&lt;/a&gt; in recent years. In the 20th century, such services were standard across the continent. Since around the millennium, however, a boom in low-cost airlines has bitten hard into their business, while high-speed trains have made overnight travel less necessary on many routes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We do this in order to cope with the climate, build a strong society and to achieve the goal of becoming the world’s fossil-free welfare country,” said Deputy Finance Minister and Green Party representative Per Bolund in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.regeringen.se/pressmeddelanden/2019/03/nattag-till-kontinenten/&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;. “More and more people want to be able to travel climate-smart, both on holiday and for work. Now it is up to us politicians to contribute to the train becoming an obvious alternative for getting to [the rest of] Europe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new funding will be used to research which routes would be most in demand, and to find companies able to run the service. This could possibly mean side-stepping the national rail company SJ (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statens_J%C3%A4rnv%C3%A4gar&quot;&gt;Statens Järnvägar&lt;/a&gt;), which currently runs one international night service (from Stockholm to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Narvik&quot;&gt;Narvik&lt;/a&gt;, Norway) but recently said it would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelocal.se/20190331/sweden-to-invest-in-night-trains-to-continent&quot;&gt;wait a decade&lt;/a&gt; before introducing night services to the European mainland. That delay would be in order to wait for the construction of an 11-mile-long rail tunnel between Denmark and Germany called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2015/03/the-tunnel-project-that-could-reshape-the-european-map/388652/&quot;&gt;Fehmarn Belt Fixed Link&lt;/a&gt;, which would reduce the journey time by train from Copenhagen to Hamburg from five hours to just two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no denying that this link would make travel in the region far faster, but with construction not due to begin until 2020, the tunnel’s inauguration is too far in the distance for Sweden’s Greens. It remains to be seen whether SJ will change its mind to win the night train contract, or whether the government will choose another carrier—such as, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.snalltaget.se/en/about-us&quot;&gt;Snälltåget&lt;/a&gt;, a company that currently runs Sweden’s only other international night services, from Malmö to Berlin and (again) Narvik.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;While changes in the travel industry have tended to pressure night trains off the market, it’s clear that there is still some appetite for them among travelers. When Germany’s Deutsche Bahn &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tagesspiegel.de/wirtschaft/auf-der-schiene-unterwegs-wie-die-deutsche-bahn-ihre-nachtzuege-schlechtgerechnet-hat/20748678.html&quot;&gt;halted its night services&lt;/a&gt; in 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelocal.de/20180709/berlin-budapest-one-of-three-sleeper-train-routes-to-return-to-germany-this-year&quot;&gt;Austrian Federal Railways&lt;/a&gt; took over some of the key routes. The takeover has proved to be a success, with passenger numbers on the services (whose conditions are outlined &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seat61.com/trains-and-routes/nightjet.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) rising from 1.4 million to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manager-magazin.de/unternehmen/artikel/nightjet-nachtzuege-der-oebb-erfolgreich-a-1246563.html&quot;&gt;1.6 million&lt;/a&gt; between 2017 and 2018, a rise in profits, and talk of expansion. Meanwhile, well-established leisure services such as the London-to-Scotland &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sleeper.scot/&quot;&gt;Caledonian Sleeper&lt;/a&gt; continue to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;c-newsletter c-newsletter--promo c-newsletter--cta&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;c-newsletter__title&quot;&gt;Cities are changing fast. Keep up with the &lt;strong&gt;CityLab Daily&lt;/strong&gt; newsletter.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;label for=&quot;promo-email-input-email&quot; class=&quot;c-newsletter__cta c-newsletter__cta--promo&quot;&gt;The best way to follow issues you care about.&lt;/label&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overnight train services remain popular because many people actually like them. The duration of travel, of course, is usually far longer than by plane, even when layovers and security are factored in, but there are other compensations. Generally scheduled to leave late evening and arrive before the working day begins, night trains offer the possibility of sleep and more leisurely travel compared to an early-morning rush to the airport. They can also be reasonably priced: On the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nightjet.com/reiseziele/deutschland/berlin.html&quot;&gt;Vienna-to-Berlin night service&lt;/a&gt;, for example, a one-way ticket with a reclining sleeper seat starts at €29 ($32.50), a couchette (a four- or six-person compartment whose bunks fold down into comfortable seating during the day) at €49 ($55), and a single-berth sleeper with private toilet and shower at €139 ($159). If the trip saves you the cost of a hotel room, many people seem to be noting, that’s not a bad deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while the outlook seemed bleak just a few years ago, Sweden’s plan arrives at a time when the sector’s fortunes seem to be brightening once more. It’s difficult to say how well the plan will fare, however, without knowing the routes. The most likely candidates for an overnight service to Sweden would be major Northern European cities such as Hamburg, Berlin, Frankfurt and Amsterdam, although other cities somewhat further afield, such as, Brussels and even Prague might be possible options too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-4&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even a successful Swedish night-train service is likely to remain a niche alternative to flying, rather than a threatening competitor. But getting more people on the rails can only have a positive effect in reducing the carbon footprint of international mobility. The idea of trains full of passengers lying asleep as their train rattles over the points may strike most of us as an image on the past. Maybe—just maybe—it could also be a vision of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 19:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aaronbrethorst</dc:creator>
<og:description>The government says it's the way to become &quot;the world’s fossil-free welfare country.”</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.citylab.com/media/img/citylab/2019/04/sweden_night_trains/facebook.jpg?1554218320</og:image>
<og:title>Why Sweden Wants to Revive Europe’s Night Trains</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/04/europe-night-train-sweden-eco-travel-sleeper-car-fossil-free/586228/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/04/europe-night-train-sweden-eco-travel-sleeper-car-fossil-free/586228/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Editor.js – Block Styled Editor</title>
<link>https://editorjs.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://editorjs.io/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;docs-header&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://editorjs.io/&quot; class=&quot;docs-header__logo&quot;&gt;
    Editor.js
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;landing-loader&quot; id=&quot;frame-loader&quot;&gt;
    &lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; class=&quot;ldi-zbvw97&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 80 80&quot; preserveaspectratio=&quot;xMidYMid&quot;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; id=&quot;Layer_1&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 80 80&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;style&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
            .st3{fill:#dff0fc}
            .st5{fill:#69cdff}
          ]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st3&quot; d=&quot;M69.4 28.7c-3-2.8-6.5-4.8-10.3-6-4.6-1.5-7.7-5.8-7.7-10.6V7.5c4.9.2 9.7 1.1 14.2 2.9 7.4 2.9 9.5 12.6 3.8 18.3z&quot; fill=&quot;#dff0fc&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st5&quot; d=&quot;M33 11c-4.4 1.9-8.5 4.6-12.1 8l3.2 3.2c3.4 3.4 8.6 4.2 12.9 2.1 3.6-1.8 7.5-2.8 11.6-3 0-8.1-8.2-13.5-15.6-10.3z&quot; fill=&quot;#69cdff&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st3&quot; d=&quot;M10.4 34.4c-1.8 4.5-2.7 9.3-2.9 14.2H12c4.8 0 9.1-3.1 10.6-7.7 1.3-3.8 3.3-7.3 6.1-10.3-5.7-5.7-15.4-3.6-18.3 3.8z&quot; fill=&quot;#dff0fc&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st5&quot; d=&quot;M11 67c1.9 4.4 4.6 8.5 8 12.1l3.2-3.2c3.4-3.4 4.2-8.6 2.1-12.9-1.8-3.6-2.8-7.5-3-11.6-8.1 0-13.5 8.2-10.3 15.6z&quot; fill=&quot;#69cdff&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st5&quot; d=&quot;M89 33c-1.9-4.4-4.6-8.5-8-12.1l-3.2 3.2c-3.4 3.4-4.2 8.6-2.1 12.9 1.8 3.6 2.8 7.5 3 11.6 8.1 0 13.5-8.2 10.3-15.6z&quot; fill=&quot;#69cdff&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st3&quot; d=&quot;M89.6 65.6c1.8-4.5 2.7-9.3 2.9-14.2H88c-4.8 0-9.1 3.1-10.6 7.7-1.3 3.8-3.3 7.3-6.1 10.3 5.7 5.7 15.4 3.6 18.3-3.8z&quot; fill=&quot;#dff0fc&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st5&quot; d=&quot;M67 89c4.4-1.9 8.5-4.6 12.1-8l-3.2-3.2c-3.4-3.4-8.6-4.2-12.9-2.1-3.6 1.8-7.5 2.8-11.6 3 0 8.1 8.2 13.5 15.6 10.3z&quot; fill=&quot;#69cdff&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st3&quot; d=&quot;M34.4 89.6c4.5 1.8 9.3 2.7 14.2 2.9V88c0-4.8-3.1-9.1-7.7-10.6-3.8-1.3-7.3-3.3-10.3-6.1-5.7 5.7-3.6 15.4 3.8 18.3z&quot; fill=&quot;#dff0fc&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;style&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
      .ld-spin {
        will-change: transform;
      }
      @keyframes ld-spin{0%{-webkit-transform:rotate(0);transform:rotate(0);animation-timing-function:cubic-bezier(.55,.055,.675,.19)}50%{-webkit-transform:rotate(180deg);transform:rotate(180deg);animation-timing-function:cubic-bezier(.215,.61,.355,1)}to{-webkit-transform:rotate(360deg);transform:rotate(360deg)}}@-webkit-keyframes ld-spin{0%{-webkit-transform:rotate(0);transform:rotate(0);animation-timing-function:cubic-bezier(.55,.055,.675,.19)}50%{-webkit-transform:rotate(180deg);transform:rotate(180deg);animation-timing-function:cubic-bezier(.215,.61,.355,1)}to{-webkit-transform:rotate(360deg);transform:rotate(360deg)}}path{stroke-width:0}.ld.ld-spin{-webkit-animation:ld-spin 1s infinite;animation:ld-spin 1s infinite}
    ]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  

      &lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mc.yandex.ru/watch/53080309&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
  </description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 16:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tortilla</dc:creator>
<og:title>Editor.js</og:title>
<og:description>A block-styled editor with clean JSON output</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://editorjs.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>From Show HN to Series D</title>
<link>https://segment.com/blog/show-hn-to-series-d/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://segment.com/blog/show-hn-to-series-d/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Every six months you see a post pop up on Hacker News like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ff3etg8jeai7jel/Screenshot%202019-04-01%2018.16.54.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reality is that it’s hard to build a business from scratch. You need the right people, the right product, the right timing, and more often than not, a lot of luck. But even those things don’t guarantee success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Segment, we’ve had the incredible and unlikely fortune of building a real business in those exact conditions. We launched the very first tiny slice of our product &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4912076&quot;&gt;6.5 years ago as a Show HN post.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still have an enormous distance to go on our journey. &lt;strong&gt;However, today is an important milestone.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2019/04/02/1795157/0/en/Segment-Raises-175-Million-Series-D-to-Liberate-Customer-Data-from-CRM-and-Usher-in-a-New-Era-of-Customer-Relationships.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re announcing that we’ve raised $175M in Series D funding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a big moment for us, and one that wouldn’t have happened without the support and feedback from all of our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like every startup journey, we’ve had our share of ups and downs. In this post, we wanted to give you a window into Segment's journey in that first year; from the &lt;strong&gt;initial product launch&lt;/strong&gt;, to our &lt;strong&gt;first hundred customers&lt;/strong&gt;, to &lt;strong&gt;the pitch deck&lt;/strong&gt; we used to raise our first funding. For all the startups out there in a similar boat, hopefully you can take something from our experience and apply it to your own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six years ago, we were just four engineers sitting in an apartment on Russian Hill in San Francisco. We had 6 months of runway, and paid ourselves almost nothing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/joM5sAnXdXEmLmwS5QViHoTfHluuNHgC6N54FUJWHd9bUKQ87snhGiT0Q1USyCXDky2hTG6ggpbkYWQ4Bt2onX0GLwmS9inKCWqAIKsVyQCL_SliUd6P81SbviJu5eLGhsEt0yu0ZEA&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the story of our first year after launching on HN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start in December, 2012. At the time, the four of us had been working on failed ideas for 18 months. We had 9 months of runway left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you the hyper-abbreviated timeline up until this point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2011:&lt;/strong&gt; we were accepted to Y Combinator as part of their summer 2011 batch (as an Edtech startup!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2011:&lt;/strong&gt; we finished the YC batch, raised a seed round, and moved to Boston &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2011:&lt;/strong&gt; after thousands of lines of code, we realized our Edtech startup did not have product market fit, so we pivoted to building a Mixpanel competitor focused on segmentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2012:&lt;/strong&gt; we moved back to SF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 2012:&lt;/strong&gt; 6 product iterations later, nothing was working. We were trying to decide between a group trip planner and what eventually became Segment. It was a dark time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We realized we had only one last shot. So we decided to open source a library we’d built to send our analytics data to all of the different analytics tools (including our Mixpanel competitor) via a single API. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, it was a just &lt;strong&gt;a 400-line javascript&lt;/strong&gt; file that could send data to &lt;strong&gt;eight&lt;/strong&gt; destinations: &lt;strong&gt;Google Analytics, KISSmetrics, Mixpanel, Intercom, Customer.io, CrazyEgg, Olark,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Chartbeat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/21ua999t97c86px/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2017.35.41.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Papering over these different APIs seemed like an almost trivial problem… but one that had clearly annoyed us enough to write some code to solve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We debated internally for 5 days whether this weekend project was actually a viable business. We kept going round in circles, coming up with arguments for and against the idea. Try as we might, we couldn’t come to a consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we put it to the test. On 12/12/12, &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4912076&quot;&gt;we launched it on HN&lt;/a&gt;, and the response was startling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/q8kr4zw8inv3xkp/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2017.23.18.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post sat at the top of Hacker News all day with hundreds of upvotes, dozens of comments, and hundreds of tweets. But most surprisingly, professional engineers were saying “we need this at work.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were blown away. We’d finally hit a real problem - but whether we could build a business remained to be seen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had put up a landing page at segment.io to test whether users wanted a hosted version. We told them to leave their email and then we’d get back to them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That day, we got hundreds of emails like the one below, coming in at all hours of day and night:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/9akg2euk967rtep/interested-signup.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’d finally built something people wanted! We’d finally tapped into something with real potential, and started solving a real business problem. So we hacked for seven days straight to deliver the first version of the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was minimal — all it did was host Analytics.js for users. They could turn on any of our 10 integrations, enter their configuration, and we would render a custom version behind a Cloudfront CDN.  We’d also collect these events via our Node API, and show the events in in a dashboard, but there wasn’t any data actively being proxied through our servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/jyhi8bv345jhzww/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2017.58.34.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The winter holidays were the first time we’d consistently had a steady stream of traffic on our API. We were seeing tens of requests per second come in around the clock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a far cry from the hundreds of thousands of requests we see today, but it was at least a start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/GC1ye1sJo0OwhBzWEskusGL0WdWXLxc-kz0dP9H1B1z5yA-j4uqqmpKjpFPMyAb44AjDBrPHDaJlta6mJ9BO370lfcupr1b6ssdEN7QZ6lehm0lsMld4KjI1bVd2Fnqil-ihJbEpg90&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We came back in January and started going “all in” on Segment.io.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pitched a few different press outlets to finally announce that we had been funded by YC. We were fortunate enough that &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2013/01/25/yc-backed-segment-io-lets-developers-integrate-with-multiple-analytics-providers-in-hours-not-weeks/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2013/01/25/yc-backed-segment-io-lets-developers-integrate-with-multiple-analytics-providers-in-hours-not-weeks/&quot;&gt;wrote about our story.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_46584B2C564A5E58FAAE704E15060C7254E69C53C7B7A2AD131CC7D48A8C537D_1553834110793_Screenshot+from+2019-03-28+21-34-55.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spurred on by our early user adoption and attention from press, we next turned our focus towards building features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most valuable thing we ever did at this stage was enable livechat via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.olark.com/&quot;&gt;Olark&lt;/a&gt;. It gave us an unparalleled window into what users were asking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike our earlier ideas, we were now getting &lt;em&gt;constant&lt;/em&gt; feedback on the product. People would start using the product and then just kept asking us for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/cw8f71d5io12fnm/olark.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was an invigorating feeling for us. Instead of making vague guesses at what users might want… they told us outright!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we had the very early ‘taste’ of product market fit, we started building like mad. We took a leaf from &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/startuplessons.html&quot;&gt;Paul Graham’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/startuplessons.html&quot;&gt;(pg)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/startuplessons.html&quot;&gt;startup lessons:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_46584B2C564A5E58FAAE704E15060C7254E69C53C7B7A2AD131CC7D48A8C537D_1554084592164_Screenshot+from+2019-03-31+19-09-38.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took his advice. We kept talking to users and launching features to see what would stick. In those first four months, we added:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 client libraries&lt;/strong&gt;: Node, Ruby, Python, Java, .NET, PHP &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; server-side integrations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 mobile libraries&lt;/strong&gt; and native integrations for iOS + Android &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout that time, we only had one medium to announce our products: our &lt;strong&gt;blog&lt;/strong&gt;. We had no real press contacts, no analyst relations, and we certainly didn’t have any money to buy ads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we built and built, and we highlighted what we had built in our blog…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While publishing on our blog certainly helped us get the word out about what we were building, there was one problem with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We felt like it didn’t quite capture all of the questions our users had. It helped answer the question “what’s new with Segment?” But it totally ignored the question of “how should I think about analytics?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then, analytics was a relatively new concept for many companies. It wasn’t enough to just talk about features; we needed to help businesses understand the most effective ways to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help answer this question, we launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/academy/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytics Academy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/academy/&quot;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analytics Academy was our first foray into trying to create our own content marketing. We launched it over email to our users (as well as launching it &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5183824&quot;&gt;on HN&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_46584B2C564A5E58FAAE704E15060C7254E69C53C7B7A2AD131CC7D48A8C537D_1554089035368_Screenshot+from+2019-03-31+20-23-39.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The premise was simple. Each week, we’d release a new lesson promising to take you from zero to analytics expert. We hoped that it would be a good way to spread all of knowledge we’d gained from working in the analytics ecosystem for the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_46584B2C564A5E58FAAE704E15060C7254E69C53C7B7A2AD131CC7D48A8C537D_1554089261000_Screenshot+from+2019-03-31+20-27-16.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once again, it seemed like we’d hit on something that people wanted! The whole analytics ecosystem was confusing… there were hundreds of different vendors… and our content seemed like it could actually teach our users something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble was, it didn’t seem like our content was landing. We weren’t seeing it get re-shared, and the posts didn’t seem to resonate. It all felt lame compared to our earlier success on the blog. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ilya (one of the four of us) sent a draft post to his brother, Mike, who runs his own bootstrapped startup to ask for his feedback. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike had some brutal, but honest criticism for us on a post we did about Live Chat tools. He sent us back this email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is, do &lt;strong&gt;I feel I learned something unique/valuable from this article? I didn’t think so.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you guys give me something valuable here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Which chat products are better at what? / how are they different?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- How do you deal with chat volume? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- What are some best ways to use the customer feedback?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom line, &lt;strong&gt;give me some juicy knowledge that (a) puts me at ease with adding live chat and (b) gives me specific techniques for benefiting from it. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He pointed out that the Academy posts had piqued his interest… but not really delivered on their core goal: &lt;em&gt;to teach him about analytics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set out to do better with the next posts. For each one we focused on a set of specifics. Things that he could immediately take away to help his business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By March, we’d gotten to a better spot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_A78A8915BAB12839AFCC9ED17A310BA0491208035A2B51FD54914A43D4E844CA_1554175183407_image_preview+new.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That lesson has really stuck with us ever since. It’s been our goal for everything that goes on our blog that the content should be both specific and actionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up publishing six different tutorials, from dashboarding to live chat and email tools. It wasn’t easy, but now the academy is still one of our most popular pieces of content to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite our first taste of success in product-market fit, we started to hit some serious problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May, our funding was starting to dry up. We still hadn’t started charging for the product, and we were looking at about three months of runway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set out to raise $1m as part of a bigger seed round at an $8m valuation. We had public pricing on our site, promising traction and a lot of momentum, but we were still pre-revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter was doing the fundraising, and reached out to all of the investors on our radar. Of the dozens of emails we sent, 3 replied. Among them were e.Ventures and KPCB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea of where the business was at, I’ve included the full set of slides from our &lt;strong&gt;2013 “Series Seed” pitch deck&lt;/strong&gt; down below. Following &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/intro-to-the-yc-seed-deck/&quot;&gt;the advice of YC&lt;/a&gt;, we included: 1) extremely clear descriptions of the product 2) the relevant pre-revenue metrics 3) a set of ideas for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started with a simple description of the product, and a few screenshots to give investors a grounding in what Segment does. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/kxowq4zy0lutapv/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2015.52.44.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/jzztknkujcc2ay1/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2015.55.09.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;At its heart, Segment is a technical product, so explaining what it does and how it works is key. We’d just launched our mobile libraries a few weeks before, and we were riding off the momentum of our new releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides 3 &amp;amp; 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next came our growth numbers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/hqfx5oq8jlpglm0/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2015.56.10.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/cfkxt2cyn03tul8/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2016.04.06.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The primary metric that mattered to us &lt;strong&gt;was the number of new projects&lt;/strong&gt; (our name for sources at the time) &lt;strong&gt;sending data.&lt;/strong&gt; Our pricing was based upon data volume, and each new project would be paying us at least $10 a month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The charts shown in the second slide were the ones that we were looking at week over week. Oddly enough, instead of using an analytics tool (we use Mode over Redshift today), we had hooked up a Google sheet. We’ve always loved being able to look at the raw data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top left graph shows the number of active projects sending data. You can see that it grows linearly, sometimes dipping on weekends when the smaller projects sent no data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom left graph shows the percentage of signups who are actually creating a project (the first step in our funnel). The bottom right graph shows the percentage of projects that actually get to the point of sending data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We put these up on a dashboard in our apartment and monitored them religiously. You can see where we fixed our signup flow to ‘auto-create’ projects about two weeks in, and steadily started seeing higher levels of activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides 5 &amp;amp; 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we didn’t have much (read: next-to-zero) revenue to speak of at this point, we thought ‘social proof’ would be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/tihxe4ajp14bpzv/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2016.06.32.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/djzlc4wqr0g70yw/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2016.17.27.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last slide became pivotal when we later went to raise our Series A, though looking back on it, we realize how cheeky it was to include at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we made it clear to investors, none of these companies actually &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; Segment at the time. They had all expressed interest, and the intent of things they wanted to do. But we hadn’t convinced any of them to actually use the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we began to raise our Series A one year later, we re-presented this same exact slide, but proudly noted: &lt;em&gt;“a year ago, these six prospects expressed interest. Today, five of the six names on here have become customers.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Segment was here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides 7 &amp;amp; 8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To really drive the point home, we included a few slides positioning ourselves in the market, how we might monetize, and spelled out the benefits of using Segment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_A78A8915BAB12839AFCC9ED17A310BA0491208035A2B51FD54914A43D4E844CA_1554174535411_Screen+Shot+2019-04-01+at+8.08.24+PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s changed the most today is how we monetize.&lt;/strong&gt; Back then we thought revenue sharing with partners might be a good idea, but that ended up being a small revenue stream and a conflict of interest in advising customers on the best tools, so we no longer practice revenue sharing with our partners. Instead, we only receive revenue from our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/9y8dazqzgpufmku/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2016.27.07.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We no longer charge for premium integrations either&lt;/strong&gt;. We realized quickly that users get the most value from Segment when they integrate more tools. Making users think twice before enabling an integration felt like it was hurting our customers and ourselves more than it helped. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slide 9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, we wanted to share a few of our ideas for the future. Building a simple way to integrate different tools felt like step 1 for Segment. We saw our bigger path forward as creating the platform for customer data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ukicn4klrp4m7y8/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2016.29.57.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We eventually integrated with 2/3 of these companies (we never got the chance with &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/20/amazons-aws-acquired-amiato/&quot;&gt;Amiato, who was acquired by Amazon&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the launch of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/the-growth-stacks-of-2019/&quot;&gt;Developer Center last month&lt;/a&gt;, this promise has become more and more of a reality. Since that time, &lt;strong&gt;we’ve added 180 integrations.&lt;/strong&gt; In the past month alone, we’ve added &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/webaficionado/status/1103012975894392832&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25 new integrations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, all built atop Segment Data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides 10 &amp;amp; 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we explained our ambitions: to be the infrastructure that lets you manage your customer data. As we’ve grown, this pitch has been largely consistent. Segment is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to send your first-party data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_A78A8915BAB12839AFCC9ED17A310BA0491208035A2B51FD54914A43D4E844CA_1554174734241_Screen+Shot+2019-04-01+at+8.11.53+PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We wrapped up by sharing every credential we could find within reach. It was a short list for four people who had never worked ‘real’ jobs before… 2 years of experience was enough to make us dangerous though  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/pbjbww03pg06f6l/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2017.21.01.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that was it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We closed $2M in new funding from e.ventures and KPCB, which gave us the necessary runway to make it through the next year, and blow past our first milestone of $1M in annual recurring revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the email Peter sent to Ray, our partner at KPCB, just after the round closed at $2m raised on $10.5m post-money valuation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_A78A8915BAB12839AFCC9ED17A310BA0491208035A2B51FD54914A43D4E844CA_1554174884672_Screenshot+2019-03-28+15+new.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We began hiring for engineering, customer success, and sales that November. And we had our first annual contracts booked in November 2013. We grew from 4 to 10 people that year, and set ourselves on the road to scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since those early days, Segment has grown enormously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;17.839285714286&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;analytics.js from the original Show HN is now loaded &lt;strong&gt;15 billion&lt;/strong&gt; distinct times per month across &lt;strong&gt;1 billion&lt;/strong&gt; distinct devices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;our data volume has grown by &lt;strong&gt;10,000x&lt;/strong&gt;, now processing &lt;strong&gt;over 100,000 messages per second&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2.8529411764706&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we now power the customer data infrastructure for some of the worlds largest brands, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/enterprise/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IBM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/enterprise/&quot;&gt;,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/enterprise/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21st Century Fox, Intuit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/enterprise/&quot;&gt;, and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/enterprise/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VMWare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-0.4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve re-branded from &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8427713&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Segment.io to Segment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8427713&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(and&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8427713&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;got the .com!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve expanded the Segment platform and grown our integrations catalog from &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/catalog/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 integrations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/catalog/&quot;&gt;to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/catalog/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more than 250&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;our users now enable over &lt;strong&gt;80,000&lt;/strong&gt; new destinations over the course of the year, which equates to one integration enabled every &lt;strong&gt;1.4 minutes&lt;/strong&gt; of every workday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0.484375&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve built out detailed views for understanding both &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/the-new-live-debugger/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;data coming in to Segment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/new-data-visibility-features/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;data going out to all of our destinations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1.3555555555556&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve added &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-segment-warehouses-redshift-postgres/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;support for data warehouses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and ETL from &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cloud sources like&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tripe,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alesforce, and&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Z&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;endesk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, syncing 20B+ rows each day &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve added &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;e-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;uplication to ensure messages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are processed correctly even in the face of flaky networks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve re-written our core pipeline to &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-centrifuge/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;improve the delivery and retry behavior in the face of downstream failures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0.14864864864865&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;released a &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/config-api-convenient-and-extensible-workspace-configuration/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;public API for managing workspaces, sources, and destinations &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0.69473684210526&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/put-your-customers-first-with-personas/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;our second product, Personas,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which provides audience management atop our core product&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1.281045751634&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;released our third product, &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-protocols/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protocols, a product to help enforce your tracking plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and our users have created &lt;strong&gt;500&lt;/strong&gt; different tracking plans for customers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;become &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/security/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISO certified,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/security/&quot;&gt;and released a new&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/security/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bug bounty program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the team has grown from &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;350+&lt;/strong&gt;, now spread across &lt;strong&gt;5 offices&lt;/strong&gt; globally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To power all of those product improvements, we’ve also made a number of infrastructure changes. Since our first launch in 2012, we:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, some things haven’t changed. Our blog is still our primary avenue for launching product. We keep open-sourcing our internal tools to share with the community. We keep reading every HN comment and tweet about the business. And we continue to share what we’ve learned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of all, we’ve just kept trying to build momentum and create value for our customers. Not all of our bets have panned out. But as long as we continue to make bets, &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of them will. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this most recent fundraise, we have three new ways we want to serve our customers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Continue building out the platform&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past 6 years, we’ve gone from &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; integrations to more than &lt;strong&gt;250&lt;/strong&gt;. This year, we are focusing on expanding on that number in a major way. We’ll be continuing to provide more powerful ways to integrate via our &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/partners/integration/&quot;&gt;developer center&lt;/a&gt;, and continuing to onboard new partners into the Segment ecosystem. This month alone, we’ve added &lt;strong&gt;25 new partners integrated with Segment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Iterating on our pricing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve heard the feedback that our pricing can be expensive for early-stage, high volume, consumer-focused startups.  We’ve already taken a first step to address this with &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/startups/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;our startup program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/startups/&quot;&gt;gives away two years of Segment for free&lt;/a&gt;. And as we speak we’re working with startups all over the world to figure out a pricing structure that will work better for them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Giving you superpowers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our renewed goal this year is to “give you superpowers”. We have a number of products in our pipeline that should give you unparalleled ways of managing your data pipelines, all without changing your tracking code. Advanced filtering, workflows, and privacy products are coming down the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a more personal note, we want to thank everyone who has been along for the ride. To this day, the four of us still re-forward 5-year-old emails from our earliest users and customers. Your excitement about the product gave us the conviction to keep building.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without you, Segment would have been another failed side project. With your help, we’re now able to help thousands of business provide world-class experiences for their customers. And tomorrow, we’re looking forward to helping tens of thousands more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-The Segment Founders&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fullung</dc:creator>
<og:title>From Show HN to Series D</og:title>
<og:url>https://segment.com/blog</og:url>
<og:description></og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.contents.io/asset_PD2Ig3qA.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://segment.com/blog/show-hn-to-series-d/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I tried creating a web browser, and Google blocked me</title>
<link>https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/images/google-widevine-gmail.png&quot; alt=&quot;I'm sorry but we're not supporting an open source solution like this&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 4 months of waiting, that is the response I got from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.widevine.com/&quot;&gt;Widevine&lt;/a&gt;, Google’s DRM for web browsers. For the last 2 years I’ve been working on a web browser that now cannot be completed because Google, the creators of the &lt;em&gt;open source&lt;/em&gt; browser Chrome, won’t allow DRM in an &lt;em&gt;open source&lt;/em&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The browser I’m building, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samuelmaddock/metastream&quot;&gt;Metastream&lt;/a&gt;, is an Electron-based (Chromium derived), MIT-licensed browser hosted on GitHub. Its main feature is the ability to playback videos on the web, synchronized with other peers. Each client runs its own instance of the Metastream browser and transmits playback information to keep them in sync.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone is creating a browser that wants to playback media, they’ll soon discover the requirement of DRM for larger web media services such as Netflix and Hulu. There are a few DRM providers for the web including Widevine, PlayReady, and FairPlay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I’m aware, Widevine is the only available DRM for a Chromium-based browser, especially so for Electron. Chromium accounts for roughly &lt;strong&gt;70% market share&lt;/strong&gt; of all web browsers, soon to include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.windowscentral.com/microsoft-building-chromium-powered-web-browser-windows-10&quot;&gt;Microsoft’s upcoming Edge browser rewrite&lt;/a&gt;. Waiting 4 months for a minimal response from a vendor with such a large percentage of the market is unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t something I’m alone in either, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/electron/electron/issues/12427&quot;&gt;several Electron users&lt;/a&gt; have waited months for a response. More prominently, the creators of Brave Browser also had &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brave/browser-laptop/issues/10449#issuecomment-323800130&quot;&gt;issues waiting for replies from Google Widevine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This is a prime example for why free as in beer is not enough. Small share browsers are at the mercy of Google, and Google is stalling us for no communicated-to-us reason.” - Brian Bondy, Co-founder &amp;amp; CTO of Brave&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m now only left with two options regarding the fate of Metastream: stop development of a desktop browser version, or pivot my project to a browser extension with reduced features. The latter requiring publishing to the Google Chrome Web Store which would further entrench the project into a Google walled garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know of any way to help out, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/contact&quot;&gt;please get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19553941&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;See post on Hacker News for discussion thread.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 13:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>smaddock</dc:creator>
<og:title>I tried creating a web browser, and Google blocked me</og:title>
<og:description>After 4 months of waiting, that is the response I got from Widevine, Google’s DRM for web browsers. For the last 2 years I’ve been working on a web browser that now cannot be completed because Google, the creators of the open source browser Chrome, won’t allow DRM in an open source project. The browser I’m building, called Metastream, is an Electron-based (Chromium derived), MIT-licensed browser hosted on GitHub. Its main feature is the ability to playback videos on the web, synchronized with other peers.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://samuelmaddock.github.io/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/</og:url>
<og:image>https://samuelmaddock.github.io/images/chromium-cover-social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google’s constant product shutdowns are damaging its brand</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/04/googles-constant-product-shutdowns-are-damaging-its-brand/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/04/googles-constant-product-shutdowns-are-damaging-its-brand/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/3-800x369.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An artist's rendering of Google's current reputation.&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;461&quot; data-width=&quot;1000&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; An artist's rendering of Google's current reputation.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Aurich Lawson&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;270 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/04/googles-constant-product-shutdowns-are-damaging-its-brand/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;270 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/04/googles-constant-product-shutdowns-are-damaging-its-brand/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;376&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 270 posters participating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's only April, and 2019 has already been an absolutely brutal year for Google's product portfolio. The Chromecast Audio &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/01/google-kills-the-chromecast-audio/&quot;&gt;was discontinued January 11&lt;/a&gt;. YouTube annotations were &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2683267&quot;&gt;removed and deleted&lt;/a&gt; January 15. Google Fiber &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/02/google-fiber-exits-louisville-after-shoddy-installs-left-exposed-wires-in-roads/&quot;&gt;packed up and left&lt;/a&gt; a Fiber city on February 8. Android Things &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/02/android-things-is-no-longer-for-things-focuses-on-smart-speakers-and-displays/&quot;&gt;dropped IoT support&lt;/a&gt; on February 13. Google's &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/03/google-hardware-makes-cuts-to-laptop-and-tablet-development-cancels-products/&quot;&gt;laptop and tablet division&lt;/a&gt; was reportedly slashed on March 12. &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/12/google-promises-to-shut-down-two-of-its-seven-messaging-apps/&quot;&gt;Google Allo&lt;/a&gt; shut down on March 13. The &quot;Spotlight Stories&quot; VR studio &lt;a href=&quot;https://variety.com/2019/digital/news/google-spotlight-stories-shutting-down-1203163117/&quot;&gt;closed its doors&lt;/a&gt; on March 14. The goo.gl URL shortener &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.googleblog.com/2018/03/transitioning-google-url-shortener.html&quot;&gt;was cut off from new users&lt;/a&gt; on March 30. Gmail's &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ifttt.com/hc/en-us/articles/360020249393-Important-update-about-Gmail-on-IFTTT&quot;&gt;IFTTT support&lt;/a&gt; stopped working March 31.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And today, April 2, we're having a Google Funeral double-header: both &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/01/google-shuts-down-april-2-all-data-will-be-deleted/&quot;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; (for consumers) &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/09/google-kills-google-inbox/&quot;&gt;Google Inbox&lt;/a&gt; are being laid to rest. Later this year, Google Hangouts &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RonAmadeo/status/1070755806264610820&quot;&gt;Classic&lt;/a&gt;&quot; will &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/01/the-great-google-hangouts-shutdown-begins-october-2019/&quot;&gt;start to wind down,&lt;/a&gt; and somehow also scheduled for 2019 is Google Music's &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/05/youtube-music-will-replace-google-play-music-but-wont-kill-user-uploads/&quot;&gt;&quot;migration&quot;&lt;/a&gt; to YouTube Music, with the Google service being put on death row sometime afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are 91 days into the year, and so far, Google is racking up an unprecedented body count. If we just take the official shutdown dates that have already occurred in 2019, a Google-branded product, feature, or service has died, on average, about every nine days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these product shutdowns have transition plans, and some of them (like Google+) represent Google completely abandoning a user base. The specifics aren't crucial, though. What matters is that every single one of these actions has a negative consequence for Google's brand, and the near-constant stream of shutdown announcements makes Google seem more unstable and untrustworthy than it has ever been. Yes, there was the one time Google killed Google Wave &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2010/08/wave-cancellation-google-gives-up-on-next-gen-messaging/&quot;&gt;nine years ago&lt;/a&gt; or when it took Google Reader away &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2013/06/its-time-to-say-goodbye-to-google-reader-and-hello-to-something-new/&quot;&gt;six years ago,&lt;/a&gt; but things were never this bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while there has been a subset of people concerned about Google's privacy and antitrust issues, but now Google is eroding trust that &lt;em&gt;its existing customers&lt;/em&gt; have in the company. That's a huge problem. Google has significantly harmed its brand over the last few months, and I'm not even sure the company realizes it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google products &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; trust and investment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/26-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot; data-height=&quot;377&quot; data-width=&quot;1500&quot; alt=&quot;The latest batch of dead and dying Google apps. &quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/26-1-640x161.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;161&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/26-1-1280x322.jpg 2x&quot; alt=&quot;The latest batch of dead and dying Google apps. &quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/26-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;377&quot; data-width=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; The latest batch of dead and dying Google apps.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google is a platform company. Be it cloud compute, app and extension ecosystems, developer APIs, advertising solutions, operating-system pre-installs, or the storage of user data, Google constantly asks for investment from consumers, developers, and partner companies in the things it builds. Any successful platform will pretty much require trust and buy-in from these groups. These groups need to feel the platform they invest in today will be there tomorrow, or they'll move on to something else. If any of these groups loses faith in Google, it could have disastrous effects for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumers want to know the photos, videos, and emails they upload to Google will stick around. If you buy a Chromecast or Google Home, you need to know the servers and ecosystems they depend on will continue to work, so they don't turn into fancy paperweights tomorrow. If you take the time to move yourself, your friends, and your family to &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2016/09/google-allo-is-incomplete-but-assistant-is-the-companys-future/&quot;&gt;a new messaging service&lt;/a&gt;, you need to know it won't be &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/04/google-gives-up-on-google-allo-hopes-carriers-will-sort-out-rcs-messaging/&quot;&gt;shut down&lt;/a&gt; two years later. If you begrudgingly join a new social network that was &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2013/11/youtube-tries-to-stem-the-flow-of-a-new-kind-of-terrible-comments/&quot;&gt;forced down your throat&lt;/a&gt;, you need to know it won't &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/10/google-exposed-non-public-data-for-500k-users-then-kept-it-quiet/&quot;&gt;leak your data&lt;/a&gt; everywhere, shut down, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/01/google-shuts-down-april-2-all-data-will-be-deleted/&quot;&gt;delete all your posts&lt;/a&gt; a few years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also enterprise customers, who, above all, like safe bets with established companies. The old adage of &quot;Nobody ever got fired for buying IBM&quot; is partly a reference for the enterprise's desire for a stable, steady, reliable tech partner. Google is trying to tackle this same market with its paid G Suite program, but the most it can do in terms of stability is &lt;a href=&quot;https://gsuite.google.com/whatsnew/calendar/&quot;&gt;post a calendar&lt;/a&gt; detailing the rollercoaster of consumer-oriented changes coming down the pipeline. There's a slower &quot;Scheduled release track&quot; that delays the rollout of some features, but things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/04/gmail-coms-massive-redesign-launches-today/&quot;&gt;a complete revamp&lt;/a&gt; of Gmail eventually all still arrive. G Suite has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gsuite.google.com/intl/en/terms/user_features.html&quot;&gt;&quot;Core Services&quot;&lt;/a&gt; list meant to show confidence in certain products sticking around, but some of the entries there, like Hangouts and Google Talk, still get shut down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;related-stories right&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;subheading notched&quot;&gt;Google kills product&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;read-more&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;recommendation-series&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/series/google-kills-product/&quot;&gt;View more stories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
Developers gamble on a platform's stability even more than consumers do. Consumers might trust a service with their data or spend money on hardware, but developers can spend &lt;em&gt;months&lt;/em&gt; building an app for a platform. They need to read documentation, set up SDKs, figure out how APIs work, possibly pay developer startup fees, and maybe even learn a new language. They won't do any of this if they don't have faith in the long-term stability of the platform.
&lt;p&gt;Developers can literally build their products around paid-access Google APIs like the Google Maps API, and when Google does things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://geoawesomeness.com/developers-up-in-arms-over-google-maps-api-insane-price-hike/&quot;&gt;raise the price&lt;/a&gt; of the Maps API by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inderapotheke.de/blog/farewell-google-maps&quot;&gt;14x for some use cases&lt;/a&gt;, it is incredibly disruptive for those businesses and harmful to Google's brand. When apps like Reddit clients are flagged by Google Play &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/androiddev/comments/96kpsf/more_issues_with_google_play_suspended_for_hate/&quot;&gt;every other month&lt;/a&gt;&quot; for the crime of displaying user-generated content and when it's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/androiddev/comments/9n88wv/the_future_of_android_development/&quot;&gt;impossible to talk to a human&lt;/a&gt; at Google about anything, developers are less likely to invest in your schizophrenic ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardware manufacturers and other company partners need to be able to trust a company, too. Google constantly asks hardware developers to build devices dependent on its services. These are things like Google Assistant-compatible speakers and smart displays, devices with Chromecast built in, and Android and Chrome OS devices. Manufacturers need to know a certain product or feature they are planning to integrate will be around for &lt;em&gt;years, s&lt;/em&gt;ince they need to both commit to a potentially multi-year planning and development cycle, and then it needs to survive long enough for customers to be supported for a few years. Watching Android Things chop off a major segment of its market nine months after launch would certainly make me nervous to develop anything based on Android Things. Imagine the risk Volvo is taking by integrating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/02/the-volvo-polestar-2-is-the-first-google-android-car/&quot;&gt;new Android Auto OS&lt;/a&gt; into its upcoming Polestar 2: vehicles need around five years of development time and still need to be supported for several years after launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google’s shutdowns cast a shadow over the entire company&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so many shutdowns, tracking Google's bodycount has become a competitive industry on the Internet. Over on Wikipedia, the list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Google_products#Discontinued_products_and_services&quot;&gt;discontinued Google products and services&lt;/a&gt; is starting to approach the size of the active products and services listed. There are entire sites dedicated to discontinued Google products, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://killedbygoogle.com/&quot;&gt;killedbygoogle.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gcemetery.co/&quot;&gt;The Google Cemetery&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://didgoogleshutdown.com&quot;&gt;didgoogleshutdown.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we're seeing a lot of the consequences of Google's damaged brand in the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/03/google-jumps-into-gaming-with-google-stadia-streaming-service/&quot;&gt;Google Stadia&lt;/a&gt; launch. A game streaming platform from one of the world's largest Internet companies should be grounds for excitement, but instead, the baggage of the Google brand has people asking if they can trust the service to stay running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the endless memes and jokes you'll see in every related comments section, you're starting to see Google skepticism in mainstream reporting, too. Over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/games/2019/mar/20/google-stadia-what-developers-think-of-the-game-streaming-service&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, this line makes the pullquote: &quot;A potentially sticky fact about Google is that the company does have a habit of losing interest in its less successful projects.&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/03/19/google-is-better-positioned-for-cloud-streaming-than-anyone-but-dont-expect-the-world-just-yet&quot;&gt;IGN&lt;/a&gt; has a whole section of a report questioning &quot;Google's Commitment.&quot; From a &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/QqG3qdi8NXo?t=1651&quot;&gt;Digital Foundry&lt;/a&gt; video: &quot;Google has this reputation for discontinuing services that are often good, out of nowhere.&quot; One of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slashgear.com/google-stadia-5-big-questions-that-still-need-answers-22570811/&quot;&gt;SlashGear's&lt;/a&gt; &quot;Stadia questions that need answers&quot; is &quot;Can I trust you, Google?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/chrome_2019-03-28_13-17-02.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot; data-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot; alt=&quot;Google's Phil Harrison talks about the new Google Stadia controller. &quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/chrome_2019-03-28_13-17-02-640x360.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/chrome_2019-03-28_13-17-02-1280x720.png 2x&quot; alt=&quot;Google's Phil Harrison talks about the new Google Stadia controller. &quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/chrome_2019-03-28_13-17-02.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; Google's Phil Harrison talks about the new Google Stadia controller.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite examples came from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://kotaku.com/google-stadia-boss-answers-and-dodges-our-questions-1833422137&quot;&gt;Kotaku&lt;/a&gt; interview with Phil Harrison, the leader of Google Stadia. In an audio interview, the site lays this whopper of a question on him: &quot;One of the sentiments we saw in our comments section a lot is that Google has a long history of starting projects and then abandoning them. There's a worry, I think, from users who might think that Google Stadia is a cool platform, but if I'm connecting to this and spending money on this platform, how do I know for sure that Google is still sticking with it for two, three, five years? How can you guys make a commitment that Google will be sticking with this in a way that they haven't stuck with Google+, or Google Hangouts, or Google Fiber, Reader, or all the other things Google has abandoned over the years?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yikes&lt;/em&gt;. Kotaku is totally justified to ask a question like this, but to have one of your new executives face questions of &quot;When will your new product shut down?&quot; must be embarrassing for Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harrison's response to this question started with a surprisingly honest acknowledgement: &quot;&lt;em&gt;I understand the concern.&lt;/em&gt;&quot; Harrison, seemingly, &lt;em&gt;gets it&lt;/em&gt;. He seemingly understands that it's hard to trust Google after so many product shutdowns, and he knows the Stadia team now faces an uphill battle. For the record, Harrison went on to cite Google's sizable investment in the project, saying Stadia was &quot;Not a trivial product&quot; and was a &quot;significant cross-company effort.&quot; (Also for the record: you could say all the same things about Google+ a few years ago, when &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2011/06/inside-google-how-the-search-giant-plans-to-go-social/&quot;&gt;literally every Google employee&lt;/a&gt; was paid to work on it. Now it is dead.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harrison and the rest of the Stadia team had nothing to do with the closing of Google Inbox, or the shutdown of Hangouts, or the removal of any other popular Google product. They are still forced to deal with the consequences of being associated with &quot;Google the Product Killer,&quot; though. If Stadia was an Amazon product, I don't think we would see these questions of when it would shut down. Microsoft's game streaming service, Project xCloud, only faces questions about feasibility and appeal, not if Microsoft will get bored in two years and dump the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Listing image by &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/author/aurich-lawson/&quot;&gt;Aurich Lawson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 12:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vanburen</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/04/googles-constant-product-shutdowns-are-damaging-its-brand/</og:url>
<og:title>Google’s constant product shutdowns are damaging its brand</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/3-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Google's product support has become a joke, and the company should be very concerned.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/04/googles-constant-product-shutdowns-are-damaging-its-brand/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The MacBook keyboard fiasco is way worse than Apple thinks</title>
<link>https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-macbook-keyboard-fiasco-is-surely-worse-than-apple-thinks/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-macbook-keyboard-fiasco-is-surely-worse-than-apple-thinks/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Apple keep insisting that only a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/27/18284042/apple-macbook-keyboard-apology-issues-bad-design&quot;&gt;small number of customers have problems&lt;/a&gt;” with the MacBook keyboards. That’s bollocks. This is a huge issue, it’s getting worse not better, and Apple is missing the forest for the trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact is that many people simply do not contact Apple when their MacBook keyboards fail. They just live with an S key that stutters or a spacebar that intermittently gives double. Or they just start &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/meabed/status/1111034845042540544&quot;&gt;using&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kraustifer/status/1111087221086408704&quot;&gt;an&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/farhadino/status/1110985745957830663&quot;&gt;external&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/whalio_p/status/1110979261219913728&quot;&gt;keyboard&lt;/a&gt;. Apple never sees these cases, so it never counts in their statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s some anecdata for Apple. I sampled the people at Basecamp. Out of the 47 people using MacBooks at the company, a staggering 30% are dealing with keyboard issues right now!! And that’s just the people dealing with &lt;em&gt;current&lt;/em&gt; keyboard issues. If you include all the people who used to have issues, but went through a repair or replacement process, the number would be even higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;11388&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-macbook-keyboard-fiasco-is-surely-worse-than-apple-thinks/screen-shot-2019-04-01-at-1-44-36-pm/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-01-at-1.44.36-PM.png?fit=1490%2C1164&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1490,1164&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-04-01 at 1.44.36 PM&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-01-at-1.44.36-PM.png?fit=600%2C469&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-01-at-1.44.36-PM.png?fit=640%2C500&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-01-at-1.44.36-PM.png?w=640&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-11388&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-01-at-1.44.36-PM.png?w=1490&amp;amp;ssl=1 1490w, https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-01-at-1.44.36-PM.png?resize=600%2C469&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-01-at-1.44.36-PM.png?resize=768%2C600&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-01-at-1.44.36-PM.png?w=1280&amp;amp;ssl=1 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worth noting here is that the 3rd generation membrane keyboard did nothing to fix the issues. Six out of thirteen – nearly half!! – of the 2018+ MacBooks we have at the company have a failed keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I backed up those figures with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh/status/1112804750263693312&quot;&gt;a Twitter poll&lt;/a&gt; that has over 7,000 respondents already. That’s a 63% failure rate!! But Apple is only seeing 11% of those, as the vast majority of customers are simply just living with their broken computer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;11394&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-macbook-keyboard-fiasco-is-surely-worse-than-apple-thinks/image-5/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-1.png?fit=1222%2C698&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1222,698&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;0&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;image&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-1.png?fit=600%2C343&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-1.png?fit=640%2C366&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-1.png?w=640&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-11394&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-1.png?w=1222&amp;amp;ssl=1 1222w, https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-1.png?resize=600%2C343&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i0.wp.com/m.signalvnoise.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-1.png?resize=768%2C439&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a disaster. A complete unmitigated disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as always, in a time of crisis, the event itself is less indicative of the health of a company than the response. Is Apple going to accept that they’re currently alienating and undermining decades of goodwill by shipping broken computers in mass quantities?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 12:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>marvindanig</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The MacBook keyboard fiasco is way worse than Apple thinks</og:title>
<og:url>https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-macbook-keyboard-fiasco-is-surely-worse-than-apple-thinks/</og:url>
<og:description>Apple keep insisting that only a “small number of customers have problems” with the MacBook keyboards. That’s bollocks. This is a huge issue, it’s getting worse not better, …</og:description>
<og:image>https://egbdmrh4mm2nyyyh-zippykid.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-1.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-macbook-keyboard-fiasco-is-surely-worse-than-apple-thinks/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Difference Between ‘Violet’ and ‘Purple’ (2015)</title>
<link>https://jakubmarian.com/difference-between-violet-and-purple/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jakubmarian.com/difference-between-violet-and-purple/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jakubmarian.com/images/bulb.png&quot; class=&quot;unprotected&quot;/&gt; Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; See my list of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jakubmarian.com/english-mistakes/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jakubmarian.com/images/book.png&quot; class=&quot;unprotected&quot;/&gt; Most&lt;/span&gt; Common Mistakes in English&lt;/a&gt;. It will teach you how to avoid mis­takes with com­mas, pre­pos­i­tions, ir­reg­u­lar verbs, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;indent&quot;&gt;People say that a picture is worth a thousand words, so let’s take a look at the two colours in comparison (there are various shades of purple and violet, and the following picture shows some of the more common ones):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://jakubmarian.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/violet-purple-palette.png&quot; alt=&quot;violet-purple-palette&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-18962&quot; data-copyright=&quot;© Jakub Marian, jakubmarian.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;no-indent&quot;&gt;So, purple is more reddish and saturated, while violet is more bluish and less saturated. Case closed, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more in it than the eyes can see (quite literally). To understand the difference, we have to take a look at how our eyes work first. The electromagnetic spectrum is a continuous range of wavelengths, only a tiny part of which is visible to humans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://jakubmarian.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/spectrum.png&quot; alt=&quot;spectrum&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;47&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-18967&quot; data-copyright=&quot;© Jakub Marian, jakubmarian.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We see neither the ultraviolet wavelengths and shorter, nor the infrared wavelengths and longer. How do we see the rest? We have &lt;strong&gt;three types of colour-sensitive cells&lt;/strong&gt; in our eyes, so-called &lt;em&gt;cones&lt;/em&gt;. The cones don’t perceive just a single wavelength; they are activated by a whole range of wavelengths, and the signals received from the cones are then processed by the brain in such a way that every colour can be thought of as composed of three different elementary signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following picture shows approximately how the brain perceives different spectral colours (the higher the curve, the higher the intensity of the elementary signal the brain receives):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://jakubmarian.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/color-cones.png&quot; alt=&quot;color-cones&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-18978&quot; data-copyright=&quot;© Jakub Marian, jakubmarian.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that this chart does not show the spectral properties of the cones themselves (but they look similar). It represents the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CIE_1931_color_space&quot;&gt;CIE 1931&lt;/a&gt; colour space, which, simply put, corresponds to the signals after they have been processed by the brain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, when you see monochromatic (pure) red light on the very right side of the spectrum, only the “red” signal path is activated, which tells your brain to create the impression of red. On the other hand, when you see pure green light (in the middle), both “green” and “red” paths are activated, but your brain knows that “a lot of green activation and a bit less red activation” is in fact just a pure green colour, which is what you see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a mixture of photons that have different wavelengths hits the retina (creating a ratio of red, green, and blue activation different from any spectral colour), the brain will perceive it as an entirely different colour. For example, there is no white wavelength. What we perceive as “white” is in fact just a mixture of many different spectral colours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What happens when violet light hits the retina?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “red” signal path has an interesting additional property. As you can see above, it has a small bump of activation around the short-wavelength (violet) end of the visible spectrum. When violet light hits the retina, both the “blue” path and (much less) the “red” path are activated. The brain interprets this kind of input in a specific way, which we call “violet”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that the pigment in the “green” cones themselves also has a small peak of absorption around violet wavelengths, but the brain seems to ignore it (it is not possible to simulate the perception of violet by a combination of green and blue light).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Purple is not a spectral colour&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indent&quot;&gt;As we noted before, many colours we can see are not in the visible spectrum. When you see an object, typically a mixture of different wavelengths reaches your retina, which causes the cones to be activated at a ratio not achievable by a spectral colour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our brains are very good at interpreting this mixture (it would be silly to simply throw away a part of the incoming information and make everything look like the closest spectral colour), and, as a result, we are able to see several million different colours, most of which are not present in the spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we noted at the beginning of the article, purple looks more “reddish” than violet, and that’s absolutely correct. Purple is formed by mixing red and blue in a ratio close to 1:1, whereas violet is perceived by your eyes as containing more blue than red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as you can see from the picture above, no spectral colour activates the “blue” path and the “red” path at the ratio of 1:1 without also stimulating the “green” path. In other words purple is not a spectral colour. You can have a source of monochromatic violet light (i.e. a source producing just a single wavelength), but everything that looks purple must emit both red and blue light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Purple and violet look similar only to humans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To us, humans, purple looks like a more saturated shade of violet, but violet objects in nature are fundamentally different from purple ones. Purple objects are “red and blue at the same time”, whereas violet objects are… just violet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indent&quot;&gt;If you take a look at the distance between violet and blue in the picture of the spectrum above, it is about the same as the distance between green and orange. Purple is a mixture of red (which is at the opposite side of the spectrum than violet) and blue (which is relatively far from violet), so it is, in terms of wavelengths, a completely different colour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why purple and violet look similar to us is because they stimulate our cones in a similar way, but &lt;strong&gt;most other animals don’t share the same types of cones and “post-processing”&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that to other animals, purple and violet may look completely different!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine a violet flower petal with a purple pattern on it. Depending on the particular shades, this pattern might be completely invisible to us, while many other animals could see it as clearly as we can see an orange pattern on green background. Even common consumer cameras wouldn’t help us; they are designed to capture the same red-green-blue information as our eyes do, so even taking a photo of the petal and editing it in Photoshop would not uncover the pattern. Quite fascinating, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;34.444751381215&quot;&gt;
&lt;form action=&quot;https://jakubmarian.com/trap/&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; accept-charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; id=&quot;subform&quot; readability=&quot;8.7317880794702&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;subscribe-first-line&quot;&gt;Subscribe to my educational newsletter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to receive a weekly summary of new articles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter your email address below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, enter a valid email address:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You tried to submit the form &lt;strong&gt;very quickly&lt;/strong&gt; after opening this page. To confirm that you are a human, please, click on the button below again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 09:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hawski</dc:creator>
<og:title>Difference between ‘violet’ and ‘purple’</og:title>
<og:image>http://jakubmarian.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/purple-violet.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jakubmarian.com/difference-between-violet-and-purple/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Evernote failed to realize its potential</title>
<link>https://usefyi.com/evernote-history</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://usefyi.com/evernote-history</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Legendary investor, programmer, and Y Combinator co-founder Paul Graham once wrote that one of the best ways to come up with ideas for your next startup is to ask what product you wish someone else would make for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Stepan Pachikov, founder of Evernote, that product was a way to help him remember things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Pachikov first began working on what ultimately became Evernote back in 2002, his fascination with human memory stems from his experiences growing up in the former Soviet Union. To Pachikov, Evernote wasn’t just another app or a way to capitalize on Silicon Valley’s burgeoning obsession with personal productivity. It was an extension of the human mind itself that would let users remember everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote has come a long way since Pachikov began working on the app seventeen years ago. Evernote was and remains one of the best examples of what a freemium product can be. Despite this, Evernote has been plagued by a series of managerial missteps and failed product launches, and the company’s future is far from certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the things I’ll be exploring in this article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why timing was so crucial to Evernote’s success, and how co-founder and former CEO Phil Libin’s vision for the product created vital tailwind for Evernote’s growth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the company resisted investor pressure and remained true to their convictions about the value of Evernote as a freemium product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Evernote lost sight of its original vision and how this almost doomed the company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea for Evernote began with the personal quest of its founder, Stepan Pachikov. He aimed to solve a giant problem: overcoming the limitations of human memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2008-2011: Creating an Impossible Vision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepan Pachikov wanted to remember everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pachikov is one of Silicon Valley’s most visionary technologists. A pioneer of virtual reality, computerized handwriting analysis, and optical character recognition, Pachikov has spent much of his life working to solve some of computing’s most challenging problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trained in economic mathematics, Pachikov earned his doctorate in fuzzy logic from the Academy of Sciences of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics in Moscow. As a scientist living and working under Communist rule in Soviet Russia, Pachikov was no stranger to the forgotten. He saw firsthand how generations of culture and collective memory were jeopardized by the gradual collapse of Soviet Russia. With few ways to preserve them, even key moments from his own past had been lost to the march of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Even 30 years ago, I had already lost so much information. Names. Jokes. Phrases. Facts. I can study and re-learn what I have forgotten, but I cannot go back to my school years, my college years, and recollect what I knew. Teachers. Friends. Experiences. In the past 20 years, I have put 75,000 pictures into my photo database. But pictures from before that are lost.” — Stepan Pachikov, founder of Evernote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pachikov saw computers as a means of not only preserving individual and cultural memories, but also as a way to empower children growing up in the political and social turmoil of Russia in the 1980s. To that end, Pachikov began working with his friend and world-renowned chess grandmaster Garry Kasparov in 1986, and the two men formed the country’s first computer club in Moscow. Pachikov and Kasparov devised a way of encouraging Russian children to develop their handwriting skills under the guise of a simple game. This game ultimately became Paragraph, the world’s first commercial computerized handwriting recognition software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of Pachikov’s educational experiments were mixed, but his work attracted the attention of Apple, Inc., which asked Pachikov to develop his handwriting recognition software for the Newton handheld computer. Pachikov left the frigid temperatures of Moscow for the warmth of Cupertino in Northern California, and made a new home in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple’s Newton project—and, by extension, Paragraph—ultimately failed. Undeterred, Pachikov once again turned his attention to educating children. He embarked on a range of projects in the ’90s, including a cutting-edge virtual reality product that allowed children to learn about history by traveling back through time to the age of the ancient Greeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until 2002 that Pachikov began working on what would later become Evernote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from his lifelong obsession with preserving and expanding human memory, Pachikov’s career has been defined by the ambition of his ideas. Pachikov’s vision of the future has always been a step ahead of the technology of the day. Initially, Pachikov’s vision for Evernote was much closer to the brain-machine interfaces promised by neurotech companies such as Elon Musk’s Neuralink. Pachikov wanted to develop a technology that would serve as an intermediary between man and machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, despite the fantastical nature of Evernote as a concept, the product would have solidly practical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“When you can’t remember somebody’s name, you look stupid. Memory and smartness are integrated. We all have hundreds of thousands of pieces of information, but it’s useless if we can’t find any of it. In business, the worst thing we can say is, ‘Oh, I’m sorry, I forgot your name.’ This is a product I need myself.” — Stepan Pachikov, founder of Evernote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Pachikov’s nascent idea shared little in common with Google, both products were grounded in the same basic principle: in the future, knowing how to find information would be far more important than remembering information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pachikov worked on the prototype of Evernote (which was initially known as EverNote) for two years, and released a beta version of the tool for Windows in 2004. Pachikov’s decision to target Microsoft’s flagship operating system made sense. In 2002, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itworld.com/article/2804237/operating-systems/microsoft-dominance-of-os-market-grows--idc-study-says.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Microsoft controlled almost 94% of the client-side operating system market&lt;/a&gt;. Apple’s OS X, which had been released just a year previously in March 2001, accounted for little more than 2% of the market. Pachikov’s early prototype was a little rough around the edges, but much of the core functionality was there––including the electronic handwriting recognition tech that Pachikov had pioneered at Paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-screenshot-2004.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote 2004&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height=&quot;423&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phonearena.com/news/Two-thirds-of-app-users-in-U.S.-have-paid-for-at-least-one_id30191&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: phoneArena&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2006, on the other side of the United States in Boston, serial entrepreneur Phil Libin was planning his next move. Like Pachikov, Libin had emigrated from Russia to the United States as a young man. And, like Pachikov, Libin was fascinated by the limitations of human memory. Having launched and sold a successful e-commerce software company and an information technology security firm, Libin was researching the possibilities of augmenting human memory electronically. His third venture, which Libin called Ribbon, would be an organizational tool that would help people save and access the information they needed, when they needed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was then that Libin first heard about Pachikov’s EverNote project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EverNote and Ribbon were very similar in both form and function. However, Pachikov had made significant headway with EverNote by the time Libin was ready to begin developing his company’s own technology. Libin traveled from Boston to Silicon Valley to meet Pachikov and the two men decided to merge their two fledgling companies rather than compete with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Pachikov and Libin were dissatisfied with the limitations of the human mind. However, while both men were idealistic, even philosophic, about their idea, Libin possessed the keen eye for business that Pachikov lacked––a quality that Pachikov believed made Libin an ideal partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“[Phil Libin] was smart, educated, and I was completely confident that he would be a much better CEO than I was. His Russian is better than my English. I believed he would transform the company and make it successful.” — Stepan Pachikov, founder of Evernote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon the merging of the two companies, Libin set to work. One of Libin’s first tasks was to streamline the various internal projects that Pachikov and his team had been working on, and he insisted that the company focus the entirety of its efforts on refining the idea behind their product: empowering users to capture, search, and store any and all information, wherever they were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Libin’s most significant contribution to the growing company came very early on, when Libin steered Evernote away from Windows towards a bold new frontier––mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central premise behind Evernote was accessibility. If Evernote was to help people remember everything, then users had to be able to capture everything. That meant mobile. However, in 2006, mobile was far from the dominant platform it is today. Apple’s flagship iPhone wouldn’t be released for another year, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com/2011/08/11/evernote-phil-libin-interview/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;by Libin’s own admission&lt;/a&gt; betting big on mobile was exactly that—a gamble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“From the start, we made a big promise to our users—we would help them remember everything. In order to live up to that, Evernote would need to be easily accessible from every computer, phone or other device that a person used, for the rest of their lives. So, it wasn’t that we predicted the rise of mobile, as much as we felt that mobile would be critical to our success.” — Phil Libin, former CEO of Evernote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That gamble paid off. When the iPhone launched in 2007, Evernote was ready. The product looked and felt completely different from its earlier incarnation. Evernote’s aesthetic was sleek, clean, and stylish, and it felt fantastic to use on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-2008-screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote 2008&quot; width=&quot;1300&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20081201043203/http://www.evernote.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: Archive.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, what drove much of Evernote’s initial adoption wasn’t the aesthetic of its mobile app––it was the emergence of the App Store. Just as smartphone apps were a brand-new way of using software, app marketplaces were brand-new, ready-made distribution channels that offered developers immediate access to millions of potential users. Evernote’s engineers worked tirelessly to ensure that Evernote would be available as each new app marketplace launched, each of which expanded Evernote’s footprint considerably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libin’s singular focus drove much of Evernote’s initial development. In 2008, Evernote launched in a limited private beta that was aimed squarely at the cult of productivity that had taken root across Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-notebooks-notes-screenshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote Notebooks&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;222&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://keywordsuggest.org/gallery/431092.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: Keyword Suggest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libin’s vision for Evernote was a seamless experience that successfully bridged the gap between the physical and digital worlds. To accomplish this, Evernote treated every piece of information—from actual handwritten notes to saved URLs—as a “note,” which are organized into thematic “notebooks.” It’s a clever, familiar convention that Evernote uses to this day. Even early on, Evernote’s functionality was impressive. Users could save all kinds of information within seconds. Digitized handwritten notes, audio recordings, links, pictures taken on a user’s mobile device, saved images, to-do lists, clipped articles—virtually anything users could find online could be saved, archived, and synched across multiple devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the real brilliance of Evernote was its search functionality, what Libin described as “the electronic version of having something at the tip of your tongue.” Users could search for saved items using an amazing range of search criteria, including date, keyword, topic, location, contacts, or any combination of the above. Users could even download add-ons that allowed notes to be searched by the dominant color of an image. This made it much easier to find saved notes, as users only had to recall a single detail to start a search, much like the way our memories work. This wasn’t just vital to Evernote’s core purpose. It was essential in recreating the rewarding, satisfying feeling of remembering something that would come to define the experience of using Evernote as a product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Evernote finds the way your mind works and gives you more and more hooks into your memories.” — Andrew Sinkov, former VP of Marketing for Evernote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sense of fun and satisfaction was critical in Libin’s view. Evernote’s unique position in the rapidly growing personal productivity space wasn’t lost on the company’s CEO. Evernote faced incumbent competitors at every turn. Box, Dropbox, iCloud, and Google Drive were already dominating online storage. Instapaper offered web clipping tools, as did its main competitor, the now-defunct Spool. Evernote preceded the wave of free online image editing tools that began with the launch of Canva back in 2012, but Evernote’s image-editing tools were far from unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Libin, the experience of using Evernote would be its competitive advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libin’s product philosophy was responsible for one of Evernote’s few hardware-based flaws—storing data natively on users’ machines and devices. Libin believed that a responsive feel was crucial to the Evernote experience, and that the delay between searching for something and finding something should be infinitesimal. This is the same principle that drove much of Spotify’s early development. Daniel Ek wanted &lt;a href=&quot;https://producthabits.com/how-spotify-built-a-20-billion-business-by-changing-how-people-listen-to-music/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Spotify to feel like users had the entirety of the world’s music right on their hard drives&lt;/a&gt;. Libin wanted the Evernote experience to feel similarly responsive, and believed that this would be central to user satisfaction with that experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Libin was fighting a losing battle. As Evernote doubled down on native storage, every other service provider was focusing on the cloud. Although this decision didn’t create any existential problems for Evernote in 2008, it was the first sign that Evernote was diverging from the broader trends in tech that would cause the company so many headaches later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote launched as a freemium product. This was vitally important to Libin. He believed that Evernote would become increasingly valuable to users the longer they used the product and the more they captured and stored within it. As such, Libin wanted to make Evernote as sticky as possible—and he did so by making the free version of the product incredibly generous. There were virtually no feature restrictions or other incentives for users to upgrade from free to paid plans. In fact, the only benefit of upgrading to a paid, $5-per-month subscription was additional storage space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I don’t need to squeeze money out of you. I’ll have the rest of your life to take your money. It’s my long-term greedy strategy. Our slogan is, ‘We’d rather you stay than pay.'” — Phil Libin, former CEO of Evernote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libin’s attitudes toward freemium software may have been popular with Evernote’s growing userbase, but it was repellent to investors. One VC after another turned Libin’s company down. There were no complaints about the product—far from it—but there just wasn’t enough incentive for free users to upgrade to paid plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After struggling to secure institutional investment, Evernote entered into an agreement with a European VC that would have seen the company receive $10M in funding. On the morning in October 2008 when the two parties were due to meet to sign the papers, the investor canceled the meeting and pulled the offer of funding. With just three weeks’ worth of cash at hand, Libin came to the grim realization that Evernote as a company would not survive. With little money and fewer prospects, Libin agonized about how he would break the news to his team and employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was around that time that Libin received an email from a Swedish user who loved Evernote. The user, whose identity remains a secret to this day, told Libin that Evernote had made him happier and more productive. However, the Swedish user didn’t want to just tell Libin how much they loved the app—they wanted to invest. Libin admitted that the company was in need of funding, at which point the mysterious Swedish Evernote evangelist offered to front the company $500,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote was saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“He was just a computer nerd and entrepreneur. He had some money and fell in love with our product, simple as that. It was just good luck. Had I gone to bed ten minutes earlier, I wouldn’t have opened his email right away and probably gone into work and closed the business.” — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanexpress.com/en-us/business/trends-and-insights/articles/phil-libin-of-evernote-building-an-empire/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Phil Libin&lt;/a&gt;, former CEO of Evernote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote’s anonymous benefactor didn’t just save the company, they opened the door to the kind of institutional investment Evernote had been chasing before the global economy tanked. Evernote kicked off a series of funding rounds over the next two years that propelled the company to new heights of growth. The company started by raising $26M as part of its Series A round led by DoCoMo Capital in September 2009. Two months later in November 2009, Evernote raised another $10M as part of its Series B round led by Morgenthaler Ventures and Sequoia Capital. Just under a year later in October 2010, Evernote raised another $20M as part of its Series C round, again led by Sequoia, as well as another $50M as part of a venture round led by Sequoia in July 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote had gone from venture capital pariah to Silicon Valley darling in less than three years, raising a total of more than $100M in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libin’s company took full advantage of its sudden reversal of fortunes, using much of its new funding to expand its engineering teams and expand beyond the company’s headquarters in Redwood City, California. One thing Evernote didn’t spend a cent of its newfound fortune on, however, was advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since launching in private beta in 2008, Evernote’s growth had been gradual, steady, and entirely organic. The product had more than 125,000 users before Evernote emerged from its closed beta, thanks in part to an article on TechCrunch that drove several thousand sign-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-user-growth-overview-graph-2011.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote User Growth 2011&quot; width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/nasakin/evernote-overview-sept-2011&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: SlideShare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the closed beta, Evernote was invite-only. However, while many products use invites as a marketing strategy to capitalize on exclusivity of access, Evernote did so out of an abundance of caution. Between the technical overhead of synchronizing native applications across multiple platforms in real time and working with a new type of backend server architecture, Libin’s engineers were more concerned with the stability of their systems than manufacturing hype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The fact that you have to sign up and send around invites to get in actually generated some buzz. That was never our intention; we never thought of the closed beta as a marketing exercise. We were frankly terrified that everything would crash all the time.” — &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.doeswhat.com/2012/02/25/interview-with-phil-libin-evernote&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Phil Libin&lt;/a&gt;, former CEO of Evernote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote’s freemium model may have been a dislike for investors, but Libin’s instincts about slow-burn, long-term growth had been proven right. In early 2011, just three years after launching, Evernote became profitable. Evernote had 80 employees, more than 10M users, and annual sales of approximately $16M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having been dangerously close to the brink of disaster, Evernote had emerged from the global financial crisis not only unscathed, but flush with VC cash. The company had achieved profitability in just three years, and the future looked bright for Evernote––until the company began to lose its way in 2011 with a series of failed product launches that jeopardized everything the company had built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2011-2015: New Products, New Markets, New Problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote began the period from 2011 to 2015 in an incredibly strong position. Evernote was already profitable and had more money in the bank than it knew what to do with. The company was growing steadily, hiring new talent and expanding into new locations. And, most importantly, the product was attracting upward of a million new users every month. However, the honeymoon period didn’t last. In an attempt to diversify its revenue streams, the company embarked upon a series of disastrous product launches that confused users and investors alike—all of which took the company farther and farther away from the core vision of its founders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2011, Evernote released the first of three standalone products it would launch over the next six months: Evernote Peek. The first Smart Cover app for Apple’s newly released iPad 2, Peek was a simple trivia application that leveraged the responsive wake and sleep function of the iPad’s Smart Cover feature. Users could lift part of their iPad’s Smart Cover to see a trivia question on-screen. To reveal the answer, all they had to do was lift up the rest of the cover. Users could use either Peek’s questions or their own answers as the basis of Notebooks within the main Evernote app, but Peek offered users little real utility besides a momentary distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months later in December 2011, Evernote released two more standalone apps for iOS: Evernote Food and Evernote Hello. Essentially a simplified, specialized version of the main Evernote app, Evernote Food allowed users to record and log their meals in digital notebooks in much the same way the main Evernote app allowed them to capture and store everything else. Users could organize their culinary memories by tagging locations and other people, making it easier for users to remember what they ate, with whom, and where. The only real differences between Food and the main Evernote app were the integrations with Facebook and Twitter. Customers could use these integrations to share details of their last amazing meal with their networks, and some food-specific navigational elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-food-ui-screenshot-mobile.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote Food&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;952&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.behance.net/gallery/6761663/Evernote-Food-for-iOS&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: Behance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote Hello was an even stranger app than Evernote Food. The purpose of Hello was ostensibly to make it easier for users to remember people. Users could create contact listings within Hello in a similar way as adding a new contact in their phone. However, what made Hello such a bizarre—and ultimately damaging—product was the fact that everything in Evernote Hello had to be done manually. The app did not support &lt;a href=&quot;https://squareup.com/guides/nfc&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;near-field communication&lt;/a&gt; (NFC), the communication protocol that powers contactless payment systems such as Apple Pay and allows mobile devices to exchange small amounts of data. Hello didn’t even have a rudimentary electronic business card reader. Every field had to be completed by hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users and investors alike were completely baffled by Food and Hello. Firstly, the main Evernote app could already do everything Evernote Food could do and more. There was no incentive whatsoever for people to use Food over the main Evernote app. Secondly, the lack of NFC or e-card support for Hello was an unforgivable sin for a contact manager product. Asking either users themselves or their new acquaintances to enter contact details manually was an immense barrier for the product to overcome and one with virtually no payoff for users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-hello-screenshots.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote Hello&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;378&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elandroidelibre.elespanol.com/2012/05/evernote-hello-una-nueva-agenda-para-no-olvidar-a-tus-nuevos-contactos.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: El androide libre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn’t hard to see the reasoning behind the two products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food selfies wouldn’t become the pop-cultural staple they are today for several years, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/07/dining/07camera.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;many people were already enthusiastically photographing their food&lt;/a&gt; and sharing it on social media by 2011. Evernote Food was a transparent attempt by Evernote to become the primary destination for food photography, a position dominated by Flickr at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it may not have seemed like it at the time, Evernote Hello aligned strongly with Pachikov’s original vision to help users remember everything. Pachikov himself often used forgetting people’s names in professional settings as a prime example of how Evernote could be an indispensable part of people’s everyday lives. What Hello got wrong, however, was the execution. If Hello had shipped with NFC support, it could have potentially opened up Evernote’s products to an entirely new market of business users. It had to be effortless to work. As it stood, Evernote Hello was virtually useless and accomplished little besides diluting the Evernote brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote’s increasing range of products was confusing, but didn’t dissuade investors. In May 2012, Evernote officially earned “unicorn” status—a valuation of $1B or more—after raising $70M as part of its Series D round led by CBC Capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote didn’t need to raise any more funding. The company still had much of the $96M it had raised to date, but the company planned to use its latest round to expand further into the Chinese market. Unlike most Western tech companies, whose products are often quickly copied and rebranded by Chinese firms, Evernote decided to create its own clone for the Chinese market, Yinxiang Biji, or “memory notebook.” This would ultimately prove to be a smart play, and China would later become Evernote’s second largest market outside the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/chinese-evernote-homepage-screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote Chinese&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2013/03/evernote-so-useful-even-malware-loves-it/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: Ars Technica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a series of worrisome decisions and bewildering product launches, Evernote attempted to course-correct in August 2012 with the launch of Evernote Business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a logical, if predictable, move for the company. By the time Evernote Business launched, Evernote was wildly popular. The company had around 230 employees worldwide, tripled the number of developers working with Evernote’s API, and more than trippled its userbase from 12M to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2012/08/24/evernote-business-launch/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more than 38M in just one year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having accepted almost $100M in venture funding, Evernote was under considerable pressure to diversify its revenue streams and pursue business users more aggressively. Professional users could connect their business account to their personal account effortlessly. This encouraged business users to bring Evernote to work with them, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://producthabits.com/how-slack-became-a-5-billion-business-by-making-work-less-boring/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;much the same way Slack had done in its early growth stage&lt;/a&gt;. To sweeten the deal, users who connected personal accounts to business accounts had their basic freemium accounts upgraded to Evernote Premium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-business-screenshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote Business&quot; width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/2012/12/04/evernote-business-launches/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: Engadget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pressure to go after business users intensified further in November 2012, when Evernote raised an additional $85M as part of its secondary market round led by British venture fund M8 Capital. This brought Evernote’s total venture funding to more than $250M and a valuation of $2B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote’s next major product launch came almost a year later in September 2013. However, this product wasn’t another specialized version of the Evernote app, it was an extensive range of physical Evernote-branded products that the company would sell via its new Evernote Market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-branded-moleskine-notebooks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote Moleskine&quot; width=&quot;1020&quot; height=&quot;510&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2013/9/26/4769844/evernote-market-lifestyle&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the space of a few short years, Evernote had achieved profitability, had millions of dollars in the bank, and the company was growing fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote Market squandered almost all of the company’s brand equity for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If you make different products and they’re great, people are like, ‘That’s genius! Clearly, the right thing to do.’ And if you focus on one product and it fails, people are like, ‘That company is no longer capable of innovating.'” — Phil Libin, former CEO of Evernote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to understate the damage that the branded products sold through the Evernote Market inflicted on the Evernote brand. It made absolutely no sense. Users didn’t want Evernote-branded tablet styluses or Evernote Moleskine notebooks or Evernote backpacks. They wanted an organizational and productivity product that worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that the 2013 version of Evernote was widely considered the buggiest, most unstable version the company had released at that point added insult to injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than fixing the software problems that users actually cared about, Evernote started selling branded backpacks instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-2013-version-buggy-user-forum-complaints.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote 2013&quot; width=&quot;1208&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote Market wasn’t just a troubling sign that the company—and Phil Libin himself—had begun to lose its way. It was another major step away from Pachikov’s vision of what Evernote could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Pachikov and Libin shared a desire to create a “100-year company,” but Evernote Market did nothing to work toward or advance Pachikov’s vision of Evernote as an extension of the human mind. Pachikov’s vision was bold, ambitious, and transformative. By comparison, Evernote Market felt like a cheap cash grab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company’s fortunes went from bad to worse in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its popularity, Evernote had developed a reputation among its growing userbase for being a buggy, unstable product. For the most part, such grumbling was largely restricted to complaints on the product’s official forums and the occasional rant on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That changed when Jason Kincaid, a former TechCrunch writer, published a post on his &lt;a href=&quot;https://jasonkincaid.net/evernote-the-bug-ridden-elephant/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;personal blog&lt;/a&gt; titled “Evernote, the bug-ridden elephant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kincaid had been an Evernote power user for years, having captured almost 7,000 notes since discovering the product. The post was a reluctant but scathing take-down of Evernote’s notorious instability, which Kincaid felt compelled to write after experiencing a slew of technical problems including corrupted files, incomplete backups, and a poor response from Evernote’s customer support team. The post went viral and garnered so much attention that Libin personally contacted Kincaid to apologize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“None of this has been life-shattering, but given how reliant I am on Evernote, it is deeply unnerving—now each note I instinctively leave myself is tinged with anxiety. I’m concerned that as I dig through my Evernote archive, I’ll encounter more corrupted audio notes, and, worse, my paranoia is increasingly convinced that there may have been notes that never were saved to the archive at all.” — Jason Kincaid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little more than a year later in October 2014, Evernote unveiled its latest product, Work Chat. A simple messaging client, Work Chat was designed to complement Evernote’s Business plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also long overdue. Team-based collaboration had been an enormous blind spot in Evernote’s vision for years. The company had already missed one major consumer tech trend by ignoring the exodus of products and services migrating to the cloud and insisting on developing Evernote as a native app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Evernote had been designed as an organizational tool for individuals, when virtually every other productivity tool on the market emphasized team-based collaboration. Work Chat was the first small step toward solving this urgent problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for Evernote, that ship had sailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a whole, the company had been distracted by chasing the wrong revenue streams. Instead of building a solid team-based product, Evernote built a food app. The company had expanded too quickly in the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything besides the main Evernote app was a distraction from the company’s core mission to help people remember everything. Products like Slack and Google’s G Suite had successfully made the leap from personal product to collaborative product, whereas Evernote had not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-work-chat-splash-page.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote Work Chat&quot; width=&quot;903&quot; height=&quot;584&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uplabs.com/posts/evernote-work-chat&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from raising an additional $20M as part of its Series E round in November 2014, Evernote kept a low profile for the next year or so until July 2015, when the company introduced major changes to its pricing. Under the new structure, Evernote’s Premium plans increased from $45 to $50 per year. The other major change to the product’s pricing was the introduction of a new, middle-tier option called Evernote Plus, which cost $25 per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote changed more than just its pricing structure in 2015, it also changed the company’s leadership. In July 2015, Libin announced that he would be stepping down as Evernote’s CEO and handing the reins to former Google Glass executive, Chris O’Neill, as his successor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disastrous launch of Evernote Market, the instability and bugginess of the product, the lack of a clear direction for the company—they had all taken their toll on Evernote as a company, and Libin as Chief Executive in particular. Apparently discouraged by Evernote’s failure to capitalize on its earlier success, Libin reportedly showed little interest in the business side of the company. He described himself as “not passionate” in the announcement about O’Neill’s appointment, an admission as frank as it was surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Attracting and retaining talent is a core responsibility of the CEO, and if Libin is seriously disinterested in the latter, he should have departed long ago. I can’t imagine the feeling of being an Evernote employee who hears your long-time CEO (and still executive chairman) publicly admit to not giving a shit about your future.” — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/evernote-the-first-dead-unicorn-2015-9&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Josh Dickson&lt;/a&gt;, founder of Syrah&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libin wasn’t the only one who saw the writing on the wall. As news of O’Neill’s position as Evernote’s new CEO spread, many people expressed doubts about O’Neill’s suitability and experience––not to mention the product’s ongoing identity crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libin’s failure to hire a COO until June 2015, when the company &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2015/06/01/evernote-has-a-new-coo-linda-kozlowski/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;promoted Linda Kozlowski&lt;/a&gt; from VP of Worldwide Operations, was seen as yet another symptom of the company’s leadership problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-chris-o-neill-ceo-tweets.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote CEO&quot; width=&quot;642&quot; height=&quot;465&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2011 to 2015, it seemed as though Evernote took two steps backward with each step forward. The company had continued to invest in the development of new products, but none of these products expanded or built upon Evernote’s core functionality or purpose. With each new experiment and failed product, Evernote drifted farther and farther away from Pachikov’s vision—an identity crisis from which Evernote never really recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2015-Present: Returning to Evernote’s Roots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Evernote, the period from 2015 until the present day can be summed up in four short words: too little, too late. Evernote’s various failed experiments to diversify its products and revenue streams hadn’t just wasted millions of dollars—it wasted precious time the company didn’t have. Moving away from the core value proposition of the Evernote product had been a huge mistake. The only thing that could save Evernote was returning to the product’s roots. For O’Neill, this meant getting back to Pachikov’s original vision for Evernote as an extension of the human mind. Unfortunately for the company, it never managed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of O’Neill’s first tasks as CEO was to get Evernote’s house in order. This began with the prompt closure of Evernote Food in August 2015. Evernote Food had been relatively popular, but ultimately, it wasn’t worth the time and resources necessary to maintain it—especially considering the primary Evernote app could already do virtually everything Food could do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-food-discontinued-august-2015-official-forum-post.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote Food&quot; width=&quot;1195&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://discussion.evernote.com/topic/87854-ending-support-for-evernote-food-apps-ios-and-android/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: Evernote Forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around six months later, the company announced it was also closing the Evernote Market. According to Evernote, the company had sold approximately $12M worth of &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2014/10/02/evernote-market-has-sold-12m-in-products-since-launch/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;branded goods&lt;/a&gt; through the Evernote Market. Even if sales figures had been higher, the Evernote Market had done considerable damage to the Evernote brand. Closing it was both long overdue and urgently necessary if the company was to regain its users and investors’ trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little more than two months after Evernote shuttered its Market, the company lost the first of many executives it would lose over the coming years. Dave Engberg, the company’s founding CTO, left the organization after almost nine years. Like many other Evernote execs who departed the company around the same time, Engberg’s departure was decidedly low-key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after Engberg’s exit, Evernote introduced sweeping changes to the product’s pricing. First, serious restrictions were introduced to Evernote’s free plans. Free users were limited to synching their Evernote data across just two devices. Second, Evernote raised the price of its Plus and Premium tiers to $34.99 and $69.99 per year respectively, a price increase of roughly 40%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-pricing-increase-2016-plan-details.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote pricing increase&quot; width=&quot;832&quot; height=&quot;245&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest and most unpopular changes to Evernote, however, wasn’t its new pricing. It was the 60MB upload limit applied to Evernote’s free plans. For customers who used Evernote to upload primarily text-based notes, the new restriction may have felt less punitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For users who relied on Evernote to save images and other media files, however, the new upload cap was brutal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Our goal is to continue improving Evernote for the long term, investing in our core products to make them more powerful and intuitive while also delivering often-requested new features. But that requires a significant investment of energy, time and money.” — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/jun/30/evernote-users-vent-anger-after-it-cuts-free-tier-and-raises-prices&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chris O’Neill&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Evernote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Evernote, the restructuring of its freemium product was both long overdue and urgently necessary. For Evernote’s users, however, it was a slap in the face. Not only had Evernote crippled its free version, severely limiting its utility to free users, it had also failed to fix many of the bugs that still plagued even paid versions of the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be fair to Evernote, the company had little choice but to increase prices. Years of Evernote’s extremely permissible freemium product had spoiled users who had grown accustomed to making use of Evernote for free and had harmed the company’s revenue growth. What the company should have done to monetize the product while aligning with customers would have been to gradually introduce restriction incentives to its free version over time, rather than transitioning from a generous freemium product to a comparatively expensive paid service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pricing changes are some of the most impactful things a company can do. Evernote didn’t put enough thought into its pricing over the years, which is why their once loyal userbase wasted little time in criticizing them over the new pricing plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-pricing-changes-troy-hunt-tweet.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote pricing changes&quot; width=&quot;596&quot; height=&quot;691&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company’s primary competitors—Microsoft’s OneNote and Apple’s Notes—weren’t as fully featured as Evernote, but they offered a lot more functionality free of charge, making Evernote’s new pricing even less appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next major change to Evernote under O’Neill’s leadership came a few months after the product’s pricing restructure when the company announced it was migrating from Evernote’s own proprietary data infrastructure to Google Cloud. This was no small feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, Evernote had approximately &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2016/09/13/evernote-google-cloud/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;3.5 petabytes&lt;/a&gt;––or 3.5 million GB––of data on its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/446885/number-of-evernote-users/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;200 million users&lt;/a&gt;. Evernote could have opted to use Amazon Web Services or Microsoft’s Azure infrastructure to host its data. The company reportedly chose Google as its cloud provider due to the potential applications of Google’s machine-learning technology. Despite the costs and sheer amount of work involved in the migration, the decision could have been seen as another small step toward Evernote becoming the company Stepan Pachikov envisioned all those years before. Evernote had long been rumored to be developing voice recognition and translation features to the product to make capturing information even easier. This made &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/customers/evernote/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google’s Cloud Machine Learning Engine&lt;/a&gt; the ideal choice for intelligent, responsive features such as voice recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data security had been a thorny problem at Evernote for some time. Roughly 50 million user accounts were compromised following a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nakedsecurity.sophos.com/2013/03/02/evernote-hacked-almost-50-million-passwords-reset-after-security-breach/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;security breach&lt;/a&gt; in 2013, and Evernote’s decision to migrate its data infrastructure to Google Cloud was seen as a smart move for a company with so much data and so many users. However, the company suffered another PR black eye when TechCrunch reported that the company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/14/evernotes-new-privacy-policy-allows-employees-to-read-your-notes/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; allowed Evernote employees to read users’ private notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The latest update to the Privacy Policy allows some Evernote employees to exercise oversight of machine learning technologies applied to account content. While our computer systems do a pretty good job, sometimes a limited amount of human review is simply unavoidable in order to make sure everything is working exactly as it should.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The policy was framed as a way for Evernote to ensure the accuracy of its machine-learning technologies. What users took exception to was how the policy was structured. Despite the company’s attempts to backtrack later, the original update to Evernote’s privacy policy clearly stated that users could not opt out of Evernote employees examining their notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-privacy-policy-update-2016-user-backlash-twitter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote privacy policy&quot; width=&quot;609&quot; height=&quot;715&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-297&quot; srcset=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-privacy-policy-update-2016-user-backlash-twitter.png 609w, https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-privacy-policy-update-2016-user-backlash-twitter-256x300.png 256w, https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-privacy-policy-update-2016-user-backlash-twitter-260x305.png 260w, https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-privacy-policy-update-2016-user-backlash-twitter-315x370.png 315w, https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-privacy-policy-update-2016-user-backlash-twitter-384x451.png 384w, https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-privacy-policy-update-2016-user-backlash-twitter-400x470.png 400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 304.5px) 304.5px, 152.25px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backlash was powerful and immediate. Many users took to Twitter to point out the intrusive nature of the policy, and many agreed that the company’s response had been &lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com/2016/12/16/evernote-privacy-reversal/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tepid and frustratingly vague&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2017, O’Neill confirmed that after several difficult years, &lt;a href=&quot;https://evernote.com/blog/turning-an-elephant/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Evernote was cash-flow positive&lt;/a&gt;. This might not have been as warmly welcomed as an announcement that the company was once again profitable, but it was an important step for the beleaguered company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote kept a relatively low profile following the machine-learning privacy debacle. A year or so later, in February 2018, Evernote took another important step forward with the launch of Evernote Spaces, the company’s first truly collaborative team-based product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spaces’ biggest problem wasn’t the product itself––it was the fact that Spaces was released about six years too late. Evernote should have developed Spaces back in 2012, rather than wasting time, money, and brand equity with Evernote Market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time Spaces was released, the team-based productivity market was already saturated with far superior products, including Slack for real-time communication, Box and Google Drive for online storage, and G Suite for personal and team-based collaboration. There was simply no need for Evernote Spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even more ironic was the rationale behind the development of Spaces. In an interview, O’Neill claimed that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexkonrad/2018/02/27/evernote-launches-spaces-in-business-push/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;70% of Evernote users&lt;/a&gt; were using the product in their personal lives and at work. Had Evernote developed Spaces sooner, it could have leveraged the significant overlap between individual and business use-cases to make greater headway into the productivity tools market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Evernote sought to get back to its roots as a product that would help users remember everything, the brand underwent a significant overhaul in August 2018. Evernote was in dire need of a clean start, and a major rebrand would embody the company’s new sense of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-brand-icon-designs-mads-elephant.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evernote brand icons&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;372&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/taking-note/ever-better-refreshing-the-evernote-brand-f3f28ff12a88&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Source: Evernote Brand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote’s new branding was fresh, but it did little to solve the company’s underlying problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next month in September, TechCrunch reported that Evernote had lost the majority of its ranking executives within the past month alone, including CFO Vincent Toolan, CPO Erik Wrobel, CTO Anirban Kundu, and Head of HR Michelle Wagner. These departures didn’t just broadcast to the world that Evernote was a company in trouble. They were symptomatic of a company that had completely lost its way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote didn’t know what it should be, only what it shouldn’t be. The company had bet big and won by being on as many devices as possible, but had ignored product reliability. Evernote wasn’t able to keep up with consumer expectations which led the company to expand too rapidly in the wrong directions and, ultimately, it was left behind by newer entrants in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Neill’s efforts to right the ship after taking the helm were admirable and badly needed, but it’s painfully clear that Evernote will probably never be the extension of the human mind that Stepan Pachikov first imagined all those years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only question now is how Evernote’s story will end and how the company will be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where Could Evernote Go From Here?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-future.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the problems that have besieged the company and product for years, Evernote still has a relatively large user base. Where could Evernote go from here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development of a truly collaborative team-based product.&lt;/strong&gt; The most optimistic step that Evernote might take is to double-down on development of Spaces or another team-based collaborative product. Evernote may have won its big bet on mobile in 2006, but it missed the boat on cloud-based collaboration, which profoundly reshaped the personal and professional productivity spaces. If Evernote hopes to survive and become the 100-year company that Phil Libin always thought Evernote could be, it will need to develop a strong, team-based product that can compete with G Suite and similar tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Committing to fixing and improving the core Evernote product.&lt;/strong&gt; Evernote’s reputation for bugs and instability is well-deserved. The company neglected critical technical flaws for years, and users took note. Just as Evernote must develop a team-based tool if it hopes to survive, the company will also have to take its legacy technical issues seriously if the company wants to win back the hearts and minds of formerly enthusiastic users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding a buyer.&lt;/strong&gt; Evernote’s fall from grace should be a cautionary tale for any aspiring founder or entrepreneur. At this time, one of Evernote’s few remaining options is to hope that a buyer will acquire the company. Evernote is nowhere near ready to IPO, and while the company is likely to sell for much less than anyone would like, an acquisition would be an ideal end-game for the beleaguered company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What Can We Learn from Evernote?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As sad as it is, Evernote’s story offers plenty of lessons to entrepreneurs hoping to launch similarly ambitious products. What can we learn from Evernote?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Timing is everything even if it’s accidental.&lt;/strong&gt; By Phil Libin’s own admission, Evernote’s timing was crucial to the company’s success. Had Evernote’s development schedule been even six months off, it would have missed the huge growth driven by its status as a launch application when the iPhone was released in 2007. Evernote’s timing may have been at least partially accidental, but it played an outsized role in the company’s growth trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider your own product:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Let’s say you have a chance to travel back through time to one year before your product’s launch. What, if anything, would you have done differently? How could you capitalize upon external trends or developments to drive initial growth, as Evernote did?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would timing the release of your product have an impact on initial adoption? Put another way, is there anything you could do (or have done) to time your product’s launch to make a bigger impact?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s the “tailwind” at your back? Aside from your own hard work, what tailwinds will push your product forward?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Stay true to your convictions even in the face of overwhelming opposition.&lt;/strong&gt; Phil Libin was criticized for years for giving so much away in Evernote’s freemium product. Contrary to conventional wisdom, Libin was right to be so protective of Evernote’s freemium version. Evernote is a classic—if not the classic—freemium product, and Libin was right to insist on maintaining the free version’s features as long as he did, because it drove growth and encouraged users to become heavily invested in Evernote as a product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about your product’s journey thus far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Can you recall a time in which you compromised on a product or business decision that you later came to regret? If so, why did you give in? Did you or your product gain anything by doing so, and conversely, would you have gained anything if you had resisted that pressure?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How well does your actual product align with your original vision for the product? Is it true to your vision, or have you lost sight of what your product should be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Libin’s leadership was widely criticized over the years, but he did an excellent job of framing Evernote as a freemium company, especially when dealing with investors. How have you evangelized or advocated for the decisions you’ve made for your product?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Pay close attention to broader trends even if they don’t affect you right —and won—on mobile.&lt;/strong&gt; Evernote missed out on an immense opportunity by failing to respond to the ongoing evolution of consumer tech and opting to double-down on Evernote as a product for individuals, not teams. This arguably set the company up to fail later on, as there was no way for Evernote to course-correct in time to fend off emerging competitors that capitalized on the team-based collaboration trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider your product and its place in the broader tech ecosystem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What’s the single most important trend in tech facing your product and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, what broader technological development poses the greatest risk to your product? How have you mitigated this threat, and could your product move quickly enough in response?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are you innovating on your original vision? Could you go after different segments of your primary market?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Elephants Never Forget&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say that elephants never forget, and Silicon Valley is no different. Despite its potential and the boldness of vision of the company’s founder, Evernote ultimately lost sight of that vision. By the time it realized this, it was too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite still having a loyal base of hardcore users, Evernote’s future is far from certain. Whether the company can dig itself out of its current predicament remains to be seen, but there’s little doubt that Evernote will not be remembered kindly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you use Evernote?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;You can find your Evernote documents, alongside documents from other apps, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://usefyi.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;3 clicks or less by using FYI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 08:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>speter</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Ahead of Its Time, Behind the Curve: Why Evernote Failed to Realize Its Potential</og:title>
<og:description>Legendary investor, programmer, and Y Combinator co-founder Paul Graham once wrote that one of the best ways to come up with ideas for your next startup is to ask what product you wish someone else would make for you. For Stepan Pachikov, founder of Evernote, that product was a way to help him remember things. Although Pachikov first began working on what ultimately became Evernote back in 2002, his fascination with human memory stems from his experiences growing up in the former Soviet Union. To Pachikov, Evernote wasn't just another app or a way to capitalize on Silicon Valley's burgeoning</og:description>
<og:url>https://usefyi.com/evernote-history/</og:url>
<og:image>https://usefyi.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/evernote-future.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://usefyi.com/evernote-history/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Idaho sets record low solar price as it starts on shift to 100pct renewables</title>
<link>https://reneweconomy.com.au/idaho-sets-record-low-solar-price-as-it-starts-on-shift-to-100pct-renewables-38566/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://reneweconomy.com.au/idaho-sets-record-low-solar-price-as-it-starts-on-shift-to-100pct-renewables-38566/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content-inner padding-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pf-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;printfriendly pf-alignright&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reneweconomy.com.au/idaho-sets-record-low-solar-price-as-it-starts-on-shift-to-100pct-renewables-38566/#&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.print(); return false;&quot; class=&quot;noslimstat&quot; title=&quot;Printer Friendly, PDF &amp;amp; Email&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.printfriendly.com/buttons/print-button-nobg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Print Friendly, PDF &amp;amp; Email&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State utility Idaho Power has agreed to buy 120MW of power from a future solar project in the state’s south at a cost of US2.175¢/kWh – a potentially record-low cost for solar power in the US&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The announcement came at the same time that Idaho Power announced it had set a goal to provide 100 per cent clean energy by 2045.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idaho Power signed a 20-year Power Purchase Agreement (PPA) with Idaho-based Jackpot Holdings for the power generated from a solar power project to be built south of Twin Falls and which will help the company replace power produced from the North Valmy coal-fired power plant in Nevada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code-block code-block-9&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-4737885209238599&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;8795554017&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot; data-full-width-responsive=&quot;true&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 120 MW project is expected to be completed by 2022 and will connect to an existing transmission line that currently delivered power from the coal power plant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, however, is the price Idaho Power will be paying for the electricity, which was awarded at US$21.75/MWh – or 2.175¢/kWh, one of the lowest-cost solar contracts of its size that has been publicly reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is lower than existing publicly known prices for solar PPAs which include a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pv-magazine-usa.com/2018/06/12/would-you-pay-1-795%C2%A2-kwh-for-solar-power-in-2043/&quot;&gt;2.375¢/kWh contract &lt;/a&gt;awarded to 8minutenergy in Nevada, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pv-magazine-usa.com/2018/06/11/hot-trend-of-the-season-trading-record-low-priced-solar-for-coal-plants/&quot;&gt;2.49¢/kWh&lt;/a&gt;solar project in Arizona, and a project in Austin, Texas, which is believed to be below &lt;a href=&quot;https://electrek.co/2017/12/20/usa-cheapest-solar-austin-texas-2-5%C2%A2-kwh/&quot;&gt;2.5¢/kWh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Today’s announcement reflects Idaho Power’s commitment to resources that balance environmental stewardship with affordability and reliability,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idahopower.com/news/idaho-power-invests-in-clean-affordable-solar-energy/&quot;&gt;said Idaho Power President and CEO Darrel Anderson&lt;/a&gt;. “This deal will provide energy that is not only clean but is also at a cost that benefits our customers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Idaho Power announced that it has set a goal of providing its customers with 100% clean energy by 2045 – a move which will see the company invest in additional wind, solar, and other clean sources, to compliment its existing hydropower facilities, which already provide around half of customers’ energy demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This decision makes Idaho Power one of the first publicly owned energy companies to set a goal for reaching 100% clean energy and doubles down on the company’s existing “Path Away From Coal” which will see the company part ways with two of its three coal-fired power plants by 2025, as it explores ending its participation with the third and final plant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has also already reduced its carbon emissions intensity by almost 50% since 2005.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Providing 100-per cent clean energy is an important goal for Idaho Power. More and more customers are telling us it is important to them, too,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idahopower.com/news/idaho-power-sets-goal-for-100-percent-clean-energy-by-2045/&quot;&gt;said Darrel Anderson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We believe this goal is attainable. We have a great head start, thanks to our clean hydropower plants that produce almost half the energy our customers use. Our recently signed agreement with Jackpot Holdings moves us even closer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This plan demonstrates Idaho Power’s commitment to doing what’s right for customers’ pocketbooks and the environment,” added Idaho Governor Brad Little. “It also shows innovation can improve our lives with solutions that are reasonably priced, responsible and delivered without government intrusion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idaho Power has promised to announce additional investments in wind, solar, other clean energy sources, and to invest in clean energy storage as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;printfriendly-bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reneweconomy.com.au/idaho-sets-record-low-solar-price-as-it-starts-on-shift-to-100pct-renewables-38566/#&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.print(); return false;&quot; class=&quot;noslimstat&quot; title=&quot;Printer Friendly, PDF &amp;amp; Email&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.printfriendly.com/buttons/print-button-nobg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Print Friendly, PDF &amp;amp; Email&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 08:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chdaniel</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Idaho sets record low solar price as it starts on shift to 100pct renewables</og:title>
<og:url>https://reneweconomy.com.au/idaho-sets-record-low-solar-price-as-it-starts-on-shift-to-100pct-renewables-38566/</og:url>
<og:description>State utility Idaho Power agrees to buy output from 120MW solar farm in the state’s south at a cost of just 2.175¢/kWh.</og:description>
<og:image>https://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/solar-photovoltaics.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-AU</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://reneweconomy.com.au/idaho-sets-record-low-solar-price-as-it-starts-on-shift-to-100pct-renewables-38566/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>