<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Denmarks shuts down all schools, daycare facilities, universities, highschools</title>
<link>https://www.thelocal.dk/20200311/denmark-to-shut-all-schools-and-universities-to-fight-virus</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thelocal.dk/20200311/denmark-to-shut-all-schools-and-universities-to-fight-virus</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelocal.dk/20200311/denmark-to-shut-all-schools-and-universities-to-fight-virus&quot;&gt;https://www.thelocal.dk/20200311/denmark-to-shut-all-schools-and-universities-to-fight-virus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22550108&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22550108&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 219&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 148&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 20:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mixmax</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thelocal.dk/20200311/denmark-to-shut-all-schools-and-universities-to-fight-virus</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>San Francisco bans public events holding more than 1,000 people</title>
<link>https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/487047-san-francisco-bans-public-events-holding-more-than-1000-people</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/487047-san-francisco-bans-public-events-holding-more-than-1000-people</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;San Francisco will place a moratorium on public events with more 1,000 people as part of an effort to slow the coronavirus outbreak, Mayor London Breed (D) announced Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ban, which will apply to Golden State Warriors games, will be in effect for two weeks and may be reauthorized by the city's health officer if necessary, the mayor's office said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“We know that this order is disruptive, but it is an important step to support public health,” Breed said in a statement. “We’re following the recommendations of public health officials to slow the spread of COVID-19 in our community. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This order mirrors actions being taken by other local governments and is informed by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) guidelines.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;dfp-ad-incontent_desk_1-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;dfp-tag-wrapper wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;ADVERTISEMENT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breed said she spoke with the Warriors organization about the need to cancel public events and the team supported the efforts. The Warriors have since said that Thursday's game against the Brooklyn Nets will be played without fans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;All events at Chase Center through March 21 will be cancelled or postponed at this time. We'll continue to monitor this evolving situation closely to determine best steps,&quot; the team said in a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;8.8919667590028&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Due to escalating concerns about the spread of the coronavirus, and in consultation with the City and County of San Francisco, tomorrow night’s game vs. the Nets at Chase Center will be played without fans. Fans with tickets to this game will receive a refund in the amount paid. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/DMpO71ocvg&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/DMpO71ocvg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Golden State Warriors (@warriors) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/warriors/status/1237803013177131009?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;c-link&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SFGiants/status/1237801046581231616&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;San Francisco Giants also announced&lt;/a&gt; that an exhibition game scheduled on March 24 against the Oakland A’s will be canceled due to the order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breed's announcement came the same day that the World Health Organization (WHO) declared the coronavirus a global pandemic and as the U.S. tally of confirmed cases of the virus surpassed 1,000. Nearly 100 confirmed cases of the virus had been reported in the Bay Area alone, including 14 in San Francisco, as of Wednesday morning, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kron4.com/news/bay-area/nearly-100-coronavirus-cases-confirmed-in-bay-area/&quot;&gt;according to local station KRON 4&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;dfp-ad-incontent_desk_2-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;dfp-tag-wrapper wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;ADVERTISEMENT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top government health officials have consistently warned that the virus's impact will continue to worsen before the outlook improves. Dr. Anthony Fauci, director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/486965-massachusetts-governor-declares-emergency-as-virus-cases-double&quot;&gt;testified before Congress&lt;/a&gt; earlier Wednesday that “we will see more cases and things will get worse than they are right now.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We would recommend there not be large crowds. If that means not having any people in the audience when the NBA plays, so be it,&quot; Fauci said. &quot;As a public health official anything that has large crowds is something that would give risk to a spread.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12.026737967914&quot;&gt;The outbreak in the U.S. has caused numerous businesses and schools to shutter and has also led to the cancellations of several music festivals and other mass gatherings, including Coachella. New York Gov. Andrew Cuomo (D) &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/policy/healthcare/486841-ny-gov-deploys-national-guard-to-assist-with-coronavirus-containment&quot;&gt;announced earlier this week&lt;/a&gt; that he would deploy the National Guard to create a containment zone around a city hit particularly hard by the virus. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Washington Gov. &lt;span class=&quot;rollover-people&quot; data-behavior=&quot;rolloverpeople&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;rollover-people-link&quot; data-nid=&quot;435710&quot; href=&quot;https://thehill.com/people/jay-inslee&quot;&gt;Jay Inslee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rollover-people-block&quot; id=&quot;rollover-people-435710&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rollover-block&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://thehill.com/sites/default/files/styles/thumb_100/public/insleejay_071219as_lead.jpg?itok=fUM7k9RB&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name&quot; href=&quot;https://thehill.com/people/jay-inslee&quot;&gt;Jay Robert Inslee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;people-articles&quot; href=&quot;https://thehill.com/homenews/administration/486911-pence-says-he-and-trump-will-continue-to-shake-hands-despite&quot;&gt;Pence says he and Trump will continue to shake hands despite coronavirus&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;people-articles&quot; href=&quot;https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/486835-states-race-to-combat-coronavirus-as-cases-mount&quot;&gt;States race to combat coronavirus as cases mount&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;people-articles&quot; href=&quot;https://thehill.com/homenews/administration/486717-business-as-usual-for-trump-as-coronavirus-spreads&quot;&gt;Business as usual for Trump as coronavirus spreads&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;more&quot; href=&quot;https://thehill.com/people/jay-inslee&quot;&gt;MORE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (D) on Wednesday banned public events with more than 250 people in three state counties. Washington has reported 267 confirmed coronavirus cases, though Inslee has conceded that “hundreds if not thousands” have contracted it but don't know it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington, D.C., Mayor Muriel Bowser (D) also recommended a pause to nonessential mass gatherings of 1,000 or more people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;The virus needs people to spread. It jumps from person to person, so by reducing the opportunity for that to happen, we can effectively slow the spread,” San Francisco Director of Health Grant Colfax said, urging people over 60 or with certain underlying health conditions to stay home as much as possible. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He also advised the general public to cut back on the amount of time spent in groups.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;--Updated at 2:14 p.m.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 18:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>maerF0x0</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>San Francisco bans public events holding more than 1,000 people over coronavirus</og:title>
<og:url>https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/487047-san-francisco-bans-public-events-holding-more-than-1000-people</og:url>
<og:description>San Francisco will place a moratorium on public events with more than 1,000 people as part of an effort to slow the coronavirus outbreak, Mayor London Breed (D) announced Wednesday.</og:description>
<og:image>https://thehill.com/sites/default/files/london_breed.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/487047-san-francisco-bans-public-events-holding-more-than-1000-people</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Don&amp;#039;t Touch Ya Face</title>
<link>https://www.donttouchyaface.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.donttouchyaface.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.donttouchyaface.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.donttouchyaface.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22548708&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22548708&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 329&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 103&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 18:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dkobran</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Don't Touch Ya Face</og:title>
<og:url>https://sites.google.com/view/donttouchyaface</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.donttouchyaface.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Visual SQL</title>
<link>https://chartio.com/blog/why-we-made-sql-visual-and-how-we-finally-did-it/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://chartio.com/blog/why-we-made-sql-visual-and-how-we-finally-did-it/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent almost a decade now obsessed with the problem of truly enabling anyone—not just data teams—to explore and understand their business data. I still obsess over this as passionately as ever. It’s a much harder problem than I ever realized, but it’s just as important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;35 years ago, Microsoft Excel was first released. It was an incredible product that truly empowered business users to work with spreadsheets of data—and remains so today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when data gets larger than a spreadsheet, Excel no longer suffices, and there still aren’t any tools intuitive enough to take its place. Users are forced to learn databases, SQL, or complex Business Intelligence (BI) interfaces—or rely on data experts to do it for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p-zxlLjiRTU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re excited to announce that we have—through thousands of design iterations, dozens of functioning prototypes, several hundred user tests, and countless hours of development—created an interface that truly enables the business user to work with data. We call the interface &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartio.com/product/visual-sql/&quot;&gt;Visual SQL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;reality-and-research&quot;&gt;Reality and research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little over a year ago, after a long customer roadshow for Chartio, I was forced to admit that we hadn’t yet solved the problem. We’d built an incredible product, created a profitable business with fantastic customers, and been rated as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartio.com/blog/chartio-receives-top-awards-in-g2-crowds-fall-2018-indexes-for-self-service-business-intelligence/&quot;&gt;most usable BI product&lt;/a&gt; on the market for years. But it was clear that we still weren’t usable enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a document summarizing the problems we were still facing in truly democratizing data, and it ended up being over 40 pages. I then had my product team run a series of user tests (thanks, &lt;a href=&quot;http://usertesting.com&quot;&gt;usertesting.com&lt;/a&gt;!) on both our product and others in the self-serve BI space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tests confirmed that we were the most usable, but still not close to being intuitive. Filtering for users who claimed to be at least moderately competent at Excel, we found that only one in ten of them could use BI products. Users weren’t confident in what data they were exploring, what “measures” and “dimensions” (ie. rows and columns, groups and values) meant, and how the interface was going to map to their desired outcome in general. There was clearly a giant learning curve—and we needed to shrink it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;problems-and-insights&quot;&gt;Problems and insights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went back to basics, and—with a lot of effort—condensed our years of experience working with data and thousands of customers into the following two truths:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-sql-is-the-most-flexible-and-powerful-way-to-query-data-but-its-not-good-for-exploration&quot;&gt;1. SQL is the most flexible and powerful way to query data, but it’s not good for exploration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love SQL—so much so, in fact, that I wrote a whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://dataschool.com/learn-sql/introduction/&quot;&gt;SQL interface and tutorial&lt;/a&gt; to help people more easily get started learning it. SQL is an incredibly flexible language, and it’s THE language for working with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But SQL just isn’t going to be learned by a significant percentage of people. Even for people who do know SQL, it’s not a great way to explore. There are so many things to memorize that writing a SQL query frequently requires quite a few Google searches for that &lt;a href=&quot;https://dataschool.com/learn-sql/dates/&quot;&gt;date format&lt;/a&gt;, or the right name of some function, or how to do window functions again. It’s also verbose, and prone to error. With straight SQL as your interface, you’ll never have the agility you need to truly explore your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-bi-is-better-for-exploration-but-still-requires-too-many-steps-and-is-not-nearly-intuitive-enough&quot;&gt;2. BI is better for exploration, but still requires too many steps and is not nearly intuitive enough&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business Intelligence products have for years been promising to tackle this problem, but have some serious limitations. Most BI exploration interfaces are built to explore a single dataset or table at a time. This reduces complexity, but at a cost. It limits what the end user can do, and requires extra steps for data teams to build datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making these datasets also requires impossible foresight into what and how the end user might like to explore the data. It results in a lot of duplication in an ill-fated attempt to flatten a 3-D model into sets of 2-D tables mostly because of the limitation that the interface cannot handle relationships during exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is that business users still have the data team as a bottleneck for a great percentage of what they might want to explore. While a noble attempt, these BI products will never allow truly democratized data exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;insight---make-sql-visual&quot;&gt;Insight - make SQL visual&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With those truths in mind, we realized that to truly enable business users to work with databases, we’d need to build something that’s both &lt;em&gt;as flexible as SQL&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;more intuitive than BI&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQL is flexible and powerful because it is a language, so we concluded that any interface we might make needed to be a language as well. Making a visual language isn’t easy, but it turns out that its flexibility has many advantages. For example, with a language, the query definition can be broken down into small actions or steps rather than one complex, everything-at-once interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reminded us of the stories of when Apple, and then Microsoft, first made the DOS operating system visual: many attempts were first (and after) made to just make one giant application that did everything. These attempts obviously didn’t work. To make DOS visual, the interface needed to be as flexible as an operating system too. BI has faced the same problem; it doesn’t work to make one giant application interface to do what SQL can do. To deal with the complexity of data, a language is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that insight, we realized we would need to design not an application but a language - a visual version of SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-prototype-test&quot;&gt;Design, Prototype, Test&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m an extreme optimist, so I knew we could do this. With an amazing newly-recruited &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/martinjerkovic/&quot;&gt;designer Martin&lt;/a&gt; we created a ton of mocks, put an internal task force together, and built a prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial results were awful. Our designs were cool, but they didn’t work. Still, only one in every ten user tests were able to work with their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried a totally new approach. And then another. We built &lt;a href=&quot;https://5ca29e67d20d9d000720a89f--visualsql2.netlify.com&quot;&gt;real working prototypes&lt;/a&gt; of NLP, simpler versions of text-based SQL, drag-and-drop solutions, spreadsheet interfaces, and lots of combinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But 3 months in, despite 2000+ figma artboards, 10 highly functioning prototypes and 500 user tests, the one in ten number hadn’t budged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were completely out of ideas, and my optimism started sinking, fast.. It seemed like there was just no way to get more people over the learning curve of working with databases without training them on how to use BI. I was realizing that our efforts would not result in a breakthrough, but instead in definitive proof that the mission I’d spent almost ten years on was impossible—or at least wouldn’t be solved by us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week later, we’d made no progress on any ideas or designs for a new approach and my morale was incredibly low. But what I didn’t realize was that our latest iteration—what we were internally calling “Visual SQL”—was showing signs of promise with users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, I started to notice a lot of excitement in our internal #visualsql Slack channel. “Listen to this guy, he’s so excited, he’s loving it,” they were saying about one user. “6/10!” someone declared. We’d finally had a breakthrough, and in the latest batch of user tests 6 in 10 people could now write queries and make charts from databases with no training or no real knowledge of databases! A number of iterations later, we got up to eight in ten. We realized that any further improvements required a full solution; the prototype stage was over, and we moved onto development!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-worked&quot;&gt;What worked?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t pretend to have all the answers, and we’re not done innovating yet—eight in ten is not ten in ten—but it’s worth reflecting on what has worked so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;browse-tables-instead-of-a-list-of-columns&quot;&gt;Browse tables instead of a list of columns&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most BI products, including Chartio’s previous version (the “Data Explorer”), feature a vertically-stacked list of columns for users to browse. We found that, in addition to this list, showing a preview of the first 10 rows of the table, in a familiar tabular layout was much more intuitive to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of choosing a column name from a list and hoping for the best, they can get a glimpse of what’s in their data source and gain confidence that they’re making the right selection. It both displays more helpful information, and gives a real feeling of browsing real tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;intelligent-and-adjustable-grouping-and-aggregation&quot;&gt;Intelligent and adjustable grouping and aggregation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all BI interfaces have what I call the Grouping problem: to use a column, you have to decide right away whether you want to group by it or apply some aggregation. In Chartio’s Data Explorer, we called these dropzones “Dimensions” and “Measures.” Others call them “rows” and “columns,” or “groups” and “values.” These categories are confusing, and force users to imagine too much data transformation in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all of our historic usage data, we discovered that we could correctly predict a user’s desired grouping or aggregation 88% of the time. So we decided to remove that decision by automatically apply it and then instantly showing a preview of what the results will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our testing, users preferred this automatic grouping and responsive preview even in the 12% of cases where the mapping was wrong. They appreciated that we made a good guess, that we showed the structure of what the output would look like, and that it was easy enough to change. They no longer had to worry about the concepts of grouping and aggregating, nor imagine any data manipulation in their heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;writes-directly-to-sql-which-you-can-edit&quot;&gt;Writes directly to SQL, which you can edit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Visual SQL is truly written on top of SQL, it can’t (and probably shouldn’t) do 100% of the things that you can do in regular SQL. That’s why we’ve made it easy to switch into text-based SQL mode when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to how visual operating systems let you go into the terminal when you’d like, Visual SQL lets you go into text mode and review and modify the SQL that’s been written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was true for our original Data Explorer as well. Over the years, we’ve found that even power users who know they’ll eventually go into SQL mode prefer to start in the visual mode, as the grouping, date formatting, and joins are all done automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;results-table-just-like-a-spreadsheet&quot;&gt;Results table just like a spreadsheet&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you ask business users to envision their dream solution for working with databases, they usually just ask for a better Excel. That’s why we’ve incorporated elements into Visual SQL that will be familiar to Excel users. For example, the lower half of the Visual SQL interface is a results table fashioned after a spreadsheet interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Query results are displayed here, and users can take all kinds of actions on them—like moving, renaming, sorting, pivoting, forecasting, and creating new columns with custom formulas—just like in Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-true-language&quot;&gt;A true language&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power of SQL lies in its flexibility. With a language, you can piece together simple words to create complex expressions. This is necessary for working with data, and it’s something that traditional BI solutions, with their monolithic interfaces and single, prepared tables, haven’t gotten right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like SQL, Visual SQL is also a language. The actions taken on results tables are processed sequentially in a pipeline that can be rearranged and modified. Each action is relatively simple, but can be flexibly combined to define complex expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pipeline allows Visual SQL to extend regular SQL in a number of ways, allowing things that would otherwise have required writing code—including merging data from different data sources, performing pivots, and generating forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;launch&quot;&gt;Launch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we’re officially launching this Visual SQL to the public. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartio.com/signup&quot;&gt;sign up for a free trial&lt;/a&gt; to give it a spin. We’d love to hear your feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existing Chartio customers can try Visual SQL today as well. Just look for the “Try Visual SQL” button in your Data Explorer. We wrote a whole other post for you on &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartio.com/blog/whats-different-with-the-new-visual-sql-interface&quot;&gt;what’s new with Visual SQL&lt;/a&gt; explaining all the new improvements over our previous Data Explorer and how we’re planning on rolling Visual SQL out as we make it 100% backward compatible and work with you at your speed to transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been a big journey, but it’s only the start. We have a great team who continue to design and develop Visual SQL. Some of the many improvements we have in store are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better error/warning messaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backwards compatibility with our old Data Explorer (both Basic and Advanced mode)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved visualizations and chart settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More intuitive spreadsheet interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More intelligent grouping and aggregation recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More intelligent visualization recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query time estimations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A more intuitive automatic join interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL mode editor upgrades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of Visual SQL with Alerts and Data Stores&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And of course, we continue to improve usability through more user tests, extensive usage and user feedback (&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:product@chartio.com&quot;&gt;send us some!&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be writing more on our design, test and build process for creating this interface and on everything we’ve discovered so far and what we continue to discover, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartio.com/blog/&quot;&gt;follow along&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank you&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m immensely proud and grateful for the incredible people we’ve had focused on designing and building Visual SQL. It’s been an honor working with them. The Visual SQL focus team and I are also grateful for the whole company for being patient, excited and supportive during all stages. They’re an amazing group - if our mission and work interests you, you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartio.com/about/careers/&quot;&gt;join us&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a company we’re also incredibly thankful to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartio.com/customers/&quot;&gt;our many fantastic customers&lt;/a&gt; who have inspired (and funded!) this innovation. Thank you all, and I look forward to continuing to build this out together and bring Visual SQL to companies everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 17:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thingsilearned</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://chartio.com/blog/why-we-made-sql-visual-and-how-we-finally-did-it/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>We made SQL visual - why and how</og:title>
<og:description>Through months of design, prototypes, and user tests we made a visual version of SQL - which has proven to enable 80% of business users to write complex quer…</og:description>
<og:image>https://chartio.com/images/uploads/visual-sql-blogpost-small-image.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://chartio.com/blog/why-we-made-sql-visual-and-how-we-finally-did-it/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>White House told federal health agency to classify coronavirus deliberations</title>
<link>https://mobile.reuters.com/article/idUSKBN20Y2LM</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mobile.reuters.com/article/idUSKBN20Y2LM</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The White House has ordered federal health officials to treat top-level coronavirus meetings as classified, an unusual step that has restricted information and hampered the U.S. government’s response to the contagion, according to four Trump administration officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The officials said that dozens of classified discussions about such topics as the scope of infections, quarantines and travel restrictions have been held since mid-January in a high-security meeting room at the Department of Health &amp;amp; Human Services (HHS), a key player in the fight against the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staffers without security clearances, including government experts, were excluded from the interagency meetings, which included video conference calls, the sources said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We had some very critical people who did not have security clearances who could not go,” one official said. “These should not be classified meetings. It was unnecessary.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sources said the National Security Council (NSC), which advises the president on security issues, ordered the classification.”This came directly from the White House,” one official said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The White House insistence on secrecy at the nation’s premier public health organization, which has not been previously disclosed, has put a lid on certain information - and potentially delayed the response to the crisis. COVID19, the disease caused by the virus, has killed about 30 people in the United States and infected more than 1,000 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HHS oversees a broad range of health agencies, including the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, which among other things is responsible for tracking cases and providing guidance nationally on the outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The administration officials, who spoke to Reuters on condition of anonymity, said they could not describe the interactions in the meeting room because they were classified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An NSC spokesman did not respond to questions about the meetings at HHS. But he defended the administration’s transparency across federal agencies and noted that meetings of the administration’s task force on the coronavirus all are unclassified. It was not immediately clear which meetings he was referring to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“From day one of the response to the coronavirus, NSC has insisted on the principle of radical transparency,” said the spokesman, John Ullyot. He added that the administration “has cut red tape and set the global standard in protecting the American people under President Trump’s leadership.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokeswoman for HHS, Katherine McKeogh, issued a statement that did not address questions about classified meetings. Using language that echoed the NSC’s, the department said it that it agreed task-force meetings should be unclassified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics have hammered the Trump administration for what they see as a delayed response to coronavirus outbreaks and a lack of transparency, including sidelining experts and providing misleading or incomplete information to the public. State and local officials also have complained of being kept in the dark about essential federal response information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20200311&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1501819662&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPEG2A21Y&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;U.S. President Donald Trump speaks during a news conference on the coronavirus outbreak with U.S. Secretary of Health and Human Services Alex Azar, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases Anthony Fauci, U.S. Vice President Mike Pence, Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Robert Redfield and U.S. Surgeon General Jerome Adams at the White House in Washington, U.S., February 29, 2020. REUTERS/Joshua Roberts&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;U.S. President Donald Trump speaks during a news conference on the coronavirus outbreak with U.S. Secretary of Health and Human Services Alex Azar, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases Anthony Fauci, U.S. Vice President Mike Pence, Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Robert Redfield and U.S. Surgeon General Jerome Adams at the White House in Washington, U.S., February 29, 2020. REUTERS/Joshua Roberts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. Vice-President Mike Pence, the administration’s point person on coronavirus, vowed on March 3 to offer “real-time information in a steady pace and be fully transparent.” The vice president, appointed by President Donald Trump in late February, is holding regular news briefings and also has pledged to rely on expert guidance. Katie Miller, Pence’s press secretary, said Wednesday that since being appointed the vice president has never requested that HHS hold meetings in the SCIF or treat information as classified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meetings at HHS were held in a secure area called a “Sensitive Compartmentalized Information Facility,” or SCIF, according to the administration officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SCIFs are usually reserved for intelligence and military operations. Ordinary cell phones and computers can’t be brought into the chambers. HHS has SCIFs because theoretically it would play a major role in biowarfare or chemical attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A high-level former official who helped address public health outbreaks in the George W. Bush administration said “it’s not normal to classify discussions about a response to a public health crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees at the meetings included HHS Secretary Alex Azar and his chief of staff Brian Harrison, the officials said. Azar and Harrison resisted the classification of the meetings, the sources said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HHS did not make Azar or Harrison available for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the administration officials told Reuters that when complex issues about a quarantine came up, a high-ranking HHS lawyer with expertise on the issue was not admitted because he did not have the proper security clearance. His input was delayed and offered at an unclassified meeting, the official said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fifth source familiar with the meetings said HHS staffers often weren’t informed about coronavirus developments because they didn’t have adequate clearance. He said he was told that the matters were classified “because it had to do with China.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coronavirus epidemic originated in China and the administration’s main focus to prevent spread early on was to restrict travel by non-U.S. citizens coming from China and to authorize the quarantine of people entering the United States who may have been exposed to the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the administration officials suggested the security clearances for meetings at HHS were imposed not to protect national security but to keep the information within a tight circle, to prevent leaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It seemed to be a tool for the White House - for the NSC - to keep participation in these meetings low,” the official said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Democratic senators, both senior members of the Intelligence Committee expressed dismay Wednesday in statements to Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_container Slideshow_small Slideshow_standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_preview-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20200311&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1501819660&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPEG2A224&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;Slideshow_count&quot;&gt;(3 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Pandemics demand transparency and competence,” said Mark Warner of Virginia. “Classification authority should never be abused in order to hide what the government is doing, or not doing, just to satisfy domestic political concerns.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron Wyden of Oregon said: “The executive branch needs to immediately come forward and explain whether the White House hid information from the American people as a result of bogus classification.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Roston and Taylor reported from Washington, D.C.; Richard Cowan contributed reporting; Editing by Julie Marquis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 17:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zigzaggy</dc:creator>
<og:title>Exclusive: White House told federal health agency to classify coronavirus deliberations - sources</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-secrecy-exclusive-idUSKBN20Y2LM</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The White House has ordered federal health officials to treat top-level coronavi...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20200311&amp;t=2&amp;i=1501819662&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEG2A21Y</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-secrecy-exclusive/exclusive-white-house-told-federal-health-agency-to-classify-coronavirus-deliberations-sources-idUSKBN20Y2LM</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Coronavirus has disrupted supply chains for nearly 75% of U.S. companies</title>
<link>https://www.axios.com/coronavirus-supply-chains-china-46d82a0f-9f52-4229-840a-936822ddef41.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.axios.com/coronavirus-supply-chains-china-46d82a0f-9f52-4229-840a-936822ddef41.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 outbreak has caused supply chain disruptions for nearly three-quarters of U.S. companies, and many are already pricing in revenue losses this year as a result, according to a special ISM survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's happening:&lt;/strong&gt; Data show global production out of China fell to an all-time low last month, with freight and shipping slowing dramatically as the virus has shuttered factories and container ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Quarantined workers and shortages of components have further crimped the availability of goods from China, which is the world's hub for manufacturing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The intrigue:&lt;/strong&gt; Of the companies surveyed that expect supply chain impacts (80% said yes), most expect the severity of the disruptions will increase after the first quarter of this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why it matters:&lt;/strong&gt; The virus' impact has not yet been quantified, but the survey from the Institute for Supply Management — the first of its kind — shows just how widespread its impacts have already been for American businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“The story the data tells is that companies are faced with a lengthy recovery to normal operations in the wake of the virus outbreak,” ISM CEO Thomas W. Derry said in a statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“For a majority of U.S. businesses, lead times have doubled, and that shortage is compounded by the shortage of air and ocean freight options to move product to the United States -- even if they can get orders filled.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details:&lt;/strong&gt; ISM's business contacts, of which 81% are firms with revenues of less than $10 billion, reported a laundry list of disruptions that have already resulted from the outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Manufacturers in China report operating at 50% capacity with 56% of normal staff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than 44% of respondents said they did not have a plan in place to address supply disruption from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Six in 10 (62%) respondents are experiencing delays in receiving orders from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than half (53%) are having difficulty getting supply chain information from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nearly one-half are experiencing delays moving goods within China (48%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost one-half (46%) report delays loading goods at Chinese ports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Of note:&lt;/strong&gt; The survey was conducted between Feb. 22 and March 5 among 628 respondents that largely represent U.S. organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 17:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hhs</dc:creator>
<og:title>Coronavirus has disrupted supply chains for nearly 75% of U.S. companies</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.axios.com/coronavirus-supply-chains-china-46d82a0f-9f52-4229-840a-936822ddef41.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.axios.com/9B0lIR6Iv3Y1VwGS-S2ruW8eno4=/2020/03/11/1583942390772.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Global production out of China fell to an all-time low last month.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.axios.com/coronavirus-supply-chains-china-46d82a0f-9f52-4229-840a-936822ddef41.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Covid-19 is now officially a pandemic, WHO says</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/03/11/814474930/coronavirus-covid-19-is-now-officially-a-pandemic-who-says</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/03/11/814474930/coronavirus-covid-19-is-now-officially-a-pandemic-who-says</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res814516627&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/11/pandemic-coronavirus-facemask-590d38a1c1bb2835694d06f71046e768d60e39ff-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/11/pandemic-coronavirus-facemask-590d38a1c1bb2835694d06f71046e768d60e39ff-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization called the COVID-19 viral disease a pandemic Wednesday. Here, workers in Spain place a medical mask on a figure that was to be part of the Fallas festival in Valencia. The festival has been canceled over the coronavirus outbreak. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Alberto Saiz/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Alberto Saiz/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/11/pandemic-coronavirus-facemask-590d38a1c1bb2835694d06f71046e768d60e39ff-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The World Health Organization called the COVID-19 viral disease a pandemic Wednesday. Here, workers in Spain place a medical mask on a figure that was to be part of the Fallas festival in Valencia. The festival has been canceled over the coronavirus outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Alberto Saiz/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated at 3:20 p.m. ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 viral disease that has swept into at least 114 countries and killed more than 4,000 people is now officially a pandemic, the World Health Organization announced Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is the first pandemic caused by coronavirus,&quot; WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus declared at a briefing in Geneva.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's the first time the WHO has called an outbreak a pandemic since the H1N1 &quot;swine flu&quot; in 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even as he raised the health emergency to its highest level, Tedros said hope remains that COVID-19 can be curtailed. And he urged countries to take action now to stop the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;WHO has been in full response mode since we were notified of the first cases,&quot; Tedros said. &quot;And we have called every day for countries to take urgent and aggressive action. We have rung the alarm bell loud and clear.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eight countries — including the U.S. — are now each reporting more than 1,000 cases of COVID-19, caused by the coronavirus that has infected nearly 120,000 people worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In the past two weeks, the number of cases of COVID-19 outside China has increased 13-fold, and the number of affected countries has tripled,&quot; Tedros said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;In the days and weeks ahead, we expect to see the number of cases, the number of deaths and the number of affected countries climb even higher.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WHO is &quot;deeply concerned, both by the alarming levels of spread and severity and by the alarming levels of inaction&quot; by world leaders in response to the outbreak, Tedros said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have therefore made the assessment that COVID-19 can be characterized as a pandemic,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res814596178&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage814091024&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2020/03/10/814091024/you-have-a-fever-and-a-dry-cough-now-what&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2020\/03\/10\/814091024\/you-have-a-fever-and-a-dry-cough-now-what&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/10/fever_sq-1f0b055a89931bc851c62c6f3d050bac4259b73b-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/10/fever_sq-1f0b055a89931bc851c62c6f3d050bac4259b73b-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;You Have A Fever And A Dry Cough. Now What?&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res814596060&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage814460233&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2020/03/11/814460233/coronavirus-1-000-cases-now-in-u-s-and-it-s-going-to-get-worse-fauci-says&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2020\/03\/11\/814460233\/coronavirus-1-000-cases-now-in-u-s-and-it-s-going-to-get-worse-fauci-says&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/11/coronavirus-fauci-cases_sq-ddc00558bcc079a2838c87210b303d68d5cfa3b1-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/11/coronavirus-fauci-cases_sq-ddc00558bcc079a2838c87210b303d68d5cfa3b1-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Coronavirus: Over 1,000 Cases Now In U.S., And 'It's Going To Get Worse,' Fauci Says&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By dubbing COVID-19 a pandemic, the WHO is placing it in a different category than several recent deadly outbreaks, including the recent Ebola outbreak in the Democratic Republic of Congo, the Zika virus outbreak &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/emergencies/zika-virus-tmp/en/&quot;&gt;in 2016&lt;/a&gt; and the 2014 Ebola outbreak in West Africa. All three of those outbreaks were deemed to be international emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last pandemic, the H1N1 influenza virus &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/csr/don/2010_08_06/en/&quot;&gt;killed more than 18,000 people&lt;/a&gt; in more than 214 countries and territories, according to the WHO. In recent years, other estimates have put H1N1's toll &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2013/11/26/247379604/2009-flu-pandemic-was-10-times-more-deadly-than-previously-thought&quot;&gt;even higher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, Tedros said that people should not fear the designation and that it should not be taken to mean that the fight against the virus is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Describing the situation as a pandemic does not change WHO's assessment of the threat posed by the virus,&quot; Tedros said. &quot;It doesn't change what WHO is doing. And it doesn't change what countries should do.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WHO had declared the outbreak a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/01/30/798894428/who-declares-coronavirus-outbreak-a-global-health-emergency&quot;&gt;global health emergency&lt;/a&gt; in January, as cases surged in China, where the novel coronavirus was first detected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Italy, more than 630 people have died of COVID-19, and the total number of cases continues to rise sharply. The country now has 10,000 cases, second only to China. There are 9,000 cases in Iran and more than 7,700 in South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those four nations are all imposing drastic measures in an attempt to slow the spread of the COVID-19 illness, which has a higher fatality rate for elderly people and those with underlying health conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those countries also have more than 90% of current cases, Tedros noted, adding that both China and South Korea have had success in reining in their epidemics. Data from China, he said, showed that the number of new cases there peaked in late January and early February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We cannot say this loudly enough, or clearly enough, or often enough: All countries can still change the course of this pandemic,&quot; Tedros said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the viral disease continues to spread around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In the Americas, Honduras, Jamaica and Panama, are all confirming coronavirus infections for the first time,&quot; NPR's Jason Beaubien reports. &quot;Elsewhere, Mongolia and Cyprus are also now reporting cases.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the outbreak has ballooned, so has speculation that the WHO would declare it a pandemic. But Tedros said WHO experts had previously determined that the scale of the coronavirus' impact didn't warrant that description. And he noted that declaring the outbreak a pandemic would raise the risk of a public panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res814596672&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage814189027&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2020/03/11/814189027/no-guarantee-youll-get-tested-for-covid-19-even-if-your-doctor-requests-it&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2020\/03\/11\/814189027\/no-guarantee-youll-get-tested-for-covid-19-even-if-your-doctor-requests-it&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/11/testkit_sq-b7383aabafbe724ef48a15ca9dba804597fe746c-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/11/testkit_sq-b7383aabafbe724ef48a15ca9dba804597fe746c-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;No Guarantee You'll Get Tested For COVID-19, Even If Your Doctor Requests It&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's now up to other countries to prove they can stop the disease, Tedros reiterated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The challenge for many countries who are now dealing with large clusters or community transmission is not whether they can do the same,&quot; he said. &quot;It's whether they will.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;People, we're in this together — to do the right things with calm and protect the citizens of the world,&quot; Tedros said as he concluded his remarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's doable.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coronavirus symptoms and prevention&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prevent the coronavirus from spreading, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommends washing hands with soap and water for at least 20 seconds or using a hand sanitizer if a sink isn't available. The World Health Organization says people should wear face masks only if they're sick or caring for someone who is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;For most people, COVID-19 infection will cause mild illness; however, it can make some people very ill and, in some people, it can be fatal,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/who-china-joint-mission-on-covid-19-final-report.pdf&quot;&gt;the WHO says&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Older people, and those with pre-existing medical conditions (such as cardiovascular disease, chronic respiratory disease or diabetes) are at risk for severe disease.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common symptoms of COVID-19, according to a recent WHO report that draws on more than 70,000 cases in China, are the following: fever (in 88% of cases), dry cough (68%), fatigue (38%) and sputum/phlegm production (33%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortness of breath occurred in nearly 20% of cases, and about 13% had a sore throat or headache, the WHO said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 16:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tmlee</dc:creator>
<og:title>Coronavirus: COVID-19 Is Now Officially A Pandemic, WHO Says</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/03/11/814474930/coronavirus-covid-19-is-now-officially-a-pandemic-who-says</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>It's the first time the WHO has called an outbreak a pandemic since the H1N1 &quot;swine flu&quot; in 2009.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/11/pandemic-coronavirus-facemask_wide-b5345d7f374fdcd9422a39f05d89ffabede7bc00.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/03/11/814474930/coronavirus-covid-19-is-now-officially-a-pandemic-who-says</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>E3 2020 Cancelled</title>
<link>https://www.e3expo.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.e3expo.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;IE=edge&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;profile&quot; nhref=&quot;http://gmpg.org/xfn/11&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;preload&quot; as=&quot;image&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/themes/e3expo/images/2020/nav-hover-anim.gif&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 1200px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;E3 2020 - Everyone Plays&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;This year’s E3 will showcase what's new in video games and provide a unique opportunity to celebrate the excitement of video game culture.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;max-snippet:-1, max-image-preview:large, max-video-preview:-1&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:locale&quot; content=&quot;en_US&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;website&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;E3 2020 - Everyone Plays&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;This year’s E3 will showcase what's new in video games and provide a unique opportunity to celebrate the excitement of video game culture.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;E3 2020&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/E3Logo_Color_RGB.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:secure_url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/E3Logo_Color_RGB.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:width&quot; content=&quot;1881&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:height&quot; content=&quot;1155&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary_large_image&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;This year’s E3 will showcase what's new in video games and provide a unique opportunity to celebrate the excitement of video game culture.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;E3 2020 - Everyone Plays&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image&quot; content=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/E3Logo_Color_RGB.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;//www.e3expo.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;//translate.google.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;//s.w.org&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/E3Logo_Color_RGB.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image:src&quot; content=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/E3Logo_Color_RGB.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:width&quot; content=&quot;1881&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:height&quot; content=&quot;1155&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; id=&quot;wp-block-library-css&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-includes/css/dist/block-library/style.min.css?ver=5.3.2&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; id=&quot;google-language-translator-css&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/plugins/google-language-translator/css/style.css?ver=6.0.4&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; id=&quot;glt-toolbar-styles-css&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/plugins/google-language-translator/css/toolbar.css?ver=6.0.4&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; id=&quot;e3expo-style-css&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/themes/e3expo/style.css?ver=2.2.4&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; id=&quot;e3expo-style-2020-css&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/themes/e3expo/style-2020.min.css?ver=2.2.4&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;application/json+oembed&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-json/oembed/1.0/embed?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.e3expo.com%2F&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;text/xml+oembed&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-json/oembed/1.0/embed?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.e3expo.com%2F&amp;amp;format=xml&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;onesignal&quot; content=&quot;wordpress-plugin&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/cropped-E3_Expo_FaviconLogo_transparent-32x32.png&quot; sizes=&quot;32x32&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/cropped-E3_Expo_FaviconLogo_transparent-192x192.png&quot; sizes=&quot;192x192&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon-precomposed&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/cropped-E3_Expo_FaviconLogo_transparent-180x180.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;msapplication-TileImage&quot; content=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/cropped-E3_Expo_FaviconLogo_transparent-270x270.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; id=&quot;gforms_reset_css-css&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/plugins/gravityforms/css/formreset.min.css?ver=2.4.17&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; id=&quot;gforms_formsmain_css-css&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/plugins/gravityforms/css/formsmain.min.css?ver=2.4.17&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; id=&quot;gforms_ready_class_css-css&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/plugins/gravityforms/css/readyclass.min.css?ver=2.4.17&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; id=&quot;gforms_browsers_css-css&quot; href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/plugins/gravityforms/css/browsers.min.css?ver=2.4.17&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;66.725891291642&quot;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;

&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;nav id=&quot;top_nav&quot; class=&quot;primary-fixed-nav y2020&quot;&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wrap-2020&quot;&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;about-us&quot; class=&quot;not-full about-us-2020&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container contain-1200 about-us-2020-contain bg-align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;about-content wsiwyg2020 main-content-for-scroll col-xs-24&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEWS: E3 2020 CANCELLED DUE TO GROWING CONCERNS OVER COVID-19 VIRUS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After careful consultation with our member companies regarding the health and safety of everyone in our industry – our fans, our employees, our exhibitors, and our longtime E3 partners – we have made the difficult decision to cancel E3 2020, scheduled for June 9-11 in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following increased and overwhelming concerns about the COVID-19 virus, we felt this was the best way to proceed during such an unprecedented global situation. We are very disappointed that we are unable to hold this event for our fans and supporters. But we know it’s the right decision based on the information we have today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team will be reaching out directly to exhibitors and attendees with information about providing full refunds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also exploring options with our members to coordinate an online experience to showcase industry announcements and news in June 2020. Updates will be shared on E3Expo.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thank everyone who shared their views on reimagining E3 this year. We look forward to bringing you E3 2021 as a reimagined event that brings fans, media, and the industry together in a showcase that celebrates the global video game industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;mainForm&quot; class=&quot;form-2020&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container-fluid&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;form-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subscribe-form&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container contain-1200&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;8.6519337016575&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-15 the-form&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sign Up to Stay in the Loop on Everything E3 2020&lt;/h3&gt;

 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-9 the-privacy&quot; readability=&quot;12.215517241379&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E3 is committed to your privacy. We do not share, sell, or rent your email address to third parties without your consent. You may unsubscribe from these communications at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theesa.com/privacy-policy/&quot;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer id=&quot;mainFooter&quot; class=&quot;footer-2019 footer-2020 y2020&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottomPart&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;copyright&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;© 2020 Entertainment Software Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;search-overlay&quot; class=&quot;search-overlay-2020&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/&quot; class=&quot;close-search&quot; id=&quot;search-overlay-close&quot; data-target=&quot;#search-overlay&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/themes/e3expo/images/2020/ham2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Close search&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;search-form-block&quot; class=&quot;search-form-block&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start typing to search...&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.theesa.com/privacy-policy/, https://www.theesa.com, https://twitter.com/theESA, https://twitter.com/ESAGovAffairs, https://vimeo.com/e3expo, https://www.facebook.com/E3Expo/, https://twitter.com/e3, https://www.instagram.com/e3expo/, https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCNy_lYhgyQAG1KAqv5DRUEw, http://compusystems.com/servlet/ar?evt_uid=124, https://www.compusystems.com/servlet/AttendeeRegLoginServlet?evt_uid=124&amp;amp;memcode=Y, https://www.compusystems.com/servlet/ar?evt_uid=124&amp;amp;site=PRESS, https://www.compusystems.com/servlet/ar?evt_uid=124&amp;amp;site=EXH, http://www.theesa.com/privacy-policy/, http://www.theesa.com/terms-of-service/, https://live-e3-expo.pantheonsite.io, https://www.compusystems.com/servlet/ar?evt_uid=124, https://www.compusystems.com/servlet/AttendeeRegLoginServlet?evt_uid=124, http://marketing19.e3expoem.com/login.aspx, http://email.e3expo.com/q/16vpRwz3lyH/wv, https://ufzt347431.exh.mapyourshow.com, https://ufzt347431.mapyourshow.com/8_0/#/, http://e3expo.vporoom.com/, https://ufzt347431.mapyourshow.com/8_0/floorplan/, https://ufzt347431.mapyourshow.com/8_0/exhibitor/exhibitor-details.cfm?exhid=V7aGdy5N, https://www.facebook.com/E3Expo/, https://videogamevoters.org/, https://www.esrb.org/EPCConfirm/802/, https://www.theesa.com/, https://www.esrb.org/tools-for-parents/parental-controls/, https://jna7jvmw5v11.mapyourshow.com, https://hsg.cmrus.com/e32020/, https://www.compusystems.com/servlet/AttendeeRegLoginServlet?evt_uid=597, https://www.compusystems.com/servlet/ar?evt_uid=597&amp;amp;site=PRESS&amp;amp;isATT=Y, https://gamegeneration.org, https://jna7jvmw5v11.exh.mapyourshow.com, https://www.e3expo.com/media-center/media-registration, https://ordering.ges.com/022601567/welcome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;Translate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 16:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>haunter</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>E3 2020 - Everyone Plays</og:title>
<og:description>This year’s E3 will showcase what's new in video games and provide a unique opportunity to celebrate the excitement of video game culture.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.e3expo.com/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.e3expo.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/E3Logo_Color_RGB.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.e3expo.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Fraidycat</title>
<link>https://fraidyc.at/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://fraidyc.at/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fraidycat web extension doesn't access websites as you visit them. It asks for permission to access all websites because it is fetching websites in the background (without using your credentials).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fraidycat doesn't communicate with a central server - unless your browser syncs Fraidycat's settings to a central server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;43&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Feeds&lt;/em&gt; (RSS, Atom or JSON Feed). This is how Fraidycat reads blogs, Tumblr, Medium, Mastodon, micro.blog, Wikipedia, Kickstarter or Stack Overflow. &lt;strong&gt;If only every network used RSS!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter, Instagram, SoundCloud.&lt;/em&gt; These sites don't support RSS, so Fraidycat does its best to pick things out of their web pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pinboard, YouTube and Reddit.&lt;/em&gt; These sites do offer RSS, but it's not advertised very well. So Fraidycat figures out where to find the RSS feeds for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitch.&lt;/em&gt; Fraidycat now also shows when a follow is live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TiddlyWiki.&lt;/em&gt; Fraidycat reads the whole wiki and treats it like a giant RSS feed. Be aware that giant wikis may load down Fraidycat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's Coming Next?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to offer a personal search box for your follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps even a keyword filter that will notify you when that keyword comes up in a follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile support. If you use Firefox, I believe I can offer this on iOS and Android with sync between all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let you use your credentials to follow private Facebook and Instagram accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to reply and share by way of the extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 13:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kickscondor</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://fraidyc.at/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alcoholics Anonymous vs. other approaches: the evidence is now in</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/11/upshot/alcoholics-anonymous-new-evidence.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/11/upshot/alcoholics-anonymous-new-evidence.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For a long time, medical researchers were unsure whether Alcoholics Anonymous worked better than other approaches to treating people with alcohol use disorder. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2006/07/25/health/25drin.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;In 2006&lt;/a&gt;, a review of the evidence concluded we didn’t have enough evidence to judge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;That has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;An &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD012880.pub2&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;updated systematic review published&lt;/a&gt; Wednesday by the Cochrane Collaboration found that A.A. leads to increased rates and lengths of abstinence compared with other common treatments. On other measures, like drinks per day, it performs as well as approaches provided by individual therapists or doctors who don’t rely on A.A.’s peer connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;What changed? In short, the latest review incorporates more and better evidence. The research is based on an analysis of 27 studies involving 10,565 participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cochranelibrary.com/cdsr/doi/10.1002/14651858.CD005032.pub2/full&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The 2006 Cochrane Collaboration&lt;/a&gt; review was based on just eight studies, and ended with a call for more research to assess the program’s efficacy. In the intervening years, researchers answered the call. The newer review also applied standards that weeded out some weaker studies that drove earlier findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In the last decade or so, researchers have published a number of very high-quality randomized trials and quasi-experiments. Of the 27 studies in the new review, 21 have randomized designs. Together, these flip the conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“These results demonstrate A.A.’s effectiveness in helping people not only initiate but sustain abstinence and remission over the long term,” said the review’s lead author, John F. Kelly, a professor of psychiatry at Harvard Medical School and director of the Recovery Research Institute at Massachusetts General Hospital. “The fact that A.A. is free and so widely available is also good news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It’s the closest thing in public health we have to a free lunch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Studies generally show that other treatments might result in about 15 percent to 25 percent of people who remain abstinent. With A.A., it’s somewhere between 22 percent and 37 percent (specific findings vary by study). Although A.A. may be better for many people, other approaches can work, too. And, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/01/27/upshot/can-this-treatment-help-me-theres-a-statistic-for-that.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;as with any treatment&lt;/a&gt;, it doesn’t work perfectly all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Rigorous study of programs like Alcoholics Anonymous is challenging because people self-select into them. Those who do so may be more motivated to abstain from drinking than those who don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/04/07/upshot/alcoholics-anonymous-and-the-challenge-of-evidence-based-medicine.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Unless a study is carefully designed&lt;/a&gt;, its results can be &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/06/upshot/employer-wellness-programs-randomized-trials.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;driven by who participates&lt;/a&gt;, not by what the program does. Even randomized trials can succumb to bias from self-selection if people assigned to A.A. don’t attend, and if people assigned to the control group do. (It may go without saying, but we’ll say it: It would be unethical to prevent people in a control group from attending Alcoholics Anonymous if they wanted to.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Despite these challenges, some high-quality randomized trials of Alcoholics Anonymous have been conducted in recent years. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19207347&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;One, published in the journal Addiction&lt;/a&gt;, found that those who were randomly assigned to a 12-step-based directive A.A. approach, and were supported in their participation, attended more meetings and exhibited a greater degree of abstinence, compared with those in the other treatment groups. Likewise, other randomized studies found that &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19309183&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;greater Alcoholics Anonymous participation&lt;/a&gt; is associated with &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16669901&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;greater alcohol abstinence&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Alcoholics Anonymous is often paired with other kinds of treatment that encourage engagement with it. “For people already in treatment, if they add A.A. to it, their outcomes are superior than those who just get treatment without A.A.,” said Keith Humphreys, a Stanford University professor and co-author of the new Cochrane review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Alcoholics Anonymous not only produced higher rates of abstinence and remission, but it also did so at a lower cost, the Cochrane review found. A.A. meetings are free to attend. Other treatments, especially those that use the health care system, are more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11371720&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; found that compared with Alcoholics Anonymous participants, those who received cognitive behavioral treatments had about twice as many outpatient visits — as well as more inpatient care — that cost just over $7,000 per year more in 2018 dollars. (Cognitive behavioral treatments help people analyze, understand and modify their drinking behavior and its context.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22633367&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Another study&lt;/a&gt; found that for each additional A.A. meeting attended, health care costs fell by almost 5 percent, mostly a result of fewer days spent in the hospital and fewer psychiatric visits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A.A. meetings are ubiquitous and frequent, with no appointment needed — you &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.aa.org/pages/en_US/find-local-aa&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;just show up&lt;/a&gt;. The bonds formed from the shared challenge of addiction — building trust and confidence in a group setting — may be a key ingredient to help people stay on the road to recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Worldwide, alcohol misuse and dependence are responsible for &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.who.int/substance_abuse/publications/alcohol_2014/en/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;3.3 million deaths per year&lt;/a&gt;, 10 times the number of fatalities from all illicit drugs combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In the United States, alcohol is &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/alcohol/fact-sheets/alcohol-use.htm&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a larger killer&lt;/a&gt; than &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/drugoverdose/data/statedeaths.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;other drugs&lt;/a&gt;; accounts &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.samhsa.gov/data/sites/default/files/NSDUH-DR-FFR2-2016/NSDUH-DR-FFR2-2016.htm&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;for the majority&lt;/a&gt; of all addiction treatment cases; and is responsible for at least &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26477807&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$250 billion per year&lt;/a&gt; in lost productivity and costs related to crime, incarceration and health care. Moreover, American deaths related to alcohol &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://tracking.nihcm.org/track/click/30157056/www.nihcm.org?p=eyJzIjoiMmZwcDdSOWtXX1EwSVlWSkY5WFN5Zkt3Wm5rIiwidiI6MSwicCI6IntcInVcIjozMDE1NzA1NixcInZcIjoxLFwidXJsXCI6XCJodHRwczpcXFwvXFxcL3d3dy5uaWhjbS5vcmdcXFwvYWRtaW5pc3RyYXRvclxcXC9jb21wb25lbnRzXFxcL2NvbV9jaXZpY3JtXFxcL2Npdmljcm1cXFwvZXh0ZXJuXFxcL3VybC5waHA_dT0yOTg1OSZxaWQ9Nzc2ODA2OVwiLFwiaWRcIjpcImFkZjg1ZmE0MDkwYzQwNWE5ZDk3YjcwYjQ1OTA2ZjRhXCIsXCJ1cmxfaWRzXCI6W1wiZmRkMmVlYTQ0ZWQ1YTljMjFkMjMwOTIxMjM3OTlkZjVhNzc5NjAzMlwiXX0ifQ&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more than doubled&lt;/a&gt; between 1999 and 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Reducing the human and financial burdens of alcohol is an often overlooked public health priority, and the new evidence suggests that on balance one of the oldest solutions — Alcoholics Anonymous has been around &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.aa.org/pages/en_US/historical-data-the-birth-of-aa-and-its-growth-in-the-uscanada&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;almost 85 years&lt;/a&gt; — is still the better one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 13:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/11/upshot/alcoholics-anonymous-new-evidence.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Alcoholics Anonymous vs. Other Approaches: The Evidence Is Now In</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/11/25/upshot/00up-health-alcohol1/00up-health-alcohol1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>An updated review shows it performs better than some other common treatments and is less expensive.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/11/upshot/alcoholics-anonymous-new-evidence.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>