<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Vitamin D uncorrelated with Covid severity in those of European descent</title>
<link>https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;boxed-text&quot; id=&quot;boxed-text-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What this paper adds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;list-unord&quot; id=&quot;list-1&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;list-item-1&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-6&quot;&gt;Uncertainty remains over the use of Vitamin D for the prevention of COVID-19 and the moderation of its symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;list-item-2&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-7&quot;&gt;Genetic predisposition for higher levels of vitamin D and for lower chance of vitamin D insufficiency do not have evidence of association with infection from SARS-CoV-2 or severity of COVID-19 following infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;list-item-3&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-8&quot;&gt;Our work supports the current NICE statement that, based on the available evidence, vitamin D should not be considered as protective of infection from SARS-CoV-2 or a way to mitigate its severity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section intro&quot; id=&quot;sec-5&quot; readability=&quot;59.654714475432&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-9&quot;&gt;Vitamin D has lately been the focus of very intense scientific interest, with more than 4500 manuscripts published per year since 2015. Although vitamin D is commonly discussed in terms of bone health and calcium and phosphate homeostasis, evidence has started to emerge that it may also be involved in cancer, the cardiovascular system and inflammation.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-1-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; With the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic, these findings, in combination with previous reports of vitamin D playing a role in upper respiratory tract (URT) infections and their severity, have resulted in further interest in vitamin D and the potential use of vitamin D supplements to mitigate the spread and severity of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-10&quot;&gt;We obtain vitamin D either through our diet, with certain foods such as oily fish and egg yolks being good sources, or through our exposure to ultraviolet B radiation from the sun.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-2-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; Vitamin D, whether generated or consumed, is biologically inactive and undergoes a complex metabolic process: it is first converted to 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) in the liver and then this is converted in the kidney to 1,25-hydroxyvitamin D, which is the active metabolite.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-2-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; The commonly assessed vitamin D levels refer to the 25(OH)D metabolite, which is the main circulating form in the body.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-2-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; Vitamin D deficiency, commonly defined as levels lower than 25 nmol/L, is a common problem both in developed&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-3-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; and in developing countries.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-4-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; Although it is usually thought to be a problem in countries located at higher latitudes and with darker days,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-5-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-5&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt; a high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency is also observed in countries close to the equator.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-6-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-6&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt; According to guidance from the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE), those with low vitamin D levels should be treated with high-dose supplementation for a short period, followed by a lower maintenance dose,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-7-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-7&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt; and all adults are advised to take a daily supplement containing 10 mg per day throughout the year to prevent vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-11&quot;&gt;URT infections are reportedly more frequent and more severe in individuals with lower vitamin D levels. Although these infections are more common during seasons with darker days, when vitamin D levels are lower, vitamin D has also been correlated with better pulmonary function in young adults&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-8-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-8&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt; and with lower reporting of coughs and colds;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-9-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-9&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt; however, these studies cannot provide evidence of causation. A meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials of vitamin D supplementation for acute respiratory tract infections found a protective effect of vitamin D,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-10-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-10&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt; but the study has been criticised for the way the approach was used.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-11-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-11&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt; Current evidence for the use of vitamin D supplementation against COVID-19 mainly relies on assumptions based on reports of lower vitamin D being associated with a higher risk of URT infections (please see the review by Lanham-New &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-12-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-12&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt; A handful of studies have used a data-based approach,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-13-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-13&quot;&gt;13–17&lt;/a&gt; but these efforts rely on correlations between vitamin D and COVID-19, which are liable to be affected by unobserved or inadequately controlled confounding factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-12&quot;&gt;Although we will need well-powered and carefully executed randomised trials and a subsequent meta-analysis of the different studies to provide an accurate estimate of the effect of vitamin D on COVID-19 prevention and severity, we can anticipate the results of such studies by comparing individuals who are genetically predisposed to lower vitamin D levels with those who are not, based on the Mendelian randomisation (MR) paradigm. In a randomised controlled trial, we would minimise the effect of confounding factors by randomly assigning participants to a treatment group receiving vitamin D supplements or to a control group receiving a placebo and thus estimate the true effect of the intervention. In the natural experiment of MR, genetic variants predisposing the individual to higher levels of vitamin D are assigned randomly at conception, based on the genetic polymorphisms of their parents, in relation to other possible confounding traits. As genetic polymorphisms remain constant throughout life and the individual does not change their vitamin D intake according to their genotype, the use of this information can provide indirect evidence of causality.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-18-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-18&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt; Here, using data from genome-wide association (GWA) studies for vitamin D levels, vitamin D deficiency and COVID-19 incidence and severity, we test whether genetically increased vitamin D levels are associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection risk and COVID-19 severity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section methods&quot; id=&quot;sec-6&quot; readability=&quot;55.836347498058&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-7&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot; readability=&quot;21.729678638941&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Population and study design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-13&quot;&gt;We predominately used previously published and freely available data for this study. The study by Jiang &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-19-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-19&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt; is a meta-analysis of GWAs of vitamin D levels carried out using participants of European descent. The COVID-19 Host Genetics Initiative&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-20-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-20&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt; uses data from multiple cohort studies,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-21-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-21&quot;&gt;21–26&lt;/a&gt; including the UK Biobank (UKB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-14&quot;&gt;The UKB individual-level data were also used following permission to use data already available for COVID-19-related research. UKB is a large prospective cohort study that recruited &amp;gt;500 000 UK residents between 2006 and 2010. The 22 UKB assessment centres, located throughout England, Wales and Scotland, collected baseline data from the participants in the form of questionnaires, physical and cognitive tests, and blood and urine samples.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-27-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-27&quot;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt; The age range of the participants at the time of enrolment in the study was between 40 and 69 years of age, with a mean age of 56.5 years. Men represent 45.6% of the sample. The use of the data for this project was approved by the UKB (application 44566).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-8&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot; readability=&quot;22.890039840637&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Genotyping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-15&quot;&gt;In the UKB, 488 377 individuals had been genotyped for up to 812 428 variants using DNA extracted from blood samples on either the UKB Axiom array (438 427 participants) or the UK BiLEVE Axiom array (49 950 participants). Variants that did not pass standard quality control checks were excluded.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-28-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-28&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt; These included tests for the presence of batch effects, plate effects, sex effects and array effects, as well as any departures from Hardy-Weinberg Equilibrium using a p value threshold of 10&lt;sup&gt;−12&lt;/sup&gt;. Variants with a minor allele frequency of &amp;lt;0.01 were also excluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-16&quot;&gt;Sample genotyping quality control metrics were provided by UKB.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-28-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-28&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt; Samples were excluded from the analysis if they were outliers for missingness and/or PC-corrected heterozygosity and/or if they had any sex chromosome aneuploidies, as well as if the genetically inferred sex differed from the reported sex. Samples which did not have a genetically determined white British ancestry were also excluded. A list of related individuals was also provided by UKB and one individual from each related pair was excluded at random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-17&quot;&gt;Genetic data from studies used by the COVID-19 Host Genetics Initiative underwent quality control and imputation using the protocol described by Lam &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-29-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-29&quot;&gt;29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-9&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot; readability=&quot;16.690909090909&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Phenotypes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-18&quot;&gt;We used summary statistics from phenotypes B1 and C1 by the COVID-19 Host Genetics Initiative (September 2020 release). Phenotype B1 is a measure of COVID-19 severity and only included individuals who were positive for SARS-CoV-2 infection based on an RNA-based and/or a serology-based test: individuals who were hospitalised due to coronavirus-related symptoms were coded as cases; and individuals who were not hospitalised for 21 days or more after their positive SARS-CoV-2 test were coded as controls. Phenotype C1 is a measure of susceptibility to SARS-CoV-2 infection: individuals were coded as cases if they were diagnosed with COVID-19 by a doctor or if they were positive for SARS-CoV-2 infection based on an RNA-based and/or a serology-based test or if they self-reported being positive for COVID-19; and individuals were coded as controls if they tested negative (for all tests if multiple tests were performed) for SARS-CoV-2 infection based on an RNA-based and/or a serology-based test or if they self-reported being negative for COVID-19. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.covid19hg.org/about/&quot;&gt;https://www.covid19hg.org/about/&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-19&quot;&gt;Vitamin D deficiency: individuals whose vitamin D levels (UKB field 30890) were &amp;lt;25 nmol/L were coded as cases; and individuals whose vitamin D levels were ≥50 nmol/L were coded as controls. COVID-19 test results&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-30-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-30&quot;&gt;30&lt;/a&gt; from the UKB were made available through linkage to national health records. Obesity: individuals whose body mass index (BMI) was ≥18.5 kg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; and &amp;lt;25 kg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; (UKB field 21001) were considered as having a normal weight; and individuals whose BMI was ≥30 kg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; were considered as being obese. Season: individuals who attended the assessment centres during December, January or February (UKB field 55) were considered as winter samples; and individuals who attended during June, July or August were considered as summer samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-10&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot; readability=&quot;60.314588088815&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Statistical analyses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-20&quot;&gt;We used R V.4.0.2&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-31-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-31&quot;&gt;31&lt;/a&gt; to carry out analyses and generate plots, unless stated otherwise. We used PLINK V.1.9&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-32-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-32&quot;&gt;32&lt;/a&gt; to carry out genetic association analyses using UKB data and to generate the genetic risk score for vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-21&quot;&gt;Welch’s two-sample t-test was used to assess the differences in the distribution of vitamin D levels in the following categories: obese versus normal weight; summer samples versus winter samples; and the bottom and top quartiles of the vitamin D levels genetic risk score generated using variants from Jiang &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-19-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-19&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-supplementary-material-1-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-supplementary-material&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#DC1&quot;&gt;online supplemental table 1B and figure 1&lt;/a&gt;). Fisher’s exact test was used to assess the differences in the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in the three aforementioned categories, except that the vitamin D deficiency genetic risk score used for this analysis was generated using the 17 variants associated with vitamin D deficiency in the UKB (see &lt;a id=&quot;xref-supplementary-material-1-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-supplementary-material&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#DC1&quot;&gt;online supplemental table 1A and figure 2&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;DC1&quot; class=&quot;supplementary-material&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Supplemental material&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-23&quot;&gt;To assess the causal effect of vitamin D levels on SARS-CoV-2 infection risk and COVID-19 severity, we used outcome summary statistics from the COVID-19 Host Genetics Initiative&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-20-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-20&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt; (see the Phenotypes section) and exposure summary statistics from Jiang &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-19-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-19&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt; (see the Population and study design section) to carry out two-sample MR using the TwoSampleMR R package.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-33-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-33&quot;&gt;33&lt;/a&gt; Note: rs3755967, rs12785878 and rs8018720 were not available in the summary statistics for phenotypes B1 and C1, so we used rs17467825, rs3794060 and rs8022510, respectively, as proxies (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; &amp;gt;0.99). The causal estimates (beta) are expressed as ln(OR) per ln(nM), where OR=Odds ratio; and nM=concentration of vitamin D in nmol/L.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-24&quot;&gt;For each genetic variant that is associated with the exposure of interest (eg, vitamin D), the causal effect of the exposure of interest on the outcome of interest (eg, SARS-CoV-2 risk or COVID-19 severity) can be estimated by calculating the Wald ratio, which is the effect of the variant on the outcome divided by the effect of the variant on the exposure. If there are multiple independently inherited variants associated with the exposure, as in this case, the inverse variance weighted MR (IVW-MR) method is used to provide an overall estimate of the causal effect by calculating a weighted average of the Wald ratios. However, in the presence of pleiotropy (ie, a genetic variant is associated with the outcome through a pathway that does not include the exposure of interest), the estimate from the IVW-MR method may be biased. The MR Egger method models this possible violation of the assumption through the intercept of a linear model between the effect of the instruments on the exposure and outcome. In the absence of pleiotropy, the value of this intercept does not differ from zero. However, if the pleiotropic effects of the variants are related to their effects on the exposure (ie, a violation of the INSIDE assumption), the MR Egger and IVW-MR methods are both susceptible to bias. In this case, the weighted median, simple mode and weighted mode MR methods are used. These methods use the median or mode of the Wald ratios to provide robust estimates in cases where some of the genetic instruments violate the pleiotropy assumption.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-34-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-34&quot;&gt;34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-25&quot;&gt;In order to use two-sample MR to estimate the causal effect of vitamin D deficiency on the aforementioned outcomes, we needed to obtain new instruments for vitamin D deficiency. We therefore carried out a GWA analysis in the UKB using PLINK V.1.9,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-32-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-32&quot;&gt;32&lt;/a&gt; adjusted for the first four principal components for the genetic variability of the genome, age at baseline, sex and the genotyping array used. The associated genes for each variant were obtained from National Center for Biotechnology Information Single Nucleotide Polymorphism (NCBI SNP). As the COVID-19 Host Genetics Initiative uses data from the UKB, there is a possibility that the estimates from two-sample MR analyses may be biased; Burgess &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-35-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-35&quot;&gt;35&lt;/a&gt; suggest that this bias can be minimised by generating exposure summary statistics using control samples only, so we excluded individuals who had been tested for COVID-19 from our GWA analysis. The summary statistics for vitamin D deficiency were then filtered using a p value threshold of 5×10&lt;sup&gt;−8&lt;/sup&gt; and clumped using the ‘clump_data’ function, which finds the variant with the smallest p value, removes any variants that are in linkage disequilibrium (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; &amp;gt;0.001) and repeats this process until there are no variants remaining. It is possible that the effects of the genetic variants associated with vitamin D deficiency may vary by season, so we repeated the genetic association analyses using winter samples only and used the effect sizes from these to carry out two-sample MR to test the sensitivity of our results to this possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section results&quot; id=&quot;sec-11&quot; readability=&quot;31.163040696186&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-26&quot;&gt;For SARS-CoV-2 infection susceptibility (phenotype C1), summary statistics from 11 181 cases and 116 456 controls were available as of 30 September 2020. For COVID-19 severity (phenotype B1), summary statistics from 1389 cases and 5879 controls were available as of 30 September 2020. For the vitamin D deficiency phenotype in the UKB, there were 35 079 cases and 140 898 controls. Please see the Methods section for the phenotype definitions. The genetic risk score generated using the six variants from Jiang &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-19-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-19&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-supplementary-material-1-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-supplementary-material&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#DC1&quot;&gt;online supplemental table 1B&lt;/a&gt;) explained 2.518% of the variance in vitamin D concentration and the genetic risk score generated using the newly identified 17 variants associated with vitamin D deficiency (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-supplementary-material-1-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-supplementary-material&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#DC1&quot;&gt;online supplemental table 1A&lt;/a&gt;) explained 2.108% of the variance in vitamin D deficiency (note: the latter is an approximation based on McFadden’s R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;). &lt;a id=&quot;xref-table-wrap-1-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-table&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#T1&quot;&gt;Table 1&lt;/a&gt; shows the distribution of vitamin D levels and the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency by genetic risk score category (1st quartile vs 4th quartile), together with the changes associated with known factors affecting vitamin concentration, such as obesity and season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;T1&quot; class=&quot;table pos-float&quot; readability=&quot;6.5722222222222&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;table-inline table-callout-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;View this table:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;table-caption&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;table-label&quot;&gt;Table 1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-27&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;Distribution of vitamin D levels and prevalence of vitamin D deficiency by obesity status, season and the genetic risk scores in the UK Biobank&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-34&quot;&gt;We estimated the causal effect of vitamin D levels on the risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection and severe COVID-19 using two-sample MR. We found no evidence in the existing data that vitamin D levels causally affect the risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection (IVW: ln(OR)=0.17 (95% CI −0.22 to 0.57, p=0.39)) nor did we find evidence that vitamin D levels causally affect COVID-19 severity (IVW: ln(OR)=0.36 (95% CI −0.89 to 1.61, p=0.57)). We also used four other more robust MR methods and we still did not find any evidence in the existing data to suggest that vitamin D levels causally affect SARS-CoV-2 risk or COVID-19 severity (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#F1&quot;&gt;figure 1&lt;/a&gt;). Testing for the presence of pleiotropy for our genetic instruments using the MR Egger method suggests that our estimates are not biased due to pleiotropy (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-supplementary-material-1-5&quot; class=&quot;xref-supplementary-material&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#DC1&quot;&gt;online supplemental table 2&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;F1&quot; class=&quot;fig pos-float odd&quot; readability=&quot;5.454954954955&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highwire-figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline-img-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline-img&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/bmjnph/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151/F1.large.jpg?width=800&amp;amp;height=600&amp;amp;carousel=1&quot; title=&quot;Log ORs (beta) and 95% CIs from a two-sample MR analysis of the effect of vitamin D levels on SARS-CoV-2 risk and COVID-19 severity. MR, Mendelian randomisation.&quot; class=&quot;highwire-fragment fragment-images colorbox-load&quot; rel=&quot;gallery-fragment-images-2067329720&quot; data-figure-caption=&quot;&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;highwire-markup&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Log ORs (beta) and 95% CIs from a two-sample MR analysis of the effect of vitamin D levels on SARS-CoV-2 risk and COVID-19 severity. MR, Mendelian randomisation.&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&quot; data-icon-position=&quot;&quot; data-hide-link-title=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hw-responsive-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;highwire-fragment fragment-image lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; data-src=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/bmjnph/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151/F1.medium.gif&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; height=&quot;297&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;highwire-fragment fragment-image&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1&quot; src=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/bmjnph/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151/F1.medium.gif&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; height=&quot;297&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns:xhtml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;fig-caption&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fig-label&quot;&gt;Figure 1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-35&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;Log ORs (beta) and 95% CIs from a two-sample MR analysis of the effect of vitamin D levels on SARS-CoV-2 risk and COVID-19 severity. MR, Mendelian randomisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-36&quot;&gt;It is possible that simply having vitamin D levels that are lower, but still within the optimal range, may not affect SARS-CoV-2 risk nor COVID-19 severity. We therefore performed a GWA analysis of vitamin D deficiency in the UKB, found that 17 independent variants were associated with this phenotype (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-supplementary-material-1-6&quot; class=&quot;xref-supplementary-material&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#DC1&quot;&gt;online supplemental table 1A&lt;/a&gt;) and used these variants in a two-sample MR analysis to estimate the causal effect of vitamin D deficiency on the risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19 severity. We found no evidence that vitamin D deficiency causally affects the risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection (IVW: ln(OR)=−0.04 (95% CI −0.1 to 0.03, p=0.25)) nor did we find evidence that vitamin D deficiency causally affects COVID-19 severity (IVW: ln(OR)=−0.24 (95% CI −0.55 to 0.08, p=0.14)). We also used four other robust MR methods and we still did not find any evidence to suggest that vitamin D deficiency causally affects SARS-CoV-2 risk or COVID-19 severity (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-2-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#F2&quot;&gt;figure 2&lt;/a&gt;). Again, we did not detect any evidence of pleiotropy bias in our results using the MR Egger method (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-supplementary-material-1-7&quot; class=&quot;xref-supplementary-material&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#DC1&quot;&gt;online supplemental table 3&lt;/a&gt;). We repeated the two-sample MR using effect sizes from the winter samples only (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-supplementary-material-1-8&quot; class=&quot;xref-supplementary-material&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#DC1&quot;&gt;online supplemental table 4&lt;/a&gt;) as a sensitivity analysis, and our results did not differ (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-supplementary-material-1-9&quot; class=&quot;xref-supplementary-material&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#DC1&quot;&gt;online supplemental table 5&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;F2&quot; class=&quot;fig pos-float odd&quot; readability=&quot;5.4823008849558&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highwire-figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline-img-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline-img&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/bmjnph/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151/F2.large.jpg?width=800&amp;amp;height=600&amp;amp;carousel=1&quot; title=&quot;Log ORs (beta) and 95% CIs from a two-sample MR analysis of the effect of vitamin D deficiency on SARS-CoV-2 risk and COVID-19 severity. MR, Mendelian randomisation.&quot; class=&quot;highwire-fragment fragment-images colorbox-load&quot; rel=&quot;gallery-fragment-images-2067329720&quot; data-figure-caption=&quot;&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;highwire-markup&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Log ORs (beta) and 95% CIs from a two-sample MR analysis of the effect of vitamin D deficiency on SARS-CoV-2 risk and COVID-19 severity. MR, Mendelian randomisation.&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&quot; data-icon-position=&quot;&quot; data-hide-link-title=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hw-responsive-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;highwire-fragment fragment-image lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 2&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; data-src=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/bmjnph/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151/F2.medium.gif&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; height=&quot;293&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;highwire-fragment fragment-image&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 2&quot; src=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/bmjnph/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151/F2.medium.gif&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; height=&quot;293&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-caption&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fig-label&quot;&gt;Figure 2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-37&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;Log ORs (beta) and 95% CIs from a two-sample MR analysis of the effect of vitamin D deficiency on SARS-CoV-2 risk and COVID-19 severity. MR, Mendelian randomisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section discussion&quot; id=&quot;sec-12&quot; readability=&quot;55.650298041442&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-38&quot;&gt;Using previously published results for the genetics of vitamin D levels, UKB individual-level data for the genetics of vitamin D deficiency and the accumulating genetic results for susceptibility and severity of COVID-19, we tested the causal effect of vitamin D levels and deficiency on protection from SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19 severity. We found no evidence that vitamin D is causally related to COVID-19 outcomes and there is no evidence to suggest that current NICE guidance should change to support the use of vitamin D supplementation against COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-39&quot;&gt;Previously published evidence,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-10-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-10&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt; though criticised,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-11-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-11&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt; supports the idea that increasing vitamin D levels are protective against acute respiratory tract infections, but these results do not appear to translate in the case of COVID-19. Studies specifically looking at the correlation of vitamin D with COVID-19 and its severity observed an inverse association between them,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-13-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-13&quot;&gt;13 15–17&lt;/a&gt; though, in one study,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-14-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-14&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt; when a number of possible confounders were adjusted for, the correlation was no longer present. These studies, however, can only provide very limited information on causality and they are sensitive to uncontrolled confounders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-40&quot;&gt;Vitamin D is lower in hospitalised individuals and even more so in those in care homes with limited mobility and exposure to sunlight,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-36-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-36&quot;&gt;36&lt;/a&gt; both of which are much more common in the elderly. COVID-19, at least in the UK, has had a disproportional effect on older people and care homes, making it difficult to disentangle the complex relationships between age and disability on one hand and diet and sunlight exposure affecting vitamin D on the other. Our approach uses genetic information to avoid the problem of unobserved confounders, a method that has rapidly gained popularity for the estimation of causal effects based on observational studies.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-37-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-37&quot;&gt;37&lt;/a&gt; Our results are based on GWA studies combining data for tens of thousands of individuals from different sources of information to ensure an unbiased estimate and a result that provides the best chance to detect an effect, if present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-41&quot;&gt;However, our work is not without limitations. The most common problem of MR analyses is the presence of pleiotropy. Although this is more likely to cause false positives, rather than false negatives, no evidence for pleiotropy was detected in our analyses. We also used multiple MR models that make slightly different assumptions and provide a more pleiotropy robust result with all of them providing the same conclusion. Vitamin D levels were represented by measures of 25(OH)D which, despite being the most commonly assessed vitamin D metabolite in a clinical setting, does not directly measure the activated form of vitamin D and its measurement and relevance to health are under discussion.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-38-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151#ref-38&quot;&gt;38&lt;/a&gt; Our results also cannot be used to comment on the relationship between vitamin D and COVID-19 in non-Europeans. Finally, the available data for SARS-CoV-2 infection or severe COVID-19 disease are still limited and a more precise picture will emerge as more information becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-42&quot;&gt;To summarise, using a two-sample MR method, GWA studies of vitamin D and the latest data from tens of thousands of individuals courtesy of the international COVID-19 Host Genetics Initiative, we found no evidence of vitamin D being protective against SARS-CoV-2 infection or severe COVID-19. Our results support the recent statement by NICE that the use of vitamin D supplementation to mitigate COVID-19 is not supported by the available data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section ack&quot; id=&quot;ack-1&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-43&quot;&gt;The authors would like to thank the UK Biobank participants for sharing their data with the research community and the UK Biobank access committee for making these data available for COVID-19 research. They also thank the COVID-19 Host Genetics Initiative for organising and making the genome-wide association data available to all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 19:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>whoisburbansky</dc:creator>
<og:title>No evidence that vitamin D is able to prevent or affect the severity of COVID-19 in individuals with European ancestry: a Mendelian randomisation study of open data</og:title>
<og:url>https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151</og:url>
<og:description>Background Upper respiratory tract infections are reportedly more frequent and more severe in individuals with lower vitamin D levels. Based on these findings, it has been suggested that vitamin D can prevent or reduce the severity of COVID-19. Methods We used two-sample Mendelian randomisation (MR) to assess the causal effect of vitamin D levels on SARS-CoV-2 infection risk and COVID-19 severity using publicly available data. We also carried out a genome-wide association analysis (GWA) of vitamin D deficiency in the UK Biobank (UKB) and used these results and two-sample MR to assess the causal effect of vitamin D deficiency on SARS-CoV-2 infection risk and COVID-19 severity. Results We found no evidence that vitamin D levels causally affect the risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection (ln(OR)=0.17 (95% CI −0.22 to 0.57, p=0.39)) nor did we find evidence that vitamin D levels causally affect COVID-19 severity (ln(OR)=0.36 (95% CI −0.89 to 1.61, p=0.57)). Based on our GWA analysis, we found that 17 independent variants are associated with vitamin D deficiency in the UKB. Using these variants as instruments for our two-sample MR analyses, we found no evidence that vitamin D deficiency causally affects the risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection (ln(OR)=−0.04 (95% CI −0.1 to 0.03, p=0.25)) nor did we find evidence that vitamin D deficiency causally affects COVID-19 severity (ln(OR)=−0.24 (95% CI −0.55 to 0.08, p=0.14)). Conclusions In conclusion, we found no evidence that vitamin D is protective against SARS-CoV-2 infection or COVID-19 severity. Our data support the recent statement by the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence that the use of vitamin D supplementation to mitigate COVID-19 is not supported by the available data.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://nutrition.bmj.com/sites/default/files/highwire/bmjnph/3/1.cover-source.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nutrition.bmj.com/content/early/2021/01/07/bmjnph-2020-000151</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I tried creating a web browser and Google blocked me (2019)</title>
<link>https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/images/google-widevine-gmail.png&quot; alt=&quot;I’m sorry but we’re not supporting an open source solution like this&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 4 months of waiting, that is the response I got from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.widevine.com/&quot;&gt;Widevine&lt;/a&gt;, Google’s DRM for web browsers, regarding a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/castlabs/electron-releases#verified-media-path-vmp&quot;&gt;license agreement&lt;/a&gt;. For the last 2 years I’ve been working on a web browser that now cannot be completed because Google, the creators of the &lt;em&gt;open source&lt;/em&gt; browser Chrome, won’t allow DRM in an &lt;em&gt;open source&lt;/em&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The browser I’m building, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samuelmaddock/metastream&quot;&gt;Metastream&lt;/a&gt;, is an Electron-based (Chromium derived), MIT-licensed browser hosted on GitHub. Its main feature is the ability to playback videos on the web, synchronized with other peers. Each client runs its own instance of the Metastream browser and transmits playback information to keep them in sync—no audio or video content is sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone is creating a browser that wants to playback media, they’ll soon discover the requirement of DRM for larger web media services such as Netflix and Hulu. There are a few DRM providers for the web including Widevine, PlayReady, and FairPlay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I’m aware, Widevine is the only available DRM for a Chromium-based browser, especially so for Electron. Chromium accounts for roughly &lt;strong&gt;70% market share&lt;/strong&gt; of all web browsers, soon to include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.windowscentral.com/microsoft-building-chromium-powered-web-browser-windows-10&quot;&gt;Microsoft’s upcoming Edge browser rewrite&lt;/a&gt;. Waiting 4 months for a minimal response from a vendor with such a large percentage of the market is unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t something I’m alone in either, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/electron/electron/issues/12427&quot;&gt;several Electron users&lt;/a&gt; have waited months for a response. More prominently, the creators of Brave Browser also had &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brave/browser-laptop/issues/10449#issuecomment-323800130&quot;&gt;issues waiting for replies from Google Widevine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a prime example for why free as in beer is not enough. Small share browsers are at the mercy of Google, and Google is stalling us for no communicated-to-us reason.”&lt;br/&gt;- Brian Bondy, Co-founder &amp;amp; CTO of Brave&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m now only left with two options regarding the fate of Metastream: stop development of a desktop browser version, or pivot my project to a browser extension with reduced features. The latter requiring publishing to the Google Chrome Web Store which would further entrench the project into a Google walled garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know of any way to help out, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/contact&quot;&gt;please get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 4th edit:&lt;/strong&gt; No response from Google Widevine yet. Because a few folks asked, here is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/widevine/gmail-thread.html&quot;&gt;full email exchange I had with Widevine&lt;/a&gt;. The initial response was received after getting in contact with another browser vendor to ping a Widevine contact they have. If you intend to inquire about a license agreement for your project, including the information they requested upfront could help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19553941&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Discuss on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/b8jekq/i_tried_creating_a_web_browser_and_google_blocked/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Discuss on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samuelmaddock/blog.samuelmaddock.com/commits/master/content/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser.md&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View changelog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 18:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gu5</dc:creator>
<og:title>I tried creating a web browser, and Google blocked me</og:title>
<og:description>After 4 months of waiting, that is the response I got from Widevine, Google’s DRM for web browsers, regarding a license agreement. For the last 2 years I’ve been working on a web browser that now cannot be completed because Google, the creators of the open source browser Chrome, won’t allow DRM in an open source project. The browser I’m building, called Metastream, is an Electron-based (Chromium derived), MIT-licensed browser hosted on GitHub.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/images/chromium-cover-social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FedEx shipping damage creates fractured artworks</title>
<link>https://kottke.org/21/01/fedex-shipping-damage-creates-fractured-artworks</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://kottke.org/21/01/fedex-shipping-damage-creates-fractured-artworks</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kottke.org/plus/misc/images/walead-beshty-fedex-01.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1288&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Walead Beshty's FedEx artworks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kottke.org/plus/misc/images/walead-beshty-fedex-02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1501&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Walead Beshty's FedEx artworks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kottke.org/plus/misc/images/walead-beshty-fedex-03.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1104&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Walead Beshty's FedEx artworks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kottke.org/plus/misc/images/walead-beshty-fedex-04.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1217&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Walead Beshty's FedEx artworks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2007, artist Walead Beshty has been cleverly using FedEx’s shipping infrastructure to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.actionstakenunderthefictitiousnamewaleadbeshtystudiosinc.com/fedex-glass-works-2007&quot;&gt;create a series of artworks&lt;/a&gt;. He constructs glass objects that fit exactly into FedEx’s shipping boxes and then ships them to galleries and museums without any protection against damage. Any cracks or breaks in the glass became part of the work upon display at its destination. According &lt;a href=&quot;https://museemagazine.com/features/2018/10/15/walead-beshty-the-end-game&quot;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt;, part of what interested Beshty about doing this project related to the proprietary sizes of FedEx’s boxes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the corporate dimension, I was aware that standard FedEx boxes are SSCC coded (serial shipping container code), a code that is held by FedEx and excludes other shippers from registering a box with the same dimensions. In other words, the size of an official FedEx box, not just its design, is proprietary; it is a volume of space which is a property exclusive to FedEx. When thinking about the work, its scale and so on, it made sense to adhere to that proprietary volume, because, as a modular, it had a real and preexisting significance in daily life, it was common, specific, and immediately familiar. That is, it had an iconic resonance that a more arbitrary form or shape wouldn’t have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And each time the work is shipped — say from one gallery to another — it’s unwittingly altered further by a system created by a massive multinational corporation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than thinking in terms of the Duchampian readymade, which is most often understood as operating iconically — as in the appropriation and repositioning of a static thing — I was thinking of readymade systems of production, of using pre-existing active systems to produce a work. No object is truly static anyway, so this opened up broader questions I had about the tradition of appropriation, the way it froze cultural signifiers and reapplied them to other contexts, treated images as dead, static things… The object isn’t treated differently than other FedEx packages, I simply used FedEx to transport an object that registers how the system treated it in aesthetic terms. The result is that the object is constantly changing. Every time the work is shipped it goes through a material transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More about...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 18:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>talonx</dc:creator>
<og:title>FedEx Shipping Damage Creates Fractured Artworks</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://kottke.org/21/01/fedex-shipping-damage-creates-fractured-artworks</og:url>
<og:image>https://kottke.org/plus/misc/images/walead-beshty-fedex-01.jpg</og:image>
<og:description> Since 2007, artist Walead Beshty has been cleverly using FedEx's shipping infrastructure to create a series of artworks. H</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://kottke.org/21/01/fedex-shipping-damage-creates-fractured-artworks</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Porting Firefox to Apple Silicon</title>
<link>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/01/porting-firefox-to-apple-silicon/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/01/porting-firefox-to-apple-silicon/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The release of Apple Silicon-based Macs at the end of last year generated a flurry of news coverage and some surprises at the machine’s performance. This post details some background information on the experience of porting Firefox to run natively on these CPUs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’ll start with some background on the Mac transition and give an overview of Firefox internals that needed to know about the new architecture, before moving on to the concept of Universal Binaries.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’ll then explain how DRM/EME works on the new platform, talk about our experience with macOS Big Sur, and discuss various updater problems we had to deal with. We’ll conclude with the release and an overview of various other improvements that are in the pipeline.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Silicon Approaching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Speculation that Apple would switch its Mac lineup to use ARM CPUs had been ongoing in the industry for several years. As early as 2013,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/uk/newsroom/2013/09/10Apple-Announces-iPhone-5s-The-Most-Forward-Thinking-Smartphone-in-the-World/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Apple had referred to the custom ARM chips they were putting in the iPhone as “desktop-class” designs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While the claim initially met some scepticism, near the end of 2018 computer hardware magazine AnandTech published the results of running the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/13392/the-iphone-xs-xs-max-review-unveiling-the-silicon-secrets/4&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;industry-standard SPEC benchmark on the iPhone XS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, showing that even workloads that reflect real-world desktop use cases reached desktop chip performance, and were doing so at significantly better power efficiency.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;This provided us with some warning that Apple might be ready to start the transition to the ARM architecture in the near future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;From the perspective of Mozillla’s platform team, an area of particular interest for such an architecture change on macOS is Firefox’s use of macOS APIs. Firefox and Gecko’s roots go back to the Netscape codebase, which already supported the Mac as it was in 1994.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Although continuously updated, Firefox still uses a wide range of macOS APIs that followed the Mac’s evolution over the years (Carbon, Cocoa, HIITheme, Quartz, …). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Apple has generally kept them — the code is there and working, after all — and has even added compatibility shims in some places where behavior has changed. But they’re not willing to keep compatibility forever, and in fact had removed 32-bit support in the previous macOS Catalina which had an impact on applications that were relying on this, among them many games.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; As such, we were concerned that not all APIs would still be supported on the new architecture and we’d have to go in and rewrite some amount of widget, toolkit or theming code in short order.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Based on the performance from the aforementioned benchmarks and Apple’s historical release schedule, the platform team estimated in March that “macOS 10.16” was likely to appear around September or October 2020 and that there was a significant risk it could involve API changes in order to add ARM support, which we took into account in our planning.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Announcement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the 22nd of June 2020, Apple confirmed it would begin moving its Mac hardware to their own ARM chips – referred to as Apple Silicon. They also confirmed that the machines would ship with an Intel x64 emulator (Rosetta 2) and would support iOS apps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The latter led to some guessing within Mozilla’s platform team as to whether the new Macs would have a touchscreen. While we were — and still are — quite ready to support it, at least the eventual first Apple Silicon-based Macs didn’t end up having one.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Together with the announcement of the transition, Apple also announced the availability of Developer Transition Kits (DTK),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/06/apple-announces-mac-transition-to-apple-silicon/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;essentially containing the iPad Pro’s chip in a Mac Mini housing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. What Apple didn’t share was when exactly the final machines were coming to market.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Based on the timing of the DTK availability and Apple’s hint that it would be “by the end of the year”, we guessed this was likely to be somewhat before the Christmas holidays.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Looking back, we noticed that Apple has very consistently been able to make hardware available near immediately after announcing it, so we figured that any next planned announcement should be taken as a release date.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When another announcement was planned for November 10th – about a month before our original estimate – we took it as the shipping date. And indeed, Apple did end up shipping the first hardware one week later on November 17th.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Steps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Of all the work needed to support the new hardware, porting Firefox to the 64-bit ARM architecture was not actually something we needed to do: we’ve supported 64-bit ARM on Android and Linux for years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We refrained from publishing the 64-bit Android builds until late 2019 because before that point our JavaScript JIT was not fully optimized for 64-bit ARM, and the resulting 64-bit version would have been slower than the 32-bit one.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;There wasn’t much demand for the browser to be able to use over 4GB of memory on phones either! In 2019,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2019/04/11/firefox-beta-for-windows-10-on-qualcomm-snapdragon-always-connected-pcs-now-available/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;we released the first Firefox version for Windows on 64 bit ARM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;which gave us some additional experience in exactly the kind of effort we were facing now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.firefox.com/dashboard/hardware&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;While Windows on ARM hardware has failed to catch on with our users so far,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;expectations were for the Apple transition to be very different. Not only was there a good reason to expect hardware performance to be groundbreaking as explained in the first section.&lt;/span&gt; Apple made it clear they were switching their entire lineup and not releasing a single device as a “feeler”. To top it off, they had a proven track record of successful architecture transitions on the Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So with 64-bit ARM support already in the codebase, the first pass of work was to go through all the Firefox code, dependencies, and various third-party build systems to see if they correctly dealt with the novel idea that a Mac could have an ARM chip inside.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Secondly, we needed to adapt and fix the various parts of the Firefox codebase that deal with low-level calling conventions and particularly the interfaces between the JavaScript and C++ (and nowadays Rust) parts of the code.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rust in particular was a concern. Firefox depends on Rust code, and we require a working Rust compiler to build the browser. Although&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/73908&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Apple Silicon support for Rust was underway&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, it took until mid-August for there to be functional compiler builds, which limited the amount of progress possible for Firefox.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Once the compiler was working, a similar exercise needed to be done with all the Rust crates we depend on. The need to update the compiler and the reliance of some crates on the exact compiler version, especially parts dealing with SIMD support, would end up biting us later on as it made it hard to push Apple Silicon support forward to an earlier release of Firefox without potentially affecting other platforms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal Binaries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;An important decision to be made was whether to produce separate builds for Intel- and ARM-based Macs, or to generate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_binary&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Universal Binaries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;which bundle both builds and select the correct version at runtime. Producing Universal Binaries is a bit more complicated, but we had existing tooling in place dating back to the time when Apple supported both 32-bit and 64-bit binaries, which could be adapted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It greatly simplifies things for the user — there is no risk of downloading the wrong version — and also meant that our download pages and some infrastructure like localization could remain unchanged.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The main downside is the installer significantly increasing in size, not just for ARM users but also for Intel ones. As this only affects the initial install, and users typically receive new versions through updates that are much smaller, we felt that this was an acceptable downside and proceeded along this route.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netflix and DRM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While we can port the open-source parts of Firefox to 64-bit ARM ourselves, Netflix and some other video streaming services such as Hulu, Disney+, or Amazon Prime require their video to be decoded with closed source, proprietary DRM software.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If the user visits such a site,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-drm&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Firefox will automatically download and install such a proprietary EME/CDM module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. This presented a problem to us as we would be dependent on those third-party vendors to publish ARM64 versions of those decoders.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We did not manage to get a commitment to a release date for such updates, and even if we did, there was no guarantee that they would be before the unknown release date of the Apple Silicon hardware.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;As a significant number of our users use the browser to watch video online, this presented a potential showstopper for a native Apple Silicon release.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We ended up leveraging a technique that we are also using for the Windows on ARM version of Firefox. The DRM video decoder already executes in a separate process so we can sandbox the proprietary code from the user’s system.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If we force this decoding process to run under emulation, we would be able to use the existing Intel x64 decoder modules and have them communicate with the main browser that was running natively.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;There were a few catches to getting this to work: because the process that loads the Google Widevine DRM module itself depends on some runtime libraries, we needed Intel x64 copies of those as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Luckily, due to the Universal Binary containing both versions of Firefox, we were able to pick them up directly from the Application Bundle.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Secondly, Apple did not actually ship their Rosetta 2 emulator preinstalled on the Apple Silicon machines but its installation is triggered when the user tries to run an Intel application.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So while it is very likely in practice that Rosetta is installed on the user’s system, we could not rely on this always being the case. Triggering the installation of Rosetta programmatically works, but&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.chromium.org/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=1150538&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;some of our colleagues found out the hard way it is not very reliable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, so we backed off on doing this in our first release and fell back to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/netflix-hulu-disney-or-prime-error-mac-apple-silicon&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;referring people that hit the relevant error to a support article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS Big Sur&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The macOS Big Sur betas arrived independently of the Apple Silicon hardware and allowed us to get an early look at the compatibility story. To our relief, no APIs we depended on were deprecated and any backwards compatibility problems or missing shims were limited to small cosmetic issues, which we&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1648487&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;typically managed to fix quickly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.documentfoundation.org/show_bug.cgi?id=138122&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Other open-source projects with a similarly old codebase were not as lucky&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bumping the version numbers from 10.x to 11.0 – somewhat predictably – produced errors&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1647816&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;both in our code&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1680516&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;external websites relying on UA sniffing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, despite Apple’s attempts to mitigate the problem by returning the old version number in apps built with older SDKs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Woes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pushing the updated Firefox application bundle to users – which was now a Universal Binary supporting both types of Apple hardware, instead of only Intel x64 as before – revealed some further complications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;During an update, after updating the files on disk, Firefox will relaunch the updated version of itself. Any application on Apple Silicon that is running under Intel x64 emulation and launches another process will also cause that process to be launched under emulation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So when the old Firefox 83 – running under emulation – launches the new Firefox 84 with native support, it would not launch the new native binary but end up forcing it to be run under emulation as well, at least until the application was fully restarted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While we&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1677036&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;developed a workaround&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;for this, we didn’t feel it was sufficiently tested by the release date for the marginal benefit it gave and ended up simply&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/upgrading-new-version-firefox-84-apple-silicon&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;adding a release note to cover this case&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;More of a concern was user reports that some antivirus software was flagging all our Universal Binaries as malware, and corrupting the Firefox installation the moment the update arrived.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The software was using machine learning techniques and presumably observed that our combined Universal Binaries didn’t quite look like any other legitimate software it had ever seen before.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Attempts to contact the vendor through regular support channels were unsuccessful so we ended up searching LinkedIn and managed to find an engineer working on the core antivirus detection.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;They immediately understood the seriousness of the problem and took prompt action to get a fix shipped, thus preventing quite the disaster for the users of this product. It’s notable that without this last-ditch effort we would have been effectively blocked from releasing a native Apple Silicon version for an indefinite period.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This wouldn’t be the first time that&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/justinschuh/status/802491391121260544&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;browser makers are exasperated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;at the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/justinschuh/status/803665580540633088&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;misaligned incentives for anti-virus vendors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;when anti-virus software and browsers&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1682834&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;don’t get along&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release Calls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Comparing the Firefox release schedule with the predicted release date from Apple meant that our Firefox 83 – scheduled for November 17th – aligned with the availability of release hardware.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While it would have been nice to announce native support in the stable version as soon as the first production machines arrived to customers, this would also have meant that it would be completely untested on the real hardware.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We decided to be conservative here and keep our initial support to the Firefox 84 beta, which was released the same day as Firefox 83, giving both us and our users a window of time to evaluate the stability of the product on the actual Apple Silicon hardware.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Though somewhat disappointed that after being one of the first to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MikeHommey/status/1327143370024738820&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;announce native support in Nightly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;we ended up delaying a stable release slightly, the difficulties experienced by other browser vendors with shipping a working version supported our decision. Firefox with native Apple Silicon support went into the wider world when 84 beta rolled into the Firefox 84 release, on December 15th, 2020.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While most benchmarking of Apple Silicon indicated that the performance impact of Rosetta emulation was typically low and that&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/16252/mac-mini-apple-m1-tested/6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;applications could be expected to run at about 70-80% of native performance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, we saw much larger gains when testing the native Firefox build, including doubled performance on some key benchmarks and a spectacular 2.5 times faster startup.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;One reasonable explanation for this faster startup could be that many parts of Firefox itself are written in the web’s own languages – JavaScript, CSS, and HTML – and thus use a JavaScript JIT for much of its own functionality.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;On startup, the JIT has to translate the JavaScript to machine code and while this is typically a very fast operation when running under emulation Rosetta has to then translate this JIT-generated machine code to machine code for another architecture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Apple&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1651455#c3&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;introduced a translation cache&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;that likely removes this overhead completely for most applications but it does not work for code that is output by a JIT. With the native build, this second translation is avoided completely and we’re back to having a snappy browser.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With the initial release out, there are a number of further improvements that we can and will make to the Apple Silicon version, some of which will already be available in Firefox 85.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;First of all, we had to disable&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2017/10/the-whole-web-at-maximum-fps-how-webrender-gets-rid-of-jank/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebRender&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;in the initial version because it triggered graphics driver bugs in the first Big Sur releases for Apple Silicon. Now that these have been addressed and we’ve validated WebRender on the final hardware,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1679998&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;we have re-enabled it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and it will ship in 85.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Secondly, Firefox currently uses the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/01/making-webassembly-even-faster-firefoxs-new-streaming-and-tiering-compiler/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;baseline compiler for WebAssembly on 64-bit ARM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. There is a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasmtime/tree/main/cranelift&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;faster optimizing compiler called Cranelift&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1660944&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;available for testing on Firefox Nightly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and in a few weeks, we expect to finish the 64-bit ARM port of our own optimizing compiler, Ion,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1687626&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;which is likely to become the new default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Apple Silicon chips are one of the first desktop chips that are a heterogeneous design with distinct performance and efficiency cores. We’re&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1637592&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;revising much of our core threading&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and thread pooling architecture to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1672257&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;handle the distinction better&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, improve efficiency, and eventually be&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1678083&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;able to schedule less performance-critical tasks on the efficiency cores&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally, we’re cleaning up and modernizing our usage of legacy macOS drawing APIs, and in some cases,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=34572&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;removing our custom drawing code entirely&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. This is expected to help with some of the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1558086&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;outstanding glitches in dark mode support&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.wxwidgets.org/ticket/18146&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the legacy macOS APIs simply don’t support it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-68891&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;color values must be obtained via newer APIs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It will also remove some of our deprecation worries!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We hope you enjoyed this inside view of how the Firefox team experienced the Apple Silicon transition and we’re looking forward to pushing the Firefox experience on macOS to even higher levels in the year to come.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Thanks to Mike Hommey and Haik Aftandilian for their substantial input to this post. They also did a lot of the engineering work described here. Further editorial suggestions were provided by Andrew Overholt, Sylvestre Ledru, and Selena Deckelmann.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;about&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;url&quot; href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/author/gpascuttomozilla-com/&quot;&gt;More articles by Gian-Carlo Pascutto…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sylvestre</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/01/porting-firefox-to-apple-silicon</og:url>
<og:title>Porting Firefox to Apple Silicon – Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog</og:title>
<og:description>The release of Apple Silicon based Macs at the end of last year generated a flurry of news and some surprises at the machine’s performance.</og:description>
<og:image>https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2021/01/screenshotm1bis.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/01/porting-firefox-to-apple-silicon/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Beeper – All Your Chats in One App</title>
<link>https://www.beeperhq.com/?hn</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.beeperhq.com/?hn</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to open source all our bridges to enable you to audit how Beeper connects to each chat network and verify the security of your data. The side effect is that you may self host if you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two options for self hosting Beeper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-premises, managed by Beeper&lt;/strong&gt;: run our install script on your amd64 server or 4gb Raspberry Pi and run all bridges locally on your own hardware. This option requires a Beeper subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-host the full stack&lt;/strong&gt;: The simplest and free way to self-host the full Matrix+bridges stack is with this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spantaleev/matrix-docker-ansible-deploy&quot;&gt;Ansible script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;NB: the Beeper client app is not open source, but the stack will work with Element (open source Matrix client).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>erohead</dc:creator>
<og:title>Beeper - All Your Chats In One App</og:title>
<og:description>A single app to chat on iMessage, WhatsApp, and 13 other chat networks. You can search, snooze, or archive messages. And with a unified inbox, you’ll never miss a message again.</og:description>
<og:image>https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ffc199ed786423eb2569667/60085426880a0ada43c6f2b7_opengraph.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.beeperhq.com/?hn</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I no longer trust The Great Suspender</title>
<link>https://dafoster.net/articles/2021/01/20/i-no-longer-trust-the-great-suspender/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://dafoster.net/articles/2021/01/20/i-no-longer-trust-the-great-suspender/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I know a number of folks use &lt;strong&gt;The Great Suspender&lt;/strong&gt; to automatically suspend inactive browser tabs in Chrome. Apparently recent versions of this extension have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/KyleTaylor/comments/jowlt2/open_source_development_the_great_suspender_saga/&quot;&gt;taken over by a shady anonymous entity&lt;/a&gt; and is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.windowscentral.com/great-suspender-extension-now-flagged-malware-edge-has-built-replacement&quot;&gt;flagged by Microsoft as malware&lt;/a&gt;. Notably the most recent version of the extension (v7.1.8) has added integrated analytics that can track all of your browsing activity across all sites. Yikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendations for users of The Great Suspender (7.1.8):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Temporary easy fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Disable analytics tracking by opening the extension options for The Great Suspender and checking the box “Automatic deactivation of any kind of tracking”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pray that the shady developer doesn’t issue a malicious update to The Great Suspender later. (There’s no sensible way to disable updates of an individual extension.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Permanent harder fix &lt;small&gt;(👈 &lt;strong&gt;Recommended!&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Close as many unneeded tabs as you can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsuspend all remaining tabs. ⏳&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uninstall The Great Suspender.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/releases/tag/v7.1.6&quot;&gt;latest good version&lt;/a&gt; of The Great Suspender (7.1.6) from GitHub, and move it to some permanent location outside your Downloads folder. (It should be commit 9730c09.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load your downloaded copy as &lt;a href=&quot;https://lifehacker.com/how-you-can-still-download-chrome-extensions-without-us-1826796797&quot;&gt;an unpacked extension&lt;/a&gt;. (This copy will not auto-update to future untrusted versions of the extension.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All done! 🎉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caveat:&lt;/strong&gt; My understanding is that installing an unpacked extension in this way will cause Chrome to &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25847171&quot;&gt;issue a new kind of security prompt&lt;/a&gt; every time it is launched, which you’ll have to ignore. 😕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other browser extensions for suspending tabs exist, as mentioned in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25846504&quot;&gt;Hacker New discussion&lt;/a&gt; for this article. However I have not conducted my own security review on any of those other extensions, so buyer beware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 14:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>davidfstr</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://dafoster.net/articles/2021/01/20/i-no-longer-trust-the-great-suspender/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: I built an online interactive course that helps you learn vim faster</title>
<link>https://www.vim.so</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vim.so</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vim.so&quot;&gt;https://www.vim.so&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25846347&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25846347&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 472&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 222&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 13:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CoffeePython</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.vim.so/meta_image.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.vim.so/</og:url>
<og:title>vim.so - Learn and Master Vim faster with interactive exercises</og:title>
<og:description>Learn and Master Vim with interactive exercises</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vim.so/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Update: YouTube-dl reinstated thanks to EFF (2020)</title>
<link>https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In October, the popular and famous archivist tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-dl.org/&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt; was taken down by GitHub due to a DMCA request by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recording_Industry_Association_of_America#Criticism&quot;&gt;Recording Industry Association of America&lt;/a&gt;. I posted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/10/youtube-dl-takedown/&quot;&gt;detailed analysis&lt;/a&gt; explaining the relation between international, US, EU and German law, and showing why this request was very different from what most people know as the “classic” DMCA takedown request. I felt this was necessary since there were a lot of rumor and wrong claims out on the Internet (not just in forums or on the (anti)social media, but also on media offerings), which did not help the discussion at all. The repository is back now, thanks to the EFF and its team. They &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/11/github-reinstates-youtube-dl-after-riaas-abuse-dmca&quot;&gt;filed a counter-notice&lt;/a&gt; on behalf of the youtube-dl maintainers, which allowed GitHub to reinstantiate the repository.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;eff-helps-out-by-writing-a-counter-notice&quot;&gt;EFF helps out by writing a counter notice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://eff.org&quot;&gt;Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, a non-governmental organization based in the U.S. dedicated to defending civil liberties and especially digital rights, helped out the youtube-dl maintainers by filing a very informative &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2020/11/17/eff_letter_to_github_re_youtube-dl_11152020.pdf&quot;&gt;counter notice&lt;/a&gt; with GitHub. This notice explained why the request itself is an abuse of the DMCA and the takedown was not justified at all. It allowed GitHub to reinstantiate the repository and, more importantly, all the metadata (for example, issues and pull requests) that was posted on the platform by users, developers and maintainers. Such information is invaluable to a project, and a takedown of the &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; repository with all this data can hurt a project very badly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The takedown was widely regarded as abuse of the DMCA by the RIAA, given that the youtube-dl code repository did not contain any infringing material. The argumentation was made up by claiming that the primary purpose was to infringe copyright of some songs whose artists are apparently represented by the RIAA. They cited some automated unit tests for this, which do not download the entire songs, and would not be seen or executed by regular users. The EFF argues that these are likely a form of “fair use” and thus allowed legally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The request also cited an obscure German court decision which considered YouTube’s “rolling cipher” an “effective technological measure”, whose bypassing would be prohibited by copyright laws around the world. The EFF explains that the decision was “wrongly decided and is not binding nor even persuasive under U.S. law”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EFF further questions the effectivity of the algorithm in general, given that YouTube delivers the code for decryption in a readable form (and also, the code can be executed outside browsers, too). On top of that, the streams are freely accessible once you have the URLs. YouTube only hides the URLs, but not in an effective way. Therefore, this algorithm cannot be considered a “technological measure”, and thus, the RIAA request is baseless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of this debate, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DeCSS&quot;&gt;DeCSS controversy&lt;/a&gt; was mentioned a lot, as there’s been some similarities with how copyright holders reacted to the existence of software to bypass their (arguably not very secure) CSS protection. Their first actions focused on software hosting sites, pressurizing them to take down the software by threatening them with legal steps. This led to a mirroring campaign, due to what we call the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Streisand_effect&quot;&gt;Streisand effect&lt;/a&gt; nowadays. There’s been some litigation in the early 2000s, where judges ruled in favor of the copyright holders. However, this has little relevance to the case of youtube-dl, as the EFF explains. Reverse-engineering YouTube’s code doesn’t enable users to save copies of the material, they already can do so in many other ways. Also, youtube-dl doesn’t bypass DRM technologies like Google’s Widevine. Also, there’s many resources under free licenses on the video platform, which users are explicitly allowed to download and share. And in the U.S., the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library_of_Congress&quot;&gt;Library of Congress&lt;/a&gt; may even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/de/deeplinks/2018/10/new-exemptions-dmca-section-1201-are-welcome-dont-go-far-enough&quot;&gt;issue exemptions of Section 1201&lt;/a&gt; of the DMCA, under which bypassing anti-circumvention is fine legally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EFF’s notice summarizes the situation as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9.8602409638554&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, youtube-dl does not violate either the Copyright Act or the DMCA. EFF and the youtube-dl maintainers thank GitHub for standing up for the rights of developers whose projects it hosts. We hope this explanation will allow you to restore the youtube-dl repository so that GitHub can continue to be the home for development of this popular and important tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2020/11/17/eff_letter_to_github_re_youtube-dl_11152020.pdf&quot;&gt;EFF letter to GitHub on youtube-dl takedown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, EFF! You did not just helped a tool that is crucial to journalists, activists, lawyers and so many other people. You also destroyed the RIAA’s wrong claims, which will hopefully prevent similar attacks on other tools in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;githubs-reactions&quot;&gt;GitHub’s reactions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding GitHub, it is sad that they took down the repository at all. It’s a well-known pattern: platforms rather comply with such requests than risking litigation, requiring projects to invest time and money to fund lawyers themselves (or hope for an association such as the EFF to pick up their case). The moment they published the request and took down the repositories, many experts immediately raised concerns that the request itself is illegal. It remains questionable why GitHub’s legal team didn’t recognize this. They likely were not prepared well enough for such a situation. GitHub did not stand up for the community that made them the most popular hosting platform for software in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nat Friedman, CEO of GitHub, later apparently reached out to the youtube-dl team personally, expressing his sympathy, and offering some support. However, the damage was already done then. The team lost its primary communication channel to their users and each other, as well as the entire history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems more likely that their PR department recognized they are criticised heavily for taking down the project in the first place, putting their (actually pretty good) relation to the open-source community at risk, and thus creating a serious threat to their business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least this case prompted them to rethink their strategy on future lawsuits. They posted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2020-11-16-standing-up-for-developers-youtube-dl-is-back/&quot;&gt;blog article&lt;/a&gt;, excusing their takedown with compliance, as expected. They promised changes for the benefit of projects threatened by similar requests in the future at least, such as donating to a “developer defense fund” dedicated to helping out projects threatened by such anti-circumvention takedown requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, they recognized that there is a strong need for maintainers to access the issues and pull requests. They promised to ensure that developers can export those after a takedown (even if requests are valid). The real question however is why they wouldn’t just keep showing them, and just hide the code repository. Introducing such an option globally for every repository would be an even bigger improvement, allowing developers to always create backups of those data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As GitHub state themselves, among all DMCA takedown requests, these circumvention ones are quite rare. We will have to see whether it is going to have a lot of effect. It would be better if they just donated money to defend developers of projects for which they receive &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; kind of unwarranted takedown request, rather than limiting it to this edge case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way: in the end, it’s up to the people to request better copyright laws from the politics. They tend to get worse, not better. Make sure your voice is heard. Call your representatives (that’s better than sending a mail, as a phone call can hardly be ignored). Go on the streets and protest against changes and for improvements &lt;em&gt;for you as a user&lt;/em&gt;. Support campaigns of civil rights organizations trying to change the laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-learned&quot;&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintainers who host their projects on large proprietary platforms like GitHub or GitLab’s cloud offering should always have a strategy for such situations. They should set up mirrors of the code proactively. Backing up metadata is significantly harder (especially if platforms don’t provide import/export tools, which most of the big ones do not). Some people use the project import features in tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitea.io/&quot;&gt;Gitea&lt;/a&gt;, but as those are one-off features, one would have to repeat the process every now and then. For the issues, there is an experimental tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug&quot;&gt;git-bug&lt;/a&gt;, which allows offline backups and migrations, and comes with bridges to import and export to a variety of tools (and is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug#help-needed&quot;&gt;looking for contributors&lt;/a&gt; to add new bridges and extend the functionality).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like the free software community should prepare themselves better in the future. We should develop better tools to back up our metadata, also allowing us to move between platforms more easily. If GitHub wants to remain the most popular hosting platform, they should consider adding such functionality out of the box (ideally in a standardized format). Offering such functionality doesn’t mean that projects would just leave for other platforms automatically. It would rather show that GitHub is really committed to the idea of open-source software, whose development can take place everywhere. After all, we are the ones who helped GitHub become the number one platform for software development in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one thing that has been and is always going to be counterproductive, especially in such situations: blind actionism. Many people flooded the Internet (read: forums, Reddit, bug trackers of projects), inciting panic and suggesting to move to some other “free” hosted platform. This is clearly not a solution. Any hosting platform will sooner or later have to comply with such a request. It can become very expensive if you end up in court. The true solution, as we have seen in this situation, is to stay calm, analyze the situation, assess the threat to your own project and remove code and text that could be abused to justify such a request (e.g., if you are developing a similar project and also use such songs in a unit test, you can change your test to content under free licenses). Moving to another platform does not solve the root issue, and it risks dividing your community and leaving people behind. Many third-party client projects reviewed their tests, screenshots and other media, and replaced them with safer material. That way, an adversary like the RIAA has a lot less attack surface to justify their claims with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally already have had some measures in place, but also started looking into how I can further improve the backup systems of the projects I am involved in. And I encourage every fellow maintainer to do the same. I also helped a few projects by analyzing the websites and the code and suggesting changes to reduce the attack surface. And I discouraged everyone who suggested any kind actionism to remain calm, because, as expected, the claims were proven wrong, so that there was nothing to be afraid of any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;see-also&quot;&gt;See also&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 13:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ericdanielski</dc:creator>
<og:title>Update: youtube-dl reinstantiated thanks to EFF</og:title>
<og:description>In October, the popular and famous archivist tool youtube-dl was taken down by GitHub due to a DMCA request by the Recording Industry Association of America. I posted a detailed analysis explaining the relation between international, US, EU and German law, and showing why this request was very different from what most people know as the “classic” DMCA takedown request. I felt this was necessary since there were a lot of rumor and wrong claims out on the Internet (not just in forums or on the (anti)social media, but also on media offerings), which did not help the discussion at all. The repository is back now, thanks to the EFF and its team. They filed a counter-notice on behalf of the youtube-dl maintainers, which allowed GitHub to reinstantiate the repository.</og:description>
<og:url>https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Linux Running on Apple M1</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/cmwdotme/status/1351838924621099008</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/cmwdotme/status/1351838924621099008</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cmwdotme/status/1351838924621099008&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/cmwdotme/status/1351838924621099008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25845201&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25845201&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 315&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 211&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ig0r0</dc:creator>
<og:title>Update: youtube-dl reinstantiated thanks to EFF</og:title>
<og:description>In October, the popular and famous archivist tool youtube-dl was taken down by GitHub due to a DMCA request by the Recording Industry Association of America. I posted a detailed analysis explaining the relation between international, US, EU and German law, and showing why this request was very different from what most people know as the “classic” DMCA takedown request. I felt this was necessary since there were a lot of rumor and wrong claims out on the Internet (not just in forums or on the (anti)social media, but also on media offerings), which did not help the discussion at all. The repository is back now, thanks to the EFF and its team. They filed a counter-notice on behalf of the youtube-dl maintainers, which allowed GitHub to reinstantiate the repository.</og:description>
<og:url>https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel outsources Core i3 to TSMC&amp;#039;s 5nm process</title>
<link>https://www.eenewseurope.com/news/intel-TSMC-5nm</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eenewseurope.com/news/intel-TSMC-5nm</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Market analyst Trendforce reports that foundry TSMC is to start making Intel's Core i3 process later in the year on a 5nm process. This follows Intel's well documented problems with its leading edge process technology at 10nm and 7nm. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Core i3 move to a 5nm process is set to be followed by mid-range and high-end CPUs being produced for Intel by TSMC on a 3nm process in 2H22. TrendForce did not give a source for the information, simply referencing &quot;investigations.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intel has long outsourced production significant amounts of its non-CPU chips to TSMC and UMC – about 15 to 20 percent of its output, according to TrendForce. This is partly because it has often acquired fabless startups that had brought products to market using foundry. It was usually not worthwhile to re-engineer such products to Intel processes. It is also because Intel has wanted to focus on leading-edge specialist processes, although with less success in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That 15 to 20 percent outsource was likely worth $10.5 billion to $14 billion in 2020, given Intel's annual revenue of $70bn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a result, the world's leading processors have been produced for Apple, Hi-Silicon and Samsung on foundry manufacturing processes at 7nm and 5nm. It also means that Advanced Micro Devices, Intel's rival in the PC processor market, has been able to gain a superior position due to access to TSMC's 7nm manufacturing process. Intel's in ability to keep pace with leading foundries is also likely to have figured in Apple's decision to develop its own PC processors for the MacBook and Mac Mini, now equipped with M1 processors manufactured for Apple by TSMC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 5nm outsourcing move will allow Intel to compete and also maintain some existence as a major IDM making higher margin chips and maintaining in-house production. It will also&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>djoldman</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Intel outsources Core i3 to TSMC's 5nm process</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.eenewseurope.com/news/intel-TSMC-5nm</og:url>
<og:description>TSMC is to start making Intel's Core i3 on its 5nm process in 2H21 says TrendForce.</og:description>
<og:image>https://eenews.cdnartwhere.eu/sites/default/files/styles/facebook/public/sites/default/files/images/inteldefinition630.jpg?itok=rP0IVJbs</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eenewseurope.com/news/intel-TSMC-5nm</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>