<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Amazon, Berkshire, JPMorgan to Create Healthcare Company</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-30/amazon-berkshire-jpmorgan-to-create-healthcare-company-jd1lraa9</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-30/amazon-berkshire-jpmorgan-to-create-healthcare-company-jd1lraa9</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-30/amazon-berkshire-jpmorgan-to-create-healthcare-company-jd1lraa9&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-30/amazon-berkshire-jpmorgan-to-create-healthcare-company-jd1lraa9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16264662&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16264662&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 344&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 149&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 12:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-30/amazon-berkshire-jpmorgan-to-create-healthcare-company-jd1lraa9</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>UK mass digital surveillance regime ruled unlawful</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2018/jan/30/uk-mass-digital-surveillance-regime-ruled-unlawful-appeal-ruling-snoopers-charter</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2018/jan/30/uk-mass-digital-surveillance-regime-ruled-unlawful-appeal-ruling-snoopers-charter</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;content__head content__head--article tonal__head tonal__head--tone-news&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__labels content__labels--not-immersive&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__section-label&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;content__section-label__link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;article section&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk/uksecurity&quot;&gt;UK security and counter-terrorism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__headline-standfirst-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;tonal__standfirst u-cf&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__standfirst&quot; data-link-name=&quot;standfirst&quot; data-component=&quot;standfirst&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judges say snooper’s charter lacks adequate safeguards around accessing personal data&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;maxed responsive-img&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;A man on his mobile phone walks past a CCTV sign&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/b7b056ff959f9f266e06eabde0df85df0e06a7d2/246_151_3714_2228/master/3714.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=e57aa35b6e4a3db04dbb79e305291d24&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;show-caption&quot; class=&quot;mobile-only u-h reveal-caption__checkbox&quot;/&gt; The court said the law allowed police to authorise their own access to personal phone and web records without adequate oversight. Photograph: Felix Clay for the Guardian&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;Appeal court judges have ruled the government’s mass digital surveillance regime unlawful in a case brought by the Labour deputy leader, Tom Watson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liberty, the human rights campaign group which represented Watson in the case, said the ruling meant significant parts of theInvestigatory Powers Act 2016 – known as the snooper’s charter – are effectively unlawful and must be urgently changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government defended its use of communications data to fight serious and organised crime and said that the judgment related to out of date legislation. Minister Ben Wallace said that it would not affect the way law enforcement would tackle crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court of appeal ruling on Tuesday said the powers in the Data Retention and Investigatory Powers Act 2014, which paved the way for the snooper’s charter legislation, did not restrict the accessing of confidential personal phone and web browsing records to investigations of serious crime, and allowed police and other public bodies to authorise their own access without adequate oversight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three judges said Dripa was “inconsistent with EU law” because of this lack of safeguards, including the absence of “prior review by a court or independent administrative authority”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responding to the ruling, Watson said: “This legislation was flawed from the start. It was rushed through parliament just before recess without proper parliamentary scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The government must now bring forward changes to the Investigatory Powers Act to ensure that hundreds of thousands of people, many of whom are innocent victims or witnesses to crime, are protected by a system of independent approval for access to communications data. I’m proud to have played my part in safeguarding citizens’ fundamental rights.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martha Spurrier, the director of Liberty, said: “Yet again a UK court has ruled the government’s extreme mass surveillance regime unlawful. This judgement tells ministers in crystal clear terms that they are breaching the public’s human rights.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said no politician was above the law. “When will the government stop bartering with judges and start drawing up a surveillance law that upholds our democratic freedoms?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Home Office &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/nov/30/police-to-lose-phone-and-web-data-search-authorisation-powers&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;announced a series of safeguards&lt;/a&gt; in November in anticipation of the ruling. They include removing the power of self-authorisation for senior police officers and requiring approval for requests for confidential communications data to be granted by the new investigatory powers commissioner. Watson and other campaigners said the safeguards were “half-baked” and did not go far enough.&lt;br tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The judges, headed by Sir Geoffrey Vos, declined to rule on the Home Office claim that the more rigorous “Watson safeguards” were not necessary for the use of bulk communications data for wider national security purposes.&lt;br tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;/&gt;
The judges said the appeal court did not need to rule on this point because it had already been referred to the European court of justice in a case which is due to be heard in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watson launched his legal challenge in 2014 in partnership with David Davis, who withdrew when he entered the government as Brexit secretary in 2016. The European court of justice &lt;a draggable=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/law/2016/dec/21/eus-highest-court-delivers-blow-to-uk-snoopers-charter&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;ruled in December 2016&lt;/a&gt; that the “general and indiscriminate retention” of confidential personal communications data was unlawful without safeguards, including independent judicial authorisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security minister Ben Wallace responded to the ruling saying: “Communications data is used in the vast majority of serious and organised crime prosecutions and has been used in every major security service counter-terrorism investigation over the last decade. It is often the only way to identify paedophiles involved in online child abuse as it can be used to find where and when these horrendous crimes have taken place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said the judgment related to legislation which was no longer in force and did not change the way in which law enforcement agencies could detect and disrupt crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We had already announced that we would be amending the Investigatory Powers Act to address the two areas in which the court of appeal has found against the previous data retention regime. We welcome the fact that the court of appeal ruling does not undermine the regime and we will continue to defend these vital powers, which Parliament agreed were necessary in 2016, in ongoing litigation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 11:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>robin_reala</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2018/jan/30/uk-mass-digital-surveillance-regime-ruled-unlawful-appeal-ruling-snoopers-charter</og:url>
<og:description>Judges say snooper’s charter lacks adequate safeguards around accessing personal data</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/b7b056ff959f9f266e06eabde0df85df0e06a7d2/246_151_3714_2228/master/3714.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8xOC9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=4c7f93e0a828199f7f15fd05b6a5c946</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>UK mass digital surveillance regime ruled unlawful</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2018/jan/30/uk-mass-digital-surveillance-regime-ruled-unlawful-appeal-ruling-snoopers-charter</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>EFF&amp;#039;s Fight to End Warrantless Device Searches at the Border</title>
<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/01/round-effs-advocacy-against-border-device-searches</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/01/round-effs-advocacy-against-border-device-searches</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;EFF has been working on multiple fronts to end a widespread violation of digital liberty—warrantless searches of travelers’ electronic devices at the border. Government policies allow border agents to search and confiscate our cell phones, tablets, and laptops at airports and border crossings for no reason, without explanation or any suspicion of wrongdoing. It’s as if our First and Fourth Amendment rights don’t exist at the border. This is wrong, which is why we’re working to challenge and end these unconstitutional practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EFF and the ACLU &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/press/releases/eff-and-aclu-ask-court-allow-legal-challenge-proceed-against-warrantless-searches&quot;&gt;filed a brief today&lt;/a&gt; in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/cases/alasaad-v-duke&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alasaad v. Nielsen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; lawsuit to oppose the government’s attempt to dismiss our case. Our lawsuit, filed in September 2017 on behalf of 11 Americans whose devices were searched, takes direct aim at the illegal policies enforced by the U.S. Department of Homeland Security and its component agencies, U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE). In our brief we explain that warrantless searches of electronic devices at the border violate the First and Fourth Amendments, and that our 11 clients have every right to bring this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the latest action we’ve taken in the fight for digital rights at the border. EFF is pushing back against the government’s invasive practices on three distinct fronts: litigation, legislation, and public education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Rampant Problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years there has been a dramatic increase in the number of searches of cell phones and other electronic devices conducted by border agents. CBP reported that in fiscal year 2012 the number of border device searches was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/qfr-kevin-mcaleenan-senate-finance-committee&quot;&gt;5,085&lt;/a&gt;. In fiscal year 2017, the number had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/national-media-release/cbp-releases-updated-border-search-electronic-device-directive-and&quot;&gt;increased to 30,200&lt;/a&gt;—a six-fold increase in just five years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DHS claims the authority to ransack travelers’ cell phones and other devices and the massive troves of highly personal information they contain. ICE agents can do so for any reason or no reason. Under a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/01/new-cbp-border-device-search-policy-still-permits-unconstitutional-searches&quot;&gt;new policy issued earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;, CBP agents can do so without a warrant or probable cause, and usually can do so without even reasonable suspicion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, agents can and do confiscate devices for lengthy periods of time and subject them to extensive examination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These practices are unconstitutional invasions of our privacy and free speech. Our electronic devices contain our emails, text messages, photos and browsing history. They document our travel patterns, shopping habits, and reading preferences. They expose our love lives, health conditions, and religious and political beliefs. They reveal whom we know and associate with. Warrantless device searches at the border violate travelers’ rights to privacy under the Fourth Amendment, and freedoms of speech, press, private association, and anonymity under the First Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These practices &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/13/technology/aclu-border-patrol-lawsuit.html&quot;&gt;have existed&lt;/a&gt; at least since the George W. Bush administration and continued through the Obama administration. But given the recent dramatic uptick in the number of border device searches since President Trump took office, a former DHS chief privacy officer, Mary Ellen Callahan, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/american-citizens-u-s-border-agents-can-search-your-cellphone-n732746&quot;&gt;concluded&lt;/a&gt; that the increase was “clearly a conscious strategy,” and not “happenstance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the U.S. border is not a Constitution-free zone. The Fourth Amendment requires the government to obtain a probable cause warrant before conducting a border search of a traveler’s electronic device. This follows from the U.S. Supreme Court case &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/riley-wurie-supreme-court-opinions&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riley v. California&lt;/em&gt; (2014)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. The court held that police need a warrant to search the cell phones of people they arrest.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The warrant process is critical because it provides a check on government power and, specifically, a restraint on arbitrary invasions of privacy. In seeking a warrant, a government agent must provide sworn testimony before a neutral arbiter—a judge—asserting why the government believes there’s some likelihood (“probable cause”) that the cell phone or other thing to be searched contains evidence of criminality. If the judge is convinced, she will issue the search warrant, allowing the government to access your private information even if you don’t consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, there are no such constraints on CBP and ICE agents—but we’re fighting in court and in Congress to change this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Litigation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 13, 2017, EFF along with ACLU filed our lawsuit, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/press/releases/eff-aclu-media-conference-call-today-announce-lawsuit-over-warrantless-phone-and&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alasaad v. Nielsen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, against the federal government on behalf of ten U.S. citizens and one lawful permanent resident whose smartphones and other devices were searched without a warrant at the U.S. border. The plaintiffs include a military veteran, journalists, students, an artist, a NASA engineer, and a business owner. Several are Muslims or people of color. All were reentering the country after business or personal travel when border agents searched their devices. None were subsequently accused of any wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the &lt;em&gt;Alasaad&lt;/em&gt; plaintiffs suffered a substantial privacy invasion. Some plaintiffs were detained for several hours while agents searched their devices, while others had their devices confiscated and were not told when their belongings would be returned. One plaintiff was even placed in a chokehold after he refused to hand over his phone. You can read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/pages/alasaad-vs-duke-bios&quot;&gt;detailed stories&lt;/a&gt; of all the &lt;em&gt;Alasaad&lt;/em&gt; plaintiffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;Alasaad&lt;/em&gt; lawsuit, we are asking the U.S. District Court for Massachusetts to find that the policies of CBP and ICE violate the Fourth Amendment. We also allege that the search policies violate the First Amendment. We are asking the court to enjoin the federal government from searching electronic devices at the border without first obtaining a warrant supported by probable cause, and from confiscating devices for lengthy periods without probable cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past year, EFF also has filed three &lt;em&gt;amicus&lt;/em&gt; briefs in U.S. Courts of Appeals (in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/us-v-kolsuz-eff-amicus-brief&quot;&gt;Fourth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/us-v-molina-isidoro-eff-brief&quot;&gt;Fifth&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2018/01/19/17_eff_amicus_brief_usa_v_cano_1.19.18.pdf&quot;&gt;Ninth&lt;/a&gt; Circuits). In those briefs, we argued that border agents need a probable cause warrant to search electronic devices. There are extremely strong and unprecedented privacy interests in the highly sensitive information stored and accessible on electronic devices, and the narrow purposes of the border search exception—immigration and customs enforcement—are not served by warrantless searches of electronic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legislation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EFF is urging the U.S. Congress to pass the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wyden.senate.gov/download/?id=9CDE0A37-24DD-4D05-B199-C7E160CAA088&amp;amp;download=1&quot;&gt;Protecting Data at the Border Act&lt;/a&gt;. The Act would require border agents to obtain a probable cause warrant before searching the electronic devices of U.S. citizens and legal permanent residents at the border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate bill (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/senate-bill/823?q=%7B%22search%22%3A%5B%22protecting+data+at+the+border+act%22%5D%7D&amp;amp;r=4&quot;&gt;S. 823&lt;/a&gt;) is sponsored by Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR) and Sen. Rand Paul (R-KY). &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamsmith.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/smith-and-polis-introduce-legislation-to-protect-data-privacy-civil&quot;&gt;Rep. Polis (D-CO), Rep. Smith (D-WA), and Rep. Farenthold (R-TX)&lt;/a&gt; are taking the lead on the House bill (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/1899?q=%7B%22search%22%3A%5B%22protecting+data+at+the+border+act%22%5D%7D&amp;amp;r=5&quot;&gt;H.R. 1899&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to creating a warrant requirement, the Act would prohibit the government from delaying or denying entry or exit to a U.S. person based on that person’s refusal to hand over a device passcode, online account login credential, or social media handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about this critical bill in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/04/border-search-bill-would-rein-cbp&quot;&gt;call to action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; and our &lt;a href=&quot;http://thehill.com/blogs/congress-blog/homeland-security/352898-pass-the-protecting-data-at-the-border-act&quot;&gt;op-ed in &lt;em&gt;The Hill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://act.eff.org/action/demand-border-agents-get-a-warrant-before-digital-searches-f3b58af9-e71d-4b7c-b5ae-52d89c70b912&quot;&gt;contact your representatives in Congress&lt;/a&gt; and urge them to co-sponsor the Protecting Data at the Border Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, EFF published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/wp/digital-privacy-us-border-2017&quot;&gt;travel guide&lt;/a&gt; that helps travelers understand their individual risks when crossing the U.S. border (which includes U.S. airports if flying from overseas), provides an overview of the law around border searches, and offers technical guidance for securing digital data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our travel guide recognizes that one size does not fit all, and it helps travelers make informed choices regarding their specific situation and risk tolerance. The guide is a useful resource for all travelers who want to keep their digital data safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download our full report &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2017/03/10/digital-privacy-border-2017-guide3.10.17.pdf&quot;&gt;as a PDF&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, you can print &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/eff-border-search-pocket-guide&quot;&gt;EFF’s pocket guide&lt;/a&gt; to protecting digital privacy at the border.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 23:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DiabloD3</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>EFF's Fight to End Warrantless Device Searches at the Border: A Roundup of Our Advocacy</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/01/round-effs-advocacy-against-border-device-searches</og:url>
<og:description>EFF has been working on multiple fronts to end a widespread violation of digital liberty—warrantless searches of travelers’ electronic devices at the border. Government policies allow border agents to search and confiscate our cell phones, tablets, and laptops at airports and border crossings for...</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.eff.org/files/issues/border-search-1.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/01/round-effs-advocacy-against-border-device-searches</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ten days in Shenzhen</title>
<link>http://www.karimyaghmour.com/blog/2018/01/ten-days-in-shenzhen.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.karimyaghmour.com/blog/2018/01/ten-days-in-shenzhen.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Shenzhen is increasingly known within tech circles as the must-go location for anyone working on hardware. The one hour &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SGJ5cZnoodY&quot;&gt;Wired documentary&lt;/a&gt; about Shenzhen, entitled “Shenzhen: The Silicon Valley of Hardware”, has been view more than 1.5M times on YouTube at the time of this writing. Countless articles, blog posts, videos, etc. have been dedicated to what takes place there. There's now even at least one book, Bunnie's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crowdsupply.com/sutajio-kosagi/the-essential-guide-to-electronics-in-shenzhen&quot;&gt;“The Essential Guide to Electronics in Shenzhen”&lt;/a&gt;, whose sole purpose is to help electronics enthusiasts and professionals navigate it effectively; think of it as a tourist guide for geeks in the geekiest city of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't remember for how long I've known about Shenzhen, but it must be a while. Because when I heard that a couple of other conferences goers at Linaro Connect Hong Kong 2013 were going to do a day-trip there guided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/Charbax&quot;&gt;Charbax&lt;/a&gt; and a Mandarin-speaking Hong Kong local, I immediately jumped on the opportunity. We were told ahead of time that the only criteria was that we had to have a non-US passport as the 5-day temporary entry visa could not be obtained by US citizens at the border – go figure. We took the train to Luohu, crossed over and then took some cabs to Huaqiangbei, where the electronics markets are found, and spent the day there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That one-day experience was exhilarating. Whatever they say about kids walking into a candy store applied to myself and the group of people I was with. Everywhere we went and looked there were kiosks upon kiosks of everything we could imagine, from finished products to parts, components, accessories, etc. Kind of like a combination of BestBuy and Fry's spanning several city blocks. Some of us picked up some interesting items along the way. Most of us were amused by how some vendors were creating phones that were either clearly knock-offs or branded with names so close to known western brands as to be confusing. I'll always remember seeing people putting the “known brand” stickers on batteries. By far the find that we found most entertaining was an iPhone lookalike that was built on Android. While I didn't buy one myself, I was more than happy to post a video of it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/0/+KarimYaghmour/posts/Gkm1DEBZpRk&quot;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For myself, having already been spending a lot of time on Android since a few years before, my visit to Huaqiangbei brought into focus how unstoppable this OS truly was. The number of inexpensive devices shipping with it was astounding. I was fascinated, for example, to find a $45 Android tablet (back then that was fairly impressive). When I declared to customs upon my return that I had $300 worth of tablets (plural), the agent first said: “each?” I said “No, for all of them.” Fearing she might think I'm playing her for dumb, I proceeded to show her the receipts and explain that the amounts were in Renminbi. To which she replied, “yeah, I know RMBs, I used to work in Hong Kong.” Still, it was clear she was as floored as I was by the price. Something about Shenzhen made it possible to produce advanced electronics at unbeatable prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't claim that my very short initiation to Shenzhen gave me enough to truly appreciate what was going on there, but it did leave a very strong impression. Something was happening there that I hadn't seen anywhere else in my travels, despite clocking over 100K miles some years. Recently, as I was ramping up work on a hardware side project of mine, it became pretty clear that I would eventually need to start spending time in Shenzhen. I wasn't entirely sure how I'd navigate my way around and find what I'm looking for, especially since I know zero Mandarin, but I was pretty determined to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My purpose here, therefore, is to share my experiences in planning and undertaking a first solo trip to Shenzhen and the lessons I've learned along the way. To an extent the purpose is selfish. I've been meaning to take the time to sit down and put my thoughts “on paper”. Still, I think some of the things I've discovered along the way may be useful to others who are thinking of making their first trip or others possibly looking to add some new tricks to their existing Shenzhen travel recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.karimyaghmour.com/.a/6a0133f2f5dd98970b01bb09edb030970d-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hqb-180129&quot; class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a0133f2f5dd98970b01bb09edb030970d img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;http://www.karimyaghmour.com/.a/6a0133f2f5dd98970b01bb09edb030970d-500wi&quot; title=&quot;Hqb-180129&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I'm most widely known for my books on embedded Linux and embedded Android, and for some of my open-source contributions such as the Linux Trace Toolkit – i.e. mostly software-related work –, my formative academic years contained a substantial amount of hardware and electronics; roughly more than half the curriculum in my computer engineering program in fact. So while I've spent most of my professional years up to now working on the lower-levels of some of the more prominent open source stacks out there, I've always longed for getting back into hardware in some way shape or form. But doing that had always seemed elusive. Despite a number of tries over the years, it remained a bridge too far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing anything &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;at scale&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; starting individually that involved hardware without being part of a project and/or company already active in that field or without significant financing did not seem feasible. I just unearthed a book I bought in the late '90s, for example, that explained how to do printed circuit boards (PCBs) using press-on tape, rub-on patterns, marker pens and etching acid. That, bread-boards, and wire-wrapping were probably the most-widely used techniques of the day. None of which gave you anything you could scale to provide/share/sell to others. Today, you can just upload a Gerber file to one of the online PCB providers and get yourself a multi-layer board within days, be it in the handful of units or enough for a pilot run. Back 15-20 years ago, evaluation boards and dev boards for even mid-range processors were typically in the low-end thousands of dollars. Today every other silicon vendor is falling over the next to get you sub-$100 dev boards. Back not too long ago the best-looking mechanical housings you could get your hands on for custom designs were prefabbed metal or plastic boxes that you could mill or carve to fit your controls and I/O. Anything custom that looked even remotely like a finished product was inaccessible. Today, you can use a cheap 3D printer or even a desktop CNC to create yourself housings of any shape you want using a variety of materials. That still won't get you to mass-produced injection-molded housings, but the iteration loop has shortened quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that last point regarding iteration loops is likely the biggest difference today from a while back. Advances in technology, such as cheap 3D printers and relatively affordable CNC printers, the advent of online on-demand manufacturing services, such as PCB manufacturing, high-end 3D printing, and even online contract manufacturing (CM), the proliferation of open-source stacks and software, such as free embedded OSes and even some free hardware development tools (nascent as those may be), the advent of cheap development boards, such as the Arduino, RaspberryPi and BeagleBone, the “maker” movement, with a critical mass of self-sustaining hardware-related projects and known-how being shared online, at conferences, in magazines and elsewhere, and crowdfunding sites, such as Kickstarter, Indigogo and CrowdSupply, have all contributed to significantly reducing the barrier to entry for a single individual or a small team to come pretty close at creating a final product using almost software-like rapid iteration loops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gradually, it seemed the stage was set to allow me to take some of my wacky ideas and bring them to fruition on my own dime and schedule. Still, there remained quite a gap between on one hand the desire to do my own hardware projects and the knowledge that the means &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;seemed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; available, and, on the other hand, actually pulling it off. Starting a few years ago, I therefore started devoting an increasing amount of serious time to hardware. One of the first things I did was shop around for a 3D printer. I kept looking at Make: magazine's annual 3D printer shootout, but something always felt amiss. Plastic was just not convincing enough for me and I couldn't get myself to ever buy one of those. I eventually settled on a desktop CNC machine. It was a bit above my pain threshold in terms of pricing, but it did what I want: create mechanical prototypes using a variety of real materials, not just plastic. Granted it's got limitations, as CNC machines can range into the hundreds of thousands of dollars, but it's good enough for creating sufficiently-realistic prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I did was read up on a variety of topics, from industrial design, to running hardware startups and including more technical topics like hardware design, and electro-magnetic interference. It rapidly became clear that despite the barrier to entry for prototyping having been reduced, the path to creating market-grade products, not just &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/+JonMasters/posts/9MXMBfh7CKN&quot;&gt;cute embedded nonsense hacks&lt;/a&gt; (btw, Jon's got a point), remains fraught with danger. It's not my goal to elaborate on that here, though I might in a subsequent post, but there is an enormous difference between cooking up a project using a standard dev board like an Arduino and self-printing a case for it, and actually charting a path to creating a finished product that can be mass-produced, marketed and supported. In software terms, the difference between using an Arduino and shipping a real product can probably be compared to creating a custom grep-based script for searching versus building a Google-like search engine. Yes, they both “search” documents, and yet they're vastly different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously one does not simply get into a new field without a specific project in mind. If nothing else, there's no better way of building organic knowledge on a topic than to have some sort of substrate to deposit the successive strata of learnings into useful experience. Within the same time-frame that I started investing more time into hardware, I had an idea that was increasingly nagging me. So I decided to use that idea as the seed of my hardware endeavor. While I'm not ready to publicly share that work just yet and, ultimately, I look forward to announcing at least prototypes, I have to say that deciding on such a project in guiding my research and learning has been very helpful. It's forced me to explore topics that hadn't originally been on my map and make some unexpected discoveries. It also forced me to continuously ask myself whether whatever detail or feature I was thinking of could be first prototyped, then built into a pilot and ultimately mass-produced. Many things you can build in a lab would simply never survive in a real product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike software where exploring the realm of possibilities and trying each one out is almost always only a click away, exploring the world of what's possible in hardware can only be done for so long in a seated position. Yes, you can find a lot of blogs with pictures and videos on Youtube on any given hardware topic. You can even take the time to explore the entire online catalogue of shops like Sparkun and Adafruit – which I did btw. But that's not enough. There comes a point where you need to touch and try. In the software world, if I want to try a project, I just grab it from github, build it and go from there. It doesn't work? No issues, go back to github, wash, rinse, repeat. For hardware, you actually have to look for parts in catalogues, order them, wait for them to arrive, try them and then decide whether you need to repeat that loop again because what you got doesn't do what you thought it did. The iteration loop is orders of magnitudes slower and that's especially painful when you're in a learning process because it means you're not learning as quickly. Plus, it's not free. You actually have to buy those parts with real money and possibly pay for shipping because it isn't sold by Amazon or the likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's when you realize that having people around you who already have significant experience in hardware is priceless. Their map of what's possible and what's not and how to implement a specific part of a design in hardware is something no amount of self-exploration can replace. For me, being able to reach out to my friend and hardware mentor David Anders (also known as prplague) has been and continues to be invaluable. Dave was often able to point out pitfalls and steer me in the right direction when I was stuck. He was also helpful in administering the occasional slap in the back of the head when I was biting off more than I could chew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By September of last year it was evident to me that a stop by Shenzhen was warranted, for a number of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some of the parts I was looking for were proving hard to find or evaluate online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt that I could benefit from expanding my hardware map beyond simply browsing online catalogues and guides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also felt that it was worth seeing what was the “state of the art” in terms or products and gizmos in Huaqiangbei (HQB hereon forward).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establishing a network of contacts in Shenzhen and understanding the hardware ecosystem there seemed vital for any hardware project meant to scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Despite having helped thousands of engineers develop and deliver embedded products based on Linux and Android, I hadn't ever visited a factory that makes PCBs or PCB assembly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, learning how to integrate Shenzhen's hardware capabilities into my planning seemed essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some might be comfortable just showing up with their backpack and exploring a city, I'm personally a bit more OCD'ed and wanted to make sure I was maximizing what I got out of the trip. So, like learning hardware itself, I spent some time researching various aspects of the trip and reaching out to contacts to help plan things. One of the very first things I did was get my hands on Bunnie Huang's “The Essential Guide to Electronics in Shenzhen” (TEGES from here on forward) off of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adafruit.com/product/3189&quot;&gt;Adafruit's site&lt;/a&gt;. I had already read his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adafruit.com/product/3465&quot;&gt;“Hardware Hacker”&lt;/a&gt; title when it came out and had been obliquely following his work ever since quite some time ago I read his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xenatera.com/bunnie/proj/anatak/xboxmod.html&quot;&gt;xbox hacking post&lt;/a&gt; where he explained spending a Friday night with his then girlfriend decapsulating xbox chips. If an adept of such romantic activities as nocturnal chip decapsulation had advice to share on Shenzhen then it was certainly worth taking the time to read. And I haven't been disappointed. Though I have suggestions to add to it, which I'll mention along the way below, I strongly recommend you get your hands on TEGES if you're planning a visit. As a matter of fact, I saw other foreigners carrying it around in HQB while there myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, there were several aspects that I wanted to nail down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Requirements for entering and traveling to China – the last time I was there was on a 5-day, single-entry visa and this time I was planning on staying an initial 10 days with possible returns in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advice on best routes and travel means to and around Shenzhen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommended tech gear setup for traveling into China – for the security-minded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendations for network connectivity, SIM cards, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial planning of day-trips to HQB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the first people I reached out to was Charbax, with whom I had done my first visit to Shenzhen a few years back, given his extensive travels there. Charbax very generously answered many of my basic questions and was able to point out a few things I hadn't thought of as well. Another person I reached out to was Benjamin Dolgin-Gardner, CEO of Shenzhen-based &lt;a href=&quot;http://hatchmfg.com/&quot;&gt;Hatch Manufacturing&lt;/a&gt;. Charbax had introduced me to Ben a few years earlier given that our day-jobs involve helping companies make custom Android devices, with Ben being more focused on the hardware side while I'm more focused on the software side. Ben helped me on a number of different fronts including making introductions to and arranging meetings with key local vendors and hardware startup incubators such as Shenzhen-based Hax. I also reached out to contacts at Seeed Studios for scheduling a meeting while I was there. Overall, I had a handful of meetings scheduled ahead of time prior to departing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By following the process published by the Chinese government I was able to secure a multiple-entry business visa at the local consulate. Just look for the visas available and requirements published by the Chinese embassy in your country and go from there. I also booked plane travel and hotel accommodation. There's nothing specific to recommend about travel and lodging other than the usual to do your research. Given that next time I'd probably stay longer than 10 days I'd probably try an AirBnB instead of a hotel. Generally, though, I try to go for the option and location that minimizes all non-productive/non-business-related activities (commuting, eating, etc.) For air travel there are two choices. Either land in Hong Kong and transfer to Shenzhen or land directly in Shenzhen. Most people, including TEGES, recommend the former given the number of airlines traveling to and from Hong Kong and the fact that Shenzhen's airport is a good distance from HQB. Though I can't personally comment on Shenzhen's airport because I've never been there, several people, including some of my contacts in Shenzhen and myself, feel that HKG is one of the better airports around the world. I wasn't unhappy in choosing it as my gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing that absorbed more time than I would've liked preparing for was the tech gear and connectivity. I had been reading and hearing all sorts of stories circulating around tech circles regarding how China has a firewall and the rumors of how it's unsafe to bring electronics into China for fear of them being hacked in some way shape or form. Some of that is also touched upon in TEGES. Personally I take the view that in a multi-polar world, it's only normal that every player is going to defend their home turf in whichever way they deem appropriate, regardless of how other parties, visitors or even some citizens may feel about such activities. We can have political debates about what's “right” and what's “wrong”, and we all benefit from asking questions. Still, at the end of the day, my focus is on respecting the interests of people I work with versus the places I visit. Hence, my concern in approaching this wasn't conspiratorial but rather pragmatic. In other words, starting from the understanding that China has interests which are legitimate with regards to itself and understanding that the base of my work is mostly done in the western hemisphere, what is the proper way for me to work while isolating the latter from the former?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I elected to take the safest route I could chart. I used a burner laptop, a burner phone and a burner email address while on travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regards to the laptop, I bought an inexpensive Chromebook for the purpose. I had been unconvinced of Chromebooks but my friend John Stultz from Linaro had been sporting one for quite a few years and I kept asking him about how he could live just on that for the type of work he did – kernel and Android development and building. He explained his remote work setup and emphasized how the device used signed images from Google to boot along with Google's constant commitment to security. Another recommendation I had seen that also promoted the security aspect of Chromebooks was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://paranoidbeavers.ca/travel-laptop-setup.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; by the Linux Foundation's Konstantin Ryabitsev in which he answers questions he was receiving from people planning to attend LF's then-upcoming Beijing Open Source Summit. Obviously working on a Chromebook requires a connection to Google, which is a problem because it isn't accessible from within China, at least under normal circumstances. I'll cover that shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one big caveat that I found with Chromebooks that I hadn't planned for in advance is that it does automagic updates if you're on Wifi and there's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;no way&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to currently turn that off. Looking around the net, it appears that I wasn't alone to be bitten by that. The apparent short-sightedness of Google engineers in that regard is baffling. I use a hotspot as my main connectivity means when traveling for all my devices. I make sure to turn off updates on any device connected to that hotspot to preserve bandwidth. It's extremely inconvenient that all of a sudden a couple of hundred megabytes were eaten up by an undesired upgrade. One can apparently turn off such automated upgrades on a Chromebook by “rooting” it, but then you loose all the benefits and “comforts” of running an officially-signed image. It sucks either way. Because of that I wonder if next time I wouldn't just travel with a cheap Ubuntu laptop instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a person that does a lot of work under Android's hood I sometimes get asked how much I trust what happens on my phone. My general response, and one that you should take with a grain of salt, has historically been that I'll use my phone for almost anything except banking. The issue for me isn't Android so much as it is the lack of sustained, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;daily updates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; such as the kind I can have on my desktop. All I want is something like a “sudo apt update; sudo apt upgrade” for my Android phone. But I'm the paranoid kind, I used to run a crypto startup for a few years, and I'm the kind of person that will usually go as far as to check the detailed certificate chain of trust of a website before entering any money-related information (credit-cards, bank creds, etc.) Your level of paranoia may be different. So this isn't so much as judgment call on Android's security, which by the way has gotten to be truly awesome and is going to get even better with Project Treble, but rather my own inclination to wear tin-foil hats from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, assuming nation-state-type resources, even the most secure device may not be impenetrable. As TEGES points out: “In an ideal world, you'd have an unlocked phone for use only in China, and a phone you use everywhere else.” Hence my decision to use a burner phone. Unfortunately I had just given my older Nexus 5 to my daughter and was left with only one choice apart from my main Android device – and apart from buying a brand new device just for the trip –, a Blackberry Z30 running BB OS10. I assumed it wouldn't be much of an issue since I'd use it mostly for phone-purposes (calls + text), and its built-in email client is good enough. That turned out to be a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself having to shop for a phone in HQB to be able to install apps from the Google Play store which I couldn't get on the Blackberry device. The phone I bought there, a Xiaomi Note 4X, ended up being no end of trouble itself. First, you need to know that phones sold in China for the local market don't have Google Apps. It'd be useless since Google isn't accessible. So the shop where I bought this from offered to reflash it to put the “international” version, several other shops also offered that on certain models. Sounded good to me. That itself worked out fine. I was asked to return in 45 minutes while they reflashed it. So I went to grab a bite and came back, picked it up and was on my way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after configuring the device with my accounts and everything, however, I noticed it would spontaneously reboot for no reason. Trying to fix that through updates and such only led to burned bandwidth, plain heartburn, and time wasted. I ended up having to endure the device for the rest of the trip with its spontaneous reboots, and concluded after some investigations upon my return that it's a hardware issue. If you're wondering why I didn't return it, first take into account that it had a custom image now and, second, that I had to make a choice between spending time getting emotionally involved in arguing the case for a return with folks whose primary language wasn't English and just living with an annoying device. Given the amount of time I had already wasted with this issue, I decided to cut my losses and keep the broken device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I would not fly out without a properly-functioning Android device as a burner next time. I have zero time to waste trying to fix devices while on-site in Shenzhen. Note that I continued to rely on the BB Z30 for all “critical” communication while the Note 4x was a wifi-only device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I pondered was whether it was safe to travel with my SIM card as-is from my ordinary phone or not. A quick Google seemed to show that there were proof-of-concept hacks of SIM card tampering. So I elected to fly out with my existing SIM card, but I had my phone company transfer my number over to a new SIM card when I returned instead of reusing the old one on my regular Android phone. As I said, you may not share my level of obsession with regards to security. Before leaving, I also took a roaming package with voice/text/data as a “just in case” fallback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I found difficult but really didn't see any way around was that I had to leave all means of access to my regular email accounts out of reach. In short, I created a junk gmail address, copied some of my contacts and alerted key people of where I was going and that I'd be running from a non-regular address. I then configured my main email accounts to forward a copy of inbound email to the junk address. That was a tradeoff. I could've risked getting “sensitive” info that I would've preferred not being forwarded during that 10 day period. But it was a risk that was manageable, whereas the alternative (i.e. compromised credentials giving access to my full email history) was not an acceptable risk. I continued CC'ing or BCC'ing my regular accounts on outbound emails from the burner accounts so that I'd have access to the discussions from the latter when I'd return back home. Mostly this bit worked out fine once it was set up. The burner gmail account turned out to be quite useful for keeping in touch over Hangout with people I closely work with and backing up pictures from the garbage phone I got in HQB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally came the question of accessing regular western-hemisphere services such as Google, etc. while in Shenzhen. After some research, it appeared that using a VPN was probably the easiest way through and I made sure to create myself an account before flying out; with a full understanding that, per TEGES, there's a chance the Chinese government may clamp down on VPNs at whim. The VPN is one precaution that turned out to be useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I landed in Hong Kong I stopped by the foreign exchange counter to get some local currency to pay for the cab to the border crossing . The lady at the counter asked if I wanted a data SIM card as well. I said I wasn't staying in Hong Kong but was rather transferring to Shenzhen. She said that that wasn't a problem as the card worked both in Hong Kong and Shenzhen, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that I wouldn't need a VPN. That turned out to be one of the best purchases I made, with one caveat that I'll explain later. For 108HKD (roughly 15 USD) I got 1.5GB of data for a maximum of 10 days. That should've been sufficient had I not had upgrade issues with the Xiaomi Note 4x and the Chromebook. I was able to recharge it through China Mobile's online site during the week though. The only trouble was that the online deal wasn't as good as the initial price of the card. In retrospect, I should've bought two of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.karimyaghmour.com/.a/6a0133f2f5dd98970b01b8d2d4b074970c-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data-card-180129&quot; class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a0133f2f5dd98970b01b8d2d4b074970c img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;http://www.karimyaghmour.com/.a/6a0133f2f5dd98970b01b8d2d4b074970c-500wi&quot; title=&quot;Data-card-180129&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially when I tried using this SIM card in my hotspot in Shenzhen it didn't work as planned. (In case you're wondering, I had actually entertained also using a burner hotspot but I decided against that as my hotspot has no passive data on it and serves as a gateway for SSL traffic anyway.) For some reason, the signal was either very weak or it just outright dropped in some cases. I figured it might have something to do with the bands supported by the device so I went shopping for a local hotspot in HQB. I tried it in a couple of units from different shops but it didn't work. I was beginning to wonder if I hadn't bought a dud. Then one shop-keeper tried it in one of the Huawei hotspots, configured it using the Chinese interface and it worked like a charm. I was relieved but confused. My hotspot is a Huawei as well and I wasn't sure what was different, except maybe bands. After closer inspection, though, it turned out that the difference in configuration was that my seller had turned on roaming. That was the key. In short, China Mobile in Hong Kong, where I bought the card, appeared as the “CMHK” network whereas the local China Mobile in Shenzhen appeared in Chinese in the list of networks. Had I figured that I needed to enable roaming and switch to the proper network, I would've likely avoided the extra hotspot. Sometimes you can't learn without wasting time and money apparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting there&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landing in Hong Kong, passing passport control, picking up bags and heading for the exit is pretty efficient. Based on TEGES I had decided to cross at the Futian border crossing. I was a bit worried about the schedule as my plane landed at 8PM and TEGES said Futian closed at 10:30PM. That ended up being a non-issue given the efficiency at Hong Kong int'l. As I exited the terminal I followed signs for taxis and was directed to one of the colored taxis – I can't recall the color. The cab ride itself took about 35 minutes and cost 357 HKD (about 45 USD). The time was within what TEGES provides (30-40 min) though the fare was a bit higher than the 310-320 HKD listed, but that's fine. The driver managed in English. We were able to have an ok conversation even though his fluency was limited. Further trips in Hong Kong later in the following week were similar, the drivers could manage English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got to the Futian border crossing, I collected my bags and went up the stairs to take the foot bridge that spans the Sham Chun River into Shenzhen. Per TEGES, this crossing is mostly frequented by locals. So at first I felt a bit uneasy as I wasn't sure I made the right choice to cross where fewer foreigners cross – I was in fact the only foreigner on the premises that I saw during my passage through the crossing. It dawned on me that I might be in a situation where there's a language barrier between me and the customs agent processing my passport. As I got closer to the end of the bridge one of the officers spotted me and immediately waived me to the left. Clearly that was where the foreigner queue was. It ended up in a very short “foreigner” queue. I started waiting but then realized that I forgot to fill out the entry/exit card. So I went to side where they had stand-up tables set up with the forms, filled it up and went back in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally it was my turn to walk up to the passport control booth. I handed my passport and the form to the agent and said hi. She looked at it intently, flipped pages around, and looked some more. She was silent long enough that I started wondering if something was amiss. Then she looked at me and asked in a most impeccable French: “C'est votre premier voyage en Chine?” (It's your first trip to China?) I was like deer in the headlight, completely floored. I live in Québec, Canada and my passport clearly indicates where it was issued. In the realm of expectations, though, it never crossed my mind that a border agent in China at a crossing mainly frequented by locals would speak to me in French. “Non, j'ai déjà traversé de Hong Kong il y a quelques années à Luohu, mais c'était sur un autre passeport” (No, I already crossed over from Hong Kong a few years ago at Luohu, but it was on another passport). I couldn't recall having been this proud of speaking French, essentially my mother tongue, ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an “au revoir”, I continued onto to baggage screening – my bags didn't seem to interest anyone FWIW. Upon exiting customs, I exchanged some money and proceeded to where the taxis are parked. This was a bit more involved than I expected and required crossing the street with my bags and such. Still, it wasn't that complicated. I had been anticipating based on TEGES that cab drivers wouldn't know much English on the Shenzhen side. And that was true. In contrast to Hong Kong, the vast majority of Shenzhen drivers generally lacked any knowledge of even the most basic English. So to get to my hotel I just pulled up the hotel's address from their site in Chinese and showed it to the driver. That recipe, showing addresses in Chinese to drivers, mostly worked during my trip. In one case I brought a card with a tiny address and the driver had a hard time reading it. I was immediately reminded of the advice in TEGES that many drivers have bad eyesight. I eventually made it to where I needed to go, but there's nothing better to remind you of something important than feeling the sting when you forget it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First few days&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a good night's sleep, I was ready to explore HQB. I had deliberately chosen a hotel with an easy access to the metro line that wasn't too far from HQB, and this proved quite useful. I had also spent quite some time studying TEGES' content for tricks and directions in and around HQB. The maps section seemed particularly useful and turned out to be quite so. I was also very happy to have the vast collection of point-to-translate pages for all sorts of things. That turned out to be less useful than I expected, at least for what I was trying to accomplish. I'll explain why later. Finally, I was initially worried about the limited number of plastic sample pages with maps wouldn't suffice for my needs. I ended up not using them at all, and found a different way of organizing my samples and marking locations that I found much more useful. In the first few days I carried TEGES everywhere. I felt much safer having it in my backpack when walking around. Later, though, I ended up taking pictures of the maps section pages on my phone and leaving the hardcopy at the hotel. Another map I had spent quite some time studying was Seeed's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seeedstudio.com/Shenzhen-Map-for-Makers-p-1585.html&quot;&gt;“Shenzhen Map for Makers”&lt;/a&gt;. I actually compared those two maps at length to identify differences and make sure I had maximum coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first day I had two goals. One was to beat jetlag and stay awake all day. That turned out to be not too bad. The other goal was to explore the parts of the map that seemed most likely to have end products targeted at the same segment I was aiming for. The idea was to get a first feel of what's trending in Shenzhen and what were the latest designs in that space. The map didn't disappoint and I was able to find a large number of kiosks selling some of the items I was interested in. Obviously many kiosks also had items that I had seen on Amazon or elsewhere as well. I was mostly focusing on things I hadn't seen before. After a few hours of walking floors upon floors of shops, I was ready to start focusing on other aspects of my research: hard to source and/or evaluate components, tools and expanding my knowledge of what was available in the hardware space. Hint: TEGES' advice about having comfortable shoes and comfortable clothing is completely warranted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding tools was relatively easy. TEGES indicates the building and floor to go to, and you'll find most anything you can think of from rework stations, to pick-and-place machines, and including things like oscilloscopes, stereo microscopes, multimeters, screwdrivers, etc. In the process I saw some tools which I couldn't immediately figure out the purpose for, but later found out their uses on some other visits. Satisfied with a first glance at the tools, I set out to look for one specific component I was having a hard time with. That proved a lot more difficult than anticipated. Actually I should qualify that. It was trivial to find tons of it, just not something that matched exactly what I needed. I used TEGES to identify one part of the market that seemed most likely to have what I was looking for, but again, I could find lots of it, just not what I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A local lady seeing me walking through a floor seemingly lost asked me in English if she could help. I was only too happy to oblige. She said that I'd be far likelier to find what I was looking for in another part of HQB. She proceeded on to pull out a map application on her phone and show me where I should head. She also asked if I had WeChat so that she could continue helping me after I left in case I couldn't find my way. That was one of the first encounters that made me regret not having a properly-working Android phone. I had to admit shamefully that my phone setup wasn't optimal. She told me that I shouldn't hesitate to ask any of the shopkeepers for assistance, they'd be happy to direct me if they knew where I could find what was looking for. That was rather comforting and turned out to be relatively true. I've found that most people are happy to help once you break the ice and they realize that you're genuinely seeking a purchase or aren't afraid to deal with the language barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first few days, however, I must admit that I was a bit wary of approaching some of the kiosks and make enquiries regarding the merchandise. The language barrier was certainly a big part of that. Another concern was my lack of understanding as to the nature of the businesses they run. Some clearly had more things on display than they could possibly stock in those tiny two-person kiosks. Yet another thing is that you walk around and there are tons of kiosks with all sort of components, some which I'm more familiar than others. Those that were most unfamiliar were sometimes the most intriguing. And yet, I just didn't see myself walking up to some of those shopkeepers and “wasting their time” with newbie questions in a foreign language. I couldn't see how TEGES would be helping me in that regard at all, and I don't think that that was ever its purpose. I eventually figured out a way to solve this, but at first I found myself just walking around kiosks not fully able to get myself to get anything done. Plus, initially, until I solved my hotspot problem, my connectivity was very bad, so I was having a hard time looking up more information. In short, the first few days were a bit frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reps at one of the stores where I stopped couldn't explain something using her basic English so she just pulled out a translation app and spoke into her phone in Mandarin and had it repeat the content in English. I found myself a bit ridiculous not having thought of using something like that. Eventually, once I got a network connection, I started resorting to using Google Translate. I would type what I wanted in English, get it translated and show the translation to the person I was interacting with. This was ok for basic interactions, but it had its limitations. Still, I was able to make good progress with that. It felt far more intuitive than having to search through TEGES while the person waited on me. Again, they're running a business and I didn't want to feel like the annoying tourist. For the technical translation, it was often just easier to point at items or parts of items than trying to find the proper language in TEGES then use Translate or something else to bridge the gap. I got even better later as I'll explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 2nd day I met up with Ben and we went to Maker Faire Shenzhen, which happened to be running while I was there. We toured a bit and saw the usual maker stuff. It was interesting to see that the maker ecosystem there was similar to maker ecosystems elsewhere. It did however feel smaller than the NYC one I attended in 2015. After lunch with Ben, I returned for more HQB exploration. I spent more time looking around for my elusive component, with little success I must add. When I returned to my hotel room at the end of the 2nd day I felt a bit underwhelmed. I had come halfway around the world with as one of my main purposes finding samples for a specific part and I couldn't find a single match for what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Booking meetings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the beginning of the 3rd day I decided to switch tactics. Over lunch the previous day when I had asked Ben how he'd shop around for what I was looking for he said that he'd go on Alibaba, find some manufacturers that produced the items I was looking for and book meetings with them. That is one piece of advice I would absolutely apply in preparation for a next trip, and one that I can't recall having seen in TEGES. Outside of HQB, Shenzhen is a town where you can find manufacturers for most any electronic component you can think of, and many not only maintain an independent online site and/or pages on Alibaba, but they'll often have a booth in HQB showing off samples. That is something I wish I would've understood beforehand because it would've made the trip even more productive. It somewhat felt like a long shot to start spending time in my hotel room finding potential manufacturers, initiating contact, and book meetings with only a few business days left in my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did however have one ace up my sleeve. This wasn't the first time I had shopped around for some of the things I had in mind. I regularly present at Embedded World in Nuremberg every year and it happens to be one of biggest (if not the biggest) embedded shows on the planet. Several months before my trip to Shenzhen, I had already harvested several business cards from reps from potential vendors that happened to be based in Shenzhen. So on Sunday morning, I sent a message to my wife and asked her to find my stash of Embedded World 2017 business cards and send me some pictures. I then emailed a couple of contacts hoping they'd respond quickly enough to be able to schedule some meetings. This turned out to be quite effective. I had a couple of meetings scheduled with some manufacturers within the remaining week. They sent a car to pick me up at the hotel, I spent an hour or so at each site, and they drove me back to the hotel. And I got the information I was looking for and prices for exactly what I'm looking for. In each case they had very competent, English-speaking staff at hand and they knew exactly what I was talking about. I'd do a lot more of this on a future trip instead of just walking around HQB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're thinking of going to Shenzhen to shop for a project and you have specific components (or process/service for that matter) which are more critical than others, I strongly suggest you spend some time finding relevant companies several weeks ahead of time and arrange meetings while you're on site. It'll be far more effective that just walking around HQB in the hopes that you'll find what you're looking for. It's not entirely a replacement for going around HQB, but I wouldn't do without it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One meeting that was planned ahead of time through Ben that almost fell through because I couldn't find how to get to the location was a visit to Hax's offices in HQB, despite all my Googling. I tried asking one of the guards in a building near where the navigation app took me but despite calling a colleague on his radio he couldn't help me find it. By that time I had been walking around HQB for long enough, this was 7th or 8th day, to know the most important landmarks. Nothing seemed right about the addresses I was finding. I ended up having to wait for Ben, who happens to be one of the mentors listed on their site, to walk me up to their offices. In short, if you ever have to go to Hax's offices, don't assume the online information will be sufficient. Ask for guidance ahead of time. Despite this little delay, the visit was great. The place reminded me of Google's ATAP offices which I visited on a few occasions as part of my involvement in Project Ara with all sorts of cool and creative things happening all around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visit to Seeed Studio's factory towards the end of my trip was very interesting as well. They showed me the line they use for PCB assembly, from the solder paste machine to the test jigs along with the infrastructure they have in place for real-time tracking of orders. Great setup and definitely a place I'd be comfortable doing business with. Plus, my contact at Seeed was very helpful in answering several questions I had about Shenzhen and HBQ in the lead up to our meeting. Not only do they have a great setup, but they're great to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigating Huaqianbei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the 3rd day I felt more comfortable approaching some types of kiosks and trying to buy some of the things I needed or wanted samples of. I stopped by one kiosk selling standoffs and screws and initially just wanted to buy some dozens. But the shopkeeper was selling them by the hundreds and was wondering why I just wasn't buying them by the 2,000-bag full. That would've been a bit much. But I did end up getting about 3,000 M3 standoffs and screws for an unbeatable price in comparison to what I could find online. The only trouble with that purchase was the weight. It was so heavy that I ended up going back to the hotel to drop the package off. Still, once the shopkeeper realized that I wasn't just casually asking for information or wasting her time, she insisted I take her chair to sit down as I selected what I needed and started making jokes which her assistant who knew some English tried to translate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might seem from my explanations above that I was being shy or too cautious in my interactions. But I spent part of my life living across cultural boundaries, and continue to do so in some circumstances, and I therefore tend to be very sensitive to cultural deltas. I could see that there were a lot of locals stopping by and being very efficient in getting things done at some of those kiosks. From the outside looking in it may seem like this place is a maker's paradise with every ware you can think of available for you to purchase, but those shops weren't built with makers or foreign hardware officiandos in mind nor as their main business. Otherwise they would've all spoken English. The place is a real hustle and bustle. As we were walking around HBQ at some point, Ben quoted a friend of his, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thatsmags.com/shenzhen/post?author=Sky%20Gidge&quot;&gt;Sky Gidge&lt;/a&gt;, as saying that if HQB had a soundtrack, it would be the sound of tape wrapping boxes. The volume of sales going through the place is fairly important. So I felt it incumbent upon me to be as effective as I could in my interactions out of respect for the people who work there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some occasions, the shopkeepers seemed more open than others to my asking exploratory questions. One shop I stopped by on the same floor where TEGES mentions that there are electronics tools was selling all manors of tape. Some of these tapes I had seen in some blogs and/or in some of the various devices I had to service or disassemble but for which I didn't know the purpose. Here they were all stacked up for me to buy in all sorts of widths and sizes. I was able to ask about all the tapes I saw. The guy at the counter would happily use his app to translate the name/purpose of the tape I was pointing at and show it to me. I essentially got a free class and the opportunity to buy myself a lifetime supply of several tape types such as kapton, copper and conductive fabric tape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karimyaghmour.com/.a/6a0133f2f5dd98970b01bb09edaaff970d-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tape-purchase-180129&quot; src=&quot;http://www.karimyaghmour.com/.a/6a0133f2f5dd98970b01bb09edaaff970d-500wi&quot; title=&quot;Tape-purchase-180129&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like other shopkeepers, the guy at the tape counter asked if I had WeChat. At the time when I first passed by his counter I still didn't have a functional device. By the 4th day, though, I had fixed this problem and I went back to several shops to connect with them via WeChat. TEGES mentions that WeChat is “handy”. From my point of view, that doesn't sufficiently highlight how crucial WeChat is. For there is one functionality not mentioned in TEGES that makes it a killer app for shopping in HQB: it's got live translation between Chinese and English. Now, I didn't figure this one on my own. At one counter where I stopped I started by asking if they had WeChat. The guy at the counter popped his phone and showed me the QR code for me to scan and connect with him, which I did. Then, as I had been doing before, I went to Google Translate to write my question and show him. Seeing what I was doing he said: “no, no, no, WeChat, WeChat”. I didn't get what he was saying at first. But he quickly showed me that he could type in Chinese on his phone, I would get the text in Chinese, long-press on it and get a menu that allowed me to translate it in English. And when I sent a message in English, he'd be able to translate it to Chinese. That was a revelation. From that point onward I was able to have very effective conversations with most shopkeepers when the discussion warranted going further than a couple of simple questions using Google Translate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thereafter WeChat became central to most everything I did in Shenzhen, including keeping in touch with the companies I met. I returned to a shop where I had bought a few neodymium magnets a few days before for example. The first time around the guy at the counter didn't know any English. When I showed up and tried to talk to him he called what seemed to be his wife on his phone over a video call and just let me speak to her. She then explained to him what I was asking for. When I returned there, she was there in person. I asked if she had WeChat and we were able to have a constructive conversation from there on. When I asked if I could order from them for delivery back home, she asked me how do you ship magnets. That clued me in to something I hadn't realized before: powerful magnets can't just be shipped like other components. I knew lipo batteries required special packaging and carrier notification to transit properly, but I hadn't realized magnets were an issue as well. After some investigation I found that the marginal quantities I bought were a non-issue for my specific trip, which was my primary concern. That, though, didn't solve my problem if I wanted to use that shop and contact for ordering larger quantities later. I told her that I needed to investigate that upon my return and I'd let her known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I found problematic with WeChat is that unlike Hangout, for example, it doesn't store any of the conversations on the backend. There's apparently a “we're not spying on you” angle to this with regards to Tencent providing this service to users. That also means that conversations that you've had on one device will be unavailable on a new device unless you explicitly copy them from one device to the next. I find that to be somewhat annoying. Also, files shared in the past don't necessarily remain available, so make sure you download local copies if something is shared with you through WeChat. WeChat can also be used for payment. I had looked at that and AliPay before leaving but it seemed to require a Chinese bank account issued from a China-based branch. From what I was reading on the net, it's not too hard to set that up for just depositing locally and then using for WeChat/AliPay, but I didn't bother doing that this time around. Maybe if I was staying longer next time I would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally I've found prices to be a good discount off of even the prices of Chinese sellers that sell through eBay. In fact, I bought some items just out of curiosity without any immediate use for them just because I was able to get them right there and then at a fire-and-forget price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keeping Track&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I kept buying stuff, there was the question of how do I organize it all in a way that allowed me to figure out which invoice was for what, where I bought it from, how to return there and how to contact the seller for more later on. This is the part where I thought the plastic sleeves and maps in TEGES would come in handy. But at least for me, that didn't work out at all. What I had been doing was taking the business cards from the kiosks, whether I bought something or not, and I'd find a spot on them where I'd write 2 things: the kiosks' number within the building (they all have one) and the number and letter corresponding to where I got this from based on the maps in TEGES. Sometimes the kiosk number was already there, but I'd write it down anyway by hand so that it was more obvious to me. If I had bought things there, I'd keep the card in the same bag with the things I bought there along with the receipt. When I eventually got WeChat working, I added another item of information on those cards: the seller's WeChat ID – which you can retrieve in the app once you're connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking samples from the bags and putting them in the plastic sleeves along with the cards didn't seem right, because I'd then loose track of the match between the stash I had and the book itself. To avoid all this confusion of where I got it from versus what it was versus what it looked like when I bought it, I decided to just line everything up on my desk in the hotel room and take pictures. For each purchase, I'd lay out on the desk the merchandise, the invoice, the business card and whatever info I hadn't put elsewhere. Here's an example for some tiny motors I found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karimyaghmour.com/.a/6a0133f2f5dd98970b01b7c94a6064970b-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tiny-motors-180129&quot; src=&quot;http://www.karimyaghmour.com/.a/6a0133f2f5dd98970b01b7c94a6064970b-500wi&quot; title=&quot;Tiny-motors-180129&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the trip I had a Google album with the picture of every purchase I made that allows me to find again the sellers that I had found before. I find this to be more useful as I can access it from anywhere and I don't have to have my physical TEGES copy around to find it again. Nor do I need to worry about the number of sleeves left that I can use. I'd also write an English description behind every invoice of what this covered so that I could do the reverse lookup if I had an invoice in hand later and was wondering that this was, since most of the descriptions on those invoices are mostly written in Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bringing “stuff” back&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier regarding the neodymium magnets, not all things travel as easily. One thing I had to constantly kept track of in my head is the amount of luggage space and allowance left for me to buy more stuff. I initially thought that I'd just ship some of the things back to myself. I went to explore the location identified as “shipping alley” in TEGES but it seemed I would've needed to invest some time just figuring out this aspect of HQB whereas I eventually told myself I still had enough space in my bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I thought about shipping out regardless instead of travelling with them was lipo batteries. But when I enquired about rates at the DHL counter I was flabbergasted. It turns out that it's extremely expensive to ship those, which I vaguely then recalled having read something about in Bunnie's “Hardware Hacker” book. After much research on the net regarding rules and regulations, it turned out the sample quantity I had bought until then, especially since they were tiny, were a non-issue so long as they were in the cabin with me – they couldn't be checked in. That though put a stop to further lipo battery shopping. Still, this is one thing I don't know how to solve for now if I wanted to order large quantities from the vendors I identified in HQB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also in the market for larger items such as a stereoscopic microscope. That sort of item just wouldn't have fit in my existing bags. I could've always purchased another bag or bought a box to stuff things and count it as another bag, but I didn't see how I'd manage that on the transfer back to Hong Kong airport. I could routinely see people walking around with bags around HQB, some of which I presumed would've just been merchandise meant to travel. Staircases around HQB often include ramps for what could be bags or wheeled trolleys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shipping things back is certainly something one thing I wish I could prepare more fully for the next time around, especially if I planned bringing back large quantities of any specific item. Ideally, I'd use some form of cheap delayed-delivery method. This is one thing TBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to taking pictures of my purchases as I mentioned earlier, I also put all the invoices in a nice spreadsheet for customs purposes as I had to declare everything as commercial merchandise upon returning to Canada. That's one thing you probably also want to keep in mind. If you bring in any substantial number of parts of anything and/or if they look like things a company could use, it's entirely possible that the customs officer inspecting your bags on return might consider this “commercial merchandise”. Depending on the country you're returning to or even transiting through, such as the US in my case for that trip, they may have some different requirements and varying penalties for not declaring what they may deem as commercial merchandise. Personally I prefer playing it safe and declare anything that could potentially be seen as commercial merchandise as actually being commercial merchandise. If the amounts involved aren't big, they usually don't care. But at least they can't come back saying I didn't declare it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closing thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere around the end of the 3rd day I was roaming around the SEG building and turning around a corner I thought I'd seen someone that looked like Bunnie. As I got closer I realized that it was indeed him. He happened to be there with Gavin Zhao, to whom TEGES is dedicated to, at a kiosk selling copies of his book. I introduced myself and mentioned that I had been using TEGES for finding my way around HQB. We had never met before but he was as friendly as in some of the videos of him that are around – some people can be different on and off camera. I asked about some recommendations regarding some of the things I was struggling with and he generously made a few suggestions. Obviously I did the total fanboy routine and asked for an autograph. I can now claim that I've got the “run into Bunnie at the SEG building in HQB and get him to sign your copy of his book” achievement unlocked ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hadn't thought of it at the time when I saw Bunnie, but having worked with TEGES throughout those ten days I've come to the conclusion that that book would make a fantastic app backed by a corresponding website. There's no reason the map section of this book couldn't be provided in an interactive format with the ability to add user-generated content. This would open the door for having the app also double as an online community of non-Mandarin speakers roaming around HQB and Shenzhen in general. Anyone looking for the tiny motors I found, for instance, could just search for tiny motors and be shown a number of locations on the map where they were spotted along possibly with user pictures and information about the actual use of those parts and contact info about the seller, etc. The same goes for the point-to-translate sections of the book. As an app, in fact, this would probably be even more effective than having to sort through several pages of a section to find the one relevant to one part of the conversation. I'd think that the content of TEGES, especially since it's CC-BY-NC-SA, would make a fantastic starting point for such an app/website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the several issues I ran into, including the tech issues I encountered because of my pig-headed insistence on preserving a high level of security and some poor choices I made, I consider my ten day stay in Shenzhen a resounding success. I feel much more confident moving my project along and more solid in my understanding of hardware after the experience. It highlighted several issues and opened the door to several new possibilities. I don't know of any other place in the world that I've traveled to that could offer this much for a hardware project. There are certainly much wider ramifications to such a realization than my personal interests and the hardware segment of the tech world, but that's a separate topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the preparation I did before the trip paid off. Though, as I mentioned earlier, I would also do a few things differently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Research vendors working in my areas of interest on Alibaba and the net ahead of the trip and book meetings in advance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit the ground in HQB with a fully-functional Android device running WeChat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay for at least 2 to 3 weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first time I was in Shenzhen the group I was with was accompanied by someone who spoke Mandarin. While there this November I did see a handful of foreigners walking with what seemed to either be translators or local contacts. Before this trip, I wasn't sure whether I'd be able to make it solo to do something as specific as discussing and shopping for electronics without knowing the local language. With the proper preparation and tools, that turned out not to be a show-stopper. I wouldn't hesitate doing it again in fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things I still haven't figured out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coming up with a shipping strategy for getting things from Shenzhen to back home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing the lack of scalability of not having access to my usual laptop and email setup while in Shenzhen. I mean, it's one thing not having my usual work setup for 10 days, it's an entirely different one not having access to it for weeks on end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd like to close by thanking everyone that has helped me both before and in preparation or during this trip, including my friends David Anders, Charbax and Benjamin Dolgin-Gardner. A big thanks to Bunnie for taking the time to write down two books that I've found to be tremendously useful and insightful. This trip was of course but one step in a much greater adventure and I've been very fortunate the find the right people and resources to help me along the way. Stay tuned for more from where this came from.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 23:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>babkayaga</dc:creator>
<og:title>Ten Days in Shenzhen</og:title>
<og:type>blog</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.karimyaghmour.com/blog/2018/01/ten-days-in-shenzhen.html</og:url>
<og:description>Shenzhen is increasingly known within tech circles as the must-go location for anyone working on hardware. The one hour Wired documentary about Shenzhen, entitled “Shenzhen: The Silicon Valley of Hardware”, has been view more than 1.5M times on YouTube at the time of this writing. Countless articles, blog posts, videos,...</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.karimyaghmour.com/.a/6a0133f2f5dd98970b01bb09edb030970d-600wi</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.karimyaghmour.com/blog/2018/01/ten-days-in-shenzhen.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Godot 3.0 game engine released</title>
<link>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-3-0-released</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://godotengine.org/article/godot-3-0-released</guid>
<description>&lt;img data-src=&quot;godot3.0-fracteed.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/uploads/public/5a6/f92/d3f/5a6f92d3f0d1d382442473.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;By: Juan Linietsky &lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Jan 29 - 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After more than 18 months of development, all Godot Engine contributors are proud to present our biggest release so far, Godot 3.0! It brings a brand new rendering engine with state-of-the-art PBR workflow for 3D, an improved assets pipeline, GDNative to load native code as plugins, C# 7.0 support, Bullet as the 3D physics engine, and many other features which are &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/article/godot-3-0-released#features&quot;&gt;described in depth below&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impatient users can put an end to 18 months of waiting by jumping directly to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/download&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; page and start playing with Godot 3.0!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Godot 3.0 ended up being a much, much bigger release than we initially expected. Originally, we planned to just add a new renderer, rework the 3D workflow and boost the major version to indicate compatibility breakage (as the new renderer would be PBR and old one is not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year ago, we decided to skip the release of Godot 2.2 (which would have included new multiplayer networking, visual scripting and many other improvements) because we realized that projects using the new features would no longer work in 3.0, and that we'd better focus fully on 3.0 instead of spending 3 months stabilizing the 2.2 work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, as we realized that we were going to fully break compatibility with the 3.0 release, we decided to take the chance to look at our long list of features and bug fixes that could not be implemented because it involved breaking compatibility. We decided to just give it a go and fix everything that had to be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also become a perfect opportunity for contributors to propose (and submit) deep changes and improvements to how Godot works, as this was not possible since Godot was open-sourced in our aim to preserve compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of this work was overwhelmingly positive. Godot 3.0 has an almost entirely new core as well as several top notch brand new features. It is the culmination of all our contributors' efforts and our most advanced and complete release yet. With 3.0, we lay the foundation for even more rapid improvements in the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you really enjoy this new release and keep tuned for the new ones that will come after!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Patreon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though we didn't roll any major release over the last 18 months, the Godot community kept growing at a lightning pace. This led us to think that we should take Godot even more seriously and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/godotengine&quot;&gt;look for funding&lt;/a&gt; to have more work time dedicated to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patreon has proven to be an excellent solution for funding the project and allow me (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/reduz&quot;&gt;Juan&lt;/a&gt;) to work on it full-time. This allowed me to spend more time helping other contributors. As a result, the number of core developers and occasional contributions has grown considerably:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/godot_contributions_december.png&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub contributions in 2017&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we always want to be crystal clear with how donations are handled and used, we registered on Patreon via our fiscal sponsor, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfconservancy.org&quot;&gt;Software Freedom Conservancy&lt;/a&gt; (which is the high-profile, US-based non-profit charity which handles our finances and legal questions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After meeting the initial goal, we hired Thomas Herzog (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/karroffel&quot;&gt;karroffel&lt;/a&gt;) to continue his work on GDNative (more about this below) and work on a new rendering backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently aiming to hire Rémi Verschelde (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/akien-mga&quot;&gt;Akien&lt;/a&gt;), our project manager, as full time project manger and representative (you can read more about this &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/article/next-patreon-goal-help-us-hire-remi-verschelde-akien-full-time&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). We need your help, as we are more than halfway there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't yet, please help us reach this goal by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/godotengine&quot;&gt;becoming our patron&lt;/a&gt;! Even a bit is a tremendous help to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thank all users who support our project so far on Patreon or via direct donations, as well as the companies who generously sponsor us (Enjin Coin, Gamblify and GameDev.TV). Last but not least, a big thank you to Mozilla and Microsoft for their grants which funded a big part of the work on 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the fantastic work done by Nathan Lovato (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GDquest&quot;&gt;GDquest&lt;/a&gt;), Chris Bradfield (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KidsCanCode&quot;&gt;KidsCanCode&lt;/a&gt;) and many other contributors, Godot 3.0 also comes with brand new documentation (which is to be expected, as most APIs changed considerably). Our built-in docs are more complete and of much better quality than ever, and our &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.godotengine.org/en/3.0/&quot;&gt;online docs&lt;/a&gt; now cover many new topics in depth (such as 3D features).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/godot_docs.png&quot; alt=&quot;Logo of the Godot documentation&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most non-official tutorials online are for the 2.1 version, so they will need to be remade for 3.x. Now that Godot is stable again, this is a great chance for everyone to start working on this.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, 3.0 has been 18 months in the making and is a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; release. Listing all its features is virtually impossible, but we'll try to give an extensive overview of what changed since Godot 2.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a long read, so here's a table of contents to easily get to a specific section:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New physically based 3D renderer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/new_3d_renderer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Examples of 3D scenes with PBR&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot 3.0 comes with a brand new renderer. For many years, when you read about Godot on the Internet, usual comments were along the lines of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;The 2D engine is very good, but 3D is still basic, lacking and nowhere comparable to XXX 3D or YYY Engine&quot;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, this is no more. The new 3D engine is outstanding, with many features out-of-the-box that are still not common in other mainstream engines. Added to this, Godot's ease of use allows reaching the best quality with much less effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new 3D renderer is state-of-the-art, with features rarely see in game engines today, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Full principled BSDF&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot is the first engine to offer the full range of Disney's principled BSDF for physically-based rendering. Due to its &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/article/godot-3-renderer-design-explained&quot;&gt;innovative rendering architecture&lt;/a&gt;, it can offer very complex materials at no extra cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that besides the typical Albedo, Metalness, Ambient Occlusion and Roughness features, Godot offers Rim, Anisotropy, Subsurface Scattering, Clearcoat, Refraction and Transmission. They are all ready to use out-of-the-box and tightly integrated to the render pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/new_material_params.png&quot; alt=&quot;Overview of state-of-the-art BSDF material parameters in Godot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other engines force you to either choose only one of those parameters at a time, apply them in a forward pass (thus leaving them out of post-processing, global illumination or making them inefficient with a high numbers of lights), or pay for them. In Godot they are built-in, work without hacks, efficiently and can be combined together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Global illumination (GI)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides materials, lighting is very important. Godot 3.0 provides two alternative workflows for global illumination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/devlog/rendering/final_quality.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3D scene with global illumination&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one is GI Probes, which act like reflection probes (they affect an area and can be blended) but provide global illumination instead. GI Probes are real-time, which means that light changes take effect immediately and objects passing by the probe will also get GI from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both indirect light and voxel reflections are provided by this technique. It's also very easy to use. Just set up the probe bounds and do a fast pre-bake of static objects. No lightmaps or anything of the sort are required, providing a very quick and efficient workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/giprobe.png&quot; alt=&quot;3D scene with GI Probes&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only downside is that it requires medium to high-end hardware to work. Even on the lowest quality settings, rendering at an halved resolution may be required on low-end systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For low-end systems or mobile devices, we provide a more classical lightmapping workflow. Still, this workflow is easy and efficient as 3D objects get a second set of UVs generated on import, and baking works with instantiated meshes, scenes and even GridMaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot also uses a light octree system together with lightmaps, which allows dynamic objects to get light from the scene without having to resort to manually-placed light probes, which are a real hassle to set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/lightmapping.png&quot; alt=&quot;3D scene with lightmapping&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Mid- and post-processing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with the new rendering capabilities, a new set of mid- and post-processing options are supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a new tonemapper, with support for HDR, multiple standard curves and auto exposure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/auto_exposure.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Auto exposure as a post-process effect&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most standard effects such as screen-space reflections, fog, depth of field, etc. are supported now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/devlog/rendering/dof1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Depth of field as a post-process effect&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a powerful SSAO implementation, which has many useful settings like light affect (how much direct light is affected), or ignoring objects with an ambient occlusion map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/environment_ssao2.png&quot; alt=&quot;SSAO as a post-process effect&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Materials and shaders&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the visual material editor from Godot 2.1 was removed in the compatibility breakage, but it will come back in 3.1. Still, Godot 3.0 makes up for it by providing an extremely powerful default material (which supports detail textures, triplanar mapping and other nice features) and an extremely easy-to-use shader language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/devlog/rendering/render_shader.png&quot; alt=&quot;Example of spatial shader code&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other engines, you have to provide many shader variants, mix HLSL with a metalanguage, error reporting is terrible and writing shaders is difficult in general. In Godot 3.0, writing shaders is very easy! It uses a custom language that supports most of the GLSL specification. It parses your code and automatically understands what you are trying to do (such as writing to alpha for transparency, reading from screen, etc.) and it generates internal shader variants for all rendering methods automatically and transparently (forward, clustered, vertex-lit, depth-pass, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this within a convenient editor supporting full auto-completion!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;GPU particles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particle systems in Godot (both 2D and 3D) are processed in the GPU. This allows for millions of particles per frame and really cool effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/particles.png&quot; alt=&quot;Editor screenshot with 100k particles&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As particles are processed on the GPU, it is also possible to create particle shaders for custom behaviors. Even converting regular particles to shaders for further tweaking is possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/particles2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Example of particle shader code&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New asset workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot 3.0 has changed how the assets pipeline work. We now use the more familiar scheme of automatically importing assets. Simply drop an asset into the project folder and it will automatically be imported with configurable default parameters. Options can be changed afterwards after importing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/import_system.png&quot; alt=&quot;Editor screenshot with import options&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting point about how this works is that copying the import folder between computers works perfectly, the editor will not attempt reimporting something until it has really changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another big plus of this new system, besides improved ease of use, is that running on a device with a networked filesystem (for very fast testing times) works much better than before. Godot will pick the right compression for textures when importing for mobile, and supply them over the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3D asset workflow has also seen great improvements. It is possible to either import a scene as a single file, or to split it into multiple instantiated subscenes, keep materials, meshes and animations external, etc. Changes to resources can also be merged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;glTF 2.0 support&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot now supports importing glTF 2.0 scenes. This is a new open standard by Khronos which we &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/article/we-should-all-use-gltf-20-export-3d-assets-game-engines&quot;&gt;encourage you&lt;/a&gt; to use and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/gltf.png&quot; alt=&quot;glTF 2.0 scene imported in Godot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The importer is new and likely not as mature as the Collada importer, but it will get better over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Improved OBJ support&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venerable OBJ format is now much better supported. Materials can be read from it and importing as a full scene is now also possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;SVG support&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Ramirez (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djrm&quot;&gt;djrm&lt;/a&gt;) implemented importing SVG as bitmaps (with customizable resolution). This functionality is also used to better support HiDPI modes, as editor icons are converted to native resolution when the editor starts up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not let you use SVGs directly as 2D meshes yet, but it's on the roadmap for future releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;GDNative&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/gdnative.png&quot; alt=&quot;C++ scripting via GDNative&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDNative is our new framework for extending Godot via external libraries. It was mostly developed by Thomas Herzog (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/karroffel&quot;&gt;karroffel&lt;/a&gt;), and it's truly amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using GDNative, it's possible to easily extend Godot in C/C++ without recompiling the engine, and that for any platform. This also means that it's easy to bundle external libraries (such as OpenVR, Steam, Kinect, SQLite, etc.), or provide support for video/audio codecs, VR, etc. as pluggable libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not all. GDNative allows setting up extra scripting languages and using them on the fly without recompiling the engine, with pretty much native performance. Currently, work is in an advanced state for community-maintained &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/touilleMan/godot-python&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; (via the PluginScript interface), &lt;a href=&quot;https://pragmagic.github.io/godot-nim/master/index.html&quot;&gt;Nim&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GodotNativeTools/godot-d&quot;&gt;D&lt;/a&gt; support, as well of course as official &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GodotNativeTools/godot-cpp&quot;&gt;C++&lt;/a&gt; bindings; others might follow if community members are interested in working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about it on its &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/article/dlscript-here&quot;&gt;original announcement&lt;/a&gt; and a later &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/article/look-gdnative-architecture&quot;&gt;in-depth look at its architecture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Mono / C# support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/monogodot.png&quot; alt=&quot;C# scripting via the Mono flavour&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a generous grant from Microsoft, Ignacio Roldán Etcheverry (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/neikeq&quot;&gt;neikeq&lt;/a&gt;) did a fantastic job and implemented Mono support in Godot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to fully script &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/article/introducing-csharp-godot&quot;&gt;Godot using C#&lt;/a&gt;, using your favorite IDE and the latest version of the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to popular demand, we also implemented an API mostly conformant with the C# conventions, so for C# users, the API is mostly PascalCase (instead of snake_case). The generated C# code API includes the full documentation embedded, so code completion works very well with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The language support is mostly complete and it's fully usable, but it will continue improving over the next months - the main missing feature as of 3.0 is the ability to export games coded in C#, as such it's not fully usable in production yet. There's not much left to implement for this to work though, and it will be available in Godot 3.0.1 within a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as not to impose the additional dependency on the Mono SDK to users of other scripting languages such as GDScript or VisualScript, the C# support comes in a separate build of Godot (labeled the &quot;mono&quot; build).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Visual Scripting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot 3.0 also comes with a brand new visual scripting language (originally named VisualScript), in the typical &quot;boxes and connections&quot; fashion. The default implementation is rather low-level, but is extensible enough for users to create more high-level behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/visual_script.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual scripting is ideal for non-programmers, or for programmers exposing behaviors to game designers, artists, etc. One of the nice features of our implementation is that it's possible to drag elements from most Godot panels (filesystem, scene, properties, etc.) to the canvas, greatly improving usability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is the first stable release shipping with VisualScript, we are looking forward to your feedback to continue improving it further in future releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;GDScript&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDScript has seen many improvements since 2.1. The main one is that the API has changed mostly from using functions to properties. This makes it less verbose, easier for newcomers and for finding the right property in the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;get_node()&lt;/code&gt; function also got syntactic sugar to obtain nodes in the local scene tree by writing less code, using the &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; alias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/gdscript3.png&quot; alt=&quot;New GDScript API in 3.0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDScript has also seen a huge performance boost thanks to the work of Hein-Pieter van Braam (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hpvb&quot;&gt;hpvb/TMM&lt;/a&gt;), which makes its execution much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new pattern matching API is also available, courtesy of Thomas Herzog (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/karroffel&quot;&gt;karroffel&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code completion has also seen a great increase in accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New audio engine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot 3.0 comes with a brand new audio engine; the old one has been completely wiped out. This version is entirely focused on AudioStreams (samples are no longer supported). Streams (supported as .wav and .ogg files) can be played in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stream players can now send their output to buses in a rack, allowing very high efficiency and freedom in game sound design:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/audiorack.png&quot; alt=&quot;Audio rack with multiple buses&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a large library of built-in sound effects than can be put in each channel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/builtinfx.png&quot; alt=&quot;Overview of the built-in sound effects&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Positional audio is also now fully supported, including stereo, 5.1 and 7.1 speaker configurations. 3D audio can be sent to any channel, but also areas will capture it and send it to custom channels (with split reverb).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allows different areas to have different reverberation and effects (reverb is not the same in small and large rooms), without having to tweak snapshots like other engines do. Here is an example using the older 3D platformer demo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aRwCxMYSIk8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;VR support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot 3.0 has also seen the introduction of the ARVRServer implementation (as the name says, for AR and VR support), thanks to the great work of Bastiaan Olij (&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/BastiaanOlij&quot;&gt;Mux213&lt;/a&gt;). While the current AR implementations that are being worked on have been moved to the 3.1 release, for VR there are now two options that are ready to be used, with more backends in the works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A built-in Cardboard-ish mobile VR solution that uses the embedded sensors for basic 3DOF head tracking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A GDNative-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BastiaanOlij/godot_openvr&quot;&gt;implementation of the OpenVR API&lt;/a&gt; making Godot fully compatible with SteamVR. Pre-compiled binaries for Windows are provided via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/asset-library/asset/150&quot;&gt;Asset Library&lt;/a&gt;, with other platforms coming soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/Sponza%20VR.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sponza scene with OpenVR&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GDNative ARVR framework is tightly knit and allows support for other VR platforms to be developed independently of the core game engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bullet Physics backend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bullet physics engine can now be used in Godot and comes enabled by default (it's configurable, the old Godot 3D physics backend can be selected in the project settings). Andrea Catania (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AndreaCatania&quot;&gt;Odino&lt;/a&gt;) made an amazing job adapting Bullet to Godot and keeping the API mostly intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/bullet.png&quot; alt=&quot;Logo of the Bullet Physics library&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from a big gain in performance and correctness of the physics, this will allow, in future Godot versions, to implement features such as soft bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New networked multiplayer API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new API for networked multiplayer was added to Godot 3.0. It's based on remote procedure calls (using ENet for communication) and it makes it very easy to synchronize multiple peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/multiplayer.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of multiplayer bomber demo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the script language front, some keywords were added, such as &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;slave&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;rpc&lt;/code&gt;. This way functions can only be called by the right peer, allowing different levels of authoritativeness and simple game synchronization. Keywords can be added to both functions and properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/multiplayer2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Code example showing new multiplayer keywords&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Rewritten export system&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The export system in Godot has been entirely rewritten. Exporting works based on presets, so it's possible to have two presets targeting the same platform, but with different configuration values (such as Android ARM and x86, demo and full game presets, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/export_presets.png&quot; alt=&quot;Configuration of export presets&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with this system, a new &quot;feature tags&quot; system was implemented. Different OS, platform and export features are exposed to Godot as special &quot;tags&quot;. The tags can be used for multiple purposes, from overriding in each platform to changing export values:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/ft.png&quot; alt=&quot;Customizable feature tags&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile, for example, comes with many predefined feature tags, to aid on reducing graphics requirements on these platforms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/ft2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Predefined mobile feature tags&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;IPv6 support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/ipv6.png&quot; alt=&quot;IPv6 logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot is now fully compliant with IPv6, thanks to Ariel Manzur (&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/punto-&quot;&gt;punto&lt;/a&gt;) and Fabio Alessandrelli (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Faless&quot;&gt;Faless&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;WebAssembly and WebGL 2.0 support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/webassembly.png&quot; alt=&quot;WebAssembly logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the great work carried out by Leon Krause (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eska014&quot;&gt;eska&lt;/a&gt;), the HTML5 exporter has greatly improved, including WebAssembly support! WebGL 2.0 has also been added together with the new physically-based renderer (WebGL 1.0 will come back in 3.1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New editor theme and customization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our main designer, Daniel Ramirez (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djrm&quot;&gt;djrm&lt;/a&gt;), with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/volzhs&quot;&gt;volzhs&lt;/a&gt; and Timo (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/toger5&quot;&gt;toger5&lt;/a&gt;), put together a fantastic new theme system. It has much better HiDPI support and allows easily changing colors and contrast levels, as well as alternating between light and dark themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/editor_theme.png&quot; alt=&quot;New editor theme&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize Godot the way you like it! (Without having to pay for it...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Auto-tiling in tile maps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot now supports auto-tiling in TileMap, authored by Mariano Suligoy (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MarianoGNU&quot;&gt;MarianoGNU&lt;/a&gt;) and enhanced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/damarindra&quot;&gt;Damar Indra&lt;/a&gt;. This new implementation is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mapeditor.org&quot;&gt;Tiled Editor&lt;/a&gt;'s Terrains and is fully compatible with previous TileSets. It has built-in collision, occlusion and navigation polygon editors, together with the possibility to extend the resource using a tool script to have control over what subtiles do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Improved flat style box&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vector-based style box (StyleBoxFlat) has been greatly improved by Timo (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/toger5&quot;&gt;toger5&lt;/a&gt;), adding support for rounded corners. Customize your game UI components with slick vector looks and soft drop shadows (which are also resolution-independent), without having to create any image!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/flatstylebox.png&quot; alt=&quot;Examples of StyleBoxFlat with rounded corners&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Font oversampling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To continue on the resolution-independent trend, Godot also now supports font oversampling. This makes sure your fonts always use the native resolution even if your UI is scaled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/font_oversample.png&quot; alt=&quot;Preview of font oversampling&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Custom hardware cursor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/cursor.png&quot; alt=&quot;Preview of custom hardware cursor&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Xavier Sellier (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/xsellier&quot;&gt;xsellier&lt;/a&gt;) and Guilherme Felipe de C. G. da Silva (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/guilhermefelipecgs&quot;&gt;guilhermefelipecgs&lt;/a&gt;), it is finally possible to change the hardware mouse cursor on desktop platforms. Set any image as cursor and it will work, with reduced latency compared to a software cursor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Greatly improved 3D editor viewport&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/3dgizmo.png&quot; alt=&quot;3D manipulation gizmos&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support for free look and fly mode, thanks to Marc Gilleron (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Zylann&quot;&gt;Zylann&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved 3D manipulation gizmos (multiple-axis editing and scale), thanks to the work of Przemysław Gołąb (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/n-pigeon&quot;&gt;n-pigeon&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpolation on motion and view change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved selection support on instanced scenes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposed grid snap and local axis transform in toolbar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information display on rendered geometry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half-resolution viewport rendering for better performance on HiDPI displays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Console support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While, due to legal and practical reasons, we can't provide ports to consoles (save for XBox One via UWP), this does not mean that separate private companies can't. Godot's open license allows any company to port the engine to consoles and offer it as a product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the case of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lonewolftechnology.com/&quot;&gt;Lone Wolf Technology&lt;/a&gt;, a company created by original Godot co-author Ariel Manzur, who offers to get your game running on any console. A Nintendo Switch port has been recently completed, allowing Godot to run on their latest console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://godotengine.org/storage/app/media/3.0%20release/godotswitch.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a new section listing the providers in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.godotengine.org/en/latest/tutorials/platform/consoles.html&quot;&gt;official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;And hundreds of other improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is already too long and it's impossible to list all the hundreds of features and bug fixes that have been implemented by Godot contributors over the last year and a half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributors are working on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Calinou/15b7b48abc0c3a22fbb2993b39a0ae99&quot;&gt;human-readable changelog&lt;/a&gt; which should give you some more details. You can also browse and filter the list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Apr+milestone%3A3.0+-label%3Aarchived&quot;&gt;GitHub pull requests&lt;/a&gt; of almost 3000 contributions (and the corresponding list for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Aissue+milestone%3A3.0+-label%3Aarchived&quot;&gt;GitHub issues&lt;/a&gt;), as well as review the raw Git changelogs since Godot 2.1 (sorted &lt;a href=&quot;https://downloads.tuxfamily.org/godotengine/3.0/Godot_v3.0-stable_changelog_chrono.txt&quot;&gt;chronogically&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://downloads.tuxfamily.org/godotengine/3.0/Godot_v3.0-stable_changelog_authors.txt&quot;&gt;by author&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Godot 3.0 lays the foundation of a fantastic engine. Over the course of the next months, the plan is to keep adding the missing features and fix known issues, as well as further improving documentation and tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot 3.1 will bring a new and more powerful animation tree, modern occlusion culling, improved rendering and a GLES 2.0 backend (for mobile and low-end desktop compatibility), as well as many other pending features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can greatly help us improve Godot, as well as make it faster and better. Besides contributing code (if you are a programmer), you can help us a lot by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/godotengine&quot;&gt;becoming our patron&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, spreading the word will always benefit us, as most game developers still have never tried (or even heard of) Godot. Finally, the best contribution might be to use Godot to develop and publish awesome games!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See our &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.godotengine.org/en/latest/community/contributing/ways_to_contribute.html&quot;&gt;community documentation&lt;/a&gt; for a description of all the ways you can contribute to Godot and how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have fun with this long-awaited release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trivia:&lt;/em&gt; Today's also the anniversary date of the writing of our namesake play by Samuel Beckett, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waiting_for_Godot&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Waiting for Godot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, whose French text was completed on 29 January 1949.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The illustration picture is courtesy of James Redmond (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fracteed&quot;&gt;@fracteed&lt;/a&gt;) who helped a lot during the development of 3.0 by stress-testing the engine with great PBR assets and reporting the issues he found doing so.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 23:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Rusky</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://godotengine.org/storage/app/uploads/public/5a6/f92/d3f/5a6f92d3f0d1d382442473.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-3-0-released</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: 5 months and counting waiting for Coinbase customer support. Advice?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16261136</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16261136</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.1487946799668&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.3615960099751&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16261136&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16261136&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: 5 months and counting waiting for Coinbase customer support. Advice?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73170731707317&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16261136&quot;&gt;441 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=benbreen&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;benbreen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16261136&quot;&gt;17 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16261136&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16261136&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16261136&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%205%20months%20and%20counting%20waiting%20for%20Coinbase%20customer%20support.%20Advice%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%205%20months%20and%20counting%20waiting%20for%20Coinbase%20customer%20support.%20Advice%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16261136&amp;amp;auth=472a552c5ab0ac3b113912333f800e069429c074&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16261136&quot;&gt;173 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;So Coinbase's disastrous customer service has come up on HN before [1]. But my issue is rather more extreme than a wire transfer that takes a few weeks to go through - I've been waiting for over &lt;em&gt;five months&lt;/em&gt; for Coinbase to unlock my account and allow me to access my funds. Since August 20 of 2017 to be exact.
&lt;p&gt;I've never experienced or even heard of such a long wait time for action to be taken on an open customer support ticket and I honestly have no idea how to proceed. Should I start contacting the CFPB or BBB, writing registered letters, etc?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, I have had contact with various Coinbase customer service reps since August. I also have tried emailing and tweeting at the CEO and Coinbase executives. The refrain is always the same: &quot;We're expanding fast and adding to our customer service team. Your case has been escalated for further review. Please bear with us.&quot; I've been patient for months now and am thinking that maybe I'm not following the right strategy - any advice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16106793&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.7448275862069&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Summer 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/dmca.html&quot;&gt;DMCA&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 22:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>benbreen</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16261136</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Software Complexity Is Killing Us</title>
<link>https://www.simplethread.com/software-complexity-killing-us/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.simplethread.com/software-complexity-killing-us/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Since the dawn of time (before software, there was only darkness), there has been one constant: businesses want to build software cheaper and faster.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is certainly an understandable and laudable goal – especially if you’ve spent any time around software developers. It is a goal that every engineer should support wholeheartedly, and we should always strive to create things as efficiently as possible, given the constraints of our situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the truth is we often don’t. It’s not intentional, but over time, we get waylaid by unforeseen complexities in building software and train ourselves to seek out edge cases, analysis gaps, all of the hidden repercussions that can result from a single bullet point of requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get enthralled by the maelstrom of complexity and the mental puzzle of engineering elegant solutions: Another layer of abstraction! DRY it up! Separate the concerns! Composition over inheritance! This too is understandable, but in the process, we often lose sight of the business problems being solved and forget that managing complexity is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;second most important&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; responsibility of software developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how did we get here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few decades, our industry has been very successful at reducing the amount of custom code it takes to write most software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of this reduction has been accomplished by making programming languages more expressive. Languages such as Python, Ruby, or JavaScript can take &lt;em&gt;as little as one third as much code&lt;/em&gt; as C in order to implement similar functionality. C gave us similar advantages over writing in assembler. Looking forward to the future, it is unlikely that language design will give us the same kinds of improvements we have seen over the last few decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But reducing the amount of code it takes to build software involves many other avenues that don’t require making languages more expressive. By far the biggest gain we have made in this over the last two decades is open source software (OSS). Without individuals and companies pouring money into software that they give freely to the community, much of what we build today wouldn’t be possible without an order of magnitude more cost and effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These projects have allowed us to tackle problems by standing on the shoulders of giants, leveraging tools to allow us to focus more of our energy on actually solving business problems, rather than spending time building infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, businesses are complex. Ridiculously complex and only getting moreso. OSS is great for producing frameworks and tools that we can use to build systems on top of, but for the most part, OSS has to tackle problems shared by a large number of people in order to gain traction. Because of that, most open source projects have to either be relatively generic or be in a very popular niche. Therefore, most of these tools are great platforms on which to build out systems, but at the end of the day, we are still left to build all of the business logic and interfaces in our increasingly complex and demanding systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what we are left with is a stack that looks something like this (for a web application)…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Our Code&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;Libraries&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;Web Framework&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;Web Server&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;Data Stores&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;lt;Operating System&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That “Our Code” part ends up being enormously complex, since it mirrors the business and its processes. If we have custom business logic, and custom processes, then we are left to build the interfaces, workflow, and logic that make up our applications. Sure, we can try to find different ways of recording that logic (remember business rules engines?), but at the end of the day, no one else is going to write the business logic for your business. There really doesn’t seem to be a way around that… at least not until the robots come and save us all from having to do any work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if we have to develop the interfaces, workflow, and logic that make up our applications, then it sounds like we are stuck, right? To a certain extent, yes, but we have a few options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To most developers, software equals code, but that isn’t reality. There are many ways to build software, and one of those ways is through using visual tools. Before the web, visual development and RAD tools had a much bigger place in the market. Tools like PowerBuilder, Visual Foxpro, Delphi, VB, and Access all had visual design capabilities that allowed developers to create interfaces without typing out any code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tools spanned the spectrum in terms of the amount of code you needed to write, but in general, you designed your app visually and then ended up writing a ton of code to implement the logic of your app. In many cases you still ended up programmatically manipulating the interface, since interfaces built using these tools often ended up being very static. However, for a huge class of applications, these tools allowed enormous productivity gains over the alternatives, mostly at the cost of flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prevalence of these tools might have waned since the web took over, but companies’ desire for them has not, especially since the inexorable march of software demand continues. The latest trend that is blowing across the industry is “low code” systems. Low code development tools are a modern term put on the latest generation of drag and drop software development tools. The biggest difference between these tools and their brethren from years past is that they are now mostly web (and mobile) based and are often hosted platforms in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And many companies are jumping all over these platforms. Vendors like Salesforce (App Cloud), Outsystems, Mendix, or Kony are promising the ability to create applications many times faster than “traditional” application development. While many of their claims are probably hyperbole, there likely is a bit of truth to them as well. For all of the downsides of depending on platforms like these, they probably do result in certain types of applications being built faster than traditional enterprise projects using .NET or Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, a few things. First is that experienced developers often hate these tools. Most Serious Developers™ like to write Real Software™ with Real Code™. I know that might sound like I’m pandering to a bunch of whiney babies (and maybe I am a bit), but if the core value you deliver is technology, it is rarely a good idea to adopt tools that your best developers don’t want to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second is that folks like me look at these walled platforms and say “nope, not building my application in there.” That is a legitimate concern and the one that bothers me the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you built an application a decade ago with PHP, then that application might be showing its age, but it could still be humming along right now just fine. The language and ecosystem are open source, and maintained by the community. You’ll need to keep your application up to date, but you won’t have to worry about a vendor deciding it isn’t worth their time to support you anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…folks like me look at these walled platforms and say “nope, not building my application in there.” That is a legitimate concern and the one that bothers me the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you picked a vendor 10 years ago who had a locked down platform, then you might be forced into a rewrite if they shut down or change their tooling too much (&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/30/facebooks-parse-developer-platform-is-shutting-down-today/&quot;&gt;remember Parse?&lt;/a&gt;). Or even worse, your system gets stuck on a platforms that freezes and no longer serves your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons to be wary of these types of platforms, but for many businesses, the allure of creating software with less effort is just too much to pass up. The complexity of software continues on, and software engineers unfortunately aren’t doing ourselves any favors here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are productive platforms out there, that allow us to build Real Software™ with Real Code™, but unfortunately our industry right now is far too worried with following the lead of the big tech giants to realize that sometimes their tools don’t add a lot of value to our projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you the number of times I’ve had a developer tell me that building something as a single page application (SPA) adds no overhead versus just rendering HTML. I’ve heard developers say that every application should be written on top of a NoSQL datastore, and that relational databases are dead. I’ve heard developers question why every application isn’t written using CQRS and Event Sourcing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is that kind of thought process and default overhead that is leading companies to conclude that software development is just too expensive. You might say, “But event sourcing is so elegant! Having a SPA on top of microservices is so clean!” Sure, it can be, but not when you’re the person writing all ten microservices. It is that kind of additional complexity that is often &lt;em&gt;so unnecessary&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, as an industry, need to find ways to simplify the process of building software, without ignoring the legitimate complexities of businesses. We need to admit that not every application out there needs the same level of interface sophistication and operational scalability as Gmail. There is a whole world of apps out there that need well thought-out interfaces, complicated logic, solid architectures, smooth workflows, etc…. but don’t need microservices or AI or chatbots or NoSQL or Redux or Kafka or Containers or whatever the tool dujour is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of developers right now seem to be so obsessed with the technical wizardry of it all that they can’t step back and ask themselves if any of this is really needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is like the person on MasterChef who comes in and sells themselves as the molecular gastronomist. They separate ingredients into their constituent parts, use scientific methods of pairing flavors, and then apply copious amounts of CO2 and liquid nitrogen to produce the most creative foods you’ve ever seen. And then they get kicked off after an episode or two because they forget the core tenet of most cooking, that food needs to taste good. They seem genuinely surprised that no one liked their fermented fennel and mango-essence pearls served over cod with anchovy foam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our obsession with flexibility, composability, and cleverness is causing us a lot of pain and pushing companies away from the platforms and tools that we love. I’m not saying those tools I listed above don’t add value somewhere; they arose in response to real pain points, albeit typically problems encountered by large companies operating systems at enormous scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I’m saying is that we need to head back in the direction of simplicity and start actually creating things in a simpler way, instead of just constantly talking about simplicity. Maybe we can lean on more &lt;em&gt;integrated&lt;/em&gt; tech stacks to provide out of the box patterns and tools to allow software developers to create software more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…we are going to push more and more businesses into the arms of “low code” platforms and other tools that promise to reduce the cost of software by dumbing it down and removing the parts that brought us to it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to stop pretending that our 20th line-of-business application is some unique tapestry that needs to be carefully hand-sewn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After writing that, I can already hear a million developers sharpening their pitchforks, but I believe that if we keep pushing in the direction of wanting to write everything, configure everything, compose everything, use the same stack for every scale of problem, then we are going to push more and more businesses into the arms of “low code” platforms and other tools that promise to reduce the cost of software by dumbing it down and removing the parts that brought us to it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our answer to the growing complexity of doing business cannot be adding complexity to the development process – no matter how elegant it may seem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must find ways to manage complexity by simplifying the development process. Because even though managing complexity is our second most important responsibility, we must always remember the most important responsibility of software developers: delivering value through working software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplethread.com/part-job-can-automate/&quot; rel=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 20:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tenhundfeld</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Software Complexity Is Killing Us - Simple Thread</og:title>
<og:description>Since the dawn of time (before software, there was only darkness), there has been one constant: businesses want to build software cheaper and faster. It is certainly an understandable and laudable goal – especially if you’ve spent any time around software developers. It is a goal that every engineer should support wholeheartedly, and we should... Read more »</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.simplethread.com/software-complexity-killing-us/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.simplethread.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/complex-maze-dark.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.simplethread.com/software-complexity-killing-us/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The U.S. Gets Less Subway for Its Money Than Its Peers</title>
<link>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2018/01/why-its-so-expensive-to-build-urban-rail-in-the-us/551408/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2018/01/why-its-so-expensive-to-build-urban-rail-in-the-us/551408/</guid>
<description>&lt;img class=&quot;c-lead-image__img&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.citylab.com/media/img/citylab/2018/01/AP_600095778376/300.jpg?mod=1516973583&quot; alt=&quot;A construction worker inside the 86th Street cavern of the Second Avenue Subway tunnel in 2014&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; onload=&quot;performance.mark('citylab_lead_image_loaded')&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-lead-image__img&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.citylab.com/media/img/citylab/2018/01/AP_600095778376/300.jpg?mod=1516973583&quot; alt=&quot;A construction worker inside the 86th Street cavern of the Second Avenue Subway tunnel in 2014&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c-lead-image__caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A construction worker inside the 86th Street cavern of the Second Avenue Subway tunnel in 2014&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c-lead-image__attribution&quot; itemprop=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;Bebeto Matthews/AP&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;l-article__dek o-small-container&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;It’s not just the Second Avenue Subway: Nearly all urban rail projects in the U.S. cost much more than their European counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;s-article__section o-small-container&quot; id=&quot;article-section-1&quot; readability=&quot;84.689218523878&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late December, &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; published a bombshell article by Brian Rosenthal about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/28/nyregion/new-york-subway-construction-costs.html&quot;&gt;high construction costs on the New York City subway&lt;/a&gt;. Doing painstaking investigative work building on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pedestrianobservations.com/2011/05/16/us-rail-construction-costs/&quot;&gt;a set of numbers I blogged about in 2011&lt;/a&gt;, Rosenthal showed how, at $2.6 billion per mile, New York’s Second Avenue Subway broke records for its costs, and that all of the reasons subway officials offered were excuses. The article documented poor contracting practices, bad management, and union featherbedding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/thisiscitylab&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/posts/2018/01/Facebook_Injector/2af933f8b.png&quot; class=&quot;lazyload&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, what Rosenthal portrays as a New York affliction is in fact a nationwide problem. The construction costs of American rail transit are a multiple of such costs in peer countries, for both subways and light-rail lines. Many U.S. lines that would be easy to justify economically if they cost as much as in France or Sweden are marginal at current American costs. Every city that hopes to expand its transit network should pay closer attention to best industry practices abroad if it wants its investments to be cost-effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much does rail cost?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approximate range of underground rail construction costs in continental Europe and Japan is between $100 million per mile, at the lowest end, and $1 billion at the highest. Most subway lines cluster in the range of $200 million to $500 million per mile; in Amsterdam, a six-mile subway line &lt;a href=&quot;https://nltimes.nl/2017/04/06/first-full-speed-full-length-test-new-amsterdam-subway-ends-successfully&quot;&gt;cost 3.1 billion Euros&lt;/a&gt;, or about $4 billion, after severe cost overruns, delays, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.railjournal.com/index.php/metros/amsterdam-north-south-line-construction-completed.html&quot;&gt;damage to nearby buildings&lt;/a&gt;. The Second Avenue Subway is unique even in the U.S. for its exceptionally high cost, but elsewhere, the picture is grim by European standards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;6.804979253112&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Length&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost/mile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4935064935065&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;San Francisco Central Subway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sf.curbed.com/2017/7/25/16019566/chinatown-san-francisco-central-subway&quot;&gt;$1.57 billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.7 miles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$920 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5063291139241&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los Angeles Regional Connector&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/local/lanow/la-me-ln-regional-connector-budget-20170118-story.html&quot;&gt;$1.75 billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.9 miles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$920 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5975609756098&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los Angeles Purple Line Phases 1-2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/local/california/la-me-westside-subway-20141108-story.html&quot;&gt;$5.2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.railwayage.com/index.php/passenger/rapid-transit/tutor-perini-og-jv-lands-lacmta-purple-line-contract.html?channel=62&quot;&gt;billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5 miles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$800 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5324675324675&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BART to San Jose (proposed)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;83% Underground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vta.org/bart/faqphaseII&quot;&gt;$4.7 billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 miles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$780 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seattle U-Link&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/transportation/university-link-light-rail-service-starts-march-19/&quot;&gt;$1.8 billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 miles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$600 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honolulu Area Rapid Transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elevated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.staradvertiser.com/2017/08/24/breaking-news/caldwell-says-state-lawmakerss-rail-funding-plan-falls-short/&quot;&gt;$10 billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 miles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$500 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4857142857143&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boston Green Line Extension&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trench&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonglobe.com/metro/2017/12/21/feds-cut-big-check-for-green-line-extension/hmWf6jNojH2gP3Jc8DhZlN/story.html&quot;&gt;$2.3 billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.7 miles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$490 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5909090909091&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington Metro Silver Line Phase 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freeway median&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dullesmetro.com/about-dulles-rail/funding/&quot;&gt;$2.8 billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.5 miles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$240 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.55&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atlanta I-20 East Heavy Rail&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freeway median&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itsmarta.com/uploadedfiles/More/Future_and_Current_Projects/Current_Projects/I-20_Corridor/I-20%20East%20Alternatives%20Fact%20Sheets.pdf&quot;&gt;$3.2 billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19.2 miles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$170 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is hard to find exact international comparisons for subway lines running in the medians of freeways. However, it should not be much more difficult to construct such lines than to build light rail. Indeed, in the study for Atlanta’s I-20 East extension, there are options for light rail and bus rapid transit, and the light rail option is only slightly cheaper than the heavy rail option, at $140 million per mile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;s-article__section o-small-container&quot; id=&quot;article-section-2&quot; readability=&quot;51.870967741935&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lists of light-rail lines built in France in recent years can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liste_des_tramways_de_France#Analyse_comparative_du_co%CB%9At&quot;&gt;French Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetransportpolitic.com/transitexplorer/france.html#7/48.027/1.055&quot;&gt;Yonah Freemark’s The Transport Politic&lt;/a&gt;, and in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobilicites.com/011-3880-Un-tramway-a-14-5-millions-du-kilometre-c-est-possible.html&quot;&gt;articles&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sudouest.fr/2016/01/04/bordeaux-voici-le-trace-de-la-ligne-d-du-tramway-2233250-2780.php&quot;&gt;French&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lefigaro.fr/flash-eco/2012/09/01/97002-20120901FILWWW00374-dijon-inaugure-son-tramway.php&quot;&gt;media&lt;/a&gt;. The cheaper lines cost about $40 million per mile, the more expensive ones about $100 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the United States, most recent and in-progress light-rail lines cost more than $100 million per mile. Two light-rail extensions in Minneapolis, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://metrocouncil.org/Transportation/Projects/Current-Projects/METRO-Blue-Line-Extension/Publications-And-Resources/Project-Facts/BLRT-Project-Facts.aspx&quot;&gt;Blue Line Extension&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://metrocouncil.org/Transportation/Projects/Current-Projects/Southwest-LRT.aspx&quot;&gt;Southwest LRT&lt;/a&gt;, cost $120 million and $130 million per mile, respectively. Dallas’ Orange Line light rail, 14 miles long, cost somewhere between &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fhwa.dot.gov/ipd/project_profiles/tx_dart.aspx&quot;&gt;$1.3 billion&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcity.org/daily/entry/an-absurd-transit-duplication-in-dallas&quot;&gt;$1.8 billion&lt;/a&gt;. Portland’s Orange Line &lt;a href=&quot;https://trimet.org/history/orangeline/index.htm&quot;&gt;cost about $200 million per mile&lt;/a&gt;. Houston’s Green and Purple Lines together cost &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.houstonchronicle.com/news/transportation/article/More-trouble-for-rail-lines-as-opening-pushed-to-5762844.php&quot;&gt;$1.3 billion&lt;/a&gt; for about 10 miles of light rail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/posts/2018/01/AP_678864769483/637e60377.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazyload&quot;/&gt;The first Orange Line train carrying passengers across the new Tilikum Crossing bridge in Portland in September 2015 (Timothy J. Gonzalez/AP)
&lt;section class=&quot;s-article__section o-small-container&quot; id=&quot;article-section-3&quot; readability=&quot;87.725252525253&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only a handful of American lines come in cheaper than $100 million per mile, the upper limit for French light rail: For example, a light-rail extension in suburban Phoenix was recently built for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.valleymetro.org/sites/default/files/legacy-images/uploads/prop_photos/CME_ProjectFactSheer_LRT1948_12_5.pdf&quot;&gt;$65 million per mile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spending $900 million per mile on a subway, or $150 million per mile on light rail, may not seem so outrageous compared to New York’s $2.6 billion per-mile subway. But there’s no reason why building subways and light rail in sprawling cities should be as expensive as it is. In Manhattan, the population density and utilities around Second Avenue make it comparable to Paris, London, Berlin, and other older cities with large subway systems that have complex tunnel networks. But San Jose has wide roads and little in the way of older infrastructure, so it is better to compare it with suburban tunnels in Europe, which come near the low end of construction costs. Among the American subway tunnels recently opened or under construction, only the Central Subway in San Francisco, passing deep under the two-level Market Street Subway, has a reason to be costly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Stockholm, construction costs are generally low, but among its &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyatunnelbanan.sll.se/sites/tunnelbanan/files/Faktablad_Upphandling_%20engelsk.pdf&quot;&gt;ongoing subway extensions&lt;/a&gt;, the most suburban one (Barkarby) is the cheapest at about $150 million per mile; an extension underwater (to Nacka) is about $220 million per mile, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20150402164159/http:/www.trafikverket.se/en/startpage/Projects/Railway-construction-projects1/The-Stockholm-City-Line/&quot;&gt;deep commuter rail tunnel under the city center&lt;/a&gt; is about $400 million per mile. Based on the difference in costs within Stockholm, it is likely that if other American cities built a project as complex as the Second Avenue Subway, they would find themselves facing the same costs as the Second Avenue Subway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost per rider&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost-per-mile metric is useful in measuring a city’s ability to build infrastructure efficiently. However, by itself, it does not reveal whether rail investments are socially or economically justified. In order to decide how cost-effective investment is, cities must compare costs with benefits—in this case, ridership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;s-article__section o-small-container&quot; id=&quot;article-section-4&quot; readability=&quot;83.714685314685&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In New York, the Second Avenue Subway, which is only two miles long, is estimated to eventually see 200,000 trips per day, and so far, it seems to be on track to achieving its ridership projection. This is a high figure, achievable only in very dense neighborhoods. The Second Avenue Subway serves segments of the Upper East Side that have among the highest population-density levels in the developed world. With such high intensity of usage, the new line is projected to cost $25,000 per daily rider. The cost-per-rider range for European subways seems to be $10,000 to $25,000, so the Second Avenue Subway is not even an outlier: Its extreme cost is balanced by very high ridership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in other American cities, there is no hope of balancing high cost with ridership in the same way. Even relatively old cities such as Boston and San Francisco have extensive suburban sprawl, and no neighborhood as dense as the Upper East Side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas the Second Avenue Subway will cost about $25,000 per rider if it meets projections, Los Angeles’ Purple Line &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesource.metro.net/2014/11/10/long-wait-is-over-groundbreaking-ceremony-today-for-subway-extension-under-wilshire-boulevard/&quot;&gt;is expected to carry 150,000 riders&lt;/a&gt; across its three phases (and some of this ridership comes from preexisting rather than new stations), which will come out to about $45,000 per rider. Boston’s Green Line Extension is projected to get &lt;a href=&quot;http://greenlineextension.eot.state.ma.us/documents/about/FactSheets/GreenLineEXTFactSheet_F_web.pdf&quot;&gt;52,000 daily riders&lt;/a&gt;, making it about $45,000 per rider as well. But many American light-rail lines have per-rider costs approaching $100,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/posts/2018/01/RTX2QJOO/ef98b5ce7.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazyload&quot;/&gt;A worker on the construction site of the T3 tramway line from Porte de la Chapelle to Porte d’Asnieres in Paris in 2016. (Benoit Tessier/Reuters)
&lt;section class=&quot;s-article__section o-small-container&quot; id=&quot;article-section-5&quot; readability=&quot;54.276923076923&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;By contrast, Parisian tramways, which combine very high ridership and reasonable (though not low) costs, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetransportpolitic.com/2010/01/19/paris-officials-push-huge-suburban-transit-investment-to-increase-metropolitan-mobility/&quot;&gt;are almost all cheaper than $10,000 per rider&lt;/a&gt;, with many around $5,000. Parisian Metro extensions are more expensive, clustering around $10,000 per rider; these balance higher investment costs with lower operating costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;s-article__section o-small-container&quot; id=&quot;article-section-6&quot; readability=&quot;75.312855517634&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Second Avenue Subway would be unbelievably cheap to build in Europe. Other American lines would not be so cheap, but they could still be justifiable, with costs per rider that fall within the European range. The budgets that American cities currently devote to the odd line could fund entire networks of light rail and subway lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are costs so high?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his exposé, Rosenthal talked about labor problems: severe overstaffing, with some workers doing jobs that are no longer necessary, and wages well into six figures. These issues are not exclusive to New York. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.michaelbradydesign.com/Transfer/ACEC%20files/Megaprojects/MP_Ch12.pdf&quot;&gt;chapter in a textbook&lt;/a&gt; about megaproject construction states that “as a result of existing union agreements covering the eastern seaboard area of the United States, underground construction employs approximately four times the number of personnel as in similar jobs in Asia, Australia, or Europe.” European subway construction uses union labor, just like American construction, but the work rules that have accumulated over the decades permit higher productivity and fewer workers doing each task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the problems are not just to do with labor. Working alongside active commuter or intercity rail lines brings a slew of new requirements and regulations. The Green Line Extension is notable for running in a trench next to a commuter rail line, and several Boston-area rail activists told me that a key reason for its high cost is that construction is not permitted to disturb commuter rail service. Another light rail line running alongside commuter rail and Amtrak, San Diego’s Mid-Coast Trolley extension, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.voiceofsandiego.org/topics/government/change-rein-costs-wildly-expensive-mid-coast-trolley-project/&quot;&gt;costs $2.1 billion for 11 miles&lt;/a&gt;; by contrast, &lt;a href=&quot;http://voiceofsandiego.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/50cbd67885fbd.pdf.pdf&quot;&gt;other light rail projects on San Diego’s wishlist&lt;/a&gt; are projected to cost less, about $100 million per mile in 2010 dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;s-article__section o-small-container&quot; id=&quot;article-section-7&quot; readability=&quot;75.894255874674&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In California, the quality of contractors is to blame for some problems. The &lt;em&gt;San Diego Union Tribune&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sandiegouniontribune.com/news/watchdog/sdut-ron-tutor-addressess-high-speed-rail-criticism-2013apr16-htmlstory.html&quot;&gt;ran an article in 2013&lt;/a&gt; focusing on Tutor Perini, which has a pattern of submitting low bids to win public construction contracts but then running over because of change orders and courtroom battles, contributing to an average 40-percent cost overrun in the San Francisco Bay Area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;California’s contractor problem does not seem to be a national one. Jaime Garmendia, a manager at Boston’s MBTA, said, “We would cease to do business with that contractor in a heartbeat.” He put the Green Line Extension’s high cost down to poor project management. Recent changes to the Green Line Extension support that diagnosis. After the transit agency fired the contractor and hired a new general manager to oversee the project, it reduced the budget to $2.3 billion from a previous $3 billion. Of the $2.3 billion price tag, only $1.1 billion is for actual construction, whereas much of the rest is sunk cost is due to the botched earlier version of the extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the solution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly all American urban rail projects cost much more than their European counterparts do. The cheaper ones cost twice as much, and the more expensive ones about seven times as much. The reasons for this are varied: Some arise from the character of the project (unique regulations related to commuter rail), some from state rules (California’s problem with contractors), and some from poor project management (Boston’s Green Line Extension).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;c-related-content u-full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;c-related-content__title&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;s-article__section o-small-container&quot; id=&quot;article-section-8&quot; readability=&quot;67&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of these problems are solvable upon a careful review of what it takes to build a new subway or light-rail line. Boston’s experience in limiting its cost overrun is instructive, and could prove to be a model for other cities. Modernizing work rules to avoid having many redundant employees, as described in detail in Rosenthal's investigation, could also provide savings. If cities overstaff tunnel construction by a factor of four, they could hire the same number of workers to build four times as much tunnel and devote the cost savings to further infrastructure improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States is not doomed to ineffective transit investment. Since many of these problems affect some cities but not others, there is scope for cities to learn best practices from each other. Additionally, the U.S. can look at what other rich countries (such as France and Sweden) do and copy what works. There is no iron curtain between the United States and Western Europe—learning good rail-project management and procurement is well within the grasp of a large urban transit agency. All it takes is the understanding that things are better abroad, and a willingness to learn and do better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;c-authors-article o-small-container&quot;&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;c-authors-article__about-title&quot;&gt;About the Author&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;c-author-article&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot; readability=&quot;16.279411764706&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;c-author-article__content&quot; readability=&quot;20.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;c-author-article__title&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;c-author-article__link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/authors/alon-levy/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'',@href&quot;&gt;Alon Levy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;c-author-article__list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;c-author-article__item&quot;&gt;@&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alon_levy&quot; itemprop=&quot;sameAs&quot;&gt;alon_levy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;c-author-article__item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/feeds/author/alon-levy/&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot;&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;c-author-article__bio&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Based in Paris, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/authors/alon-levy/&quot; class=&quot;author-link&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;Alon Levy&lt;/a&gt; has written about public transit and urbanism at &lt;a href=&quot;http://pedestrianobservations.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pedestrian Observations&lt;/a&gt; since 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 18:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jseliger</dc:creator>
<og:description>Most developed countries can build subways and light rail at a reasonable cost. Not the United States.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.citylab.com/media/img/citylab/2018/01/AP_600095778376/facebook.jpg?1516973583</og:image>
<og:title>Why Does Urban Rail Cost So Much in the U.S.?</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2018/01/why-its-so-expensive-to-build-urban-rail-in-the-us/551408/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2018/01/why-its-so-expensive-to-build-urban-rail-in-the-us/551408/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>LinuxBoot: Linux as Firmware</title>
<link>https://www.linuxboot.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.linuxboot.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tired of reinventing the wheel by implementing drivers for firmware again and again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not with LinuxBoot!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/fb5faff7373a56066d127aac1a207f2bf3d0381b/02f35/images/linuxboot_info.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what&quot;&gt;What?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinuxBoot is a firmware for modern servers that replaces specific firmware functionality like the UEFI DXE phase with a Linux kernel and runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improves boot reliability by replacing lightly-tested firmware drivers with hardened Linux drivers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improves boot time by removing unnecessary code. Typically makes boot 20 times faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows customization of the initrd runtime to support site-specific needs (both device drivers as well as custom executables).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proven approach for almost 20 years in military, consumer electronics, and supercomputing systems – wherever reliability and performance are paramount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;contact&quot;&gt;Contact?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-info&quot;&gt;More info?&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 18:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<og:title>LinuxBoot</og:title>
<og:description>Linux as Firmware Tired of reinventing the wheel by implementing drivers for firmware again and again. Not with LinuxBoot! What? LinuxBoot is a firmware for modern servers that replaces specific firmware functionality like the UEFI DXE phase with a Linux kernel and runtime. Why? Improves boot reliability by replacing lightly-tested firmware drivers with hardened Linux drivers. Improves boot time by removing unnecessary code. Typically makes boot 20 times faster.</og:description>
<og:image>https://linuxboot.org/images/logo.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://linuxboot.org/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.linuxboot.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My new favorite book of all time</title>
<link>https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/Enlightenment-Now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/Enlightenment-Now</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For years, I’ve been saying Steven Pinker’s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/The-Better-Angels-of-Our-Nature&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Better Angels of Our Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; was the best book I’d read in a decade. If I could recommend just one book for anyone to pick up, that was it. Pinker uses meticulous research to argue that we are living in the most peaceful time in human history. I’d never seen such a clear explanation of progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to stop talking up &lt;em&gt;Better Angels&lt;/em&gt; so much, because Pinker has managed to top himself. His new book, &lt;em&gt;Enlightenment Now&lt;/em&gt;, is even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ABVVDSgihYs?rel=0&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enlightenment Now&lt;/em&gt; takes the approach he uses in &lt;em&gt;Better Angels&lt;/em&gt; to track violence throughout history and applies it to 15 different measures of progress (like quality of life, knowledge, and safety). The result is a holistic picture of how and why the world is getting better. It’s like &lt;em&gt;Better Angels&lt;/em&gt; on steroids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pinker was generous enough to send me an early copy, even though &lt;em&gt;Enlightenment Now&lt;/em&gt; won’t be released until the end of February. I read the book slowly since I loved it so much, but I think most people will find it a quick and accessible read. He manages to share a ton of information in a way that’s compelling, memorable, and easy to digest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It opens with an argument in favor of returning to the ideals of the Enlightenment—an era when reason, science, and humanism were touted as the highest virtues. (Gates Notes Insiders can get a preview of this section of the book.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;PinkerCTAHolder&quot; readability=&quot;12.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PinkerCTA_InlineLeft&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com/media/features/books/np_ebook_c2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PinkerCTA_InlineMiddle&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PinkerCTA_InlineMT&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PinkerCTA_InlineMTL&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com/media/features/books/np_ebook_c2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PinkerCTA_InlineMTR&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to read a free chapter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gates Notes Insiders can download an exclusive chapter of Steven Pinker's new book, &lt;em&gt;Enlightenment Now,&lt;/em&gt; for free. Sign up or log in to read it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign Up &amp;amp; Download Chapter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already joined? &lt;span class=&quot;PinkerCTA_InlineSignInClick&quot;&gt;Log in here.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Gates Notes Insider, you have early access to an exclusive chapter of Steven Pinker's new book, &lt;em&gt;Enlightenment Now,&lt;/em&gt; for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download Chapter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PinkerCTA_InlineRight&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com/media/features/books/np_books_c2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;PinkerCTA_SU_Insert_Title&quot;&gt;Please sign up or log in to download the chapter.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;PinkerCTA_SU_Insert_Description&quot;&gt;In order to download an exclusive chapter from &lt;em&gt;Enlightenment Now,&lt;/em&gt; you must be a Gates Notes Insider. You can also &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;PinkerCTA_SU_Insert_Link&quot; class=&quot;PinkerCTA_SU_Insert_Description PinkerCTA_SU_Insert_Link&quot;&gt;go back to the article.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m all for more reason, science, and humanism, but what I found most interesting were the 15 chapters exploring each measure of progress. Pinker is at his best when he analyzes historic trends and uses data to put the past into context. I was already familiar with a lot of the information he shares—especially about health and energy—but he understands each subject so deeply that he’s able to articulate his case in a way that feels fresh and new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love how he’s willing to dive deep into primary data sources and pull out unexpected signs of progress. I tend to point to things like dramatic reductions in poverty and childhood deaths, because I think they’re such a good measure of how we’re doing as a society. Pinker covers those areas, but he also looks at more obscure topics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are five of my favorite facts from the book that show how the world is improving:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’re 37 times less likely to be killed by a bolt of lightning than you were at the turn of the century&lt;/strong&gt;—and that’s not because there are fewer thunderstorms today. It’s because we have better weather prediction capabilities, improved safety education, and more people living in cities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time spent doing laundry fell from 11.5 hours a week in 1920 to an hour and a half in 2014.&lt;/strong&gt; This might sound trivial in the grand scheme of progress. But the rise of the washing machine has improved quality of life by freeing up time for people—mostly women—to enjoy other pursuits. That time represents nearly half a day every week that could be used for everything from binge-watching &lt;em&gt;Ozark&lt;/em&gt; or reading a book to starting a new business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’re way less likely to die on the job.&lt;/strong&gt; Every year, 5,000 people die from occupational accidents in the U.S. But in 1929—when our population was less than two-fifths the size it is today—20,000 people died on the job. People back then viewed deadly workplace accidents as part of the cost of doing business. Today, we know better, and we’ve engineered ways to build things without putting nearly as many lives at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The global average IQ score is rising by about 3 IQ points every decade.&lt;/strong&gt; Kids’ brains are developing more fully thanks to improved nutrition and a cleaner environment. Pinker also credits more analytical thinking in and out of the classroom. Think about how many symbols you interpret every time you check your phone’s home screen or look at a subway map. Our world today encourages abstract thought from a young age, and it’s making us smarter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;War is illegal.&lt;/strong&gt; This idea seems obvious. But before the creation of the United Nations in 1945, no institution had the power to stop countries from going to war with each other. Although there have been some exceptions, the threat of international sanctions and intervention has proven to be an effective deterrent to wars between nations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pinker also tackles the disconnect between actual progress and the perception of progress—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com/About-Bill-Gates/Some-Good-News-For-Once&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;something I’ve spent a lot of time thinking about&lt;/a&gt;. People all over the world are living longer, healthier, and happier lives, so why do so many think things are getting worse? Why do we gloss over positive news stories and fixate on the negative ones? He does a good job explaining why we’re drawn to pessimism and how that instinct influences our approach to the world, although I wish he went more in depth about the psychology (especially since he’s a psychologist by training). The late Hans Rosling explains this more fully in his excellent new book &lt;em&gt;Factfulness&lt;/em&gt;, which I plan to review soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with Pinker on most areas, but I think he’s a bit too optimistic about artificial intelligence. He’s quick to dismiss the idea of robots overthrowing their human creators. While I don’t think we’re in danger of a &lt;em&gt;Terminator-&lt;/em&gt;style scenario, the question underlying that fear—who exactly controls the robots?—is a valid one. We’re not there yet, but at some point, who has AI and who controls it will be an important issue for global institutions to address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big questions surrounding automation are proof that progress can be a messy, sticky thing—but that doesn’t mean we’re headed in the wrong direction. At the end of &lt;em&gt;Enlightenment Now&lt;/em&gt;, Pinker argues that “we will never have a perfect world, and it would be dangerous to seek one. But there is no limit to the betterments we can attain if we continue to apply knowledge to enhance human flourishing.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; getting better, even if it doesn’t always feel that way. I’m glad we have brilliant thinkers like Steven Pinker to help us see the big picture. &lt;em&gt;Enlightenment Now&lt;/em&gt; is not only the best book Pinker’s ever written. It’s my new favorite book of all time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;PrevNextTabsHolder&quot; class=&quot;PrevNextTabsHolder&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;PrevNextTabs_PrevTab&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous Article&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;PrevNextTabs_NextTab&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 16:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yarapavan</dc:creator>
<og:description>Bill Gates reviews “Enlightenment Now” by author Steven Pinker.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.gatesnotes.com/-/media/Images/Books/Enlightenment-Now/enlightenment-now_2018_article_1200px_v2.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>My new favorite book of all time</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/Enlightenment-Now</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/Enlightenment-Now</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>