<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Researcher at center of epic fraud remains an enigma to those who exposed him</title>
<link>http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/08/researcher-center-epic-fraud-remains-enigma-those-who-exposed-him</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/08/researcher-center-epic-fraud-remains-enigma-those-who-exposed-him</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;article__header article__header--inline&quot; readability=&quot;25.1484375&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;byline byline--article&quot;&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/author/kai-kupferschmidt&quot;&gt;Kai Kupferschmidt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;time&gt;Aug. 17, 2018 , 9:15 AM&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JAPAN—&lt;/strong&gt;The first thing that went through Alison Avenell's head when she heard Yoshihiro Sato had died was that it might be a trick. It was March 2017, and in the previous years, Avenell, a clinical nutritionist at the University of Aberdeen in the United Kingdom, had spent thousands of hours combing through Sato's papers, together with three colleagues in New Zealand. They had discovered that Sato, a bone researcher at a hospital in southern Japan, had fabricated data for dozens of clinical trials published in international journals. &quot;With so much going on, so much fabrication, you just wonder if it's convenient for the person to go and hide,&quot; Avenell says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her second thought was that Sato might have killed himself. &quot;We have no indication that he committed suicide, but it concerns us,&quot; Avenell said when I met her at her office in late 2017. Three years earlier, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2014/08/senior-riken-scientist-involved-stem-cell-scandal-commits-suicide&quot;&gt;Japanese stem cell scientist Yoshiki Sasai had hanged himself&lt;/a&gt; in the stairwell of the RIKEN Center for Developmental Biology in Kobe after he was caught up in a stem cell scandal. &quot;We were aware of the culture in Japan and the dishonor something like this could bring,&quot; Avenell said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was one more mystery in a deeply unsettling case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sato's fraud was one of the biggest in scientific history. The impact of his fabricated reports—many of them on how to reduce the risk of bone fractures—rippled far and wide. Meta-analyses that included his trials came to the wrong conclusion; professional societies based medical guidelines on his papers. To follow up on studies they did not know were faked, researchers carried out new trials that enrolled thousands of real patients. Exposing Sato's lies and correcting the literature had been a bruising struggle for Avenell and her colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet they could not understand why Sato faked so many studies, or how he got away with it for so long. They puzzled over the role of his co-authors, some of whom had their names on dozens of his papers. (&quot;Do we honestly believe they knew nothing at all about what was going on?&quot; Avenell asked.) They wondered whether other doctors at his hospital read Sato's work—and whether the Japanese scientific community ever questioned how he managed to publish more than 200 papers, many of them ambitious studies that would have taken most researchers years to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tools of science that the group had used—analyzing studies, calculating statistics, writing papers—could reveal fraud. But they could not expose the personal and cultural factors that drove it, or assess its emotional toll. So I set off on a quest that would eventually lead me to the Mitate Hospital in Tagawa, a small town on the island of Kyushu, where Sato had worked in the last 13 years of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I: Suspicion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avenell's own quest began in 2006, when she was combing through dozens of papers for a review evaluating whether vitamin D reduces the risk of bone fractures. In two papers by Sato, she stumbled on a weird coincidence. They described different trials—one in stroke victims, the other in Parkinson's disease patients—but the control and study groups in both studies had the exact same mean body mass index. Looking further, she quickly found several other anomalies. She decided not to include Sato's studies in her analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wasn't the first to notice something was off. In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://n.neurology.org/content/64/5/811.long&quot;&gt;2005 &lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt; paper&lt;/a&gt;, Sato claimed that a drug named risedronate reduces the risk of hip fractures in women who have had a stroke by a stunning 86%. In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://n.neurology.org/content/65/9/1513.full&quot;&gt;polite letter to the journal&lt;/a&gt;, three researchers from the University of Cambridge in the United Kingdom noted that the study was &quot;potentially of great importance,&quot; but marveled that the authors had managed to recruit 374 patients in just 4 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the number of papers he published, he must have spent a very large amount of time on them. I don't understand what his gain was. … There must have been some reason to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;Mark Bolland, University of Auckland&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years later, a letter in what was then the &lt;em&gt;Archives of Internal Medicine&lt;/em&gt; was less polite. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/765620?resultClick=1&quot;&gt;A study of male stroke patients published by Sato&lt;/a&gt; had managed to enroll 280 patients in just 2 months; another one, of &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/765639?resultClick=1&quot;&gt;women with Alzheimer's disease&lt;/a&gt;, recruited a staggering 500 in an equally short period. Sato claimed to have diagnosed all of the Alzheimer's patients himself and done follow-up assessments of all 780 patients every 4 weeks for 18 months. Both studies had very few dropouts, and both showed risedronate, again, to be a resounding success. &quot;We are deeply concerned whether the data provided by Sato et al are valid,&quot; Jutta Halbekath of &lt;em&gt;Arznei-Telegramm&lt;/em&gt;, a Berlin-based bulletin about the drug industry, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/article-abstract/411829&quot;&gt;and her co-authors wrote&lt;/a&gt;. Sato apologized in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/article-abstract/411832?resultClick=1&quot;&gt;published response&lt;/a&gt; and claimed the study had been conducted at three hospitals, not one. &quot;The authors did not describe this fact, the reason being that these hospitals were reluctant to have their names in the article,&quot; he wrote. He didn't name the other hospitals or explain why they wanted to remain anonymous. The journal apparently accepted the explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The letter's authors also spotted a troubling pattern. In addition to the two papers in the &lt;em&gt;Archives of Internal Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, they found 11 further studies by Sato, published elsewhere, that tested whether sunlight, vitamin D, vitamin K, folate, and other drugs could reduce the risk of hip fractures. All but two reported &quot;extremely large effects with significant results,&quot; they noted. But the &lt;em&gt;Archives of Internal Medicine&lt;/em&gt; didn't want to point fingers at other journals. &quot;You may allude to your concern that other papers have similar concerns,&quot; its editors warned Halbekath, &quot;but we cannot allow you to mention those other papers by journal name.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, several researchers had raised red flags and waved them for everyone to see—and then everybody moved on. &quot;The trail just went cold,&quot; Avenell says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II: Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Bolland had never heard of Sato when Avenell first mentioned him in late 2012. She and Bolland, a clinical epidemiologist at the University of Auckland in New Zealand, have never met in person, but they joined forces to write meta-analyses on calcium supplements in 2008, together with Andrew Grey and Greg Gamble, both also at the University of Auckland. One topic the quartet discussed frequently was why meta-analyses on the same topic sometimes reach different conclusions. Avenell mentioned Sato's studies and noted that the effects they reported were so strong that they might swing meta-analyses if they were included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intrigued, Bolland looked up the papers. He, too, was stunned by the large cohorts, the low number of dropouts, and the big effects of almost any treatment tested. &quot;There is nothing that I can think of that produces a 70% to 80% reduction in hip fractures, yet Sato was able to do it consistently in all his trials,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow up on his suspicions, Bolland turned to statistics. When scientists compare a treatment and a control group, they usually report &quot;baseline characteristics&quot; for each—things like age, weight, and sex, or, in osteoporosis studies, bone density and calcium intake. From these values, scientists can calculate p-values that are a measure of the similarity of two groups for a given characteristic; the closer to one the value is, the more the groups resemble each other. Because the groups are randomly selected, the p-values should normally be &quot;equally distributed&quot;; the value for age or weight is just as likely to be between 0 and 0.1 as between 0.9 and 1.0, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Included in systematic reviews, meta-analyses, or treatment guidelines Did not change the outcome Unclear whether outcome changed Changed the outcome Used as (partial) rationale for a new trial 2002 1998 2006 2010 2014 2018 Number of citations by year Trial published Number of patients 628 84 Retracted 32 A 2006 paper on hip fractures in Parkinson’s patients was cited as evidence behind 2008 U.S. College of Physicians treatment guidelines. Other scientists cited a 2005 paper in The Journal of the American Medical Association to help justify five new trials. 0 10 20 0 10 20 0 10 20 Number of papers 0 10 20 30 Total scientific output Clinical trials 1996 2000 2004 2008 2012 Number of patients 0 100 200 300 400 500 600 700 1980 1990 2000 2010 2015 Retracted Not retracted A far-reaching fraud A team of four researchers has worked since 2012 to expose scientific misconduct by Japanese bone researcher Yoshihiro Sato, who published more than 200 papers before he died in 2016. The team has focused on Sato’s 33 clinical trials, together involving 5894 patients. Ripple effects The 12 trials Sato published in high-impact journals have been widely cited. Many were included in meta- analyses, sometimes changing the outcomes, or were translated into treatment guidelines. Other researchers used Sato’s fake data as part of the rationale for launching new clinical studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(GRAPHIC) J. YOU/&lt;em&gt;SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;; (DATA) F. STEWART, A. AVENELL, A. GREY, G. GAMBLE, AND M. BOLLAND; WEB OF SCIENCE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolland extracted the baseline characteristics from the 33 clinical trials Sato had published at the time, more than 500 variables all in all, and calculated their p-values. More than half were above 0.8, he found. &quot;That just shouldn't happen,&quot; he says. &quot;The randomized groups were incredibly similar.&quot; There was just one plausible explanation, he says: Sato had fabricated data for both groups and had made them more similar than they would ever be in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team felt it had a damning indictment. &quot;I thought: ‘This is so convincing. Everybody is going to believe this,’&quot; Avenell says. Still, &quot;It needed detailed statistical refereeing, and it needed to be published by a journal so that other affected journals would take note,&quot; she adds. So they wrote their accusation as a scientific paper. All they had to do was publish it and wait for researchers, journals, and institutions to react, investigate, and retract. Or so they thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III: Accusation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2013, the team submitted the manuscript to &lt;em&gt;The Journal of the American Medical Association&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt;), the highest profile journal &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/200453&quot;&gt;Sato had published in&lt;/a&gt;, and one it felt might have the resources for an in-depth investigation. After reviewing the evidence, &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt; Editor-in-Chief Howard Bauchner told the team the editors would ask Sato and, if necessary, his institution to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years later, in April 2015, &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt; told the researchers the hospital had not responded, and it would publish an &quot;expression of concern&quot;—a short note to flag Sato's &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt; paper as suspicious. It would not publish the whistleblowers' paper, however; if the team had concerns about other papers, it should contact the journals that had published them, Bauchner said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four researchers were shocked. &quot;To find out after waiting 2 years that in fact nothing much had really happened and, other than an expression of concern, was going to happen in &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt;, was quite frustrating,&quot; Bolland says. (Bauchner declined to answer &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;'s questions about the case.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the paper was rejected by &lt;em&gt;JAMA Internal Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, which had also published Sato's work. The &lt;em&gt;Journal of Bone and Mineral Research&lt;/em&gt;, a highly rated journal in the osteoporosis field, said it would investigate Sato's papers, but would not publish the manuscript either. The editors of &lt;em&gt;Trials&lt;/em&gt;, which had not published Sato's work, said it would not be appropriate to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolland became demoralized. The other three persuaded him not to give up. &quot;If you ever embark on something like this, make sure you have a good support team,&quot; he says now. Avenell, too, was sometimes despondent. Whereas the other three researchers at least saw each other in Auckland, she was on her own, frustrated, in the dreary, gray town of Aberdeen. Sometimes, she says, she would just sit in a corner of her open floor plan office and cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journals don’t really like going back to investigate when things go wrong. …They complain that it’s time-consuming and laborious and difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;Andrew Grey, University of Auckland&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, in June 2015, came a small success: The &lt;em&gt;Journal of Bone and Mineral Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jbmr.2725&quot;&gt;retracted one of the 33 trials&lt;/a&gt; the team had analyzed. A few other journals followed suit in the months after. But some seemed irritated by the group's persistence. &quot;It is apparent that the responses to the &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt; investigation by Dr. Sato and his institution have been either inadequate or not forthcoming,&quot; Grey wrote to Bauchner in December 2015. &quot;At what point will &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt; consider more decisive action, such as retraction?&quot; &quot;We will consider your opinion about how you think it best we should conduct the investigation,&quot; Bauchner responded. &quot;We often hear from people how they think we should perform our responsibilities as editors.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what Bolland calls &quot;really just the last throw of the dice,&quot; that same month the group submitted the paper to &lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt;, where Sato had published three papers about bone fractures in patients with neurological disease. When it was accepted 8 months later, Avenell cried again. &quot;I'm not one usually given to showing such emotion, especially when all I have is a computer screen and emails to look at,&quot; she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Journals don't really like going back to investigate when things go wrong,&quot; Grey concludes. &quot;They complain that it's time-consuming and laborious and difficult.&quot; (It is all of that, says Avenell, &quot;and no one ever thanks you for it.&quot;) The group says investigations of this scale should not be handled by journals or institutions; it has suggested a levy on journals to fund an independent investigative body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time &lt;a href=&quot;http://n.neurology.org/content/early/2016/11/09/WNL.0000000000003387&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt; published the investigation in December 2016&lt;/a&gt;, 10 of the 33 trials had been retracted, all but one by journals the team had contacted. One month later, Avenell received an email from an editor with troubling news. Sato was dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IV: Ripples&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When scientists die, their published papers live on—even if they're based on lies. Downloaded in seconds from anywhere in the world, fake results continue to steal other scientists' time, influencing their choice of which research avenues to follow and which trials to design and seek ethical approval for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, 21 of Sato's 33 trials have been retracted by the journals or Sato himself; Avenell has crossed them off a list taped next to her computer with a red marker. But now the team is following the ripples that the studies caused, focusing, for the time being, on a dozen papers published in the journals with the highest impact factors. Together, these studies reported results for 3182 participants. They have been referenced more than 1000 times, and 23 systematic reviews or meta-analyses have included one or more of the 12 trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strokejournal.org/article/S1052-3057(14)00304-8/pdf&quot;&gt;One meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt;, which found drugs called bisphosphonates to be highly effective in preventing hip fractures in elderly patients with stroke or Parkinson's, is based entirely on eight trials from Sato, as he was the only one to study the issue. A key conclusion &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hindawi.com/journals/tswj/2012/872173/&quot;&gt;in another meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; rests only on Sato's four studies on bone mineral density in Alzheimer's patients. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/410550&quot;&gt;Two other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mdpi.com/2072-6643/7/5/3322&quot;&gt;meta-analyses&lt;/a&gt; would probably come to different conclusions if Sato's trials were removed, Avenell says. One of those, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/410550&quot;&gt;review showing that vitamin K helps prevent fractures&lt;/a&gt;, was the basis of &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs11657-012-0109-9&quot;&gt;2011 Japanese guidelines&lt;/a&gt; that recommend the supplement for people at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fake trials led to further, real research. Eight trials referenced at least one of Sato's fabricated papers in explaining the rationale for the trial. Researchers in the Netherlands, for instance, launched a huge study in 2008 to determine whether B vitamins could help prevent hip fractures. Two previous studies found they didn't, but Sato had observed &quot;a large protective effect&quot; in elderly women. &quot;Given the conflicting results and low generalizability to the general older population, further investigation is needed,&quot; the Dutch researchers wrote to explain their thinking. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/ajcn/article/100/6/1578/4576655&quot;&gt;2-year study in 2919 elderly people found no effect of the vitamins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;The fraud has also drawn attention to the two co-authors whose names appear on Sato's papers most often. One is Kei Satoh, president of Hirosaki University, in a small town at the northern tip of Japan's main island, Honshu. Sato worked at Hirosaki University, where he collaborated with Satoh, until 2003; even after he left for Mitate Hospital, 1600 kilometers to the southwest, he and Satoh remained frequent co-authors, including on 13 of the 33 clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entity entity-paragraphs-item paragraphs-item-image align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure__head&quot;&gt;&lt;img sizes=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/350SecondaryIllustration_HiRes.jpg?itok=QVIYOzrq&quot; srcset=&quot;//www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/350SecondaryIllustration_HiRes.jpg?itok=QVIYOzrq 1w, //www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__699w__no_aspect/public/350SecondaryIllustration_HiRes.jpg?itok=OnDasTFN 700w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;SARA GIRONI CARNEVALE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Satoh—whose name, confusingly, is sometimes spelled Sato—did not respond to &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;'s emails. In a short letter to Grey, Hirosaki University Vice President Chizuko Kohri wrote last November that the university had asked &quot;three outside experts&quot; to investigate after the &lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt; paper was published. The committee investigated 38 papers, Kohri wrote. Of these, Sato had already retracted seven and wanted to retract another seven. The committee &quot;concluded that there was research misconduct in these 14 papers,&quot; Kohri wrote, but that Sato alone was responsible. According to Japanese press reports, Satoh maintains that he only corrected the English in the papers. As a sign of contrition, he gave up 10% of his salary for 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Sato's most important collaborator, however, was Jun Iwamoto. A board member of the Osteoporosis Society of Japan, Iwamoto was a senior lecturer at Keio University in Tokyo—one of the country's most prestigious—until 2017, when his contract wasn't renewed in the wake of the Sato affair. He and Sato collaborated for more than a decade and published more than 130 papers together, including 25 of the 33 clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;A panel at Keio University has been investigating Iwamoto's clinical trials. Iwamoto told the panel that he first contacted Sato in 1998, when Iwamoto was working at the New York University Winthrop Hospital in Mineola. In 2002 they started to put each other's name on every paper they authored. Still, Iwamoto claims he was unaware of Sato's practice. &quot;We talked to Dr. Iwamoto and in most of the papers which Dr. Sato published, which included Dr. Iwamoto's name, Dr. Iwamoto did not know that his name was included,&quot; says cancer researcher Hideyuki Saya, who heads the investigation. The panel was &quot;very shocked&quot; by this, Saya says. At the same time, he says, &quot;For Dr. Iwamoto it was an honor to put his name on Dr. Sato's [papers] even though he did not know much about the content.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Although considered highly irregular today, such &quot;gift authorships&quot; were common in the recent past, Saya argues. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/ijjs.12016&quot;&gt;2014 study in the &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Japanese Sociology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; found they are particularly common in Japan. &quot;We speculate that most natural science researchers in Japan may be either confused about or struggle with the situation where the strict global criteria conflict with specific local cultures that often condone gift and ghost authorships,&quot; the researchers wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Saya says the seven trials listing Iwamoto as the first author appear not to be fabricated. Data for the first four of those no longer exist, but Iwamoto can't be faulted for that, says Saya, because under rules at the time they were conducted, he had to save the data for only 5 years. Iwamoto did provide data for three more recent trials. &quot;That data, it seems, was really collected,&quot; Saya says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;But Avenell and her colleagues say they have uncovered many problems in trials on which Iwamoto was a first author as well. For instance, two of them, which tested a drug named alendronate, seem to include the same group of 25 patients, as indicated by their average age, height, serum calcium, and numerous other characteristics, but the two papers give different recruitment dates and inclusion criteria, and some of the outcome data differ. Saya chalks problems in the papers up to &quot;immaturity.&quot; &quot;We do not think there is fabrication,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Iwamoto now works at another hospital, Saya says. &quot;He has a very nice reputation.&quot; When I mention that I would like to talk to him, he suggests I should not. &quot;He is very exhausted,&quot; he says. &quot;Better not to contact him at this moment.&quot; Otherwise &quot;the same thing&quot; might happen that happened with Sato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&quot;What happened with Sato?&quot; I ask. &quot;People say he committed suicide over this,&quot; Saya says. But he doesn't know whether that's true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V: Enigma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Sato's fraudulent work has propelled him to No. 6 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/the-retraction-watch-leaderboard/&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch's list of researchers who have racked up the most retractions&lt;/a&gt;. At the top is Japanese anesthesiologist Yoshitaka Fujii, with 183 retractions; his frequent co-author Yuhji Saitoh, also from Japan, is at 10th place, while Japanese endocrinologist Shigeaki Kato is No. 8. Iwamoto is at No. 9. That means half of the top 10 are Japanese researchers. Yet only about 5% of published research comes from Japan. What explains the number of prolific Japanese fraudsters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Michiie Sakamoto, who is leading another investigation at Keio University, into Iwamoto's studies in animals, says it has to do with respect. &quot;In Japan, we don't usually doubt a professor,&quot; he says. &quot;We basically believe people. We think we don't need strict rules to watch them carefully.&quot; As a result, researchers faking their results may be exposed only after they have racked up many publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Outside researchers may also be less likely to question anomalous results from Japan. Several early critics of Sato's work say they thought at first that his unusual results might be due to something uniquely Japanese. One case in point: In 2003, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1738449/&quot;&gt;Sato published a study&lt;/a&gt; on data from 40 patients with a very rare affliction named neuroleptic malignant syndrome, collected over 3 years. In a letter to the journal, a U.K. neurologist said he and his colleagues &quot;could only recall two such cases in living memory&quot;—but instead of casting doubt on the study, they said it was interesting that the syndrome seemed so prevalent in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Japan, we don’t usually doubt a professor. We basically believe people. We think we don’t need strict rules to watch them carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;Michiie Sakamoto, Keio University&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But none of that explains why Sato decided to embark on his fraud—and nobody seems to be able to shed much light on that question. &quot;Given the number of papers he published, he must have spent a very large amount of time on them,&quot; Bolland says. &quot;I don't understand what his gain was. … There must have been some reason to do it.&quot; The Keio University panel is just as puzzled. &quot;We discussed this a lot in the committee,&quot; Saya says. It might have been like a hobby, he suggests. A thrill. Saya uses the word &quot;&lt;em&gt;otaku&lt;/em&gt;,&quot; a Japanese term often applied to people who read manga obsessively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I might find more clarity at the place where Sato perpetrated the fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitate Hospital is not known for its scientific excellence. Except for one 2006 paper on schizophrenia, its entire research output over the past 20 years was produced by Sato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hospital is a sprawling complex of beige buildings set against green hills. I walk up to the reception. It's quiet, no patients in sight. The receptionist does not understand me and asks me to write down what I want to say. &quot;I am a journalist,&quot; I write. &quot;I would like to talk to the director about Yoshihiro Sato.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her eyes widen as she reads the name and she calls a nurse who speaks English. The nurse calls the director. &quot;He does not want to talk to you,&quot; she says after she hangs up. We stand awkwardly next to each at the reception desk, both embarrassed. It is clear that everybody wants me to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I walk back to the bus stop I look back at the hospital. It is an unlikely place for an unlikely story. What did people here think about the research superstar in their midst? What do they remember about the man?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effects of Sato's fraud are still rippling out: citations, retractions, investigations. But the place at the epicenter of the disaster reveals nothing. Mitate Hospital squats silently in the midday sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VI: Epilogue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hours before I leave Japan, I meet Iwamoto's lawyer, Satoshi Ogawa. We sit in the lobby of my Tokyo hotel, our words echoing from the bare walls and the marble floor. Ogawa says Iwamoto agreed to our conversation because he wants me to understand his point of view. &quot;From his perspective, he is a victim.&quot; Avenell's team, says Ogawa, is now giving Iwamoto's papers a level of scrutiny that is unfair and is causing his client a great deal of distress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ogawa says Sato wrote a detailed account of his interactions with Iwamoto a year before he died. He shows me an English version of the document, signed by Sato and witnessed by Ogawa and a notary. &quot;I strongly requested Mr. Iwamoto to include my name as an author on the articles for which Mr. Iwamoto was the lead author,&quot; Sato wrote. &quot;I also started including Mr. Iwamoto's name in the articles for which I myself was the lead author.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The letter does not mention fraud, however. &quot;I couldn't force him to confess,&quot; Ogawa says. &quot;I think he had a mental illness.&quot; His emails were not logical, he says. &quot;To tell the truth, I predicted that he would commit suicide.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Suicide.&lt;/em&gt; Is he sure that's what happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I received the information from the lawyer of Mr. Sato,&quot; Ogawa says. Sato also left a note, he says, and he paraphrases it: &quot;I am very sorry for Mr. Iwamoto. I decided to commit suicide.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I call Avenell after my return from Japan and tell her what I have learned, there is stunned silence at first. &quot;That's what we were dreading,&quot; she says. &quot;That's horrible, really horrible.&quot; Exposing the misconduct was important, she says. &quot;Could we have done it without Sato committing suicide? So that he felt less guilty? I just don't know.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later she follows up with an email, still astonished at &quot;how such a small piece of data analysis a long time ago can end up with someone dying.&quot; As a clinician and a researcher, Avenell wrote, she knows her work can eventually make the difference between life and death. &quot;But seldom is the connection between a clinician and another human being's death so obvious.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 19:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>maxerickson</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/08/researcher-center-epic-fraud-remains-enigma-those-who-exposed-him</og:url>
<og:title>Researcher at the center of an epic fraud remains an enigma to those who exposed him</og:title>
<og:description>After years of detective work, it's still unclear why a Japanese doctor faked dozens of clinical trials</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/article_main_large/public/720MainIllustration_HiRes.jpg?itok=uTr6RdeD</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/08/researcher-center-epic-fraud-remains-enigma-those-who-exposed-him</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The new MacBook Pros with T2 chips do indeed kernel panic randomly</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/bdkjones/status/1030140659729133568</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/bdkjones/status/1030140659729133568</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Your tweet says &quot;MacBook Pros&quot;. Plural. I assume that means you have successfully replicated this error on other machines. Right? And I assume you did a full macOS reinstall to see if the problem went away before trumpeting to the entire world. Right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 19:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>miles</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/bdkjones/status/1030140659729133568</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>HUD Files Housing Discrimination Complaint Against Facebook</title>
<link>https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/HUD_No_18_085</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/HUD_No_18_085</guid>
<description>&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;4&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;HUD No. 18-085&lt;br/&gt;HUD Public Affairs&lt;br/&gt;(202) 708-0685&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR RELEASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Friday&lt;br/&gt;August 17, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HUD FILES HOUSING DISCRIMINATION COMPLAINT AGAINST FACEBOOK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Secretary-initiated complaint alleges platform allows advertisers to discriminate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON – The U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) announced today a formal complaint against Facebook for violating the Fair Housing Act by allowing landlords and home sellers to use its advertising platform to engage in housing discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HUD claims Facebook enables advertisers to control which users receive housing-related ads based upon the recipient's race, color, religion, sex, familial status, national origin, disability, and/or zip code. Facebook then invites advertisers to express unlawful preferences by offering discriminatory options, allowing them to effectively limit housing options for these protected classes under the guise of 'targeted advertising.' &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/PIH/documents/HUD_01-18-0323_Complaint.pdf&quot;&gt;Read HUD's complaint against Facebook.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Fair Housing Act prohibits housing discrimination including those who might limit or deny housing options with a click of a mouse,&quot; said Anna María Farías, HUD's Assistant Secretary for Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity. &quot;When Facebook uses the vast amount of personal data it collects to help advertisers to discriminate, it's the same as slamming the door in someone's face.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fair Housing Act prohibits discrimination in housing transactions including print and online advertisement on the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, sex, disability, or familial status. HUD's Secretary-initiated complaint follows the Department's investigation into Facebook's advertising platform which includes targeting tools that enable advertisers to filter prospective tenants or homebuyers based on these protected classes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, HUD's complaint alleges Facebook's platform violates the Fair Housing Act. It enables advertisers to, among other things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;display housing ads either only to men or women;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not show ads to Facebook users interested in an &quot;assistance dog,&quot; &quot;mobility scooter,&quot; &quot;accessibility&quot; or &quot;deaf culture&quot;;   &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not show ads to users whom Facebook categorizes as interested in &quot;child care&quot; or &quot;parenting,&quot; or show ads only to users with children above a specified age;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to display/not display ads to users whom Facebook categorizes as interested in a particular place of worship, religion or tenet, such as the &quot;Christian Church,&quot; &quot;Sikhism,&quot; &quot;Hinduism,&quot; or the &quot;Bible.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not show ads to users whom Facebook categorizes as interested in &quot;Latin America,&quot; &quot;Canada,&quot; &quot;Southeast Asia,&quot; &quot;China,&quot; &quot;Honduras,&quot; or &quot;Somalia.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;draw a red line around zip codes and then not display ads to Facebook users who live in specific zip codes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Facebook promotes its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/business/success/quadrant-homes&quot;&gt;advertising targeting platform for housing purposes with &quot;success stories&lt;/a&gt;&quot; for finding &quot;the perfect homeowners,&quot; &quot;reaching home buyers,&quot; &quot;attracting renters&quot; and &quot;personalizing property ads.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, today the U.S. Attorney for the Southern District of New York (SDNY) filed a statement of interest, joined in by HUD, in U.S. District Court on behalf of a number of private litigants challenging Facebook's advertising platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;HUD Secretary-Initiated Complaints&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secretary of HUD may file a fair housing complaint directly against those whom the Department believes may be in violation of the Fair Housing Act. Secretary-Initiated Complaints are appropriate in cases, among others, involving significant issues that are national in scope or when the Department is made aware of potential violations of the Act and broad public interest relief is warranted or where HUD does not know of a specific aggrieved person or injured party that is willing or able to come forward. A Fair Housing Act complaint, including a Secretary initiated complaint, is not a determination of liability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Secretary-Initiated Complaint will result in a formal fact-finding investigation. The party against whom the complaint is filed will be provided notice and an opportunity to respond. If HUD's investigation results in a determination that reasonable cause exists that there has been a violation of the Fair Housing Act, a charge of discrimination may be filed. Throughout the process, HUD will seek conciliation and voluntary resolution. Charges may be resolved through settlement, through referral to the Department of Justice, or through an administrative determination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year marks the 50th anniversary of the Fair Housing Act. In commemoration, HUD, local communities, and fair housing organizations across the country have coordinated a variety of activities to enhance fair housing awareness, highlight HUD's fair housing enforcement efforts, and end housing discrimination in the nation. For a list of activities, log onto &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hud.gov/fairhousingis50&quot;&gt;www.hud.gov/fairhousingis50&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persons who believe they have experienced discrimination may file a complaint by contacting HUD's Office of Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity at (800) 669-9777 (voice) or (800) 927-9275 (TTY).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 19:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>google_censors</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/HUD_No_18_085</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stacking concrete blocks is a surprisingly efficient way to store energy</title>
<link>https://qz.com/1355672/stacking-concrete-blocks-is-a-surprisingly-efficient-way-to-store-energy/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://qz.com/1355672/stacking-concrete-blocks-is-a-surprisingly-efficient-way-to-store-energy/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Thanks to the modern electric grid, you have access to electricity whenever you want. But the grid only works when electricity is generated in the same amounts as it is consumed. That said, it’s impossible to get the balance right all the time. So operators make grids more flexible by adding ways to store excess electricity for when production drops or consumption rises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;About 96% of the world’s energy-storage capacity comes in the form of one technology: pumped hydro. Whenever generation exceeds demand, the excess electricity is used to pump water up a dam. When demand exceeds generation, that water is allowed to fall—thanks to gravity—and the potential energy turns turbines to produce electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;But pumped-hydro storage requires particular geographies, with access to water and to reservoirs at different altitudes. It’s the reason that about three-quarters of all pumped hydro storage has been built &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1295901/why-energy-storage-is-key-to-a-global-climate-breakthrough/&quot;&gt;in only 10 countries&lt;/a&gt;. The trouble is the world needs to add a lot more energy storage, if we are to continue to add the intermittent solar and wind power necessary to cut our dependence on fossil fuels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;A startup called Energy Vault thinks it has a viable alternative to pumped-hydro: Instead of using water and dams, the startup uses concrete blocks and cranes. It has been operating in stealth mode until today (Aug. 18), when its existence will be announced at &lt;a href=&quot;https://kentpresents.org/&quot;&gt;Kent Presents&lt;/a&gt;, an ideas festival in Connecticut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;On a hot July morning, I traveled to Biasca, Switzerland, about two hours north of Milan, Italy, where Energy Vault has built a demonstration plant, about a tenth the size of a full-scale operation. The whole thing—from idea to a functional unit—took about nine months and less than $2 million to accomplish. If this sort of low-tech, low-cost innovation could help solve even just a few parts of the huge energy-storage problem, maybe the energy transition the world needs won’t be so hard after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;🌍&lt;em&gt; Quartz is running a series called The Race to Zero Emissions that explores the challenges and opportunities of energy-storage technologies. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2ioY0AA&quot;&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt; to be the first to know when stories are published.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;container _5e420 quartz&quot;&gt;Concrete plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;The science underlying Energy Vault’s technology is simple. When you lift something against gravity, you &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1302711/to-hit-climate-goals-bill-gates-and-his-billionaire-friends-are-betting-on-energy-storage/&quot;&gt;store energy in it&lt;/a&gt;. When you later let it fall, you can retrieve that energy. Because concrete is a lot denser than water, lifting a block of concrete requires—and can, therefore, store—a lot more energy than an equal-sized tank of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Bill Gross, a long-time US entrepreneur, and Andrea Pedretti, a serial Swiss inventor, developed the Energy Vault system that applies this science. Here’s how it works: A 120-meter (nearly 400-foot) tall, six-armed crane stands in the middle. In the discharged state, concrete cylinders weighing 35 metric tons each are neatly stacked around the crane far below the crane arms. When there is excess solar or wind power, a computer algorithm directs one or more crane arms to locate a concrete block, with the help of a camera attached to the crane arm’s trolley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_5fc35 quartz&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_83471&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/energy-vault-landscape_colorcorrected.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=940&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy Vault&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Simulation of a large-scale Energy Vault plant.
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Once the crane arm locates and hooks onto a concrete block, a motor starts, powered by the excess electricity on the grid, and lifts the block off the ground. Wind could cause the block to move like a pendulum, but the crane’s trolley is programmed to counter the movement. As a result, it can smoothly lift the block, and then place it on top of another stack of blocks—higher up off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;The system is “fully charged” when the crane has created a tower of concrete blocks around it. The total energy that can be stored in the tower is 20 megawatt-hours (MWh), enough to power 2,000 Swiss homes for a whole day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;When the grid is running low, the motors spring back into action—except now, instead of consuming electricity, the motor is driven in reverse by the gravitational energy, and thus generates electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;container _5e420 quartz&quot;&gt;Big up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;The innovation in Energy Vault’s plant is not the hardware. Cranes and motors have been around for decades, and companies like ABB and Siemens have optimized them for maximum efficiency. The round-trip efficiency of the system, which is the amount of energy recovered for every unit of energy used to lift the blocks, is about 85%—comparable to lithium-ion batteries which offer upto 90%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Pedretti’s main work as the chief technology officer has been figuring out how to design software to automate contextually relevant operations, like hooking and unhooking concrete blocks, and to counteract pendulum-like movements during the lifting and lowering of those blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Energy Vault keeps costs low because it uses off-the-shelf commercial hardware. Surprisingly, concrete blocks could prove to be the most expensive part of the energy tower. Concrete is much cheaper than, say, a lithium-ion battery, but Energy Vault would need a lot of concrete to build hundreds of 35-metric-ton blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;So Pedretti found another solution. He’s developed a machine that can mix substances that cities often pay to get rid off, such as gravel or building waste, along with cement to create low-cost concrete blocks. The cost saving comes from having to use only a sixth of the amount of cement that would otherwise have been needed if the concrete were used for building construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_5fc35 quartz&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_83471&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/andre-pedretti-energy-vault-rob-piconi.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=940&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akshat Rathi for Quartz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Rob Piconi (left) and Andrea Pedretti.
&lt;h2 class=&quot;container _5e420 quartz&quot;&gt;The storage challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;The demonstration plant I saw in Biasca is much smaller than the planned commercial version. It has a 20-meter-tall, single-armed crane that lifts blocks weighing 500 kg each. But it does almost all the things its full-scale cousin, which the company is actively looking to sell right now, would do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Robert Piconi has spent this summer visiting countries in Africa and Asia. The CEO of Energy Vault is excited to find customers for its plants in those parts of the world. The startup also has a sales team in the US and it now has orders to build its first commercial units in early 2019. The company won’t share details of those orders, but the unique characteristics of its energy-storage solution mean we can make a fairly educated guess at what the projects will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Energy-storage experts broadly categorize energy-storage into three groups, distinguished by the amount of energy storage needed and the cost of storing that energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;First, expensive technologies, such as lithium-ion batteries, can be used to store a few hours worth of energy—in the range of tens or hundreds of MWh. These could be charged during the day, using solar panels for example, and then discharged when the sun isn’t around. But lithium-ion batteries for the electric grid &lt;a href=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=1355672&amp;amp;action=edit&quot;&gt;currently cost&lt;/a&gt; between $280 and $350 per kWh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Cheaper technologies, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1302711/to-hit-climate-goals-bill-gates-and-his-billionaire-friends-are-betting-on-energy-storage/&quot;&gt;flow batteries&lt;/a&gt; (which use high-energy liquid chemicals to hold energy) can be used to store weeks worth of energy—in the range of hundreds or thousands of MWh. This second category of energy storage could then be used, for instance, when there’s a lull in wind supply for a week or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;The third category doesn’t exist yet. In theory, yet-to-be-invented, extra-cheap technologies could store months worth of energy—in the range of tens or hundreds of thousands of MWh—which would be used to deal with interseasonal demands. For example, Mumbai hits peak consumption in the summer when air conditioners are on full blast, whereas London peaks in winters because of household heating. Ideally, energy captured in one season could be stored for months during low-use seasons, and then deployed later in the high-use seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;container _5e420 quartz&quot;&gt;David vs Goliath&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Piconi estimates that by the time Energy Vault builds its 10th or so 35-MWh plant, it can bring costs down to about $150 per kWh. That means it can’t fill the needs of the third category of energy-storage use; to do that, costs would have to be closer to $10 per kWh. In theory, at the current capacity and price point, it could compete in the second category—if it could find a customer that wanted Energy Vault to build dozens of plants for a single grid. Realistically, Energy Vault’s best bet is to compete in the first category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;That said, some experts told Quartz that the cost of lithium-ion batteries, the current dominant battery technology, could fall to about $100 per kWh, which would make them cheaper even than Energy Vault when it comes to storing days or weeks worth of energy. And because batteries are compact, they can be transported vast distances. Most of the lithium-ion batteries in smartphones used all over the world, for example, are made in East Asia. Energy Vault’s concrete blocks will have to be built on-site, and each 35 MWh system would need a circular piece of land about 100 meters (300 feet) in diameter. Batteries need a fraction of that space to store the same amount of energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Batteries do have some limitations. The maximum life of lithium-ion batteries, for example, is 20 or so years. They also lose their capacity to store energy over time. And there aren’t yet reliable ways to recycle lithium-ion batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Energy Vault’s plant can operate for 30 years with little maintenance and almost no fade in capacity. Its concrete blocks also use waste materials. So Piconi is confident that there’s still a niche that Energy Vault can fill: Places that have abundant access to land and building material, combined with the desire to have storage technologies that last for decades without fading in capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, whether or not Energy Vault succeeds, it does make a strong case for the argument that, while everyone else is out looking for high-tech, futuristic battery innovation, there may be real value in thinking about how to apply low-tech solutions to 21st-century problems. Energy Vault built a functional test plant in just nine months, spending relative pennies. It’s a signal of sorts that some of the answers to our energy-storage problems may still be sitting hidden in plain sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was updated with information about Energy Vault’s first commercial-unit orders.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;container _92842 quartz&quot;&gt;🌍&lt;em&gt; Quartz is running a series called The Race to Zero Emissions that explores the challenges and opportunities of energy-storage technologies. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2ioY0AA&quot;&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt; to be the first to know when stories are published.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 17:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nabla9</dc:creator>
<og:description>To deal with variable solar and wind power, the startup Energy Vault is coming out of stealth mode to offer alternatives to lithium-ion batteries.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/energy-vault-landscape-x.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1400</og:image>
<og:title>Stacking concrete blocks is a surprisingly efficient way to store energy</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://qz.com/1355672/stacking-concrete-blocks-is-a-surprisingly-efficient-way-to-store-energy/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://qz.com/1355672/stacking-concrete-blocks-is-a-surprisingly-efficient-way-to-store-energy/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mastodon Is Better Than Twitter: Elevator Pitch</title>
<link>https://www.codesections.com/blog/mastodon-elevator-pitch/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.codesections.com/blog/mastodon-elevator-pitch/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Mastodon is a newcomer social media platform that is a lot like Twitter—short messages, followers, hashtags, all that. But Mastodon is much better than Twitter, and not just because being totally ad-free and keeping chronological timelines make it far more enjoyable to use (though that certainly helps!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that is nice, but the real advantage Mastodon has over Twitter is that Mastodon is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; an &lt;a href=&quot;http://shamusyoung.com/twentysidedtale/?p=41853&quot;&gt;outrage machine that's corroding our ability to view our politic opponents as real humans, deserving of sympathy and understanding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain how much better Mastodon is, I'm going to give you three examples of &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; Mastodon is better, and then I'll step back and talk about &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; Mastodon is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-retweets-to-boosts&quot;&gt;From Retweets to Boosts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most pernicious parts of Twitter is how people will retweet something dumb, offensive, or awful that an opponent said, along with a message mocking that opponent. Over time, this leads people on all sides of an issue to see only a distorted caricature of their opponents, comprised of an amalgam of all the worst features of that group. (This phenomenon of cherry-picking the worst bits of an opposing group &lt;a href=&quot;http://slatestarcodex.com/2014/05/12/weak-men-are-superweapons/&quot;&gt;exists independently of Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, but Twitter makes it much, much worse.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Mastodon solve this issue? Well, Mastodon doesn't have retweets; it has &quot;boosts&quot;. Boosts are essentially like retweets, with one key difference: there's no option to add your own commentary. You simply &lt;em&gt;can't&lt;/em&gt; post something awful with a message saying how awful it is—all you can do is boost something awful without commentary. What's more, the name itself—&quot;boost&quot;—draws attention to a fact that Twitter does its best to obscure: by boosting something you disagree with, you're ultimately giving that viewpoint &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; exposure, not less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, Mastodon users basically never boost toots to say how wrong they are, and there isn't an issue with armies of followers descending on the original author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mastodon-is-local-while-still-being-global&quot;&gt;Mastodon Is Local (while still being global)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Twitter, everyone belongs to a single, global Twitter, with a single set of moderation policies spanning every group individual on the service. If you get banned from Twitter, you're banned from &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Mastodon, you don't really join Mastodon itself. Instead, you join a particular server (called an &quot;instance&quot;). Your instance might have a few hundred people and a moderator or two—just the right scale to keep the discussion civil without degenerating into bureaucratic rules-lawyering. And, because you get a &quot;local&quot; feed of all posts on your instance in addition to posts from people you follow, your instance really can start to feel like a community. Finally, with instances, you keep control: if you find that you don't like the moderation policies or culture of a particular instance, you're always free to pick up and move to a different one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This neatly solves Twitter's huge problem with moderation—as Mastodon grows, the number of mods will inherently scale with that growth. Yet, even as their number grows, they'll stay part of (and accountable to) a relatively small community on their home instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Mastodon would be pretty useless if it only let you talk to a few hundred people, so it doesn't impose that limit at all. You can follow &lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt;, regardless of what instance they call home. The only difference is that if you have a problem with them, then you'd complain to &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; instance's moderators rather than to your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what stops people from setting up instances that allow for any sort of awful content and then pestering the rest of us? Well, they &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt;, but Mastodon lets you or your moderators decide to block entire instances. If a particular instance won't mind its own users, then it will likely find that few other instances want anything to do with it—or at least that it's limited to equally laissez-faire instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-user-interface-that-encourages-thoughtfulness&quot;&gt;A User Interface that Encourages Thoughtfulness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastodon's user interface provides the very prominent option to hide a portion of a post behind a screen that is only removed when and if the user chooses. This is a great format for hiding the punchline in jokes or concealing spoilers. More importantly, it's also commonly used to hide controversial posts—including posts about politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this comes down to is &lt;strong&gt;control&lt;/strong&gt;. This pattern of tagging politics and letting the reader decide whether they want to engage with them puts the reader back in control; they can chose to engage with politics—and many do! But if they don't want to (or don't want to right now), they also have the option not to view those posts. And that's not the only way the Mastodon UI puts the reader back in control; for example, it also has very powerful options for hiding toots based on keywords to give you a middle ground between unfollowing someone and seeing every toot they ever make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I acknowledge that some of this is just a cultural practice; having political toots hidden is dependent on Mastodon users recognizing how corrosive political discussions can be and opting to give their readers control over when and if they see those toots. But it's a cultural practice that the technology nudges people towards with good user-interface design, and it's a cultural practice that, at this point, is firmly established.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-why-twitter-is-in-the-outrage-business-mastodon-isn-t-a-business&quot;&gt;The Why: Twitter Is in the Outrage Business; Mastodon Isn't a Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter is a business that makes money (… er, &lt;em&gt;tries&lt;/em&gt; to make money) by selling ads. To maximize ad revenue, they want to keep you on Twitter for as long as they possibly can, which means making sure their content is as engaging as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But often, tweets are at their most engaging when they're at their most enraging. Any tweet that keeps people clicking and talking—even if they're talking about how awful the other side is—is a tweet that keeps people around to view ads. Outrage is good for Twitter's bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's why Twitter isn't—and will never be—as healthy a community as Mastodon is. Mastodon's innovations aren't &lt;em&gt;technologically&lt;/em&gt; that challenging (I mean, a lot of the tech is pretty cool, but it's nothing Twitter couldn't copy if they really wanted to). No, the reason that Mastodon has all these advantages is that they &lt;em&gt;aren't&lt;/em&gt; advantages from Twitter's perspective. From Twitter's perspective, anything that makes people less likely to angrily retweet a rival's obnoxious view is a loss, pure and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Twitter doesn't have any choice in the matter, either. Even if they wanted to sacrifice their ad revenues out of a desire to improve the quality of public discourse, they couldn't. Twitter is a public company, funded by investor money; they thus owe a legal duty to make as much money for their investors as they can. Twitter can't, and won't, stop prioritizing ad revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastodon, on the other hand, isn't profit motivated and never will be. At the top, Mastodon is a small, open-source project &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/mastodon&quot;&gt;funded on Patreon&lt;/a&gt;. Mastodon can afford to stay small, because it's not trying to be centralized—the vast bulk of the work is being done by thousands of small sys-admins across the globe running small instances of a few dozen or a few hundred users. And that part is sustainable too—running a small instance costs only a few dollars a month, and is a rewarding gig: it comes with a lot of control, and a privileged position to help craft a healthy community. Mastodon's entire model gets its incentives right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;joining&quot;&gt;Joining&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this sounds at all appealing to you, I encourage you to check out Mastodon. It's not perfect, and it might not fully replace Twitter if you're a heavy user—if for no other reason than that people you like to follow won't (yet) have switched. But the community is really great, and growing quickly. And I've had a blast with it since I got involved. If you'd like to join, the main website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmastodon.org/&quot;&gt;joinmastodon.org&lt;/a&gt;, is full of good info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmastodon.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.codesections.com/blog/mastodon-elevator-pitch/mastodon_homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;joinmastodon.org&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You certainly don't need to understand the details of how Mastodon works, but if you would like a bit better understanding of how Mastodon works under the hood, Mastodon user &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosstodon.org/@kev&quot;&gt;@kev&lt;/a&gt; wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/how-does-mastodon-work/&quot;&gt;an excellent guide to Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;And, when you're ready to pick an instance, there's a great tool that lets you search available instances at &lt;a href=&quot;https://instances.social/&quot;&gt;instances.social&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation is to use that tool to find a few relatively small instances with names that sound interesting to you. Then, click through and read about the culture and moderation policies of each instance and maybe scan through the public posts to get a sense of the local vibe. And then dive right in—you can always change your mind later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal note, if you happen to be interested in FOSS (Free and Open Source Software), then I can personally vouch for the community at &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosstodon.org&quot;&gt;fosstodon.org&lt;/a&gt;. And, on an even more personal note, whatever instance you join, please feel free to look me up. I'm &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosstodon.org/@codesections&quot;&gt;@codesections@fosstodon.org&lt;/a&gt; and would love for you to say hi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 11:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>codesections</dc:creator>
<og:title>Mastodon Is Better than Twitter: Elevator Pitch | CodeSections</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>www.codesections.com</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.codesections.com/codesections_logo_large.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.codesections.com/blog/mastodon-elevator-pitch/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My dad’s resume and skills from 1980</title>
<link>https://github.com/runvnc/dadsresume</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/runvnc/dadsresume</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad is 92 and we just put him in a home. I have been clearing out the house and found his resume and skills (application letter) from 1980. In case anyone is interested in what one particular old timer programmer did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/runvnc/dadsresume/blob/master/IMG_20180817_232813.jpg?raw=true&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/runvnc/dadsresume/raw/master/IMG_20180817_232813.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Skills&quot; title=&quot;Skills&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/runvnc/dadsresume/blob/master/IMG_20180817_233142.jpg?raw=true&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/runvnc/dadsresume/raw/master/IMG_20180817_233142.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;Title&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 07:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ilaksh</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/347804?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>runvnc/dadsresume</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/runvnc/dadsresume</og:url>
<og:description>dadsresume - My dad's resume and skills from 1980</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/runvnc/dadsresume</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Python Fire – Generates CLIs from any Python object</title>
<link>https://github.com/google/python-fire</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/google/python-fire</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Python Fire is a library for automatically generating command line interfaces (CLIs) from absolutely any Python object.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Python Fire is a simple way to create a CLI in Python. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/benefits.md#simple-cli&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Fire is a helpful tool for developing and debugging Python code. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/benefits.md#debugging&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Fire helps with exploring existing code or turning other people's code into a CLI. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/benefits.md#exploring&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Fire makes transitioning between Bash and Python easier. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/benefits.md#bash&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Fire makes using a Python REPL easier by setting up the REPL with the modules and variables you'll need already imported and created. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/benefits.md#repl&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install Python Fire with pip, run: &lt;code&gt;pip install fire&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install Python Fire with conda, run: &lt;code&gt;conda install fire -c conda-forge&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install Python Fire from source, first clone the repository and then run: &lt;code&gt;python setup.py install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Basic Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can call &lt;code&gt;Fire&lt;/code&gt; on any Python object:&lt;br/&gt;functions, classes, modules, objects, dictionaries, lists, tuples, etc. They all work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's an example of calling Fire on a class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; fire

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Calculator&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;object&lt;/span&gt;):
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;A simple calculator class.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;double&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;number&lt;/span&gt;):
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; number

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;__name__&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;__main__&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:
  fire.Fire(Calculator)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, from the command line, you can run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
python calculator.py double 10  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; 20&lt;/span&gt;
python calculator.py double --number=15  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; 30&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn how Fire behaves on functions, objects, dicts, lists, etc, and to learn about Fire's other features, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/using-cli.md&quot;&gt;Using a Fire CLI page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For additional examples, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/guide.md&quot;&gt;The Python Fire Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is it called Fire?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you call &lt;code&gt;Fire&lt;/code&gt;, it fires off (executes) your command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where can I learn more?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/guide.md&quot;&gt;The Python Fire Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Setup&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Command&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;install&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install fire&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Creating a CLI&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Command&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;import&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;import fire&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Call&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;fire.Fire()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Turns the current module into a Fire CLI.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Call&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;fire.Fire(component)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Turns &lt;code&gt;component&lt;/code&gt; into a Fire CLI.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Using a CLI&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Command&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/using-cli.md#help-flag&quot;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;command -- --help&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/using-cli.md#interactive-flag&quot;&gt;REPL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;command -- --interactive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Enters interactive mode.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/using-cli.md#separator-flag&quot;&gt;Separator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;command -- --separator=X&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;This sets the separator to &lt;code&gt;X&lt;/code&gt;. The default separator is &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/using-cli.md#completion-flag&quot;&gt;Completion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;command -- --completion [shell]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Generate a completion script for the CLI.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/using-cli.md#trace-flag&quot;&gt;Trace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;command -- --trace&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Gets a Fire trace for the command.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/python-fire/blob/master/docs/using-cli.md#verbose-flag&quot;&gt;Verbose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;command -- --verbose&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that flags are separated from the Fire command by an isolated &lt;code&gt;--&lt;/code&gt; arg.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an official Google product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 19:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tzury</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/1342004?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>google/python-fire</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/google/python-fire</og:url>
<og:description>python-fire - Python Fire is a library for automatically generating command line interfaces (CLIs) from absolutely any Python object.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/google/python-fire</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Do Keynote Speakers Keep Suggesting That Improving Security Is Possible?</title>
<link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity18/presentation/mickens</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity18/presentation/mickens</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;@conference {218395,&lt;br/&gt;author = {James Mickens},&lt;br/&gt;title = {Q: Why Do Keynote Speakers Keep Suggesting That Improving Security Is Possible? A: Because Keynote Speakers Make Bad Life Decisions and Are Poor Role Models},&lt;br/&gt;year = {2018},&lt;br/&gt;address = {Baltimore, MD},&lt;br/&gt;publisher = {{USENIX} Association},&lt;br/&gt;}&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 19:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zdw</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity18/presentation/mickens</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Faster – Fast key-value store from Microsoft Research</title>
<link>https://github.com/Microsoft/FASTER</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/Microsoft/FASTER</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing large application state easily and with high performance is one of the hardest problems in the cloud today. We present FASTER, a new concurrent key-value store designed for point lookups and heavy updates. FASTER supports data larger than memory, by leveraging fast external storage. What differentiates FASTER are its cache-optimized index that achieves very high performance — up to 160 million operations per second when data fits in memory; its unique “hybrid record log” design that combines a traditional persistent log with in-place updates, to shape the memory working set and retain performance; and its architecture as an component that can be embedded in cloud apps. FASTER achieves higher throughput than current systems, by more than two orders of magnitude, and scales better than current pure in-memory data structures, for in-memory working sets. FASTER also offers a new consistent recovery scheme that achieves better performance at the expense of slightly higher commit latency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://aka.ms/FASTER&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;our website&lt;/a&gt; for more details and papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For C#, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Microsoft/FASTER/tree/master/cs&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For C++, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Microsoft/FASTER/tree/master/cc&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://cla.microsoft.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://cla.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA-bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., label, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&quot;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 19:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JeffCyr</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/6154722?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>Microsoft/FASTER</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/Microsoft/FASTER</og:url>
<og:description>FASTER - Fast key-value store from Microsoft Research</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/Microsoft/FASTER</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Arm Announces Client CPU Roadmap For Laptops</title>
<link>https://www.arm.com/company/news/2018/08/accelerating-mobile-and-laptop-performance</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.arm.com/company/news/2018/08/accelerating-mobile-and-laptop-performance</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;By Nandan Nayampally, vice president and general manager, Client Line of Business, Arm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Arm unveils its first-ever public CPU forward-looking roadmap and performance numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client CPU’s expected to deliver year-over-year performance improvements of &amp;gt;15% for compute through 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arm positioned for laptop share gain with roadmap designed for 5G always-on, always-connected devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last five years, advances in Arm technology have brought desktop-class PC performance into our smartphones, fundamentally changing how we use technology in our daily lives. This is a direct result of Arm’s annual cadence of introducing new world-class CPU designs, which have delivered double-digit gains every year in instructions-per-clock (IPC) performance since 2013. Arm is now applying this same design leadership, along with optimizing for the latest advances in process technology from our foundry partners, to enable the PC industry to overcome their reliance on Moore’s law – which has definitely slowed – and deliver a high-performance, always-on, always-connected laptop experience. It’s an experience that will be a necessity as 5G enables an entirely new world of connected possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest example of this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arm.com/company/news/2018/05/arm-announces-new-suite-of-ip-for-premium-mobile-experiences&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;our recently launched Cortex-A76 CPU&quot;&gt;our recently launched Cortex-A76 CPU&lt;/a&gt;.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.arm.com/processors/b/blog/posts/cortex-a76-laptop-class-performance-with-mobile-efficiency&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Cortex-A76 is delivering an unprecedented 35% gain in performance compared to the previous generation&quot;&gt;Cortex-A76 is delivering an unprecedented 35% gain in performance compared to the previous generation&lt;/a&gt;, without compromising Arm’s efficiency leadership. This is an industry milestone for multiple reasons. Firstly, it’s the foundational CPU IP for the first 7nm SoCs expected to be in production later this year. More importantly, Cortex-A76 represents the continuation of the trajectory that will increase performance at a staggering pace, enabling consumers to do more with their smartphones and level the performance playing field against mass-market laptop CPUs from the competition.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                         &lt;img alt=&quot;Arm client roadmap performance comparison chart&quot; src=&quot;https://www.arm.com/-/media/global/news/arm-client-roadmap-performance-comparison-chart-2.jpg?revision=0179f0d5-3f22-4e75-9920-467301a6b8f3&amp;amp;h=494.75&amp;amp;w=1055.25&amp;amp;la=en&amp;amp;hash=6D78932D4F021387B14574EE5C3FDCFDD76972A8&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking ahead: Breakthrough performance for the always-on, always-connected user&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is another milestone for Arm as we’re publicly disclosing both forward-looking compute performance data and a CPU roadmap for Arm’s Client Line of Business from now through 2020. It’s the first time we’ve ever shared a roadmap of any kind publicly, and it won’t be the last (hint: come to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.armtechcon.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Arm TechCon&quot;&gt;Arm TechCon&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                         &lt;img alt=&quot;Arm client Compute CPU roadmap&quot; src=&quot;https://www.arm.com/-/media/global/news/Arm_Client_Compute_CPU_roadmap_lo-res_FINAL.JPG?revision=ce4ecc5f-6945-4c94-9c3e-90bba7af1178&amp;amp;h=529&amp;amp;w=1000&amp;amp;la=en&amp;amp;hash=185C194B716D5D10B33EE8A8623A9B86C65C905D&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some important details you need to know about our client CPU roadmap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The follow-up to Cortex-A76 will be codenamed ‘Deimos’ and delivered to our partners in 2018. Optimized for the latest 7nm nodes, ‘Deimos’ is based on Arm DynamIQ technology and is expected to deliver a 15+ percent increase in compute performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In 2019, the CPU codenamed ‘Hercules’ will be available to Arm partners. ‘Hercules’, also based on DynamIQ technology, will be optimized for both the latest 5nm and 7nm nodes. ‘Hercules’ continues the trajectory of increased compute performance, while also improving power and area efficiency by 10 percent (in addition to the efficiency gains achievable from the 5nm process node).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why it matters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our roadmap of client CPUs has been designed to take advantage of the disruptive innovation 5G will bring to all client devices. This combined with innovations from our silicon and foundry partners will enable Arm SoCs to break through the dominance of x86 and gain substantial market share in Windows laptops and Chromebooks over the next five years.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the Arm Artisan Physical IP platform and Arm POP IP will also help Arm partners get every bit of performance-per-watt they can out of their SoCs on whatever process node they choose. Artisan is a key part of building industry-leading process nodes for our foundry partners from 130nm down to 5nm, while POP IP has helped our partners realize market-leading performance, power, and area (PPA) over many generations of Arm cores. Arm POP IP is already helping to enable laptop-class performance in 7nm SoCs based on Cortex-A76 by giving our partners the opportunity to push the clock-speed past 3.0GHz and up to 3.3GHz within power envelopes around half that of today’s mass-market x86 processors.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A robust and rapidly-expanding laptop ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading PC OEMs already recognize that efficiency is a key differentiator for the always-on, always-connected, laptop experience which is characterized by very slim, light form factors, full day battery, and excellent responsiveness. Windows 10 systems powered by Arm-based Qualcomm Snapdragon SoCs are already available from ASUS, Lenovo, HP, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualcomm.com/news/releases/2018/06/04/qualcomm-announces-snapdragon-850-mobile-compute-platform-windows-10-pcs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Qualcomm Announces Snapdragon 850 Mobile Compute Platform for Windows 10 PCs&quot;&gt;and Samsung have also announced they will join the mix as well&lt;/a&gt;. Along with Microsoft, these partners have given users a new choice for connectivity and an always-on experience that was not possible a year ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Arm didn’t build the mobile ecosystem by just relying on its efficiency leadership. We accelerated the performance gain through our annual design cadence, while improving efficiency and silicon footprint. This has enabled our ecosystem of silicon, software, and OEM partners to bring smartphones to market every year with new innovations and features. Our latest roadmap highlights that we’re bringing these same annual PPA improvements to the PC industry which now has both the opportunity and headroom to accelerate innovation like never before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The CPU roadmap Arm has laid out coupled with Qualcomm’s heterogenous approach to computing across our various IP block and integrated connectivity, will allow for new advancements in the always-on, always-connected PC experience offered by the Qualcomm Snapdragon Mobile Compute Platform,” said Alex Katouzian, senior vice president and general manager, mobile, Qualcomm Technologies, Inc. “Our mission continues to bring the best of the mobile world to the PC, with great battery life, sleek innovative form factors, and Windows 10 for on-the-go productivity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 was an important first step in expanding the Arm PC ecosystem and showing the world that we’re no longer bound to the idea that process technology will only incrementally improve every two years and that a laptop will need charging every few hours.  The pace of innovation that transformed smartphones into the compute platform of choice is now powering  and transforming the larger screen devices.  The question now for the broader PC industry is: Are you ready to liberate yourselves from the slowing pace of Moore’s law and deliver the mobile productivity experience consumers and businesses will need as we enter the 5G era? &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 14:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>redial</dc:creator>
<og:title>Arm acquires Treasure Data to set the stage for IoT transformation</og:title>
<og:description>Arm unveils its first-ever public CPU forward-looking roadmap and performance numbers</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.arm.com:443</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.arm.com/company/news/2018/08/accelerating-mobile-and-laptop-performance</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.arm.com/company/news/2018/08/accelerating-mobile-and-laptop-performance</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>