<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Hubble finds first galaxy in the local universe without dark matter</title>
<link>http://www.spacetelescope.org/news/heic1806/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.spacetelescope.org/news/heic1806/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;pr_typeid&quot;&gt;heic1806 — Science Release&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;28 March 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text_intro pr_first&quot;&gt;An international team of researchers using the NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope and several other observatories have, for the first time, uncovered a galaxy in our cosmic neighbourhood that is missing most — if not all — of its dark matter. This discovery of the galaxy NGC 1052-DF2 challenges currently-accepted theories of and galaxy formation and provides new insights into the nature of dark matter. The results are published in Nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astronomers using Hubble and several ground-based observatories have found a unique astronomical object: a galaxy that appears to contain almost no dark matter &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spacetelescope.org/news/heic1806/#1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;. Hubble helped to accurately confirm the distance of NGC 1052-DF2 to be 65 million light-years and determined its size and brightness. Based on these data the team discovered that NGC 1052-DF2 larger than the Milky Way, but contains about 250 times fewer stars, leading it to be classified as an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultra_diffuse_galaxy&quot;&gt;ultra diffuse galaxy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;I spent an hour just staring at this image,&quot;&lt;/em&gt; lead researcher Pieter van Dokkum of Yale University says as he recalls first seeing the Hubble image of NGC 1052-DF2. &lt;em&gt;&quot;This thing is astonishing: a gigantic blob so sparse that you see the galaxies behind it. It is literally a see-through galaxy.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further measurements of the dynamical properties of ten &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Globular_cluster&quot;&gt;globular clusters&lt;/a&gt; orbiting the galaxy allowed the team to infer an independent value of the galaxies mass. This mass is comparable to the mass of the stars in the galaxy, leading to the conclusion that NGC 1052-DF2 contains at least 400 times less &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_matter&quot;&gt;dark matter&lt;/a&gt; than astronomers predict for a galaxy of its mass, and possibly none at all &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spacetelescope.org/news/heic1806/#2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;. This discovery is unpredicted by current theories on the distribution of dark matter and its influence on galaxy formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;Dark matter is conventionally believed to be an integral part of all galaxies — the glue that holds them together and the underlying scaffolding upon which they are built,&quot;&lt;/em&gt; explains co-author Allison Merritt from Yale University and the Max Planck Institute for Astronomy, Germany. And van Dokkum adds: &lt;em&gt;&quot;This invisible, mysterious substance is by far the most dominant aspect of any galaxy. Finding a galaxy without any is completely unexpected; it challenges standard ideas of how galaxies work.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merritt remarks: &lt;em&gt;&quot;There is no theory that predicts these types of galaxies — how you actually go about forming one of these things is completely unknown.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although counterintuitive, the existence of a galaxy without dark matter negates theories that try to explain the Universe without dark matter being a part of it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spacetelescope.org/news/heic1806/#3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;: The discovery of NGC 1052-DF2 demonstrates that dark matter is somehow separable from galaxies. This is only expected if dark matter is bound to ordinary matter through nothing but gravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the researchers already have some ideas about how to explain the missing dark matter in NGC 1052-DF2. Did a cataclysmic event such as the birth of a multitude of massive stars sweep out all the gas and dark matter? Or did the growth of the nearby massive elliptical galaxy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NGC_1052&quot;&gt;NGC 1052&lt;/a&gt; billions of years ago play a role in NGC 1052-DF2’s dark matter deficiency?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These ideas, however, still do not explain how this galaxy formed. To find an explanation, the team is already hunting for more dark-matter deficient galaxies as they analyse Hubble images of 23 ultra-diffuse galaxies — three of which appear to be similar to NGC 1052-DF2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] The galaxy was identified with the Dragonfly Telephoto Array (DFA) and also observed by the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS). As well as the NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gemini.edu&quot;&gt;Gemini Observatory&lt;/a&gt; and the Keck Observatory were used to study the object in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Since 1884 astronomers have invoked dark matter to explain why galaxies do not fly apart, given the speed at which the stars within galaxies move. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kepler%27s_Second_Law&quot;&gt;Kepler's Second Law&lt;/a&gt; it is expected that the rotation velocities of stars will decrease with distance from the centre of a galaxy. This is not observed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] The MOND theory — Modified Newtonian Dynamics — suggests that the phenomena usually attributed to dark matter can be explained by modifying the laws of gravity. The result of this would be that a signature usually attributed to dark matter should always be detected, and is an unavoidable consequence of the presence of ordinary matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;More information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hubble Space Telescope is a project of international cooperation between ESA and NASA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results were published in a paper entitled “A galaxy lacking dark matter” in the journal Nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The international team of astronomers in this study consists of P. van Dokkum (Yale University, USA), S. Danieli (Yale University, USA), Y. Cohen (Yale University, USA), A. Merritt (Yale University, USA; Max Planck Institute for Astronomy, Germany), A.J. Romanowsky (San José State University, USA; University of California Observatories, USA), R. Abraham (University of Toronto, Canada), J. Brodie (University of California Observatories, USA), C. Conroy (Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, USA), D. Lockhurst (University of Toronto, Canada), L. Mowla (Yale University, USA), E. O’Sullivan (Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, USA), and J. Zhang (University of Toronto, Canada).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image credit: NASA, ESA, P. van Dokkum (Yale University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contacts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pieter van Dokkum&lt;br/&gt;Yale University&lt;br/&gt;Yale, USA&lt;br/&gt;Tel: +001 2034323019&lt;br/&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:pieter.vandokkum@yale.edu&quot;&gt;pieter.vandokkum@yale.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allison Merritt&lt;br/&gt;Max Planck Institute for Astronomy&lt;br/&gt;Heidelberg, Germany&lt;br/&gt;Tel: +49 6221 528-455&lt;br/&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:merritt@mpia.de&quot;&gt;merritt@mpia.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathias Jäger&lt;br/&gt;ESA/Hubble, Public Information Officer&lt;br/&gt;Garching bei München, Germany&lt;br/&gt;Tel: +49 176 62397500&lt;br/&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mjaeger@partner.eso.org&quot;&gt;mjaeger@partner.eso.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 19:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sampo</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Hubble finds first galaxy in the local Universe without dark matter</og:title>
<og:image>http://cdn.spacetelescope.org/archives/images/screen/heic1806a.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.spacetelescope.org/news/heic1806/</og:url>
<og:description>An international team of researchers using the NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope and several other observatories have, for the first time, uncovered a galaxy in our cosmic neighbourhood that is missing most — if not all — of its dark matter. This discovery of the galaxy NGC 1052-DF2 challenges currently-accepted theories of and galaxy formation and provides new insights into the nature of dark matter. The results are published in Nature.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.spacetelescope.org/news/heic1806/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Will MySpace ever lose its monopoly? (2007)</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2007/feb/08/business.comment</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2007/feb/08/business.comment</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;ristotle distinguished between friendships based on communal interests and those of soulmates who bonded out of mutual affection. The vast majority of people signed up for MySpace, Rupert Murdoch's phenomenally successful networking site, fall into the former category. But on present showing that won't stop its continuing expansion which, as the MySpace generation goes into employment, could eventually extend Murdoch's influence in ways that would make his grip on satellite television seem parochial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was said at the time of purchase that if Murdoch tried to mess with MySpace's &quot;sharing&quot; culture by commercialising it, punters would simply switch to one of the dozens of clones it has spawned from Bebo.com to the upwardly mobile Cyworld.com, which has taken South Korea by storm and is now taking the battle into MySpace's backyard in the US. Cyworld points to research showing that MySpace is a &quot;rites-of-passage&quot; site that kids will grow out of while Cyworld is a &quot;real you&quot; experience. It is an interesting, almost Aristotelian, distinction but some argue it may already be too late for competitors to dislodge MySpace, except in niche markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Barrett of TechNewsWorld claims that MySpace is well on the way to becoming what economists call a &quot;natural monopoly&quot;. Users have invested so much social capital in putting up data about themselves it is not worth their changing sites, especially since every new user that MySpace attracts adds to its value as a network of interacting people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is common knowledge that a fax machine is worthless until others have one too. That is what is happening in social networking except that, unlike a fax machine, it can't be instantly swapped for another. It is easy to change search engines, even if it is Google. But if you change social networks you not only have to move all your videos, audios, messages, photos elsewhere but you also lose your network of friends unless they migrate with you. MySpace won't make that easy. Its massive user base will help maintain its dominance, according to co-founder Chris DeWolfe. &quot;In social networking, there is a huge advantage to have scale. You can find almost anyone on MySpace and the more time that has been invested in the site, the more locked in people are&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it were a country, MySpace would be the seventh biggest, ahead of Russia and Bangladesh, though not all users are active. It had 153,339,321 users when I started writing this article and 153,523,640 when I had finished. What does this growth bode for the future? For the first time a like-minded media generation will grow up interacting instantaneously: globalisation personified. Maybe we won't need CVs any more as our lives will be there online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But will commercialisation kill the culture that spawned MySpace? The $900m (£450m) three-year deal Google did to put its adverts on MySpace is, reportedly, being renegotiated. Upwards. When I visited the site this week I was met by offputting flashing adverts. Logging on I was then greeted with a loud video advert there was no obvious way of turning off. Good job I was not in a library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn't bother MySpacers and they don't seem bothered by other matters. User-generated content, for instance. MySpace is a huge generator of it, maybe the biggest, but users don't get paid. But why not? Google, the owner of YouTube, the vast site that hosts video clips, is under siege from corporations, doubtless including Murdoch's Fox empire, to get royalty income from those clips. Yet MySpace creams off all the advertising income associated with user content without which MySpace's goldmine would vaporise. The difference is that YouTube's predators are large corporations, whereas consumer power is diffused among over 150m individuals on MySpace. Maybe they should form a virtual trade union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;·&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:vic.keegan@theguardian.com&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;vic.keegan@theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;·&lt;/strong&gt; If you'd like to comment on any aspect of Technology Guardian, send your emails to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:tech@theguardian.com&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;tech@theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 18:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jarred</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2007/feb/08/business.comment</og:url>
<og:description>Rupert Murdoch's influence could eventually extend in ways that would make his grip on satellite television seem parochial, says Victor Keegan.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.guim.co.uk/images/eada8aa27c12fe2d5afa3a89d3fbae0d/fallback-logo.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Victor Keegan: Will MySpace ever lose its monopoly?</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2007/feb/08/business.comment</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>VPN leaks users’ IPs via WebRTC</title>
<link>https://voidsec.com/vpn-leak/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://voidsec.com/vpn-leak/</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TL:DR: VPN leaks users’ IPs via WebRTC.&lt;br/&gt;I’ve tested seventy VPN providers and 16 of them leaks users’ IPs via WebRTC (23%)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, during a small event in my city, I’ve presented a small research on “decloaking” the true IP of a website visitor (ab)using the WebRTC technology (thx to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wsxarcher&quot;&gt;wsx&lt;/a&gt; for the tip).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is WebRTC?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WebRTC is a free, open project&lt;/strong&gt; that provides browsers and mobile applications with Real-Time Communications (RTC) capabilities via simple APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It includes the fundamental building blocks for high-quality communications on the web, such as network, audio and video components used in voice and video chat applications, these components, when implemented in a browser, can be accessed through a JavaScript API, enabling developers to easily implement their own RTC web app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;STUN/ICE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is a component allowing calls to use the STUN and ICE mechanisms to establish connections across various types of networks. The STUN server sends a ping back that contains the IP address and port of the client&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These STUN (Session Traversal Utilities for NAT) servers are used by VPNs to &lt;strong&gt;translate a local home IP address to a new public IP address and vice-versa&lt;/strong&gt;. To do this, the STUN server maintains a table of both your VPN-based public IP and your local (“real”) IP during connectivity (routers at home replicate a similar function in translating private IP addresses to public and back.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebRTC allows requests to be made to STUN servers which return the “hidden” home IP-address as well as local network addresses for the system that is being used by the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of the requests can be accessed using JavaScript, but because they are made outside the normal XML/HTTP request procedure, they are not visible in the developer console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only requirement for this de-anonymizing technique to work is WebRTC and JavaScript support from the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;VPN and WebRTC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This functionality could be also used to de-anonymize and trace users behind common privacy protection services such as: VPN, SOCKS Proxy, HTTP Proxy&lt;/strong&gt; and in the past (TOR users).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browsers that have WebRTC enabled by default:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brave&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Chrome on Android&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet (Samsung Browser)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opera&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivaldi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23% of the tested VPNs and Proxies services disclosed the real IP address of the visitors making the users traceable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following providers leaks users’ IP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;BolehVPN (USA Only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ChillGlobal (Chrome and Firefox Plugin)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glype (Depends on the configuration)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hide-me.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hola!VPN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hola!VPN Chrome Extension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTP PROXY navigation in browser that support Web RTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBVPN Browser Addon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP Proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;phx.piratebayproxy.co&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;psiphon3 (not leaking if using L2TP/IP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PureVPN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SOCKS Proxy on browsers with Web RTC enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SumRando Web Proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TOR as PROXY on browsers with Web RTC enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windscribe Addons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find the complete spreadsheet of tested VPN providers here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Nm7mxfFvmdn-3Az-BtE5O0BIdbJiIAWUnkoAF_v_0ug/edit#gid=0&quot;&gt;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Nm7mxfFvmdn-3Az-BtE5O0BIdbJiIAWUnkoAF_v_0ug/edit#gid=0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a comment or send me a tweet if you have updated results for any of the VPN which I am missing details. (especially the “$$$” one, since I cannot subscribe to 200 different payed VPN services :P)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Stay anonymous while surfing:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tips to follow in order to protect your IP during the internet navigation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Disable WebRTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable JavaScript (or at least some functions. &lt;a href=&quot;https://noscript.net/&quot;&gt;Use NoScript&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable Canvas Rendering (Web API)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always set a DNS fallback for every connection/adapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always kill all your browsers istances before and after a VPN connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear browser cache, history and cookies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drop all outgoing connections except for VPN provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;PoC:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check if your VPN leaks through this POC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ip.voidsec.com&quot;&gt;http://ip.voidsec.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PoC Code:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve updated Daniel Roesler code in order to make it works again and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/VoidSec/WebRTC-Leak&quot;&gt;you can find it on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 16:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BlueGh0st</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>VPN Leak - VoidSec</og:title>
<og:description>VPN leaks users’ IPs via WebRTC. I’ve tested seventy VPN providers and 16 of them leaks users’ IPs via WebRTC (23%)</og:description>
<og:url>https://voidsec.com/vpn-leak/</og:url>
<og:image>https://voidsec.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/WebRTC.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://voidsec.com/vpn-leak/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Au Revoir</title>
<link>https://blog.docker.com/2018/03/au-revoir/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.docker.com/2018/03/au-revoir/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.docker.com/2018/03/au-revoir/&quot;&gt;https://blog.docker.com/2018/03/au-revoir/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16698932&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16698932&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 615&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 246&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 16:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zapita</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.docker.com/2018/03/au-revoir/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kubernetes 1.10 released</title>
<link>http://blog.kubernetes.io/2018/03/kubernetes-1.10-stabilizing-storage-security-networking.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.kubernetes.io/2018/03/kubernetes-1.10-stabilizing-storage-security-networking.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor's note: today's post is by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/sig-release/blob/master/releases/release-1.10/release_team.md&quot;&gt;1.10 Release Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re pleased to announce the delivery of Kubernetes 1.10, our first release of 2018!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today’s release continues to advance maturity, extensibility, and pluggability of Kubernetes. This newest version stabilizes features in 3 key areas, including storage, security, and networking. Notable additions in this release include the introduction of external kubectl credential providers (alpha), the ability to switch DNS service to CoreDNS at install time (beta), and the move of Container Storage Interface (CSI) and persistent local volumes to beta.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive into the key features of this release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Storage - CSI and Local Storage move to beta&lt;/h3&gt;
This is an impactful release for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/community/tree/master/sig-storage&quot;&gt;the Storage Special Interest Group (SIG)&lt;/a&gt;, marking the culmination of their work on multiple features. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/features/issues/178&quot;&gt;Kubernetes implementation&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/container-storage-interface/spec/blob/master/spec.md&quot;&gt;Container Storage Interface&lt;/a&gt; (CSI) moves to beta in this release: installing new volume plugins is now as easy as deploying a pod. This in turn enables third-party storage providers to develop their solutions independently outside of the core Kubernetes codebase. This continues the thread of extensibility within the Kubernetes ecosystem.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/features/issues/121&quot;&gt;Durable (non-shared) local storage management&lt;/a&gt; progressed to beta in this release, making locally attached (non-network attached) storage available as a persistent volume source. This means higher performance and lower cost for distributed file systems and databases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This release also includes many updates to Persistent Volumes. Kubernetes can automatically &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/features/issues/498&quot;&gt;prevent deletion of Persistent Volume Claims that are in use by a pod&lt;/a&gt; (beta) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/features/issues/499&quot;&gt;prevent deletion of a Persistent Volume that is bound to a Persistent Volume Claim&lt;/a&gt; (beta). This helps ensure that storage API objects are deleted in the correct order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Security - External credential providers (alpha)&lt;/h3&gt;
Kubernetes, which is already highly extensible, gains another extension point in 1.10 with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/features/issues/541&quot;&gt;external kubectl credential providers&lt;/a&gt; (alpha). Cloud providers, vendors, and other platform developers can now release binary plugins to handle authentication for specific cloud-provider IAM services, or that integrate with in-house authentication systems that aren’t supported in-tree, such as Active Directory. This complements the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/administer-cluster/running-cloud-controller/&quot;&gt;Cloud Controller Manager&lt;/a&gt; feature added in 1.9.&lt;h3&gt;Networking - CoreDNS as a DNS provider (beta)&lt;/h3&gt;
The ability to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/website/pull/7638&quot;&gt;switch the DNS service&lt;/a&gt; to CoreDNS at &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/administer-cluster/coredns/&quot;&gt;install time&lt;/a&gt; is now in beta. CoreDNS has fewer moving parts: it’s a single executable and a single process, and supports additional use cases.&lt;p&gt;Each Special Interest Group (SIG) within the community continues to deliver the most-requested enhancements, fixes, and functionality for their respective specialty areas. For a complete list of inclusions by SIG, please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/blob/master/CHANGELOG-1.10.md#110-release-notes&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Availability&lt;/h3&gt;
Kubernetes 1.10 is available for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/releases/tag/v1.10.0&quot;&gt;download on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. To get started with Kubernetes, check out these i&lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/tutorials/&quot;&gt;nteractive tutorials&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;h3&gt;2 Day Features Blog Series&lt;/h3&gt;
If you’re interested in exploring these features more in depth, check back next week for our 2 Days of Kubernetes series where we’ll highlight detailed walkthroughs of the following features:&lt;p&gt;Day 1 - Container Storage Interface (CSI) for Kubernetes going Beta&lt;br/&gt;Day 2 - Local Persistent Volumes for Kubernetes going Beta&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Release team&lt;/h3&gt;
This release is made possible through the effort of hundreds of individuals who contributed both technical and non-technical content. Special thanks to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/sig-release/blob/master/releases/release-1.10/release_team.md&quot;&gt;release team&lt;/a&gt; led by Jaice Singer DuMars, Kubernetes Ambassador for Microsoft. The 10 individuals on the release team coordinate many aspects of the release, from documentation to testing, validation, and feature completeness.&lt;p&gt;As the Kubernetes community has grown, our release process represents an amazing demonstration of collaboration in open source software development. Kubernetes continues to gain new users at a rapid clip. This growth creates a positive feedback cycle where more contributors commit code creating a more vibrant ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Project Velocity&lt;/h3&gt;
The CNCF has continued refining an ambitious project to visualize the myriad contributions that go into the project. &lt;a href=&quot;https://devstats.k8s.io/&quot;&gt;K8s DevStats&lt;/a&gt; illustrates the breakdown of contributions from major company contributors, as well as an impressive set of preconfigured reports on everything from individual contributors to pull request lifecycle times. Thanks to increased automation, issue count at the end of the release was only slightly higher than it was at the beginning. This marks a major shift toward issue manageability. With 75,000+ comments, Kubernetes remains one of the most actively discussed projects on GitHub.&lt;h3&gt;User Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;
According to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/blog/2018/03/26/cncf-survey-china/&quot;&gt;recent CNCF survey&lt;/a&gt;, more than 49% of Asia-based respondents use Kubernetes in production, with another 49% evaluating it for use in production. Established, global organizations are using &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/case-studies/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes in production&lt;/a&gt; at massive scale. Recently published user stories from the community include:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Huawei&lt;/strong&gt;, the largest telecommunications equipment manufacturer in the world, &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/case-studies/huawei/&quot;&gt;moved its internal IT department’s applications to run on Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;. This resulted in the global deployment cycles decreasing from a week to minutes, and the efficiency of application delivery improved by tenfold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jinjiang Travel International&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the top 5 largest OTA and hotel companies, use Kubernetes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/blog/managing-production-systems-kubernetes-chinese-enterprises&quot;&gt;speed up their software release velocity&lt;/a&gt; from hours to just minutes. Additionally, they leverage Kubernetes to increase the scalability and availability of their online workloads. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Haufe Group&lt;/strong&gt;, the Germany-based media and software company, utilized Kubernetes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/case-studies/haufegroup/&quot;&gt;deliver a new release in half an hour&lt;/a&gt; instead of days. The company is also able to scale down to around half the capacity at night, saving 30 percent on hardware costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlackRock&lt;/strong&gt;, the world’s largest asset manager, was able to move quickly using Kubernetes and built an investor research web app from &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/case-studies/blackrock/&quot;&gt;inception to delivery in under 100 days&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Is Kubernetes helping your team? &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/a/google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScuI7Ye3VQHQTwBASrgkjQDSS5TP0g3AXfFhwSM9YpHgxRKFA/viewform&quot;&gt;Share your story&lt;/a&gt; with the community.&lt;h3&gt;Ecosystem Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The CNCF is expanding its certification offerings to include a Certified Kubernetes Application Developer exam. The CKAD exam certifies an individual's ability to design, build, configure, and expose cloud native applications for Kubernetes. The CNCF is looking for beta testers for this new program. More information can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/blog/2018/03/16/cncf-announces-ckad-exam/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes documentation now features &lt;a href=&quot;https://k8s.io/docs/home/&quot;&gt;user journeys&lt;/a&gt;: specific pathways for learning based on who readers are and what readers want to do. Learning Kubernetes is easier than ever for beginners, and more experienced users can find task journeys specific to cluster admins and application developers. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CNCF also offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/certification/training/&quot;&gt;online training&lt;/a&gt; that teaches the skills needed to create and configure a real-world Kubernetes cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;KubeCon&lt;/h3&gt;
The world’s largest Kubernetes gathering, &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe-2018/&quot;&gt;KubeCon + CloudNativeCon&lt;/a&gt; is coming to Copenhagen from May 2-4, 2018 and will feature technical sessions, case studies, developer deep dives, salons and more! Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe-2018/program/schedule/&quot;&gt;schedule&lt;/a&gt; of speakers and &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe-2018/attend/register/&quot;&gt;register&lt;/a&gt; today!&lt;h3&gt;Webinar&lt;/h3&gt;
Join members of the Kubernetes 1.10 release team on April 10th at 10am PDT to learn about the major features in this release including Local Persistent Volumes and the Container Storage Interface (CSI). Register &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/event/webinar-kubernetes-1-10/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;h3&gt;Get Involved:&lt;/h3&gt;
The simplest way to get involved with Kubernetes is by joining one of the many &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/community/blob/master/sig-list.md&quot;&gt;Special Interest Groups&lt;/a&gt; (SIGs) that align with your interests. Have something you’d like to broadcast to the Kubernetes community? Share your voice at our weekly &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/community/blob/master/communication.md#weekly-meeting&quot;&gt;community meeting&lt;/a&gt;, and through the channels below.&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your continued feedback and support.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Post questions (or answer questions) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/kubernetes&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the community portal for advocates on &lt;a href=&quot;http://k8sport.org/&quot;&gt;K8sPort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow us on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kubernetesio&quot;&gt;@Kubernetesio&lt;/a&gt; for latest updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chat with the community on &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.k8s.io/&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share your Kubernetes &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/a/linuxfoundation.org/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScuI7Ye3VQHQTwBASrgkjQDSS5TP0g3AXfFhwSM9YpHgxRKFA/viewform&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 13:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>el_duderino</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://blog.kubernetes.io/2018/03/kubernetes-1.10-stabilizing-storage-security-networking.html</og:url>
<og:title>Kubernetes 1.10: Stabilizing Storage, Security, and Networking</og:title>
<og:description>The official Kubernetes blog.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.kubernetes.io/2018/03/kubernetes-1.10-stabilizing-storage-security-networking.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AV1  Release</title>
<link>https://aomedia.org/the-alliance-for-open-media-kickstarts-video-innovation-era-with-av1-release/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aomedia.org/the-alliance-for-open-media-kickstarts-video-innovation-era-with-av1-release/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;AV1 Unleashes 4K and Higher UHD, Royalty-Free Video for All&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WAKEFIELD, Mass., USA – March 28, 2018 –&lt;/strong&gt; Consumers’ video expectations are being shaped by the brilliant images promised by 4K Ultra High Definition (UHD) video and beyond. However, the technical-based hurdles and data demands of higher quality video mean that the majority of users only have access to full HD or lower video technology. For nearly three years, the Alliance for Open Media (AOMedia) has been working in lock-step with its members, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aomedia.org/about/&quot;&gt;world’s best-known leaders in video&lt;/a&gt;, to develop a better quality internet video technology that benefits all consumers. Today, the Alliance is proud to announce the public release of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aomedia.org/av1-features/get-started#specifcations&quot;&gt;AOMedia Video Codec 1.0 (AV1) specification,&lt;/a&gt; which delivers cross-platform, 4K UHD or higher online video, royalty-free – all while lowering data usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether watching live sports, video chatting with loved ones, or binging on a favorite show, online video is becoming a bigger part of consumers’ daily lives. In fact, video is so important to users that by 2021, 82 percent of all the world’s internet traffic will be video, according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/solutions/collateral/service-provider/visual-networking-index-vni/complete-white-paper-c11-481360.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Cisco Visual Networking Index™, 2016–2021.&lt;/a&gt; To remove many of the hurdles required by older, optical disc-era, video technologies, AOMedia developed AV1 specifically for the internet video-era, paving the way for companies to make more of the royalty-free, 4K UHD and higher video devices, products, and services that consumers love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Nearly three years after launching AOMedia, the AV1 codec addresses real bottlenecks for unleashing the highest-quality video for the entire ecosystem, allowing for better viewing experiences across all screens and data networks,” said AOMedia Executive Director Gabe Frost. “By listening to the industry’s feedback in an open and collaborative manner and bringing together leading experts to develop AV1, an entire ecosystem can begin creating video products and experiences that customers love.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By delivering 4K UHD video at an average of 30 percent greater compression over competing codecs according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://aomedia.org/news/av1-test-results/&quot;&gt;independent member tests&lt;/a&gt;, AV1 enables more screens to display the vivid images, deeper colors, brighter highlights, darker shadows, and other enhanced UHD imaging features that consumers have come to expect – all while using less data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We expect that the installed base of 4K television sets to reach 300 million by the end of 2019 and therefore there is already latent demand for UHD services over today’s infrastructure. AV1 will be widely supported across the entire content chain, especially including services. We forecast rapid introduction of AV1 content delivery to help the widespread proliferation of UHD streaming,” said Paul Gray, a Research Director at IHS Markit, a global business information provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The availability of AV1 as an open-source codec is a significant milestone in fulfilling the organization’s promise to deliver a next-generation video format that is interoperable, open, optimized for internet delivery and scalable to any modern device at any bandwidth. Designed at the outset for hardware optimization, the AV1 specification, reference code, and bindings are available for tool makers and developers to download &lt;a href=&quot;https://aomedia.org/av1-features/get-started#specifcations&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to begin designing AVI into products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the release of AV1 includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bitstream specification to enable the next-generation of silicon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unoptimized, experimental software decoder and encoder to create and consume the bitstream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reference streams for product validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binding specifications to allow content creation and streaming tools for user-generated and commercial video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the Alliance for Open Media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Launched in 2015, the Alliance for Open Media (AOMedia) was formed to define and develop media technologies to address marketplace demand for an open standard for video compression and delivery over the web. Founding Members include Amazon, Apple, Arm, Cisco, Facebook, Google, IBM, Intel, Microsoft, Mozilla, Netflix, and NVIDIA. AOMedia is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jointdevelopment.org/start-a-project.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Joint Development Foundation Projects&lt;/a&gt;, LLC series. The Joint Development Foundation is an independent nonprofit organization that provides the corporate and legal infrastructure to enable groups to establish and operate standards and source code development collaborations. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aomedia.org&quot;&gt;www.aomedia.org&lt;/a&gt; or follow AOMedia on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/a4omedia?lang=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;@a4omedia&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;AOMedia Supporting Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Founding Members&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMAZON&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“As a Founding Member of AOMedia, Amazon is committed to providing a great viewing experience for customers worldwide,” said Greg Hart, vice president of Amazon Video. “AV1’s royalty-free and compelling compression technology, once optimized, has the potential for broad adoption that will benefit customers all over the globe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“As a Founding Member of AOMedia, Arm has been actively contributing to and steering the new AV1 video codec specifications,” said Nandan Nayampally, vice president and general manager, Client Line of Business, Arm. “This is a significant effort in bringing high-quality video to mobile and consumer markets, and the Arm® Mali™ multimedia suite will deliver seamless hardware implementations of AV1.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CISCO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“The creation of an advanced, royalty-free video codec is paramount to the ongoing success of collaboration products and services,” said Jonathan Rosenberg, CTO, Collaboration Technology Group, Cisco. “This is why Cisco joined AOMedia as a Founding Member, and why Cisco has invested in making AV1 both efficient and accessible to the internet community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FACEBOOK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“As the amount of video being watched and shared online continues to grow, we are committed to making the video experience even better,” said Mike Coward, engineering director at Facebook. ” As a Founding Member of AOMedia, Facebook is proud to be directly participating in the advancement of AV1 to help achieve this mission.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOOGLE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“In 2015, Google was one of the initial Founding Members of AOMedia with the goal of producing a next-generation codec for the web. Three years later, we have achieved that goal. AV1 reflects the hard work of many technical experts, the success of open collaboration, and our commitment to royalty-free products that are accessible to everyone. Critically, the technology arrives with the support of partners throughout the web video ecosystem – content distributors, web platform providers, application developers and hardware manufacturers. AV1 is poised to power the future of media experiences consumers love to watch, upload and stream,” Matt Frost, Head of Strategy and Partnerships, Chrome Media, Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTEL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“The Alliance for Open Media AV1 codec is the result of collaboration across the industry’s biggest players who are dedicated to delivering unrivaled next-generation video experiences while transforming the ecosystem through a royalty-free, open-source approach. Intel is a Founding Member of AOM and believes the AV1 codec will provide unmatched video quality and lower delivery costs across consumer and business devices as well as the cloud’s video delivery infrastructure. We’re looking forward to delivering AV1 hardware implementations in our Intel products in the future,” Zach Hamm, Intel Director of Strategy and Planning, Visual Technologies Team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NVIDIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“Visual computing is at the core of our business,” said Matt Wuebbling, head of GeForce marketing at NVIDIA. “With ever more computing moving to the cloud, video compression is essential to delivering server-generated content to consumers. The AV1 codec enables streaming video at a higher quality than any other codec over networks with limited bandwidth — and it’s royalty-free, so there’s no barrier to incorporating it into consumer devices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MOZILLA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“Mozilla’s mission is to ensure that the internet is a global public resource, open and accessible to all, and we’ve long been focused on making sure that includes high-quality video,” said David Bryant, emerging technologies fellow at Mozilla. “Our efforts with AOMedia exemplify our commitment to making state-of-the-art video compression technology royalty-free and accessible to creators and consumers everywhere.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NETFLIX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“AV1 proves that a performant next-generation video codec can be developed with a royalty-free license, made possible by the wide-ranging industry commitment of expertise within AOMedia. Netflix is proud to have helped found and contribute to AOMedia and to validate the performance of AV1 on entertainment content, from highly efficient mobile streams to premium 4K HDR. We’re pleased to see the broad interest in decoder support and excited to bring the benefit of better streaming quality to our members in the coming year,” said Mark Watson, director, streaming standards, Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MICROSOFT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“As a Founding Member of AOMedia, Microsoft is committed to empowering the media and entertainment industry through transformative, royalty-free, open-source technology. The release of the open and interoperable AV1 video specification will empower and advance the entire ecosystem. From browsers and operating systems to devices, apps, and gaming, AV1 will drive the transformation of higher-quality 4K UHD video and beyond for more screens and devices,” said Gabe Frost, executive director of AOMedia, and principal group program manager at Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PROMOTERS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ADOBE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“Creative video and image editing software companies enable the making of hours and hours of movies and TV shows that viewers watch. But the surprisingly high cost to license basic coding technology has become a major impediment to innovation for companies trying to make content easily available to millions (billions!) of consumers, which is why Adobe is proud to be a member of the Alliance for Open Media. By collaborating with industry leaders, AOMedia has created AV1, a leading-edge and royalty-free video codec that will meet all of our customers’ needs. Bottom line: this means faster and higher resolution content is on its way at a lower cost to the consumer,” said Adobe’s Vice President of Intellectual Property and Litigation Dana Rao.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALLEGRO DVT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“Allegro DVT recognized the importance of the AV1 video format early on. We decided to join the Alliance for Open Media and have been an actively contributing member,” said Pierre Marty, CEO of Allegro DVT. “We also immediately started AV1 compliance streams product development and have now available Allegro AV1 syntax, performance and error resilience streams that have been licensed to multiple leading chip manufacturers already adopting the AV1 codec.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“AV1 offers the potential of superior video quality and interoperability across the industry,” said David Wang, senior vice president of engineering of the Radeon Technologies Group at AMD.” As a proud member of the Alliance for Open Media, AMD is committed to supporting world-class video codec technologies that enable the best media experiences for consumers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMLOGIC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“AV1 offers the industry the potential to improve video quality while using less data. With AV1’s support of 4K UHD and HDR, users will be able to take advantage of HDR-enabled content, devices, and displays. As an AOMedia member, we are proud to be part of the cross-industry collaboration. Ultimately, AV1 will enable consumers to watch more streaming media regardless of whether they are online or offline, watching on smart TVs or their mobile devices,” said James Xie, vice president, corporate business strategy at Amlogic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARGON DESIGN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“The high encoding quality and the reduced bit rates provided by AV1 will lead to its rapid adoption as the de-facto codec of choice for the entire streaming media ecosystem,” said Alan Scott, CEO of Argon Design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BITMOVIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Stefan Lederer, CEO and co-founder of Bitmovin, said: “The Alliance for Open Media’s AV1 is a game changer for video. Based on open source, it opens the door to greater innovation in the way we watch content – whether online, on mobile devices, social media – and represents a boost to the upcoming VR, AR and 360-video revolution. As an early adopter, we are proud to be the first company to have integrated AV1 into products, supporting both live streaming and video-on-demand.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BROADCOM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“AV1 offers the industry the potential to further improve video quality while using even less data than current 4K UHD and HDR video technologies. As an AOMedia member, we are proud to be part of the cross-industry collaboration to further enhance the video experience across all forms of viewing. Ultimately, AV1 will enable consumers to watch more of the streaming media they love regardless of whether they are online or offline, watching on smart TVs or their mobile devices,” said John H. Gleiter, vice president-marketing, Broadcom Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HULU&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“Improving streaming quality for our viewers has always been one of Hulu’s top priorities, which is why we are active members of industry groups like AOMedia,” said Rob Post, vice president, engineering at Hulu.” AV1 is a step in the right direction, and we look forward to working with AOMedia and other streaming media leaders to build industry standards for open, interoperable video formats.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ITTIAM SYSTEMS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“We believe that AV1 – the next-generation AOMedia video codec – is all set to define the future of online video and video compression,” said Srini Rajam, chairman and CEO, Ittiam Systems. “By leveraging our in-depth expertise, and experience in working with AOMedia members like Netflix and Google on previous generation video formats, we are working towards enabling large-scale deployments of AV1 through optimized software implementations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NGCODEC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“The need for improved compression efficiency is accelerating as consumers adopt higher quality and more immersive video experiences,” said NGCodec CEO and founder Oliver Gunasekara. “NGCodec is committed to delivering AV1 cloud encoding solutions which leverage FPGA hardware to reduce the cost of encoding by 10x vs. traditional software encoders.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOCIONEXT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“Socionext is uniquely positioned to have the capability of delivering comprehensive solutions for video streaming, based on its SoC engineering expertise covering both encoding and decoding. As a participant in the Alliance for Open Media, we are excited about the opportunity to collaborate with the other member companies to develop and provide exceptional services, which can be made possible by the next-generation video format AV1,” said Socionext CMO Tsutomu Nozaki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VIDEOLAN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“The Alliance for Open Media’s AV1 video codec is one of the best opportunities we have to finally put multimedia on the right track without having to fear hidden fees or legal threats, or resorting to sub-par quality codecs,” said Jean-Baptiste Kempf, president of the VideoLAN association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VIDYO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“AV1 is a monumental development,” said Alex Eleftheriadis, chief scientist of Vidyo and co-chair of Real-Time Communications Subgroup. “It is the first open source, royalty-free codec with state-of-the-art performance, backed by the broadest group of internet-focused technology and content delivery companies. By incorporating scalability as an integral part of AV1’s design specifically for real-time communication applications, this new codec can solve the ongoing WebRTC browser fragmentation problem, and achieve universal video interoperability across all browsers and communication devices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XILINX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“AV1 is an ideal specification for bringing royalty-free video across the entire streaming media ecosystem,” said Johan Janssen, chief video architect at Xilinx. “Xilinx FPGAs are expected to accelerate AV1 encoding by at least a factor of 10x compared to software-based encoders. Their adaptability enables optimizations across a wide range of encoding profiles, so as AV1 evolves and improves over time, FPGAs ensure that cloud data centers always have a state-of-the-art video acceleration solution.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 13:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>themihai</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Alliance for Open Media Kickstarts Video Innovation Era with &quot;AV1&quot; Release</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://aomedia.org/the-alliance-for-open-media-kickstarts-video-innovation-era-with-av1-release/</og:url>
<og:description>AV1 Unleashes 4K and Higher UHD, Royalty-Free Video for All WAKEFIELD, Mass., USA – March 28, 2018 – Consumers' video expectations are being shaped by the brilliant images promised by 4K Ultra High Definition (UHD) video and beyond. However, the technical-based hurdles and data demands of higher quality video mean that the majority of users only</og:description>
<og:image>https://aomedia.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/aomedia_logo_200.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aomedia.org/the-alliance-for-open-media-kickstarts-video-innovation-era-with-av1-release/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Are you ready? This is all the data Facebook and Google have on you</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/mar/28/all-the-data-facebook-google-has-on-you-privacy</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/mar/28/all-the-data-facebook-google-has-on-you-privacy</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;ant to freak yourself out? I’m going to show just how much of your information the likes of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and Google store about you without you even realising it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google knows where you’ve been&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google stores your location (if you have location tracking turned on) every time you turn on your phone. You can see a timeline of where you’ve been from the very first day you started using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/google&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on this link to see your own data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/timeline?pb&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;google.com/maps/timeline?…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is every place I have been in the last 12 months in Ireland. You can see the time of day that I was in the location and how long it took me to get to that location from my previous one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;A Google map of every place I’ve been in Ireland this year.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/8807ef46be77f95fb9d7378420b056d44d58004d/129_0_1070_642/master/1070.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=0b7eebbdaf987b4f58ac4140935e7ac4&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

‘A Google map of every place I’ve been in Ireland this year.’ Photograph: Dylan Curran
&lt;h2&gt;Google knows everything you’ve ever searched – and deleted&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google stores search history across all your devices. That can mean that, even if you delete your search history and phone history on one device, it may still have data saved from other devices&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on this link to see your own data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://myactivity.google.com/myactivity&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;myactivity.google.com/myactivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-2 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Google has an advertisement profile of you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google creates an advertisement profile based on your information, including your location, gender, age, hobbies, career, interests, relationship status, possible weight (need to lose 10lb in one day?) and income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on this link to see your own data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/settings/ads/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;google.com/settings/ads/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google knows all the apps you use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google stores information on every app and extension you use. They know how often you use them, where you use them, and who you use them to interact with. That means they know who you talk to on Facebook, what countries are you speaking with, what time you go to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on this link to see your own data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://security.google.com/settings/security/permissions&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;security.google.com/settings/secur…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google has all of your YouTube history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google stores &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of your YouTube history, so they probably know whether you’re going to be a parent soon, if you’re a conservative, if you’re a progressive, if you’re Jewish, Christian, or Muslim, if you’re feeling depressed or suicidal, if you’re anorexic …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on this link to see your own data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/feed/history/search_history&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;youtube.com/feed/history/s…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The data Google has on you can fill millions of Word documents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google offers an option to download all of the data it stores about you. I’ve requested to download it and the file is 5.5GB &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt;, which is roughly 3m Word documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;Manage to gain access to someone’s Google account? Perfect, you have a diary of everything that person has done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;This link includes your bookmarks, emails, contacts, your Google Drive files, all of the above information, your YouTube videos, the photos you’ve taken on your phone, the businesses you’ve bought from, the products you’ve bought through Google …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also have data from your calendar, your Google hangout sessions, your location history, the music you listen to, the Google books you’ve purchased, the Google groups you’re in, the websites you’ve created, the phones you’ve owned, the pages you’ve shared, how many steps you walk in a day …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on this link to see your own data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/takeout&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;google.com/takeout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Facebook has reams and reams of data on you, too&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook offers a similar option to download all your information. Mine was roughly 600MB, which is roughly 400,000 Word documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This includes every message you’ve ever sent or been sent, every file you’ve ever sent or been sent, all the contacts in your phone, and all the audio messages you’ve ever sent or been sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here to see your data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/help/131112897028467&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/help/131112897028467&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;A snapshot of the data Facebook has saved on me.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/2c967a570e20258286a3d0722effabdca6c1cb2e/0_183_1046_628/master/1046.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=cdd37560df65face04c7d42c4758c048&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

‘A snapshot of the data Facebook has saved on me.’ Photograph: Dylan Curran
&lt;h2&gt;Facebook stores everything from your stickers to your login location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook also stores what it thinks you might be interested in based off the things you’ve liked and what you and your friends talk about (I apparently like the topic “girl”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat pointlessly, they also store all the stickers you’ve ever sent on Facebook (I have no idea why they do this. It’s just a joke at this stage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also store every time you log in to Facebook, where you logged in from, what time, and from what device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they store all the applications you’ve ever had connected to your Facebook account, so they can guess I’m interested in politics and web and graphic design, that I was single between X and Y period with the installation of Tinder, and I got a HTC phone in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Side note, if you have Windows 10 installed, this is a picture of &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; the privacy options with 16 different sub-menus, which have all of the options enabled by default when you install Windows 10)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Privacy options in Facebook.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/b2a28723e6d5e41c3757d6eae63535388cf155a4/0_0_1200_720/master/1200.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=7c6eea03687ec7ed66cbb70d1b9d9bdc&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Privacy options in Facebook. Photograph: Dylan Curran
&lt;h2&gt;They can access your webcam and microphone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data they collect includes tracking where you are, what applications you have installed, when you use them, what you use them for, access to your webcam and microphone at any time, your contacts, your emails, your calendar, your call history, the messages you send and receive, the files you download, the games you play, your photos and videos, your music, your search history, your browsing history, even what radio stations you listen to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-2 | 2&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Here are some of the different ways Google gets your data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got the Google Takeout document with all my information, and this is a breakdown of all the different ways they get your information.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;My Google Takeout document.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a878835b3fb42028b8359804ae8e9749c4e0296b/0_33_1045_627/master/1045.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=12f75d14c9fc649b5b5af95cf6aaf0cf&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

‘My Google Takeout document.’ Photograph: Dylan Curran
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the search history document, which has 90,000 different entries, even showing the images I downloaded and the websites I accessed (I showed the Pirate Bay section to show how much damage this information can do).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;data&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/98c278edcd3b01f07a763ed42e7e69b72a6c8dc8/196_0_808_485/master/808.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=4ff85622385abcfd3ea9dc06f0c01078&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

‘My search history document has 90,000 different entries.’ Photograph: Dylan Curran
&lt;h2&gt;Google knows which events you attended, and when&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my Google Calendar broken down, showing all the events I’ve ever added, whether I actually attended them, and what time I attended them at (this part is when I went for an interview for a marketing job, and what time I arrived).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;data&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/2408e81c138f9444053b56a8716721cc9de34650/41_0_1017_610/master/1017.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=7e4a6b6482b745e6539b9054e5e49bb5&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

‘Here is my Google calendar showing a job interview I attended.’ Photograph: Dylan Curran
&lt;h2&gt;And Google has information you deleted&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my Google Drive, which includes files I &lt;em&gt;explicitly&lt;/em&gt; deleted including my résumé, my monthly budget, and all the code, files and websites I’ve ever made, and even my PGP private key, which I deleted, that I use to encrypt emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;data&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/7c44cec69c92ea03b72778dc0377b9e784e0ba6f/0_5_1044_626/master/1044.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=f93f5c00c569d955da46b1ed1a652830&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Google can know your workout routine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my Google Fit, which shows all of the steps I’ve ever taken, any time I walked anywhere, and all the times I’ve recorded any meditation/yoga/workouts I’ve done (I deleted this information and revoked Google Fit’s permissions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;data&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6187f204c6a11807bab3078e37d4bcafdd92fa30/0_119_762_457/master/762.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=4ea5917b3bb80f3121f24ea3e7d559ed&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;And they have years’ worth of photos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all the photos ever taken with my phone, broken down by year, and includes metadata of when and where I took the photos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;data&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/4dac4ddaa2b42076b8c3688ac6f258f30995de08/0_3_1055_633/master/1055.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=4c968995de34c011ae548f7f05eb6a4c&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Google has every email you ever sent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every email I’ve ever sent, that’s been sent to me, including the ones I deleted or were categorised as spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;data&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/bdf0ab62ea318b0c2b1aa113597eb3a5bfd4cc20/12_0_1177_706/master/1177.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=9d6f9e3a5468a4a56431bea5b1804609&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;And there is more&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll just do a short summary of what’s in the thousands of files I received under my Google Activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, every Google Ad I’ve ever viewed or clicked on, every app I’ve ever launched or used and when I did it, every website I’ve ever visited and what time I did it at, and every app I’ve ever installed or searched for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;data&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/42522522e2e40045bdca3bf94a9551038a866120/0_82_1005_603/master/1005.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=8b36de248f55c4b44f9fba4297844aee&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

‘They have every single Google search I’ve made since 2009.’
&lt;p&gt;They also have every image I’ve ever searched for and saved, every location I’ve ever searched for or clicked on, every news article I’ve ever searched for or read, and &lt;em&gt;every single&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Google search&lt;/em&gt; I’ve made since 2009. And then finally, every YouTube video I’ve ever searched for or viewed, since 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This information has millions of nefarious uses. You say you’re not a terrorist. Then how come you were googling Isis? Work at Google and you’re suspicious of your wife? Perfect, just look up her location and search history for the last 10 years. Manage to gain access to someone’s Google account? Perfect, you have a chronological diary of everything that person has done for the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the craziest things about the modern age. We would never let the government or a corporation put cameras/microphones in our homes or location trackers on us. But we just went ahead and did it ourselves because – to hell with it! – I want to watch cute dog videos.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 13:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bookofjoe</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/mar/28/all-the-data-facebook-google-has-on-you-privacy</og:url>
<og:description>The harvesting of our personal details goes far beyond what many of us could imagine. So I braced myself and had a look</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/2c967a570e20258286a3d0722effabdca6c1cb2e/0_92_1046_628/master/1046.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19vcGluaW9ucy5wbmc&amp;s=bdb3b96570859d80e590f17df760e003</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Are you ready? This is all the data Facebook and Google have on you | Dylan Curran</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/mar/28/all-the-data-facebook-google-has-on-you-privacy</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: A site that makes Spotify playlists of bands coming to town</title>
<link>http://www.nextweeksplaylist.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.nextweeksplaylist.com</guid>
<description>&quot;).addClass(&quot;band-item&quot;);
                $li.append($(&quot;&lt;p&gt;&quot;).html(&quot;&lt;b&gt;&quot; + bandShow.name + &quot;&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;em&gt;&quot; + bandShow.date + &quot;&lt;/em&gt;&quot;));
                $(&quot;#bandlist&quot;).append($li);
              });
            },
            complete: function() {
              $(&quot;#getBands&quot;).remove();
              $(&quot;.bandlist&quot;).addClass(&quot;invisible&quot;); //Resize first
              $(&quot;.bandlist&quot;).removeClass(&quot;hidden&quot;);
              setTimeout(function() {
                $(&quot;.bandlist-loading&quot;).addClass(&quot;hidden&quot;);
                $(&quot;.bandlist&quot;).removeClass(&quot;invisible&quot;);
              }, 100);
            }
          });
  
          return false;
        });
      });
  
      window.markers[venue.id] = marker;
      window.venues[venue.id] = venue;
  
      var showAllVenues = $('input#showAllVenues').prop('checked');
      if (!showAllVenues) {
        if (venue.show_count &amp;gt; 0) {
          marker.setMap(map);
        }
      } else {
        marker.setMap(map);
      }
  
      if (venue.show_count &amp;gt; 0) {
        return { location: position, weight: venue.show_count / 100.0 };
      }
    }).compact().value();
  
    var heatmap = new google.maps.visualization.HeatmapLayer({
      data: heatMapData
      , radius: 20
      , map: map
    });
  };
  
  var updateVenuePopup = function(venue) {
    window.infoWindowContent[venue.id] = generateInfoContent(venue);
  
    if (window.currentVenue === venue) {
      var addRemove = venue.selected ? 'remove' : 'add';
      var link = $(&quot;span.venue-info-map[data-venue-id='&quot; + venue.id + &quot;']&quot;);
      var icon = $(&quot;span.venue-info-map[data-venue-id='&quot; + venue.id + &quot;'] .icon&quot;);
      var onclick = addRemove + &quot;VenueClickHandler('&quot; + venue.id.replace(&quot;'&quot;, &quot;\\'&quot;) + '\',\'' + venue.name.replace(&quot;'&quot;, &quot;\\'&quot;) + '\')';
  
      link.attr(&quot;onclick&quot;, onclick);
      icon.removeClass();
      icon.addClass(&quot;icon&quot;);
      icon.addClass(addRemove + &quot;-icon&quot;);
    }
  };
  
  $(function() {
    $('#user_venues_genres').on('new-items', function() {
      var venues = $('#venue_map').data('heat-maps');
      var selectedVenues = $(&quot;#user_venues_genres&quot;).select2(&quot;data&quot;);
      _(venues).each(function(venue) {
        if (_(selectedVenues).find(function(selectedVenue) { return selectedVenue.id === venue.id; })) {
          if (window.currentVenue === venue) {
            venue.follower_count += 1;
          }
          venue.selected = true;
          updateVenuePopup(venue);
        } else {
          if (window.currentVenue === venue) {
            venue.follower_count -= 1;
          }
          venue.selected = false;
          updateVenuePopup(venue);
        }
      });
    });
  
    $(&quot;input#showAllVenues&quot;).on(&quot;change&quot;, function() {
      _(window.markers).each(function(marker, venueId) {
        if (!$(&quot;input#showAllVenues&quot;).prop(&quot;checked&quot;)) {
          if (window.venues[venueId].show_count &amp;gt; 0) {
            marker.setMap(window.map);
          } else {
            marker.setMap(null);
          }
        } else {
          marker.setMap(window.map);
        }
      });
    });
  
    $(&quot;#fullmapToggle&quot;).on(&quot;click&quot;, function(event) {
      if ($(&quot;body&quot;).hasClass(&quot;fullscreen&quot;)) {
        var $map = $(&quot;#mapView&quot;);
        $map.detach();
        $(&quot;#map_holder&quot;).append($map);
        $(&quot;body&quot;).removeClass(&quot;fullscreen&quot;);
  
        $('html,body').scrollTop($(&quot;a[name=GetStarted]&quot;).offset().top);
        var center = window.map.getCenter()
        google.maps.event.trigger(window.map, 'resize');
        window.map.setCenter(center);
        window.map.setZoom(window.map.getZoom() - 1);
  
        return false;
      } else {
        var $map = $(&quot;#mapView&quot;);
        $map.detach();
        $(&quot;body&quot;).append($map);
        $(&quot;body&quot;).addClass(&quot;fullscreen&quot;);
  
        var center = window.map.getCenter()
        google.maps.event.trigger(window.map, 'resize');
        window.map.setCenter(center);
        window.map.setZoom(window.map.getZoom() + 1);
      }
    });
  });


&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 13:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>slashblake</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Next Week's Playlist</og:title>
<og:description>Follow your favorite venues. Get a weekly playlist. Discover upcoming bands!</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.nextweeksplaylist.com</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.nextweeksplaylist.com/adimage.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nextweeksplaylist.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quit Social Media, Your Career May Depend on It (2016)</title>
<link>https://mobile.nytimes.com/2016/11/20/jobs/quit-social-media-your-career-may-depend-on-it.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mobile.nytimes.com/2016/11/20/jobs/quit-social-media-your-career-may-depend-on-it.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;45.237752161383&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-fb2i0r emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;36.386887608069&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;I’m a millennial computer scientist who also writes books and runs a blog. Demographically speaking I should be a heavy social media user, but that is not the case. I’ve never had a social media account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At the moment, this makes me an outlier, but I think many more people should follow my lead and quit these services. There are many issues with social media, from its corrosion of civic life to its cultural shallowness, but the argument I want to make here is more pragmatic: You should quit social media because it can hurt your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;This claim, of course, runs counter to our current understanding of social media’s role in the professional sphere. We’ve been told that it’s important to tend to your so-called social media brand, as this provides you access to opportunities you might otherwise miss and supports the diverse contact network you need to get ahead. Many people in my generation fear that without a social media presence, they would be invisible to the job market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://nymag.com/selectall/2016/09/andrew-sullivan-technology-almost-killed-me.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;New York magazine essay&lt;/a&gt;, Andrew Sullivan recalled when he started to feel obligated to update his blog every half-hour or so. It seemed as if everyone with a Facebook account and a smartphone now felt pressured to run their own high-stress, one-person media operation, and “the once-unimaginable pace of the professional blogger was now the default for everyone,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;51&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-fb2i0r emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;47&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;I think this behavior is misguided. In a capitalist economy, the market rewards things that are rare and valuable. Social media use is decidedly not rare or valuable. Any 16-year-old with a smartphone can invent a hashtag or repost a viral article. The idea that if you engage in enough of this low-value activity, it will somehow add up to something of high value in your career is the same dubious alchemy that forms the core of most snake oil and flimflam in business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Professional success is hard, but it’s not complicated. The foundation to achievement and fulfillment, almost without exception, requires that you hone a useful craft and then apply it to things that people care about. This is a philosophy perhaps best summarized by the advice Steve Martin used to give aspiring entertainers: “Be so good they can’t ignore you.” If you do that, the rest will work itself out, regardless of the size of your Instagram following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A common response to my social media skepticism is the idea that using these services “can’t hurt.” In addition to honing skills and producing things that are valuable, my critics note, why not also expose yourself to the opportunities and connections that social media can generate? I have two objections to this line of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;First, interesting opportunities and useful connections are not as scarce as social media proponents claim. In my own professional life, for example, as I improved my standing as an academic and a writer, I began receiving more interesting opportunities than I could handle. I currently have filters on my website aimed at &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;reducing&lt;/em&gt;, not increasing, the number of offers and introductions I receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;My research on successful professionals underscores that this experience is common: As you become more valuable to the marketplace, good things will find you. To be clear, I’m not arguing that new opportunities and connections are unimportant. I’m instead arguing that you don’t need social media’s help to attract them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;50&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-fb2i0r emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;45&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;My second objection concerns the idea that social media is harmless. Consider that the ability to concentrate without distraction on hard tasks is becoming increasingly valuable in an increasingly complicated economy. Social media weakens this skill because it’s engineered to be addictive. The more you use social media in the way it’s designed to be used — persistently throughout your waking hours — the more your brain learns to crave a quick hit of stimulus at the slightest hint of boredom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Once this Pavlovian connection is solidified, it becomes hard to give difficult tasks the unbroken concentration they require, and your brain simply won’t tolerate such a long period without a fix. Indeed, part of my own rejection of social media comes from this fear that these services will diminish my ability to concentrate — the skill on which I make my living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The idea of purposefully introducing into my life a service designed to fragment my attention is as scary to me as the idea of smoking would be to an endurance athlete, and it should be to you if you’re serious about creating things that matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Perhaps more important, however, than my specific objections to the idea that social media is a harmless lift to your career, is my general unease with the mind-set this belief fosters. A dedication to cultivating your social media brand is a fundamentally passive approach to professional advancement. It diverts your time and attention away from producing work that matters and toward convincing the world that &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; matter. The latter activity is seductive, especially for many members of my generation who were raised on this message, but it can be disastrously counterproductive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Most social media is best described as a collection of somewhat trivial entertainment services that are currently having a good run. These networks are fun, but you’re deluding yourself if you think that Twitter messages, posts and likes are a productive use of your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;If you’re serious about making an impact in the world, power down your smartphone, close your browser tabs, roll up your sleeves and get to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;29.973684210526&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ExtendedInformation-extendedInformation--3og6I ExtendedInformation-news--2QoWo&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cal Newport is an associate professor of computer science at Georgetown University and the author of “Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World” (Grand Central).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 11:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>navinsylvester</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/20/jobs/quit-social-media-your-career-may-depend-on-it.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Quit Social Media. Your Career May Depend on It.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2016/11/20/business/20PRE/20PRE-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Our increasing addiction to the constant stimulus of updates, likes and posts is damaging our ability to concentrate deeply and focus on work that matters.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.nytimes.com/2016/11/20/jobs/quit-social-media-your-career-may-depend-on-it.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Just one QUIC bit</title>
<link>https://blog.apnic.net/2018/03/28/just-one-quic-bit/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.apnic.net/2018/03/28/just-one-quic-bit/</guid>
<description>&lt;img width=&quot;555&quot; height=&quot;202&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/quic-start-555x202.jpg&quot; class=&quot;attachment-featuredImageLarge size-featuredImageLarge wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/quic-start.jpg 555w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/quic-start-300x109.jpg 300w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/quic-start-206x75.jpg 206w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/quic-start-256x93.jpg 256w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 555px) 100vw, 555px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m never surprised by the ability of an IETF Working Group to obsess over what to any outside observer would appear to be a completely trivial matter.  Even so, I was impressed to see a large-scale discussion emerge over a single bit in a transport protocol being standardized by the IETF.  Is this an example of a severe overload of obsessive compulsive behaviour? Or does this single bit represent a major point of design principle, and was the extended discussion about that design principle rather than the use of the bit itself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transport protocol under consideration here is QUIC. QUIC was originally developed by Google, and is in use by their Chrome browser and by various Google servers. Given the extensive use of Chrome in the Internet, and the extensive use of Google services by Internet users, the obvious corollary is that QUIC is used extensively in the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QUIC is a version of an end-to-end transport control protocol that eschews the traditional use of TCP and uses UDP instead. However, QUIC behaves in a manner that is approximately consistent with TCP behaviour, and it is intended to function more predictably and potentially produce better outcomes than TCP in many conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way it achieves this feat is to treat the UDP transport layer as identical to IP itself, which is largely the purpose of UDP, and use a TCP-like protocol as an “inner” protocol one level lower than UDP. The devil is in the details here, and in this case the detail is that this UDP payload is encrypted. This means that QUIC’s pseudo-TCP session control information is hidden within the encryption veil, and the shared TCP state is a secret that is shared between the two end systems of the communication but occluded from all other parts of the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if you last saw a description of the Internet architecture back in 1990, and you’ve been sleeping since then, this deliberate occlusion of the end-to-end transport protocol would not raise your eyebrows at all. The network’s switching systems were only supposed to look at the outer IP packet header, and the inner payload was to be exclusively used by the two end systems (this explains IP packet fragmentation behaviour, where the IP packet header was replicated across all the fragmented packets, but the inner transport protocol header is only contained within the first fragment). If networks are not meant to look further into an IP packet header than just the IP header, then why should it matter whether the transport layer protocol is hidden by encryption or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, theory and practice have headed down widely divergent paths over the past thirty years. Since 1990, network operators of all shapes, sizes and roles have become accustomed, or even addicted, to seeing deeply inside the IP packet. The firewalls that are ubiquitously deployed in today’s networks use the inner transport protocol port numbers to guide the accept or reject decisions. Then there is the NAT function, where the 5-tuple of protocol, source and destination addresses and the source and destination port numbers is used as a lookup vector into a translation table, and both the IP and the inner transport packet headers are altered by the NAT before passing the packet onward. This inspection and potential modification of the transport headers goes further than just NATs. Many network operators use the IP and transport packet headers to perform traffic engineering functions, packet interception and forced proxy caching. Various forms of middleware may reach into the TCP control fields and manipulate these values to modify session flow rates. All of these activities are commonplace, and some network operators see this as an essential part of their service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Google offered the IETF the opportunity to take the work on QUIC and produce an open standard that could be used by all, it excited a debate within the IETF as to how much transport information should be deliberately occluded from the network. The general principle used by QUIC appears to be to expose as little as possible, and in the short form QUIC header what’s left is basically a connection identifier and a packet number. The proposal that was considered by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/quic/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;QUIC Working Group&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/101/session/quic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;recent IETF 101 meeting&lt;/a&gt; was simple: to add a further single bit to this open part of the QUIC header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bit, the “spin bit” is intended to be used by passive observers on the network path to expose the round trip time of the connection. The management of the bit’s value is simple: the server simply echoes the last seen value of the bit in all packets sent in this connection. The client echoes the complement of the last seen bit when sending packets to the server. The result is that when there is a continuous sequence of packets in each direction this spin bit is flipped between 0 and 1 in time intervals of one Round Trip Time (RTT). Not only is this RTT time signature visible at each end, but it is visible to any on-path observer as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Is exposing this spin bit “safe”?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some claim that exposing this bit, and the associated ability by onlookers on the traffic path to derive the connection RTT, is reasonable and the information exposed here does not represent any particular harm to the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others take the view that the gratuitous exposure of any information beyond the IP header and the base essentials of a UDP header is both unnecessary and unsafe. There is no compelling protocol reason for this spin bit to be exposed, and there is an unknown factor in how this bit may be used were it to be added to the protocol. The sad history of meddlesome middleware appears to support this cautious view, where what was seen as a helpful intervention to gratuitously leak information becomes a point of potential breakage and even a potential data breach. Their view is that even the deliberate exposure of one purportedly harmless bit takes QUIC down an irreversible path. They point to the advocacy of the use of two, three or even more of these bits that could be used to expose packet loss rates, jitter or more. At some point these bits expose the same level of session control information that was in the now encrypted TCP header and the entire point of QUIC’s efforts to elude the meddlesome and ossifying grip of network middleware is lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s raise the level and think about the larger issues that are exposed by this debate within the IETF QUIC Working Group for a second. Is it even possible for these large disparate groups of people to exercise careful and considered constraint in the area of protocol design? Can a set of highly focused technicians looking at a technical matter of protocol behaviour also factor in a broader understanding on the compromises between privacy and exposure in the domain of a public communications realm and reach a common understanding of where and how to balance these factors? It sure looks unlikely these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these issues are by no means recent matters. When we look at the original Internet Protocol design we see evidence of similar balancing of such factors, and the decisions made at the time would probably never be made in today’s context. As an example of these changing circumstances, the open mutual trust assumptions that underpinned many of the Internet’s protocol developments in years gone by are being turned against us in the forms of hostile crippling attacks. Were these protocols poorly designed at the time? Would we have thought about the protocols in a different light had we factored in the assumption that the environment of deployment would be both truly massive and truly toxically hostile?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we asking too much of the IETF in its efforts to undertake a group grope towards some ill-defined concept of “rough consensus”? We should bear in mind that the process of attempting to accommodate widely divergent motives and produce a coherent outcome suffers from the same fundamental flaws as the design process that lead to the extremely odd design choice of the 53 byte ATM cell. Sometimes difficult choices admit to no sensible compromise between them and the process simply has to make a contentious decision one way or the other. While individuals make such decisions all the time, the collective process that enlists a large group of diverse perspectives, interests and motivations finds such decision making extraordinarily challenging. Little wonder that they often fail at the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was it a helpful action by Google to push their implementation of QUIC into the open source domain and request the IETF process to produce a standard open specification? It has certainly triggered a useful conversation in the IETF’s transport area about the degree to which applications and end-to-end data flows should be exposed to the network, or even whether any level of exposure is just too much, but at the same time it is unclear how the IETF can use its processes to make difficult decisions about where to draw the lines here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What emerges from all this is the observation that if you want to expose your session control state to the network, and have network middleware observe and potentially tamper with that session state, then TCP is a fine choice of end-to-end transport protocol. If you would prefer to keep your end-to-end transport session state as something known only to you and the party with whom you are communicating, then maybe you should use Google’s version of QUIC. And where does the IETF version of QUIC sit? It’s completely unclear where the IETF is heading in this respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cynical view would see the IETF as being incapable of holding the line that the end-to-end control state should be completely withheld from the network, and this spin bit is just one more step along an inexorable path of compromise that once more ends up gratuitously exposing users’ actions to the network. There is probably a less cynical view as well, but I just can’t think what it may be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;rw-rating-table rw-ltr rw-left&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;Rate this article&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;views-disclaimer&quot;&gt;The views expressed by the authors of this blog are their own and do not necessarily reflect the views of APNIC. Please note a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.apnic.net/?p=395&quot;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; applies to this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 06:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>okket</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Just one QUIC bit | APNIC Blog</og:title>
<og:description>A proposal to add a &quot;spin bit&quot; to the QUIC protocol sparked much debate at IETF 101.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.apnic.net/2018/03/28/just-one-quic-bit/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/quic-start.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.apnic.net/2018/03/28/just-one-quic-bit/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>