<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Why is Stack Overflow trying to start audio?</title>
<link>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/386487/why-is-stack-overflow-trying-to-start-audio</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/386487/why-is-stack-overflow-trying-to-start-audio</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The ad is attempting to use the Audio API as one of literally hundreds of pieces of data it is collecting about your browser in an attempt to &quot;fingerprint&quot; it, to uniquely identify you across sites despite your privacy settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't general speculation; I've spent the last half hour going though the source code you linked above, and it goes to considerable lengths to de-anonymize viewers. Your browser may be blocking this particular API, but it's not blocking most of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've included several examples below. To be absolutely clear, &lt;strong&gt;this logic is not being used for legitimate feature detection&lt;/strong&gt;. The results of these checks are not used to enable/disable parts of the ad; they're only used in aggregate to generate a user fingerprint, which the ad includes along with the advertising ID when recording analytics for the publisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It detects your system's resolution and accessibility settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;function &quot;==typeof matchMedia&amp;amp;&amp;amp;a239.a341.a77 (&quot;
all and(min--moz - device - pixel - ratio: 0) and(min - resolution: .001 dpcm)
&quot;)},function(){return&quot;
function &quot;==typeof matchMedia&amp;amp;&amp;amp;a239.a341.a77 (&quot;
all and(-moz - images - in -menus: 0) and(min - resolution: .001 dpcm)
&quot;)},function(){return&quot;
function &quot;==typeof matchMedia&amp;amp;&amp;amp;a239.a341.a77 (&quot;
screen and(-ms - high - contrast: active) and(-webkit - min - device - pixel - ratio: 0), (-ms - high - contrast: none) and(-webkit - min - device - pixel - ratio: 0)
&quot;)},function(){return&quot;
function &quot;==typeof matchMedia&amp;amp;&amp;amp;a239.a341.a77 (&quot;
screen and(-webkit - min - device - pixel - ratio: 0)
&quot;)},function(){return&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks for the presence of vendor-specific cryptography APIs,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;return &quot;function&quot; == typeof MSCredentials &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a239.a341.a66(MSCredentials)
    }, function() {
        return &quot;function&quot; == typeof MSFIDOSignature &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a239.a341.a66(MSFIDOSignature)
    }, function() {
        return &quot;function&quot; == typeof MSManipulationEvent &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a239.a341.a66(MSManipulationEvent)
    }, function() {
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks at the list of fonts you have installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;    return &quot;object&quot; == typeof document &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a239.a341.a68(&quot;fonts&quot;, document.fonts)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It detects which Audio API capabilities your browser supports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;    return &quot;undefined&quot; != typeof window &amp;amp;&amp;amp; &quot;undefined&quot; !== window.StereoPatternNode &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a239.a341.a66(window.StereoPannerNode)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It detects which mobile browser-specific APIs you support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;    return &quot;function&quot; == typeof AppBannerPromptResult &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a239.a341.a66(AppBannerPromptResult)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It checks for platform-specific DRM support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;}, function() {
    return !!a239.a341.a72() &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a239.a341.a66(a239.a341.a72().webkitGenerateKeyRequest) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a239.a341.a66(a239.a341.a72().webkitCancelKeyRequest) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a239.a341.a66(a239.a341.a72().webkitSetMediaKeys) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a239.a341.a66(a239.a341.a72().webkitAddKey)
}, function() {
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It detects a hundred other things but this post is long enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use an ad blocker!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 20:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>iokanuon</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/386487/why-is-stack-overflow-trying-to-start-audio</og:url>
<og:image>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/content/Sites/stackoverflowmeta/img/apple-touch-icon@2.png?v=6de7587d1583</og:image>
<og:title>Why is Stack Overflow trying to start audio?</og:title>
<og:description>I often have my browser's devtools open since I'm often debugging a snippet. I noticed this message often recently: Why is Stack Overflow trying to start audio? Update. I see it's from an ad? h...</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/386487/why-is-stack-overflow-trying-to-start-audio</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Next steps toward Go 2</title>
<link>https://blog.golang.org/go2-next-steps</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.golang.org/go2-next-steps</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;26 June 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_1.&quot;&gt;Status&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re well on the way towards the release of Go 1.13, hopefully in early August of this year. This is the first release that will include concrete changes to the language (rather than just minor adjustments to the spec), after a longer moratorium on any such changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To arrive at these language changes, we started out with a small set of viable proposals, selected from the much larger list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/golang/go/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3AGo2+label%3AProposal&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Go 2 proposals&lt;/a&gt;, per the new proposal evaluation process outlined in the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go2-here-we-come&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Go 2, here we come!&lt;/a&gt;” blog post. We wanted our initial selection of proposals to be relatively minor and mostly uncontroversial, to have a reasonably high chance of having them make it through the process. The proposed changes had to be backward-compatible to be minimally disruptive since &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/using-go-modules&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;modules&lt;/a&gt;, which eventually will allow module-specific language version selection, are not the default build mode quite yet. In short, this initial round of changes was more about getting the ball rolling again and gaining experience with the new process, rather than tackling big issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go2-here-we-come&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;original list of proposals&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/20706&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;general Unicode identifiers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/19308&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;binary integer literals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/28493&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;separators for number literals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/19113&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;signed integer shift counts&lt;/a&gt; – got both trimmed and expanded. The general Unicode identifiers didn’t make the cut as we didn’t have a concrete design document in place in time. The proposal for binary integer literals was expanded significantly and led to a comprehensive overhaul and modernization of &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/design/19308-number-literals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Go’s number literal syntax&lt;/a&gt;. And we added the Go 2 draft design proposal on &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/design/go2draft-error-inspection&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;error inspection&lt;/a&gt;, which has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/29934#issuecomment-489682919&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;partially accepted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these initial changes in place for Go 1.13, it’s now time to look forward to Go 1.14 and determine what we want to tackle next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_2.&quot;&gt;Proposals for Go 1.14&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goals we have for Go today are the same as in 2007: to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/toward-go2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;make software development scale&lt;/a&gt;. The three biggest hurdles on this path to improved scalability for Go are package and version management, better error handling support, and generics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Go module support getting increasingly stronger, support for package and version management is being addressed. This leaves better error handling support and generics. We have been working on both of these and presented &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/design/go2draft&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;draft designs&lt;/a&gt; at last year’s GopherCon in Denver. Since then we have been iterating those designs. For error handling, we have published a concrete, significantly revised and simplified proposal (see below). For generics, we are making progress, with a talk (“Generics in Go” by Ian Lance Taylor) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gophercon.com/agenda/session/49028&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;coming up&lt;/a&gt; at this year’s GopherCon in San Diego, but we have not reached the concrete proposal stage yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also want to continue with smaller improvements to the language. For Go 1.14, we have selected the following proposals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/32437&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#32437&lt;/a&gt;. A built-in Go error check function, “try” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/design/32437-try-builtin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;design doc&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our concrete proposal for improved error handling. While the proposed, fully backwards-compatible language extension is minimal, we expect an outsize impact on error handling code. This proposal has already attracted an enormous amount of comments, and it’s not easy to follow up. We recommend starting with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/32437#issue-452239211&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;initial comment&lt;/a&gt; for a quick outline and then to read the detailed design doc. The initial comment contains a couple of links leading to summaries of the feedback so far. Please follow the feedback recommendations (see the “Next steps” section below) before posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/6977&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#6977&lt;/a&gt;. Allow embedding overlapping interfaces (&lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/design/6977-overlapping-interfaces&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;design doc&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an old, backwards-compatible proposal for making interface embedding more tolerant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/32479&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#32479&lt;/a&gt; Diagnose &lt;code&gt;string(int)&lt;/code&gt; conversion in &lt;code&gt;go vet&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;string(int)&lt;/code&gt; conversion was introduced early in Go for convenience, but it is confusing to newcomers (&lt;code&gt;string(10)&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;&quot;\n&quot;&lt;/code&gt; not &lt;code&gt;&quot;10&quot;&lt;/code&gt;) and not justified anymore now that the conversion is available in the &lt;code&gt;unicode/utf8&lt;/code&gt; package. Since removing this conversion is not a backwards-compatible change, we propose to start with a &lt;code&gt;vet&lt;/code&gt; error instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/32466&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#32466&lt;/a&gt; Adopt crypto principles (&lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/design/cryptography-principles&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;design doc&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a request for feedback on a set of design principles for cryptographic libraries that we would like to adopt. See also the related &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issue/32716&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;proposal to remove SSLv3 support&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;code&gt;crypto/tls&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_3.&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are actively soliciting feedback on all these proposals. We are especially interested in fact-based evidence illustrating why a proposal might not work well in practice, or problematic aspects we might have missed in the design. Convincing examples in support of a proposal are also very helpful. On the other hand, comments containing only personal opinions are less actionable: we can acknowledge them but we can’t address them in any constructive way. Before posting, please take the time to read the detailed design docs and prior feedback or feedback summaries. Especially in long discussions, your concern may have already been raised and discussed in earlier comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless there are strong reasons to not even proceed into the experimental phase with a given proposal, we are planning to have all these implemented at the start of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/wiki/Go-Release-Cycle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Go 1.14 cycle&lt;/a&gt; (beginning of August, 2019) so that they can be evaluated in practice. Per the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go2-here-we-come&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;proposal evaluation process&lt;/a&gt;, the final decision will be made at the end of the development cycle (beginning of November, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for helping making Go a better language!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;By Robert Griesemer, for the Go team&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 17:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rom16384</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.golang.org/go2-next-steps</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘Pre-bunk’ game reduces susceptibility to disinformation</title>
<link>https://www.cam.ac.uk/research/news/fake-news-vaccine-works-pre-bunk-game-reduces-susceptibility-to-disinformation</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cam.ac.uk/research/news/fake-news-vaccine-works-pre-bunk-game-reduces-susceptibility-to-disinformation</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;An online game in which people play the role of propaganda producers to help them identify real world disinformation has been shown to increase “psychological resistance” to fake news, according to a study of 15,000 participants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2018, University of Cambridge researchers helped launch the &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbadnews.com/#intro&quot;&gt;browser game Bad News&lt;/a&gt;. Thousands of people spent fifteen minutes completing it, with many allowing the data to be used for a study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players stoke anger and fear by manipulating news and social media within the simulation: deploying twitter bots, photo-shopping evidence, and inciting conspiracy theories to attract followers – all while maintaining a “credibility score” for persuasiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Research suggests that fake news spreads faster and deeper than the truth, so combatting disinformation after-the-fact can be like fighting a losing battle,” said Dr Sander van der Linden, Director of the Cambridge Social Decision-Making Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We wanted to see if we could pre-emptively debunk, or ‘pre-bunk’, fake news by exposing people to a weak dose of the methods used to create and spread disinformation, so they have a better understanding of how they might be deceived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a version of what psychologists call ‘inoculation theory’, with our game working like a psychological vaccination.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To gauge the effects of the game, players were asked to rate the reliability of a series of different headlines and tweets before and after gameplay. They were randomly allocated a mixture of real (“control”) and fake news (“treatment”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study, published today in the journal &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/s41599-019-0279-9&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Palgrave Communications&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, showed the perceived reliability of fake news before playing the game had reduced by an average of 21% after completing it. Yet the game made no difference to how users ranked real news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also found that those who registered as most susceptible to fake news headlines at the outset benefited most from the “inoculation”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We find that just fifteen minutes of gameplay has a moderate effect, but a practically meaningful one when scaled across thousands of people worldwide, if we think in terms of building societal resistance to fake news,” said van der Linden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jon Roozenbeek, study co-author also from Cambridge University, said: “We are shifting the target from ideas to tactics. By doing this, we are hoping to create what you might call a general ‘vaccine’ against fake news, rather than trying to counter each specific conspiracy or falsehood.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roozenbeek and van der Linden worked with Dutch media collective DROG and design agency Gusmanson to develop Bad News, and the idea of a game to inoculate against fake news has attracted much attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with the UK Foreign Office, the team have translated the game into nine different languages, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbadnews.de/#intro&quot;&gt;German&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbadnews.rs/#intro&quot;&gt;Serbian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbadnews.pl/#intro&quot;&gt;Polish&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbadnews.gr/#intro&quot;&gt;Greek&lt;/a&gt;. WhatsApp have commissioned the researchers to create a new game for the messaging platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team have also created a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://getbadnews.com/droggame_book/junior-uk/#intro&quot;&gt;junior version&lt;/a&gt;” for children aged 8-10, available in ten different languages so far. “We want to develop a simple and engaging way to establish media literacy at a relatively early age, then look at how long the effects last,” said Roozenbeek.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first set of results from Bad News has its limitations, say researchers. The sample was self-selecting (those who came across the game online and opted to play), and as such was skewed toward younger, male, liberal, and more educated demographics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, however, the study found the game to be almost equally effective across age, education, gender, and political persuasion. Bad News has ideological balance built in: players can choose to create fake news from the left and right of the political spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are six “badges” to earn in the game, each reflecting a common strategy used by purveyors of fake news: impersonation; conspiracy; polarisation; discrediting sources; trolling; emotionally provocative content.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to limited bandwidth, in-game questions measuring the effects of Bad News were deployed for four of its featured fake news badges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the disinformation tactic of “impersonation”, often seen in the mimicking of trusted personalities on social media, the game reduced perceived reliability of the fake headlines and tweets by 24% from pre to post gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad News gameplay reduced perceived reliability of deliberately polarising headlines by about 10%, and “discrediting” – attacking a legitimate source with accusations of bias – by 19%.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For “conspiracy”, the spreading of false narratives blaming secretive groups for world events, perceived reliability was reduced by 20%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our platform offers early evidence of a way to start building blanket protection against deception, by training people to be more attuned to the techniques that underpin most fake news,” added Roozenbeek.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 15:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>EndXA</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cam.ac.uk/research/news/fake-news-vaccine-works-pre-bunk-game-reduces-susceptibility-to-disinformation</og:url>
<og:title>Fake news ‘vaccine’ works: ‘pre-bunk’ game reduces susceptibility to disinformation</og:title>
<og:description>Study of thousands of players shows a simple online game works like a “vaccine”, increasing skepticism of fake news by giving people a “weak dose” of the methods behind disinformation. </og:description>
<og:image>https://www.cam.ac.uk/sites/www.cam.ac.uk/files/news/research/news/fakenews.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cam.ac.uk/research/news/fake-news-vaccine-works-pre-bunk-game-reduces-susceptibility-to-disinformation</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Real-world dynamic programming: seam carving</title>
<link>https://avikdas.com/2019/05/14/real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://avikdas.com/2019/05/14/real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#cdffcd&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Real-world dynamic programming: seam carving&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/css/blog.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/css/syntax-github.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;588.65775954608&quot;&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;May 14, 2019 • &lt;a href=&quot;https://avikdas.com/&quot;&gt;Avik Das&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic programming has a reputation as a technique you learn in school, then only use to pass interviews at software companies. Indeed, most developers do not regularly work on problems where dynamic programming is needed. Ultimately, &lt;strong&gt;dynamic programming is a technique for efficiently solving problems that can be broken down into highly-repeated subproblems&lt;/strong&gt;, and as a result, is useful in many situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’ll work through an interesting real-world application of dynamic programming: seam carving. The problem and proposed technique is discussed in detail in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1276390&quot;&gt;the paper &lt;em&gt;Seam Carving for Content-Aware Image Resizing&lt;/em&gt; by Avidan and Shamir&lt;/a&gt;. (The paper is freely available if you search for the title.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is part of an ongoing series on dynamic programming. If you need a refresher on the technique, see my &lt;a href=&quot;https://avikdas.com/2019/04/15/a-graphical-introduction-to-dynamic-programming.html&quot;&gt;graphical introduction to dynamic programming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;content-aware-image-resizing&quot;&gt;Content-aware image resizing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to solve a real-world problem with dynamic programming, it’s necessary to frame the problem in a way where dynamic programming is applicable. This section covers the necessary setup for our chosen problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors of the original paper introduce content-aware image resizing, that is changing the width or height of an image in a way that intelligently accounts for the contents of that image. I’ll let the paper go into details, but here’s a brief overview. Suppose you want to resize the following image of a surfer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/surfer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overhead view of a surfer prominently visible in the middle of a calm ocean, with turbulent waves behind them on the right. Credit goes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/users/kirildobrev-12266114/&quot;&gt;Kiril Dobrev&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/photos/blue-beach-surf-travel-surfer-4145659/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the paper discusses in detail, there are multiple ways to reduce the width of the image. Cropping and scaling come to mind, with their associated downsides, but there’s also the possibility of removing columns of pixels from the middle of the image. As you might imagine, doing so leaves a visible line in the image where the image on the left and right don’t match up. And even after doing all this, there’s only so much of the image that can be removed this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/surfer-crop-middle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attempting to reduce the image width by cropping out the left part of the image, as well as a block from the middle. The latter leaves a visible line in the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Avidan and Shamir show in their paper is a technique known as &lt;em&gt;seam carving&lt;/em&gt;. The technique first identifies “low-energy” areas of the image that are less interesting, then finds the lowest-energy “seams” that weave through the image. In the case of reducing the width of an image, seam carving finds a vertical seam that stretches from the top of the image to the bottom, moving left or right by at most one pixel from one row to the next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the surfer image, the lowest-energy seam goes through the middle of the image, where the water is the calmest. This matches our intuition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/surfer-seam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lowest-energy seam found in the surfer image. The seam is visualized by a red line five pixels wide for visibility, even though in reality the seam is only one pixel wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By identifying the lowest-energy seam, then removing it, we reduce the width of the image by one pixel. Repeating this process again and again lets us reduce the width of the image substantially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/surfer-resized.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surfer image after its width has been reduced by 1,024 pixels!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, following our intuition, the algorithm has removed the still water in the middle, as well as the water on the left of the image. Unlike the crop, however, the texture of the water on the left is preserved, and there are no jarring transitions. It’s true that there are some less than perfect transitions in the middle of the image, but for the most part, the result looks natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;defining-the-energy-of-an-image&quot;&gt;Defining the energy of an image&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The magic is in finding the lowest-energy seam. To do so, we first assign each pixel of the image an energy. Then, we apply dynamic programming to find the lowest-energy path through the image, an algorithm we’ll discuss in detail in the next section. First, let’s cover how energy values are assigned to the pixels of the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper discusses a few different energy functions and the effect they have on resizing. We’ll keep it simple with an energy function that simply captures how sharply the color in the image changes around each pixel. For the sake of completeness, I’ll describe the energy function in a little bit of detail in case you want to implement it yourself, but this part of the computation is simply setup for the dynamic programming later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/energy-gradient-horizontal.png&quot; alt=&quot;On the left, three pixels ranging from dark to light. The difference between the first and last pixel is large, visualized by a thick arrow between them. On the right, three pixels that are all dark. The different between the first and last pixel is small, visualized by a thin arrow between them.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the left, the energy of a single pixel is large when its neighbors have very different colors. On the right, the energy of a pixel is small when its neighbors have similar colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To compute the energy of a single pixel, we look at the pixels to the left and right of that pixel. We find the squared component-wise distance between them, that is compute the squared difference between the red components, the squared difference between the green components and the squared difference between blue components, then add them up. We do the same for the pixels above and below the center pixel. Finally, we add up the horizontal and vertical distances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only caveat is if a pixel is up against, say, the left edge, there is no pixel to the left. In that case, we just compare the pixel itself to the pixel to the right. A similar adjustment is made for pixels on the top, right and bottom edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This energy function is large when the surrounding pixels are very different in color, and small when the surrounding pixels are similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/surfer-energy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The energy of each pixel in the surfer image, visualized with higher-energy pixels shown in white and lower-energy ones in black. As expected, the surfer in the middle and the turbulent waves on the right have the highest energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This energy function works well for the surfer image. However, the energy function takes on a very large range of values, so when visualizing the energy, it looks like most of the image has zero energy. In reality, those regions simply have low energy values compared to the highest-energy regions. To make the energy function easier to visualize, I’ve zoomed in on the surfer and brightened up the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-dynamic-programming-to-find-low-energy-seams&quot;&gt;Using dynamic programming to find low-energy seams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the energy computed for each pixel, we can now look for the lowest-energy seam that goes from the top of the image down to the bottom. The same analysis applies for horizontal seams going from the left edge to the right edge, which would allow us to reduce the height of the original image. However, we’ll focus on vertical seams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by defining the lowest-energy seam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A seam is sequence of pixels, exactly one per row. The requirement is that between two consecutive rows, the $x$ coordinate can only vary by at most one. This keeps the seam connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lowest-energy seam is the one whose total energy across all the pixels in the seam is minimized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s important to notice the lowest-energy seam may not pass through all the lowest-energy pixels in the image. It’s the total energy of the seam being minimized, not the individual pixel energies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/seam-finding-greedy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Three rows of an image, with each pixel in the row assigned an energy value.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greedy approach does not work. By picking a low-energy pixel early on, we get stuck in a high-energy region of the image, represented by the red path on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see starting at the top row and trying to pick the lowest-energy pixel in the next row doesn’t work. By going to the pixel with an energy of $2$, we are forced into a high-energy region of the image. Instead, if we had chosen to go with the higher-energy pixel at the left side of the middle row, we would have access to the lower-energy region at the bottom left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;break-the-problem-into-subproblems&quot;&gt;Break the problem into subproblems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with the greedy approach above is that, when deciding how to continue a seam, we don’t take into account the rest of the seam yet to come. We can’t look into the future, but we can capture everything we know up to this point in order to look at the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s turn our choice on its head. &lt;em&gt;Instead of choosing between multiple pixels to continue a single seam, let’s choose between multiple seams to connect to a single pixel.&lt;/em&gt; What we’ll do is look at each pixel and choose between the pixels in the above row we can connect with. If each of the pixels in the above row encodes the path taken up to that point, we essentially look at the full history up to that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/seam-finding-choice.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At each pixel, we will look at three pixels in the row above. The fundamental choice is which of the seams do we continue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggests having a subproblem corresponding to each pixel in the image. Because the subproblem needs to capture the best path up to that pixel, a good choice is associating with each pixel the energy of the lowest-energy seam &lt;em&gt;ending at that pixel&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the greedy approach, the above approach essentially tries all possible paths through the image. It’s just that, when trying all possible paths, the same subproblems are solved again and again, making this approach a perfect candidate for dynamic programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;define-a-recurrence-relation&quot;&gt;Define a recurrence relation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, we now have to formalize the above intuition into a recurrence relation. There is a subproblem corresponding to each pixel in the original image, so the inputs to our recurrence relation can just be the $x$ and $y$ coordinates of that pixel. This gives us integer inputs, allowing easy ordering of subproblems, as well as the ability to store previously-computed values in a two-dimension array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll define a function $M(x, y)$ that represents the energy of the lowest-energy vertical seam that starts at the top of the image and ends at pixel $(x, y)$. The name $M$ was chosen because that’s what the paper defines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we need a base case. In the top row of the image, all the seams ending at those pixels are just one pixel long, because there are no pixels farther above. So, the energy of the lowest-energy seam ending at those pixels are just the energies of those pixels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the remaining pixels, we have to look at the pixels in the row directly above. Because a seam has to be connected, we only look at the pixels directly to the top-left, directly above and directly to the top-right. From those pixels, we’ll pick the lowest-energy seam ending at one of those pixels, and add on the current pixel’s energy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an edge case, we need to consider what happens when the pixel we’re looking at is along the left or right edge of the image. In these cases, we omit either $M(x - 1, y - 1)$ for pixels on the left edge or $M(x + 1, y - 1)$ for pixels on the right edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we need to extract the energy of the lowest energy seam that spans the entire height of the image. This means looking at the bottom row of the image and picking the lowest energy seam ending at one of those pixels. Assuming the image is $W$ pixels wide and $H$ pixels tall, we want:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this definition, we have a recurrence relation with all the properties we want:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The recurrence relation has integer inputs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The final answer we want is easy to extract from the relation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The relation depends on itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;inspecting-the-subproblem-dag-directed-acyclic-graph&quot;&gt;Inspecting the subproblem DAG (directed acyclic graph)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because each subproblem $M(x, y)$ corresponds to a single pixel in the original image, the subproblem dependency graph is really easy to visualize. Just lay out the subproblems in a two-dimensional grid, just like in the original image!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/dag-layout.png&quot; alt=&quot;A two dimensional grid with width four and height three. Each cell corresponds to two numbers x and y, with x increasing from left to right, and y increasing from top to bottom.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subproblems are laid out in a two-dimensional grid, just like the pixels in the original image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the base case for the recurrence relation shows, the top row of subproblems, corresponding to the top row of the image, can simply be initialized with the individual energy values for those pixels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/dag-top-row.png&quot; alt=&quot;The same grid as above, but with the top row is highlighted.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top row of subproblems don't depend on any other subproblems. Notice the lack of arrows coming out of the top row of cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second row is where the dependencies start appearing. First, on the left-most cell in the second row, we encounter a literal edge case. Because there are no cells to left, the cell marked $(1, 0)$ depends only on the cells directly above and to the top-right of it. The same will happen later with the left-most cell in the third row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/dag-left-edge.png&quot; alt=&quot;The same grid as above, but with the left-most cell in the middle row highlighted. Two arrows are coming out of the cell, pointing to the cell above and to the top-right of the cell.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subproblems on the left edge depend only on two subproblems above them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving onto the second cell in the second row, labeled $(1, 1)$, we see the most typical manifestation of the recurrence relation. That cell depends on the cells to the top-left, directly above and to the top-right of it. This dependency structure applies to all “middle” cells in the second and subsequent rows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/dag-middle-cell.png&quot; alt=&quot;The same grid as above, but with the second cell in the middle row highlighted. Three arrows are coming out of the cell, pointing to the top-left, directly above and to the top-right of the cell.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subproblems between the left and right edges depend on three subproblems above them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the right edge presents the second edge case. Because there are no more cells to the right, this cell depends only on the cells directly above and to the top-left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/dag-right-edge.png&quot; alt=&quot;The same grid as above, but with the right-most cell in the middle row highlighted. Two arrows are coming out of the cell, pointing to the cell above and to the top-left of the cell.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subproblems on the right edge depend only on two cells above them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, this process is repeated for all subsequent rows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/dag-animation.gif&quot; alt=&quot;An animation that shows the dependencies for each cell in the grid above. Each cell is highlighted, going left to right, row by row from top to bottom.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the dependency graph contains many dependency arrows, this animation shows the dependencies for each subproblem one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the full dependency graph is intimidating due to the sheer number of arrows, looking at each subproblem one by one helps establish noticeable patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;bottom-up-implementation&quot;&gt;Bottom-up implementation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the above analysis, we have an ordering we can exploit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Proceed from the top of the image to the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In each row, proceed in any order. A natural choice is to go from the left to the right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because each row only depends on the previous one, we only need to keep two rows of data available: one for the previous row, and one for the current row. In fact, by going from left to right, we can actually throw away individual elements from the previous row as they are used up. However, this complicates the algorithm, as we have to figure out which parts of the previous row can be discarded and how to discard them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following Python code, the input is a list of rows, where each row is a list of numbers representing individual pixel energies for the pixels in that row. The input is named &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pixel_energies&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pixel_energies[y][x]&lt;/code&gt; represents the energy of the pixel at coordinates $(x, y)$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by computing the seam energies of the top row by simply copying over the individual pixel energies at the top row:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;previous_seam_energies_row&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, loop through the remaining rows of the input, computing the seam energies for each row. The trickiest part is determining which elements of the previous row to reference, since there are no pixels to the left of the left edge or to the right of the right edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each iteration, a new list of seam energies is created for the current row. At the end of the iteration, replace the previous row’s data with the current row’s data for the next iteration. This is how we throw away the previous row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Skip the first row in the following loop.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies_row&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies_row&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;enumerate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies_row&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Determine the range of x values to iterate over in the previous&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# row. The range depends on if the current pixel is in the middle of&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# the image, or on one of the edges.&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_left&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;max&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_right&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies_row&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_range&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_right&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min_seam_energy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; \
            &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;previous_seam_energies_row&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies_row&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min_seam_energy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;previous_seam_energies_row&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies_row&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, at the end, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;previous_seam_energies_row&lt;/code&gt; contains the seam energies for the bottom row. Find the minimal value in this list, and that’s the answer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;previous_seam_energies_row&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can test this implementation by wrapping the above code in a function, then calling the function with a two-dimensional array you construct. The following input data has been constructed so that a greedy approach would fail, but also so that there is an obvious lowest-energy seam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;16.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ENERGIES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min_seam_energy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ENERGIES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;time-and-space-complexity&quot;&gt;Time and space complexity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one subproblem corresponding to each pixel in the original image. For each subproblems, there are at most $3$ dependencies, so we do a constant amount of work to solve each subproblem. Finally, we go through the last row one more time. Thus, if the image is $W$ pixels wide and $H$ pixels tall, the time complexity is $O(W \times H + W)$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At each time, we store two lists, one for the previous row and one for the current row. The first one has $W$ elements, and second one grows to have $W$ elements at most. Thus, the space complexity is $O(2W)$, which is simply $O(W)$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that if we actually discarded elements from the previous row’s data, we would shrink the previous row’s list at about the same rate as the current row’s list. Thus, the space complexity would still be $O(W)$. Depending on the width of the image, the constant factor can certainly matter, but usually, it’s not a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-pointers-to-find-the-lowest-energy-seam&quot;&gt;Back pointers to find the lowest-energy seam&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve found the energy of the lowest-energy vertical seam, what do we do with this information? It turns out we don’t actually care about the energy of the seam, but the seam itself! The problem is, from the ending position of the seam, we don’t have a way to back track through the rest of the seam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I’ve skipped over in previous articles, but the same concern applies to many dynamic programming problems. For example, if you remember &lt;a href=&quot;https://avikdas.com/2019/04/15/a-graphical-introduction-to-dynamic-programming.html#the-house-robber-problem&quot;&gt;the House Robber Problem&lt;/a&gt;, we found a numerical value corresponding to the maximum value we could extract, but not which houses yielded that total value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;representing-back-pointers&quot;&gt;Representing back pointers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is a common one: store &lt;em&gt;back pointers&lt;/em&gt;. In the seam carving problem, we don’t just want the value of the seam energy at each pixel. We also want to know which of the pixels in the previous row led to that energy. By storing this information, we can follow these pointers all the way to the top of the image, yielding the pixels that make up the lowest-energy seam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let’s create a class to store both the energy and the back pointers. The energy will be used for the calculation of subproblems. Since the back pointer simply identifies which pixel in the previous row yielded the current energy, we can represent the pointer as just the x coordinate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;SeamEnergyWithBackPointer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;__init__&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;energy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_coordinate_in_previous_row&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;energy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;energy&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_coordinate_in_previous_row&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_coordinate_in_previous_row&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of each subproblem will be an instance of this class, instead of just a number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;storing-back-pointers&quot;&gt;Storing back pointers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, we’ll need to back track through the entire height of the image, following back pointers, to reconstruct the lowest-energy seam. This unfortunately means we need to keep back pointers around for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the pixels in the image, not just for the previous row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve this, we will just keep around the full result of all subproblems, though we could technically discard the numerical seam energies of earlier rows. We can store these results in a two-dimensional array that looks just like the input array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the first row, which just contains the individual pixel energies. Because there is no previous row, all the back pointers are &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;None&lt;/code&gt;, but for consistency, we’ll store instances of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SeamEnergyWithBackPointer&lt;/code&gt;s anyway:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Initialize the top row of seam energies by copying over the top row of&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# the pixel energies. There are no back pointers in the top row.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SeamEnergyWithBackPointer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main loop works mostly the same as the previous implementation, with the following differences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data for the previous row contains instances of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SeamEnergyWithBackPointer&lt;/code&gt;, so when calculating the value of the recurrence relation, we have to look inside those objects for the seam energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When storing the data for the current pixel, we have to construct a new instance of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SeamEnergyWithBackPointer&lt;/code&gt;. This is where we’ll store the seam energy for the current pixel, but also the x coordinate from the previous row used to calculate the current seam energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of each row, instead of discarding the previous row’s data, we simply append the current row’s data to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;seam_energies&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Skip the first row in the following loop.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies_row&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies_row&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;enumerate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies_row&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Determine the range of x values to iterate over in the previous&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# row. The range depends on if the current pixel is in the middle of&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# the image, or on one of the edges.&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_left&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;max&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_right&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energies_row&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_range&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_right&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min_parent_x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;key&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;lambda&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;][&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;energy&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min_seam_energy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SeamEnergyWithBackPointer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pixel_energy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;][&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min_parent_x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;energy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min_parent_x&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies_row&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min_seam_energy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies_row&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;following-the-back-pointers&quot;&gt;Following the back pointers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the entire subproblem table filled out, we can now reconstruct the lowest-energy seam. Start by finding the x coordinate in the bottom row that corresponds to the lowest-energy seam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Find the x coordinate with minimal seam energy in the bottom row.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min_seam_end_x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])),&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;key&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;lambda&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;][&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;energy&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, proceed from the bottom of the image up to the top, varying $y$ from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;len(seam_energies) - 1&lt;/code&gt; down to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;. In each iteration, add the current ($x, y)$ pair to a list representing our seam, then set the $x$ value to whatever the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SeamEnergyWithBackPointer&lt;/code&gt; object in the current row points to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Follow the back pointers to form a list of coordinates that form the&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# lowest-energy seam.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_point_x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;min_seam_end_x&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_point_x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_point_x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; \
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_energies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;][&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam_point_x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x_coordinate_in_previous_row&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seam&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This builds up the seam from bottom to top, so reverse the list if you want the coordinates from top to bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;time-and-space-complexity-1&quot;&gt;Time and space complexity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time complexity is similar to before, because we still need to process each pixel once. At the end, in addition to looking at the last row for the lowest seam energy, we then go up the entire height of the image to reconstruct the seam. Thus, for a $W \times H$ image, the time complexity is $O(W \times H + W + H)$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for space, we still store a constant amount of data for each subproblem, but now we don’t discard any of the data. Thus, we use $O(W \times H)$ space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;removing-low-energy-seams&quot;&gt;Removing low-energy seams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the lowest-energy vertical seam has been found, we can simply copy over the pixels from the original image into a new one. Each row of the new image has all the pixels from the corresponding row of the original image, except for the pixel from the lowest-energy seam. Because we remove a single pixel in each row, starting with a $W \times H$ image, we end up with a $(W - 1) \times H$ image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can repeat this process by recomputing the energy function on the new image, then finding the lowest-energy seam in the new image. It seems tempting to find more than one low-energy seam in the original image, then remove them all in one go. The problem is that two seams may cross each other, sharing a pixel in the middle. When the first of these two seams is removed, the second seam is no longer valid because it’s missing a pixel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B9HPREBePI4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An animation of the seam removal process applied to the surfer image. View in full screen to view the seam more clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above video shows the seam removal process applied to the surfer image. I made the video by taking the image at each iteration, and overlaying a visualization of the lowest-energy seam at that iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;another-example&quot;&gt;Another example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a lot of in-depth explanation, so let’s finish off with some more pretty pictures! Take the following photo of a rock formation in Arches National Park:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/arch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rock formation with a hole in the middle in Arches Nation Park. Credit goes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/exit78/&quot;&gt;Mike Goad&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/4hxxz5&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The energy function for this image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/arch-energy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The energy of each pixel in the arch image, visualized with higher-energy pixels shown in white and lower-energy ones in black. Notice high energy around the edge of the hole in the rock formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This yields the following lowest-energy seam. Notice the seam goes through the rock on the right, entering the rock formation right where the lit part on the top of the rock matches up with the color of the sky. Perhaps we should choose a better energy function!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/arch-seam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lowest-energy seam found in the arch image. The seam is visualized by a red line five pixels wide for visibility, even though in reality the seam is only one pixel wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, after resizing the arch image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avikdas.com/assets/images/2019-05-14-real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving/arch-resized.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arch image after its width has been reduced by 1,024 pixels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is definitely not perfect, with many of the edges in the original image distorted in the resized image. One improvement may be to implement one of the other energy functions discussed in the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dynamic programming, while typically encountered in academic settings, is a useful technique for solving complex problems. In this article, we covered one application of dynamic programming: content-aware image resizing using seam carving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We applied the same principles of breaking down the problem into smaller subproblems, analyzing the dependencies between these subproblems, then solving the subproblems in an order that minimizes the space and time complexities of the algorithm. Additional, we also explored the use of back pointers to not only find the minimized numerical value we computed, but the specific choices that yielded that value. These pieces were then applied to a real-world problem, which requires both pre- and post-processing to make the dynamic programming algorithm actually useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 14:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>akdas</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://avikdas.com/2019/05/14/real-world-dynamic-programming-seam-carving.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Toyota Way</title>
<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way</guid>
<description>&lt;a class=&quot;mw-jump-link&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#mw-head&quot;&gt;Jump to navigation&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;mw-jump-link&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#p-search&quot;&gt;Jump to search&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;div id=&quot;mw-content-text&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;mw-content-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;mw-parser-output&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Toyota Way&lt;/b&gt; is a set of principles and behaviors that underlie the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toyota&quot; title=&quot;Toyota&quot;&gt;Toyota&lt;/a&gt; Motor Corporation's managerial approach and production system. Toyota first summed up its philosophy, values and manufacturing ideals in 2001, calling it &quot;The Toyota Way 2001&quot;. It consists of  principles in two key areas: continuous improvement, and respect for people.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-3&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Overview_of_the_principles&quot;&gt;Overview of the principles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Toyota Way has been called &quot;a system designed to provide the tools for people to continually improve their work&quot;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-Exec_sum_4-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-Exec_sum-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The 14 principles of The Toyota Way are organized in four sections: 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Long-Term Philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Right Process Will Produce the Right Results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Value to the Organization by Developing Your People&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuously Solving Root Problems Drives Organizational Learning&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two focal points of the principles are continuous improvement and respect for people. The principles for a continuous improvement include establishing a long-term vision, working on challenges, continual innovation, and going to the source of the issue or problem. The principles relating to respect for people include ways of building respect and teamwork.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;The_14_Principles&quot;&gt;The 14 Principles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system can be summarized in 14 principles.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-The_Toyota_Way_5-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-The_Toyota_Way-5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The principles are set out and briefly described below:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Section_I_.E2.80.94_Long-Term_Philosophy&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Section_I_—_Long-Term_Philosophy&quot;&gt;Section I — Long-Term Philosophy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 1&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Base your management decisions on a long-term philosophy, even at the expense of short-term financial goals.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;People need purpose to find motivation and establish goals.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Section_II_.E2.80.94_The_Right_Process_Will_Produce_the_Right_Results&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Section_II_—_The_Right_Process_Will_Produce_the_Right_Results&quot;&gt;Section II — The Right Process Will Produce the Right Results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 2&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Create a continuous process flow to bring problems to the surface.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work processes are redesigned to eliminate waste (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muda_(Japanese_term)&quot; title=&quot;Muda (Japanese term)&quot;&gt;muda&lt;/a&gt;) through the process of continuous improvement — &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaizen&quot; title=&quot;Kaizen&quot;&gt;kaizen&lt;/a&gt;. The seven types of muda are:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Overproduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waiting (time on hand)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unnecessary transport or conveyance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overprocessing or incorrect processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excess inventory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defects&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 3&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Use &quot;pull&quot; systems to avoid overproduction.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A method where a process signals its predecessor that more material is needed. The pull system produces only the required material after the subsequent operation signals a need for it. This process is necessary to reduce overproduction.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 4&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Level out the workload (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heijunka&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Heijunka&quot;&gt;heijunka&lt;/a&gt;). (Work like the tortoise, not the hare).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This helps achieve the goal of minimizing waste (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muda_(Japanese_term)&quot; title=&quot;Muda (Japanese term)&quot;&gt;muda&lt;/a&gt;), not overburdening people or the equipment (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muri_(Japanese_term)&quot; title=&quot;Muri (Japanese term)&quot;&gt;muri&lt;/a&gt;), and not creating uneven production levels (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mura_(Japanese_term)&quot; title=&quot;Mura (Japanese term)&quot;&gt;mura&lt;/a&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 5&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Build a culture of stopping to fix problems, to get quality right the first time.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quality takes precedence (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jidoka&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Jidoka&quot;&gt;Jidoka&lt;/a&gt;). Any employee in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toyota_Production_System&quot; title=&quot;Toyota Production System&quot;&gt;Toyota Production System&lt;/a&gt; has the authority to stop the process to signal a quality issue.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 6&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Standardized tasks and processes are the foundation for continuous improvement and employee empowerment.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although Toyota has a bureaucratic system, the way that it is implemented allows for continuous improvement (kaizen) from the people affected by that system. It empowers the employee to aid in the growth and improvement of the company.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 7&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Use visual control so no problems are hidden.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Included in this principle is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/5S_(methodology)&quot; title=&quot;5S (methodology)&quot;&gt;5S&lt;/a&gt; Program - steps that are used to make all work spaces efficient and productive, help people share work stations, reduce time looking for needed tools and improve the work environment.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sort: Sort out unneeded items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Straighten: Have a place for everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shine: Keep the area clean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardize: Create rules and standard operating procedures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustain: Maintain the system and continue to improve it&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 8&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Use only reliable, thoroughly tested technology that serves your people and processes.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technology is &lt;b&gt;pulled by&lt;/b&gt; manufacturing, not &lt;b&gt;pushed to&lt;/b&gt; manufacturing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Section_III_.E2.80.94_Add_Value_to_the_Organization_by_Developing_Your_People&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Section_III_—_Add_Value_to_the_Organization_by_Developing_Your_People&quot;&gt;Section III — Add Value to the Organization by Developing Your People&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 9&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Grow leaders who thoroughly understand the work, live the philosophy, and teach it to others.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without constant attention, the principles will fade. The principles have to be ingrained, it must be the way one thinks. Employees must be educated and trained: they have to maintain a learning organization.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 10&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Develop exceptional people and teams who follow your company's philosophy.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teams should consist of 4-5 people and numerous management tiers. Success is based on the team, not the individual.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 11&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Respect your extended network of partners and suppliers by challenging them and helping them improve.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toyota treats suppliers much like they treat their employees, challenging them to do better and helping them to achieve it. Toyota provides cross functional teams to help suppliers discover and fix problems so that they can become a stronger, better supplier.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Section_IV_.E2.80.94_Continuously_Solving_Root_Problems_Drives_Organizational_Learning&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Section_IV_—_Continuously_Solving_Root_Problems_Drives_Organizational_Learning&quot;&gt;Section IV — Continuously Solving Root Problems Drives Organizational Learning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 12&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Go and see for yourself to thoroughly understand the situation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genchi_Genbutsu&quot; title=&quot;Genchi Genbutsu&quot;&gt;Genchi Genbutsu&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toyota managers are expected to &quot;go-and-see&quot; operations. Without experiencing the situation firsthand, managers will not have an understanding of how it can be improved. Furthermore, managers use Tadashi Yamashima's (President, Toyota Technical Center (TTC)) ten management principles as a guideline:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Always keep the final target in mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clearly assign tasks to yourself and others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think and speak on verified, proven information and data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take full advantage of the wisdom and experiences of others to send, gather or discuss information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share information with others in a timely fashion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always report, inform and consult in a timely manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze and understand shortcomings in your capabilities in a measurable way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relentlessly strive to conduct &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaizen&quot; title=&quot;Kaizen&quot;&gt;kaizen&lt;/a&gt; activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think &quot;outside the box,&quot; or beyond common sense and standard rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always be mindful of protecting your safety and health.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 13&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Make decisions slowly by consensus, thoroughly considering all options; implement decisions rapidly (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nemawashi&quot; title=&quot;Nemawashi&quot;&gt;nemawashi&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are decision parameters:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find what is really going on (go-and-see) to test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the underlying cause&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider a broad range of alternatives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build consensus on the resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use efficient communication tools&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Principle 14&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Become a learning organization through relentless reflection (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hansei&quot; title=&quot;Hansei&quot;&gt;hansei&lt;/a&gt;) and continuous improvement (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaizen&quot; title=&quot;Kaizen&quot;&gt;kaizen&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process of becoming a learning organization involves criticizing every aspect of what one does. The general problem solving technique to determine the root cause of a problem includes:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Initial problem perception&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarify the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locate area/point of cause&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Root_cause_analysis&quot; title=&quot;Root cause analysis&quot;&gt;Investigate root cause&lt;/a&gt; (5 whys)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Countermeasure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardize&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Research_findings&quot;&gt;Research findings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2004, Dr. Jeffrey Liker, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Michigan&quot; title=&quot;University of Michigan&quot;&gt;University of Michigan&lt;/a&gt; professor of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Industrial_engineering&quot; title=&quot;Industrial engineering&quot;&gt;industrial engineering&lt;/a&gt;, published &lt;i&gt;The Toyota Way&lt;/i&gt;. In his book Liker calls the Toyota Way &quot;a system designed to provide the tools for people to continually improve their work.&quot;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-Exec_sum_4-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-Exec_sum-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; 
According to Liker, the 14 principles of The Toyota Way are organized in four sections: (1) long-term philosophy, (2) the right process will produce the right results, (3) add value to the organization by developing your people, and (4) continuously solving root problems drives organizational learning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Long-term_philosophy&quot;&gt;Long-term philosophy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first principle involves managing with a long-view rather than for short-term gain. It reflects a belief that people need purpose to find motivation and establish goals.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Right_process_will_produce_right_results&quot;&gt;Right process will produce right results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next seven principles are focused on process with an eye towards quality outcome. Following these principles, work processes are redesigned to eliminate waste (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muda_(Japanese_term)&quot; title=&quot;Muda (Japanese term)&quot;&gt;muda&lt;/a&gt;) through the process of continuous improvement — &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaizen&quot; title=&quot;Kaizen&quot;&gt;kaizen&lt;/a&gt;. The seven types of muda are (1) overproduction; (2) waiting, time on hand; (3) unnecessary transport or conveyance; (4) overprocessing or incorrect processing; (5) excess inventory; (6) motion; and (7) defects.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The principles in this section empower employees in spite of the bureaucratic processes of Toyota, as any employee in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toyota_Production_System&quot; title=&quot;Toyota Production System&quot;&gt;Toyota Production System&lt;/a&gt; has the authority to stop production to signal a quality issue, emphasizing that quality takes precedence (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jidoka&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Jidoka&quot;&gt;Jidoka&lt;/a&gt;). The way the Toyota bureaucratic system is implemented to allow for continuous improvement (kaizen) from the people affected by that system so that any employee may aid in the growth and improvement of the company.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recognition of the value of employees is also part of the principle of measured production rate (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heijunka&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Heijunka&quot;&gt;heijunka&lt;/a&gt;), as a level workload helps avoid overburdening people and equipment (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muri_(Japanese_term)&quot; title=&quot;Muri (Japanese term)&quot;&gt;muri&lt;/a&gt;), but this is also intended to minimize waste (muda) and avoid uneven production levels (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mura_(Japanese_term)&quot; title=&quot;Mura (Japanese term)&quot;&gt;mura&lt;/a&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These principles are also designed to ensure that only essential materials are employed (to avoid overproduction), that the work environment is maintained efficiently (the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/5S_(methodology)&quot; title=&quot;5S (methodology)&quot;&gt;5S&lt;/a&gt; Program) to help people share work stations and to reduce time looking for needed tools, and that the technology used is reliable and thoroughly tested.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Value_to_organization_by_developing_people&quot;&gt;Value to organization by developing people&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human development is the focus of principles 9 through 11. Principle 9 emphasizes the need to ensure that leaders embrace and promote the corporate philosophy. This reflects, according to Liker, a belief that the principles have to be ingrained in employees to survive. The 10th principle emphasizes the need of individuals and work teams to embrace the company's philosophy, with teams of 4-5 people who are judged in success by their team achievements, rather than their individual efforts. Principle 11 looks to business partners, who are treated by Toyota much like they treat their employees. Toyota challenges them to do better and helps them to achieve it, providing cross functional teams to help suppliers discover and fix problems so that they can become a stronger, better supplier.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Solving_root_problems_drives_organizational_learning&quot;&gt;Solving root problems drives organizational learning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final principles embrace a philosophy of problem solving that emphasizes thorough understanding, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Consensus&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Consensus&quot;&gt;consensus&lt;/a&gt;-based solutions swiftly implemented and continual reflection (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hansei&quot; title=&quot;Hansei&quot;&gt;hansei&lt;/a&gt;) and improvement (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaizen&quot; title=&quot;Kaizen&quot;&gt;kaizen&lt;/a&gt;). The 12th principle (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genchi_Genbutsu&quot; title=&quot;Genchi Genbutsu&quot;&gt;Genchi Genbutsu&lt;/a&gt;) sets out the expectation that managers will personally evaluate operations so that they have a firsthand understanding of situations and problems. Principle 13 encourages thorough consideration of possible solutions through a consensus process, with rapid implementation of decisions once reached (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nemawashi&quot; title=&quot;Nemawashi&quot;&gt;nemawashi&lt;/a&gt;). The final principle requires that Toyota be a &quot;learning organization&quot;, continually reflecting on its practices and striving for improvement. According to Liker, the process of becoming a learning organization involves criticizing every aspect of what one does.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Translating_the_principles&quot;&gt;Translating the principles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a question of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diffusion_(business)&quot; title=&quot;Diffusion (business)&quot;&gt;uptake&lt;/a&gt; of the principles now that Toyota has production operations in many different countries around the world. As a &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; article notes, while the corporate culture may have been easily disseminated by word of mouth when Toyota manufacturing was only in Japan, with worldwide production, many different &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture&quot; title=&quot;Culture&quot;&gt;cultures&lt;/a&gt; must be taken into account. Concepts such as &quot;mutual ownership of problems&quot;, or &lt;i&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genchi_Genbutsu&quot; title=&quot;Genchi Genbutsu&quot;&gt;genchi genbutsu&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/i&gt;, (solving problems at the source instead of behind desks), and the &lt;i&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaizen&quot; title=&quot;Kaizen&quot;&gt;kaizen&lt;/a&gt; mind&quot;&lt;/i&gt;, (an unending sense of crisis behind the company’s constant drive to improve), may be unfamiliar to North Americans and people of other cultures. A recent increase in vehicle recalls may be due, in part, to &quot;a failure by Toyota to spread its obsession for craftsmanship among its growing ranks of overseas factory workers and managers.&quot; Toyota is attempting to address these needs by establishing training institutes in the United States and in Thailand.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-6&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toyota Way has been driven so deeply into the psyche of employees at all levels that it has morphed from a strategy into an important element of the company's culture.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-Heskett_7-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-Heskett-7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  According to Masaki Saruta, author of several books on Toyota, &quot;the real Toyota Way is a culture of control.&quot;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-8&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-9&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The Toyota Way rewards intense company loyalty that at the same time invariably reduces the voice of those who challenge authority.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-10&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-11&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &quot;The Toyota Way of constructive criticism to reach a better way of doing things 'is not always received in good spirit at home.'&quot;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-12&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The Toyota Way management approach at the automaker &quot;worked until it didn't.&quot;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-Heskett_7-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-Heskett-7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One consequence was when Toyota was given reports of sudden acceleration in its vehicles and the company faced a potential recall situation. There were questions if Toyota's crisis was caused by the company losing sight of its own principles.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-13&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The Toyota Way in this case did not address the problem and provide direction on what the automaker would be doing, but managers instead protected the company and issued flat-out denials and placed the blame at others.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-14&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The consequence of the automaker's actions led to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2009–11_Toyota_vehicle_recalls&quot; title=&quot;2009–11 Toyota vehicle recalls&quot;&gt;2009–11 Toyota vehicle recalls&lt;/a&gt;. Although one of the Toyota Way principles is to &quot;build a culture of stopping to fix problems to get quality right the first time,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Akio_Toyoda&quot; title=&quot;Akio Toyoda&quot;&gt;Akio Toyoda&lt;/a&gt;, President and CEO, stated during Congressional hearings that the reason for the problems was that his &quot;company grew too fast.&quot;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-15&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Toyota management had determined its goal was to become the world's largest automotive manufacturer.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-16&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; According to some management consultants, when the pursuit of growth took priority, the automaker &quot;lost sight of the key values that gave it its reputation in the first place.&quot;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-17&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;See_also&quot;&gt;See also&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_India_Way&quot; title=&quot;The India Way&quot;&gt;The India Way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; - a modern management book, after the Toyota Way&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-18&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_note-18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban&quot; title=&quot;Kanban&quot;&gt;Kanban&lt;/a&gt;: a workflow management system also pioneered at Toyota&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karoshi&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Karoshi&quot;&gt;Karoshi&lt;/a&gt; death from overwork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2009–11_Toyota_vehicle_recalls&quot; title=&quot;2009–11 Toyota vehicle recalls&quot;&gt;2009–11 Toyota vehicle recalls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;References&quot;&gt;References&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;reflist columns references-column-width&quot; style=&quot;-moz-column-width: 30em; -webkit-column-width: 30em; column-width: 30em; list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-1&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation web&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://www.toyota.co.jp/en/environmental_rep/03/pdf/E_p80.pdf&quot;&gt;&quot;Environmental &amp;amp; Social Report 2003&quot;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-format&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/span&gt;. Toyota Motor. p. 80&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;26 March&lt;/span&gt; 2012&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Environmental+%26+Social+Report+2003&amp;amp;rft.pages=80&amp;amp;rft.pub=Toyota+Motor&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.toyota.co.jp%2Fen%2Fenvironmental_rep%2F03%2Fpdf%2FE_p80.pdf&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;style data-mw-deduplicate=&quot;TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:&quot;\&quot;&quot;&quot;\&quot;&quot;&quot;'&quot;&quot;'&quot;}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-2&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;Toyota Motor Corporation Annual Report, 2003, page 19. &quot;The Toyota Way, which has been passed down since the Companyʼs founding, is a unique set of values and manufacturing ideals. Clearly, our operations are going to become more and more globalized. With this in mind, we compiled a booklet, The Toyota Way 2001, in order to transcend the diverse languages and cultures of our employees and to communicate our philosophy to them.&quot; (Mr. Fujio Cho, President, Toyota Motor Corporation)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-3&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation web&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://www.toyota-global.com/sustainability/sustainability_report/pdf_file_download/09/pdf/sr09_p54_p59.pdf&quot;&gt;&quot;Sustainability Report 2009&quot;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-format&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/span&gt;. Toyota Motor. p. 54&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;26 March&lt;/span&gt; 2012&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Sustainability+Report+2009&amp;amp;rft.pages=54&amp;amp;rft.pub=Toyota+Motor&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.toyota-global.com%2Fsustainability%2Fsustainability_report%2Fpdf_file_download%2F09%2Fpdf%2Fsr09_p54_p59.pdf&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-Exec_sum-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-Exec_sum_4-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-Exec_sum_4-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation web&quot;&gt;Liker, Jeffrey (2004). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://ICOS.groups.si.umich.edu//Liker04.pdf&quot;&gt;&quot;The 14 Principles of the Toyota Way: An Executive Summary of the Culture Behind TPS&quot;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-format&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/span&gt;. University of Michigan. p. 36&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;26 March&lt;/span&gt; 2012&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.btitle=The+14+Principles+of+the+Toyota+Way%3A+An+Executive+Summary+of+the+Culture+Behind+TPS&amp;amp;rft.pages=36&amp;amp;rft.pub=University+of+Michigan&amp;amp;rft.date=2004&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Liker&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Jeffrey&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2FICOS.groups.si.umich.edu%2F%2FLiker04.pdf&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-The_Toyota_Way-5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-The_Toyota_Way_5-0&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation book&quot;&gt;Liker, Jeffrey K. (2004). &lt;i&gt;The Toyota Way: 14 Management Principles from the World's Greatest Manufacturer&lt;/i&gt;. McGraw-Hill. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number&quot; title=&quot;International Standard Book Number&quot;&gt;ISBN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:BookSources/978-0-07-139231-0&quot; title=&quot;Special:BookSources/978-0-07-139231-0&quot;&gt;&lt;bdi&gt;978-0-07-139231-0&lt;/bdi&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=book&amp;amp;rft.btitle=The+Toyota+Way%3A+14+Management+Principles+from+the+World%27s+Greatest+Manufacturer&amp;amp;rft.pub=McGraw-Hill&amp;amp;rft.date=2004&amp;amp;rft.isbn=978-0-07-139231-0&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Liker&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Jeffrey+K.&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-6&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-6&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation news&quot;&gt;Fackler, Martin (February 15, 2007). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2007/02/15/business/worldbusiness/15toyota.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;&quot;The 'Toyota Way' Is Translated for a New Generation of Foreign Managers&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;The New York Times&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;26 March&lt;/span&gt; 2012&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=The+New+York+Times&amp;amp;rft.atitle=The+%27Toyota+Way%27+Is+Translated+for+a+New+Generation+of+Foreign+Managers&amp;amp;rft.date=2007-02-15&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Fackler&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Martin&amp;amp;rft_id=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2007%2F02%2F15%2Fbusiness%2Fworldbusiness%2F15toyota.html%3Fpagewanted%3Dall&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-Heskett-7&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-Heskett_7-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-Heskett_7-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation book&quot;&gt;Heskett, James L (2012). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=LCDoh6-opEkC&amp;amp;pg=PA130&amp;amp;dq=%22Toyota+way%22+so+shocking+that+it+may+have+led+to+some+amount+of+denial+as+well+as+loyal+customers&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The culture cycle : how to shape the unseen force that transforms performance&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. FT Press. p. 130. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number&quot; title=&quot;International Standard Book Number&quot;&gt;ISBN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:BookSources/9780132779784&quot; title=&quot;Special:BookSources/9780132779784&quot;&gt;&lt;bdi&gt;9780132779784&lt;/bdi&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=book&amp;amp;rft.btitle=The+culture+cycle+%3A+how+to+shape+the+unseen+force+that+transforms+performance&amp;amp;rft.pages=130&amp;amp;rft.pub=FT+Press&amp;amp;rft.date=2012&amp;amp;rft.isbn=9780132779784&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Heskett&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=James+L&amp;amp;rft_id=https%3A%2F%2Fbooks.google.com%2Fbooks%3Fid%3DLCDoh6-opEkC%26pg%3DPA130%26dq%3D%2522Toyota%2Bway%2522%2Bso%2Bshocking%2Bthat%2Bit%2Bmay%2Bhave%2Bled%2Bto%2Bsome%2Bamount%2Bof%2Bdenial%2Bas%2Bwell%2Bas%2Bloyal%2Bcustomers&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-8&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-8&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation news&quot;&gt;Glionna, John M. (24 March 2010). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2010-03-24/news/sc-biz-0325-toyota-man-20100324_1_toyota-motor-corp-toyota-officials-paul-nolasco&quot;&gt;&quot;Toyota's rigid culture criticized in light of recalls - Automaker's Toyota Way handbook dictates details of employees' lives, even in their off time&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Chicago+Tribune&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Toyota%E2%80%99s+rigid+culture+criticized+in+light+of+recalls+-+Automaker%E2%80%99s+Toyota+Way+handbook+dictates+details+of+employees%E2%80%99+lives%2C+even+in+their+off+time&amp;amp;rft.date=2010-03-24&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Glionna&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=John+M.&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Farticles.chicagotribune.com%2F2010-03-24%2Fnews%2Fsc-biz-0325-toyota-man-20100324_1_toyota-motor-corp-toyota-officials-paul-nolasco&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-9&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation book&quot;&gt;Hino, Satoshi (2006). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=rAlcjg0QhGkC&amp;amp;pg=PA65&amp;amp;dq=Masaki+Saruta+Toyota+Way&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Inside the mind of Toyota : management principles for enduring growth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Productivity Press. p. 65&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=book&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Inside+the+mind+of+Toyota+%3A+management+principles+for+enduring+growth&amp;amp;rft.pages=65&amp;amp;rft.pub=Productivity+Press&amp;amp;rft.date=2006&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Hino&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Satoshi&amp;amp;rft_id=https%3A%2F%2Fbooks.google.com%2Fbooks%3Fid%3DrAlcjg0QhGkC%26pg%3DPA65%26dq%3DMasaki%2BSaruta%2BToyota%2BWay&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-10&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-10&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation web&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://www.toyota-global.com/sustainability/csr_initiatives/stakeholders/employees/index3.html&quot;&gt;&quot;Relations with Employees&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. Toyota Motors&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Relations+with+Employees&amp;amp;rft.pub=Toyota+Motors&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.toyota-global.com%2Fsustainability%2Fcsr_initiatives%2Fstakeholders%2Femployees%2Findex3.html&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-11&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-11&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation web&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20120914012629/http://www.toyota.dk/Images/ToyotaCodeOfConduct_tcm200-635681.pdf&quot;&gt;&quot;Toyota Code of Conduct&quot;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-format&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/span&gt;. Toyota Motor Europe. October 2006. Archived from &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://www.toyota.dk/Images/ToyotaCodeOfConduct_tcm200-635681.pdf&quot;&gt;the original&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-format&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/span&gt; on 14 September 2012&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Toyota+Code+of+Conduct&amp;amp;rft.pub=Toyota+Motor+Europe&amp;amp;rft.date=2006-10&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.toyota.dk%2FImages%2FToyotaCodeOfConduct_tcm200-635681.pdf&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-12&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-12&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation book&quot;&gt;Stanford, Naomi (2013). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=nrYWDniU9X8C&amp;amp;pg=PA130&amp;amp;lpg=PA130&amp;amp;dq=Atkins+noted+wryly+that+the+Toyota+Way+of+constructive+criticism+to+reach+a+better+way+of+doing+things+“is+not+always+received+in+good+spirit+at+home%22&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Corporate culture: getting it right&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Wiley. p. 130. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number&quot; title=&quot;International Standard Book Number&quot;&gt;ISBN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:BookSources/9781118163276&quot; title=&quot;Special:BookSources/9781118163276&quot;&gt;&lt;bdi&gt;9781118163276&lt;/bdi&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=book&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Corporate+culture%3A+getting+it+right&amp;amp;rft.pages=130&amp;amp;rft.pub=Wiley&amp;amp;rft.date=2013&amp;amp;rft.isbn=9781118163276&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Stanford&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Naomi&amp;amp;rft_id=https%3A%2F%2Fbooks.google.com%2Fbooks%3Fid%3DnrYWDniU9X8C%26pg%3DPA130%26lpg%3DPA130%26dq%3DAtkins%2Bnoted%2Bwryly%2Bthat%2Bthe%2BToyota%2BWay%2Bof%2Bconstructive%2Bcriticism%2Bto%2Breach%2Ba%2Bbetter%2Bway%2Bof%2Bdoing%2Bthings%2B%E2%80%9Cis%2Bnot%2Balways%2Breceived%2Bin%2Bgood%2Bspirit%2Bat%2Bhome%2522&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-13&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-13&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation news&quot;&gt;Tseng, Nin-Hai (10 March 2010). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://money.cnn.com/2010/03/10/autos/toyota_way.fortune/?section=magazines_fortune&quot;&gt;&quot;Can the Toyota Way survive Toyota's ways?&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. CNN Money&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Can+the+Toyota+Way+survive+Toyota%27s+ways%3F&amp;amp;rft.date=2010-03-10&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Tseng&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Nin-Hai&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fmoney.cnn.com%2F2010%2F03%2F10%2Fautos%2Ftoyota_way.fortune%2F%3Fsection%3Dmagazines_fortune&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-14&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-14&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Ordonez, Edward (1 December 2010). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://www.rmmagazine.com/2010/12/01/when-the-toyota-way-went-wrong/&quot;&gt;&quot;When the Toyota Way Went Wrong&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Risk Management&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Risk+Management&amp;amp;rft.atitle=When+the+Toyota+Way+Went+Wrong&amp;amp;rft.date=2010-12-01&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Ordonez&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Edward&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.rmmagazine.com%2F2010%2F12%2F01%2Fwhen-the-toyota-way-went-wrong%2F&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-15&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-15&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation web&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/CHRG-111hhrg58346/html/CHRG-111hhrg58346.htm&quot;&gt;&quot;Hearing before the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform: Toyota gas pedals: is the public at risk&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. U.S. Government Printing Office, Serial No. 111-75. 24 February 2010&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Hearing+before+the+Committee+on+Oversight+and+Government+Reform%3A+Toyota+gas+pedals%3A+is+the+public+at+risk&amp;amp;rft.pub=U.S.+Government+Printing+Office%2C+Serial+No.+111-75&amp;amp;rft.date=2010-02-24&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gpo.gov%2Ffdsys%2Fpkg%2FCHRG-111hhrg58346%2Fhtml%2FCHRG-111hhrg58346.htm&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-16&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-16&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation news&quot;&gt;Harden, Blaine (13 February 2010). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2010/02/12/AR2010021205371.html&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;span class=&quot;cs1-kern-left&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;Toyota Way' was lost on road to phenomenal worldwide growth&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=The+Washington+Post&amp;amp;rft.atitle=%27Toyota+Way%27+was+lost+on+road+to+phenomenal+worldwide+growth&amp;amp;rft.date=2010-02-13&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Harden&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Blaine&amp;amp;rft_id=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fwp-dyn%2Fcontent%2Farticle%2F2010%2F02%2F12%2FAR2010021205371.html&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-17&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-17&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation web&quot;&gt;Harrison, Denise. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cssp.com/CD0310b/SuccessSowsSeedsOfFailure/&quot;&gt;&quot;Success Sows the Seeds of Failure - Toyota's Complacency Causes Reputation to Crash&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. Center for Simplified Strategic Planning&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;29 January&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Success+Sows+the+Seeds+of+Failure+-+Toyota%27s+Complacency+Causes+Reputation+to+Crash&amp;amp;rft.pub=Center+for+Simplified+Strategic+Planning&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Harrison&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Denise&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cssp.com%2FCD0310b%2FSuccessSowsSeedsOfFailure%2F&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-18&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way#cite_ref-18&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation news&quot;&gt;Choudhury, Uttara (10 April 2010). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://www.dnaindia.com/opinion/interview_jugaad-enters-management-jargon_1369496&quot;&gt;&quot;Jugaad enters management jargon&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;DNA India&lt;/i&gt;. Diligent Media Corporation. DNA&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;26 March&lt;/span&gt; 2012&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=DNA+India&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Jugaad+enters+management+jargon&amp;amp;rft.date=2010-04-10&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Choudhury&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Uttara&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.dnaindia.com%2Fopinion%2Finterview_jugaad-enters-management-jargon_1369496&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Further_reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation book&quot;&gt;Hino, Satoshi (2005). &lt;i&gt;Inside the Mind of Toyota: Management Principles for Enduring Growth&lt;/i&gt;. Productivity Press. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number&quot; title=&quot;International Standard Book Number&quot;&gt;ISBN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:BookSources/978-1-56327-300-1&quot; title=&quot;Special:BookSources/978-1-56327-300-1&quot;&gt;&lt;bdi&gt;978-1-56327-300-1&lt;/bdi&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=book&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Inside+the+Mind+of+Toyota%3A+Management+Principles+for+Enduring+Growth&amp;amp;rft.pub=Productivity+Press&amp;amp;rft.date=2005&amp;amp;rft.isbn=978-1-56327-300-1&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Hino&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Satoshi&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation book&quot;&gt;Liker, Jeffrey K.; Meier, David (2005). &lt;i&gt;The Toyota Way Fieldbook: A Practical Guide for Implementing Toyota's 4Ps&lt;/i&gt;. McGraw-Hill. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number&quot; title=&quot;International Standard Book Number&quot;&gt;ISBN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:BookSources/978-0-07-144893-2&quot; title=&quot;Special:BookSources/978-0-07-144893-2&quot;&gt;&lt;bdi&gt;978-0-07-144893-2&lt;/bdi&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=book&amp;amp;rft.btitle=The+Toyota+Way+Fieldbook%3A+A+Practical+Guide+for+Implementing+Toyota%27s+4Ps&amp;amp;rft.pub=McGraw-Hill&amp;amp;rft.date=2005&amp;amp;rft.isbn=978-0-07-144893-2&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Liker&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Jeffrey+K.&amp;amp;rft.au=Meier%2C+David&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AThe+Toyota+Way&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!-- 
NewPP limit report
Parsed by mw1327
Cached time: 20190606111422
Cache expiry: 2592000
Dynamic content: false
CPU time usage: 0.276 seconds
Real time usage: 0.312 seconds
Preprocessor visited node count: 867/1000000
Preprocessor generated node count: 0/1500000
Post&amp;#8208;expand include size: 32600/2097152 bytes
Template argument size: 106/2097152 bytes
Highest expansion depth: 7/40
Expensive parser function count: 0/500
Unstrip recursion depth: 1/20
Unstrip post&amp;#8208;expand size: 56748/5000000 bytes
Number of Wikibase entities loaded: 0/400
Lua time usage: 0.169/10.000 seconds
Lua memory usage: 3.21 MB/50 MB
--&gt;&lt;!--
Transclusion expansion time report (%,ms,calls,template)
100.00%  255.217      1 -total
 96.89%  247.271      1 Template:Reflist
 50.75%  129.525      7 Template:Cite_web
 14.99%   38.269      6 Template:Cite_book
 14.77%   37.699      5 Template:Cite_news
  3.63%    9.259      1 Template:Cite_journal
  0.98%    2.491      1 Template:Main_other
  0.85%    2.173      1 Template:Column-width
--&gt;&lt;!-- Saved in parser cache with key enwiki:pcache:idhash:9040377-0!canonical and timestamp 20190606111422 and revision id 847550678
 --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:CentralAutoLogin/start?type=1x1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;border: none; position: absolute;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		
		&lt;div class=&quot;printfooter&quot;&gt;Retrieved from &quot;&lt;a dir=&quot;ltr&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Toyota_Way&amp;amp;oldid=847550678&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Toyota_Way&amp;amp;oldid=847550678&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/div&gt;
		
		
		
		&lt;div class=&quot;visualClear&quot;/&gt;
		
	</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 13:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>qin</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Consumers Are Becoming Wise to Your Nudge</title>
<link>https://behavioralscientist.org/consumers-are-becoming-wise-to-your-nudge/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://behavioralscientist.org/consumers-are-becoming-wise-to-your-nudge/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I know exactly how the conversation will go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m interviewing Chris, a 52-year-old man living a small coastal town, for the second time. We’ve been exploring the new checkout process for a client’s redesigned website. The new site isn’t performing as well as the company thought it would, so I’m exploring why and seeing what we can learn from competitors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Only 2 rooms left? They don’t expect me to believe that do they? You see that everywhere.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I leave with a wry smile. The client won’t be happy, but at least the project findings are becoming clear. Companies in certain sectors use the same behavioral interventions repeatedly. Hotel booking websites are one example. Their sustained, repetitive use of scarcity (e.g., “Only two rooms left!”) and social proof (“16 other people viewed this room”) messaging is apparent even to a casual browser. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Chris the implication was clear: this “scarcity” was just a sales ploy, not to be taken seriously&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleagues and I at Trinity McQueen, an insight consultancy, wondered, was Chris’s reaction exceptional, or would the general public spot a pattern in the way that marketers are using behavioral interventions to influence their behavior? Are scarcity and social proof messages so overused in travel websites that the average person does not believe them? Do they undermine brand trust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The broader question, one essential to both academics and practitioners, is how a world saturated with behavioral interventions might no longer resemble the one in which those interventions were first studied. Are we aiming at a moving target?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The broader question, one essential to both academics and practitioners, is how a world saturated with behavioral interventions might no longer resemble the one in which those interventions were first studied.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the basis for a research project we completed in February 2019 examining reactions of the British public to a range of behavioral interventions. We took a nationally representative sample of 2,102 British adults, and undertook an experimental evaluation of some of marketers’ most commonly used tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started by asking participants to consider a hypothetical scenario: using a hotel booking website to find a room to stay in the following week. We then showed a series of nine real-world scarcity and social proof claims made by an unnamed hotel booking website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two thirds of the British public (65 percent) interpreted examples of scarcity and social proof claims used by hotel booking websites as sales pressure. Half said they were likely to distrust the company as a result of seeing them (49 percent). Just one in six (16 percent) said they believed the claims. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results surprised us. We had expected there to be cynicism among a subgroup—perhaps people who booked hotels regularly, for example. The verbatim commentary from participants showed people see scarcity and social proof claims frequently online, most commonly in the travel, retail, and fashion sectors. They questioned truth of these ads, but were resigned to their use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It’s what I’ve seen often on hotel websites—it’s what they do to tempt you.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Have seen many websites do this kind of thing so don’t really feel differently when I do see it.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a follow up question, a third (34 percent) expressed a negative emotional reaction to these messages, choosing words like &lt;em&gt;contempt&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;disgust&lt;/em&gt; from a precoded list. Crucially, this was because they ascribed bad intentions to the website. The messages were, in their view, designed to induce anxiety:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; “… almost certainly fake to try and panic you into buying without thinking.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I think this type of thing is to pressure you into booking for fear of losing out and not necessarily true.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these people, not only are these behavioral interventions not working but they’re having the reverse effect. We hypothesize &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/1967-08061-000&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;psychological reactance&lt;/a&gt; is at play: people kick back when they feel they are being coerced. Several measures in our study support this. A large minority (40 percent) of the British public agreed that that“when someone forces me to do something, I feel like doing the opposite.” This is even more pronounced in the commercial domain: seven in ten agreed that “when I see a big company dominating a market I want to use a competitor.” Perhaps we Brits are a cynical bunch, but any behavioral intervention can backfire if people think it is a cynical ploy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heuristics are dynamic, not static&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping back from hotel booking websites, this is a reminder that heuristics are not fixed, unchanging. The context for any behavioral intervention is dynamic, operating in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indiana.edu/~abcwest/pmwiki/pdf/todd.currentdirections.2007.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;“a coadapting loop between mind and world.”&lt;/a&gt; Repeated exposure to any tactic over time educates you about its likely veracity in that context. Certain tactics (e.g., scarcity claims) in certain situations (e.g., in hotel booking websites) have been overused. Our evidence suggests their power is now diminished in these contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two questions for the future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our study, we focused on a narrow commercial domain. It would be unwise to make blanket generalizations about the efficacy of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; behavioral interventions based on this evidence alone. And yet nagging doubts remain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#1: Like antibiotic resistance, could overuse in one domain undermine the effectiveness of interventions for everyone? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so, the toolkit of interventions could conceivably shrink over time as commercial practitioners overuse interventions to meet their short-term goals. Most would agree that interventions used to boost prosocial behavior in sectors such as healthcare have much more consequential outcomes. In time, prosocial practitioners may be less able to rely on the most heavily used tactics from the commercial domains such as social proof and scarcity messaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;#2&lt;/em&gt; : How will the growing backlash against big tech and “&lt;a href=&quot;https://profilebooks.com/surveillance&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;surveillance capitalism&lt;/a&gt;” affect behavioral science?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the feedback from the public relates to behavioral interventions they have seen online, not offline. Many of the strategies for which big tech companies are critiqued center on the undermining of a user’s self-determination. The public may conflate the activities of these seemingly ubiquitous companies (gathering customer data in order to predict and control behavior) with those of the behavioral science community. If so, practitioners might find themselves under much greater scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback loops matter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There probably was never an era when simple behavioral interventions gave easy rewards. Human behavior—context-dependent, and driven by a multitude of interacting influences—will remain gloriously unpredictable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketers should design nudges with more than the transaction in mind, not only because it is ethical or because they will be more effective over time but also because they bear responsibility toward the practitioner community as a whole.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lesson I take from our study? Feedback loops affect the efficacy of behavioral interventions more than we realize. Just because an intervention was successful five years ago does not mean it will be successful today. Practitioners should pay as much attention to the ecosystem their interventions operate in as their customers do. There’s no better place to start than spending time with them—talking, observing, and empathizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should also consider our responsibilities as we use behavioral interventions. Marketers should design nudges with more than the transaction in mind, not only because it is ethical or because they will be more effective over time but also because they bear responsibility toward the practitioner community as a whole. We owe an allegiance to the public, but also to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 12:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hirundo</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Consumers Are Becoming Wise to Your Nudge - Behavioral Scientist</og:title>
<og:description>New research indicates that consumers are catching on and may be annoyed by certain nudges, potentially limiting the nudges' effectiveness.</og:description>
<og:url>https://behavioralscientist.org/consumers-are-becoming-wise-to-your-nudge/</og:url>
<og:image>https://behavioralscientist.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/marketing_shaw_0619.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://behavioralscientist.org/consumers-are-becoming-wise-to-your-nudge/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iceland tire of tourists trashing their nature</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-48703462</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-48703462</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;A photographer takes a picture of a landscape in Iceland&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/3B3F/production/_107476151_gettyimages-578023152.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Locals say they have seen numerous examples of bad behaviour from Instagrammers
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;With more than 10 million images on Instagram, Iceland is a popular destination among tourists wanting to get the perfect picture. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Nordic country has long been considered an &quot;Instagrammable destination&quot; but now locals say the island has an issue with inconsiderate influencers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, one visitor was criticised in Iceland for going off road in his hire car and becoming stuck in clay. He was rescued by police officers who documented the incident on their Facebook page. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Driving off-road is strictly prohibited in Iceland over fears it could damage wildlife. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;North-east Iceland police&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Iceland police said this driver had got into trouble driving into clay near hot springs
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The issue has now become so problematic that there are Facebook and Instagram pages where Icelanders document bad behaviour by Instagrammers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The accounts show influencers drinking and driving, sitting on glaciers, walking on moss, crossing tourist perimeters at popular sites and flying drones over horses. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michalina Okreglicka told the BBC that many influencers coming to Iceland &quot;don't have the knowledge about the country's dos and don'ts&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I have a feeling now everything is about Instagram and the perfect Instagram shot. I have never seen so much stupid and irresponsible behaviour in different countries compared to Iceland. I'm going to their profiles and commenting on what they are doing and trying to inform them to stop this.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tourist board Visit Iceland has launched several initiatives attempting to promote responsible behaviour by tourists. It warns visitors in videos and on its website about the importance of Icelandic moss and the need to keep to the main roads and tracks when driving. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has also started a pledge for tourists to sign at the airport where they can promise to leave places as they found them and stop urinating in the countryside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Icelandic moss is particularly fragile and &lt;a href=&quot;https://grapevine.is/mag/articles/2017/12/07/the-life-and-death-of-icelandic-mosses/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;can die if trampled on&lt;/a&gt;. It helps prevent soil erosion, retains water and humidity and is home to many microorganisms. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;EPA&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Visitors to Iceland are drawn to its hot springs and geyser
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Driving off-road is considered to be destructive to the country's environment. Summers in the highlands are short and wet which means it can take the vegetation time to recover from the effects of off-roading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Standing on a cliff for a selfie&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pall Jokull Petursson, who makes a living out of showing photographers Iceland's unique nature, believes there are good and bad influencers on Instagram. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The bad ones often attract the bad visitors by showing reckless behaviour and breaking the rules, giving others the idea that in Iceland you don't have to follow rules, like driving off-road. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I have seen all kinds of behaviour that is both dangerous and disrespectful - like climbing over fences to stand on the edge of a cliff just for the Instagram selfie. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The good instagrammers try to show different ways of enjoying nature. We don't tag places that are off the beaten path that we want to protect as long as possible. Some places have become &quot;insta-famous&quot; without ever mentioning where they are but eventually they become known to everyone. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Many locals have highlighted the need to preserve Iceland's natural beauty
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;One destination that has become known to tourists is Fjadrargljufur Canyon, which became overrun with tourists after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PfGaX8G0f2E&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Justin Bieber filmed his I'll Show You music video &lt;/a&gt;there. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government was forced to close the area for two weeks before opting to close it until the beginning of June. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;'Do they really care?'&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Rash behaviour by one famous person can dramatically impact an entire area if the mass follows,&quot; Environment Minister Gudmundur Ingi Gudbrandsson told the Associated Press.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While photographer Ben Simon Rehn loves Instagram for inspiration and networking, he also sees big problems when visitors show conduct that he considers disrespectful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Some instagrammers are sponsored by companies and don't obey pretty easy rules just to get a more spectacular photo from a slightly different angle. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's a shame Instagrammers behave like this - especially landscape/adventure 'photographers' who seem to be so close to the natural world and love the outdoors, but then seem to forget or fail when it comes to the simplest understanding of laws to protect it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;So I always ask myself, is it about likes and themselves or do they really care about the planet and nature?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 12:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>listentojohan</dc:creator>
<og:title>Icelanders tire of disrespectful influencers</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Locals are frustrated at a number of cases where influencers have been disrespectful at tourist sites.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-48703462</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/3B3F/production/_107476151_gettyimages-578023152.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-48703462</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I was seven words away from being spear-phished</title>
<link>https://robertheaton.com/2019/06/24/i-was-7-words-away-from-being-spear-phished/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://robertheaton.com/2019/06/24/i-was-7-words-away-from-being-spear-phished/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;24 Jun 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks ago I received a very flattering email from the University of Cambridge, asking me to judge the Adam Smith Prize for Economics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Robert,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Gregory Harris. I’m one of the Adam Smith Prize Organizers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each year we update the team of independent specialists who could assess the quality of the competing projects: http://people.ds.cam.ac.uk/grh37/awards/Adam_Smith_Prize&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our colleagues have recommended you as an experienced specialist in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need your assistance in evaluating several projects for Adam Smith Prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to receiving your reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards, Gregory Harris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t say I’m an “expert” in economics exactly, but the university’s request wasn’t that surprising. I do have a subscription to The Economist, and I do understand - very roughly - how and why central banks set interest rates. I’ve read “Capital in the Twenty-First Century” and basically got the gist of the first half. I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/2018/06/05/why-economists-need-bureaucracy/&quot;&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/2019/03/17/robert-prove-that-your-randomized-trial-really-was-random/&quot;&gt;a few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/2019/02/24/making-peace-with-simpsons-paradox/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/2019/03/31/the-robot-reserve-army-of-labor/&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; that I’ve generously tagged as “economics”, and perhaps there’s a new discipline of computational economics that I might be able to shed some software industry insight onto. Overall it felt perfectly plausible that the organizers of the Adam Smith prize would want my perspective. I assumed that being a judge for the Adam Smith Prize would be a lot of work and would not be paid, but it would still be great fuel for the ole ego.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this said, in my heart of hearts I knew that some wires had probably got crossed somewhere. There was no doubt a Professor Hobert Reaton at UC San Diego, expert in Heckscher-Ohlin trade theory, who was patiently waiting for the chance to further his career through a Transatlantic collaboration. Nonetheless, I judged this a thread worth pulling and a mild fantasy worth entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reflexively did some basic security hygiene checks. The email was from an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@cam.ac.uk&lt;/code&gt; email address. I hovered over the link in the email - &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://people.ds.cam.ac.uk/grh37/awards/Adam_Smith_Prize&lt;/code&gt;. It pointed to the same URL that the email text claimed it did, and was located on a valid &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cam.ac.uk&lt;/code&gt; subdomain. It did strike me as a little odd that the page was hosted inside &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gh327&lt;/code&gt;’s personal directory instead of the main economics department’s site; but hey, it’s probably less bureaucracy that way. I clicked on the link and read a little about the history of the Adam Smith prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If “Gregory” had added just 7 extra words to this page - “THIS PAGE MUST BE VIEWED IN FIREFOX” - I would have been screwed. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I think I visited the root &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cam.ac.uk&lt;/code&gt; website to make sure that this really was the domain of the University of Cambridge. I did a quick Google for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gregory harris cambridge&lt;/code&gt; to see how much of a big deal he was. I couldn’t find much - I vaguely remember turning up only a very sparse LinkedIn account. But that’s fine; not everyone has to have a Twitter profile or a cooking blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember thinking that Gregory’s email seemed very curt and poorly phrased, and that he could use a few lessons on how to most effectively ask strangers on the internet to do free work for him. He was lucky that I didn’t care about such trivialities. He was also lucky that I didn’t care that he’d missed a “the” in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;We need your assistance in evaluating several projects for Adam Smith Prize&lt;/code&gt;. Apparently I further didn’t care that he’d unnecessarily capitalized the word &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Organizers&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Adam Smith Prize Organizers&lt;/code&gt;, or that he didn’t seem to understand that a paragraph can contain more than a single sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time I just thought he wasn’t a very good writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sent Gregory a short reply, expressing preliminary interest and asking for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Gregory,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your email, I’m certainly interested. Could you tell me a bit more about what this would involve and who recommended me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best, Rob&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gregory quickly replied - I was in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Rob,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for prompt reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your candidacy is in the candidate list we received from the San Francisco State University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll send you the description of several projects and the list of questions and criteria to assess them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the plan will be ready by mid-June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards, Gregory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to feel like a bit of a huckster. I pictured Hobert Reaton sitting in his office in San Diego, all alone, wondering why no one wanted him to judge their competitions. I decided that I would share my reservations with my new friend, and be completely open about my skills and weaknesses. If he still wanted me to judge his competition then that wasn’t my fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Gregory,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m starting to wonder if some wires have got crossed - I’ve read a few books by Paul Krugman, but aside from that have never studied or practiced economics. I’m a software engineer - this is my experience and education https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertjheaton/ . What do you think? Is there maybe another Robert Heaton in San Francisco who knows a bit more about economics?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Gregory agreed (rather quicker than I had hoped) that maybe a mistake had been made and that actually I wasn’t of any use to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Rob,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it may be a mistake. I’ll consult with my colleagues and get back to you shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards, Gregory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the last I ever heard from Gregory Harris. I thought nothing more of the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday I received an email from Coinbase:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi there,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have recently received an email from individuals named Gregory Harris or Neil Morris, claiming to administer prize grants for the University of Cambridge. These are in fact fraudulent profiles, and belong to an advanced attacker attempting to deliver malware to your laptop…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This made a lot of sense, when I thought about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had almost fallen victim to a technically advanced spear-phishing campaign. As far as I can make out (I haven’t seen this explicitly written anywhere, and I could very well be wrong about it), attackers compromised email accounts and webpages at the University of Cambridge belonging to two people called “Gregory Harris” and “Neil Morris”. The attackers used these accounts to run a spear-phishing campaign, with the goal of inducing their targets to visit one of two compromised pages hosted on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://people.ds.cam.ac.uk&lt;/code&gt;. If a target who visited one of the attackers’ pages was using Firefox, malicious Javascript on the page &lt;a href=&quot;https://objective-see.com/blog/blog_0x43.html&quot;&gt;exploited a 0-day vulnerability in Firefox&lt;/a&gt; that allowed the attackers to break out of the browser sandbox and drop malware directly onto the user’s operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had happily and repeatedly clicked on the link that “Gregory Harris” had sent me. Fortunately I was using Chrome, so the attackers’ Javascript exploit achieved nothing. But all it would have taken is for the attackers to add the 7 words “THIS PAGE MUST BE VIEWED IN FIREFOX” to the top of their page, and I’d have been toast. I’d have chuckled at how some poor chumps still couldn’t figure out basic cross-browser compatibility, and I’d have smugly copied the link over into Firefox. It’s not clear to me why the attackers didn’t do this. Maybe they didn’t have complete control over the contents of the page, or maybe they wanted to be as subtle as possible. Next time, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attackers originally targeted employees of Coinbase, a cryptocurrency exchange. However, according to members of the Coinbase team who I briefly corresponded with, the attackers subsequently broadened their campaign to a larger pool of people they believed to be associated with cryptocurrency. Presumably they wanted to steal our delicious, untraceable blobs of the blockchain. The joke was at least partially on them, since I’ve never owned any cryptocurrency other than a handful of Stellars that I got for free and have lost the password for. If they or any other attackers can help me get them back then I would be very grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with two legitimate-seeming identities, a Firefox 0-day, and an email list of people associated with cryptocurrency (plus me), the attackers set to work. They ruthlessly exploited innocent people’s slightly over-inflated beliefs of their own abilities and importance, and infected anyone viewing their links in Firefox on Mac OS with a Trojan. The Firefox vulnerabilities have now been fixed, and the webpages that the phishing emails pointed at have been taken down. But I’d be surprised if at least a few people haven’t been taken for a Satoshi or a billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how the University of Cambridge fits into this story. I don’t know if “Gregory Harris” and “Neil Morris” are real people whose university accounts were compromised, or if they’re fake people created by someone who compromised the university computing system itself, or if I’m just completely misunderstanding what happened. I don’t want to publicly pry too much into Gregory or Neil’s online lives, just in case they are in fact real, but my strong suspicion is that they are fake. This is wild speculation, as is everything else that follows, so if you work in IT at the University of Cambridge then please don’t hate me. Please do tell me more about what actually went on though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been able to find any online trace of either Gregory Harris or Neil Morris, other than their alleged LinkedIn profiles. Once again, this is perfectly fine. Not everyone has to be on Instagram or write Star Wars fan fiction. However, Gregory Harris’s LinkedIn profile has recently been taken down - it still appears in Google searches, but is not available on LinkedIn. And while Neil Morris’s profile is still up, it sure looks like it’s a fake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil’s profile looks reasonable enough at first glance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/images/phish-neil-main.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a quick Google search reveals that his self-description has been copy and pasted from another LinkedIn profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/images/phish-neil-copy.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, this is enough on its own to confirm my prior suspicions. But if we look closer we can start to detect several other funny odors too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Neil’s description of his Master’s degree is a little strange. He’s gone to the trouble of writing “Five courses and a dissertation”, but then only lists four courses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/images/phish-neil-edu.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Neil spent 7 years at secondary school. That’s standard in the UK. But his final 2 years apparently overlapped with his first 2 years at university. That doesn’t make much sense.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neil describes his pre-university education as “High School”. We don’t have “High School” in the UK - we call it “Secondary School”. This might make sense if Neil was American, or trying to communicate with an American audience, but there’s no indication that this is the case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/images/phish-neil-sec.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Neil’s LinkedIn cover photo is a stock photo of Cambridge University. I didn’t think twice about this at first, but in light of all of the above, it strikes me as a little odd. Does he really love his university so much that he uses a stock photo of it in his professional profile? Not even a nice photo of his office that he took himself? It seems more likely to me that this is the work of someone trying to make a phony profile that persuades the casual reader “I work at Cambridge University, nothing to see here”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/images/phish-neil-cover.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil, if you are real and this is your real LinkedIn profile then I am so sorry. But if you’re so real then why did you copy someone else’s self-description?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t think that it was careless of me to click on the link in the phishing email. Browser 0-days that are exploited by a sub-domain of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cam.ac.uk&lt;/code&gt; aren’t in my personal threat model, and I think that this is sensible. Security always has to be balanced with pragmatism, and not everything can be GPG-signed by a web of trust that leads back to Bruce Schneier. My &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RobJHeaton&quot;&gt;Twitter DMs&lt;/a&gt; are open for splenetic criticisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, this episode has left me feeling incredibly uneasy. Even though my story ends safely, I still fell for a phishing attack hook and line, if not also sinker. It was blind chance that the attack vector was a 0-day for a piece of software that I don’t use, rather than something more run-of-the-mill. After a few more back and forths I think I would have probably have enabled macros on any Microsoft Office documents that Gregory Harris sent me, and I might even have run code for him if he said it was part of an entry into the competition. As I mentioned I don’t have any cryptocurrency to lose, but I sure do have money in my online banking accounts that I’d like to keep there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t have an exhaustive list of the morals of this story yet. I think the main one is that you should keep your guard up when communicating with internet people who you don’t know, even if their email address and website domain look legit and their DKIM signatures check out. Also, remember that it’s extremely easy to overlook a large number of inconsistencies and oddities if you believe someone’s underlying story, especially if this story makes you feel good. Looking back it’s obviously completely absurd that the &lt;em&gt;University of Cambridge&lt;/em&gt; would ask me to judge &lt;em&gt;an economics competition&lt;/em&gt;, and re-reading Gregory Harris’s email it’s immediately apparent that it is not the work of someone skilled in professional online communication. But I wasn’t thinking critically, and had been lulled into a false sense of security by that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@cam.ac.uk&lt;/code&gt; email address and my own ego.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, a final moral - think twice before you start humble-bragging (and brag-bragging) to too many people that you’ve been asked to judge the Adam Smith Prize for Economics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;More on Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 11:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>_ttg</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://robertheaton.com/images/phish-cover.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://robertheaton.com/2019/06/24/i-was-7-words-away-from-being-spear-phished/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>I was 7 words away from being spear-phished | Robert Heaton</og:title>
<og:description>Three weeks ago I received a very flattering email from the University of Cambridge, asking me to judge the Adam Smith Prize for Economics:</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://robertheaton.com/2019/06/24/i-was-7-words-away-from-being-spear-phished/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>HTTP Cats</title>
<link>https://http.cat/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://http.cat/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://http.cat/&quot;&gt;https://http.cat/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20283794&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20283794&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 379&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 71&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 11:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>afshinmeh</dc:creator>
<og:title>HTTP Cats</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://http.cat</og:url>
<og:image>https://http.cat/100.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>API for HTTP Cats</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://http.cat/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hey advertisers, track this</title>
<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/hey-advertisers-track-this/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/hey-advertisers-track-this/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;If it feels like the ads chasing you across the internet know you a little too well, it’s because they do (unless you’re an avid user of ad blockers, in which case this is not for you). Earlier this month &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/06/04/firefox-now-available-with-enhanced-tracking-protection-by-default/&quot;&gt;we announced Enhanced Tracking Protection&lt;/a&gt; on by default for new users in our flagship Firefox Quantum browser as a way to stop third-party cookies in their tracks. If you’re still not sure why you’d want to block cookies, today we’re launching a project called &lt;a href=&quot;https://trackthis.link/&quot;&gt;Track THIS&lt;/a&gt; to help you recognize what they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re being followed across the web through cookies—&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences&quot;&gt;small data files stored by your browser&lt;/a&gt;—that remember things like language preferences, sites you’ve visited, or what’s in your shopping cart. That might sound generally fine, but it gets shady when data brokers and advertising networks also &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/cross-site-tracking-lets-unpack-that/&quot;&gt;use cookies to collect information about your internet habits without your consent&lt;/a&gt;. You should still have control over what advertisers know about you—if they know anything about you at all—which can be tough when web trackers operate out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why we made &lt;a href=&quot;https://trackthis.link/&quot;&gt;Track THIS&lt;/a&gt;: to bring that out-of-sight tracking front and center. Step into someone else’s shoe ads for a while by opening up 100 tabs at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1797&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/firefox/files/2019/06/Screenshot_2019-06-25-Track-This-A-new-kind-of-Incognito.png&quot; alt=&quot;track this site&quot; width=&quot;2886&quot; height=&quot;1512&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/files/2019/06/Screenshot_2019-06-25-Track-This-A-new-kind-of-Incognito.png 2886w, https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/files/2019/06/Screenshot_2019-06-25-Track-This-A-new-kind-of-Incognito-300x157.png 300w, https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/files/2019/06/Screenshot_2019-06-25-Track-This-A-new-kind-of-Incognito-768x402.png 768w, https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/files/2019/06/Screenshot_2019-06-25-Track-This-A-new-kind-of-Incognito-600x314.png 600w, https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/files/2019/06/Screenshot_2019-06-25-Track-This-A-new-kind-of-Incognito-1000x524.png 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2886px) 100vw, 2886px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be clear, though. This will show you ads for products you might not be interested in at all, so it’s really just throwing off brands who want to advertise to a very specific type of person. You’ll still be seeing ads. And eventually, if you just use the internet as you typically would day to day, you’ll start seeing ads again that align more closely to your normal browsing habits. If you’d rather straight-up block third-party tracking cookies, go ahead and get &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/06/04/when-it-comes-to-privacy-default-settings-matter/&quot;&gt;Enhanced Tracking Protection in Firefox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;WARNING. Before you try Track THIS, get your tabs in order and save your work. Maybe even open up a new window or browser. Track THIS will open A LOT of tabs. 100 tabs is a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a profile to trick advertisers into thinking you’re someone else. If you’ve ever wondered what life might be like as an owner of a YouTube tea channel or someone who is actively preparing for the end of the world, this is your chance! The choices are: Hypebeast, Filthy Rich, Doomsday, or Influencer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirm that you’re ready to open 100 tabs based on that profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close all 100 tabs and open up a new window. Watch your ads across the internet change before your eyes. Your ads will probably only be impacted for a few days, but ad trackers are pretty sophisticated. They could start reflecting your normal browsing habits sooner than that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you’re done with the experiment, get &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/06/04/when-it-comes-to-privacy-default-settings-matter/&quot;&gt;Firefox with Enhanced Tracking Protection&lt;/a&gt; to block third-party tracking cookies by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try it out for yourself &lt;a href=&quot;https://trackthis.link/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 09:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dantondwa</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/hey-advertisers-track-this</og:url>
<og:title>Hey advertisers, track THIS – The Firefox Frontier</og:title>
<og:description>If it feels like the ads chasing you across the internet know you a little too well, it’s because they do (unless you’re an avid user of ad blockers, in which case this is not for you).</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/files/2019/06/FX_Track_This_Blog_1200x660.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/hey-advertisers-track-this/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>